<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
  <language>English</language>
  <scanningcenter>alberta</scanningcenter>
  <sponsor>University of Alberta Libraries</sponsor>
  <contributor>University of Alberta Libraries</contributor>
  <date>1998</date>
  <subject>Education</subject>
  <subject>Education</subject>
  <subject>Special education</subject>
  <subject>Home and school</subject>
  <subject>Special education</subject>
  <subject>Education, Special</subject>
  <title>The parent advantage : helping children become more successful learners at home and school, grades 1-9</title>
  <creator>Alberta. Special Education Branch</creator>
  <creator>Learning Disabilities Association of Alberta</creator>
  <collection>albertagovernmentpublications</collection>
  <collection>university_of_alberta_libraries</collection>
  <collection>toronto</collection>
  <shiptracking>agov38</shiptracking>
  <cat_key>2012579</cat_key>
  <description>Includes bibliographic references</description>
  <description>The organizational advantage -- Use self-talk to create a positive attitude -- Organize materials -- Set goals for school success -- Taking notes -- Study buddies -- The homework advantage -- The reading advantage -- Beginning to read: learning about letters and sounds -- Learning new sight words -- Paired reading -- Read around -- Keeping your place -- Choosing the right book -- Helping children understand what they read: asking good questions -- RIDER: a visualization strategy -- Keep them reading -- RAP: paraphrasing -- Highlighting key words -- Learning new vocabulary -- Reading textbooks -- The technological advantage -- The writing advantage -- Tips for getting started -- The writing process -- Paragraph writing -- COPS: a proofreading strategy -- Parents as editors -- How much help is too much? -- Editing questions -- The neatness advantage -- The technological advantage -- The spelling advantage -- Helping children find the correct spelling of a word -- Editing spelling in written work -- How to learn new words -- Reversals -- The technological advantage -- The mathematics advantage -- Getting the facts -- Practising the facts -- Getting your math work done -- Problem solving -- Getting ready for a math test -- The technological advantage -- The test advantage -- Show what you know -- Ten study tricks -- Special accomodations for test taking -- Alberta education achievement tests -- The night before the test -- Test writing strategies -- The anxiety advantage -- What to do when the test comes back -- The technological advantage -- The project advantage -- Finding the information -- Alternative ways to show learning -- Book reports -- The technological advantage</description>
  <description>2 8 28 31 38 41</description>
  <mediatype>texts</mediatype>
  <repub_state>4</repub_state>
  <page-progression>lr</page-progression>
  <publicdate>2016-05-11 14:15:25</publicdate>
  <updatedate>2016-05-11 15:16:12</updatedate>
  <updater>associate-aaron-campbell@archive.org</updater>
  <identifier>parentadvantageh00albe</identifier>
  <uploader>associate-aaron-campbell@archive.org</uploader>
  <addeddate>2016-05-11 15:16:14</addeddate>
  <scanner>scribe1.alberta.archive.org</scanner>
  <notes>No copyright page found.</notes>
  <repub_seconds>58</repub_seconds>
  <ppi>500</ppi>
  <camera>Canon EOS 5D Mark II</camera>
  <operator>ekaitlyn@ualberta.ca</operator>
  <scandate>20160516205910</scandate>
  <republisher>associate-alex-white@archive.org</republisher>
  <imagecount>74</imagecount>
  <foldoutcount>0</foldoutcount>
  <identifier-access>http://archive.org/details/parentadvantageh00albe</identifier-access>
  <identifier-ark>ark:/13960/t5fb9rf4x</identifier-ark>
  <bookplateleaf>0008</bookplateleaf>
  <ocr>ABBYY FineReader 11.0</ocr>
  <scanfee>250</scanfee>
  <invoice>1</invoice>
  <sponsordate>20160531</sponsordate>
  <backup_location>ia906108_9</backup_location>
</metadata>
