<collection xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim">
   <record>
      <leader>08727cam a2200601 i 4500</leader>
      <controlfield tag="001">6774766</controlfield>
      <controlfield tag="003">OCoLC</controlfield>
      <controlfield tag="005">20150106073455.0</controlfield>
      <controlfield tag="006">m     o  d        </controlfield>
      <controlfield tag="007">cr |||</controlfield>
      <controlfield tag="008">141006t20152015paua    ob    000 0 eng d</controlfield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020">
         <subfield code="a">9781455756179</subfield>
         <subfield code="q">electronic bk.</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020">
         <subfield code="a">1455756172</subfield>
         <subfield code="q">electronic bk.</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020">
         <subfield code="z">9781455756179 (2 v. set : hardcover : alk. paper)</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020">
         <subfield code="z">1455756172 (2 v. set : hardcover : alk. paper)</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="035">
         <subfield code="a">ocn892338394</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="039">
         <subfield code="a">exclude</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040">
         <subfield code="a">OPELS</subfield>
         <subfield code="b">eng</subfield>
         <subfield code="e">rda</subfield>
         <subfield code="e">pn</subfield>
         <subfield code="c">OPELS</subfield>
         <subfield code="d">OPELS</subfield>
         <subfield code="d">MMU</subfield>
         <subfield code="d">AEU</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2="4" tag="050">
         <subfield code="a">RJ254</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="1" ind2="4" tag="060">
         <subfield code="a">WS 420</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="0" ind2="4" tag="082">
         <subfield code="a">618.92/01</subfield>
         <subfield code="2">23</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="090">
         <subfield code="a">Internet Access</subfield>
         <subfield code="b">AEU</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="0" ind2="0" tag="245">
         <subfield code="a">Fanaroff and Martin's neonatal-perinatal medicine :</subfield>
         <subfield code="b">diseases of the fetus and infant /</subfield>
         <subfield code="c">[edited by] Richard J. Martin, Avroy A. Fanaroff, Michele C. Walsh.</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="246">
         <subfield code="a">Neonatal-perinatal medicine</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="250">
         <subfield code="a">Tenth edition.</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2="1" tag="264">
         <subfield code="a">Philadelphia, PA :</subfield>
         <subfield code="b">Elsevier/Saunders,</subfield>
         <subfield code="c">[2015]</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2="4" tag="264">
         <subfield code="c">©2015</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
         <subfield code="a">1 online resource :</subfield>
         <subfield code="b">illustrations (some color)</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="336">
         <subfield code="a">text</subfield>
         <subfield code="b">txt</subfield>
         <subfield code="2">rdacontent</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/contentTypes/txt</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="337">
         <subfield code="a">computer</subfield>
         <subfield code="b">c</subfield>
         <subfield code="2">rdamedia</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/mediaTypes/c</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="338">
         <subfield code="a">online resource</subfield>
         <subfield code="b">cr</subfield>
         <subfield code="2">rdacarrier</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/carriers/cr</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="504">
         <subfield code="a">Includes bibliographical references.</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505">
         <subfield code="a">Growth of neonatal-perinatal medicine : a historical perspective -- Epidemiology for neonatologists -- The organization of perinatal services -- Medical ethics in neonatal care -- Legal issues in neonatal-perinatal medicine -- Evaluating and improving the quality and safety of neonatal intensive care -- Simulation in neonatal-perinatal medicine -- Coding and reimbursement : principles and practices -- Practicing evidence-based neonatal-perinatal medicine -- Perinatal and neonatal care in developing countries -- Genetic aspects of perinatal disease and prenatal diagnosis -- Perinatal imaging -- Estimation of fetal well-being -- Surgical treatment of the fetus -- Adverse exposures to the fetus -- Intrauterine growth restriction -- Developmental origins of adult health and disease -- Hypertensive disorders of pregnancy -- Diabetes mellitus during pregnancy -- Obstetric management of prematurity -- Fetal effects of autoimmune disease -- Obstetric management of multiple gestation and birth -- Post-term pregnancy -- Immune and nonimmune hydrops fetalis -- Amniotic fluid volume -- Chorioamnionitis -- Placental pathology -- Anesthesia for labor and delivery -- Physical examination of the newborn -- Birth injuries -- Congenital anomalies -- Overview and initial management of delivery room resuscitation -- Role of positive pressure ventilation in neonatal resuscitation -- Oxygen therapy in neonatal resuscitation -- Chest compression, medications, and special problems in neonatal resuscitation -- The thermal environment of the intensive care nursery -- The sensory environment of the intensive care nursery -- Design considerations of the intensive care nursery -- Biomedical engineering aspects of neonatal cardiorespiratory monitoring -- Diagnostic imaging of the neonate -- Anesthesia in the neonate -- The late preterm infant -- Nutrient requirements and provision of nutritional support in the premature neonate -- Fluid, electrolytes, and acid-base homeostasis -- Normal mother-infant attachment -- Attachment challenges with premature or sick infants -- Parental mental health issues -- Care of the long-stay infant and parents -- Principles of drug use in the fetus and neonate -- Principles of drug use during lactation -- Pharmacokinetics in neonatal medicine -- Enhancing safe prescribing in the neonatal intensive care unit -- Infants with antenatal exposure to drugs -- Developmental immunology -- Postnatal bacterial infections -- Perinatal fungal and protozoal infections -- Perinatal viral infections -- Normal and abnormal brain development -- White matter damage and encephalopathy of prematurity --</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505">
         <subfield code="a">Intracranial hemorrhage and vascular lesions in the neonate -- Hypoxic-ischemic encephalopathy -- Seizures in neonates -- Hypotonia and neuromuscular disease in the neonate -- Disorders in head shape and size -- Myelomeningocele and related neural tube defects -- Hearing loss in the newborn infant -- Assessment and optimization of neurobehavioral development in preterm infants -- Early childhood neurodevelopmental outcomes of high-risk neonates -- Role of imaging in neurodevelopmental outcomes of high-risk neonates -- Lung development and maturation -- Assessment of neonatal pulmonary function -- Respiratory distress syndrome in the neonate -- Assisted ventilation and its complications -- Neonatal respiratory disorders --Neonatal apnea and the foundation of respiratory control -- Upper airway lesions in the neonate -- Bronchopulmonary dysplasia in the neonate -- Therapy for cardiorespiratory failure in the neonate -- Cardiac embryology -- Pulmonary vascular development -- Genetic and environmental contributions to congenital heart disease -- Prenatal diagnosis of congenital heart disease -- Patent ductus arteriosus -- Congenital defects of the cardiovascular system -- Cardiovascular problems of the neonate -- Disorders of cardiac rhythm and conduction in newborns -- Principles of medical and surgical management of the neonate -- Hematologic and oncologic problems in the fetus and neonate -- Blood component therapy for the neonate -- Development of the neonatal gastrointestinal tract -- Gastroesophageal reflux and gastroesophageal reflux disease in the neonate -- Disorders of digestion in the neonate -- Selected gastrointestinal anomalies in the neonate -- Neonatal necrotizing enterocolitis -- Disorders of carbohydrate metabolism in the neonate -- Disorders of calcium, phosphorus, and magnesium metabolism in the neonate -- Thyroid disorders in the neonate -- Disorders of sex development -- Inborn errors of metabolism -- Neonatal jaundice and liver diseases -- The kidney and urinary tract of the neonate -- The skin of the neonate -- Examination and common problems of the neonatal eye -- Retinopathy of prematurity -- Musculoskeletal disorders in neonates -- Bone and joint infections in neonates -- Congenital abnormalities of the upper and lower extremities and spine -- Therapeutic agents -- Tables of normal values -- Schedule for immunization of preterm infants.</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="506">
         <subfield code="a">Access restricted to authorized users and institutions.</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="520">
         <subfield code="a">Tackle your toughest challenges and improve the quality of life and long-term outcomes of your patients with authoritative guidance from Fanaroff and Martin's Neonatal-Perinatal Medicine. Drs. Richard J. Martin, Avroy A. Fanaroff, and Michele C. Walsh and a contributing team of leading experts in the field deliver a multi-disciplinary approach to the management and evidence-based treatment of problems in the mother, fetus and neonate. New chapters, expanded and updated coverage, increased worldwide perspectives, and many new contributors keep you current on the late preterm infant, the fetal origins of adult disease, neonatal anemia, genetic disorders, and more.</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="588">
         <subfield code="a">Description based on online resource; title from digital title page (ClinicalKey, viewed on October 31, 2014).</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="596">
         <subfield code="a">44</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
         <subfield code="a">Newborn infants</subfield>
         <subfield code="x">Diseases.</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85066052</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
         <subfield code="a">Fetus</subfield>
         <subfield code="x">Diseases.</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85047967</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="1" ind2="2" tag="650">
         <subfield code="a">Fetal Diseases.</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://id.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/D005315</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="2" ind2="2" tag="650">
         <subfield code="a">Infant, Newborn, Diseases.</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://id.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/D007232</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="2" ind2="2" tag="650">
         <subfield code="a">Perinatal Care.</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://id.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/D018743</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="2" ind2="2" tag="650">
         <subfield code="a">Pregnancy Complications.</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://id.nlm.nih.gov/mesh/D011248</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="700">
         <subfield code="a">Martin, Richard J.</subfield>
         <subfield code="q">(Richard John),</subfield>
         <subfield code="d">1946-</subfield>
         <subfield code="e">editor.</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n82040467</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://viaf.org/viaf/84856096</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="700">
         <subfield code="a">Fanaroff, Avroy A.,</subfield>
         <subfield code="e">editor.</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n79065141</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://viaf.org/viaf/32091347</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="700">
         <subfield code="a">Walsh, Michele C.,</subfield>
         <subfield code="e">editor.</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n96803207</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://viaf.org/viaf/75591791</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="758">
         <subfield code="0">http://worldcat.org/entity/work/id/288710566</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="0" ind2="8" tag="776">
         <subfield code="i">Print version:</subfield>
         <subfield code="t">Fanaroff and Martin's neonatal-perinatal medicine.</subfield>
         <subfield code="b">10th edition</subfield>
         <subfield code="z">9781455756179</subfield>
         <subfield code="w">(DLC)  2014023366</subfield>
         <subfield code="w">(OCoLC)881508552</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="787">
         <subfield code="n">OCLC Work Id</subfield>
         <subfield code="o">http://worldcat.org/entity/work/id/288710566</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="4" ind2="0" tag="856">
         <subfield code="3">University of Alberta Access</subfield>
         <subfield code="u">https://www.clinicalkey.com/dura/browse/bookChapter/3-s2.0-C20121027749</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="949">
         <subfield code="h">UAIN</subfield>
         <subfield code="z">CKEY</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="926">
         <subfield code="a">Internet Access</subfield>
         <subfield code="w">LC</subfield>
         <subfield code="c">1</subfield>
         <subfield code="i">6774766-1001</subfield>
         <subfield code="l">INTERNET</subfield>
         <subfield code="m">UAINTERNET</subfield>
         <subfield code="r">Y</subfield>
         <subfield code="s">Y</subfield>
         <subfield code="t">E-RESOURCE</subfield>
         <subfield code="u">1/13/2015</subfield>
         <subfield code="x">E-BOOK</subfield>
         <subfield code="z">CKEY</subfield>
      </datafield>
   </record>
</collection>
