<collection xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim">
   <record>
      <leader>07538nam a2200517 i 4500</leader>
      <controlfield tag="001">6805680</controlfield>
      <controlfield tag="005">20141120144011.0</controlfield>
      <controlfield tag="008">141120s2015    caua   foab   001 0 eng d</controlfield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020">
         <subfield code="z">9781627052627</subfield>
         <subfield code="q">ebook</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="020">
         <subfield code="a">9781627052610</subfield>
         <subfield code="q">print</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="035">
         <subfield code="a">ocn981888738</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="039">
         <subfield code="a">exclude</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="040">
         <subfield code="a">CaBNVSL</subfield>
         <subfield code="b">eng</subfield>
         <subfield code="e">rda</subfield>
         <subfield code="c">CaBNVSL</subfield>
         <subfield code="d">CaBNVSL</subfield>
         <subfield code="d">AEU</subfield>
         <subfield code="d">AGPC</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2="4" tag="050">
         <subfield code="a">QA76.9.H85</subfield>
         <subfield code="b">L255 2015</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="0" ind2="4" tag="082">
         <subfield code="a">004.019</subfield>
         <subfield code="2">23</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="090">
         <subfield code="a">QA 76.9 H85 L255 2015</subfield>
         <subfield code="b">AGPC</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="100">
         <subfield code="a">Lalmas, Mounia,</subfield>
         <subfield code="e">author.</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n98073004</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://viaf.org/viaf/45439655</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="1" ind2="0" tag="245">
         <subfield code="a">Measuring user engagement /</subfield>
         <subfield code="c">Mounia Lalmas, Heather O'Brien, Elad Yom-Tov.</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2="1" tag="264">
         <subfield code="a">San Rafael, California (1537 Fourth Street, San Rafael, CA  94901 USA) :</subfield>
         <subfield code="b">Morgan &amp; Claypool,</subfield>
         <subfield code="c">2015.</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="300">
         <subfield code="a">xv, 116 pages :</subfield>
         <subfield code="b">illustrations ;</subfield>
         <subfield code="c">24 cm.</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="336">
         <subfield code="a">text</subfield>
         <subfield code="b">txt</subfield>
         <subfield code="2">rdacontent</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/contentTypes/txt</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="337">
         <subfield code="a">unmediated</subfield>
         <subfield code="b">n</subfield>
         <subfield code="2">rdamedia</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/mediaTypes/n</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="338">
         <subfield code="a">volume</subfield>
         <subfield code="b">nc</subfield>
         <subfield code="2">rdacarrier</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/carriers/nc</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="490">
         <subfield code="a">Synthesis lectures on information concepts, retrieval, and services,</subfield>
         <subfield code="x">1947-9468 ;</subfield>
         <subfield code="v"># 38</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="500">
         <subfield code="a">Part of: Synthesis digital library of engineering and computer science.</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="504">
         <subfield code="a">Includes bibliographical references (pages 93-112) and index.</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="505">
         <subfield code="a">1. Introduction and scope -- 1.1 Definitions -- 1.2 User engagement vs. user experience -- 1.3 Characteristics -- 1.3.1 Focused attention -- 1.3.2 Positive affect -- 1.3.3 Aesthetics appeal -- 1.3.4 Endurability -- 1.3.5 Novelty -- 1.3.6 Richness and control -- 1.3.7 Reputation, trust, and expectation -- 1.3.8 User context, motivation, incentives, and benefits -- 1.4 Measurements -- 1.5 Scope -- 1.6 Structure --</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="505">
         <subfield code="a">2. Approaches based on self-report methods -- 2.1 Self-report approaches -- 2.2 Advantages and limitations of self-report methods -- 2.2.1 Communication -- 2.2.2 Methodology bias -- 2.2.3 Reliability and validity -- 2.3 Interviews -- 2.3.1 Types of interviews -- 2.3.2 Applying interviews to measure user engagement -- 2.4 Think aloud and think after protocols -- 2.4.1 Think aloud -- 2.4.2 Think after -- 2.4.3 Relationship to user engagement -- 2.5 Questionnaires -- 2.6 Questionnaires for measuring user engagement -- 2.6.1 Survey to evaluate engagement -- 2.6.2 Engagement and influences on questionnaire -- 2.6.3 User engagement scale -- 2.6.4 eHealth engagement scale -- 2.7 Constructs related to user engagement -- 2.7.1 Mental workload -- 2.7.2 Disorientation -- 2.7.3 Playfulness -- 2.7.4 Cognitive absorption -- 2.8 Summary --</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="505">
         <subfield code="a">3. Approaches based on physiological measurements -- 3.1 Psychophysiological measurements -- 3.2 Facial expressions -- 3.3 Eye tracking -- 3.3.1 Eye tracking and search -- 3.3.2 Eye tracking and reading -- 3.3.3 Eye tracking and selection -- 3.3.4 Summary and limitations -- 3.4 Cursor tracking -- 3.4.1 Aligning eye gaze and mouse movement -- 3.4.2 Mouse movement in search -- 3.4.3 Mouse movement elsewhere -- 3.5 Summary --</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="505">
         <subfield code="a">4. Approaches based on web analytics -- 4.1 Intra-session vs. inter-session engagement -- 4.2 Some dimensions of online measurements -- 4.2.1 Dependence on the type of website -- 4.2.2 Dependence on the type of user -- 4.2.3 Dependence on the task -- 4.3 Large-scale measurements -- 4.4 Intra-session measurements -- 4.4.1 Dwell time and similar measures -- 4.4.2 Revisits to a site -- 4.4.3 Clickthrough rate -- 4.4.4 Number of pages viewed -- 4.4.5 Other measurements -- 4.5 Inter-session measurements -- 4.5.1 Direct value measurement -- 4.5.2 Total use measurement -- 4.5.3 Return-rate measurement -- 4.6 Summary --</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="505">
         <subfield code="a">5. Beyond desktop, single site, and single task -- 5.1 Measuring for online multitasking -- 5.2 Measuring on a network of sites -- 5.3 Measuring in mobile information seeking -- 5.4 Summary --</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="505">
         <subfield code="a">6. Enhancing the rigor of user engagement methods and measures -- 6.1 Scale -- 6.2 Setting -- 6.3 Temporality -- 6.4 Objectivity and subjectivity -- 6.5 Process- and product-based -- 6.6 Summary --</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="505">
         <subfield code="a">7. Conclusions and future research directions -- 7.1 Summary -- 7.2 Future research directions -- 7.3 Take-aways --</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="8" ind2=" " tag="505">
         <subfield code="a">Bibliography -- Authors' biographies -- Index.</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="3" ind2=" " tag="520">
         <subfield code="a">User engagement refers to the quality of the user experience that emphasizes the positive aspects of interacting with an online application and, in particular, the desire to use that application longer and repeatedly. User engagement is a key concept in the design of online applications (whether for desktop, tablet or mobile), motivated by the observation that successful applications are not just used, but are engaged with. Users invest time, attention, and emotion in their use of technology, and seek to satisfy pragmatic and hedonic needs. Measurement is critical for evaluating whether online applications are able to successfully engage users, and may inform the design of and use of applications. User engagement is a multifaceted, complex phenomenon; this gives rise to a number of potential measurement approaches. Common ways to evaluate user engagement include using self-report measures, e.g., questionnaires; observational methods, e.g. facial expression analysis, speech analysis; neuro-physiological signal processing methods, e.g., respiratory and cardiovascular accelerations and decelerations, muscle spasms; and web analytics, e.g., number of site visits, click depth. These methods represent various trade-offs in terms of the setting (laboratory versus "in the wild"), object of measurement (user behaviour, affect or cognition) and scale of data collected. For instance, small-scale user studies are deep and rich, but limited in terms of generalizability, whereas large-scale web analytic studies are powerful but negate users' motivation and context. The focus of this book is how user engagement is currently being measured and various considerations for its measurement. Our goal is to leave readers with an appreciation of the various ways in which to measure user engagement, and their associated strengths and weaknesses. We emphasize the multifaceted nature of user engagement and the unique contextual constraints that come to bear upon attempts to measure engagement in different settings, and across different user groups and web domains. At the same time, this book advocates for the development of "good" measures and good measurement practices that will advance the study of user engagement and improve our understanding of this construct, which has become so vital in our wired world.</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="530">
         <subfield code="a">Also issued electronically.</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="596">
         <subfield code="a">28</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="650">
         <subfield code="a">Human-computer interaction</subfield>
         <subfield code="x">Measurement.</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="700">
         <subfield code="a">O'Brien, Heather,</subfield>
         <subfield code="d">1977-</subfield>
         <subfield code="e">author.</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/no2015007078</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://viaf.org/viaf/313497660</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="1" ind2=" " tag="700">
         <subfield code="a">Yom-Tov, Elad,</subfield>
         <subfield code="e">author.</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n2004002587</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://viaf.org/viaf/36301636</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="758">
         <subfield code="0">http://worldcat.org/entity/work/id/1060511625</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1="0" ind2=" " tag="787">
         <subfield code="n">OCLC Work Id</subfield>
         <subfield code="o">http://worldcat.org/entity/work/id/1060511625</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="830">
         <subfield code="a">Synthesis digital library of engineering and computer science.</subfield>
         <subfield code="0">http://id.loc.gov/authorities/names/n2016188085</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2="0" tag="830">
         <subfield code="a">Synthesis lectures on information concepts, retrieval, and services ;</subfield>
         <subfield code="v"># 38.</subfield>
         <subfield code="x">1947-9468</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="949">
         <subfield code="h">UAIN</subfield>
         <subfield code="z">SYNTHDIG</subfield>
      </datafield>
      <datafield ind1=" " ind2=" " tag="926">
         <subfield code="a">QA 76.9 H85 L255 2015</subfield>
         <subfield code="w">LC</subfield>
         <subfield code="c">1</subfield>
         <subfield code="i">31847001272613</subfield>
         <subfield code="l">ON_SHELF</subfield>
         <subfield code="m">GPRC_GP</subfield>
         <subfield code="p">$150.00</subfield>
         <subfield code="r">Y</subfield>
         <subfield code="s">Y</subfield>
         <subfield code="t">BOOK</subfield>
         <subfield code="u">2/17/2015</subfield>
      </datafield>
   </record>
</collection>
