<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:diag="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/diagnostic/" xmlns:oclcterms="http://purl.org/oclc/terms/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/">
    <title>OCLC Worldcat Search: Oil in ice computer model /</title>
    <id>http://worldcat.org/webservices/catalog/search/worldcat/opensearch?q=Oil+in+ice+computer+model+%2F&amp;start=1&amp;count=10&amp;format=atom&amp;wskey=1QSLAhHnqyQYTlcnREquxaYmTBEng0FbYgPUwa5clqNAmG1Qe8m0LsqRxh22iTfoi1TGdOMloHfTjzXf</id>
    <updated>2018-05-16T16:50:21-04:00</updated>
    <subtitle>Search results for Oil in ice computer model / at http://worldcat.org/webservices/catalog</subtitle>
    <opensearch:totalResults>68</opensearch:totalResults>
    <opensearch:startIndex>1</opensearch:startIndex>
    <opensearch:itemsPerPage>10</opensearch:itemsPerPage>
    <opensearch:Query role="request" searchTerms="Oil in ice computer model /" startPage="1"/>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://worldcat.org/webservices/catalog/search/worldcat/opensearch?q=Oil+in+ice+computer+model+%2F&amp;start=1&amp;count=10&amp;wskey=1QSLAhHnqyQYTlcnREquxaYmTBEng0FbYgPUwa5clqNAmG1Qe8m0LsqRxh22iTfoi1TGdOMloHfTjzXf" type="text/html"/>
    <link rel="self" href="http://worldcat.org/webservices/catalog/search/worldcat/opensearch?q=Oil+in+ice+computer+model+%2F&amp;start=1&amp;count=10&amp;format=atom&amp;wskey=1QSLAhHnqyQYTlcnREquxaYmTBEng0FbYgPUwa5clqNAmG1Qe8m0LsqRxh22iTfoi1TGdOMloHfTjzXf" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link rel="first" href="http://worldcat.org/webservices/catalog/search/worldcat/opensearch?q=Oil+in+ice+computer+model+%2F&amp;start=1&amp;count=10&amp;format=atom&amp;wskey=1QSLAhHnqyQYTlcnREquxaYmTBEng0FbYgPUwa5clqNAmG1Qe8m0LsqRxh22iTfoi1TGdOMloHfTjzXf" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link rel="next" href="http://worldcat.org/webservices/catalog/search/worldcat/opensearch?q=Oil+in+ice+computer+model+%2F&amp;start=11&amp;count=10&amp;format=atom&amp;wskey=1QSLAhHnqyQYTlcnREquxaYmTBEng0FbYgPUwa5clqNAmG1Qe8m0LsqRxh22iTfoi1TGdOMloHfTjzXf" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link rel="last" href="http://worldcat.org/webservices/catalog/search/worldcat/opensearch?q=Oil+in+ice+computer+model+%2F&amp;start=68&amp;count=10&amp;format=atom&amp;wskey=1QSLAhHnqyQYTlcnREquxaYmTBEng0FbYgPUwa5clqNAmG1Qe8m0LsqRxh22iTfoi1TGdOMloHfTjzXf" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    <link rel="search" type="application/opensearchdescription+xml" href="http://worldcat.org/webservices/catalog/opensearch.description.xml"/>
    <entry>
        <author>
            <name>Wotherspoon, P. (Paul)</name>
        </author>
        <title>Oil in ice computer model</title>
        <link href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/13724855"/>
        <id>http://worldcat.org/oclc/13724855</id>
        <updated>2018-05-08T22:44:22Z</updated>
        <summary>This report documents a computer simulation program that depicts the behaviour and distribution of oil spilled in or under sea ice. The program combines mathematical models developed in previous studies to describe the motion of oil in or under the ice surface. By inputting or estimating such key parameters as oil type, spill duration, flow rate under ice, current speeds and direction, under ice roughness, shoreline, and ice boundaries, a time series of plots are generated showing the distribution of the spilled oil. The simulation plots the position of the oil with respect to the particular ice sheet, however, it does not include the subsequent movement of oil contaminated ice.</summary>
        <dc:identifier>urn:ISBN:092078318X</dc:identifier>
        <dc:identifier>urn:ISBN:9780920783184</dc:identifier>
        <oclcterms:recordIdentifier>13724855</oclcterms:recordIdentifier>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <author>
            <name>Taylor, Charles E. (Charles Eugene), 1956- Kwan, Jonathan T., 1950-</name>
        </author>
        <title>Advances in the study of gas hydrates</title>
        <link href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/57346575"/>
        <id>http://worldcat.org/oclc/57346575</id>
        <updated>2017-12-16T03:12:11Z</updated>
        <dc:identifier>urn:ISBN:0306486458</dc:identifier>
        <dc:identifier>urn:ISBN:9780306486456</dc:identifier>
        <dc:identifier>urn:ISBN:9780306484810</dc:identifier>
        <dc:identifier>urn:ISBN:0306484811</dc:identifier>
        <oclcterms:recordIdentifier>57346575</oclcterms:recordIdentifier>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <author>
            <name>Shen, Hung T. Yapa, Poojitha D. Wang, De S. Yang, Xiao Q.</name>
        </author>
        <title>A Mathematical Model for Oil Slick Transport and Mixing in Rivers</title>
        <link href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1026501056"/>
        <id>http://worldcat.org/oclc/1026501056</id>
        <updated>2018-03-13T21:39:53Z</updated>
        <summary>The growing concern over the impacts of oil spills on aquatic environments has led to the development of many computer models for simulating the transport and spreading of oil slicks in surface waters. Almost all of these models were developed for coastal environments. A few river models exist. These models only considered the movement of surface oil slicks. In this study a two- layer model, ROSS2, is developed for simulating oil spills in rivers. This model considers the oil in the river to consist of a surface slick and suspended oil droplets entrained over the depth of the flow. The oil transformation processes considered in the model include advection, mechanical spreading, turbulent diffusion and mixing, evaporation, dissolution, emulsification, shoreline deposition and sinking. The model can be used for simulating instantaneous or continuous spills either on or under the water surface in rivers with or without an ice cover. The model has been implemented for the Ohio-Monongahela-Allegheny river system and the upper St. Lawrence River. This report describes the model formulation and implementation. A case study is presented along with detailed explanations of the program structure and its input and output. Although it is developed for simulating oil spills, the model can be applied to spills of other hazardous materials. Computer models, Oil spills, Oil slicks, Rivers.</summary>
        <oclcterms:recordIdentifier>1026501056</oclcterms:recordIdentifier>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <author>
            <name>SOCO (Conference) (7th : 2012 : Ostrava, Czech Republic)</name>
        </author>
        <title>Soft computing models in industrial and environmental applications 7th International Conference, SOCO'12, Ostrava, Czech Republic, September 5th-7th, 2012</title>
        <link href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/809202190"/>
        <id>http://worldcat.org/oclc/809202190</id>
        <updated>2018-01-05T11:37:00Z</updated>
        <summary>This volume of Advances in Intelligent and Soft Computing contains accepted papers presented at SOCO 2012, held in the beautiful and historic city of Ostrava (Czech Republic), in September 2012. Soft computing represents a collection or set of computational techniques in machine learning, computer science and some engineering disciplines, which investigate, simulate, and analyze very complex issues and phenomena. After a through peer-review process, the SOCO 2012 International Program Committee selected 75 papers which are published in these conference proceedings, and represents an acceptance rate of 38%. In this relevant edition a special emphasis was put on the organization of special sessions. Three special sessions were organized related to relevant topics as: Soft computing models for Control Theory &amp; Applications in Electrical Engineering, Soft computing models for biomedical signals and data processing and Advanced Soft Computing Methods in Computer Vision and Data Processing. The selection of papers was extremely rigorous in order to maintain the high quality of the conference and we would like to thank the members of the Program Committees for their hard work in the reviewing process. This is a crucial process to the creation of a high standard conference and the SOCO conference would not exist without their help.</summary>
        <dc:identifier>urn:ISBN:9783642329227</dc:identifier>
        <dc:identifier>urn:ISBN:3642329225</dc:identifier>
        <dc:identifier>urn:LCCN:2012945408</dc:identifier>
        <oclcterms:recordIdentifier>809202190</oclcterms:recordIdentifier>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <author>
            <name>Hay and Company Consultants Inc. Environmental Studies Revolving Funds (Canada)</name>
        </author>
        <title>Motion and impact of icebergs : development of a model to predict ice mass motions in the vicinity of an offshore structure</title>
        <link href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/757734328"/>
        <id>http://worldcat.org/oclc/757734328</id>
        <updated>2018-05-08T22:42:41Z</updated>
        <summary>1. Review of available literature pertaining to the problem. 2. Survey of existing computer models useful in investigating the problem. 3. Development and testing of a computer model appropriate for the hydrodynamic interactions of two bodies in waves and currents. 4. Survey of model tank facilities capable of performing tests of the behaviour of ice masses in close proximity to a structure.</summary>
        <dc:identifier>urn:ISBN:0920783430</dc:identifier>
        <dc:identifier>urn:ISBN:9780920783436</dc:identifier>
        <oclcterms:recordIdentifier>757734328</oclcterms:recordIdentifier>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <author>
            <name>Comfort, G.</name>
        </author>
        <title>Analytical modelling of oil and gas spreading under ice</title>
        <link href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/51650428"/>
        <id>http://worldcat.org/oclc/51650428</id>
        <updated>2016-10-05T00:42:59Z</updated>
        <summary>Wotherspoon et al. (1985) developed an analytical model to describe the spread of oil and/or gas under a level ice cover. This paper evaluates that model by undertaking a separate spreading analysis based on the observed processes and on a review of the available literature. The evaluation was performed for a spill in the southern Beaufort Sea for the case where currents are negligible. The resulting analysis was used to predict the probable spread of oil and gas under an ice sheet. Results are compared to the Wotherspoon model predictions. The most significant differences between those two approaches are discussed. A computer program listing of a spreading model is appended.</summary>
        <dc:identifier>urn:ISBN:0920783767</dc:identifier>
        <dc:identifier>urn:ISBN:9780920783764</dc:identifier>
        <oclcterms:recordIdentifier>51650428</oclcterms:recordIdentifier>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <author>
            <name>Los Alamos National Laboratory. United States. Department of Energy. United States. Department of Energy. Office of Scientific and Technical Information.</name>
        </author>
        <title>GASFLOW : a computational model to analyze accidents in nuclear containment and facility buildings.</title>
        <link href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/727215671"/>
        <id>http://worldcat.org/oclc/727215671</id>
        <updated>2016-08-02T10:03:14Z</updated>
        <summary>GASFLOW is a finite-volume computer code that solves the time-dependent, compressible Navier-Stokes equations for multiple gas species. The fluid-dynamics algorithm is coupled to the chemical kinetics of combusting liquids or gases to simulate diffusion or propagating flames in complex geometries of nuclear containment or confinement and facilities' buildings. Fluid turbulence is calculated to enhance the transport and mixing of gases in rooms and volumes that may be connected by a ventilation system. The ventilation system may consist of extensive ductwork, filters, dampers or valves, and fans. Condensation and heat transfer to walls, floors, ceilings, and internal structures are calculated to model the appropriate energy sinks. Solid and liquid aerosol behavior is simulated to give the time and space inventory of radionuclides. The solution procedure of the governing equations is a modified Los Alamos ICE'd-ALE methodology. Complex facilities can be represented by separate computational domains (multiblocks) that communicate through overlapping boundary conditions. The ventilation system is superimposed throughout the multiblock mesh. Gas mixtures and aerosols are transported through the free three-dimensional volumes and the restricted one-dimensional ventilation components as the accident and fluid flow fields evolve. Combustion may occur if sufficient fuel and reactant or oxidizer are present and have an ignition source. Pressure and thermal loads on the building, structural components, and safety-related equipment can be determined for specific accident scenarios. GASFLOW calculations have been compared with large oil-pool fire tests in the 1986 HDR containment test T52.14, which is a 3000-kW fire experiment. The computed results are in good agreement with the observed data.</summary>
        <oclcterms:recordIdentifier>727215671</oclcterms:recordIdentifier>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <author>
            <name>World Water &amp; Environmental Resources Congress (2004 : Salt Lake City, Utah)</name>
        </author>
        <title>Critical transitions in water and environmental resources management : proceedings of World Water and Environmental Resources Congress 2004, June 27-July 1, 2004, Salt Lake City, Utah, USA</title>
        <link href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/65287629"/>
        <id>http://worldcat.org/oclc/65287629</id>
        <updated>2017-03-21T14:24:13Z</updated>
        <oclcterms:recordIdentifier>65287629</oclcterms:recordIdentifier>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <author>
            <name>International Conference on Advances in Fluid Mechanics (5th : 2004 : Lisbon, Portugal)</name>
        </author>
        <title>Advances in fluid mechanics V</title>
        <link href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/55025250"/>
        <id>http://worldcat.org/oclc/55025250</id>
        <updated>2018-04-23T17:13:19Z</updated>
        <dc:identifier>urn:ISBN:1853127043</dc:identifier>
        <dc:identifier>urn:ISBN:9781853127045</dc:identifier>
        <dc:identifier>urn:LCCN:2004275363</dc:identifier>
        <oclcterms:recordIdentifier>55025250</oclcterms:recordIdentifier>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <author>
            <name>Li, Guofu. Shchukin, Valery Ya.</name>
        </author>
        <title>Advances in engineering design and optimization III : selected, peer reviewed papers from the third international conference on engineering design and optimization (ICEDO 2012), May 25-27, 2012, Shaoxing, P.R. China</title>
        <link href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/819517372"/>
        <id>http://worldcat.org/oclc/819517372</id>
        <updated>2016-03-15T08:46:57Z</updated>
        <dc:identifier>urn:ISBN:9783037854822</dc:identifier>
        <dc:identifier>urn:ISBN:3037854820</dc:identifier>
        <oclcterms:recordIdentifier>819517372</oclcterms:recordIdentifier>
    </entry>
</feed>
