<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><metadata xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://dublincore.org/documents/dcmi-terms/"><dcterms:title>Alberta Adverse Childhood Experiences Survey 2013 (ACE 2013)</dcterms:title><dcterms:identifier>https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10801</dcterms:identifier><dcterms:creator>McDonald, Sheila</dcterms:creator><dcterms:creator>Tough, Suzanne</dcterms:creator><dcterms:publisher>UAL Dataverse</dcterms:publisher><dcterms:issued>2016-05-31</dcterms:issued><dcterms:modified>2019-09-09T15:17:33Z</dcterms:modified><dcterms:description>The 2013 Alberta Adverse Child Experiences survey is a computer-assisted telephone survey of 1200 Albertan adults designed to assess Adverse Childhood Experiences (ACEs). It is a portion of the 2013 Alberta Survey (doi:10.7939/DVN/10573) conducted by the Population Research Lab, and commissioned by PolicyWise for Children&#xd;
&amp; Families (formerly the Alberta Centre for Child, Family and Community Research).  Eight questions about adverse childhood experiences (ACEs) were derived from the original ACE checklist administered through Kaiser Permanente. Questions were modified to reflect the Alberta, Canada environment, the emerging literature on child development, and to be acceptable for a telephone survey. Question modifications included deleting a question about having a parent incarcerated, and adding a question on&#xd;
living with a household member with a chronic medical condition. Questions were pilot tested. Three questions covered abuse, and the remaining five focused on aspects of household risk that can increase dysfunction.&#xd;
&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;strong>These metadata are also available through SAGE's searchable metadata website:&lt;br>&#xd;
http://sagemetadata.policywise.com/nada/index.php/catalog/3&lt;/strong></dcterms:description><dcterms:subject>Medicine, Health and Life Sciences</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>Social Sciences</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>Adverse experience</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>Childhood experience</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>Health</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>Stress</dcterms:subject><dcterms:date>2013</dcterms:date><dcterms:dateSubmitted>2016-05-25</dcterms:dateSubmitted><dcterms:temporal>2013-06-18</dcterms:temporal><dcterms:temporal>2013-07-23</dcterms:temporal><dcterms:type>Computer-assisted telephone survey</dcterms:type><dcterms:spatial>Canada</dcterms:spatial><dcterms:spatial>Edmonton, Alberta; Calgary, Alberta; Other parts of Alberta</dcterms:spatial><dcterms:license>NONE</dcterms:license><dcterms:rights>No restrictions</dcterms:rights></metadata>