<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><metadata xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://dublincore.org/documents/dcmi-terms/"><dcterms:title>The Alberta Maternal Mental Health Survey 2012 - What Albertans Know About Maternal Mental Health</dcterms:title><dcterms:identifier>https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10813</dcterms:identifier><dcterms:creator>Kingston, Dawn</dcterms:creator><dcterms:creator>McDonald, Sheila</dcterms:creator><dcterms:creator>Tough, Suzanne</dcterms:creator><dcterms:creator>Austin, Marie-Paule</dcterms:creator><dcterms:creator>Hegadoren, Kathy</dcterms:creator><dcterms:creator>Lasiuk, Gerri</dcterms:creator><dcterms:publisher>UAL Dataverse</dcterms:publisher><dcterms:issued>2016-06-10</dcterms:issued><dcterms:modified>2019-09-09T15:14:50Z</dcterms:modified><dcterms:description>At a prevalence rate of 13-25%, mental health problems are among the most common morbidities of the prenatal and postnatal periods. They have been associated with increased risk of preterm birth and low birthweight, child developmental delay, and poor child mental health. However, very few pregnant and postpartum women proactively seek help or engage in treatment and less than 15% receive needed mental healthcare.  The Alberta Maternal Mental Health Survey 2012: What Albertans Know About Maternal Mental Health is a c&#xd;
omputer assisted telephone survey of Alberta adults conducted in 2012 by the Population Research Lab on behalf of PolicyWise for Children&#xd;
&amp; Families (formerly the Alberta Centre for Child, Family and Community Research). This survey was a part of the Alberta Survey 2012b. The subject areas covered by the survey include:  a) Adults' understanding of the effects of depression and anxiety in the prenatal and post-partum period b) Adults' views on mental health screening and treatment in pregnant and post-partum women c) Help-seeking for prenatal and postpartum anxiety and depression  Questions were drawn from the Australian Perinatal&#xd;
Depression Monitor, a 26-item survey designed to measure populationbased awareness, attitudes and knowledge regarding prenatal and postnatal mental health. Additional questions were developed and tested for this survey to address the Canadian context.&#xd;
&lt;br>&lt;br>&lt;strong>These metadata are also available through SAGE's searchable metadata website:&lt;br>&#xd;
http://sagemetadata.policywise.com/nada/index.php/catalog/7&lt;/strong></dcterms:description><dcterms:subject>Medicine, Health and Life Sciences</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>Social Sciences</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>Prenatal mental health</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>Post-partum mental health</dcterms:subject><dcterms:date>2012</dcterms:date><dcterms:dateSubmitted>2016-06-10</dcterms:dateSubmitted><dcterms:temporal>2012</dcterms:temporal><dcterms:temporal>2012</dcterms:temporal><dcterms:temporal>2012-06-05</dcterms:temporal><dcterms:temporal>2012-06-27</dcterms:temporal><dcterms:type>Survey</dcterms:type><dcterms:spatial>Canada</dcterms:spatial><dcterms:spatial>Metropolitan Calgary; Metropolitan Edmonton; Rest of Alberta</dcterms:spatial><dcterms:license>NONE</dcterms:license><dcterms:rights>No restrictions</dcterms:rights></metadata>