<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><metadata xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://dublincore.org/documents/dcmi-terms/"><dcterms:title>Prenatal fruit juice exposure enhances memory consolidation in male post-weanling Sprague-Dawley rats</dcterms:title><dcterms:identifier>https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/4VN1X0</dcterms:identifier><dcterms:creator>Ward-Flanagan, Rachel</dcterms:creator><dcterms:creator>Scavuzzo, Claire</dcterms:creator><dcterms:creator>Mandhane, Piush</dcterms:creator><dcterms:creator>Bolduc, Francois</dcterms:creator><dcterms:creator>Dickson, Clayton T.</dcterms:creator><dcterms:publisher>UAL Dataverse</dcterms:publisher><dcterms:issued>2019-12-19</dcterms:issued><dcterms:modified>2019-12-19T17:32:09Z</dcterms:modified><dcterms:description>Objectives. Nutritional intake during gestation is known to impact health outcomes for&#xd;
progeny. Correlational evidence in humans suggests that increased fruit consumption&#xd;
of pregnant mothers enhances infant cognitive development. Moreover, wild-type&#xd;
Drosophila supplemented with a combination of orange and tomato juice showed&#xd;
robust enhancements in performance on an associative olfactory memory task. The&#xd;
current study aimed to experimentally test the effects of prenatal fruit juice exposure in&#xd;
a non-human, mammalian model of learning and memory. &#xd;
&#xd;
Methods. Across three separate birth cohorts, pregnant rats were given access to&#xd;
diluted tomato and orange juice (N = 2 per cohort), with control rats (N = 2 per cohort)&#xd;
receiving only water, in addition to standard rodent chow, throughout the duration of&#xd;
gestation, ending at parturition. Following weaning, male offspring were tested for&#xd;
learning and memory in a spatial version of the circular water maze and an auditory cued fear-conditioning task.&#xd;
&#xd;
Results. All pregnant rats increased fluid and food intake over the gestational period.&#xd;
Fruit juice-fed pregnant rats had increased fluid intake compared to control pregnant&#xd;
rats. When testing progeny, there were no effects of prenatal fruit juice on spatial&#xd;
learning, while it appeared to  impair learning in fear conditioning relative to controls.&#xd;
However, we measured significant enhancements in both spatial memory and&#xd;
conditioned fear memory in the prenatal fruit-juice group compared to controls.&#xd;
Measures of vigilance, in response to the conditioned cue, were increased in prenatal&#xd;
fruit treated rats compared to controls, suggesting less generalized, and more adaptive&#xd;
anxiety-related behaviours.&#xd;
&#xd;
Discussion.  Our results corroborate the human and Drosophila findings of prenatal&#xd;
fruit effects on behaviour, specifically that prenatal fruit juice exposure may be&#xd;
beneficial for early-life memory consolidation in rats.</dcterms:description><dcterms:subject>Medicine, Health and Life Sciences</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>gestational diet</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>memory</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>consolidation</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>cognition</dcterms:subject><dcterms:contributor>Ward-Flanagan, Rachel</dcterms:contributor><dcterms:dateSubmitted>2019-12-19</dcterms:dateSubmitted><dcterms:license>CC0</dcterms:license><dcterms:rights>CC0 Waiver</dcterms:rights></metadata>