<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><metadata xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://dublincore.org/documents/dcmi-terms/"><dcterms:title>Edmonton Food Policy Council Study, 1990</dcterms:title><dcterms:identifier>https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10585</dcterms:identifier><dcterms:creator>Kathryn W. Olson</dcterms:creator><dcterms:publisher>UAL Dataverse</dcterms:publisher><dcterms:issued>2015-09-15</dcterms:issued><dcterms:modified>2018-03-16T16:53:10Z</dcterms:modified><dcterms:description>The objectives of the project were to: 1. Define the criteria for food security in the identified target communities 2. Describe the level of food security among the designated target populations and identify the barriers which prevent them from obtaining nutritious, high quality foods. 3. Inform the Edmonton public and key stakeholders in the food industry of the survey results, and engage them in discussion to produce proposals for action that redress the barriers to food security. 4. Evaluate the effectiveness of the strategies, processes and outcomes of the project with respect to developing healthy public policy and community action.  Key objectives for the survey: 1. to find out who is experiencing food insecurity in Edmonton and how many people are having difficulty getting enough healthy affordable food. 2. To find out why these people are experiencing food insecurity and to identify the barriers to food security. 3. To identify existing coping strategies of low income people--strategies that help to reduce their experience of food insecurity. 4. To identify potential solutions as seen by those people experiencing food insecurity. 5. To gather information that has programming implications or that suggests needed policy changes for joint action by the community, business and government to address the issues of food security in Edmonton.</dcterms:description><dcterms:subject>Social Sciences</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>food consumption</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>food supply</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>food security</dcterms:subject><dcterms:date>1992-05</dcterms:date><dcterms:dateSubmitted>2015-09-14</dcterms:dateSubmitted><dcterms:temporal>1990-11</dcterms:temporal><dcterms:temporal>1990-12</dcterms:temporal><dcterms:temporal>1990-11</dcterms:temporal><dcterms:temporal>1990-12</dcterms:temporal><dcterms:type>Microdata</dcterms:type><dcterms:spatial>Canada</dcterms:spatial><dcterms:spatial>City of Edmonton</dcterms:spatial><dcterms:license>NONE</dcterms:license></metadata>