<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><metadata xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://dublincore.org/documents/dcmi-terms/"><dcterms:title>Data for Chiming In: Social Presence in an International Multisite Blended Learning Course</dcterms:title><dcterms:identifier>https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/FHOMRF</dcterms:identifier><dcterms:creator>MacIsaac, Peggy Lynn</dcterms:creator><dcterms:publisher>UAL Dataverse</dcterms:publisher><dcterms:issued>2021-06-08</dcterms:issued><dcterms:modified>2021-06-08T17:56:58Z</dcterms:modified><dcterms:description>These are WhatsApp mobile instant messaging chats between refugee and non-refugee learners in one 2018 summer term York University undergraduate course offered through the Borderless Higher Education for Refugees Program. The learners are attributed to a country of location while studying, a gender, a final grade, and a chat group which was composed for the purposes of supporting a group presentation. Refugee learners were based in Kenya and Thailand, while none refugees were based in Canada. More learners were in the groups than were participants in the study. Non-participants' data and chats were removed from the groups. The chat messages are attributed to a learner, a date and time, and then coded for the indicators of social presence as described by the Community of Inquiry Framework.</dcterms:description><dcterms:subject>Social Sciences</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>social presence</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>refugee</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>mobile instant messaging</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>grade</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>higher education in emergencies</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>Community of Inquiry</dcterms:subject><dcterms:isReferencedBy>MacIsaac, P. L. (2021). Chiming In: Social presence in an international multi-site blended learning course (Doctoral dissertation, Athabasca University). http://hdl.handle.net/10791/348, handle, 10791/348, http://hdl.handle.net/10791/348</dcterms:isReferencedBy><dcterms:contributor>MacIsaac, Peggy Lynn</dcterms:contributor><dcterms:dateSubmitted>2021-06-07</dcterms:dateSubmitted><dcterms:license>CC0</dcterms:license><dcterms:rights>CC0 Waiver</dcterms:rights></metadata>