<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><metadata xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://dublincore.org/documents/dcmi-terms/"><dcterms:title>Supplementary data for 'Chapter 3: The impact of diagenetic processes on sediment-hosted massive sulfide ore distribution: Geochronological, stratigraphic, textural, and petrographic relationships between silica, barite and sulfides in the Anarraaq Zn-Pb-Ag deposit, Red Dog District, Alaska'</dcterms:title><dcterms:identifier>https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/C2Q7SS</dcterms:identifier><dcterms:creator>Reynolds, Merilie</dcterms:creator><dcterms:publisher>UAL Dataverse</dcterms:publisher><dcterms:issued>2020-07-01</dcterms:issued><dcterms:modified>2020-07-02T01:01:27Z</dcterms:modified><dcterms:description>Supplementary files associated with PhD thesis Chapter 3 - The impact of diagenetic processes on sediment-hosted massive sulfide ore distribution: Geochronological, stratigraphic, textural, and petrographic relationships between silica, barite and sulfides in the Anarraaq Zn-Pb-Ag deposit, Red Dog District, Alaska. This includes one figure and one data table.&lt;br>&lt;br>&#xd;
&#xd;
Figure S3.1: Drill core sub-sampled for Re-Os isotopic analysis.&lt;br>&lt;br>&#xd;
&#xd;
Table S3.1: Whole rock analyses of select subsamples of Anarraaq black shale analyzed for Re-Os.&lt;br>&lt;br>&#xd;
&#xd;
These data are also included as Fig. A1 and Tab. A1 in a manuscript submitted to Economic Geology.&lt;br>&lt;br></dcterms:description><dcterms:subject>Earth and Environmental Sciences</dcterms:subject><dcterms:isReferencedBy>Reynolds, MA (2019) Sediment-hosted Zn-Pb-Ag mineralization in the Red Dog district, Alaska, USA: pre-ore environments and mineralizing processes. PhD Thesis, University of Alberta, Edmonton. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.7939/r3-mmsk-9x89">https://doi.org/10.7939/r3-mmsk-9x89&lt;/a></dcterms:isReferencedBy><dcterms:contributor>Reynolds, Merilie</dcterms:contributor><dcterms:dateSubmitted>2018-11-11</dcterms:dateSubmitted><dcterms:license>CC0</dcterms:license><dcterms:rights>CC0 Waiver</dcterms:rights></metadata>