<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><metadata xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://dublincore.org/documents/dcmi-terms/"><dcterms:title>Canadian Children's Book Centre Collection - Metadata Records</dcterms:title><dcterms:identifier>https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/10708</dcterms:identifier><dcterms:creator>University of Alberta Libraries</dcterms:creator><dcterms:publisher>UAL Dataverse</dcterms:publisher><dcterms:issued>2016-03-16</dcterms:issued><dcterms:modified>2021-03-13T18:19:00Z</dcterms:modified><dcterms:description>This collection includes files representing Canadian Children's Book Centre titles: A full extract of the CCBCC collection from the University of Alberta as of February 2018 (14,433 records); an extract of CCBCC titles added to the University of Alberta collection in spring 2017 (626 records); an extract of CCBCC titles added to the University of Alberta collection in fall 2017 (211 records); a full extract of the CCBCC collection from the University of Alberta as of Feb. 2016 (13,009 records); an extract of CCBCC titles added to the University of Alberta collection from Feb. 27th - Oct. 31st 2016 (393 records); an extract of CCBCC titles added to the University of Alberta collection from Nov. 1st 2016 - March 20th 2017 (258 records); a full extract of the CCBCC collection from the University of Alberta as of March 2017 (13,650 records); an extract of CCBCC titles added to the University of Alberta collection in fall 2018 (432 records); a full extract of the CCBCC collection from the University of Alberta as of May 31, 2019 (15,343 records); an extract of CCBCC titles added to the University of Alberta collection in spring 2019 (413 records); a full extract of the CCBCC titles from the University of Alberta as of August 28, 2019 (15,751 records). Format of all files: MARC</dcterms:description><dcterms:subject>Other</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>young readers</dcterms:subject><dcterms:date>2017-03</dcterms:date><dcterms:dateSubmitted>2017-03-20</dcterms:dateSubmitted><dcterms:temporal>1957</dcterms:temporal><dcterms:temporal>2017</dcterms:temporal><dcterms:spatial>Canada</dcterms:spatial><dcterms:license>NONE</dcterms:license><dcterms:rights>This work is licensed under a &lt;a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License&lt;/a>.</dcterms:rights></metadata>