<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><metadata xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/" xmlns="http://dublincore.org/documents/dcmi-terms/"><dcterms:title>List of Canadian independent, scholarly journals (2020)</dcterms:title><dcterms:identifier>https://doi.org/10.7939/DVN/EPSJJR</dcterms:identifier><dcterms:creator>Lange, Jessica</dcterms:creator><dcterms:creator>Severson, Sarah</dcterms:creator><dcterms:publisher>UAL Dataverse</dcterms:publisher><dcterms:issued>2021-04-29</dcterms:issued><dcterms:modified>2021-10-01T20:48:50Z</dcterms:modified><dcterms:description>This data set contains a list of active, Canadian independent, scholarly journals compiled as a part of the "Documenting labour in Canadian academic publishing" research study. The data was collected between October 2019 - April 2020, and reviewed and updated in July-August 2020. &#xd;
&lt;br>&lt;br>&#xd;
For the purposes of this project, the following inclusion criteria were used: &#xd;
&lt;ol>&#xd;
&lt;il>&lt;b>Canadian&lt;/b>: a minimum of one-third of the core editorial board is affiliated with an eligible Canadian post-secondary institution. We used this as the primary criteria and not whether or not the journal title is owned by a Canadian not-for-profit organization. As we are interested primarily in labour, limiting it based on the editorial board was natural for this study.&lt;/il>&lt;br>&#xd;
&lt;il>&lt;b>Independent&lt;/b>: A journal is not affiliated with a commercial publisher (e.g. Springer, Elsevier, Sage, etc.). Non-profits, like Érudit and University of Toronto Press, were included in the project.&lt;/il>&lt;br>&#xd;
&lt;il>&lt;b>Scholarly&lt;/b>:  defined as a peer-reviewed academic publication that disseminates the results of original scholarship. We have excluded additional student-run journals as per the SSHRC guidelines as well.&lt;/il>&#xd;
&lt;il>&lt;b>Active&lt;/b>: The journal has published in the last 3 years.&lt;/il>&lt;br>&#xd;
&lt;/ol>&#xd;
&lt;br>&#xd;
The second list is of the journals that we removed from our original data collection that did not meet the above criteria when reviewed. &#xd;
&lt;br>&lt;br>&#xd;
For more information on the project you can see the presentation slides from the Library Publishing Forum when the initial results were discussed: &lt;a href="https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/presentations/7w62fd646?locale=en">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/presentations/7w62fd646?locale=en&lt;/a> and a forthcoming article in the &lt;i>Journal of Electronic Publishing&lt;/i> (May 2020)</dcterms:description><dcterms:subject>Arts and Humanities</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>Other</dcterms:subject><dcterms:subject>Scholarly Publishing</dcterms:subject><dcterms:language>English</dcterms:language><dcterms:contributor>Severson, Sarah</dcterms:contributor><dcterms:dateSubmitted>2021-02-03</dcterms:dateSubmitted><dcterms:temporal>2019-10-01</dcterms:temporal><dcterms:temporal>2020-04-28</dcterms:temporal><dcterms:license>NONE</dcterms:license><dcterms:rights>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License CC BY 4.0.</dcterms:rights></metadata>