<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:46:29Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40800" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149q544</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Self-consistent field multiple scattering (SCF-MS) calculations have been performed on the aluminium trihalides, AlX$ sb3$ (X = F, Cl, Br, I) and their dimers, Al$ sb2$X$ sb6$ and on the large organometallic compounds diphenyltin(IV) dichloride and diphenyllead(IV) dichloride monomers and dimers. All these molecules have nuclear quadrupole resonance (n.q.r.) active nuclei and strong or weak intermolecular halogen interaction. In addition, diphenyltin(IV) dichloride has a Mossbauer active $ sp{119}$Sn nuclei to study the isomer shift and quadrupole splitting. Calculations used the Vosko-Wilk-Nusair(VWN) exchange-correlation potential in addition to Slater's X$ alpha$ exchange potential and also a quasi-relativistic wavefunction for the heavy nuclei in these molecules. The VWN and X$ alpha$ n.q.r. results are compared for the aluminium trihalides. The non-relativistic and relativistic calculations which are very important for the hyperfine interactions are compared for diphenyltin(IV) dichloride and the calculated relativistic Mossbauer isomer shift and quadrupole splitting agree well with experiment. The electric field gradients, which are very sensitive to the charge distribution around the nuclei in the molecules, gave very important information, using the n.q.r. and Mossbauer results, about the intermolecular halogen interactions in these molecules, supporting the conclusions arrived at using the one-electron energies and the HOMO-LUMO gap, and from the wavefunction contours and density maps. The relative Lewis acidity order and ionization potentials are also studied in the aluminium trihalides. Qualitative interpretation and agreement with experiment were found whenever experiment was available. Electronic structure and n.q.r. comparison of the diphenyltin(IV) dichloride and diphenyllead(IV) dichloride monomers and dimers lead to the conclusion that the diphenyltin(IV) dichloride is a monomer and the diphenyllead(IV) dichloride is a polymer.</description><creator>Berksoy-Bölük, Ebise Mualla</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Chemistry, Inorganic.</subject><title>Multiple scattering calculations of large inorganic systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010q80r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149q544</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z903071n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work attempts to examine the relevance of the conceptual opposition between modernity and postmodernity on the basis of a typological analysis of the modes of subjectivity and intersubjectivity which are implicated in the integration and the reproduction of a given form of society. We first show that traditional societies rest on concrete and particular modes of personal identity and of mutual recognition, which are integrated together within a common culture, whereas modern societies rest on an abstraction and universalization of forms societally legitimized of subjective identity and of intersubjective recognition. These we propose to designate by the concept of individualism. After presenting the main stages in the construction of modern individualism, we attempt to illuminate some of the implications, but also some of the aporias, that the modern conception of subjectivity and intersubjectivity presents. In the final part of this work, we seek to establish the validity of the notion of postmodernity to define contemporary society. We try to show that the universalist type of individualism, which characterizes modern society and provides its identity, gradually gives way to a "singularist" type of individualism. This latter form of individualism attests to a crisis of personal identity and is associated with the progressive dissolution of any collective identity, that is, of any a a priori intersubjectivity.</description><creator>Bonny, Yves</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Civilization, Modern -- 19th century</subject><subject>Individualism</subject><subject>Civilization, Modern -- 20th century</subject><title>L'individualisme, de la modernité à la post-modernité : contribution à une théorie de l'intersubjectivité</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z854n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903071n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225b67z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The efficiencies of many rigidly held cis-aquahydroxotetraazacobalt(III) complexes in promoting the hydrolysis of phosphate esters (BDNPP, BNPP, NPP) have been compared. The phosphate diester bond in ((trpn)Co(OH)(BNPP)) $ sp{+}$ is hydrolyzed at about the same rate as BNPP bound to a real enzyme from Enterobacter aerogenes and about 10$ sp{10}$ times more rapidly than free BNPP. The dramatic increase in the activity of the Co(III) complex with change in the tetraamine ligand structure can be explained in terms of a detailed mechanism of the reaction. Co(III) complexes, ((tren)Co(OH$ sb2)$(OH)) $ sp{2+}$ and ((trpn)Co(OH$ sb2)$(OH)) $ sp{2+}$ have been shown to be highly efficient in promoting the hydrolysis of phosphate di- and monoesters with poor leaving groups. ((trpn)Co(OH$ sb2)$(OH)) $ sp{2+}$ promoted hydrolysis of phosphate monoesters leads to a novel binuclear phosphato complex which is a model for the active site of Purple Acid Phosphatases. For the first time it has been shown that hydrolysis of carboxylic esters catalyzed by ((trpn)Co(OH$ sb2)$(OH)) $ sp{2+}$ is truly catalytic. The hydrolytic activity of ((trpn)Co(OH$ sb2)$(OH)) $ sp{2+}$ has been linked to the fact that this complex chelates carboxylic acids as shown by $ sp{13}$C NMR spectroscopy and the crystal structure of ((trpn)Co($ eta sp2$-OCC(CH$ sb3) sb3) rbrack sp{2+}$. This complex is the first example of a cobalt(III) complex in which carboxylic acid is chelated.</description><creator>Banaszczyk, Mariusz G.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Artificial hydrolytic enzymes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278t733.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225b67z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72p788v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pseudomonas saccharophila could fix N$ sb2$ under micro-aerobic conditions, heterotrophically and chemolithotrophically. Uptake hydrogenase activity under heterotrophic conditions had no effect on the O$ sb2$ sensitivity of nitrogenase. H$ sb2$ induced whereas sucrose and O$ sb2$ repressed hydrogenase synthesis. Sucrose and O$ sb2$ did not inhibit hydrogenase activity. Hydrogenase and urease were located in the membrane and soluble fractions, respectively. Nickel stimulated growth, hydrogenase expression, and nitrogenase activity under N-limited chemolithotrophic conditions. Hydrogenase synthesis specifically required nickel and its repression by O$ sb2$ was alleviated by increasing the nickel concentration. Incorporated $ sp{63}$Ni$ sp{2+}$ was about 3 times higher in the soluble than in the membrane fraction. The short-term uptake of nickel was energy-independent and had an apparent $K sb{m}$ of 31.7 uM and $V sb{max}$ of 3.8 nmol Ni$ sp{2+}$ (mg protein)$ sp{-1}$min$ sp{-1}$. A counting method for heterotrophic and chemolithotrophic N$ sb2$-fixing H$ sb2$-oxidizing bacteria was developed. The white bean rhizosphere soil showed relatively high numbers of these bacteria.</description><creator>Barraquio, Wilfredo L.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Nitrogen -- Fixation.</subject><subject>Bacteria -- Physiology.</subject><subject>Nickel.</subject><subject>Pseudomonas saccharophila.</subject><title>Nitrogen fixation, hydrogen oxidation, and nickel utilization by Pseudomonas saccharophila</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v838129h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p788v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:79407x99q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The biochemical characterization of phase I and phase II components considered to be important in the metabolism of carcinogens and other xenobiotics was examined in two experimental models. This was done to elucidate the relationship between the process of carcinogenesis and the selection of a biochemical phenotype which could result in drug resistance, previously described in rat hepatocarcinogenesis models. A model of mammary carcinogenesis in mice demonstrated no significant biochemical change relating to potential drug resistance among normal, preneoplastic and neoplastic mammary tissues. This is of particular interest since human breast cancer is usually quite drug sensitive at the start of the treatment. Human colon cancer is probably induced by carcinogenic compounds present in the environmental dietary elements and also exhibits de novo resistance to most antineoplastic drugs. Most of the biochemical elements examined were found to be present in these colon tissues. Additionally, the detoxification pathways including glutathione and its related enzymes, were found to be significantly elevated in colon tumor versus normal adjacent mucosa. The molecular characterization of glutathione S-transferase (GST) isoenzymes using antibodies and cloned molecular probes to specific enzyme forms showed that the anionic form of GST (GST-$ pi)$ is greater in tumors than in the respective normal mucosa. The neutral form (GST-$ mu)$ is conversely decreased in tumor relative to normal. The cationic (GST-$ alpha)$ is present only in 30% of the samples examined, with no difference between tumor and adjacent normal mucosa. The expression of cytochrome P-450 isoenzymes was also examined in a similar fashion; a phenobarbital-inducible form was expressed in most colon tissues examined, and expression of the polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons-inducible P$ sb3$-450 was present in some colon tissues while mRNA for P$ sb1$-450 was not detected in any. The biochemical alterations found in human colon could be the targets of therapeutic manoeuvers to enhance the efficacy of antineoplastic treatment of human colon cancer.</description><creator>Mekhail-Ishak, Kamilia</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Biochemical components of xenobiotic metabolism in human colon and in murine breast : relation to drug sensitivity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gh11t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/79407x99q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dn062</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The work described in this thesis had as its major objective the development of improved protein-targeted, pH-sensitive liposomes for in vitro delivery of encapsulated molecules to cells. This work comprised two major facets: biophysical studies of the phase preferences and fusion-promoting abilities of different neutral phospholipids, and fluorescence-microscopic and biochemical assays of the delivery of liposome-associated molecules to CV-1 (monkey kidney fibroblast) cells in culture. To study the relationship between lipid headgroup structure, physical behavior and fusion-supporting ability, novel structural analogues of phosphatidylethanolamine (PE) were synthesized and characterized using biophysical techniques and fluorescence assays of lipid vesicle fusion. The ability of these PE analogues to form nonbilayer structures was evaluated using $ sp{31}$P-NMR, differential scanning calorimetry, freeze-fracture electron microscopy, and X-ray diffraction. Fluorescence assays were used to monitor the abilities of these same PE analogues to promote various types of interactions (including lipid intermixing and fusion) between lipid bilayers. The results of the physical and fusion studies allowed the identification of specific physical parameters that appear to be good predictors of the fusion-supporting abilities of different neutral phospholipids. In the second part of this thesis, the interactions of transferrin-coupled, pH-sensitive liposomes with CV-1 cells were studied by fluorescence microscopy and measurements of the cytotoxicity of encapsulated cytosine arabinoside (araC). The results of these studies indicated that membrane fusion between liposomes and cells was not a major route of intracellular delivery of liposome-encapsulated fluorescent dyes. Instead, encapsulated araC gained access to the cytoplasm by a predominantly carrier-mediated mechanism. An improved protocol for the covalent coupling of protein molecules to pH-sensitive liposomes is also described. Studies such as these which provide information about the mechanisms of liposome-mediated delivery to cells will allow the 'rational design' of liposomes with properties optimized to exploit various pathways of delivery.</description><creator>Brown, Pamela M. (Pamela Marie)</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Development of pH-sensitive liposomes for delivery of bioactive molecules to animal cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623d366.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dn062</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v838131j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The formation and chiroptical properties of liquid crystals of ethyl cellulose (EC) and some related polymers are investigated to determine which features affect the mesophase behaviour. The onset of mesophase formation is studied by employing literature data on the viscosity/molar mass relationship of several cellulose derivatives, including EC in several solvents, to calculate their molecular dimensions by a recent hydrodynamic theory. The phase separation behavior is compared with the predictions of theories for both freely-jointed and wormlike chains. The effects of solvent and degree of substitution (DS) on the cholesteric structure are assessed by studying the chiroptical properties using Circular Reflectance and Optical Rotatory Dispersion (ORD) techniques. The DS strongly influences the helicoidal twist sense, reflection wavelength and response of the reflection wavelength to changes in temperature. Mesophases and cholesteric films of the methyl and n-butyl derivatives of EC are also investigated. The ORD spectra of isotropic EC solutions are found to be strongly influenced by the solvent employed.</description><creator>Budgell, Derek Richard</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Liquid crystalline properties of ethyl cellulose</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17ct680.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838131j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fh81z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main topic of this thesis is the study of the fundamental solution of the heat equation for the symmetric spaces of positive definite matrices, Pos(n,R). Our first step is to develop a "False Abel Inverse Transform" ${ cal G}$ which transforms functions of compact support on an euclidean space into integrable functions on the symmetric space. The transform ${ cal G}$ is shown to satisfy the relation $ Delta{ cal G}(f; cdot) = { cal G}( Gamma( Delta)f; cdot)$ $( Gamma( Delta)$ is the usual Laplacian with a constant drift). Using this transform, we find explicit formulas for the heat kernel in the cases n = 2 and n = 3. These formulas allow us to give the asymptotic development for the heat kernal as t tends to infinity. Finally, we give an upper and lower bound of the same type for the heat kernel. In the case n = 3, the lower bound is completely new.</description><creator>Sawyer, Patrice</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>The heat equation on the symmetric space associated with SL(n,R) /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386j987.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fh81z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n583xv73k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two studies of voluntary movement in Parkinson's disease were carried out. In the first study, both parkinsonians and age-matched controls performed unconstrained prehensile movements in which subjects produced reaching and grasping (hand opening/closing) movements under varying conditions of movement amplitude, speed and object size. The act of prehension requires the intersegmental coordination of limb transport and grasp trajectories. Although parkinsonians were slower overall than controls, patients and controls similarly adjusted the spatial and temporal characteristics of their limb movement and grasp in response to changes in task demands. All groups showed increases in the speed of limb transport, the speed of hand opening and began hand opening proportionately earlier at faster movement speeds. All groups similarly increased hand opening velocity and initiated grasp earlier for smaller amplitude movements. Likewise, grasp was initiated earlier when reaching for wider objects. However, in contrast to controls, the onset time of hand opening during limb transport was delayed in these patients and was found to be more closely coupled with the timing of limb transport than in the controls. Moreover, patients showed greater curvature in their motion paths at the wrist during limb transport suggesting that the timing of joint motion (shoulder and elbow) may be different in these patients as well. Underlying differences between the groups in the temporal sequencing of movement are discussed. In a second study, parkinson and control subjects performed continuous tracking movements in pursuit of sinusoidal and constant-speed target trajectories varying in frequency and amplitude. This task provided explicit temporal and spatial accuracy constraints by requiring subjects to reproduce the precise trajectory (i.e., velocity profile) of target movement. The results show that patients, similar to controls, were capable of modifying peak movement velocity while varying their times to reversal (i.e., movement durations) in response to changes in the movement time requirements of target motion. Indeed, both patients and controls were shown to alter the timing of movement deceleration in order to maintain their movement durations within the temporal limits of target movement. In contrast to controls, patients show progressive reduction in endpoint accuracy (undershooting the target) and, hence, reduced movement amplitudes, over the course of the trial. However, when endpoint accuracy requirements were reduced, by providing mechanical constraints on movement amplitude, patients were able to increase movement amplitudes while satisfying the temporal requirements of the task. These results are interpreted in terms of tradeoffs in performance between competing spatial and temporal demands of pursuit tracking. The significance of movement accuracy constraints on motor function in parkinsonian performance is discussed.</description><creator>Zackon, Warren T.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Parkinson's disease -- Pathophysiology.</subject><subject>Parkinson's disease -- Patients.</subject><subject>Motor ability.</subject><subject>Parkinson's disease.</subject><title>Reaching movements and pursuit tracking performance in patients with Parkinson's disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mq46f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xv73k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wh246s75j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>All eukaryotic cellular mRNAs (except for organelle mRNAs) are blocked at their 5$ sp prime$ end by the cap structure m$ sp7$GpppX (where X = any nucleotide). The cap structure plays a multifunctional role in both the nucleus and the cytoplasm. Two polypeptides of molecular mass of 20 and 115 kDa in HeLa nuclear extracts were shown to recognize and be crosslinked to the cap structure of eukaryotic mRNAs in a cap-dependent fashion. Their cap binding properties have been characterized, although their function in the nucleus is unknown. Previous studies have shown that cap function in the cytoplasm is mediated by eukaryotic initiation factors (eIF)-4A, -4B and -4F (termed cap binding proteins) which interact with the cap structure and are involved in 40S ribosomal subunit binding to mRNA during translation initiation. eIF-4A contains an ATP binding consensus sequence AXXGXGKT, consistent with its ATP binding and hydrolyzing activity. The amino proximal glycine and lysine were mutated to isoleucine and asparagine, respectively, in order to determine the importance of these amino acids in ATP binding as examined by UV-induced crosslinking to ($ alpha sp{32}$P) dATP. Mutation of the lysine, but not the glycine, abolished ($ alpha sp{32}$P) dATP crosslinking to eIF-4A. There has been indirect evidence to suggest that eIF-4A, -4B and -4F interact with the cap structure and use the energy derived from ATP hydrolysis to unwind 5$ sp prime$ proximal secondary structure in mRNA, to facilitate ribosome binding. Using a novel RNA unwinding assay, direct evidence was obtained indicating that combinations of eIF-4A and eIF-4B, or eIF-4F and eIF-4B, exhibit helicase activity. A unique aspect of this activity is that it functions in a bidirectional fashion. The data indicate that cap binding proteins in the cytoplasm, and possibly the nucleus, play a key role in the regulation of gene expression.</description><creator>Rozen, Florence</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Identification and role of cap binding proteins in eukaryotic cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225b69h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246s75j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k0698822h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effects of plasticisation on the phase behaviour in random and ABA triblock styrene-N-alkyl-4-vinylpyridinium iodide ionomers were studied using small angle X-ray scattering and dynamic mechanical techniques. It was found that the internal plasticisation of a random ionomer by quaternisation with n-iodoalkanes does not result in phase separation. The glass transition temperatures of such materials can be predicted on the basis of the vinylpyridine content and the iodoalkane chain length. Plasticisation of the random ionomers with nonpolar additives, either internally, via alkylation of the phenyl ring with 1-decene, or externally, by the addition of diethylbenzene, results in the phase separation of the material into a multiplet-containing phase and clusters. In the internally plasticised ionomers, the multiplet phase predominated at low levels of alkylation, and the cluster phase predominated when more than 20 mole % of the styrene had been alkylated. The cluster phase was always dominant in the externally plasticised ionomers. ABA triblocks of styrene (B) and vinylpyridine (A) are phase separated even in the nonionic state. Quaternisation of the end blocks yielded ionomers whose domains exhibited different morphologies depending on the midblock, end block and quaternising chain lengths, even though they had the same sample history. It was found that the styrene matrix T$ sb{ rm g}$ in the quaternised materials was depressed relative to a comparable styrene homopolymer; this reduction was attributed to inefficient packing of the styrene chains around the vinylpyridinium domains. Plasticisation of the ABA ionomers with diethylbenzene reduced the glass transition temperature of the styrene matrix, but did not affect the ionic phase. Plasticisation of the ionic regions with glycerol resulted in the depression of the vinylpyridinium T$ sb{ rm g}$, but did not appear to affect the nonpolar matrix.</description><creator>Wollmann, Daphne</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>The structure and dynamic mechanical properties of some plasticised styrene-vinylpyridinium iodide ionomers /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cx04g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698822h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tm751</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It was shown, previously that N. crassa contains an endo-exonuclease which exist in two forms, an active form and an inactive form activated by trypsin treatment in vitro. Both of these forms were found in the cytosol and in mitochondria, but only the active form is present in the vacuoles. In the present work, it has been shown that both forms are also present in the nuclei bound to the chromatin. Active endo-exonuclease was previously implicated in DNA repair and in this study additional evidence was obtained in further support of such a role: (i) the mutagen sensitive uvs-3 mutant of N. crassa was found to contain only 10% of the level of active enzyme in the two DNA-containing organelles, in comparison to the levels found in the wild-type, (ii) in response to low doses of the DNA-damaging agent 4-nitroquinoline 1-oxide (4-NQO), the inactive enzyme decrease and the active form increase in the DNA-containing organelles indicating that the inactive enzyme may have been converted proteolytically to the active form. This response did not occur in the uvs-3 mutant. Under a different stress, namely heat shock, endo-exonuclease was regulated differently in the DNA-containing organelles. Active enzyme was released from the nuclei, mitochondria, and vacuoles into the cytosol where it was nearly completely inhibited by a specific inhibitor induced by heat shock. This heat shock-induced inhibitor shared some properties in common with a constitutive endo-exonuclease inhibitor recently isolated from this laboratory. However, there were also some distinct differences between these two inhibitors. At least one difference may be explained by phosphorylation of the heat shock inhibitor.</description><creator>Ramotar, Dindial</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Intracellular regulation of neurospora endo-exonuclease in response to DNA damage and heat shock</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fp65s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tm751</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn106z84q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Neurotensin (NT) is a putative neurotransmitter, the central actions of which appear to be mediated by specific high affinity binding sites. Radioautographic studies using emulsion-coated sections have selectively localized a major proportion of NT binding sites over nerve cell bodies in the rat midbrain tegmentum and basal forebrain. In the present studies, it was shown that the vast majority of $ sp{125}$I-NT-labeled neurons in the rat midbrain tegmentum were dopaminergic, while those in the magnocellular basal forebrain of both rats and humans were predominantly cholinergic using adjacent-section light microscopic $ sp{125}$I-NT radioautography combined with either tyrosine hydroxylase (TH) immunohistochemistry or acetylcholinesterase (AChE) pharmacohistochemistry. In specific, cell counts demonstrated that 95-100% of TH-immunoreactive neurons in the rat substantia nigra (SN) and 80-90% in the ventral tegmental area (VTA) exhibited dense $ sp{125}$I-NT labeling. In the rat basal forebrain, 65-80% of AChE-positive perikarya in the vertical limb of the diagonal band, 45-60% in the horizontal limb of the diagonal band, and 75-90% in the nucleus basalis magnocellularis demonstrated selective $ sp{125}$I-NT binding sites. Moreover, competition studies using levocabastine, a selective blocker of the low affinity NT binding component, revealed that the vast majority of $ sp{125}$I-NT binding sites labeled in the SN, VTA, and NBM were of the levocabastine insensitive, high affinity type, previously documented to correspond to the physiologically active NT receptor. These data provide an anatomical substrate for NT-dopaminergic interactions in the rat midbrain tegmentum and for NT-cholinergic interactions in the rat and human basal forebrain. Ibotenic acid-induced lesions of the NBM produced a marked reduction in both AChE reactivity and cellular $ sp{125}$I-NT binding suggesting that most of the labeled binding sites detected in this region were indeed associated with cholinergic neurons themselves rather than with impinging afferent terminals. In fact, electron microscopic examination of the distribution of $ sp{125}$I-NT binding sites in the NBM revealed that 84% of labeled sites were inside AChE-positive perikarya and proximal dendrites and presumably represented intracellular receptors undergoing synthesis, transport, and/or degradation. The remainder were evenly dispersed along the plasma membrane of AChE-reactive neurons, but were only rarely concentrated opposite synapsing axon terminals. These latter results are consistent with a paracrine mode of action of NT in influencing the NBM cholinergic system.</description><creator>Szigethy, Eva Maria</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Cellular and subcellular radioautographic localization of neurotensin receptors to chemically-identified neuronal subpopulations in the rat brain</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117p605.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn106z84q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8623hz44r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis presents an electrophysiological study on cat spinal motoneurons using the technique of intracellular recording and iontophoresis. It was demonstrated that underlying the action potential there are two major potassium currents, which differ from each other in their pharmacological properties. The action potential repolarization is largely mediated by a fast, calcium-independent potassium conductance, which is tetraethylammonium- and 4-aminopyridine-sensitive. While a slow, calcium-dependent potassium conductance generates the post-spike afterhyperpolarization, which is apamin-sensitive. The afterhyperpolarization markedly regulates the repetitive discharge of this motoneuron. 5-hydroxytryptamine (5-HT) produces a relatively short-lasting depolarization and several long-lasting changes in the motoneuronal membrane properties, including potentiations of the action potential and afterhyperpolarization and an induction of hyperpolarization with unchanged input resistance. The long-lasting effects of 5-HT are likely due to activation of 5-HT$ sb2$ receptor subtype, though they appear to be intracellular calcium-dependent. Intracellular injections of inositol trisphosphate (IP$ sb3$) and activators of protein kinase C or kinase C itself, mimic the long-lasting effects of 5-HT, also via an intracellular calcium-dependent process. Phosphoinositide metabolites may therefore be the intracellular messengers for 5-HT in this motoneuron. The present data support the concept that intrinsic properties of the postsynaptic membrane can be modulated by neurotransmitters and related intracellular messengers, which may result in long term of plastic changes.</description><creator>Zhang, Liang, 1952-</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>The action potential repolarization and after-hyperpolarization in cat spinal motoneurons : effects of neurotransmitters, internal messengers and other agents</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zb76t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623hz44r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b6805</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The mechanisms by which lupus anticoagulant and antiphospholipid autoantibodies cause hemostatic abnormalities in patients with systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE) are poorly understood. We have approached this problem by investigating the binding and functional effects of human hybridoma lupus anticoagulant, anti-phospholipid and anti-DNA autoantibodies derived from SLE patients on platelets and endothelial cells. Most lupus anticoagulant antibodies did not bind to intact platelets and endothelial cells in vitro, while many antiphospholipid and anti-DNA antibodies were reactive. A comparison of SLE and normal-derived autoantibodies demonstrated that platelet-binding autoantibodies derived from SLE patients exhibited greater antigen specificity and platelet cytotoxicity than similar antibodies derived from normal individuals. By Western blotting analysis, many SLE-derived polyspecific antibodies reacted specifically with individual platelet proteins, whereas normal-derived polyspecific antibodies did not. One SLE-derived antibody, 9604 was found to react with ADP-activated platelets but not resting platelets. The reactive components in platelets were reducible polypeptides of approximately 200,000 and 32,000 molecular weight. These data suggest that some SLE autoantibodies may be able to interact with platelets and result in cell lysis or dysfunction in vivo.</description><creator>Meng, Qiang-hua</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Characterization of the reactivities of SLE and normal-derived human hybridoma lupus anticoagulant, anti-phospholipid and anti-dDNA autoantibodies with platelets and endothelial cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r638m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b6805</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54kn87x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The standardized patient is one method which can be used in the measurement of clinical competence. The accuracy of reproduction of important features of the patient case by the standardized patient was evaluated in Studies 1 and 2. In 839 encounters reviewed, only 13/89 patients provided an accurate reproduction of the case. Attributes of the patient, training process and evaluation procedure were associated with better patient accuracy. A significant inverse relationship was found between patient accuracy and competence score. In Study 3, the use of standardized patients as raters of behaviour was assessed. There were systematic differences in the scoring by different raters, and overall rater agreement was r =.41.</description><creator>Tamblyn, Robyn M.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><title>The use of the standardized patient in the measurement of clinical competence : the evaluation of selected measurement properties</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c3552.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kn87x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ff3655809</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Sandberg, L. Anders, 1953-</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Industries -- Nova Scotia -- Pictou (County)</subject><subject>Pictou (N.S. : County) -- Economic conditions.</subject><title>The deindustrialization of Pictou County, Nova Scotia : capital, labour and the process of regional decline, 1881-1921</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354f97f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff3655809</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354f98q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Cloutier, Daniel.</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Chufa.</subject><subject>Weeds -- Integrated control.</subject><subject>Plants -- Propagation.</subject><title>Population dynamics of yellow nutsedge (Cyperus esculentus L.)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547s15p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354f98q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g732d972q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Nguyen-Ba, Nghe</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Antiviral agents</subject><subject>Nucleosides</subject><subject>Virus diseases</subject><title>Synthesis of acyclonucleosides with potential antviral activity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732d9730.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732d972q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17ct719</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Scott, P. J. B.</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Invertebrates -- Jamaica.</subject><subject>Corals -- Jamaica.</subject><title>Infaunal invertebrates associated with live coral in Jamaica</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161689n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17ct719</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Oceanography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52j8776</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Stiebeling, Detlef.</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Millais, John Everett, Sir, 1829-1896 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Painting -- Themes, motives</subject><subject>Symbolism in art</subject><subject>Pre-Raphaelites.</subject><subject>Oxford movement</subject><title>Traditional iconographic themes in a Victorian context : paintings by Sir John Everett Millais between 1848 and 1860</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n203z83p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j8776</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rb68xc509</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Gilkeson, Linda A.</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Aphididae.</subject><subject>Aphididae -- Biological control.</subject><subject>Gall midges.</subject><title>Genetic selection, evaluation and management of nondiapause Aphidoletes aphidimyza (Rondani) (Diptera : Cecidomyiidae) for control of greenhouse aphids in winter</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25x930p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xc509</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k35695249</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Tremblay, André, 1948-</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Convective clouds</subject><subject>Atmospheric chemistry</subject><subject>Clouds</subject><title>A three dimensional cloud chemistry model /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26xz05s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k35695249</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v838132t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Clarke, Kenneth Allan.</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Judgment.</subject><subject>Child development</subject><subject>Child psychology -- Case studies.</subject><title>Children's judgments of the certainty of their knowledge</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505121v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838132t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rv18v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Wong, Lawrence Tak-lai</creator><date>1971</date><subject>Benzophosphole.</subject><subject>Organic compounds -- Synthesis.</subject><subject>Peptides -- Synthesis</subject><subject>Chemical bonds</subject><subject>Amides</subject><title>Silicon tetrachloride as a coupling reagent for amide bond formation. Synthesis of benzophosphole.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666520f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rv18v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40825</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>