<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:25:52Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34200" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558f87j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Simone Weil is best known to the world as a mystic and a philosopher. She died in 1943 at the age of 34, ostensibly because she refused the hypernutrition prescribed for the treatment of her tuberculosis. Shortly after her death, thanks to the posthumous publication of her work, she was recognised as one of the twentieth centuries most original thinkers in areas as diverse as philosophy, political history, religion, and ethics. Few writers have delved into the foundational relationship she discerned between a destructive form of suffering she called "affliction" and the experience of divine love. The present dissertation exposes how this fundamental relationship lies at the centre of Weil's life and thought. First, we correlate biographical details of Weil's life with key insights into the reality of affliction. Second, the nature of human suffering is treated as a theological concept. Through Weil we consider the limits of creatureliness to the point at which one no longer feels a part of the human community. Third, we examine Weil's insight into the radical possibility of love in response to the annihilating experience of affliction, that is, the experience of God's love for us as well as the possibility of loving the afflicted neighbour. Finally, we consider several critiques of Weil's sense of her own identity as a woman and as a Jew, and the impact of this identity crisis on her unique understanding of the relationship between suffering and the love of God.</description><creator>Athanasiadis, Nicholas.</creator><contributor>Hall, Douglas John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Weil, Simone, 1909-1943.</subject><subject>Suffering -- Moral and ethical aspects.</subject><subject>Suffering -- Religious aspects.</subject><title>The experience of affliction and the possibility of love in the life and thought of Simone Weil /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881n69g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558f87j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343t78t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The 9 PAX genes constitute a family of developmental transcriptional regulators characterized by a highly conserved "paired-box" domain. Mutations in 6 of the 9 PAX genes result in autosomal dominant congenital malformations in mice and in humans. PAX2 transcripts are detected in the CNS, throughout the genitourinary tract, eye and ear. In humans, mutations of PAX2 cause Renal-Coloboma Syndrome (RCS), a constellation of renal anomalies, eye defects and, less frequently, hearing loss and mild CNS manifestations. Homozygous PAX2 mutations in mice cause complete renal agenesis and perinatal death. PAX8 transcripts are found in the CNS, kidney and thyroid glands. PAX8 mutations cause congenital thyroid hypoplasia. No renal defects have been detected either in human or murine PAX8 mutants. In spite of considerable information about PAX2 and PAX8 genes, their precise functions in development are poorly understood. This project was aimed at elucidating the functions of PAX2 and PAX8 in nephrogenesis and is subdivided into two parts: mutational screening of the PAX8 gene (Chapter 4) and delineation of the role of PAX2 in developing kidney (Chapters 5--7). The latter evolved into the major portion of this work. Familial juvenile nephronophthisis (NPH1) is a rare disease characterized by multiple small cysts at the cortico-medullary junction and end-stage renal failure in pediatric populations. Because of its proximity to the disease locus, we considered PAX8 a candidate gene for NPH1. During analysis of PAX8 exons from patients, we identified a rare non-conservative polymorphic amino acid change, but found no causative mutations. Subsequently, other groups isolated the novel NPH1 gene. Following reports that PAX8 knockout mice have no obvious renal anomaly, we considered the possibility that PAX8 mutations might, nevertheless, affect proximal tubule function. In patients with thyroid hypoplasia and proven PAX8 mutations we found no aminoaciduria, indicating that haploinsufficiency for PAX8 does not alter tubular transport function. In order to define PAX2 function in the two primordial cell lineages of developing kidney (induced metanephric mesenchyme and ureteric epithelium), we used both a cell culture approach and an in vivo PAX2 mutant mouse model (1Neu). We demonstrated that PAX2 plays a dual role. In mesenchymally-derived HEK293 cells expressing regulatable exogenous PAX2, we showed that PAX2 is responsible for expression of genes involved in differentiation of mesenchyme. Contrary to one published hypothesis, we found that PAX2 does not affect cell division. In ureteric epithelium, however, PAX2 plays a different role, serving as a survival factor, critical for sustaining the ureteric bud stem cell population. Attenuation of PAX2 dosage (1Neu mouse mutants or collecting duct cells transfected with an antisense PAX2 vector) results in increased apoptosis. We demonstrate that the primary renal defect in RCS is reduced nephron number associated with excessive apoptosis and simplified branching of the ureteric bud. We hypothesize that arborization of the uretric bud requires accumulation of sufficient stem cell mass to allow the next round of branching---possibly by lifting the branch point beyond a putative local inhibitory field. In summary, we establish that inactivation of PAX8 gene expression does not disturb normal kidney development and function. Conversely, PAX2 plays a crucial dual role in the two primordial kidney cell lineages: being a differentiating factor in mesenchyme and a survival factor in ureteric epithelium.</description><creator>Torban, Elena.</creator><contributor>Goodyer, Paul (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Functions of PAX2 and PAX8 genes during kidney development</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97ks093.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343t78t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720f50g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Leukocyte recruitment into tissues in response to infection or injury is a crucial event for the elimination of pathogens to protect the host. However, when leukocytes invade the central nervous system (CNS) and neuromflammatory disorders result, neurological function may be compromised. Infiltration of the CNS, predominantly by T cells and macrophages, characterizes Multiple Sclerosis and its animal counterpart, Experimental Autoimmune Encephalomyelitis (EAE). Autoreactive T cells that initiate EAE produce Th1 cytokines (e.g., IFNgamma, TNFalpha). Nevertheless, previous studies also indicated an unnecessary or even protective role for IFNgamma in EAE. I have identified a novel role for IFNgamma in my studies using IFNgamma- or IFNgammaR-knockout mice. IFNgamma promotes the expression of the chemokines RANTES, MIP-1alpha, and MCP-1, which recruit mononuclear cells in the CNS to induce a non-lethal remitting EAE. Without IFNgamma, the chemokines MIP-2 and TCA-3, and polymorphonuclear leukocytes prevail, producing an unusually lethal EAE. MIP-1alpha is, however, dispensable in recruiting mononuclear cells, as EAE could still be induced in mice deficient in MIP-1alpha or its CCRS receptor. To examine how much T cells depend on the cooperation with macrophages in the CNS to induce EAE, selective depletion of peripheral macrophages in mice was achieved by intravenous administration of clodronate-loaded liposomes. Treated mice showed no clinical signs of EAE following adoptive transfer of myelin-reactive T cells, but an altered distribution of leukocytes. These leukocytes were confined within the perivascular or meningeal space, not invading the CNS parenchyma. Levels of TNFalpha and inducible nitric oxide synthase (iNOS) in the CNS were reduced in these asymptomatic macrophage-depleted mice compared to untreated mice with EAE. In these asymptomatic mice, NOS expression was restricted to parenchymal astrocytes. In mice with EAE, however, both macrophages/microglia and astrocytes in infiltrates expressed NOS. Surprisingly, some astrocytes that were distant from infiltrates also expressed NOS, thus suggesting that astrocytes may modulate leukocyte infiltration via release of NO through their foot processes in the blood-brain barrier. Collectively, my data propose a model of a dynamic network in which the interplay among cytokines, chemokines and nitric oxide, may determine the magnitude, the composition, or the resolution of inflammatory infiltrates, as well as the clinical outcome of EAE.</description><creator>Tran, Elise H.</creator><contributor>Owens, Trevor (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Immune invasion and glial activation in experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547t165.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720f50g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52j9632</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An understanding of the effects of harvest on wild plant populations is essential for discerning the ecological impacts of past and present human uses of wild species, and for conserving species which are currently overexploited. This dissertation builds on theories and methods to describe and predict the impacts of harvesting non-timber forest products (NTFP) through an ethnoecological study of the terrestrial bromeliad Aechmea magdalenae. A. magdalenae is harvested from the rainforests of South-eastern Mexico where it has a long history of exploitation. The fiber extracted from its leaves is used to embroider leather articles in an artwork known as piteado. The sustainable harvest of this species has been promoted in Mexico as a strategy to conserve forests and provide local people with a stable income. A combination of demographic, ethnobotanical and participatory methods was used to quantify harvest strategies, measure their impacts on A. magdalenae populations, and assess potential for cultivation. The impacts of harvesting: (1) ramets used for forest plantations; (2) leaves and ramets; (3) and whole plants and ramets, were measured by comparing the dynamics of harvested and nonharvested populations. The demographic implications of variation in the ecological and human context of harvest were examined. The effects of variation in traditional management and traditional knowledge of this species were also quantified. Analyses using matrix models indicate that primary forest populations harvested for their ramets are declining due to overexploitation. Secondary forest populations are tolerant to ramet harvest and show elevated rates of growth and vegetative propagation in wild and cultivated plants. High rates of fiber harvest have little impact on population growth rates and increase A. magdalenae's tolerance to ramet harvest. The economic and ecological implications of local harvesting strategies vary within regions as well as between regions with short and long histories of A. magdalenae management. A test of the accuracy of estimating maximum sustainable harvests using current approaches illustrates that these methods can lead to erroneous conclusions. The results of this study are used to suggest improvements for approaches to assessing the impacts of NTFP harvest, for combining traditional ecological knowledge and science in management plans, and for using participatory ecological and ethnoecological research to promote conservation.</description><creator>Ticktin, Tamara.</creator><contributor>Johns, Timothy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Chinantec Indians -- Ethnobotany -- Mexico.</subject><subject>Bromeliaceae -- Mexico.</subject><subject>Non-timber forest products -- Mexico -- Management.</subject><title>Ethnoecology of Aechmea magdalenae (Bromeliaceae) : a participatory investigation into the sustainable harvest and conservation of a non-timber rainforest product</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qt670.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j9632</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fx719n88s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A delicate balance exists between the protective effects of adrenal glucocorticoids (GCs) secreted in response to stress and the negative consequences that the excessive production of these hormones may have for numerous systems. GCs are involved in the regulation of the stress response, have effects on feeding and body weight gain and are associated with the acceleration of central nervous system aging. Their production, secretion, and containment are subject to both environmental modulation and individual variation. Neonatal manipulations known to affect the development of the adult hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal (HPA) response to stress had profound effects on both basal and stress-induced dietary choice, body weight and insulin dynamics. We followed this study with an examination of how the physiological and emotional response to stress can affect diet choices and affective status. Stress had an impact on diet choice and had a strong effect on emotional status but did not affect subjects uniformly. We then explored the reciprocal relationship, i.e. how diet itself can affect the response to stress and found that basal and stress-induced activation of the HPA axis in both young and aged rats is augmented following the feeding of high-fat diets and fat-feeding cause aberrations in glucose-insulin axis. Since aging can be associated with profound changes in HPA axis function, we assessed how dietary habits may contribute to the emergence of the cortisol (F) profile in a population of healthy elderly humans. We found a strong positive relationship between individual F production, feelings of depression and the high fat content in their diets. While dietary habits may have a negative impact on the emergence of an individuals' cortisol profile and on the aging process, we wanted to explore whether a beneficial intervention at mid-life would allow animals to age "successfully" by reducing glucocorticoid production. Environmental enrichment lowered corticosterone lev</description><creator>Tannenbaum, Beth.</creator><contributor>Meaney, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Nutrition.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health.</subject><title>Hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal axis regulation over the lifespan : contribution of dietary and lifestyle factors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354g98x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719n88s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bw20m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Human immunodeficiency virus type 1 (HIV-1) utilizes the NF-kappaB/Rel pathway to mediate, in part, its transcriptional regulation through NF-kappaB binding sites present in the HIV-1 LTR. In unstimulated cells, DNA binding NF-kappaB sub-units are retained in the cytoplasm by inhibitory IkappaB proteins. Upon stimulation by cytokines, viruses or dsRNA, IkappaBalpha is rapidly phosphorylated and degraded, resulting in the release of NF-kappaB and the subsequent increase in NF-kappaB-regulated gene expression. The effect of transdominant mutants of IkappaBalpha (TD-IkappaBalpha) on the synergistic activation of the HIV-1 LTR by TNFalpha and the HIV-1 transactivator Tat, was examined in Jurkat T cells. Co-expression of WT IkappaBalpha and TD-IkappaBalpha inhibited Tat-TNF activation of HIV-1 LTR in a dose dependent manner. TD-IkappaBalpha also effectively inhibited HIV-1 multiplication in a single cycle infection model in COS-1 cells. To examine the effect of inducible expression of TD-IkappaBalpha on de novo HIV-1 multiplication, we generated Jurkat T cells inducibly expressing TD-IkappaBalpha by doxycycline (Dox). Dox induction of TD-IkappaBalpha dramatically reduced both NF-kappaB DNA binding activity and LTR directed gene activity. The time course of de novo HIV-1 infection was altered by Dox induction of TD-IkappaBalpha in Jurkat cells, resulting in a dramatic inhibition of HIV-1 multiplication. Interestingly, induced expression of TD-IkappaBalpha also progressively decreased the expression of endogenous IkappaBalpha to undetectable levels by 24h after induction, indicating that TD-IkappaBalpha was able to repress endogenous NF-kappaB dependent gene expression. We also demonstrated that production of TD-IkappaBalpha reduced endogenous IkappaBalpha gene transcription, due to the continued cytoplasmic sequestration of RelA(p65) by TD-IkappaBalpha. In vivo genomic footprinting revealed stimuli-responsive protein-DNA binding not only to the -63 to -53 kappaB1 site but also to the adjacent -44 to -36 Spl site of the IkappaBalpha promoter. In vivo protection of both sites was inhibited by Dox-inducible TD-IkappaBalpha expression. Prolonged NF-kappaB binding and a temporal switch in the composition of NF-kappaB complexes bound to the -63 to -53 kappaB1 site of the IkappaBalpha promoter were also observed; with time after induction, decreased levels of transcriptionally active p65-p50 and increased c-rel-p50 heterodimers were detected at the kappaB1 site. Mutation of either the kappaB1 site or the Sp1 site abolished transcription factor binding to the respective sites, as well as the inducibility of the IkappaBalpha promoter in transient transfection studies. Based on these results, specific activation of TD-IkappaBalpha can block NF-kappaB-regulated gene expression and HIV-1 infection.</description><creator>Kwon, Hakju, 1971-</creator><contributor>Hiscott, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Mutants of IkBa interfere with NF-kB regulated gene expression and HIV-1 replication</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nj83n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bw20m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn301295h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation investigates a novel approach to seismic design of eccentrically braced frames. The proposed design procedure incorporates non-linear time-history analysis directly into the design process. Member forces introduced by a chosen earthquake record are monitored throughout the time history, and the frame elements are selected so that they have adequate resistances for peak forces. This process is carried out iteratively. For the earthquake records used, the proposed procedure leads to a design which achieves desired seismic behaviour, characterized by the stable elastic response of columns and braces, and with inelastic action confined primarily to links. The procedure was implemented by means of three computer programs, two of which were developed as part of this study. The sensitivity of the procedure to initial section selection was studied and a methodology to obtain an appropriate site-specific earthquake record to use in the analysis was proposed. The application of the procedure was illustrated through examples of three Chevron-type EBFs, these having four, eight and fourteen storeys and being located in Victoria, B.C. It was demonstrated that the proposed design method is simple and efficient, and can be used either as an alternative design method or in combination with current design practice. Analytical results indicate that frames designed using this alternative approach have improved behaviour compared to those designed in accordance with the present Canadian design requirements, in particular regarding the response of columns and braces. In the second part of the study, the analytical tools developed were used to further investigate and enhance the understanding of seismic behaviour of EBFs. Modifications of seismic design requirements for EBFs, suitable for incorporation in the Canadian Standard for design of steel buildings, CSA/CAN-S16.1 were examined. The inelastic response of an eight-storey EBF designed following these modified requirements is compared to that of a corresponding structure designed using the iterative procedure. Attention was further directed to seismic force profiles, magnitudes of axial forces and moments for use in the design of columns, force modification factors and the relationship between inelastic inter-storey drifts and inelastic link deformations.</description><creator>Koboević, Sanda.</creator><contributor>Redwood, R. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>An approach to seismic design of eccentrically braced frames /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612q30q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301295h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r2736</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fourier transform near-infrared (FT-NIR) spectroscopy was investigated as a means of quantitative analysis of edible fats and oils. Initially, a method of simultaneously determining the cis and trans content, iodine value and saponification number of neat fats and oils using a heated transmission flow cell was developed. Two partial least squares (PLS) calibrations were devised, a process-specific calibration based on hydrogenated soybean oil and a more generalized calibration based on many oil types, the latter able to analyze oils from a variety of sources accurately and reproducibly. Methodology for the quantitative determination of the peroxide value (PV) of edible oils using a novel glass-vial sample handling system was subsequently developed, based on the stoichiometric reaction of triphenylphosphine with hydroperoxides to form triphenylphosphine oxide. The PV calibration was derived using PLS regression, and the results of a validation study demonstrated that PV could be quantitated accurately if a normalization routine was used to compensate for the inherent dimensional variability of the vials. The vial sample handling system was then used in the development of PLS IV calibrations for the process analysis of commercial oil samples, and these samples were also used to evaluate a global IV calibration devised by Bomem Inc. The discriminant features available through PLS were shown to enhance the accuracy of the IV predictions by facilitating the selection of the most appropriate calibrations based on the spectral characteristics of closely related oils. The predictions obtained using the global IV calibration provided clear evidence that a generalized calibration based on a large and varied selection of oils could provide a means of IV determination by FT-NIR spectroscopy. Subsequently, a generalized FT-NIR trans calibration was developed and shown to yield trans values that were in good agreement with those obtained by the AOCS mid-FTIR single-bounce hori</description><creator>Li, Hui, 1970-</creator><contributor>van de Voort, F. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Oils and fats, Edible -- Analysis.</subject><subject>Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy.</subject><title>Analysis of edible oils by Fourier transform near-infrared spectroscopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666623g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r2736</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930bz95k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Specific strategic control (executive) processes were investigated in 17 boys with ADHD and 18 normal control boys, ages 9--13 years, using a paradigm combining the Warned Reaction Time and Stimulus-Response Compatibility tasks. The length and constancy of the preparatory interval (PI) were manipulated in order to study preparatory processes associated with prediction and temporal adjustment. Compared to control boys, boys with ADHD had particular difficulty with long, fixed, and short, variable preparatory intervals, suggesting problems with the strategic control of response preparation and adaptation to temporal changes. Heart rate deceleratory patterns recorded during the PI indicated that impaired active, accurate, prediction played a major role in the preparatory deficit. The study also manipulated compatibility and predictability of response demands in order to assess inhibitory processes and the ability to shift flexibly between changing response demands. Boys with ADHD had particular difficulty shifting flexibly between compatible and incompatible responding, indicating a problem with strategic response adjustment. Findings also suggested possible difficulties with the allocation of consistent, effortful attention and the inhibition of inappropriate responding. In addition, interactions were also observed in the ADHD group between the strategic and inhibitory measures. Overall, the findings supported Douglas's (1988; 1999) conceptualization of ADHD as involving a self-regulatory deficiency consisting of interacting strategic, effortful, and inhibitory components. The study also addressed the question of whether Sanders' (1983) cognitive-energetic model, which has been used widely in studies of ADHD, can deal adequately with the cognitive difficulties associated with ADHD. The findings indicated that the model has not been developed adequately to deal with the kinds of higher level processing deficits that were identified in the ADHD group. In addition, in</description><creator>King Elbaz, Zmira.</creator><contributor>Douglas, V. I. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder.</subject><subject>Cognition in children.</subject><title>Cognitive control processes in attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder : behavioural and cardiovascular measures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806157s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930bz95k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pp69z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The dissertation examines Liszt's experimentation with harmonic, formal, and programmatic procedures in the piano works of his Weimar period (1848--1861). Liszt's music has often been criticized as "new wine in old bottles." His radical development of keyboard technique and harmonic vocabulary appears contained within, and constrained by, traditional forms. Here, however, it is argued that Liszt's "form" and "content" go hand in hand. A change in one compositional element (e.g., harmonic vocabulary) leads to changes in other elements (e.g., formal and tonal design), so that a kind of compositional "chain reaction" occurs. Chapter one (introduction) establishes the plan of study and describes three organizational strategies ("conflict," "block," and "object") found in the selected works. Chapter two investigates the Etudes d'execution transcendante and focuses on harmonic innovations at the thematic level. In comparing different versions of the Etudes, the chapter shows how the composer's virtuoso keyboard idiom interacts with harmonic content and how surface harmonic procedures function as structural determinants. Chapter three concentrates on the smaller sets of "poetic" piano works. These include the Consolations , the Liebestraume, and the two Ballades as well as selections from the larger cyclical collections, the Annees de pelerinage and the Harmonies poetiques et religieuses. The analytical focus is on Liszt's manipulations of phrase- and section-level formal functions. The works display strophic and through-compositional tendencies that mirror developments in nineteenth-century lieder, and formal ambiguities that arise from the hybridization of traditional instrumental formal types. Chapter four focuses exclusively on the B-minor Sonata. The composition, perhaps Liszt's most successful and complex work, engages us in a synthetic approach to harmony, form, and programme. The motivic and formal design of the Sonata may be accounted for in programmatic terms. Compositional similarities between the Sonata and the Faust Symphony suggest their shared programmatic subtext. The extensively developed "love interest" in Goethe's Faust invokes issues of gender and sexuality. The programme-related construction of gender as well as the arousal and channeling of desire can be connected with the Sonata's formal and tonal organization. Emphasizing the use of five motives and their various transformations, it is shown how Liszt portrays, through musical means, the three principal characters---Faust, Marguerite, and Mephistopheles---and how the work embodies a variety of narratological and interpretive paradigmsheroic, feminist, and psychological.</description><creator>Shin, Minna Re, 1969-</creator><contributor>McLean, Don (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Liszt, Franz,1811-1886. Piano music.</subject><subject>Piano music -- Analysis, appreciation.</subject><title>New bottles for new wine : Liszt's compositional procedures (harmony, form, and programme in selected piano works from the Weimar period, 1848-1861)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p877j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pp69z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306t082z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Alzheimer's disease (AD) is a condition marked by progressive intellectual decline and memory loss, which typically affects individuals over the age of 60. Its origins are unknown but genetic factors are suspected in some cases. There is limited information about the subjective experience of AD although it is often described as a calamity that inevitably destroys the self irrespective of its victims' social circumstances. This dissertation offers an alternative to this nihilistic portrayal that draws on a critical phenomenological framework. It explores the loss of self as an intersubjective phenomenon that is mediated by three contexts: (1) Western representations of the self as autonomous and individualistic; (2) the public description of AD; and (3) the biomedical practices that construct AD as a diagnostic object. The dissertation examines the experiences of 16 patients and 37 family members who participated in a multi-disciplinary assessment at a dementia clinic. The participants also include 14 clinicians and staff members from the clinic. The findings are derived from a prospective study that includes in-depth, at-home interviews and observations of clinical assessment activities and research-based genetic counseling. The dissertation examines how memory trouble interferes with the intersubjective fabric of everyday life in families as affected participants lose the ability to meaningfully reciprocate on the basis of their individualistic identities. The analysis emphasizes the role of the clinical assessment, diagnosis, and public description in restoring intersubjective order. A salient aspect of this process is the way in which medicalized interpretations of memory trouble facilitate reinterpretation of the eroding self as being animated by pathology. The self is thus rendered meaningful again as it is being indexed to lay descriptions of what people do and say in AD. The analysis also considers how this process extends to participants who came to perceive themselves as victims of AD although they were assessed as not having a dementia disorder. The dissertation finally considers the impact of acquiring genetic knowledge about AD on interpretations of the self. Overall, the research underscores the loss of self in AD as a phenomenological process that is mediated by familial and institutional contexts.</description><creator>Smith, André P.</creator><contributor>Rains, Prudence (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Self.</subject><subject>Alzheimer's disease -- Diagnosis.</subject><title>Medicalizing intersubjectivity : diagnostic practices and the self in Alzheimer's disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827d36h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t082z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3n204082s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation examines the complex and multi-faceted ways in which contemporary minority women's fictions may be thought of, both generically and individually, as practices of bearing witness to silence---practices of giving testimony to the presence of lives, experiences, events and historical realities which, otherwise, have been absented from the critical terrain of North American literary studies. For the most pact, the texts included in this study all tell tales of various, and often extreme, forms of sexual, racial, gender, colonial, national and cultural violence. Through readings of select works by Toni Morrison, Shani Mootoo, Arundhati Roy, Louise Erdrich, M. K. Indira, Mahasweta Devi and Leslie Feinberg, I argue for the ways in which these fictions may be understood as situated within the bounds of a genre---a genre that attempts to provide an account of what we might call "the half not told." I examine these fictions, both generically and specifically, as texts which have the ability to make several important critical interventions in the field of literary studies. Firstly, these texts have the potential to negotiate the impasse that feminist and postcolonial literary scholarship finds itself in around debates about the relationship between theory, activism and experience---as well as in debates about the relationship between violence, beauty, culture, subjectivity and desire. Secondly, the fictions under study help to challenge our very definitions of witnessing. Witnessing, in these works, is not simply a matter of "speaking out" against violence, but rather the issue of making space for the affective and emotive dimensions of various kinds of silences and silencings. Finally, in attempting to chart more precise vocabularies with which to assume readings of these narratives, my thesis also helps to think about the ways in which reading, writing and storytelling may, themselves, be seen as profoundly ethical undertakings that seek to give evidence</description><creator>Tagore, Proma.</creator><contributor>Cope, Karin M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Fiction -- Minority authors -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Fiction -- Technique.</subject><subject>Fiction -- Women authors -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Violence in literature.</subject><title>The shapes of silence : contemporary women's fiction and the practices of bearing witness</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wp48f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n204082s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zc825</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Historians working with texts often experience a tension in their work. On the one hand there are questions raised by ancient documents. On the other, limited data makes it impossible to answer these questions with certainty. Second Peter illustrates both phenomena and as a result there is a proliferation of theories about its origin. It is used therefore as a test case in this dissertation which is primarily concerned with historical methodology. Scholars have questioned the authorship of 2 Peter since at least the second century and there remains to this day no consensus about such issues as date of composition, provenance, and destination. In short, fixing a precise historical location for 2 Peter is impossible because of a lack of evidence. To compensate for such historical gaps, scholarship has developed various theories that allow for tentative conclusions about where this and other writings best fit within early Christianity. In many cases literary parallels have played a role in both developing and defending such theories. By observing similarities between texts (and put negatively, by observing how texts differ from one another---the absence of parallels) a variety of conclusions may be reached: one writing borrowed from another, writings that share a theological perspective belong to the same period of history, writings derive from a school, and so on. This dissertation analyses several examples of how 2 Peter specifically is located using parallels as a basis. It is argued for a number of reasons that this 'tool' is not reliable and so, to assist with historical research, a series of criteria are given. These are provided as guidelines to help historians evaluate literary parallels and also to safeguard against inappropriate conclusions based on them. With respect to 2 Peter, it is argued that firm answers are out of reach for various questions given the available data.</description><creator>Gilmour, Michael J.</creator><contributor>Wisse, Frederik (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Religion, Biblical Studies</subject><title>The significance of parallels between 2 Peter and other early Christian literature /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sv43s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zc825</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225c721</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study was designed to develop an in-situ flushing system for remediating metal-contaminated soils. Specifically, the capabilities of citric acid, an organic acid, to extract metal ions from a metal-contaminated sandy soil, containing 0.42, 0.04, 0.01, and 41.52 mg g-1 of Zn, Cu, Cd, and Pb, respectively, were tested at bench-scale and large-scale levels. Citric acid, at pH 5.5, was used at different levels of concentration and retention time in batch experiments to establish optimum conditions for the maximum removal of heavy metals from the soil. Citric acid exhibited a tremendous potential to extract metal ions from the metal-contaminated soil. The extraction of metal ions increased with an increase in citric acid concentration. A column study (height = 0.6 m; internal diameter = 0.1 m) was conducted to compare metal leaching with surface and subsurface application of citric acid. The results indicated that the subsurface application resulted in a more efficient extraction of metal ions due to uniform distribution of the citric acid. Finally, a large-scale experiment involving soil columns (height = 1.0 m; internal diameter = 0.2 m) was carried out to develop an in situ soil flushing system to remediate the metal-contaminated soil. Citric acid was supplied into the soil columns through a subsurface irrigation system. This process resulted in an overall extraction of Zn, Cu, Cd, and Pb ions from the soil columns at 83.27%, 1.47%, 16.70%, and 26.55%, respectively. Results obtained in different experimental protocols suggested that continuous flushing of the soil is a suitable method for extracting metal ions from the contaminated soil using citric acid. The metal-rich leachate was effectively treated with chitosan flakes. Results indicate that for 0.1 M citric acid leachate containing 0.06, 0.02, 0.003, and 5.87 mumoles ml-1 of Zn, Cu, Cd, and Pb, respectively, about 20 g of chitosan would be sufficient to remove about 50% of the contaminants from one liter of leachate in 6 h. Various batch experiments involving pure solutions of metal ions as well as the metal-rich leachate were conducted to establish the metal adsorption properties of chitosan under various physico-chemical conditions. The controlled parameters were the amount of chitosan, reaction time with and without shaking, and the pH of the solution. The sorption of metal ions from pure metal solutions and the leachate was not improved by the agitation, and the maximum adsorption of metal ions onto chitosan flakes occurred at pH 6.0. Sorption equilibrium studies were also conducted with a constant sorbent weight and varying initial concentration of metal ions. The experimental data of adsorption from the solutions, containing metal ions, were found to correlate well with the Langmuir isotherm equation.</description><creator>Bassi, Raman.</creator><contributor>Prasher, S. O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Soil remediation.</subject><subject>Metals -- Environmental aspects.</subject><title>A laboratory study to remediate a metal-contaminated soil /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dr322.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225c721</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150k83k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The subject of this dissertation is the intellectual European New Right (ENR), also known as the nouvelle droite. A cultural "school of thought" with origins in the revolutionary Right and neo-fascist milieus, the nouvelle droite was born in France in 1968, the year of the spectacular student and worker protests. In order to rid the Right of its negative connotations, the nouvelle droite borrowed from the New Left ideals of the 1968ers. In a Gramscian mould, it situated itself exclusively on the cultural terrain of political contestation in order to challenge what it considered the ideological hegemony of dominant liberal and leftist elites. This metapolitical focus differentiated the nouvelle droite from both the parliamentary and radical, extra-parliamentary forces on the Right. This dissertation traces the cultural, philosophical, political, and historical trajectories of the French nouvelle droite in particular and the ENR in general. The dissertation argues that the ENR worldview is an ambiguous synthesis of the ideals of the revolutionary Right and New Left, and that it is neither a new form of cultural fascism, nor a completely novel political paradigm. In general, the ENR symbiotically fed off the cultural and political twists of the Left and New Left, thus giving it a degree of novelty. In the 1990s, the ENR has taken on a more left wing and ecological aura rather than a right-wing orientation. As a result, some critics view this development as the formulation of a radically new, post-modern and post-fascist cultural and political paradigm. Yet, other critics contend that the ENR has created a repackaged form of cultural fascism. The nouvelle droite has been able to challenge the main tenets of its "primary" enemy, namely, the neo-liberal Anglo-American New Right. Moreover, it has restored a measure of cultural respectability to a continental right-wing heritage battered by the burden of 20th century history. In an age of rising economic globalization and cultural homogenization, its anti-capitalist ideas embedded within the framework of cultural preservation might make some political inroads into the Europe of the future.</description><creator>Bar-on, Tamir.</creator><contributor>Meadwell, Hudson (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Conservatism -- Europe.</subject><subject>Europe -- Politics and government -- 1945-</subject><subject>Right and left (Political science)</subject><title>The ambiguities of the intellectual European New Right, 1968-1999 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r274g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150k83k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j721q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The enteric protozoan parasite Entamoeba histolytica is the etiologic agent of the disease amebiasis which is characterized by colitis or hepatic lesions. Amebae colonize the colon by binding to mucous glycoproteins (mucins). Secretory mucins provide the gel nature to mucus and are a vital component of epithelial barrier function. Mucins prevent contact-dependent cytolysis of colonic cells by E. histolytica. To possibly circumvent this barrier, the parasite secretes a potent yet unidentified mucin secretagogue, which could deplete the stored mucin pool and render the mucous layer less protective. The objective of this study was to investigate the molecular mechanisms by which E. histolytica modulates colonic mucin exocytosis. We showed that E. histolytica converts exogenous arachidonic acid to prostaglandin E2 (PGE2), a known mucin secretagogue and potential mechanism by which the parasite evokes mucin secretion. Conversion was via a novel cyclooxygenase-like activity and was inhibitable with the known cyclooxygenase inhibitor aspirin. To study E. histolytica-mucin interactions, we developed an in vitro model of LS174T human colonic epithelial cells that secrete mucin constitutively and in response to mucin agonists. Highly purified mucins isolated from LS174T cells markedly inhibited amebic adherence to target cells and the mucous barrier protected the LS174T monolayers from amebic cytolysis. We have identified that Gal and GalNAc residues (O-linked sugars) of mucins are the protective moiety as O- but not N-linked glycosylation inhibitors decreased their protective effect. To understand how mucins are regulated during intestinal amebiasis and in the inflamed gut, we determined that PGE2 binds the EP4 receptor on LS174T cells and in rat colon to stimulate cyclic adenosine monophosphate-dependent mucin exocytosis. Taken together, these studies delineate how E. histolytica modulates host responses during infection to allow the parasite to survive and persist in th</description><creator>Belley, Adam.</creator><contributor>Chadee, Kris (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Entamoeba histolytica.</subject><subject>Mucins.</subject><subject>Amebiasis.</subject><subject>Prostaglandins E -- Synthesis.</subject><title>Molecular interactions between Entamoeba histolytica and colonic mucins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096879g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j721q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207tq990</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of the research reported in this thesis is to explore analogical reasoning in complex situations. In three manuscripts, novel aspects of analogy use are investigated. In Manuscript 1, analogies used in a political campaign were analyzed with the framework developed in the analogical reasoning literature. Results show a number of novel features of analogy use. The majority of source analogs used were not superficially similar to the target problem, most of the mappings between source and target were implicit, and emotion appeared to be an important feature in the selection of source analogs. In Manuscript 2, three experiments were conducted that explored some of the effects uncovered in the first study. In these experiments, participants were asked either to generate their own source analogs in relation to a target problem or to retrieve a source from a predetermined set. Results show that when generating their own sources, people are not constrained by superficial similarity. However, when asked to retrieve from a predetermined set of sources, participants retrieve based on surface similarity. These results suggest that previous studies may have underestimated people's ability to use structural features in analogical retrieval. The research reported in Manuscript 3 explores the impact of analogical inferences on the representations of target problems. Descriptions of target problems were presented followed by potential source analogs. Results show that people engage in analogical mapping and draw inferences. These inferences, that were not presented, are incorporated in people's representation of the target and cannot be differentiated from information that was actually presented. People falsely recognize analogical inferences as having been presented when in fact they had not. Results from all these studies are discussed in terms of the novel insights they contribute to the analogy literature and in terms of their implications for theoretical models of</description><creator>Blanchette, Isabelle.</creator><contributor>Dunbar, Kevin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Reasoning.</subject><subject>Analogy.</subject><title>An investigation of analogical retrieval and mapping in complex reasoning situations /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tn625.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tq990</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zc84q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Despite the plethora of material written on the history of prisoners-of-war in the Second World War, surprisingly few works treat the issue analytically, at least from the perspective of German military policy toward, and treatment of, British and American prisoners-of-war. The handful of dissertations written on the subject have examined tightly focused aspects within this subject, or did not make thorough use of the German federal military archives. Most published works, indeed, have tended to examine the issue from the perspective of the prisoners themselves. While these were valid and valuable approaches to the subject, they also left a significant gap in the historiography: what precisely was German policy towards British and American prisoners-of-war, how did it evolve over the course of the war years, and how was it ultimately put into practice? The largest portions of this dissertation consist of distilling, from the thousands of pages of German military orders and documents which survived the war, the essence of the German Armed Forces Supreme Command (the Oberkommando der Wehrmacht, or OKW) directives to the lower levels of command, ultimately reaching the level of the camp Commandants, with regard to the many facets of prisoner-of-war life, from shelter, clothing, and food, to labour policy and security measures. Every report by the International Committee of the Red Cross and the Protecting Power delegates of their visits to most of the British or American prisoners-of-war in German-run camps for non-commissioned soldiers (Stalags) and camps for commissioned officers (Oflags) which could be found in the national archives of Great Britain, the United States, and Canada, was then examined, with the aim of providing a standard by which to measure German policy. Given the sensitivities of each of the belligerents to the plight of their own soldiers held captive in enemy hands, the final results of the investigation are then presented in conclusion with a brief comparison of how German prisoners-of-war fared while in British or American captivity. Though necessarily relying on the scholarship of other historians in this regard, it allows for the original findings of this dissertation to be placed in a wider context for the reader. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Vourkoutiotis, Vasilis.</creator><contributor>Hoffmann, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Germany. Oberkommando der Wehrmacht.</subject><subject>Prisoners of war -- Great Britain.</subject><subject>Prisoners of war -- Germany.</subject><subject>World War, 1939-1945 -- Prisoners and prisons, German.</subject><subject>Prisoners of war -- United States.</subject><title>The German Armed Forces Supreme Command and British and American prisoners-of-war, 1939-1945 : policy and practice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jw32d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zc84q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977w73w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>TiC reinforcement particles were incorporated into a Ti-6 %Al-4%V matrix and processed by two powder metallurgy techniques, namely elevated temperature pressureless sintering and hot deformation-assisted sintering (also known as hot pressing). For these composites, processing by sintering alone necessitated high temperatures (&gt;1500°C) for near-complete density consolidation, whilst the conditions for temperature and hold time were reduced (i.e. 1000°C and 1/2 hour) through deformation-assisted sintering. During high temperature processing in the absence of deformation, considerable coarsening of the lamellar matrix microstructure occurred. The interfacial reaction between the reinforcement and matrix was characterized by in situ neutron diffraction sintering studies at temperatures between 1100°C and 1350°C. Initial reaction occurred by carbon diffusion from the TiC particle to the titanium alloy, as evidenced through the increase in the lattice parameter of the matrix phase with holding time at the various sintering temperatures. Beyond the carbon solubility limit of the matrix phase, a stable stoichiometric phase formed as shown by the appearance of distinct peaks in the neutron diffraction patterns. Room temperature lattice parameter measurement gave a value of 4.290 A with a fractional occupancy of carbon of 0.45 +/- 0.04, which corresponds to a stoichiometry of Ti2C. For the various isothermal sintering temperatures, change in the Ti2C volume fraction with hold time was determined and growth of this interfacial phase was reasoned to occur by carbon diffusion from the TiC particles, through the reaction zone and to the Ti-6%Al-4%V alloy. Transformation of the entire TiC particle to Ti2C occurred in the composites sintered at 1500°C. For the composites processed by sintering only, the mechanical properties determined by shear punch testing indicated that the strength and ductility are limited at low temperature sintering because of high por</description><creator>Wanjara, Priti.</creator><contributor>Drew, Robin (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Yue, Steve (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Characterization of Ti-6%A1-4%VTiC particulate reinforced metal matrix composites consolidated by sintering and thermomechanical processing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42n9618.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977w73w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fn442</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Optical properties of polyethylene blown films are of great commercial and scientific interest. An understanding of the relationship between morphology and optical properties will have a significant impact on product and process optimization. In this work, a number of linear low density polyethylene (LLDPE) resins of different molecular and structural characteristics were studied. Intrinsic properties such as refractive index and absorption coefficient were estimated from resin compositions using group contribution models. The refractive indices of sample films were also measured using the method of Transmission Spectrum. The morphology of polyethylene films was investigated using Atomic Force Microscopy (AFM) and Near-field Scanning Optical Microscopy (NSOM). Both the surface and bulk morphologies were evaluated. The observation shows the dominant spherulitic structure on the surface as well as in the bulk, as the result of nucleation and crystallization during the film blowing process. In addition to qualitative observations and comparisons; quantitative characterization methods were employed to describe the features of the morphology. Based on the morphology characterization, the surface reflection was described by the Beckmann-Davies theory of reflection of electro-magnetic waves by rough surface. The directional distribution of reflected intensity was computed according to the surface roughness information. The gloss values of sample films were computed accordingly and compared with experimental measurements. Furthermore, the problem of light transmission and scattering was investigated. A scattering geometry was proposed from the observations of the morphology of sample films. The light scattering by the surface of polymer films was analyzed using a model that is based on the Mie theory of scattering. The haze values of sample films were computed and compared with experimental measurements.</description><creator>Wang, Lei, 1972-</creator><contributor>Rey, A. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Kamal, M. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Morphology and optical properties of polyolefin blown films</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z705s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fn442</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn1070843</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study traces the imperial ideas of Lord Salisbury (1830--1903) who was both British prime minister and foreign secretary in 1885, 1886--1892, and 1895--1900. In 1900 he resigned as foreign secretary but remained prime minister until 1902. Previous research on Lord Salisbury has neglected his imperial thought and has seen him as essentially a pragmatist. Instead, this work argues that his outlook consisted of High Anglican Christian faith, and Tory beliefs which were modified by contemporary liberalism. This trilogy of convictions can be seen in his view of British domestic politics and in each of the issues which are examined in detail: namely, his reaction to the American Civil War, his view of India, his reflections on nationalist movements, his role at the Congress of Berlin, his perspective on the civilizing mission and the partition of Africa, his ideas on race, his thoughts on Ireland, Egypt and the Sudan, his opinion on the colonies of settlement, Imperial Federation, and the South African War in 1899. Essentially, this study revises the existing historiography by demonstrating that Salisbury's Christian faith was a central feature of his approach to diplomatic and imperial affairs.</description><creator>Vuoto, Grazia.</creator><contributor>Elbourne, Elizabeth (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Great Britain -- Politics and government -- 1837-1901.</subject><subject>Salisbury, Robert Cecil, marquess of, 1830-1903.</subject><title>The imperial ideas of Lord Salisbury, 1851-1902 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tt346.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn1070843</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns064750d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Maya sites of Marco Gonzalez and San Pedro are located on the southern end of Ambergris Caye, a limestone-based coral island off the coast of modern-day Belize. When combined, the archaeological settlements at these sites represent some of the longest occupations in coastal Belize. Evidence suggests the earliest occupation occurred at Marco Gonzalez in the Late Preclassic and extended into the Late Postclassic, while San Pedro's population thrived well into the Historic period. An analysis of the stone tools recovered from excavations at Marco Gonzalez and San Pedro and a study of the use-wear patterns on these artifacts has revealed that the Maya from both sites were primarily engaged in subsistence-based activities with a limited amount of small-scale craft production. Use-wear evidence suggests that the majority of these activities focused on the exploitation of local resources necessary in everyday Maya life. The activities included the acquisition of seafoods such as fish and molluscs, and the preservation and/or processing of fish and other marine by-products, such as shell, coral, and stingray spines for both local use and trade. As consumer sites, the Caye inhabitants offered many of these products in exchange for stone tools produced in mainland workshops, such as Colha, in the 'chert-bearing zone' of Northern Belize. In addition to the local and regional trade of marine resources and salt, the sites of Marco Gonzalez and San Pedro served as transshipment points for the long-distance exchange of valuable wealth or prestige goods along the coast. The large inland site of Lamanai likely served as ally and trade partner with these sites based on archaeological evidence for socioeconomic and sociopolitical ties between this mainland centre and the smaller Caye settlements. This relationship assisted the Maya from southern Ambergris Caye in surviving the breakdown in trade relations and depopulation that plagued other Maya centres in the Late to Terminal</description><creator>Stemp, William James.</creator><contributor>Bisson, Michael S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Stone implements -- Belize -- Ambergris Cay.</subject><subject>Ambergris Cay (Belize) -- Antiquities.</subject><subject>Excavations (Archaeology) -- Belize -- Ambergris Cay.</subject><subject>Mayas -- Belize -- Ambergris Cay -- Antiquities.</subject><title>An analysis of stone tool use in the Maya coastal economies of Marco Gonzalez and San Pedro, Ambergris Caye, Belize /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322g00n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064750d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h3519</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Human retinoid X receptor alpha (hRXRalpha) plays a critical role in DNA binding and transcriptional activity through its heterodimeric association with several members of the nuclear receptor superfamily, including the vitamin D receptor (VDR). Several cancer cell lines derived from many tissues have been shown to be resistant to the growth inhibitory action of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D3, (1,25(OH)2D3), the biologically active metabolite of vitamin D3. In the malignant ras-transformed human keratinocyte cell line, HPK1Aras, 10--100 fold higher concentrations of 1,25(OH)2D3 are required than the non-malignant normal human epidermal keratinocytes to achieve comparable inhibition of cell growth. Here we show that in ras-transformed keratinocytes, ser260 of hRXRalpha is phosphorylated through the Ras-Raf-MAP kinase cascade. This phosphorylation event results in the inhibition of vitamin D signaling via VDR/hRXRalpha heterodimers. Strategies to reverse this resistance include the use of the MAP kinase inhibitor, PD098059, and a non-phosphorylatable hRXRalpha mutant, ala260, which completely abolishes RXR phosphorylation and restores the function of both 1,25(OH)2D3 and a specific RXR ligand, LG1069 (4-[1-(5,6,7,8-tetrahydro-3,5,5,8,8-pentamethyl-2-naphtalenyl)ethenyl]-benzoic acid). In addition, we show that a vitamin D analog with low calcemic activity (EB1089) is more potent than 1,25(OH)2D3 in inhibiting cancer cell growth in this system. Targeted therapy with selective analogs such as EB1089, in combination with the inhibition of phosphorylation of the RXR, could play a critical role in the therapeutic strategies of cancer biology. In addition, we also demonstrate that resistance to 1,25(OH)2D 3 can be acquired through genetic alterations in the VDR, implying that both components of the VDR/RXR heterodimer are potential targets for the induction of cellular resistance to 1,25(OH)2D3 and present two distinct mechanisms through which tumour cells can escape the growt</description><creator>Solomon, Cynthia, 1974-</creator><contributor>Kremer, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Mechanisms of 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D resistance in tumor cells as they progress from the normal to the malignant phenotype</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jn17x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h3519</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mx09z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The questions posed and examined in Violent Femmes take their genesis from psychoanalytic arguments which contend that identity is not a stable monadic thing but rather a continuing process of engagement and negotiation between the self and others. Sigmund Freud, Melanie Klein, D. W. Winnicott, and Christopher Bollas, amongst others, have noted the temporary, coalitional, and provisional nature of the ways in which identity is apprehended and experienced. This thesis expands upon such a theoretical framework of identity formation to specifically question the ways in which the formation and maturation of an artistic identity may, in part, be predicated upon the psychological capacity to enact violence within the realm of the imaginary. Violent Femmes examines the complex relationship between psychological violence and artistic identity as that relationship is recorded in the autobiographical writings of Virginia Woolf, Radclyffe Hall, and Emily Carr. This project traces the written vestiges of Woolfs, Hall's, and Carr's individual internalised struggles to formulate an artistic identity in specific relationship with an already established 'model' of artistic creativity and identity. Woolfs, Hall's, and Carr's struggles to claim a personal artistic identity, in some ways from their individual model of the artist, are waged within the minds of the authors themselves. However, the violence enacted within their imaginations---the violence perpetrated against the models of the artist---is thrust into the external world, not only within the writings of these three women, but also by the ways in which each author resolves or fails to resolve her own violent conflict with her imaginary model of the artist.</description><creator>Stewart, Janice, 1966-</creator><contributor>Cope, Karin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Hall, Radclyffe -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Carr, Emily, 1871-1945 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Woolf, Virginia, 1882-1941 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Identity (Philosophical concept) in literature.</subject><title>Violent femmes : identification and the autobiographical works of Virginia Woolf, Radclyffe Hall, and Emily Carr</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kv58w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mx09z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3n204084b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:44:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of this dissertation is to study the use, function and possibilities of the classical concept of imagination in the "comedias" of Pedro Calderon de la Barca (1600--1681). To begin, I explore the possibilities and limitations of imagination at three different levels: literary and aesthetic theory, psychological and gnoseological theory, and lastly that of cosmology. Thus, after tracing the presence of the concept of imagination in all of Calderon's "comedias," I study its use in the dramatic discourse of Pinciano and Bances Candamo. Likewise, I discuss the ambiguities of this concept that Calderon himself openly explored in several of his plays. Later, I focus on an analysis and interpretation of imagination in La vida es sueno (Life is a Dream), particularly as it concerns the relationships between mankind and the universe, as well as the imaginative and dramatic possibilities of dreaming. My next step deals with the relationship between theories of drama and imagination. This concentrates on: the way in which the author plays and manipulates the audience's affections, the creation of marvellous dramatic effects, and the relationship between imagination and performance. After, I analyze the interaction between physical senses and imagination, as well as the public's perception influenced by sophisticated staging techniques. Lastly, I discuss three crucial concepts, those of taste, public opinion and disillusionment ("desengano"), that are for Calderon obvious limitations to the possibilities of imagination.</description><creator>Suárez, Juan Luis.</creator><contributor>Perez-Magallon, Jesus (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Calderón de la Barca, Pedro, 1600-1681 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Imagination in literature.</subject><title>El escenario de la imaginación : Calderón en su teatro</title><language>spa</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612q310.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n204084b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Hispanic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34225</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>