<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:58:27Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2075" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xt909</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Stephanie de Genlis (1746--1830) is amongst the most productive women authors of her generation. We will base our work upon the research of Catherine Rubinger and Roland Bonnel (in Femmes savantes et femmes d'esprit) in order to describe the society of women authors at the end of the 18th century; we will also look at their literary practices, as well as analyze the environment which contributed to their discourse. We will then study the literary styles favored by de Genlis; Georges May's study on the novel (Le Dilemme du roman) will be used as a first step towards understanding de Genlis' choices as an author. Our third chapter will be dedicated to De l'influence des femmes sur la litterature francaise, in which the author develops her theory about the institution of French literature, about the status of women authors, and about literature in general. Finally, we will put forward an analysis of the ways in which women authors are portrayed in selected narrative texts. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Navarro, Pascale, 1962-</creator><contributor>Desrosiers-Bonin, Diane (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Genlis, Stéphanie Félicité, comtesse de, 1746-1830 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>La femme lettrée au 18e siècle : fiction et théorie chez S. de Genlis</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731613k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xt909</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6395w9567</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis addresses the question of educating for democratic development from the perspective of women leaders in community development organizations. The goal of this study is to expand our current understanding of education by giving voice to women's insights and experiences while considering their philosophical and practical contributions to the field. Education is first considered in its traditional form as a static phenomenon which promotes hierarchy and perpetuates the status quo. The deconstruction of oppression is then addressed in order to develop a theoretical framework of critical, feminist and engaged pedagogies. This framework offers insight into a reconstruction of education as an instrument for promoting social responsibility and social action. Nine women leaders in social action are interviewed using qualitative and phenomenological research methodologies. Their motivations, philosophies and organizational practices, and ideas are considered in the context of education. As a result, the insight that these women offer to the field of education is revealed and illustrated.</description><creator>Nathani, Nisha.</creator><contributor>Wood, Elizabeth (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Ghosh, Ratna (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Women social workers -- Canada.</subject><subject>Social action -- Canada.</subject><title>Educating for democratic development : a study of women leaders in social action</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cj738.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w9567</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2r36v061r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The works of Edwin M. Duval, especially The Design of Rabelais's "Pantagruel" will act as a springboard for our proposition that Theleme is a New Jerusalem. Through textual analysis of biblical texts and those of Rabelais, we intend to bring to light their intertextual relationships as well as that of certain works pertaining to a New Jerusalem which were of importance during the sixteenth century, namely those of Joachim of Flora, Calvin and Torquato Tasso. We will begin by presenting a compilation of what has been established about Theleme to date. Following this, we will present Duval's arguments culminating in his two conclusions: firstly, that Pantagruel is a "Christ-Redeemer" for the race of Giants, and secondly, that Pantagruel is an epic of the New Testament. We will then take these conclusions one step further by proposing that just as the New Testament ends with the Book of Revelation, the Rabelaisian cycle Pantagruel-Gargantua is also brought to a close with the advent of a New Jerusalem. Next, we will present a historical overview of the founding of abbeys up to the time of Rabelais in order to counter the claim that Theleme is an anti-monastery or a counter-abbey. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Morin-Asselin, Michelle.</creator><contributor>Desrosiers-Bonin, Diane (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Rabelais, François, ca. 1490-1553? -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Thélème, une nouvelle Jérusalem?</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bw67h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36v061r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429c446</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Toru Takemitsu (1930--96) composed several musical works which adopt as their titles quotations from James Joyce' s final and most revolutionary novel, Finnegans Wake. In this thesis I focus on one of these compositions, Far Calls. Coming, Far! (1981) for solo violin and orchestra. I explain the ways in which Takemitsu and Joyce possess similar philosophies and aesthetics, and examine their mutual interest in the phenomena of dreams. The Wake explores one night of a family's unconscious sleep activity and is heavily influenced by Freud's The Interpretation of Dreams. I argue that Takemitsu composes Far Calls. Coming, Far! as a "dreamwork" modelled after Joyce's similar literary endeavour. Accordingly, I categorize the analogous dream structures between Takemitsu's music and Joyce's text. These are: The Dreamer, Language, Time and Water, which I discuss in turn.</description><creator>Miller, Lynette.</creator><contributor>Levitz, Tamara (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Music and literature.</subject><subject>Joyce, James, 1882-1941. Finnegans wake.</subject><subject>Takemitsu, Tōru. Far calls, coming, far!</subject><title>The sound of dreams : Toru Takemitsu's Far Calls. Coming, Far! and James Joyce's Finnegans Wake</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322g44q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429c446</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214r29b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The autonomy of the shari` a courts in Ottoman-Egypt during the 16th and 17th centuries, is the subject of this thesis. Specifically, it pursues the question of formalization (the incorporation of courts and their functionaries into the civil apparatus of the state) and, relatedly, the legal innovations which accompanied this policy (the merger of siyasa to shari `a and the development of the qanun ), gauging the implications of both for the judiciaries independence from the state. With regards to procedural law, it finds the courts to be the autonomous domain of its practitioners, muftis and qadis, while concluding that formalization renders the efficacy of the courts dependent on the fortunes of the state. With respect to the two innovations described above, it finds that in the contemplative realm of law, the manipulations of the state spurred certain legal trends without affording the state a place in the domain of law.</description><creator>Meshal, Reem A.</creator><contributor>Turgay, A. Uner (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Hallaq, Wael B (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Islam and state -- Egypt -- History -- 16th century.</subject><subject>Islam and state -- Egypt -- History -- 17th century.</subject><subject>Courts, Islamic -- Egypt -- History -- 17th century.</subject><subject>Courts, Islamic -- Egypt -- History -- 16th century.</subject><title>Straddling the sacred and the secular : the autonomy of Ottoman Egyptian courts during the 16th and 17th centuries</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811km82n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214r29b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xp68kj41h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A strange and enigmatic collection of myths, lyrical storytelling and fantastic folklore, Zora Neale Hurston's Tell My Horse: Voodoo and Life in Haiti and Jamaica details Hurston's Caribbean travels and journey as initiate into Haitian Voudoun. My thesis engages Hurston's contact with Voudoun as a phenomenon of encounter which begins for her with the complex crossing of rumours, secrets, lies, myths and memories embodied in stories of spirit-possession, secret societies and zombies circulating in Haiti. As Hurston pursues the "truth" of these stories she is caught in an experience of possession which I call "the rumour of Voudoun." This rumour is contagious in that these stories pull her toward the scene of Voudoun ritual and permeate her consciousness. By retracing Hurston's own phenomenon of bodily possession back in and through Voudoun's historicity across the Middle Passage and as a "medium of conspiracy" among the slaves during the rebellious uprisings in colonial Saint Domingue, I will argue that the rumour of Voudoun is a contagious affect by which an insurgent communal consciousness is passed on. The rumour circulates in and through a non-national, affective community in Haiti which continues to survive amid the silent history of anticolonial nationalisms.</description><creator>McNulty, Lori.</creator><contributor>Cope, Karin (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Hurston, Zora Neale. Tell my horse.</subject><title>Contagious poetics : rumour, ritual and resistance in Zora Neale Hurston's Tell my horse</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225d15m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kj41h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w6634582j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose was to examine the acute effects of a HBO 2 treatment on (1) recovery following prolonged exercise and (2) aerobic performance in a trained population. Subjects were 6 male and 6 female, trained runners with mean VO2max values of 64.6 +/- 5.6 and 51.9 +/- 6.6 ml·g-1·min-1 respectively. Subjects were randomly assigned to four exercise-HBO2 conditions: (1) control, (2) exercise - no HBO2. (3) no exercise - HBO2, and (4) exercise - HBO2. Exercise was a 90-minute run at 75--80% of VO2max. HBO2 treatments consisted of breathing 95% O2 at 2.5 atm abs for 90 minutes. At the end of each condition, aerobic performance was assessed with a VO 2max test and by the oxygen cost of running on a treadmill at three submaximal velocities. Recovery was not enhanced following a single HBO 2 treatment at 2.5 atm abs for 90 minutes, nor did it alter submaximal or maximal running performance.</description><creator>McGavock, Jonathan M.</creator><contributor>Montgomery, David L. (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Hyperbaric oxygenation.</subject><subject>Running.</subject><title>The effect of hyperbaric oxygen therapy on aerobic performance following fatigue /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kj42s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634582j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s4551</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This qualitative case study adopts a phenomenological approach to describe the socialization and learning experiences of three Turkish graduate students of International Relations. It employs ethnographic tools of inquiry such as interviews, observations, and document analysis. To contribute to the understanding of context, the study includes interviews with three professors of International Relations and an extensive analysis of leading disciplinary journals. The study draws on the works of critical theorists such as Foucault, Bourdieu and Gee to discuss the complex interplay of factors that affect the learning experiences of developing world students in International Relations. Lave and Wenger's (1993) refinement of the cognitive apprenticeship model on situated learning, Legitimate Peripheral Participation, provides a theoretical framework of analysis for the themes of social identity construction and power relations which emerge from the research. Implications for the teaching of discipline-specific materials in English for Academic Purposes are suggested.</description><creator>Mathews, Julie.</creator><contributor>Maguire, Mary (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>International relations -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Socialization -- Case studies.</subject><title>The socialization of students from the developing world into the academic discipline of international relations /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dx51f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s4551</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Second Language Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816p623</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the late 1970's and 1980's, education issues formed a pivotal part of the American religious conservative agenda. The issues of school prayer, textbook content and the teaching of evolution in particular inspired lively debate and committed activism on the part of conservative Protestant leaders and activists. Confronting the behemoth of secular humanism, these leaders sought to win converts and to foment action in the converted through two separate modes of rhetoric: the emotional, which used impassioned arguments, and the intellectual, a more phlegmatic approach used to achieve political ends. Finding their roots in the 1920's, conservative Protestants have placed paramount importance on education issues throughout American history, believing that the United States is a fundamentally Christian nation, founded on a normative Protestant world view, and that American children should be taught according to these principles.</description><creator>MacNeill, Molly.</creator><contributor>Moore, Leonard (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Education and state -- United States -- History -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Religious education -- United States -- History -- 20th century.</subject><title>Church and state : public education and the American religious right</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42n996c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816p623</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945t01b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>With ecological crises remaining at the forefront of public concern it is now more important than ever to develop connections between human beings and the natural world. Consequently, environmental education programs have included values in their objectives in an effort to stimulate appreciation for and dedication to maintaining the health of the planet. This case study examines the values and values education approaches implicit in the Fort Whyte Centre for Environmental Education in Winnipeg, Manitoba. Based on the theoretical framework of both values education and environmental education, analysis revealed that embedded in the program are the values of respect, appreciation and care-taking. Furthermore, it indicates that early childhood experiences in nature are integral in sustained dedication to the environment. Finally, it was apparent that ingrained in the strategies employed by the facility are elements of values education models. Outlining values in program objectives ensures that these beliefs are a central focus of the lessons. Concurrently, teacher training programs must directly teach values education approaches with reference to environmental education. Ecological dilemmas are moral-ethical issues and must be dealt with as such. By neglecting to adequately prepare instructors to deal with these issues programs cannot achieve their objectives. Environmental value systems cannot be developed unless programs are specifically designed to achieve this goal.</description><creator>Lynch, Monica.</creator><contributor>Smith, David (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Environmental education -- Manitoba -- Winnipeg.</subject><title>Values orientation of an environmental education centre : a case study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hx57v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945t01b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mx616</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This essay explores the benefits and limits of teaching and learning music in a changing technological environment, where both students and instructors are faced with the perpetual problem of keeping up with new methods of practicing music for the purpose of maintaining competence. The essay critically reflects on the argument that present societies overvalue technical instruments, at times giving consumers a false hope of achieving quick results in a brief period of time, and with the unintended consequence that playing techniques can be compromised. The idealizing of mechanical devices has become strongly associated today with sophisticated taste and class. Following Mumford and Postman, the essay argues that these technological tools should be seen as posing a challenge to instructional values and to human agency. This essay concludes that while we cannot help the fact that tradition is constantly being renewed, in part through technological change, the role of teaching that learning music needs to be focused on are historic values which incorporate experience and reciprocity.</description><creator>Lukianenko, Sofia.</creator><contributor>Crowley, David (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Music -- Instruction and study -- Technological innovations.</subject><subject>Music -- Computer-assisted instruction.</subject><title>A critical reflection on teaching and learning music in the context of technological change /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440v84d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mx616</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75df69x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One seldom comes across felicitous love in nineteenth-century French literature. Viewed in an unfavourable light, being looked upon as sheer utopianism, felicitous love never quite made it as a major theme in fiction. But idealized as it is in the works of George Sand, this particular topic never ceases to be true to life: the "weltanschauung" in which it originates is far too focused on the realm of reality for love to be put through senseless poetising. To highlight this singularity, this essay focuses on the love symbolic in three George Sand's novels, Indiana (1832), Le Meunier d'Angibault (1845), and Le Marquis de Villemer (1860), by going into the heroine's quest for the ideal. Contemplated with the romantic presupposition (that of the self versus society), this particular quest is subjected to a plural approach (ideological, chronotopical, initiatory) likely to fathom out a symbolic inherent to a writer known after all as "la romanciere de l'amour".</description><creator>Iezzoni, Nadia.</creator><contributor>Duquette, Jean-Pierre (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Sand, George, 1804-1876 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>L'héroïne et la symbolique de l'amour dans trois romans de George Sand</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sc42k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75df69x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj430683p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the articulations of gender, class, and race in a specific sample of films from the 1930's to the 1990's. The tendency in these films is to depict women as passive, rather than heroic. Because this has been the common practice, I chose to outline it through fourteen films that exemplified an inherent bias when dealing with women as subject matter. Brief summaries of several recently produced progressive films are provided to show that it is possible to improve the image of women in film, hence we may finally witness justice on the big screen. In this discursive analysis, I trace specific themes from the feminist and film literature to provide a critical overview of the chosen films, with a view to establishing educational possibilities for the complex issues dealt with in this study.</description><creator>Lewis, Alanna.</creator><contributor>Wood, Elizabeth (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Heroes in motion pictures.</subject><subject>Women in motion pictures.</subject><title>The political and educational implications of gender, class and race in Hollywood film : holding out for a female hero</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237ht850.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430683p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r525w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The essential goal of this study is to expose the complex nature of the connections between Milan Kundera's theory and practice of literature and philosophy. Through a brief investigation of his essays and novels, this thesis attempts to demonstrate that Kundera maintains a relation of both proximity to and distance from certain of the "great" thinkers from the world of philosophy (Nietzsche, Husserl, Heidegger). This study's succinct examination of the evolution of contemporary philosophy allows a better grasp of the influence of philosophy on the structure and intentions of Kundera's work, while its reflections on the form of Kundera's interrogation caste in relief the degree to which Kundera's art moves beyond the strict limits of philosophical discourse and seizes upon the paradoxes of our existence and our epoch.</description><creator>Lemmens, Kateri.</creator><contributor>Ricard, Francois (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Kundera, Milan -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>La philosophie à l'épreuve du roman chez Milan Kundera /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nw69t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r525w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514nn610</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Thomas Kuhn's essay The Structure of Scientific Revolutions has had an overwhelming impact upon academics from various fields, creating a virtual paradigm industry. Authors have frequently had recourse to Kuhn's book, applying insights into the structure and development of the sciences to nonscientific fields. This essay presents a critical review of Kuhn citation in the music-theoretic literature, first reviewing similar citation analyses in the humanities and the social sciences for comparison. While much of the Kuhn citation is problematic, music scholars are found to sin less broadly than those in other fields. After reviewing some of the salient distinctions between scientific and nonscientific endeavors, some of Kuhn's insights into science are found to clarify an issue in the history of music theory, namely the nature of the succession from figured-bass theory to the formulations of J. P. Rameau.</description><creator>Lefcoe, Andrew.</creator><contributor>Caplin, William (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Kuhn, Thomas S. Structure of scientific revolutions.</subject><subject>Music theory -- History -- 20th century.</subject><title>Kuhn's paradigm in music theory</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903203x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nn610</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd375z57s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to identify and describe the teaching tasks used by disciplinary mastery (DM) and ecological integration (EI) oriented teachers. Specifically, this case study of four high school physical educators examined (a) the types of instructional tasks used, (b) the extent to which the instructional tasks were reflected in their teaching, and (c) the extent to which their articulated goals translated into action. Primary data sources involved the Value Orientation Inventory-2 (Ennis &amp; Chen, 1993b), class observations (TSOBS; Jones, 1992), interviews with the teachers, and field notes that were analyzed using constant comparison. The most notable finding of this research was that EI teachers were just as likely as DM teachers to articulate learning goals consistent with their respective orientations and select teaching tasks that facilitated the implementation of their beliefs in their operational setting. The DM teachers shaped their programs to emphasize motor skill development and cognitive knowledge. This was confirmed by interview statements and the use of tasks that enabled them to exercise their value orientation in their teaching. The EI teachers structured their programs to address the inter-relatedness of the learner, content, and context by selecting specific tasks and teaching strategies that related to their value orientation. The persistence shown by all four teachers in terms of maintaining the strength of their beliefs as they made curricular, instructional, and evaluative decisions, is what determined the extent to which their value orientations were reflected in their teaching.</description><creator>Laricchiuta, Nelly.</creator><contributor>Downey, Peggy (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Physical education and training -- Study and teaching (Secondary) -- Québec (Province) -- Case studies.</subject><subject>School discipline -- Québec (Province) -- Case studies.</subject><title>A description of four high school physical education teachers from the perspective of disciplinary mastery and ecological integration value orientations /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qk95t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375z57s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21th581</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Inter-related passages from his 1850 Hawthorne and his Mosses and 1851 Moby-Dick provide maps into the formulations of Melville's basic epistemology which allow us to better understand the author's interest in fragmentation, and in turn help us trace the developments of Melville's creative consciousness during the years 1853--1856, the period in which the author produced sixteen works of experimental short prose fiction following the critical failures of his longer romances. Although the study approaches the collected body of sketches as the major shift in the author's stylistic evolution, emphasis is placed on individual texts within the period which mark key shiftings in Melville's ongoing experimentations with modalities of form. A paradigm of tenuous equilibrium without reconciliation is embodied in various image strands throughout the works and will be shown to give shape to the experimental formlessness of Melville's sketches. Collectively, the strands make up Melville's aesthetics of incompleteness.</description><creator>Landeck, Jeffrey.</creator><contributor>Gibian, Peter (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Melville, Herman, 1819-1891 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>The vine and the rose : towards an aesthetics of incompleteness in Melville's sketch pieces, 1853-1856</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77ft58w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21th581</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945t02m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study is to give an overview of the writings on postmodernism and explores a number of different postmodern constructs. Postmodernism's insistence on the decentred and fragmented nature of the human subject is investigated and challenged. A psychoanalytic solution to the postmodern impasse is suggested and as such, the thesis argues for a reading of a mutual entanglement between postmodernism and psychoanalytic theory and practice by demonstrating their reciprocal influences and strengths. This 'solution' is illustrated by examining an object relations case study of a fragmented postmodern subject. A final chapter explores possible implications of the postmodern debate for educational theory.</description><creator>Kriegler, Diane.</creator><contributor>Wood, E. (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Psychoanalysis.</subject><subject>Postmodernism.</subject><title>The implications of engagement : postmodernism, psychoanalysis and pedagogy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50gz299.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945t02m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214r303</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to validate an abbreviated interview schedule for the assessment of adolescent life stress based on the original Life Events and Difficulties Schedule (LEDS) by Brown and Harris (1978). The main objective of the abbreviated instruments was to elicit the severe stressors shown to be of etiological significance for predicting psychiatric disorder without requiring two hours to administer. A non-clinical sample of 58 adolescents (mean age = 15.67 years) completed the Childhood Depression Inventory (Kovacs, 1982), the Abbreviated Life Event and Difficulty Schedule - Adolescent version (ALEDS-A), and the full-length LEDS-Adolescent Version (LEDS-A). The abbreviated instrument elicited significantly fewer minor stressors, while retaining its ability to solicit the most severe stressors in a 30-minute time period. Results are interpreted with reference to Brown and Harris's (1978) sociological theory of major life stress and depression.</description><creator>Kaufman, Felicia D.</creator><contributor>Smith, Tim A. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Stress in adolescence.</subject><subject>Stress (Psychology) -- Testing.</subject><title>Life-stress assessment in adolescents : validation of the Abbreviated Life Events and Difficulties Schedule - Adolescent version (ALEDS-A)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qp246.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214r303</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644t69f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Description is a form of writing that has long been perceived with some contempt. Due to its undefinable and vague nature, it is indeed uncategorizable, and seems to escape all parameters. What adds to its contempt is its non-utilitarian, non-pragmatical nature; that is, description for the sake of description, or a way to show off knowledgability. Since the Classical period, description had been classified into various categories, just to name a few: chronography, topography, prosopography, prosopopaeia , portrait, parallel, hypotyposis. And still, it had never been attributed a definite theoretical status. Today, the debate continues. In this thesis, I will discuss the linguistic systems of description as defined by Philippe Hamon and Jean-Michel Adam, and to which Jean Molino opposes. The creative text illustrates that man is in fact indissociable from his environment. Man is greatly determined by the place where he lives. The story is about a woman is forced to return to her original social and cultural background because of her father's death. Her return back to her roots, namely the family business, instigates a requestioning of her cultural identity, and consequently, she develops a pessimistic view of her surroundings.</description><creator>Karamanoukian, Charry.</creator><contributor>Duquette, Jean-Pierce (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Lane-Mercier, Gillian (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Description (Rhetoric)</subject><title>Les systèmes linguistiques du descriptif, suivi de, Exilée /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472z53x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644t69f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xt91k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Mishnah depends on the Bible for its authority, vocabulary, and much of its contents. Nearly six hundred Bible citations are distributed in fifty-three of the Mishnah's tractates and are quoted from all but six biblical books. Most citations are from the Torah and are used for proof-texting. The Mishnah uses thousands of words derived from or related to the Bible (e.g., Shabbat, Peah, Kohen). Its content is unquestionably tied to that of the Bible (e.g., Seder Moed is based on the discussions of the various holy days in Exodus). Finally, the Mishnah contains multiple discussions of Biblical characters and events, of Bible reading, interpretation, and teaching. The works of Georg Aicher, Samuel Rosenblatt, Peter Acker Pettit, and Jacob Neusner help examine the Bible-Mishnah relationship. The first three discuss the use of Bible citation in the Mishnah. Neusner uses form-analysis to examine its historical development and describes the Mishnah by viewing it as a whole. Our approach, an examination of the Mishnah's details, is more in line with those of Aicher, Rosenblatt, and Pettit. The dependence of the Mishnah on the Bible is demonstrated by examining the distribution and use of Bible citations, comparing the content of the Mishnah to that of the Bible, and analyzing various Mishnaic passages.</description><creator>Kalman, Jason.</creator><contributor>Levy, B. Barry (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Religion, Biblical Studies</subject><title>The place of the Hebrew Bible in the Mishnah /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128d100.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xt91k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Jewish Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kc84k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:17:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Many studies have been done of Fakhr al-Dinal-Razi and his system of thought, taking into account his contributions from theology, philosophy, and exegesis. However, works specifically devoted to his exegetical thought have been few. In fact, none of these has dealt with al-Razi's exegetical methodology in the light of his basic assumptions regarding the Qur'an. In view of this fact, the present thesis aims at elucidating Fakhr al-Din al-Razi's methodology in interpreting the Qur'an in his magnum opus, known by the title al-Tafsir al-Kabir or Mafatiḥ al-Ghayb. In order to achieve this purpose, we will focus on his interpretation of the third chapter of the Qur'an, printed in volumes 7, 8, and 9 of the standard edition of his work. In overall terms, al-Razi contributed greatly to the dissemination of a rational approach to the study of the Qur'an. Yet, he could not avoid the debate over theological issues, which were common in his time. In many parts of his al-Tafsir al-Kabir, therefore, he defends Ash'arite thought against the views of Mu'tazilites, Ẓahirites, and the Ḥashwiyyah, among others. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Kafrawi, Shalahudin.</creator><contributor>Boullata, Issa J. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Rāzī, Fakhr al-Dīn Muḥammad ibn ʻUmar, 1149 or 50-1210. Mafātīḥ al-ghayb.</subject><title>Fakhr al-Dīn al Rāzī's methodology in interpreting the Qurān</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731614v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kc84k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q524jq99k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:17:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Epilepsy in Medieval Islamic History focuses on the perception, etiology and treatment of epilepsy in the work of four medieval Islamic scholars, Ibn Sina, Razi, Ibn Qayyim and S&amp;dotbelow;anawbari, while attempting to place their views in the wider context of a medieval Islamic cultural milieu. This work suggests that the understanding of epilepsy in the medieval Islamic period was both porous and flexible. Despite the fact that these scholars believed they were writing in different genres, in fact, they shared both healing techniques and theoretical perspectives. The Islamic culture which shaped all of these writers imbued them with a synthesized world-view which transcends the genre of each work. Medieval Islamic understandings and treatment of epilepsy were undeniably influenced by Greek medicine and the Middle Eastern cultural milieu; nonetheless, they represent a distinct cultural interpretation of the disease.</description><creator>Jolin, Paula.</creator><contributor>Little, Donald (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Medicine, Arab.</subject><subject>Epilepsy -- History -- To 1500.</subject><title>Epilepsy in medieval Islamic history</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hx584.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jq99k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p2676x89f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:17:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The cultural and historical context in which La hija del adelantado was first published in 1866, is very important in this study because it helps us understand why Milla chose to write about the early colonial past, and why he valued the traditions and customs of those years. It is also shown how the author---mixing history and fiction---denounces the system of exploitation practiced by the colonizers of America, and uncovers the historical roots of some of the contemporary problems that affected the Guatemala of those days. The main purpose of this work is to highlight the importance that Jose Milla places on his country's history, and to demonstrate that through the rewriting of the colonial past, the author contributes to the building process of the national identity. Also emphasized is the way in which Milla---giving priority to national history and to America's natural forces and beauty---places La hija del adelantado, as Guatemala's foundational text.</description><creator>Jerez, Olga Estela.</creator><contributor>Alba-Koch, Beatriz de (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Colonies in literature.</subject><subject>Guatemala -- History -- To 1821 -- In literature.</subject><subject>Milla, José, 1822-1882. Hija del adelantado.</subject><subject>Guatemalan literature -- History and criticism.</subject><title>La hija del adelantado, de José Milla : reflejo del pasado y proyección del futuro nacional guatemalteco</title><language>spa</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sm567.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676x89f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Hispanic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c534fr04g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:17:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study looks at art education as an essential component of education and the place of values education within it. My observations in a Grade 5/6 art class within an elementary school in a working class district of Montreal attempt to identify some of the factors that contribute to value awareness. I observed children at work over a period of seven weeks, and use the data to present a picture of the ways in which art activities influence value awareness in the classroom. General discussions on some theories on values and art education initiate my study. The finding is that art activities contribute to an awareness of personal, social, cultural, aesthetic, and moral values and validate my claim that art education can be used to develop value awareness.</description><creator>Ibrahim, Md. Nasir.</creator><contributor>White, Boyd E. (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Values -- Study and teaching (Elementary)</subject><subject>Art -- Study and teaching (Elementary)</subject><title>The development of value awareness through art education /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f569z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fr04g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2100</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>