<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:33:47Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11500" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dj52w785j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The reaction between copper and dithiocarbamic acid derivatives produces a brown coloured complex which absorbs light at 435 m.u. When this reaction is applied to the determination of copper, it provides a very sensitive method that can detect, and measure accurately, concentrations as low as 0.1 µ.g. of copper. For this particular determination, the dithiocarbamic acid derivatives function as the reagent. It should be possible, however, to apply the same reaction to the determination of dithiocarbamio acid derivatives by using the copper component as the reagent. If the determination was limited to the dithiocarbamic acids as such the method would have little biological value since these acids do not seem to occur in nature. But since amines can be converted into the corresponding dithiocarbamic acids, and these in turn into the brown coloured copper complexes, the reaction could become a measure of the amines. The amino acids, having the characteristic amino group, should possess this property of amines. One of the important applications of the determination of copper is in relation to the keeping quality of foods. Milk powder was given special attention because of its increasing importance as a food. It is generally agreed that concentrations of copper of the order of 10 p.p.m. will favour the development of off-flavours in milk powder in a relatively short time. It is recognized also that varying amounts of copper may be introduced into the milk [...]</description><creator>Boulet, Marcel A.</creator><contributor>McFarlane, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>A study of the reaction between copper and dithiocarbamic acid, as applied to the determination of copper and amino acids.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sw99v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w785j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999981f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The use of the electron microscope as a powerful instrument in the study of crystal structure, colloids, fibres, and bacteriological specimens has now become widely recognized. In an effort to obtain images of higher quality, an electron microscope using magnetic lenses was constructed in this laboratory during 1939-40. The writer’s work along this line was interrupted by war work from the summer of 1940 onward. In the spring of 1945 the University acquired a Type EMU (R.C.A.) instrument which has been used for a variety of studies in electron microscopy; the writer has taken a number of photographs of pulp fibres at high magnification. [...]</description><creator>Black, Robson Hughdeburgh M.</creator><contributor>Keys, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>Examination of fibres by electron microscopy.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zt80n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999981f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p352g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This investigation is concerned with the potash status of the podzolised soils of the province of Quebec, and particularly with the effects upon it, of the application of limestone and superphosphate to these soils. A Greensboro loam from the Sawyerville area in the Eastern Townships has been selected for study, partly because of the extensive area in the province occupied by this soil, and partly because of the availability of experimental material from fertilizer plots located on it. The investigation has consisted of a study of two independent problems, each having a bearing upon the more general problem under observation, these are: (a) The possibility of a biological fixation of potassium, and (b) The efficiency of present treatments in securing an improved potassium status in the soils and crops of the experimental area. [...] It was hoped that a study of this kind, when considered in conjunction with treatment, yields, and available soil potash, would provide some information about the following problems. 1. What are the critical values of K, Ca, and Ca/K of clover for this area? 2. What levels of soil and plant potassium are correlated with good stands of clover? 3. What is the effect of applications of Ca, P, and Ca + P upon the soil and plant potassium? [...]</description><creator>Gillingham, J. T. (John Theodore)</creator><contributor>DeLong, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>Studies on the availability of potassium in a podzol soil.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096b26v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p352g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fp95r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>215 kilovolt electrons have been produced by two successive applications of ultra high frequency voltages. The electrons travel through two cavities which are resonant to an electrical oscillation having a wave-length of 10.7 cm. Simple radar equipment is used to generate a peak power of 110 kilowatts which comes in a pulse lasting one micro-second and occurs one thousand times per second. With one-half of the power dissipated in each resonator, the resulting electric field strength is 92,000 volts/cm. over a distance of 2.5 cm. The maximum voltage across the accelerating gap is 2.5 x 92,000 volts. Owing to the time taken in traversing this 2.5 cm. gap, the electrons acquire 36% of this voltage in the first cavity and 56% in the second. The highest possible efficiency, which occurs when the electrons are travelling at almost the velocity of light, is 90%. This method of accelerating electrons is readily adaptable to 30 or 40 resonators which, when supplied with a total power of 2 1/4 megawatts, might be expected to yield 7 Mev. electrons. The entire wave-guide system would not exceed 12 feet in length.</description><creator>Guptill, Ernest Wilmot.</creator><contributor>Foster, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>A linear accelerator for electrons.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gw89x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fp95r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795b977</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>High energy particles can be produced most directly by allowing the ionized particle to be accelerated through a single large potential drop. This method was first successfully applied by Van de Graaff. The large voltage involved leads to an obvious difficulty of insulation which results in extremely bulky and expensive equipment for voltage outputs of only several million volts. This insulation difficulty has been overcome in two ways. One method is to enclose the equipment of high potential in a container, which is then either evacuated or filled with freon at high pressure. That has been applied by Herb at the University of Wisconsin, ( ) and resulted in a condensed version of the Van de Graaff, entirely enclosed in a tank 20’ long 5 1/2’ diameter, but developing a voltage difference of over 2 M.E.V. The second method is to eliminate the high voltage involved by giving the ions a large number of relatively small increments of energy. The simplest device of this second type makes use of a number of hollow cylinders arranged in a straight line, and connected alternately to opposite poles of a high frequency oscillator. [...] It was therefore decided to investigate the problems connected with a Linear Electron Accelerator, consisting of a number of Resonant Cavities coupled to a wave guide, and suitably phased for an electron to acquire energy each time it crosses the gap of a Cavity.</description><creator>Munn, Allan.</creator><contributor>Foster, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>A Linear electron accelerator.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602411g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795b977</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w66346874</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Graphitization in iron-carbon alloys has been for several years a favorite subject of research, forming as it does the basis of the malleable iron casting industry, and having in addition a considerable importance in the length of service of iron-carbon alloys subjected to high temperatures for long periods. The instability of iron carbide, or cementite, and its tendency to break down into graphite and other products under suitable conditions has been rather completely surveyed, most noteworthy in this respect being the work of Wells . Graphitization in white cast iron has been investigated and reported by Schwartz and his associates. Their work includes the study of such graphitization governing factors as composition, casting temperatures, moulds, pre-annealing heat-treatments, graphitizing temperatures and cycles, and heat-treating (or “annealing”) atmospheres, as well as the formulation of a mechanism of graphitization. The effect of various heat-treatments has been reported by Sauveur and Anthony, together with an explanation of the graphitization mechanism. Details on the effect of chilling of castings, annealing temperature and recommended short cycle anneals are given by Rehder. [...]</description><creator>Perrault, Charles Hubert.</creator><contributor>Sproule, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Metallurgical Engineering.</subject><title>The effect of aluminum additions on the graphitization rate of white cast iron.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719q36f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w66346874</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65vb80x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Research on growth factors essential to the metabolism of microorganisms and higher animals has proceeded with ever increasing strides in the past fifty years. The correlation of microbial growth factors with animal vitamins was a recent development. Indeed, as recently as 1936, B.C.J.G. Knight (15) stated, “It is not unlikely that some of the animal vitamins may be required by bacteria, but at present it has not been shown that any pure animal vitamin is required as an essential nutrient by any”. The work covered in this thesis concerns itself with one vitamin, namely, riboflavin. At first it was proposed to investigate the use of waste materials as substrates for the bacterial synthesis of riboflavin. However, four years elapsed before the work was completed and chemically synthesized riboflavin had become very cheap. The commercial production of riboflavin from waste materials was, therefore, considered unfeasible. Nevertheless, the investigation was continued and many strains of riboflavin synthesizing bacteria were isolated. Methods for the fluorometric and microbiological assay of riboflavin were applied to bacterial cultures. Riboflavin concentrates have been prepared from some of these cultures. At the same time species of bacteria which required riboflavin for growth and some of the conditions for the synthesis of riboflavin by Vibrio perimastix were investigated. [...]</description><creator>Pinsky, Alex.</creator><contributor>McFarlane, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>The determination and synthesis of riboflavin in cultures of microorganisms.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qn03h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65vb80x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311s62t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The toxicity of synthetic organic compounds was evaluated by techniques involving impregnated substrata (filter paper or glass), direct spraying of the test animals (Drosophila melanogaster), and exposure to vapours only. The techniques are described and compared. Eighteen compounds were tested. 666 and the difluoro analogue of DDT were the only compounds more toxic than DDT. Of these, 666 exhibited a strong fumigant effect, while the difluoro analogue rapidly lost its toxicity. In compounds having two phenyl groups para substitution in both phenyl radicles is essential for high toxicity. No other halogen can replace the chlorine atoms on the phenyl groups and still leave the compound with a high residual toxic effect. There is a suggestion of an inverse relationship between toxicity and the length of the para-substituted radicles, with alkoxy and alkyl substitutions. Apparently toxicity is lowered by any alteration in the trihalogen grouping.</description><creator>Proverbs, Maurice Desmond.</creator><contributor>Morrison, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Entomology.</subject><title>Studies on the insecticidal action of DDT (1,1, BIS (4,4’ Dichlorophenyl) 2,2,2- Trichloroethane) and regulated compounds, with a view to correlating this action with chemical structure.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q939z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311s62t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386n76t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Biological response is characterized by variation: different organisms do not react in exactly the same way to identical situations; nor do individual organisms, on different occasions. Such lack of uniformity of response causes many difficulties in the interpretation of biological data. This has resulted in the development, in recent years, of special techniques for obtaining and analyzing experimental results. In particular, there has been great improvement in experimental designs, to which modern statistical methods may be applied in a satisfactory manner. While some statistical techniques have long been recognized as valuable in the reduction of large masses of data to comprehensible form, it has been only recently that exact methods of treating small numbers of observations have been worked out. Most biological data is of the latter sort. The methods have been found of great value in agricultural investigations, while notable improvements have been made in the field of biological assay. The difficulties which are encountered in biological assay are multiplied many times when the responses used are “subjective” rather than “physical.” Such is the case when panels of judges are used in assessing the quality of foodstuffs. It is the intention of this thesis to illustrate how modern statistical procedures may be applied to such psychometric investigations in a manner similar to that in which they have been applied in other fields. [...]</description><creator>Reid, David Buchanan William.</creator><contributor>Kellogg, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Statistics.</subject><subject>Psychology, Experimental.</subject><title>Some applications of modern statistical methods to psychometric data.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kr22q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386n76t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zh59n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study was undertaken with the hope that something further could be added to the question of cerebral localization of speech. To know the anatomical location of a lesion in a patient with a specified type of aphasia is of interest to the neurologist but in the majority of cases it is only a matter of interest, and does little to help the patient. To the neurosurgeon, in planning and executing an excision of cortex, it becomes a matter of paramount importance. He wants to know what areas can be removed without affecting speech, and if known speech areas have to be removed, what the chances of recovery will be. Dr. Wilder Penfield has accumulated, since his arrival at McGill University, a unique series of cases in which he has performed cortical excisions for the treatment of focal epilepsy. These cases form the basis of this study. Most of the information has been obtained from the hospital records of the patients. Eleven cases reported here were seen and followed by the author. The cases were reviewed to see what areas could be removed from the major hemisphere without producing any aphasia and what areas, when excised, did produce an aphasia. [...]</description><creator>Robb, James P.</creator><contributor>Penfield, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Neurology &amp; Neurosurgery.</subject><title>A study of the effect of cortical excision on speech in patients with previous cerebral injuries.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892f14b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zh59n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pk40p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>World War II has come to a close, and the leading democracies of the world have started to reconvert towards a peace time economy. Many objectives have been put forward, and are in the process of accomplishment, but a Tax policy which will effectively contribute towards these objectives is still lacking. Although taxation, and particularly business taxation, as a part of the Fiscal Policy program, has been the subject of much discussion, and several proposals have been advanced, much revision will have to be undertaken to incorporate the discussions and proposals in the Full Employment peace Time Economy towards which we are striving. An effective postwar tax policy must be found, and if this paper makes some contribution towards this goal its writing has seen warranted; if not it is hoped that future attempts on the subject may benefit from its mistakes.</description><creator>Rothschild, Fred.</creator><contributor>Higgins, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Taxation -- Canada.</subject><subject>INVESTMENTS</subject><subject>Finance -- Canada.</subject><title>Business taxes and investment.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wq97k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pk40p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r424p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study was undertaken to determine the effect of the large amounts of citrate administered in massive transfusions of blood. [...] Before blood transfusion could become safe enough for universal use, the dangers of incompatibility and clotting of bloods had to be overcome. Incompatibility difficulties were minimized by the discovery of blood groups in the early years of this century and all but eliminated by the recent discovery of the Rh factors. Clotting also has been largely eliminated as a source of trouble in transfusions, although the ideal anticoagulant has yet to be found. The administration of clotting or clotted blood has been avoided in two ways: (a) by the rapid transfusion of the blood before it has a chance to clot, and (b) by the modification of the blood in some way so as to prevent or delay the clotting changes. [...]</description><creator>Saffran, Murray.</creator><contributor>Denstedt, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>The clearance of injected citrate from the blood.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v161z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r424p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8910jx719</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The amazing rise in importance of the synthetic rubber industry in the United States and Canada during the war years is now a well-known fact and requires no further description. To-day this industry has ceased to be merely an alternative source of rubber, and has achieved the status of a major industry with an annual capacity of one million tons. The maintenance of this position, in a peace time economy, depends on its ability to produce a low cost product with properties approaching or surpassing those of natural rubber. The properties of the present GR-S type synthetic rubber, are mainly controlled by the action of the chain transfer agents or modifiers used in its production. These modifiers act to control the physical properties of the polymer through the medium of regulating the chain length and the chain length distribution, i.e. the homogeneity of the polymer. In the absence of such control, a product would be produced containing much insoluble material of the cross-linked type, which is difficult to process and some low molecular weight polymer which lacks mechanical strength, along with the desirable medium-high molecular weight product. It is the purpose of this investigation to study some of the possible causes of this anomalous behaviour of tertiary hexadecyl mercaptan. Two possible effects will be considered, namely: (i) Polymer-Mercaptan Interaction. (ii) Oxidative Degradation of the Polymer.</description><creator>Russell, Gordon Douglas.</creator><contributor>Nicholls, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The reaction of tertiary hexadecyl mercaptan with a butadiene-styrene copolymer.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343w213.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jx719</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gf06g574f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The functional significance of the testis has been known since the time of Aristotle (121) who ascribed post-pubertal changes to the function of the gonads, as such manifestations were absent in castrates — both in man and in birds. Accurate knowledge of the nature and metabolism of the androgenically active substance secreted  by the testis has, however, been acquired only during the past decade. It was not until the first half of the Nineteenth Century that the gonads were recognized as being ductless glands, and capable of secreting a substance into the blood-stream. That the testis is normally the main source of the androgenic substance in man and other animals was first indicated experimentally by Berthold in 1849 (4). He removed the testis of four roosters and replaced one testis in an unusual abdominal position in each of two capons. He killed these two capons six months later and found that because of the testicular grafts, “these animals remained male in regard to voice, reproduction, instinct, fighting spirits, and growth of comb and wattles”. Berthold further suggested that the testicle exerted its influence upon the organism via the blood, and this viewpoint is now the generally accepted one. [...]</description><creator>Sabin, I. Morris.</creator><contributor>Hoffman, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Metabolism.</subject><subject>Testosterone.</subject><title>The metabolism of testosterone.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vm145.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g574f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t530x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The development of the frog egg into the terrestrial adult is a discontinuous process divided into two periods of intensive morphogenetic activity. The first of these developmental periods leads to the aquatic larva or tadpole. The second developmental period, termed metamorphosis, results in the rapid transformation of the aquatic tadpole into the profoundly different terrestrial frog, adapted to a totally different mode of life. The rapid reorganization during metamorphosis distinguishes that process from the gradual post-embryonic development of most animals. Metamorphotic phenomena lend themselves readily to a study of development, and many investigators have attempted to elucidate the causative factors underlying them. Some of these factors are now fairly well understood, and it is regrettable that this has distracted from an equally intensive investigation of the properties of the reacting system and of the tissues undergoing change. [...]</description><creator>Schachter, Ruth.</creator><contributor>Berrill, N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Zoology.</subject><title>Analysis of frog metamorposis by means of thiouracil.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731719f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t530x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Zoology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vp09f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study aims to show the kind of social situations which tend to produce delinquency in an urban area which has not been markedly and only intermittently delinquent. [...] The area dealt with is a suburban, largely English speaking middle-class area. It was found that urgencies variously growing out of Montreal’s cultural bifurcation, the social and horizontal mobility of the population type of the area , and its intermediary class position reinforced by ecological factors have tended to isolate a smaller sub-area with a somewhat less homogeneous population, creating thereby an institutional gap. With regard to the adolescents mainly involved this came to approximate a “wrong side of the track” situation. Actual experience of discrimination and conscious rejection by differentiated individuals of the institutional facilities of the superordinate group resulted in segregation and gave rise to the typical adolescent delinquent gang and to emancipation of its members from traditional moralities. It is felt that this study to some extent may show how delinquent patterns become established in contrast to the many and exhaustive studies of the transmission of delinquent patterns in areas where this kind of behavior and attitudes are traditional. [...]</description><creator>Seywerd, Henry.</creator><contributor>LaViolette, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Juvenile delinquency -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>A case study of community consensus with respect to emerging delinquent behavior.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rh575.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vp09f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xw201</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>With the realization (1) that lipid extracts of urine contain material possessing the biological properties of adrenal cortical hormones and (2) that the physiologically active and some inactive crystalline adrenal steroids contain an α-ketol in position 20 and 21 (a functional group which has intensive reducing properties), it was proposed that a method be developed to determine the quantity of reducing material in the neutral lipid soluble urinary extracts and to determine if any correlation could be found between the quantity of reducing material and the degree of activity of the adrenal cortex. This project would represent a pioneer work in the search for a chemical method for the estimation of urinary cortin; one that would make available a means of chemical assay, suitable for routine clinical use and for the assistance to certain experimental work. While this work was in progress several papers appeared in the literature with reference to the search for a chemical analytical method.[...]</description><creator>Sobel, Harry.</creator><contributor>Heard, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>The correlation between neutral urinary reducing lipids and adrenal cortical function.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xh966.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xw201</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5138jh67w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An experiment is described which was designed to study the effect of storage of livestock feeds for ninety days on the nutritive value of their proteins, as measured by the growth of young rats. Initial weight of the rats, the amount of feed consumed and other experimental data are examined in assessing nutritive value. The proteins of whole wheat did not decrease in value on storage. Fish meal gave greater growth after storage than before, when combined in the ration with fresh or stored whole wheat. The proteins of skim milk powder deteriorated rapidly in ninety days, while mixed hog supplement did not alter in value. Digestibility changes during storage were negligible. The inferior growth-promoting value of white flour proteins as compared with those of unmilled wheat and the superior digestibility of white flour were confirmed.</description><creator>Sourkes, Theodore L.</creator><contributor>Crampton, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Nutrition.</subject><title>The nutritive value of the proteins of stored livestock rations.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xw219.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5138jh67w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440w94v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The story of art, viewed in its broad pattern, is largely the story of its growth from speculative beginnings, through a succession of critical conceptualizations, towards a more rationalistic frame of reference. No inevitable or evolutionary trend is implied in the sequence ‘speculative-scientific’ except to point out the thin thread apparent throughout the history of art investigations from initial ‘a priori’ generalizations and subjective recordings concerning the nature of esthetic experience to the more scientific approach of objective inquiry into the function of art in specific social situations. An attempt is made to classify material in the field around ‘classical-speculative’ conceptions of art activity, through ‘medieval-authorative’ to a pending ‘modern-scientific’ frame of reference, and to present in the light of insights gained the ‘natural history’ of a new field of inquiry...the sociology of art.</description><creator>Spurrell, Althea Constance Lorraine.</creator><contributor>Dawson, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Aesthetics.</subject><title>Towards a ’natural history’ of the sociology of art.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395wb67z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440w94v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rx78q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>When Charles Fletcher was appointed Dominion Entomologist in 1884, the codling moth was already recognized as a major pest of the apple in Eastern Canada. While control of the insect by trapping the larvae in tree bands had been practiced since 1846 (Slingerland, 1898), it was only about the time of Fletcher’s appointment that the use of poison sprays for the control of this insect had become well established. From the time of his earliest reports, he recommends both methods of control. The available records indicate that for awhile after the turn of the century the codling moth markedly decreased in importance as an apple pest, following the use of bordeaux-arsenical sprays in the Annapolis valley. About 1924 it apparently started increasing in importance so that by 1930 it again became a major pest in a few restricted areas, particularly that around Berwick. In 1927 Brittain (1927) was still able to say that, “The control of the codling moth is not the problem in Nova Scotia that it is in many other apple growing sections and the ordinary sprays or ousts, applied immediately after blossom fall and again in two weeks time, are usually sufficient to keep it in control”. By 1937, however, it threatened to make commercial apple growing impracticable in a few orchards in the Berwick area unless special methods of control were used against it. Until the present project was started in 1939, no special biological study of this insect had been made in the Annapolis valley[...]</description><creator>Stultz, Harold Thorne.</creator><contributor>DuPorte, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Entomology.</subject><title>Bionomics of the codling moth, Carpocapsa Pomenella L., in the Annapolis Valley, Nova Scotia.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d570084j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rx78q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nx801</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the mammalian species, the concentration of plasma electrolytes determines to a great extent the physical properties of extracellular fluids. The bicarbonate ion is under respiratory control, but the other electrolytes, sodium, potassium, calcium, magnesium, chloride, phosphate and sulphate are regulated by the kidney. Maintenance of normal plasma values of the various ions is an indication of the degree of success attained by the regulatory mechanisms of the kidney (129). Intracellular fluids are in osmotic equilibrium with the extracellular fluids. Sodium is the dominant kation of the extracellular fluids, while potassium is the chief cellular base. The degree of hydration in the two main divisions of body water depends upon the relative proportions of sodium and potassium. The water of the body is in a dynamic state, in which an exchange of water freely occurs across cell membranes to meet the exigencies of the continually occurring processes of metabolism (425, 74, 315). A historical review of the literature concerning the role played by the endocrine glands in the metabolism of potassium, sodium, chloride, calcium and phosphorus follows in the next section.</description><creator>Sylvester, Elizabeth Marjorie.</creator><contributor>Selye, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Electrolytes -- Metabolism.</subject><subject>Hormones.</subject><title>The hormonal control of electrolyte metabolism.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jv348.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nx801</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2r36v1627</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study was prompted by purely practical needs. In clinical psychological work, especially in diagnostic testing, it is often useful to have a rough idea of the mental age of a patient. This can be obtained from the Stanford-Binet (1937) Vocabulary List, for which mental age equivalents are available. However, one of the tests most commonly administered in a diagnostic situation, the Wechsler-Bellevue Adult Scale, includes a vocabulary subtest, but this does not yield mental ages*, and one would have to administer the Stanford-Binet Vocabulary Test as well. This procedure is time consuming for the psychologist and undesirable from the patient’s point of view. A mentally ill person usually does not enjoy mental tests, and two tests that to the patient appear practically the same may irk and irritate him unnecessarily. To circumvent the above difficulty scores on the Stanford-Binet Vocabulary could be estimated from those on the Wechsler-Bellevue Vocabulary, provided the two tests had a sufficiently high correlation. This paper offers a comparison between the Wechsler-Bellevue Vocabulary and the (1937) Stanford-Binet Vocabulary; it also supplies a table for estimating scores on the latter from scores on the former. Also, an attempt was made to gauge roughly the equivalence of the two tests, since it would be useful to know to what extent they could be interchanged for purposes of retest and follow up studies. [...]</description><creator>Tagiuri, Renato.</creator><contributor>Malmo, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Stanford-Binet Test.</subject><subject>Wechsler Adult Intelligence Scale.</subject><subject>Mentally ill -- Psychological testing.</subject><title>Comparison of results obtained from the Wechsler-Bellevue vocabulary test with those from the Stanford-Binet vocabulary, using a population of normal subjects and mental patients.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fc462.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36v1627</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343w22c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The development of microorganisms, as well as other forms of living cells, is based on the requirements of those organisms or cells for certain essential nutrients; not only are these substances needed for building up cellular material but also for certain catalytic actions and for the maintenance of various factors in the physical environment. Foster (4) states that a nutrient may serve two purposes: (a) structural, or comprising the cell substance, (b) functional, or associated with some specific physiological activity or reaction within the cell matrix. An examination of the variety of substances required to serve these purposes reveals that the subject matter concerning nutrition may be resolved into four main categories: (1) the mineral elements that are necessary to sustain growth and how they effect certain physiological processes to which bacterial cells are known to be subjected; (2) the trace elements that are required in the substrate; (3) the part played by growth factors; (4) the requirements for organic carbonaceous and nitrogenous compounds.[...]</description><creator>Wallace, Raphael Herman.</creator><contributor>Gray, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Agricultural Bacteriology.</subject><title>Nutritional requirements of celluloytic bacteria isolated from Quebec soils.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dg81d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343w22c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Bacteriology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x4517</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The detailed study of the larval development of the tongueless Anuran Xenopus laevis Daud, as reported in the present thesis, is made desirable by two factors. One is the increasing interest in the adult toad since Hogben (‘30) has established the usefulness of Xenopus as a human pregnancy test animal. Many investigators since that time have elaborated on this discovery, among them Weisman (‘38), Elkan_(‘38), Landgrebe (‘39), et al.; the information on the clinical aspects of the adult toad has recently been summarized by Weisman and Coates (‘44). Secondly, detailed work on the embryology of the tadpole has been justified in view of the truly remarkable developmental and morphological deviations in the larva from so-called “typical” Anuran characteristics, especially as regards the circulatory, respiratory and digestive systems. So unique are the peculiarities of the Xenopus tadpole, that the latter, from an academic viewpoint, becomes one of the most interesting vertebrate forms. No previous exhaustive work on the larva is on record. [...] Both Bles and Dreyer failed to recognize the extraordinary singularity of the morphology of the late larva of Xenopus, and a great many statements in their papers remain of purely speculative character. In the present report, the embryonic period of Xenopus laevis is described in the form of standard tables of normal development. Larval development has arbitrarily been divided into four phases; each of these, beginning and terminating with the appearance of certain characteristic external features (Table I), is separately discussed.</description><creator>Weisz, Paul B., 1921-</creator><contributor>Berrill, N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Shrimps.</subject><subject>Xenopus laevis.</subject><title>Studies on the development of the young of the South Africa clawed toad, Xenopus laevis. Part II. Studies on development and growth of the brine shrimp, Arternia salina.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hs81x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x4517</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Zoology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p096b274</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:05:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The synthesis of some mono-amino acid esters or thiodiglycol has been investigated, and a method for the preparation of these esters has been described. Successful reduction of N-carbobenzoxy glycyl thiodiglycol could not be effected by standard methods. The product obtained by reacting H with glycine in aqueous sodium hydroxide has been found to be a nitrogen-containing sulphonium salt. Treatment of this compound with strong hydrockloric acid yields a new sulphonium salt, for which a tentative structure has been proposed. An investigation into the reaction of H with various amino acids other than glycine in aqueous alkaline solution has been initiated. In general, about 90 percent of the amino groups are obscured during the reaction. Sulphonium salt formation is believed to occur.</description><creator>Douglas, Donald Edward.</creator><contributor>Heard, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1945</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>The reaction of H with amino acids.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q469g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p096b274</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11525</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>