<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:00:25Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2725" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x3554</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The book of Deuteronomy turns out to be very interesting for the study of passing on religious traditions within family. On the one hand, with a canonical approach — i.e. an approach where the function of a biblical text within the canon is emphasised over die history of this text - Deuteronomy acts like the hermeneutical key explaining how the new generations must face and actualise the Torah — the principles of life and conduct given by the Lord to His people. On the orner hand, the content of Deuteronomy represents the family as the privileged place, or rather die "vehicle" by which die Torah will be handed down to the next generation.</description><creator>Leblanc, Simon</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Bible -- O.T. -- Study and teaching -- History.</subject><subject>Bible -- O.T. -- Deuteronomy -- criticism, interpretation, etc.</subject><subject>Family -- Biblical teaching.</subject><title>Le Deutéronome, la famille et la transmission de la loi en Israël ancien</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956j09k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x3554</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zd34q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Free-space optical interconnects (FSOIs) represent an attractive alternative technology for the implementation of short distance high bandwidth interconnections for applications such as massively parallel computing systems. However, FSOIs have still not been accepted commercially as an interconnect technology. Examples of obstacles preventing the commercial deployment of FSOI systems are the problem of optical alignment and the absence of optical system design tools. This thesis addresses these concerns and proposes a series of tools for the design and alignment of free-space optical links. The need for these tools was emphasised in the context of the optical design and implementation of a dense vertical-cavity surfaceemitting laser (VCSEL) based FSOI demonstrator. The link interconnected two boards separated by 83 mm through 512 optical channels giving a record channel density of 28.4 channels/mm2.</description><creator>Châteauneuf, Marc</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Design and alignment methodologies for two-dimensional free-space optical interconnects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nn66c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zd34q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d56zz80x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research examines the many different ethical issues that emerge in the health care setting with regards to prenatal diagnostic testing. Identifying the areas of clinical practice and religious counselling in need of improvements, particularly physician-client communication, is important to ensure that competent pregnant women make informed, considered choices about prenatal testing. This paper investigates the many factors that contribute to pregnant women's decision-making processes surrounding the acceptance or refusal of the maternal serum alpha-fetoprotein screen, ultrasonography, amniocentesis, chorionic villus sampling, and preimplantation diagnosis. Integrating scholarship in bioethics, religious studies, and the anthropological and sociological study of medicine, this dissertation offers a comparative analysis of religious attitudes toward prenatal diagnostic testing, describes the complexities of practical decision-making by pregnant women faced with genuine ethical dilemmas, and provides an analysis of ethical issues related to prenatal testing. This research will be of interest to scholars in religious studies and bioethics, prenatal genetic counsellors and obstetricians involved in the provision of prenatal diagnostic testing services, and specialists in women's health and reproductive decisionmaking.</description><creator>Sutton, Erica J.</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Prenatal diagnosis -- Moral and ethical aspects.</subject><subject>Prenatal diagnosis -- Religious aspects.</subject><subject>Pregnant women -- Counseling of.</subject><title>Prenatal testing and informed choice : the need for improved communication and understanding between health care professionals and pregnant women</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cj78n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zz80x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hh63sz124</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The method of fundamental solutions (MFS) is a boundary method applied to predict the geometric properties of acoustic scatterers present in a soft biological medium by modeling the medium as a randomized volume distribution of small bodies of any size and shape suspended in a fluid medium and insonified by a short pulse. MFS-based scattering techniques are derived and used to estimate scattering from non-spherical sources in Rayleigh-range as well as medium-range frequencies. The validity of the MFS is investigated by characterizing scattering from bodies of known geometry such as spheres using MFS-based techniques and comparing results to those obtained using known spherical correlation methods derived analytically. Both techniques are in good agreement. Thus, MFS-based techniques account for all types of scatterers beyond particles where solutions are limited to particle shape for which a Laplace's equation is separable. Random media with different structural properties are used to simulate fetal lamb lung parenchyma. The size and shape of tissue microscopic constituents are estimated from an analysis of the radio frequency echo signal power spectrum. Correlation functions are used to model backscatter from spherical as well as non-spherical bodies. The relationship between the backscattered power spectrum and the medium correlation function is expressed in terms of an acoustic form factor model which describes the size and shape properties of the acoustic scatterers present in the medium. Numerical results demonstrate that the form factor models vary with the size and shape of the scatterers. Using these methods it is possible to assess the effect of bodies not perfectly spherical (spheroids) present in a sample tissue on the estimation of the size of scatterers. If spheroidal bodies are present in the medium, the spherical correlation model overestimates or underestimates the size of scatterers. This is what has been observed in the lamb fetal lung. This implies that the spherical correlation model may not be sufficient to predict backscatter accurately in media containing not perfectly spherical bodies. These numerical studies have provided insight into bulk scattering from non-spherical bodies using simple and fast numerical techniques in comparison to Finite Element Methods (FEM) and Boundary Element Methods (BEM) techniques used to solved the scattering problem.</description><creator>Hakim, Souheil</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Scatter analysis using the method of fundamental solutions with applications to the sheep fetal lung</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rg59h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sz124</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80hx62q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis elaborates a so-called queued testing framework for input/output transition systems (IOTS) and demonstrates its applicability to delay-insensitive (DI) systems. IOTS are an appropriate model of systems with concurrent input and output, such as distributed systems and asynchronous circuits. We develop the queued testing framework based on the assumption that output of IOTS cannot be blocked. For this, a tester is separated into two independent processes: one applies stimuli and the other observes responses of a system under test through finite queues. We apply queued testing to DI systems, concurrent systems that are invariant under communication delays. As we prove, however, most DI systems are not robust, which means that not all input actions are acceptable (specified) in each state. The theorem is proved for a unified formalization of DI systems that considers a wide range of delay models: single-capacity buffers, queues, stacks, etc. To test DI systems, we extend the queued testing framework, which is originally elaborated for fully specified IOTS, to cover partially specified IOTS by preventing testers from sending unspecified input actions. Case studies in the thesis demonstrate that the extended queued testing framework is applicable to DI systems.</description><creator>Huo, Jiale.</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>On queued testing and its application to delay-insensitive systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zs774.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hx62q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62fb57c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The medial surface of a 3D object is comprised of the locus of centers of its maximal inscribed spheres. Interest in this representation stems from a number of interesting properties: i) it is a thin set, i.e., it contains no interior points, ii) it is nomotopic to the original shape, iii) it is invariant under rigid transformations of the object and iv) given the radius of the maximal inscribed sphere associated which each skeletal point, the object can be reconstructed exactly. Hence, it provides a compact representation while preserving the object's genus and making certain useful properties explicit, such as its local width. These properties have led to its application in a variety of domains, including the analysis and quantification of the shape of volumetric structures in medical images. Despite its popularity, its numerical computation remains non-trivial. Most algorithms are not stable with respect to small perturbations of the boundary, and heuristic measures for simplification are often introduced. The study of the medial surface is the subject of this thesis.</description><creator>Bouix, Sylvain</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>Medial surfaces</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m4055.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fb57c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30pv89n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The international year of fresh water represents the opportunity to look back at the seemingly irresistible movement toward privatization and at the devolution of State responsibilities in water and wastewater services. The welfare State appears to be increasingly ill-adapted to times dominated by globalisation and efficiency, while the market and the private corporations are presented as a panacea for solving the water crisis. But expectations of the market have not been met. This thesis analyses the debate over privatization of these services and the fondamental impacts on public values of introducing a market philosophy into this industry. Rather than witnessing a retreat of the State, its role is evolving although direct service provision is superseded by heavy regulation of the industry. In criticizing the neoclassical approach to the public good and regulation, the thesis argues that individualizing the process of valuing the public good fosters a culture of conflict and complexity that ultimately undermines our ability to formulate and achieve common goals. This creates an important accountability deficit. The need for environmental efficiency and democracy in an era of uncertainty requires that we search for means of expanding the reach of public values and thus suggests an even deeper reshaping of our governance structures, public and private.</description><creator>Proulx, Marianne</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Liability (Law)</subject><subject>Privatization.</subject><subject>Water -- Purification</subject><subject>Privatization -- Law and legislation.</subject><title>Gouvernance et imputabilité : la protection des valeurs publiques à l'ère de la privatisation des services d'eau</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128d143.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pv89n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sm63n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis provides a comprehensive review of recent developments in the economic regulation of air transport in the Asia-Pacific region. The focus is on the progressive liberalisation of the designation criteria in selected agreements. A brief historical overview is followed by a summary of the decision of the European Court of Justice in the "open skies" cases. The thesis then examines three recent Asia-Pacific agreements: the Australia - New Zealand arrangements; the APEC Multilateral agreement; and the Pacific Islands agreement. This review is followed by a discussion of some potential developments in the region that could lead to the conclusion of a new multilateral agreement between the European Union and selected Asia-Pacific States.</description><creator>McGonigle, Sean</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Aeronautics -- Law and legislation -- Asia</subject><subject>Aeronautics -- Law and legislation -- Pacific Area</subject><subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Pacific Area</subject><subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Asia</subject><title>Comparative regulation of air transport in the Asia-Pacific region</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bd881.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sm63n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wg01d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Over the last years the demand for satellite communication services has been increased. Global and domestic regulatory developments and support, as well as the emerge of new services, have facilitated launcMng capabilities and reduced the costs of manufacturing, launching and operating the satellites. Financing the telecommunication satellite systems is one of the most relevant issues that prospective satellite operators face on these days. Mstitutional lenders require adequate legal advise in order to properly instrument multimillion transactions where securitization is not enough clear and risks are extremely Mgh. TMs work analyzes the most important sources of financing of telecommunication satellites and the most adequate legal structures and methods based in legislation, legal cases, jurisprudence, doctrine, and legal practice.</description><creator>Fernández-Briseño, Raúl</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Artificial satellites in telecommunication -- Law and legislation.</subject><subject>Artificial satellites in telecommunication -- Economic aspects.</subject><subject>Space law</subject><title>Legal aspects of telecommunication satellites operation and financing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h667h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wg01d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xp68kj48f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An indirect crisis, the terrorist attacks of September 1 1 , is used as a catalyst to review the tasks of the Nuclear Nonproliferation Regime. However, it is insufficient to initiate a comprehensive change to the regime to incorporate the challenge from non-state nuclear terrorism. There will not be a change of regime, understood in terms of principles and norms. Yet, potential for change within the regime exists, with regard to rules and procedures. This is demonstrated by analysing the organisational and state levels of the regime through a synthesis of rationalist and weak-cognitivist assumptions. The organisational level is more adaptable in light of new information and more susceptible to change. Two factors limit this change. Member states will handle issues arising from the crisis outside the venue of the regime. Also, consensual knowledge among actors remains key for significant change to occur. An indirect crisis lacks the force to cultivate an epistemic community able to promote such knowledge among decision-makers.</description><creator>Thompson, Jean-Philippe</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Crises.</subject><subject>Nuclear nonproliferation.</subject><subject>Nuclear terrorism.</subject><title>Crisis and regime change : the nuclear nonproliferation regime and the challenge from nuclear terrorism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m625r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kj48f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pj48p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The increasing intermingling of civilian and military space activities could lead to serious, and perhaps unintended, consequences. While international space law is very permissive with regard to military uses of space, there are considerable legal and security implications resulting from military and civilian dependence on the same space services. From a military perspective, intentional reliance on civilian systems must address, inter alia, national security concerns, contractual obligations, licensing restrictions, liability, and long-term political relationships, while respecting the interests of the commercial sector. Policy decisions leading to an increase in civilian-military space interdependence must also consider potential impacts of this symbiosis on trade, international relations, and the conduct of armed hostilities. The thesis addresses these and certain related issues in four chapters. The first chapter explores the depth of the interdependence of military and civilian users on the same space systems. The second chapter considers the implications of dual use space technologies, such as proliferation concerns. The third chapter discusses various legal mechanisms States employ to address security issues involving space activities. The final chapter outlines legal restrictions on the use of space assets by armed forces.</description><creator>Waldrop, Elizabeth Seebode</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Astronautics, Military -- Law and legislation.</subject><subject>Space law</subject><title>Integration of military and civilian space assets : legal and national security implications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sj449.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pj48p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kw01z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study of string theory has recently opened the way to many ground-breaking ideas in theoretical physics. An aspect that had been neglected until recently concerns the role played by time in this theory. It is an important subject because of its possible connections with the field of cosmology. In the first part of this thesis we study S(pacelike)D-branes which are objects arising naturally in string theory when Dirichlet boundary conditions are imposed on the time direction. SD-brane physics is inherently time-dependent. We set up the problem of coupling the most relevant open-string tachyonic mode to massless closed-string modes in the bulk, with back-reaction and Ramond-Ramond fields included. We find solutions (numerically) that are asymptotically flat in the future but plagued with a singularity in the past. The second part of the thesis is concerned with the study of important aspects related to the proposed duality between quantum gravity in de Sitter space and a Euclidean eonformal field theory: the dS/CFT correspondence. First, we study solutions of Einstein gravity coupled to a positive cosmological constant and matter which are asymptotically de Sitter and homogeneous. These solutions are 'tall', meaning that the perturbed universe lives through enough eonformal time for an entire spherical Cauchy surface to enter any observer's past light cone. Our main focus is on the implications of tall universes for the correspondence. Particular attention is given to the associated renormalization group flows, leading to a more general de Sitter c-theorem. We also discuss the eonformal diagrams for various classes of homogeneous flows. Then, we consider the evolution of massive scalar fields in (asymptotically) de Sitter spacetimes of arbitrary dimension. Through the dS/CFT correspondence, our analysis points to the existence of new non-local dualities for the eonformal field theory.</description><creator>Leblond, Frédéric</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Physics - Theory</subject><title>Aspects of time dependence in string theory</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn107117f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kw01z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j333450g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Confidentiality is unanimously recognized to be one of the most characteristic and attractive features of international commercial arbitration. The confidential character of arbitral proceedings has often been presumed on the basis of the privacy of the hearings, but this presumption has proven ill-founded in arbitrations between private and public actors ("mixed arbitration"). National courts and international tribunals have come to recognize and to enforce a public interest exception to confidentiality based on the principle that the public has a right to be informed of the contents and outcome of the arbitral proceedings whenever the subject-matter of the dispute is of public concern. This thesis will assess the basis upon which and the limits within which the public interest exception to confidentiality might operate. The thesis will then provide an analysis of the benefits—the accommodation of moral and legal expectations of public participation—and risks—the politicization of the arbitrated dispute and disclosure of trade secrets—of greater transparency and openness in mixed arbitral proceedings. The thesis will show that the public interest exception to confidentiality is a valuable and important development along the path of democratic governance, but also that, in order to avoid the indiscriminate disclosure of information, the precise range of its application needs to be carefully defined and limited to only those cases wherein it appears to be fully justified.</description><creator>Chirichiello, Michela</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Arbitration and award, International.</subject><subject>Confidential communications.</subject><title>Confidentiality and public interest in mixed international arbitration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xk79p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j333450g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322g52d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, a new parallel synchronization mechanism, XTW, is proposed. XTW is designed for the parallel simulation of large logic circuits on a cluster of computer workstations. In XTW, a new event queue structure, XEQ, is created in order to reduce the cost of event-scheduling; a new message "un-sending" mechanism, "rb-messages", is proposed to reduce the cost of un-sending" previously sent messages. Both theoretical analysis and actual simulations provide evidence that XTW speeds up parallel logic simulations and provides excellent scalability versus the number of processors and the circuit size. An object-oriented parallel logic simulation software framework, XTWFM, is built upon the base of the XTW mechanism. A milliongates circuit, which can not be simulated by our sequential simulator, is successfully simulated by XTWFM over a cluster of 6 "small" PCs. This success demonstrates that a cluster of PCs is an attractive low-cost alternative for large scale circuit simulation.</description><creator>Xu, Qing</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>XTW, a parallel and distributed logic simulator</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580p77s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322g52d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860906x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this thesis is to demonstrate, through legal and regulatory analysis, how three non-trade issues - SPS measures, trade in GMOs and food security concerns - might result in new modem barriers to trade that might diminish the gains of freer markets. If developed countries use non-trade concerns to justify more generous domestic support in a non-decoupled way, may do as much harm to international trade as the traditional trade policies instruments did in the past. Such undesired behavior from the developed world is possible due to the inability of current WTO norms to control these new problems. These three special issues must be addressed in future negotiations in order to modify developing countries' perception that the payoffs of trade liberalization are not advantageous for them. The continuance of this perception during current negotiations might lead to the collapse of the current trading system.</description><creator>Pizarro Aliaga, Lucia</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Free trade -- Developing countries</subject><subject>International trade.</subject><subject>Produce trade -- Law and legislation -- Developing countries</subject><title>Agricultural liberalization : the case of developing countries</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644t76v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860906x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848s670</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Caenorhabditis elegans" locomotion consists of long forward crawling interrupted by short spontaneous reversals. We identified several intrinsic and extrinsic variables that influence the reversal frequency. In particular, reversal frequency can be transiently suppressed by touch. The genes glr-1 and nmr-1, which encode subunits of AMPA- and NMDA-type glutamate receptors, play a central role in touch-induced reversal suppression. Thus, reversal behavior is a motor output reflecting the integration of sensory inputs that display a form of memory. Food has a dramatic effect on reversal frequency that depends on chemosensation. Wild-type worms dramatically reduce reversal frequency on food but chemosensory mutants do not. A null allele of eat-2, a gene necessary for the proper response to food, confers a hyperreversal phenotype. eat-2 also enhances dauer formation in a serotonin deficient genetic background. These phenotypes do not appear to result from the effect of eat-2 on eating efficiency.</description><creator>Zhao, Beibei</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Caenorhabditis elegans -- Molecular genetics.</subject><subject>Caenorhabditis elegans -- Locomotion.</subject><title>Genetic analysis of reversal behavior in C. elegans</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418q34b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848s670</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w6634589g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In becoming a signatory to the World Intellectual Property Organization (WIPO) Treaties, Canada has undertaken the obligation to provide protection against the circumvention of technological measures designed to protect copyright works. While on its face the obligation appears simple, in reality it brings about an intersection of policy, law and technology; a complex situation with far reaching repercussions. The U.S., a co-signatory to the WIPO Treaties, responded to this tension by enacting the Digital Milennium Copyright Act (DMCA), which heavily regulated circumvention technology and garnered wide-spread criticism. Critics labeled the law as unpredictable and overbroad legislation, which has chilled free speech, violated fair use, stifled research and study and encouraged monopolies by eliminating competition. Drawing largely on the U.S. experience, this thesis aims to suggest a possible route for Canada to take when fulfilling its own obligations under the WIPO. It will begin with a review of the relevant provisions of the Treaties to determine the extent of Canada's obligation. It will then examine Canada's proposal papers and the responses of its citizens to the questioned posed regarding future anti-circumvention legislation. It will also examine the DMCA in detail and attempt to distil its flaws. Finally, it will investigate the extent of the need for new anti-circumvention legislation in Canada by examining Canada's existing laws dealing with the protection of technology measures. Such process will provide evidence that Canada has, to a large extent, complied with its obligations under the WIPO while maintaining the delicate balance between the stakeholders of copyright law. Thus while new anti-circumvention legislation may still be in order, Canada has the latitude to craft a law that fully recognizes the rights of all stakeholders in the copyright equation and is consistent with its own copyright policies.</description><creator>Garcia, Natanya</creator><date>2003</date><subject>World Intellectual Property Organization</subject><subject>Copyright and electronic data processing -- United States.</subject><subject>Copyright -- United States.</subject><subject>Copyright and electronic data processing -- Canada.</subject><subject>Copyright -- Electronic information resources -- Canada.</subject><subject>Copyright -- Electronic information resources -- United States.</subject><subject>Copyright -- Canada.</subject><subject>United States -- Digital Millennium Copyright Act.</subject><title>Anti-circumvention technology legislation in Canada : drafting a new law in the wake of the DMCA</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225d25v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634589g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74cs67r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis addresses the question of the application of a supra-national legal regime to the substance of disputes arising from State contracts in the context of international arbitral dispute settlement. Foreign private parties seek to subject the merits of their contractual relationships with a State arising from a State contract to a legal regime superior to the national law of the State party. Such a supra-national legal regime has been advanced through a de-localization trend in international arbitration. In the main, the de-localization trend defies a jurisdictional concept of the legal regime governing a State contract with a view to dissociating the contract from the legal jurisdiction of the State party. How paradoxical the idea of subjecting the substance of a State contract to a Stateless legal regime proves is an issue that the present thesis embarks upon.</description><creator>Falsafi, Alireza</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Contracts</subject><subject>Arbitration and award, International.</subject><title>Applicable law in state contracts : the drive to create a supranational legal regime in international arbitral dispute settlement</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hc01x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cs67r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x356d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Historical data of sea ice concentration in Canadian waters are analysed using projections methods (Principal Component Analysis, Singular Value Decomposition, Canonical Correlation Analysis and Projection on Latent Structures) to identify the main patterns of evolution in the sea ice cover. Three different areas of interest are studied: (1) the Gulf of St Lawrence, (2) the Beaufort Sea and (3) the Labrador Sea down to the east coast of Newfoundland. Forcing parameters that drive the evolution of the sea ice cover such as surface air temperature and wind field are also analysed in order to explain some of the variability observed in the sea ice field. Only qualitative correlations have been identified, essentially because of the singular nature of the sea ice concentration itself and the accuracy of available data. However, several statistical models based on identified patterns have been developed showing forecasting skills far better than those of the persistence assumption, which currently remains one of the best 'model' available. Forecasts are tested over periods of time ranging from a few days to several weeks. Some of these models constitute innovative approaches in the context of statistical sea ice forecasting. Some others models have been developed using a probabilistic approach. These models provide forecasts in terms of sea ice severity (low-medium-high), which is often accurate enough for navigation purposes for the three areas of interest. Forecasting skills of these models are also better than the persistence assumption. Finally, an existing dynamic sea-ice model has been adapted and used to predict sea ice conditions in the Gulf of St Lawrence during the Winter season 1992-1993. Simulations provided by this model are compared to the forecasts of different statistical models over the same period of time.</description><creator>Garrigues, Laurent</creator><date>2001</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Applied Mechanics</subject><title>Statistical analysis and forecasting of sea ice conditions in Canadian waters</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v990z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x356d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p096936w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The permanent mold casting process is a relatively popular and effective casting technology that can produce near-net-shape aluminum components with integrity, particularly for the automotive and aerospace industries. It is well recognized by the casting industry that it is essential to control the cooling of permanent mold castings in order to improve the quality of the castings, so there is a considerable incentive to develop a more effective method of mold cooling to control the temperature distribution of the mold and the casting. The current technologies for controlled cooling are air or water cooling passages and chill inserts. Each of these cooling methods presents certain disadvantages, and none offer optimum cooling control. Based on these considerations, a novel, effective and controllable water-based heat pipe has been successfully developed to be used as a new method of permanent mold cooling where high heat fluxes are normally encountered. Heat pipes featuring this design have been incorporated in an experimental permanent mold made of HI3 tool steel that  contains three symmetric steps. Computer modeling for the permanent mold casting process has been accomplished to predict the effect and potential of heat pipe cooling for permanent mold casting. Castings of A3 56 alloy have been produced by this permanent mold. The effects of heat pipe cooling on permanent mold castings have been evaluated by analyzing the temperature distribution of the mold and the casting, as well as by measuring the dendrite arm spacing and shrinkage distribution of the castings. The effect of heat pipe cooling on the mold solidification time of castings of A356 alloy with different coating types was also studied. Industrial trials have been carried out to evaluate this new cooling technology on an industrial scale casting machine. Because the space around the mold installed on a low pressure die casting machine is very limited, it is often very difficult to install the heat pipe in the specific desired location in the mold. A new version flexible heat pipe cooling system has been developed for the industrial casting process. Preliminary and industrial tests of the heat pipe cooling system have been performed. The effects of heat pipe cooling, as well as the effects of using traditional water and air cooling on the low pressure die casting were studied. Data on the cooling rates obtained by heat pipes, as well as some microstructures and measurements of the dendrite arm spacing are presented in this thesis. Modeling and experimental results have shown that the water based heat pipe can provide high cooling rates in casting processes. The dendrite arm spacing (DAS) of A356 alloy is refined considerably by the heat pipes, and changes in the shrinkage pattern are provided by the dramatic changes in the heat flow patterns.</description><creator>Zhang, Chunhui</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy</subject><title>Controlled cooling of permanent mold castings of aluminum alloys</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278w43s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p096936w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343v19v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The warm rolling of steels is becoming an increasingly common practice in industry. Nevertheless, the poor formability of warm rolled low carbon (LC) steels is problematic, as this property is important in deep drawing applications, which require uniform deformation. Compression tests were conducted to study the effect of chromium content on rate sensitivity (m), using two experimental LC-chromium alloys and an extralow carbon (ELC) steel. Samples were tested at various temperatures and strain rates, and the flow stress was measured for each condition. A second dynamic strain aging (DSA) peak was present in both LC-Cr alloyed steels, indicating that chromium raised the DSA temperature range into that for warm rolling. At these temperatures, the chromium addition reduced m as compared to the ELC steel, increasing the shear band content of the warm rolled microstructures. This increased shear band content modified the type and distribution of the recrystallization nuclei. Thus, it is expected that LC-Cr steels will have better formability after warm rolling than unmodified LC steels.</description><creator>Romani, Nadia Diane</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering - Metallurgy</subject><title>Effect of chromium addition on the warm rolled behaviour of low carbon steels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811km92w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343v19v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w95052590</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cold headability is the ability of a cylindrical metallic specimen to be shaped at high strain rate into the head of a bolt, screw or other cold-formed part without cracking. This property is material dependent and can be influenced by many factors such as chemical composition, surface condition, and microstructure. This project focuses on the effect of microstructure upon the cold headability of a medium carbon steel (1036M). Six different microstructures were produced by various heat treatment conditions. Drop Weight  Tower (DWT) tests, developed at McGill in 2000 by Dr. N. Nickoletopoulos, were used on samples of these materials. Visual inspection, metallographic and SEM analysis were performed to identify cracks on the surface of tested samples, and trace their cause. The axial and circumferential strains of tested samples were measured and the strains at which cracks first occurred were used to assess the cold headability. This research further indicates that DWT testing is a valid method for evaluating the cold headability of metallic materials and that the cold headability is particularly sensitive to the microstructure of a material.</description><creator>Ma, Xiaoyu</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering - Metallurgy</subject><title>Effect of microstructure on the cold headability of a medium carbon steel</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227ms075.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95052590</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zs25xb74z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Polymer clay nanocomposites (PCN) exhibit many advantages over conventional composites, while using substantially smaller quantities of filler. For various reasons, it is desirable, in nanocomposite manufacturing, to employ processes based on melt exfoliation of modified clay particles. While various researchers have studied the effects of processing variables and material properties on the effectiveness of melt exfoliation, many issues remain unresolved. This study attempts to deal with some of these. In this study an amorphous polymer, atactic polystyrene (PS), has been chosen to avoid complications related to crystallization. Three grades of (PS), having different molecular weight, were pre-blended with Cloisite® 1OA (a modified montmorillonite) in a twin-screw extruder (TSE). The TSE blends were subsequently fed to a single screw extruder, fitted with one of three specially designed attachments at the front of the screw. The attachments were designed to provide combinations of shear and elongational deformations. The resins, TSE blends, and final nanocomposites were characterized for the degree of exfoliation, mechanical properties, and rheological behavior using capillary and rotational rheometers, FTIR, XRD and TEM. The effects of molecular weight, mixing time, and levels of shear and elongational stresses, on the degree of intercalation and the properties of the nanocomposites were studied. Surprisingly, the complex and shear viscosities of the nanocomposites were found to be lower than the corresponding viscosities of the virgin polystyrene. Intercalation was achieved with in a short residence time. However, the degradation of the clay intercalant increased with residence time which causes degradation of PS.</description><creator>Nassar, Nashaat</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering - Chemical</subject><title>Melt exfoliation in montmorillonitepolystyrene nanocomposites</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j115w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xb74z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712m9018</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This master's thesis seeks to establish a comparison between the lyrical work of the Austrian Ingeborg Bachmann (1926-1973) and the Argentinean Alejandra Pizarnik (1936-1972). First, we draw from the similarities in the lives of both authors. Then, the survey of secondary literature shows that the two writers were the «black sheep» of their literary generation. Finally, our analysis focuses on the last phase of their lyrical production (1963-1966 for Bachmann; 1970-1972 for Pizarnik), most especially on two poems which are considered by the critics to be their «farewell» to poetry : «Keine Delikatessen» [No delicacies] by Bachmann (1963) and «En esta noche, en este mundo» [In this night, in this world] by Pizarnik (1971). We demonstrate that both poets show the same distrust of their medium, language, accompanied by a particular concern for silence, which appears in their respective poems both thematically and formally.</description><creator>Stratford, Madeleine</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Pizarnik, Alejandra, 1936-1972 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>Bachmann, Ingeborg, 1926-1973 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>Entre les mots et les silences : la crise créative (et existentielle) dans la dernière phase de la poésie de Ingeborg Bachmann et de Alejandra Pizarnik</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p936h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m9018</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of German Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72p937s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:25:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation explores how architecture is valorized by the cultural artifacts, both visual and text-based, which present and describe it. It examines aspects of the Gothic Revival in early Victorian Britain, to consider the assimilation of models of evolving architectural discourse by one organization with specialized interest in its promotion, and adaptations of that discourse in the realm of popular culture. The dissertation focuses on the ideology of the Cambridge Camden Society, from its inception in 1839 through to 1850. The Society advocated an appreciation of Gothic churches both for aesthetic, and for religious and moral reasons. A key dimension of its mandate, captured in the rhetoric of ecclesiology, was to prioritize an empirical investigation of extant medieval churches. Findings were to be recorded on specially-devised questionnaires, called "church schemes," using a text-based, specially-encoded taxonomy. Given the availability both of extensive documentation by the Society concerning these schemes, and of almost seven hundred completed forms, areas of conformity and divergence between the prescriptive, instructional material, and the descriptive material which indicates the actual reception of the architecture, may be discerned. "Church visiting" hence became the primary means of personal engagement with the architecture, enacted through the elaborate ritual of scripted tourism spelled out by the church schemes and attendant pedagogical documents. The importance, and the implications, of tourism to members of the Cambridge Camden Society are addressed through an evaluation of travel theories and methodologies, developed, especially, since the 1990s. An understanding of ecclesiology in terms of travel theory enables it to be evaluated in a wider context, namely as part of an emerging tourist ethos based on expanding opportunities and incentives to travel through Britain. From this perspective, the Cambridge Camden Society is to be perceived as part of a larger consortium of advocates of tourism to sights of medieval architecture, who employed similar inducements and terminology, and who created such markers of  architectural authenticity as travel guides to mediate the traveller's reception of a given sight. As a result, the possibilities of the widespread dissemination of at least the architectural components of ecclesiological ideals, as part of the groundswell of promotional material devoted to all things Gothic, were enhanced.</description><creator>Kenneally, Rhona Richman</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Travel -- History -- 19th century.</subject><subject>Anglican church buildings -- Britain.</subject><subject>Architecture, Gothic -- Britain.</subject><subject>Cambridge Camden Society</subject><subject>Ecclesiological Society</subject><title>The tempered gaze : medieval church architecture, scripted tourism, and ecclesiology in early Victorian Britain</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w458m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p937s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2750</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>