<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:25:15Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):36025" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085k85s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effects of aging on estrogen receptor (ER) levels and dynamics were assessed in hypothalamus (HYPO), pituitary (PIT), and uterus (UT) of female mice, 0-24 h following a bolus of estradiol. Nuclear ER levels were reduced and dynamics were altered in all tissues of aged mice. Age-related reductions of nuclear ER were associated with both losses of ER and reduced ability of cell nuclei to bind ER. Irrespective of age, ER dynamics differed among tissues. The duration of elevated nuclear ER was longest, and the rate of replenishment of cytosolic ER was fastest, in HYPO. Transient loss of ER was observed in UT and PIT, but not HYPO. In separate experiments involving chronic E2 exposure, tissue differences in the duration of elevated nuclear ER persisted, but all tissues exhibited ER loss. This thesis reveals age and tissue differences in ER dynamics. These differences may contribute to altered responsiveness to estrogens during aging and among tissues.</description><creator>Bergman, Mark</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Estrogen receptor dynamics and reproductive aging in female mice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988k58m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085k85s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z1495</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The properties of tubulins from Brugia malayi, B. pahangi, Nippostrongylus brasiliensis and rat brain were compared. Tubulins from all nematodes and rat brain were partially purified by polylysine agarose chromatography, those of brain also by cycles of assembly/disassembly, and all by taxol-induced assembly. The tubulins were compared with respect to concentration ($ mu$g tubulin/mg soluble protein), drugs binding and isoforms. The tubulins of B. malayi and B. pahangi were similar. However, the tubulin from these filariae were different from those of N. brasiliensis. Even larger differences were detected between the nematode tubulins and those of rat brain. However, all tubulins reacted to $ alpha$- and $ beta$-tubulin monoclonal antibodies, and had similar mobility on SDS-PAGE. Different peptide maps were obtained for N. brasiliensis tubulin compared with rat brain tubulin. Tubulins of N. brasiliensis bound more mebendazole than did those of Brugia nematodes (B$ sb{ rm max}$: pmoles/$ mu$g tubulin). The binding of benzimidazoles to nematode tubulins was much higher than to rat brain tubulin. Benzimidazole binding to brain tubulin was influenced by the degree of assembly of the tubulin. This did not appear to be the case for the nematode tubulins. In vitro translation of B. malayi mRNA resulted in two isoforms for both $ alpha$- and $ beta$-tubulins in contrast to the 4 $ alpha$- and 4-5 $ beta$-isoforms found naturally. This suggest post translational modification of tubulin may take place in B. malayi. This study has characterized some of the differences that exist between mammalian tubulins and those of nematodes on the one hand, and between the tubulins of a gastrointestinal nematode (N. brasiliensis) and those of filariae (B. malayi and B. pahangi) on the other hand.</description><creator>Tang, Liang</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Microtubules.</subject><subject>Brain -- Cytochemistry</subject><subject>Nematodes -- Research.</subject><title>Characterization of tubulins from parasitic nematodes (Brugia malayi, B. pahangi and Nippostrongylus brasiliensis) and comparison with mammalian brain tubulin</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hw00h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z1495</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s1616848</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The model of nuclear dynamics according to the Boltzmann-Uehling-Uhlenbeck (BUU) equation which incorporates fluctuations is presented. This model is employed to calculate heavy-ion reactions in the intermediate energy regime $(20 leq E sb{lab}/A leq 200MeV)$. Using a local (Skyrme-type) interaction, the model is capable of reproducing diverse features of spectator and participant observables. A finite range interaction is introduced to generate diffuse nuclear surfaces in the Vlasov approach. The peripheral reaction of $ sp{40}Ar$ on $ sp{27}Al$ is calculated with this interaction. Characteristic features of the angular distribution of the projectile-like fragments and its correlation with the target-like fragments are in agreement with experiments. The stability condition of self-consistent Vlasov solutions with a finite range interaction is derived. This condition is cast into an eigenvalue equation. The lowest eigenmodes correspond closely to giant vibration modes. The relationship of these eigenmodes to the time-dependent Vlasov equation is explored.</description><creator>Gan, Hin Hark</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Physics, Nuclear.</subject><title>A study of nuclear fragmentation at intermediate energies /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d040p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s1616848</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h5084</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this study was to determine whether formal, primary education could increase the level of ethnicity in children. One hundred Jewish children completing grade 6, and their parents, were measured on a series of instruments designed to evaluate their level of ethnic identity. Half the children had received their full education in private, parochial schools, while the other half had attended public, secular schools. The two samples were further sub-divided so that each sample consisted of 25 children of Ashkenazi descent and 25 of Sephardi descent. The data were subjected to a multivariate analysis of covariance wherein the variance attributable to the parents was partialled out. The results indicated that formal, parochial education does not effect an increase in the level of ethnicity, and that parental and community factors are the primary determinants of a child's ethnic identity. The results also demonstrate that the Sephardi children, despite their affinity to the Jewish people, have a less positive image of the Jewish community when compared to the Ashkenazi majority. The Conflict Theory model, which views the school as a mirror of the forces in society at large, was seen as the best explanation of the data.</description><creator>Hirschberg, Jack Jacob</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Jews -- Quebec (Province) -- Montreal -- Identity -- Research.</subject><subject>Jews -- Education -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><subject>Ethnicity in children -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><title>Secular and Parochial education of Ashkenazi and Sephardi Jewish children in Montreal : a study in ethnicity.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q4695.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h5084</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wd41z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines the effects of maternal teaching style on the developing problem-solving abilities of deaf and hearing preschool children. Mothers and children from three matched groups, hearing mother-deaf child, hearing mother-hearing child, and deaf mother-deaf child, were videotaped while the mother taught the child to construct a small pyramid from 21 interlocking blocks and again when the child attempted the task independently. The tapes were coded and analyzed to examine maternal instructional style and subsequent independent child performance. The mothers in the deaf mother-deaf child and hearing mother-hearing child dyads used appropriate scaffolding behavior significantly more often than the other mothers; their children were significantly more adept and independent problem-solvers than the deaf children of hearing mothers. The more contingent the mother's instructions, the more independent and successful child. Scaffolding is discussed in terms of its benefits for instructing deaf children.</description><creator>Jamieson, Janet Ruth</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Problem solving in children</subject><subject>Mother and child</subject><subject>Deaf children</subject><title>Deafness and mother-child interaction : scaffolded instruction and the learning of problem-solving skills</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526d024.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wd41z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80hw01s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The photolysis of bilirubin IX-$ alpha$ in organic solvents leads to both EZ/ZE isomers and lumirubins, with the latter being formed from the former. The relative yields of the various photoproducts is markedly dependent on the solvent. Small amounts of photoproducts are also produced on irradiation of aqueous bilirubin solutions; however, the addition of human serum albumin increases the efficiency of the photoreaction, predominantly by isomerization of bound bilirubin. The formation of photoproducts from aqueous bilirubin solutions increases the rate of adsorption onto cholestyramine but not peptide-substituted polyacrylamide resins. The photoproducts, principally lumirubins produced by irradiation of bilirubin in DMSO, are selectively adsorbed by cholestyramine. Using a semi-quantitative model it is shown that in aqueous solution the binding of derivatives of indoles and pyrroles onto cholestyramine involves electrostatic interactions as well as hydrophobic interactions. The free energy of transfer of the small molecule from water to an organic phase permits an estimation of the role of the hydrophobic interactions.</description><creator>Sailofsky, Bruce M.</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>The binding of bilirubin, photobilirubin and bilirubin model compounds by polymeric resins /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924c45h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hw01s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977v579</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Automatic analysis methods based on multichannel radiance data measured by the Advanced Very High Resolution Radiometer (AVHRR) on the NOAA7 and NOAA9 satellites are used to: (a) detect clear and cloudy areas above coastal regions; and (b) detect clouds and to estimate cloud amount above the Arctic. Channels 1 2 and 4 of the AVHRR were employed to separate clear from cloudy radiances above coastal regions. All AVHRR channels were used above the Arctic. A large number of orbits were analysed automatically and the analysis results were compared to manual analyses performed by an independent observer and to published analyses. The comparisons yield that the present algorithm provides a reliable method for the automatic detection of clouds in the Arctic.</description><creator>Sakellariou, Nikolaos</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>Identification of clear and cloudy areas from AVHRR radiances</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jp37c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977v579</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924c46s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Questionnaires were constructed to measure dieter's beliefs in their abilities to (1) adhere to a diet in eating situations, (2) perform various dieting behaviors, and (3) reach their dieting goals. The three questionnaires were called the Situation-, Behavior-, and Goal-Based Dieting Self-Efficacy Scales. Preliminary work examined the reliability of the three scales. The Situtation-Based scale demonstrated a high level of test-retest reliability over a two to four week period in the two college samples. Examination of scale intercorrelations in the clinical sample indicated that the scales were correlated at only a low level, suggesting that the scales measure different aspects of the construct of dieting self-efficacy. Results of the laboratory studies demonstrated that the Situation-Based scale was a significant predictor of how much dieters ate in response to two different types of challenges to their diets, high calorie preloads and a depressed mood induction. The ability of the three scales to predict weight changes was examined in the clinical sample. Only the Goal-Based scale was found to predict weight change. In summary, the present study adds to the body of literature supporting goal-based dieting self-efficacy as a significant predictor of weight change during dieting attempts. Suggestions were offered about ways to apply this finding to clinical practice, in the areas of patient selection and treatment prescription. The present research was limited in the following ways. The laboratory studies were limited by the narrow range of subjects, and the artificiality of the eating situation. Future research should extend this finding with other populations, as well as methodologies for examining the relation between dieting self-efficacy and eating in real-life situations. The clinical study was limited by the absence of a follow-up assessment. Future research must examine the ability of dieting self-efficacy to predict weight change over longer periods of time. Finally, suggestions were made concerning the importance of future research attempting to clarify the construct of dieting self-efficacy, particularly research aimed at determining the relation between responses to these questionnaires and the actual cognitive processes engaged in by dieters in eating situations, and over the course of their weight control efforts. (Abstract shortened with permission of author.)</description><creator>Stotland, Stephen Charles</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Dieters -- Case studies.</subject><subject>Reducing diets -- Research.</subject><title>Dieting self-efficacy : its relation to situational and long-term dieting success</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vp26t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924c46s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n583xv711</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Pd(0) catalyzed coupling reaction of o-dibromobenzene with acetylenes afforded bis acetylenic compounds which were used as precursors for the synthesis of 10, 11, 12, 13, 18 and 20-membered ring systems. The 10-membered benzo-oxadiyne ring 29 is a model compound of the core of antitumor antibiotic calichemicin $ bf{ gamma sp1 sb1}$. Molecular modeling calculations on 29 indicated the possibility of two conformers. A method for the conversion of aryl carboxylic acids to their iodides has been developed. Intermediates were prepared as model compounds towards the synthesis of the antitumor antibiotic neocarzinostatin.</description><creator>Singh, Rina</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>The synthesis of cyclic polyacetylenes /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956g52f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xv711</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m039k5624</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This is a case study, based on fieldwork research carried out in 1980-1981 and 1986-1987 among the inhabitants of Haouch Moussa ('Anjar)--a Lebanese Armenian community in the Beka'a valley of Lebanon. The study itself constitutes a reconstruction of the practices and experiences (and their genesis) of the people in question, as Lebanese and Armenians (and therefore, of my own history as a Lebanese and an Armenian (and a woman)). The settlement itself was established in 1939 by Armenian refugees deported from their original habitat in Mount Moussa, the Sanjak of Iskandaroun (Turkey). When relocated in the Central Beka'a the inhabitants initiated a collectivisation experiment. However, it was brought to an end shortly after Lebanese Independence. During the following decades, while the socialist ideology has persisted the individual households have at first become petty commodity producers for a regional, national and international market, and later through the dynamics of petty commodity production, capitalism, and the effects of the civil war in Lebanon further transformations have occurred. This thesis examines these transformations and attempts to translate the dynamics of the reality of the inhabitants of 'Anjar into anthropological discourse.</description><creator>Aprahamian, Sima</creator><date>1989</date><subject>ʻAnjar (Lebanon) -- Social conditions -- 20th century</subject><subject>Armenians -- Lebanon -- ʻAnjar -- Economic conditions</subject><subject>Armenians -- Lebanon -- ʻAnjar -- Social conditions</subject><subject>ʻAnjar (Lebanon) -- Economic conditions -- 20th century</subject><title>The inhabitants of Haouch Moussa : from stratified society through classlessness to the re-appearance of social classes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w297w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k5624</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rb68xc49j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation consists of three essays in international asset pricing. The first essay develops a model where investors face barriers to foreign portfolio investment. Using the standard mean-variance framework, risk return relationships for all securities are developed. It is also shown that: (1) previous models adopting this approach are special cases of this model, and (2) all investors generally prefer complete removal of barriers over other market structures. Essay #2 empirically explores the issue of the degree of segmentation of the international capital market for risky securities. Using the 'emerging market' (EM) data base, it is shown that the international capital market is neither completely segmented nor completely integrated. Finally, the third essay investigates the relationship between stock returns and inflation for the EM securities. It is shown that stock returns are positively (negatively) related to inflation, for the group of high (low) inflation countries in the sample.</description><creator>Padmanabhan, Prasad</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Inflation (Finance)</subject><subject>Pricing.</subject><subject>Securities</subject><subject>Investments, Foreign.</subject><subject>Stock exchanges</subject><title>Three essays in international asset pricing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pr005.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xc49j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78tc698</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The reaction of a series of 1,1-disubstituted-1-silacyclo-3-pentenes with butyllithium reagents was studied. This reaction depends critically on the substituent at silicon. 1,1-Dimethyl- or 1,1-diphenyl-1-silacyclo-3-pentene has the propensity to undergo anionic polymerization whereas 1,1-bis(4-tert-butylphenyl)-1-silacyclo-3-pentene was metalated cleanly to give the anion derived from proton abstraction on the cyclopentenyl ring. The regioselectivity of the reaction of the silacyclopentenyl anion with electrophiles was examined and found to be influenced by the steric size of the electrophile. Small electrophiles favor $ alpha$-selection while larger ones show slight $ gamma$-preference. The regiochemistry of reactions of $ alpha$-silylallyl lithium with alkyl halides can be controlled with metal-ion complexing substituents on silicon to give selectively the $ alpha$-substituted allylsilane. The extent of $ alpha$-selection depends significantly on the nature of the ligand and solvent. Allyl (bis(2-ethoxyethyl)aminomethyl) dimethylsilane gives higher $ alpha$-selection than allylsilanes with fewer binding heteroatoms. When the ligand is chiral the alkylation reaction also proceeds stereoselectively. Changing the solvent from tetrahydrofuran to diethyl ether further increases the yield of the $ alpha$-isomer. The synthetic utility of these silyl-ligands was demonstrated by an application to the synthesis of $ alpha$-(E)-bisabolene.</description><creator>Horvath, Raymond Frank</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Regiochemical control in alkylation reactions of a-silylallyl carbanions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956g53q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tc698</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6q182k851</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation considers the history and philosophy of emergent evolution, and in particular the attempt to answer the question of the role of qualitative novelty in the evolutionary process. Chapter one examines the background to the theory of emergent evolution in the work of Charles Darwin. It is argued that Darwin's theory is neither tautologous nor revolutionary, and the application of Thomas Kuhn's theory of scientific revolution to the case of Darwinian evolution is criticized. Chapter two analyzes the work of the comparative psychologist Conwy Lloyd Morgan, and his views on qualitative novelty are compared with those of other major contemporaneous emergentist theorists: Samuel Alexander, C. D. Broad and Roy Wood Sellars. Chapter three discusses the history of emergent evolution as a philosophical trend, up to and including the emergent materialism of Mario Bunge. An alternative emergentist view of the level structure of reality based on the four levels of matter, life, society and mind is proposed in the conclusion.</description><creator>Blitz, David</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Evolution</subject><title>Emergent evolution : the problem of qualitative novelty in the evolutionary process</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999735x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182k851</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qf85nb85s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The tonoplast H$ sp+$-ATPase of Beta vulgaris L. was partially purified by Triton X-100 solubilization and Sepharose 4B chromatography resulting in the enrichment of two polypeptides (57 and 67 kDa). Kinetic analysis of ($ alpha$-$ sp{32}$P) BzATP labeling identified the 57 kDa polypeptide as a nucleotide-binding subunit with a possible regulatory function. In addition, ($ sp{14}$C) DCCD-labeling identified a 16 kDa polypeptide as a putative transmembrane proton channel. It is concluded that the tonoplast H$ sp+$-ATPase is a multimer composed of at least three polypeptides. Anti-57 and anti-67 kDa sera reacted with polypeptides of the corresponding size in bovine chromaffin granules, bovine clathrin-coated vesicles, and yeast vacuolar membranes, suggesting common structural features and common ancestry for endomembrane H$ sp+$-ATPases of different organelles and different phyla. Anti-57 serum was used to isolate a cDNA encoding the corresponding subunit from Arabidopsis. Protein sequence analysis revealed homologies between endomembrane, F$ sb0$F$ sb1$ and archaebacterial ATPases, suggesting that these different classes of ATPases have evolved from a common ancestor.</description><creator>Manolson, Morris F.</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Adenosine triphosphatase.</subject><subject>Plant vacuoles.</subject><title>Characterization of the vacuolar H r-AtPase of higher plants</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qj401.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nb85s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qq245</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Interactions among stationary planetary waves in the winter stratosphere are studied using steady-state quasi-geostrophic models from both a theoretical and numerical point of view. A triad of small amplitude waves is examined analytically using a constant zonal wind $ beta$-plane model in which dissipation is required for the waves to interact. The nature of the modifications to the linear solutions is found to depend both on the propagation characteristics and the zonal wavenumber of the modes. Numerical solutions are determined using a climatological basic state and boundary forcing. The changes to the linear structure are relatively weak. Zonal wavenumber 1 is the most affected, experiencing primarily an increase in amplitude in the vicinity of 65$ sp circ$N, 26 km. As a direct consequence of the almost linear relationship found to exist between the zonal streamfunction and the zonal potential vorticity in middle and northerly latitudes, the wave-wave interactions are, to a first approximation, dissipation-induced. The presence of weak dissipation in this region implies only weak interactions, which explains the quasi-linear structure of the solutions.</description><creator>McLandress, Charles</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>A study of wave-wave interactions in a steady-state stratospheric model /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rp34r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qq245</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b5919156</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Programming a robotic workcell involves much more than simply writing a program for each element, because the operations to be performed are tightly coupled by precedence constraints on their time ordering, and by constraints associated with the shared resources. The situation is further complicated because robotic workcells are typically configured to repetitively perform a desired application; we would therefore like to optimize the order in which operations take place, so as to minimize the total time required. But even when the operations have deterministic outcomes, there may exist alternative sequences with different durations, due to non-determinism in the workcell sequencing problem itself. In this dissertation, we introduce a classification of sequencing problems according to the presence of non-determinism. We then develop a particular model of workcell behavior called the Constraints Net, based on the Timed Petri Net of Ramchandani. Some new results are presented about the relationship between repetitive runtime behavior and the strong connectivity of the CN. We then define strong reducibility as the graph-theoretic property associated with modelling conflict in a meaningful way. Existing descriptions of repetitive behavior in the Petri Net literature are unified and extended. We conclude with a description of a Prolog-based decision support system called SAGE (Sequence Analysis by Graphical Evaluation) which resolves non-determinism in the user description by exploring the consequences of alternate orderings of workcell operations, and ultimately constructs the time-optimal sequence to be used by the workcell runtime environment. The analysis and optimization is illustrated with an example implemented in our laboratory.</description><creator>Freedman, Paul</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Optimal sequencing of workcell operations with deterministic outcomes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52j871j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b5919156</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8049g5788</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The principles of Tribology are introduced to the general problem of tyre-soil interaction with a view to development of a better knowledge of the manner in which the tyre-soil interface behaves under rolling motion subjected to tractive force. In essence, an analytical model based on the finite element method is developed to evaluate the tyre-soil longitudinal slippage in connection with the tractive applied torque. The following major considerations are included in the proposed model: (1) A quasi-static finite element approach to cope with the actual dynamic behaviour of the tyre-soil interface. (2) Implementing the tyre tread effect in terms of an equivalent constrictive relationship for the entire contact patch. (3) Simulating the tyre motion effect on the subsoil media. The experimental program of this study has two main objectives: (1) Seeks verifications of the proposed analytical model. (2) Evaluates the tread effect on the general performance of pneumatic tyres moving on soft soil. The behaviour of the proposed model is presented in terms of the local variation of the longitudinal slip velocity, coefficient of friction, shear stress and developed relative displacement along the tyre-soil interface for different boundary conditions and for different interface features (buffed/treaded). The role of the tyre constant translational velocity is discussed and a linkage between the laboratory velocity and the actual field velocity is suggested. Finally, the applicability of the proposed model is demonstrated and the general practical usage is outlined.</description><creator>Foda, Mohamed A.</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Analysis and prediction of tyre-soil longitudinal slippage using the finite element method</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn009z51x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g5788</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860769s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Neisseria meningitidis is able to utilize a variety of biologically relevant compounds as its sole source of sulphur. Sulphate transport in the meningococcus is temperature-, pH-, concentration-, and energy-dependent. Group VI anions and sulphur-containing amino acids affect sulphate uptake. Selenate is a competitive inhibitor of sulphate transport and enters the meningococcus via the sulphate transporter. L-cysteine, a noncompetitive inhibitor of sulphate transport, exerts allosteric control on the system. L-cysteine has its own energy-dependent uptake system. Thiocyanate, a unique sulphur source for a heterotrophic bacterium, appears to be transported in the meningococcus by a system other than that for sulphate or L-cysteine uptake. Sulphur starvation enhances transport capacity and causes variations in some of the enzymes in the meningococcus. The sulphur source used for growth causes changes in the protein profiles of the envelope and cytosol fractions. The soluble sulphur pool in N. meningitidis regulates transport and metabolism of sulphur-containing compounds. The presence of thiosulphate reductase may be to allow thiosulphate to serve as an alternate electron acceptor during in vivo anaerobic growth.</description><creator>Port, Jennifer L.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><title>Sulphur acquisition in Neisseria meningitidis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623d277.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860769s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827c458</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The ability to generate different responses, and the ability to inhibit inappropriate behaviour, were explored in patients with unilateral cerebral excisions. Site-of-lesion effects were found to interact with the sex of the subject, the time of test-administration, and the nature of the response criteria. In Part I, the Thurstone Word Fluency Test revealed impairments two weeks postoperatively in patients with frontal, temporal, or central-area lesions. In men, removals from the left cerebral hemisphere caused greater deficits than removals from the right, but only left central-area excisions resulted in long-lasting impairments. Patients with left frontal-lobe removals produced few words on a sentence-completion fluency task, but on visual-image fluency, no patient-group was impaired. In Part II, an inability to inhibit impulsive actions on risk-taking tasks was seen after frontal lobectomy, as was a tendency to disregard the instructions on a word-fluency task. These results are consistent with the fact that patients with frontal-lobe lesions described themselves on a behavioural-trait questionnaire as less flexible and more impulsive than did control subjects.</description><creator>Miller, Laurie Ann</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Frontal lobotomy.</subject><subject>Frontal lobes.</subject><subject>Impulse.</subject><subject>Response consistency.</subject><title>The ability to generate or inhibit responses after frontal lobectomy /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pt42j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827c458</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qm669</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this research was to design and evaluate an instrumental method for electroanalysis in highly resistive media. A coulostatic detector for high performance liquid chromatography was designed and constructed. Equations were developed to describe the detector's performance under regenerative and nonregenerative experimental conditions. With mobile phases of high resistance, the detector was found to respond to both electroactive and ionic electroinactive species with the magnitude of the observed signal depending on the recent history of the electrode. Thus, the elimination of iR drop by the coulostatic method does not provide a straightforward method for electroanalysis in highly resistive media. At low electrolyte concentrations, double-layer effects become prominent. A method was devised to quantitate the static double-layer effect at solid electrodes.</description><creator>Mikkelsen, Susan R.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Electrochemical apparatus -- Design and construction</subject><subject>Electrochemical analysis -- Computer simulation</subject><title>Electroanalysis in highly resistive media</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623hz39w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qm669</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8049g579j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the sixties decade, the literature of Quebec is marked by the emergence of the works of women writers who give precedence to the female protagonist. Thus, contrary to her counterpart prior to 1960, the fictitious woman of the sixties is no longer relegated to the background of the novel. This image of the female as a principal character around whom all the elements of the narrative unfold is new to our literature. Our writers seem to desire, consciously or not, to create heroines who are more than mere props for their husbands or their children. Furthermore, these heroines are portrayed as rarely having access to happiness. Indeed, more often than not, they are described as unhappy. Their distress seems to spring from the fact that their family and their milieu persist in defining them, symbolically or concretely, as inferior beings. Their world is a masculine one governed by patriarchal law. Our authors take great care in showing us that it is this law that transforms many of their female characters into figures who tend to submit to the prevalent attitudes and mores of their time. These heroines lead repetitively dismal and somber lives. From one narrative to the next, the central character expresses feelings of unworthiness, of hatred of self and of others that often culminates in mental instability. Concurrently, certain protagonists are shown to rebel against traditional female roles. In doing so, they illustrate a new kind of character in our literature. One does not find in these works the representation of the following myths: the good mother, the faithful wife, the submissive daughter, the inconsolable widow, the charitable nun. The new depictions of the female protagonist have a great symbolic value for they show that women authors of the sixties repudiate old models and elaborate an image of the heroine that is absolutely novel to our fiction. Indeed, in recognizing their condition of servitude and in breaking the traditional mould, these characters illustrate a freedom never before accorded to women in our literature. This transformation of the female character as detailed in these works foreshadows the writings authored by Quebecois women in the following decades.</description><creator>Brown, Anne</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Women in literature</subject><subject>French-Canadian literature -- Québec (Province) -- History and criticism</subject><title>L'image de la femme dans le roman féminin québécois de 1960 à 1970</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161685j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g579j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967439h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The major aim of this thesis has been to contribute to the understanding of the CH$ sb2$/OH/NH$ sb2$ group interactions by means of studies of alcohol-amine mixtures in the gas and liquid phases. To study these interactions in the gas phase a Burnett type equipment was designed, built and operated at low pressure, obtaining experimental pressure-temperature (P-T) data for various systems including alcohol-amylamine mixtures. The P-T data were reduced by a method developed in this work to give values of second virial coefficients. Measurements on known systems were in excellent agreement with values reported in the literature. A group contribution method for predicting pure compounds and interaction second virial coefficients is presented. This method is equal, or superior to methods already available. To study the CH$ sb2$/OH/NH$ sb2$ group interactions in the liquid phase, vapor-liquid-equilibrium (VLE) experiments with alcohol-amylamine mixtures were carried out in a Van Ness type apparatus. The raw data were reduced by a novel model free method using the second virial coefficients obtained previously for these mixtures. A group contribution method for predicting vapor-liquid-equilibria of multicomponent multigroup mixtures is proposed. Excellent predictions are obtained with this method. Finally, computer experiments of Lennard-Jones fluid mixtures were carried out to help in the understanding of the local composition concept. This concept is of fundamental importance not only in the models used in this work but also in numerous other solution models.</description><creator>Abusleme, Julio A.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Amino alcohols -- Thermodynamics</subject><subject>Vapor-liquid equilibrium -- Computer simulation</subject><title>Measurements, models and simulations in mixtures : thermodynamics of aminealcohol binary systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881m655.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967439h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tv81h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Reevaluation of organosulfur heats of formation resulted in the conclusion that the sulfur-sulfur bond of aliphatic disulfides is nearly 15 Kcal/mole stronger than the disulfide carbon-sulfur bond energy. Semi-empirical calculations using AM1, MNDO and MINDO/3 from the AMPAC program package confirmed these results and clarified their relative impact on organosulfide and disulfide properties. Existing organoselenium bond energy data were also reevaluated and erroneous assumptions discovered. New bond energy estimates were made via a new procedure. It was concluded that the selenium-selenium bond is also stronger than the selenium-carbon of aliphatic diselenides. The above results led to the conclusion that loss of molecular dichalcogen from molecules such as disulfides or diselenides is favored over the stepwise loss of a single chalcogen by about 40 Kcal/mol. Loss of molecular diselenium from dibenzyl diselenide is reported. The average carbon-selenium bond energy of the latter is calculated to be only 27 Kcal/mol. The preparation of 2-thiatriselenides (RSeSSeR) and 2,3-dithiatetraselenides (RSeSSSeR) has been achieved from selenosilanes. The products were characterized by $ sp{77}$Se NMR and the trends of chemical shifts were analyzed. The preparation of the first selenium transfer reagents, including the first unsymmetrical chalcogen transfer reagent, is reported. Their use to effect the synthesis of 2-selenatrisulfides (RSSeSR) is also reported. Low temperature $ sp{77}$Se NMR was used to elucidate the reaction mechanism and characterize several intermediates such as selenuranes, selenonium ions and azole selenides. In addition, 2,3-diselenatetrasulfides (RSSeSeSR) were characterized by $ sp{77}$Se NMR.</description><creator>Ryan, M. Dominic (Michael Dominic)</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Organoselenium compounds -- Structure.</subject><subject>Selenium -- Structure.</subject><subject>Organosulfur compounds -- Structure.</subject><subject>Chalcogenides.</subject><title>Organopolychalcogenides, new bond energy results and synthesis via the first selenium transfer reagent</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t2601.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tv81h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bc248</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A data structure editor is presented for use in an integrated, fragment-based programming environment. This editor employs high resolution computer graphics to present the user with an iconic representation of the internal storage of a running program. The editor allows the creation, modification, and deletion of data structures. These abilities allow the user to quickly sketch data structures with which to test incomplete program fragments, alleviating the need for driver routines. To keep the user cognizant of events inside his program, a technique for automated display management is presented allowing the user to keep the most important objects in the viewport at all times. A history facility permits the user to see the former values of all variables. Execution controls are provided allowing the user to control the scope and speed of execution, manipulate frames on the run-time stack, set breakpoints, and profile the executing algorithm.</description><creator>Robson, R.</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Data structures (Computer science)</subject><subject>Modula-2 (Computer program language) -- Research.</subject><subject>Computer programming -- Management.</subject><title>Data views for a programming environment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623d28h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bc248</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c823j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:56:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores the visual functions of the right anterior temporal cortex of the human brain. In Part 1, 92 patients with unilateral temporal- or frontal-lobe excisions and 35 normal control subjects were tested under two experimental conditions (global, local) of a reaction-time task, employing hierarchically structured letters or designs as stimuli. In both versions, the right temporal-lobe group was less affected than other groups by interference from the global aspect of the stimulus. These findings support the hypothesis that the right temporal lobe contributes to global visual processing. In Part 2, the ability to learn a cue-system for discriminating between two targets against a background of visually similar items was examined in 107 patients with unilateral temporal- or frontal-lobe excisions and 37 control subjects, using three versions of a visual-cue learning task. With letters and nonsense syllables, all groups took longer to complete the task when the background information was changed after three learning trials. With abstract designs, only patients with right temporal-lobe lesions failed to show this interference effect after three learning trials, but did so after six. Hence, it is argued that the right temporal lobe plays a role in visual pattern-discrimination learning.</description><creator>Doyon, Julien</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Brain -- Localization of functions.</subject><subject>Visual perception -- Testing.</subject><subject>Visual cortex.</subject><title>Right temporal-lobe contribution to global visual processing and visual-cue learning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bf65p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c823j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):36050</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>