<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:39:11Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):39050" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3f4627397</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Drawing on the manuscript records of the Department of Crown Lands, its published reports, and case law, this thesis examines the illegal occupation of rural land, known as squatting in the Eastern Townships of Quebec in the period 1838 to 1866. By 1838, demographic pressure in the seigneuries, inflated land prices due to speculation, and inaccessible public land granting practices had made squatting a commonplace strategy for land acquisition. The responses to squatting of the Department of Crown Lands, the Legislature and the judiciary are analysed for what they implied about ideas of property in Lower Canada. While the Department of Crown Lands' policy of pre-emption affirmed that squatters held rights to public land because they laboured to cultivate and improve it, the legislature refused to acknowledge that squatters could acquire such rights on private land; nine out of ten bills intended to ensure ejected squatters a systematically determined remuneration for improvements made by them on the private property of absentees failed to pass into law during the period. Most were rejected by the Legislative Council which defended the interests of landed wealth. Lower Canadian courts, meanwhile, struggled to sort out laws relating to squatting. Ultimately they found that while squatters on private property owned their improvements, they had no right to the land itself. Thus the judiciary applied a bifurcated concept of property to rural land in Lower Canada despite the prevalence of liberal theories of absolute property rights during the nineteenth century.</description><creator>Whan, Eric.</creator><contributor>Young, Brian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Squatters -- Québec (Province) -- Eastern Townships -- History.</subject><subject>Land tenure -- Québec (Province) -- Eastern Townships -- History.</subject><subject>Eastern Townships (Québec) -- Rural conditions -- History -- 19th century.</subject><subject>Squatter settlements -- Québec (Province) -- Eastern Townships -- History.</subject><title>Improper property : squatters and the idea of property in the Eastern Townships of Lower Canada, 1838-1866</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vq44z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f4627397</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1j92g9360</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In 1991, a project was initiated at Quinn and Ormstown, two sites with soils representative of Quebec's present-day agriculture. Three field management techniques were studied related to their possible impact on the soils: tillage, rotation, and N fertilization. The three treatments were randomly assigned in two blocks of a split-split-plot design. The main treatment, tillage, had two levels, conventional tillage (CT) and no-till (NT). The sub-treatment was represented by five 4-year rotations, starting from 1991 as follows: CCCC (continuous corn), CSAC (corn-soybean-alfalfa-corn), CSCS (corn-soybean-corn-soybean), SCSC (soybean-corn-soybean-corn) and SSSS (soybean monocrop). The third factor was N fertilization, at three different rates: 0, 90, and 180 kg/ha, excepting the continuous soybeans which received lower rates of, respectively, 0, 20 and 40 kg N/ha. Soil sampling was performed in 1994, during the last year of the 4-year rotations, at two different moments over the growing season, June and August, for all analysed soil properties, except aggregate stability and organic matter for which samples were taken only in September. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Vig-Dinescu, Ina.</creator><contributor>Mehuys, Guy R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Tillage -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Crop rotation -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Nitrogen fertilizers -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Soil physics -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>No-tillage -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>Tillage, rotation, and N fertilizer rate effects on surface soil physical properties</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k461w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g9360</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z316q346z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The development of pre-conception and post-conception reproductive technologies has substantial implications and consequences for women. To better establish the impact of the eugenic and sexist traditions which support the elimination of disability/defect and the propagation of "designer babies," a survey of literature outlining the scientific, feminist, legal, cultural, and social perspectives regarding new reproductive technologies was undertaken. Three conclusions of this review are that while new reproductive technologies are not responsible for the environment which fosters bias and intolerance towards oppressed members of society, they have created eugenic demands by supporting genetic perfection; they have informally displaced women's rights to bodily autonomy in favour of the fetus' or potential future person's rights by supporting fetal personhood; and they have perpetuated sexism within the Indian community in Canada by supporting patriarchal institutions.</description><creator>Misri, Anita P.</creator><contributor>Nichols, Barbara (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Feminist theory.</subject><subject>Sex of children, Parental preferences for -- Social aspects.</subject><subject>Human reproductive technology -- Social aspects.</subject><title>A feminist interpretation of the implications and consequences of new reproductive technologies /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j3079.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q346z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042v928</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>While the study of non-composite castellated beams have received much attention, very little work has been done on composite castellated beams. The effect of the composite concrete slab is to significantly increase the flexural resistance of a steel section; it is however uncertain what effect this will have on the shear resistance. In this research project tests to destruction of five composite castellated beams were performed, and relate to previous tests on non-composite castellated beams. Ultimate failure loads of the three shear critical test beams were associated with web-post buckling, comprising double curvature bending. The remaining two flexural test beams failed when most of the studs in one-half of the span failed, resulting in lateral torsional buckling of the suddenly unconstrained flange. A numerical study using the finite element method was then employed in investigating the nonlinear buckling behavior of the web-posts in shear critical composite and non-composite castellated beams. Buckling of the web-posts was observed to be the dominant mode of failure in all finite element models; the composite beams were found to have significantly higher ultimate shear carrying capacities than their non-composite counterparts. It was found that the effect of the composite slab is to reduce the shear force in the web-posts, thus increasing the beam ultimate shear carrying capacity. Finally, yield analyses were performed on castellated beams using moment-to-shear interaction diagrams originally developed for isolated web openings. Results based on yield failures were found to be in good agreement with the test failure loads for the flexure critical beams. Yield analysis tended to slightly overestimate the failure loads for the shear critical composite test beams, due largely to the buckling failures of the web-posts in the tests. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Megharief, Jihad Dokali.</creator><contributor>Redwood, R. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Behavior of composite castellated beams</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816p46q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042v928</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429c24q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The quasi-steady-state ignition temperature was measured for the following metal-sulfur compounds: Cr-S, Mo-S, Mg-S, Mn-S, Si-S, Ti-S and Zn-S. The ignition temperatures for these mixtures ranged from 350$ sp circ$C to 600$ sp circ$C. For a same element (Mn) an increase in particle size of the metal reactant caused an increase in the ignition temperature of the mixture. For the Mn + S system, preliminary estimates using classical thermal explosion theory indicate that an apparently low activation energy reaction is present. Estimates of the activation energy derived from the results of transient ignition experiments involving Mn-S and Cr-S mixtures with large metal particle reactants yield similar low values. It is suggested that the classical method of solution using a high-activation energy assumption to solve the heat conduction equation modeling the reaction may be inappropriate. Modifications to the zeroth-order reaction term in the model which incorporate reactant consumption, diffusion kinetics or two-step reactions could improve modeling results.</description><creator>Mizera, Michel Adam.</creator><contributor>Lee, John H. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Ignition temperature measurements of metallic sulfides in SHS processes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b5300.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429c24q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h646r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The first part of this thesis reviews in detail the state of stress due to pore water pressure, and effective stress methods in wet grounds in an attempt to present a global perspective on the subject. Through the second part of the thesis, a 2-dimensional finite element program has been developed for stress and stability analysis of wet rock and soil masses. The program uses the effective stress method which allows for a unified approach for dry and wet analysis. It computes the displacements, effective stresses and excess pore water pressure. Safety levels are then calculated in the postprocessor using rock and soil ultimate strength parameters. Three failure criteria are available. These are: Mohr-Coulomb and Hoek-Brown. The effective stress method used allows for the computation of pore water effect due to both volumetric and deviatoric changes. A case study of an open mine slope has been carried out to demonstrate the application of the developed program to practical problems.</description><creator>Mohammed, Marwan M.</creator><contributor>Mitri, H. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Effects of groundwater on stability of rock and soil slopes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cg38k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h646r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r9675706</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Isolated high grade and low tonnage uranium ore pods are prevalent in Saskatchewan. This thesis reviews mining such a pod with both conventional and unconventional methods. The geomechanical characteristics of the overburden and the bedrock in the area of the pods must be investigated before evaluating the technical feasibility of possible mining methods. Conventional ore recovery techniques appraised include open pit and underground mining. The unconventional mining techniques considered are blind boring and jet boring from surface. These last two techniques can offer a greater degree of selectivity, although ground reinforcement techniques had to be considered due to the poor quality of the ground. Ground reinforcement techniques considered were shaft lining, grouting, and ground freezing. This mining design challenge was found to be feasible with the combination of jet boring and freezing. Recommendations are presented to define future areas of study for blind boring, jet boring, grouting, and freezing.</description><creator>Morrish, Colin.</creator><contributor>Scoble, Malcolm (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Mitri, Hani (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Mining techniques for uranium ore pod recovery</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311r335.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r9675706</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jn275</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Caseins are present in milk in the form of large spherical complexes called micelles that are stabilized by kappa-casein found on the surface. This stabilizing effect is lost when milk clotting enzymes hydrolyze kappa-casein thereby initiating the coagulation process. The objective of this study was to analyze the effect of kappa-casein polymorphism upon hydrolysis by proteases. The A and B forms are the most common genetic variants of kappa-casein in Canadian Holstein dairy herds, representing three phenotypes AA, AB and BB. Whole casein from Holstein milk samples was fractionated into its four major components by ion-exchange chromatography using Express Ion Exchanger Q Anion Exchanger and Macro-Prep High Q Anion Exchange Support columns. The kappa-casein fraction was isolated, dialyzed, and assessed for its phenotype and purity by PAGE. The pure forms of the three different phenotypes of kappa-casein (AA, AB, BB) at a final concentration of 0.5% were then hydrolyzed by calf chymosin (1:500) and porcine pepsin (1:1000) at a pH of 5.8 at 37°C. Aliquots were collected at 0, 5, 15, 30, 60 and 90 min and the reaction stopped by using 24% NH4OH. The rate of hydrolysis of the three phenotypes was analyzed by comparing the disappearance of the substrate with time from the RP-HPLC chromatograms using Waters MAXIMA software. SDS-PAGE was used to calculate the approximate molecular weight of the hydrolytic products. Analysis of the hydrolysate profiles indicated that there was significant difference (P &lt; 0.05) in the rate of hydrolysis between the phenotypes. Under the present conditions at a pH of 5.8, the AA phenotype showed a significantly slower rate of hydrolysis by both chymosin and pepsin, than the other two phenotypes. There was no significant difference in the rate of hydrolysis between the phenotypes AB and BB during chymosin hydrolysis. The BB phenotype is hydrolyzed more extensively and the AB phenotype is intermediate between the two variants in the p</description><creator>Jefferson, Julius J.</creator><contributor>Ng-Kwai-Hang, K. F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Chymosin.</subject><subject>Genetic polymorphisms.</subject><subject>Casein.</subject><subject>Pepsin.</subject><title>Effect of genetic variants on hydrolysis of bovine k-casein by chymosin and pepsin</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375z17t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jn275</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306t0926</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Objectives. To determine whether the emergency psychiatric treatment of patients with psychosis varies with immigrant status and ethnicity. Methods. Data on immigrant and ethnic status of psychotic patients admitted in 1999 were extracted from records of a general hospital in Montreal. Of the 217 subjects, 97 (44.7%) were immigrants, 125 were Euro-Canadian (57.6%),39 were Asian (18.0%), and 27 were Black (12.4%). All Asians and most Blacks (87%) were immigrants. Measures of emergency psychiatric treatment included use of seclusion, restraints, and medication in the emergency department. Multiple regression models examined the relationship of immigrant status and ethnicity to emergency psychiatric treatment controlling for age, gender, patient height and weight, and mode of emergency department admission (coercive versus non-coercive). Results. Immigrant status and Asian ethnicity were not associated with emergency treatment measures. Coercive mode of emergency department admission (i.e. by police or ambulance) predicted use of seclusion (p &lt; .001) and restraints (p &lt; .05), but being Black was independently and positively associated with received dose of emergency antipsychotic (p &lt; .05). Being Black was also positively associated with police or ambulance contact prior to emergency department presentation (p &lt; .01). Conclusion. While some aspects of the emergency treatment of psychosis seem to occur as a consequence of the mode of admission, the administration of antipsychotic medication may be motivated by patient ethnicity. These results point to the need for training of emergency department staff to reduce potential bias in treatment.</description><creator>Jarvis, G. Eric.</creator><contributor>Kirmayer, Laurence J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Sociology, Ethnic and Racial Studies.</subject><subject>Psychology, Clinical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health.</subject><title>Emergency psychiatric treatment of immigrants with psychosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/707959483.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t0926</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n583xw76m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Over the years, epithelial cells of the male reproductive tract have been suggested to be involved in apocrine secretion. However, this method of secretion has not been fully accepted, nor is it well understood. In the present study, apocrine secretion was examined in the mouse epididymis and rat and human vas deferens. Throughout these regions of the duct, the apex of the epithelial principal cells often shows protrusions extending towards the lumen of the duct, referred to as apical blebs (ABs). Of different shapes and sizes, ABs appear to form at the apex of principal cells, and morphological and immunocytochemical evidence suggests that ABs detach from the cell surface whereupon they eventually undergo fragmentation in the lumen. ABs contain selective organelles suggesting a segregation of their contents. Numerous polysomes suggest the synthesis of nonglycosylated proteins which upon the fragmentation of ABs in the lumen could act directly or indirectly on sperm. The presence of spherical vesicles of various sizes (20--200mn) within ABs as well as within the lumen of the duct supports AB fragmentation in the lumen and may play a role in modifying the sperm surface. Taken together the data provide strong evidence for apocrine secretion that could play important roles in relation to sperm maturation, viability and protection.</description><creator>Jacks, Duncan.</creator><contributor>Hermo, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Apocrine secretion in the mouse epididymis and rat and human vas deferens</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv9354746.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xw76m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qr411</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Phosphorous concentrations exceed water quality guidelines in most of the major rivers in southern Quebec. The problem is particularly acute in the Pike River, which drains into the Missisquoi Bay of Lake Champlain, in southeastern Quebec. Elevated phosphorus concentrations can lead to a reduction in the palatability of drinking water, a decrease in diversity of aquatic life and loss of recreational opportunities. All of these problems have been observed in the Bay. Two agricultural fields (the Marchand and Gagnon sites) located on the Pike River watershed, in southeastern Quebec were selected and equipped with instrumentation to measure and evaluate the partitioning of phosphorus between surface runoff and subsurface drainage, on a year round basis. The snowmelt event was the dominant surface and subsurface event for the 2000/2001 hydrological year. On the Marchand site surface flow data was incomplete as a result of a failure of the surface runoff flume. On both sites the IF 200 subsurface flow meters failed, which resulted in missing subsurface flow data during certain runoff events. Therefore, the majority of the comparisons made relate to the Gagnon site. The 2000/2001 hydrological year was unusually dry, which resulted in a limited number of surface and subsurface runoff events. The annual depth of surface runoff for the Gagnon site was 87.5 mm/ha, of which only 0.2mm occurred outside the snowmelt event. The estimated depth of subsurface runoff of the snowmelt event at the Gagnon site based upon a water balance equation was 93.7 mm/ha, or 51.7% of the total volume that occurred on the Gagnon field during the snowmelt event. The total phosphorus load in surface runoff for the spring snowmelt at the Gagnon site was 166.4 g/ha, whereas the estimated total phosphorus load in subsurface drainage was 98.2 g/ha, or 37.1% of the total load. Subsurface drains can therefore be a significant pathway for phosphorus losses.</description><creator>Jamieson, Andrew, 1976-</creator><contributor>Madramootoo, Chandra A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Agricultural pollution -- Pike River Watershed (Vt. and Québec).</subject><subject>Subsurface drainage -- Pike River Watershed (Vt. and Québec).</subject><subject>Water -- Phosphorus content -- Pike River (Vt. and Québec).</subject><title>Evaluating phosphorus losses in surface and subsurface runoff from two agricultural fields in Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75df353.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qr411</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p207f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Beaver ponds are important parts of peatland landscapes and have high fluxes of CO2 and CH4. This study was undertaken in Mer Bleue Bog, Ontario, to determine the response of a beaver pond to drainage (lowering by 25 cm) as a sink or source of carbon. Plant distribution was changed in response to a new water table gradient. Each vegetation community and the remaining beaver pond were sampled for fluxes of CO2 and CH4 from mid-April to end-November, 1999, one year after the water table was lowered. A flow-through chamber system was used to measure CO2 flux from vegetated sites. Mean daily CO2 flux ranged from 0.4--1.6 g CO2-C M-2 (positive denoting uptake from the atmosphere). Variations in CO2 flux amongst the sites along the gradient could not be related to differences in plant species composition, peat temperature, or water table. The mean daily CO2 emission measured by a static floating chamber on the pond area was -24.1 g CO2-C m-2. A closed chamber was used to measure CH4 on vegetated sites. Daily CH4 fluxes ranged from 1 to -159 mg CH4-C m-2, increasing from the beaver pond margin to the open water surface. The water table explained 83% of the seasonal average CH 4 flux variability and the vegetation added another 11%. The mean daily CH4 flux measured by a static floating chamber on the pond area was -54 mg CH4-C m-2. The seasonal measurements were integrated into an areal estimate of CO 2 and CH4 flux for the beaver pond area prior to and after drainage. The beaver pond area sequestered 96 g m-2 before drainage (104 g CO2-C m-2 and -8 g CH 4-C m-2), and the same area more than doubled the uptake to 231 g m-2 after being drained (233 g CO 2-C m-2 and -3 g CH4-C m -2).</description><creator>Isernhagen, Birgit.</creator><contributor>Moore, Tim (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Carbon cycle (Biogeochemistry) -- Ontario -- Ottawa Region.</subject><subject>Atmospheric carbon dioxide -- Ontario -- Ottawa Region.</subject><subject>Peatlands -- Ontario -- Ottawa Region.</subject><subject>Atmospheric methane -- Ontario -- Ottawa Region.</subject><title>The effect of beaver pond drainage on CO and CH fluxes in Canadian temperate peatland /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tn74z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p207f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78td910</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We investigated the use of oral corticosteroids (OCS) among patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and the subsequent risk of death from all causes, COPD, cardiac problems, and pneumonia. We identified an incident cohort of 2050 patients with COPD using the Saskatchewan Health databases. We matched 668 case patients who died with 6742 controls with respect to date of entry into the cohort. A nested case-control analysis was then conducted using conditional multivariate regression. The matched adjusted rate ratio (RR) of all cause mortality for any use of OCS was 1.48 (95% CI 1.18--1.84). An increased risk of death was also shown with cumulative dose (RR 1.17; 95% CI 1.08--1.25) and average yearly dose (RR 1.31; 95% CI 1.19--1.43). A dose-related increase in the adjusted rate ratios for cumulative OCS doses above 250 mg was observed. The risk is particularly evident among patients filling prescriptions for OCS in the 12 months before death. An increased risk of death from COPD was found, but no significant association was found for cardiac and pneumonia mortality. Although the results suggest the use of OCS increases the risk death among COPD patients, the possibility of confounding by indication and channelling may have influenced the results.</description><creator>Innes, Michael, 1974-</creator><contributor>Ernst, Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>The use of oral corticosteroids and the risk of death from Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m357q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78td910</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m3555</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The i&amp;barbelow;nterf&amp;barbelow;eron&amp;barbelow; (IFN) inducible d&amp;barbelow;ouble s&amp;barbelow;tranded (ds) RNA activated protein kinase PKR inhibits protein synthesis by phosphorylating the alpha-subunit of the eukaryotic translation initiation factor 2 (eIF-2alpha). The introduction of dominant negative mutants of PKR leads to cell transformation and tumor formation in nude mice, and is thought to be due to the deregulation of general protein synthesis. In addition to translational control, PKR has been implicated in several signaling pathways leading to gene transcription. For example, a link between PKR and NF-kappaB activation was first detected when PKR knockout mouse embryonic fibroblasts were deficient in NF-kappaB DNA binding upon dsRNA mediated activation. Recently, PKR has been shown to induce IkappaB kinase (IKK) activity resulting in the induction of NF-kappaB mediated gene transcription. The mechanism of activation of IKK by PKR has been suggested to be independent of PKR's catalytic capacity and may be due to a protein-protein interaction between PKR and IKK. The effects of dominant negative mutants of PKR (PKRDelta6/PKRLS4/PKRLS9) on the activation of NF-kappaB was examined in NIH3T3 cells. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Ishii, Tetsu.</creator><contributor>Koromilas, Antonis E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Molecular mechanism of activation of transcription factor NF-kB by the mutants of the interferon-inducible protein kinase PKR</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m356f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m3555</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1j92g9182</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Published maps of the postcentral gyrus (SI) of macaque monkeys and other primates have been incomplete in that there has been little study on the double representation of the face. The present study was undertaken to describe trigeminal representation in SI and the thalamus in 4 Old World monkeys (Macaca fascicularis). Microelectrode recording procedures were used to electrophysiologically characterize the facial areas. The somatotopic pattern of the connections of the ventroposterior nucleus with the representation of the face in SI, in particular the lower jaw, were investigated using the retrograde tracers Texas Red and Fluorescein. These tracers were injected after the facial fields within the cortex had been defined electrophysiologically. Injection in a cortical location representing the upper head area and the primary face area led to the labeling of neurons in the ventroposterior lateral nucleus (VPL) and ventroposterior medial nucleus (VPM). We conclude that there are two distinct facial areas in SI and that the upper head area is closely associated with the area subserved by the upper cervical dermatomes at the thalamic level. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Hyams, Sarah</creator><contributor>Lund, James P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Psychology, Psychobiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Representation of the face in the somatosensory cortex and thalamus in macaque monkey</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jn28f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g9182</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dt87s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The formation of heterocyclic amines (HAs) have been proven to be carcinogenic and mutagenic and these compounds have been found in cooked food such as meat, poultry, and fish. There are strong relationships between potential cancer development and HAs through intake of the cooked food. The yield of HAs along with the influence of fat content and soy protein on the formation of HAs were determined during heating (as in cooking) at different temperatures using the kinetic modeling approach. The formation of HAs is dependent on temperature, time, fat content, and soy protein. The increase of fat content in samples resulted in a lower concentration of HAs' concentrations and a lower activation energy of reaction. Fat apparently enhanced the formation of HAs in meats but diluted availability of precursors for reactions. An increase in soy protein concentration decreased the maximum concentration of HAs formed in the different cooking conditions. Two different approaches were used in order to model the formation of HAs. First, an artificial neural network (ANN) was used with two data sets to train and test the ANN. An ANN consisting of 18 processing elements and two hidden layers showed the best performance for predicting the formation of HAs. Second, the formation of HAs were predicted using temperature profiles in a cooked sample during pan-frying. The temperature profiles in cooked meat patty were predicted using finite element method. The concentration of HAs depended on the meat patty's surface temperature developed during pan frying. The result of this study can be used to develop methods to reduce HAs in food thus optimize product quality and safety.</description><creator>Hwang, Dae Kun, 1972-</creator><contributor>Ngadi, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Amines -- Synthesis -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Heterocyclic compounds -- Synthesis -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Neural networks (Computer science)</subject><subject>Frying.</subject><subject>Hamburgers.</subject><title>Mathematical modeling of heterocyclic amines formation in meat patties during pan frying</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752j56n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dt87s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3197xn44q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Glutamate formiminotransferase deficiency (OMIM 229100) is an autosomal recessive disorder marked by clinical heterogeneity. The severe phenotype, first identified in patients of Japanese descent, includes high levels of formiminoglutamate (FIGLU) in the urine in response to histidine loading, megaloblastic anemia, and mental retardation. The mild phenotype is marked by high levels of FIGLU in the urine in the absence of histidine loading, mild developmental delay and no hematological abnormalities. The gene for human glutamate formiminotransferase-cyclodeaminase consists of 15 exons and is located at 21q22.3. The protein consists of a tetramer of dimers, with dimerization essential for both formiminotransferase and cyclodeaminase activity. Genomic DNA extracted from cell lines from three patients with suspected glutamate formiminotransferase deficiency was analyzed by PCR and sequencing of individual exons. Cell lines WG 1758 and WG 1759 are from two siblings of Germanic descent. Both siblings are heterozygous for the mutations c457 C → T and c940 G → C. The c457 C → T changes a conserved arginine to a cysteine in a loop involved in the binding of formiminotetrahydrofolate to the enzyme. The c940 G → C mutation converts an arginine to a proline in an alpha-helix essential for the dimerization of the formiminotransferase domain. Cell line WG 1795 is from a patient of Danish descent. The patient appears to be hemizygous for a c1033 insG mutation. Quantitative PCR suggests the presence of a deletion on the other chromosome, which minimally encompasses exon 9. All of the FTCD gene changes were absent in 100 control individuals (200 alleles).</description><creator>Hilton, John Frederick.</creator><contributor>Rosenblatt, D. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Hydroxymethyl and Formyl Transferases -- deficiency.</subject><subject>Folic acid -- Metabolism -- Disorders -- Genetic aspects.</subject><subject>Transferases.</subject><title>The molecular basis of glutamate formiminotransferase deficiency /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33rz428.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xn44q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k643b287t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The CDP/Cut transcription factor has been demonstrated to be proteolytically processed at the G1/S transition. The goal of my project was to establish an in vitro processing assay which would enable further analysis of this event. The assay utilized whole cell extracts from NIH 3T3 cells combined with purified CDP/Cut substrates prepared from either mammalian or bacterial cells. Equivalent electrophoretic mobility, cell cycle dependence, and similar protease inhibitor sensitivity served as criteria to demonstrate that processing in vitro was identical to that in vivo. I have found that the processing event occurs rapidly, is insensitive to variations in salt concentration, and takes place optimally at a lower pH. Interestingly, the bacterially-produced protein was more efficiently processed than the mammalian-produced protein. Treatment of the mammalian-produced substrate with the Cdc25A phosphatase increased the level of processing in vitro. Similarly, processing in vivo was stimulated following over-expression of Cdc25A. This assay will provide a useful tool for further research into CDP/Cut proteolysis.</description><creator>Hebert, Sherry Dawn.</creator><contributor>Nepveu, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>In vitro analysis of the proteolytic processing of the CCAAT-displacement protein (CDPCut)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n296r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b287t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207tr07g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A crucial part of the Scanning Near-Field Microscope (SNOM) is the distance regulation that keeps the separation of a fiber probe tip and the sample surface constant. Previously, shear-force detection was implemented. Shear-force interactions have the disadvantage of being destructive on soft sample. The implementation of an alternative tapping-mode is investigated in this thesis. In tapping-mode, the fiber tip oscillates perpendicularly to the sample surface, thus avoiding the destructive lateral shear-force. This thesis also provides a general overview of SNOM, including the theory of near-field, the definition of spatial resolution, as well as the tip-sample distance regulation. Tapping-mode feedback is implemented and discussed in comparison to traditional shear-force feedback. Both CD stamper and Polystyrene images were obtained by using tapping-mode SNOM, and compared to images taken under shear-force mode SNOM and Scanning Electron Microscope. Different factors, which affect the performance of tapping-mode SNOM are discussed.</description><creator>Huang, Yi-ting, 1976-</creator><contributor>Gruetter, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Physics, General.</subject><title>Investigation of tapping-mode scanning near-field optical microscope</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53wx59k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tr07g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xp68kj13b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In Caenorhabditis elegans, mutations in the clk-1 gene result in delayed embryonic and post-embryonic development, a slowing down of rhythmic behaviors and an extended life span. CLK-1 encodes the demethoxyubiquinone (DMQ or DMQn) hydroxylase in the ubiquinone (CoQ or Qn) biosynthesis pathway. Thus, clk-1 mutants produce DMQ instead of CoQ. In order to understand the relationship between the CoQ biosynthesis defect and the pleiotropic phenotype of clk-1 mutants, I isolated a deletion mutant, coq-4(qm143), in C. elegans. In Saccharomyces cerevisiae, mutants in COQ4, the coq-4 homologue, do not produce ubiquinone, like those in COQ7, the clk-1 homologue. coq-4(qm143) is a non-strict maternal-effect lethal mutation. Most of the progeny from a homozygous coq-4(qm143) hermaphrodite die during embryogenesis. However, homozygous coq-4(qm143) hermaphrodites from a heterozygous mother can develop and behave normally until adulthood. As adults, they become uncoordinated and paralytic, and are defective in egg-laying. Unlike hermaphrodites, homozygous coq-4(qm143) males are fully maternally rescued. The qm143 is a 1469 base pair deletion, which completely removes the coq-4 gene and does not affect the coding sequence of any other gene. By performing germline transformation, I also showed that the non-viable phenotype of coq-4 (qm143) is indeed due to the removal of the coq-4 gene itself. The preliminary study of COQ-4 expression pattern by using a COQ-4::GFP fusion protein indicates that COQ-4 is expressed in mitochondria of the worm.</description><creator>Han, Dong, 1970-</creator><contributor>Hekimi, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Caenorhabditis elegans -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Caenorhabditis elegans -- Development.</subject><title>Identification and molecular genetic characterization of a coq-4 knockout mutation in Caenorhabditis elegans</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967541r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kj13b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x081d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>E1B-55K is a multifunctional protein that plays many essential roles during adenoviral infection. During early stages of infection E1B-55K blocks E1A-induced apoptosis by inactivating the p53 tumour suppressor protein. E1B-55K binds to p53 and prevents the activation of p53 responsive genes. However, E1B-55K binding is not sufficient for inhibition of p53 transactivation suggesting that E1B-55K actively represses transcription. Studies using a series of E1B-55K deletion mutants identified a repression domain located at the carboxy terminus between amino acids 420 and 443. A second repression domain may also be present toward the amino terminus of the protein. Furthermore, E1B-55K did not display intrinsic HDAC activity and repression was not affected by the HDAC inhibitor trichostatin A, suggesting that E1B-55K repression functions independently of HDACs. In addition to repression of p53 activation, E1B-55K was also observed to disrupt p53-dependent repression in H1299 cells expressing exogenous wild type p53. E1B-55K inhibited p53-mediated repression of the cdc2 and dp1 promoters whereas E4orf6 had no effect. E1B-55K was also observed to inhibit p53-associated cell cytotoxicity, while E4orf6 displayed no significant effect. Since E4orf6 has been observed to repress p53 transactivation, these results may indicate that inhibition of p53 activation is insufficient to block apoptosis in this system. This may signify the importance of p53-mediated repression for the induction of apoptosis.</description><creator>Gurd, Scott J.</creator><contributor>Branton, P. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Functional analysis of the adenovirus type 5 E1B-55 kDa protein</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676x507.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x081d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w6634560h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Rainfall is essential for the design of many hydraulic structures. In particular, rainfall data are usually required as input to watershed models for simulating the runoff process. However, in practice rainfall records, even if they are available, contain only a finite amount of information regarding the historical patterns. A stochastic simulation of the rainfall process is thus needed to generate many sequences of synthetic rainfall series that have similar properties as those of the observed data. A large number of generated rainfall sequences would provide more adequate information for assessing the response of a watershed system. The present study is therefore concerned with finding the best rainfall model that could provide reliable synthetic rainfall series for practical application purposes. More specifically, two popular stochastic rainfall-modeling schemes were assessed for their accuracy and suitability in the description of the rainfall process. The first model (MCME) represents a combination of the rainfall occurrence process and the distribution of rainfall amounts on wet days. The second model is based on the Neyman-Scott rectangular pulses (NSRP) stochastic process. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Han, Sang-Yoon, 1971-</creator><contributor>Nguyen, Van-Thanh-Van (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Stochastic modeling of rainfall processes : a comparative study using data from different climatic conditions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn1070907.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634560h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rg28h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A time course study was conducted to monitor disease development and expression of the defense-related genes phenylalanine ammonia-lyase (PAL), chalcone synthase (CHS), chalcone isomerase (CHI), and hydroxyproline-rich glycoprotein (HRGP) in bean (Phaseolus vulgaris L.) plants colonized by the arbuscular mycorrhizal (AM) fungus Glomus intraradices , and post-infected with the soil-borne pathogen Rhizoctonia solani. Pre-colonization of bean plants by the AM fungus did not significantly reduce the severity of rot symptoms. RNA blot analysis revealed a systemic increase in transcript levels of the four defense-related genes in response to R. solani infection. On the other hand, pre-colonization of bean plants with G. intraradices elicited no change in PAL, CHS and CHI transcripts, but an increase of HRGP transcripts in leaves was detected. A differential and systemic alteration in the expression of all four defense genes was observed in AM beans post-infected with R. solani. Depending on the time after infection with R. solani and the tissue examined, varying responses from stimulation, suppression, to no change in transcript levels were detected.</description><creator>Guillon, Christopher.</creator><contributor>Jabaji-Hare, Suha (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Vesicular-arbuscular mycorrhizas.</subject><subject>Glomus intraradices.</subject><subject>Beans -- Disease and pest resistance -- Genetic aspects.</subject><subject>Rhizoctonia solani -- Biological control.</subject><title>Systemic alteration of defense-related gene transcript levels in mycorrhizal bean plants infected with Rhizoctonia solani</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752j57x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rg28h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qf85nc893</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The reproductive performance of Sharp-shinned Hawks (Accipiter striatus) nesting in southern Quebec was studied during the 1999 and 2000 breeding seasons. In 2000, 37.5% of breeders (equal numbers of males and females) were immature, whereas none were in 1999. In 2000, clutch size and hatching success were 4.4 and 3.1 eggs per nest, respectively. Of 10 pairs monitored in 2000, six hatched at least one chick and five raised young to a bandable age. However, only three pairs successfully fledged at least one young that year, whereas all seven nests observed in 1999 did so. Unseasonable weather in 2000 may have contributed to this decrease in nesting success. In 2000, levels of organochlorines were measured in blood samples taken from sharpshin females and their young at five of the above-mentioned 10 nests. While most compounds were not detected at all, or at least not at levels likely to affect reproduction, concentrations of DDE and PCB's in these breeding females were much higher than in female migrants previously sampled in the eastern United States or Great Lakes. Whereas global contamination of the environment appears to be the source of PCB exposure, this population may be accumulating DDE on its wintering grounds. Habitat assessments were conducted at 12 sharpshin nests over both years of the study. Means of the variables measured (among others) were nest tree height, 15.3 m; tree density, 1052/ha; total canopy cover, 86.7%; coniferous cover, 42.95%; and distance to the nearest opening, 17.5 m. Nests were found in a range of forested habitats, but this population did not exhibit a noteworthy degree of plasticity with respect to the measured parameters. That these sharpshins tended to use structurally older stands with more deciduous cover than other populations did may reflect regional differences in habitat availability and/or in the abundance of competitors.</description><creator>Coleman, Joanna L.</creator><contributor>Bird, David M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Sharp-shinned hawk -- Ecology -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Sharp-shinned hawk -- Québec (Province) -- Reproduction.</subject><title>Ecology of the sharp-shinned hawk (Accipiter striatus) in southern Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612q42h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nc893</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj2363897</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:54:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the spring of 1998, a closed end gravity flow pipeline was installed in the Lethbridge Northern Irrigation District. The pipes ranged from 900 mm to 300 mm in diameter. Manholes were placed at several locations along the pipeline and were used to install velocity meters and pressure transducers, which recorded data every second. Pressures and velocities during periods of steady state were used to calculate the head loss, Re and the Hazen-Williams friction factor, "C", along lengths of constant diameter. The results were compared to the industry design standard of C = 150 (used for the design of rigid PVC pipe installations) and to the theoretical hydraulically smooth line developed from the Moody diagram and the Darcy-Weisbach equation. Since the maximum and minimum calculated values of C came in the 750 mm and 900 mm diameter pipes, respectively, and all other C values, including those from the 300 mm and 650 mm diameters, fell between these, pipe diameter was assumed not to be a variable. Therefore all the field data was averaged. The average value of Re for the range studied was 9.73 x 105 . The corresponding best-fit C value is 147.7, which is 6.0% lower than the derived theoretical maximum. Since the derived theoretical maximum is the ideal condition and the recorded data was slightly lower and therefore determined be a good representation of what can be expected in true field conditions.</description><creator>Connell, David, 1974-</creator><contributor>Bonnell, Bob (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Irrigation farming -- Alberta, Southern.</subject><subject>Pipelines -- Hydrodynamics.</subject><subject>Frictional resistance (Hydrodynamics)</subject><subject>Polyvinyl chloride.</subject><title>Hazen-Williams C-factor assessment in an operational irrigation pipeline</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193b70n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj2363897</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):39075</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>