<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:32:45Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11175" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s4655k649</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:00:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It can be said without fear of serious contradiction that among the notions of mathematics, none imposed so difficult a task in formulating a definition as that of infinite applied in the theory of sets. Indeed, the whole subject of theory of functions is so preeminently based upon a proper understanding of the infinite that it is not surprising that early writers in analysis, having no clear concept of the infinite, were led to erroneous results. It was Dedekind, who perceiving mathematics as a free creation of the human mind and consequently independent of spatio-temporal relations, set about rendering analysis rigorous. He was immediately followed by George Cantor whose notion of power of sets led to extremely significant results. Indeed, this notion may be placed alongside differentiation in originality and breadth of scope. He created as one of the nineteenth-century mathematicians said “a heaven from which there was no escape”. Dedekind and Cantor were not concerned with the nebulous philosophy which the notion of infinite had previously inspired, and were what we now term Formalists. It is this point of view which will be adopted in the development of the theory of transfinite numbers. Mindful, however, of the fact that no dogmatic attitude exists but that there exists at least a compelling if not convincing counter-dogma, there will be found a short essay on Intuitionism, the counter point of view further on in this work. [...]</description><creator>Ayoub, Raymond George.</creator><contributor>Sullivan, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Transfinite numbers.</subject><title>Transfinite numbers.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rx75w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655k649</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62fc44h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:00:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Coronary heart disease is today the most important cause of morbidity in many parts of the world. In 1967, one-third of all deaths in the United States were due to heart disease and coronary heart disease accounted for 80 per cent of these. Narrowing of the coronary arteries by atherosclerosis is the cause of 99 per cent of cases of coronary heart disease, and until the etiology of atherosclerosis is better understood and effective methods for its prevention are established, surgery will remain the only treatment possible.</description><creator>Kheir, Simon</creator><contributor>Vineberg, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>I. An experimental attempt to revascularize the myocardium directly from the left ventricle. II. Evaluation of the use of intramyocardial ivalon sponge strips for myocardial revascularization.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386n72q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fc44h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vm13w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:00:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The term “rearrangement” refers to an irreversible reaction which produces a change in the structural arrangement of a molecule, “Essentially the processes of rearrangement are basically in every case accompanied by intramolecular oxidation and reduction. This oxidation reduction mechanism involves electron transfers within the molecule and consequently is best explained on the basis of an electronic mechanism. This concept was first advanced by Jones and later expressed by Stieglitz , Robinson and Ingold.” Molecular transformations are relatively rare because simple adjustments that can occur within a single molecule have usually been accomplished in the process of synthesis. However, molecules may, under the influence of some reagent, enter a chemical reaction in which the electron density of the carbon atom containing the reactive group is greatly increased or decreased. To compensate for this electronic displacement electrons or groups migrate to the low electron density carbon atom and reestablish equilibrium. Often these shifts are the result of degradation reactions such as the elimination of water or hydrogen halide. Yet addition reactions to olefins, replacement reactions - as in the transformation of amines to alcohols - as well as reactions involving no change of total molecular formula, can also be accompanied by intramolecular rearrangements. [...]</description><creator>Barry, J. Guy Thomas.</creator><contributor>Ross, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The action of sulfuric acid on "D.D.T." and some related compounds and The synthesis and derivatives of 1-4 chlorophenyl 2,2,2-trichloroethanol.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dq35x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vm13w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78tg263</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:00:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Plasma corticosterone (PC) levels and urinary corticosteroids (UC) and androgen (UA) amounts were determined in male and female high mammary cancer C3H/HeJ (H) and low mammary cancer C3HeB/FeJ (F) mice. Before the tumor appeared, the PC levels were significantly depressed, became significantly elevated when it first manifested and again decreased significantly during tumor development. The UC amounts also increased when the tumor first appeared but the values were not subnormal prior to its appearance nor did they decline during its development. The UA amounts followed the same pattern except that they decline as the tumor developed. Females had significantly higher UC and significantly lower UA amounts, but the PC level showed no reliable sex difference. F mice had significantly higher PC levels, significantly lower UC amounts and lower UA amounts of borderline significance.</description><creator>Sancho, Esperanza</creator><contributor>Grad, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Investigative Medicine.</subject><title>Plasma and urinary corticosteroids and androgens in murine mammary cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf2688410.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tg263</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z316q4686</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:00:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis examines the attempts to develop the political and constitutional system of Uruguay, recognizing the special character of the political tradition given to it by José Batlle y Ordonez in the period 1903-1929. His understanding of his world gave Uruguay both its peculiar economic development and its political structure. In due course, the demands of modern government created, however, excessive strains on the plural executive, led to near economic collapse and constitutional reform. The thesis traces the ideological and social factors which, in spite of the recent political crisis, have preserved a tradition of constitutional growth in Uruguay.</description><creator>Simon, James</creator><contributor>Mallory, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Economics.</subject><title>Uruguay: from pioneering democracy to developing nation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r421v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q4686</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26z1310</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:00:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Bishop of Norwich was descended from the baronial Despenser family. The name was originally Despenser or le Despenser, but in his case the contracted form of Spencer or le Spenser was often used. The origin of the name goes back to the Latin word dispensator, which is defined as a man who spends, accepts, compensates and impends or weighs out. It means one who administrates money or handles loans and debts for another man, for example the despenser of the public money of the state of Carthage. A despenser was a servant who corresponded to the maitre du palais, but who worked in the king’s palace or in the houses of prominent people. Hence in Aragon he lived in the palace, and was the official who bought supplies for the palace and who spent the money. Joseph held this post in Egypt, and it existed under the Roman emperors and Frankish kings. It also existed under Anglo-Saxon kings like Harold and under the Angevins. The Roman of Jourdain says that the despensers bought the food. The office existed also in Flanders, and there were despensers of the church or priests who bought supplies for a church. In France the despensier or depensier was a maitre du palais. Thus we see that it originated as a trade name. [...]</description><creator>Barry, Rexford Gerald.</creator><contributor>Bayley, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>England -- Church history -- 1066-1485.</subject><subject>Great Britain -- History -- Richard II, 1377-1399.</subject><subject>Despenser, Henry le, Bishop of Norwich, 1341 or 2-1406.</subject><title>Some aspects of Spencer, Bishop of Norwich.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rh52s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z1310</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43p140j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:00:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Many writers have dealt with the ever-recurring themes of Love and War. As such, Marlowe is neither original nor singular in the fact that he too deals with these aspects of man's life. His originality and singularity, however, lie in the fact that in each of the plays under discussion, namely The Tragedy of Dido, Tamburlaine l &amp; II and Edward II, a different attitude towards Love and War is presented. In The Tragedy of Dido, the conflict between Love and War is resolved in love's defeat as the hero departs for his struggles in a strange land. In Tamburlaine, a delicate balance is maintained between Love and War in the person or the hero, while the king in Edward II creates the conditions for war through his pre-occupation with an unnatural love affair. Furthermore, these major attitudes are usually underlined by minor Love-War relationships in the plays.</description><creator>Williams, John R.</creator><contributor>Piehler, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>English.</subject><title>Love and war in four plays of Christopher Marlowe</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vf58s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p140j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8p58ph099</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:00:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The calibration of a microphone consists of finding the ratio of electrical output to incident sound pressure as a function of frequency and angle of incidence. The amount of non-linear distortion and the effect of temperature and static pressure may also be required. The calibration may be given in terms of the sound pressure actually acting on the microphone diaphragm (“pressure” calibration), or in terms of the sound pressure that would be present in a plane progressive wave if the microphone were not there. It is this latter quantity, termed the “field” calibration, that is of most interest in microphones used in broadcasting (6). The distortion of the sound field caused by the presence of the microphone, which may be appreciable at wavelengths comparable to the dimensions of the unit, is in this case charged to the response characteristics of the microphone itself.[...]</description><creator>Bastin, Douglas Halford.</creator><contributor>Howes, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Electrical Engineering.</subject><title>Problems encountered in the development of a standard test for microphones.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tq12c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58ph099</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2j62s8052</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:00:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>De toute la production littéraire du dix-huitième siècle, le roman érotique est le genre le plus méprisé et, de ce fait, le plus mal connu. Considéré comme création frivole et malsaine, ce genre est ignoré du grand public. Certes, on lit les romans de Diderot et Voltaire, mais seulement dans la mesure où ils figurent dans le courant philosophique. Des auteurs tels que d'Aucourt, de Montbron, Nougaret, parmi tant d'autres, n'attirent guère l'attention du public ou des critiques littéraires. Si l'on néglige les auteurs mineurs et leur genre maudit, celui-ci n'est cependant pas dépourvu d'importance, puisqu'il met en évidence l'étendue de l'épanouissement philosophique. L'étude du rôle des membres du clergé dans le roman, érotique révèle l'omniprésence des soucis de l'époque dans l'esprit des écrivains. En créant des romans badins, ils font ressortir non seulement une certaine exubérance de la vie mais aussi les préoccupations courantes de liberté, égalité et fraternité. Quand les religieux deviennent les porte-parole des auteurs, ils détournent le roman érotique de sa position marginale pour le replacer au centré de la pensée du "siècle des lumières".</description><creator>Stern, Janet L.</creator><contributor>Leduc, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>French.</subject><title>Le clergé dans le roman érotique du dix-huitième siècle</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v838368m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s8052</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf2688428</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:00:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse a pour but de chercher les tendances pro-cubiste et pro-surréaliste de la poésie de Tristan Corbière, tant dans la forme que dans les thèmes. Dans le premier chapitre, l'auteur se demande jusqu'à quel point Corbière appartient au mouvement décadent, et veut mettre en lumière l'aspect précurseur des Amours jaunes. Le second chapitre analyse la technique de composition des poèmes qui rappellent la recherche de quelques écrivains cubistes: la superposition d'images, le raccourci et l'ellipse. Le troisième chapitre mettra l'accent sur la richesse des images venues de l'inconscient et qui échappent au contrôle de la raison. Une analyse de l'humour, de l'absurde et du bestiaire des Amours jaunes tentera de rattacher ces notions au courant surréaliste.</description><creator>Lebeuf, Jacqueline</creator><contributor>Jones, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>French.</subject><title>Tristan Corbière précurseur du cubisme et du surréalisme</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qg405.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf2688428</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hs762</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:00:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It has become increasingly more obvious during the past few years that various hormones have an effect upon renal structure. The fact that thyroxin is capable of producing kidney enlargement has been known for some time. In 1934, during the course of some experiments to determine the effect of androgenic extracts upon the accessory sex organs of castrate rats, it was incidently noted that the weight of the castrate kidney returned to normal after the injection of these extracts. No systematic study of the effect of steroid hormones on the kidney was made, however, until 1939. At that time testosterone propionate was found to cause marked enlargement of the kidneys in the mouse. Further experimentation revealed that other steroids had some kidney enlarging activity, but of these steroids the testoids proved to be the most active. This action which stimulated the growth of the kidney and was characterized by hypertrophy and hyperplasia of the cells of the distal and proximal convoluted tubules was referred to as a “renotropic” action. Subsequent observations established that steroid hormones exert a certain renotropic effect even in hypophysectomized animals. Their activity in the absence of the pituitary shows that the kidney stimulating effect of these hormones is not mediated by the hypophysis but is probably direct. Doses in excess of the amount normally produced in the organism, however, failed to restore the kidney in the hypophysectomized animal to its normal size[...]</description><creator>Beland, Eleanor.</creator><contributor>Selye, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Hormones.</subject><subject>Kidneys.</subject><title>The renotropicaction of various hormones.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dd135.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hs762</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d504rp46v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:00:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Hepatocellular alterations following administration of fructose have been reported recently in a patient with hereditary fructose intolerance and subsequently in experimental animals by Phillips et al. (Lab. Invest., 16: 627,1967; Am. J. Med., 44: 910,1968; Am. J. Path., 52: 54a, 1968). In the present work, 20% solutions of fructose, glucose, galactose, and mannitol were infused intraportally into fasted, adult rats at a rate of 20 mg./min. for an hour, using an Harvard infusion pump. The livers were fixed by perfusion of a mixture of glutaraldehyde and paraformaldehyde, and tissue was obtained for electron microscopic study. Ultrastructural hepatic cell changes were observed in rats after infusion of fructose, consisting of proliferation of the smooth endoplasmic reticulum, disarray of the rough endoplasmic reticulum, rarefaction of the hyaloplasm and the formation of concentric membranous arrays and occasional cytolysomes. No lesion was seen in rats infused with glucose and galactose and mannitol was found to produce vacuolation of the hepatocytes. These changes are more extensive and severe than those previously described, and are almost identical to the electron microscopic findings observed in hereditary fructose intolerance. The pathophysiology of this experimentally induced lesion is ascribed to the accumulation of fructose and its metabolites in the hepatocytes.</description><creator>Yu, Dinah T.</creator><contributor>Phillips, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Pathology.</subject><title>Ultrastructural changes in rat liver cells induced by In vivo infusion of fructose, glucose, and galactose and mannitol</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vr74w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rp46v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v692t9527</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:00:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Clearance studies performed in fifteen dogs, during massive extracellular volume expansion and furosemide administration showed that the mean fractional excretion of magnesium, sodium and potassium were 55%, 40% and 160% respectively. Infusion of magnesium sulfate, chloride and citrate to these diuretic dogs resulted in a sharp increase in the fractional excretion of magnesium with no further increase in fractional excretion of sodium and potassium. Glomerular filtration rate was depressed to a significant degree (12 - 45%). The high fractional excretion of magnesium, sodium and potassium in the diuretic control period indicates that excretion of all three ions is greatly enhanced by common factors; whereas after magnesium infusion, there is a marked dissociation in the transport of magnesium as compared to that of sodium and potassium. The consistently greater fractional excretion of magnesium than 100% after magnesium infusions strongly suggests magnesium secretion under these experimental conditions.</description><creator>Wong, Norman L.</creator><contributor>Dirks, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Evidence for tubular secretion of magnesium in dogs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881q21q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t9527</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zh548</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:00:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Stimuli which cause the accumulation of increased amounts of fat in the liver have interested both the clinician and the biochemist. To the former, they are of import, not only because fatty infiltration of the liver is found as a frequent pathological finding associated with various diseases, but also because this change has been shown to result in an impairment of hepatic function (129,380) and, if severe, to terminate in cirrhosis (79,83, 84,110,112). They are of interest to the latter as aids in the elucidation of fat metabolism, and therefore, indirectly, of other phases of metabolism. There is no doubt that the liver plays a highly important role in the assimilation and catabolism of lipid substances. Thus, the study of factors influencing liver fat have yielded particularly useful information as to the reactions involved. It is well known that several of the endocrine glands exercise pronounced, though not yet fully understood, effects upon carbohydrate and protein metabolism. Their influence on fat metabolism has not received such wide recognition. The first purpose of this thesis is to attempt to amass and correlate what is known of the endocrine factors influencing the deposition of hepatic fat. A complete understanding of factors affecting liver fat necessarily involves a knowledge, not only of the effect of these factors on fat metabolism itself, but also of their effect on carbohydrate and protein metabolism. To cover the whole of this field would not be feasible within the limits of a single thesis. The discussion has, therefore, been restricted to a consideration of factors that directly result in an alteration in the amount of hepatic fat [...]</description><creator>Berman, Doreen.</creator><contributor>Selye, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Liver.</subject><subject>Hormones.</subject><title>Hormonal effects on fat deposition in the liver.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dg77t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zh548</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m503t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:00:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Following a comparative electron microscopic study, both Clara and type II alveolar cells of mice are found to be epithelial, non-phagocytic, and secretory in nature. Evidence is found which suggests that the mitochondria of the Clara cell are participating in the process of the cellular synthesis. The chemical type of pulmonary edema was induced by adrenalin, pilocarpine or ANTU injection. Contrary to the previous belief, the type II alveolar cell also became vacuolated and eventually ruptured as did the other lining cells of alveoli and bronchioles. In addition, bullae formation of the type II alveolar cell and myelin-like figures in the Clara cell were observed. These changes are non-specific and both types of cells are probably not tropic to either adrenalin or pilocarpine. Proliferation of smooth endoplasmic reticulum in the Clara cell was induced by starvation and the possible explanation of it is given.</description><creator>Wang, Nai-San</creator><contributor>Thurlbeck, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Pathology.</subject><title>The clara and type II alveolar cells of mice under normal and altered conditions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712mb02r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m503t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g3217</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:00:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Previous work had indicated that acetylcarnitylcholine might play a role in nerve metabolism. In the present study, a column chromatographic method, using Sephadex G-10 was developed to separate synthetic acetylcarnitylcholine from acetylcholine. When a formic acid-acetone extract of rat brain was applied to this column, and chromatographed in this system, two peaks with ACh-like activity were obtained. The Rf's of these two peaks corresponded to those of synthetic acetylcarnitylcholine and acetylcholine in the same system. The identity of the material in one of the two peaks as acetylcarnitylcholine was established using the following procedures: (i) Rechromatography of the material on paper for 138 hours using a water-saturated butanol system. (ii) Rechromatography of the material on thin-layer in methanol/acetone/HCI. (iii) Treatment of the material with alkali, chymotrypsin and atropine. (iv) Incubation of the material with butyrylcholinesterase (horse serum). (v) Incubation of the material with acetylcholinesterase (bovine erythrocyte). From these data, the presence of acetyl carnityl choline in rat brain was established.</description><creator>Vine, Elizabeth</creator><contributor>Hosein, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Isolation of acetylcarnitylcholine from rat brain extract by column chromatography</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n170q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g3217</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tq13n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A recent investigation in humans with septic shock has shown a significant increase of the extracellular space, a decrease in the intracellular volume, with an unchanged total body water. There was an increase in the total exchangeable sodium. The present study was undertaken to study the effects of a lethal dose of Eshcerechia coli endotoxin, on changes in body fluid distribution in the controllable laboratory animal, and to demonstrate any change in the total exchangeable sodium. The multiple isotope dilution technique was employed for measuring the pre and two hour post lethal dose of endotoxin, changes of the red cell, plasma and extracellular volumes. Changes for the total exchangeable sodium were performed as an acute experiment with a lethal dose of endotoxin and with a sublethal dose. There was a significant decrease in the plasma volume and the extracellular fluid volume as measured with radiosodium and inulin. The red cell volume was unchanged. There was no evidence of mobilization of the fixed sodium by endotoxin. Endotoxin induced shock in dogs failed to show any change in the total exchangeable sodium. These results indicate a major difference in the body fluid distribution response of humans and dogs in septic shock.</description><creator>Sossoyan, Meguerditch</creator><contributor>Gutelius, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Body fluid studies following endotoxin in dogs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42nc03s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tq13n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74ct79r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Smith, Sherwood P.</creator><contributor>MacLean, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Studies with a pulsatile pump-oxygenator system for preservation of canine kidneys</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806327g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74ct79r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20sw979</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Human IgA myeloma proteins isolated by standard purification procedures and immunoadsorbents exhibited individual variations in the amino acid composition. e.g. in the number of residues of lysine, histidine, arginine, threonine, isoleucine, tyrosine and phenylalanine. IgA molecules contained fewer lysine and serine and more leucine than IgG molecules. That the dimer and trimer of A.P. are disulfide linked and the tetramer an aggregate was revealed by solvent solute interaction studies with urea and guanidine. The higher the polymeric status of IgA (A.P.) the greater is the susceptibility to depolymerization under mild conditions of disulfide bond reduction. The polymer-predominant IgA proteins contained a higher galactosamine content than the monomer-predominant IgA proteins. The monomer-predominant IgA (R.G.) appeared to be more labile to papain and pepsin cleavage than the polymer-predominant one (A.P.). IgA was more resistant to pepsin than to papain. The higher polymers (tetramer and trimer) of A.P. were more susceptible to proteolytic cleavage than the lower ones (dimer and monomer).</description><creator>Smart, Kenwyn I.</creator><contributor>Saha, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Studies on human immunoglobulin A.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311s608.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20sw979</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d5700820</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Previous studies of Franklin and Skoryna have indicated that gastric secretions from fasting human subjects contains viable microorganisms in 82% of cases. In the following experiments it was attempted to determine the effect of gastric mucin on the growth of bacterial strains under different pH conditions. The following strains were selected for these studies: Streptococcus salivarius, Staphylococcus aureus, Corynebacterium pseudodiphtheriticum, Lactobacillus casei, Staphylococcus epidermidis, Proteus vulgaris, Streptococcus pyogenes, Neisseria catarrhalis, Yeast-Candida albicans. These were grown separately in different mucin to broth concentrations in the following range (Mucin, 1:1, 1:2, 1:4, 1:8, 1:16, Broth). The studies were carried out on mucin obtained by aspiration of gastric juice from fasting human subjects. Mucin was then prepared and purified by the filtration and lyophilization method developed by Edward and Skoryna.</description><creator>Rosenthall, Richard A.</creator><contributor>Skoryna, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Investigative Medicine.</subject><title>The interaction of bacterial flora with gastric mucin</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257j010.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d5700820</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8p58ph102</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The pressure-volume characteristics and the regional distribution of liquid ventilation in left lower lobes of excised dogs' lungs were determined by infusion of saline containing I131 labelled albumin into preparations suspended in a second liquid, whose density was lower than that of the ventilating liquid. Surface tension in the lung was thereby abolished, and a vertical transpulmonary pressure gradient was created. The elastic properties of the lung were therefore altered and the pressure-volume curve was no longer exponential as it is during ventilation with air. Above functional residual capacity ventilation was distributed preferentially to the alveoli of the upper zones. The pattern of filling was sequential: namely, the proportion of a tidal breath reaching a given alveolus was not constant but varied with preinspiratory volume. It was shown that this altered pattern of ventilation could be explained by the changes in the elastic properties of the liquid-filled lung.</description><creator>Rona, Mary</creator><contributor>Milic-Emili, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>Surface tension and distribution of ventilation within the lung</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xm74h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58ph102</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128nh806</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work attempted to determine the optimum composition of a perfusate for fixation of young rat tissues using either glutaraldehyde or formaldehyde with post-osmication. One micron thick Epon sections of thyroid, liver and kidney were analyzed in the light microscope with occasional reference to the electron microscope for clarification. Criteria included staining, cell separation, distension of cell organelles and vacuoles. The optimum composition of the fixative varied with the brand used. Differing tissue requirements restricted the effective composition to relatively narrow limits. Thyroid, liver, and also parathyroid and duodenum seemed to have similar requirements, while kidney needed more concentrated solutions. The best overall results were achieved with 2.5% Ladd glutaraldehyde in 0.05 M Sorensen's buffer and 0.1% sucrose, 3. 5% Taab glutaraldehyde in 0.045 M modified Sorensen 's buffer and 0.1% sucrose, and with 6% Taab formaldehyde in 0.09 M Sorensen 's buffer and 0.005% calcium chloride. A successful perfusion was prerequisite to good fixation.</description><creator>Rau, Ethel B.</creator><contributor>Leblond, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Anatomy.</subject><title>The effects of varying the composition of aldehyde fixatives for perfusion of young rats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v884w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nh806</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fb494c496</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The plasma and urinary corticosteroids, haemoglobin, blood urea nitrogen and plasma creatinine were determined in CF1 female mice before, during and after exposure to -10°C. Plasma corticosterone levels increased significantly soon after exposure, remained significantly elevated even in comatose animals and tor an hour during recovery in the warmth, and returned to normal levels a day after the stress. The pattern of change was similar in mice exposed twice, though the deviations from the control levels were less. Urinary corticosteroids were depressed the first day following each exposure, and more so following the second one, with the values tending to return to normal by the seventh day. Haemoglobin levels were not reliably changed during the first exposure, but were elevated during the second. Blood urea nitrogen and plasma creatinine levels were elevated after each exposure, and the latter remained elevated for at least 7 days following the second cold exposure.</description><creator>Rafizadeh, Firouz</creator><contributor>Grad, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Investigative Medicine.</subject><title>Plasma and urinary corticosteroids levels in mice exposed to acute cold (-10°)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x238j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494c496</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rm46p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Whether the fibroblast of granulation tissue is a product of resting connective tissue cells or is derived from circulating mononuclear blood cells is a question of dispute. At the same time it has been suggested that the small lymphocyte is capable of transformation into macrophages and fibroblasts. This investigation seeks to follow the behaviour of the lymphocyte in a surgical wound. In vivo labelled thoracic duct lymphocytes are transfused into isologous rats and sections of surgical wounds at varying stages of healing are studied by autoradiography. In over four hundred and eighty-five slides examined, labelled cells were found in the wound on only two occasions, while it was possible to demonstrate labelled lymphocytes both in the circulation at 72 hours and in the alveolar septa at 5 days after infusion. Transfused lymphocytes do not appear to have any significant structural role in the healing of fresh wounds, at least as can be demonstrated by the method employed.</description><creator>Piper, William A.</creator><contributor>Williams, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>The lymphocyte in healing wound</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d309t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rm46p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806328r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:01:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Animals presenting lesions of the nigrostriatal pathway had concentration of HVA in cisternal CSF lower than control animals; this constitutes evidence that the HVA in CSF originates in the brain. Parkinsonian patients had lower HVA in ventricular CS, than non-parkinsonians; no correlation was found with age, duration of illness, thalamatomy, tremor or rigidity. A possible correlation was found with akinesia. Harmaline induced a short-lasting elevation of decarboxylation of DL-DOPA-14COOH in rats, while L-tryptophan-14COOH showed lower decarboxylation; harmalol reduced the decarboxylation with bath amino acids. Patients with endogenous depression and psychomotor retardation presented lower HVA in lumbar CS, than controls. The above data are discussed in light of recent acquisitions on the function of dopamine in extrapyramidal centres.</description><creator>Papeschi, Raffaello</creator><contributor>Sourkes, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Psychiatry.</subject><title>Homovanillic acid in extrapyramidal and psychiatric diseases</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g814b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806328r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11200</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>