<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:15:23Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):6450" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n583xx60x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction : l'urticaire chronique (CU) est définie lorsque l'urticaire récidive durant au moins 6 semaines. Lorsqu'aucune cause ne peut être identifiée, cette condition est désignée urticaire spontanée chronique (CSU). Environ 50% des patients avec CSU sont considérés avoir une étiologie auto-immune qui peut être établie in vitro avec plusieurs tests incluant le test d'activation des basophiles (BAT) mesurant l'expression du marqueur CD63. En raison de sa chronicité, CU chez les enfants affecte considérablement la qualité de vie (QOL).Le lymphome cutané à cellules T (CTCL) représente une inflammation maligne qui est causée par les cellules T néoplasiques localisées à la peau. Environ 20% des patients au stade I ou II vont progresser et succomber à la maladie. Il n'est pas possible de prédire quels patients progresseront. Il est difficile de diagnostiquer CTCL puisqu'il mime des conditions cutanées bénignes. Méthodes : nous avons créé une cohorte de 139 enfants touchés par CU et suivi les patients pendant 2 ans. Nous avons étudié l'utilité de BAT pour diagnostiquer et surveiller la réponse au traitement. Nous avons évalué l'histoire naturelle et les facteurs prédictifs de la résolution à l'aide du score de l'activité hebdomadaire de l'urticaire (UAS7) et le questionnaire sur la qualité de vie (CU-Q2oL).Dans le projet de recherche sur le CTCL, nous avons utilisé le PCR en temps réel et l'expression des gènes sur les échantillons de peau de 60 patients atteints de CTCL et sur 11 lignées de cellules dérivées de patients avec CTCL pour découvrir de nouveaux marqueurs diagnostiques et pronostiques. Nous avons testé l'expression des gènes de cellules souches embryonnaires (ESC) dans ce cancer.Résultats : en fonction de la distribution logarithmique normale des valeurs de CD63 chez les enfants témoins, on a établi que l'intervalle de référence et le seuil positif pour le BAT utilisant l'expression du marquer CD63 sont de 1,2 % à 1,8 % (intervalle de confiance à 95 %) et 1,8 %, respectivement. Les valeurs du BAT chez les enfants avec la CSU ont été significativement plus élevés que chez les témoins sains. Il n'y avait pas de différence entre les résultats du BAT chez les témoins et les patients avec PU. Le BAT a été associé avec une maladie plus sévère et résistante au traitement. À l'aide du BAT, nous avons établi que 57 % des enfants dans notre cohorte avaient une origine auto-immune. Le taux de résolution annuel de CSU était de 10,3 %. Le résultat positif du BAT et la basopénie étaient statistiquement associés à une résolution plus rapide. Le CU-Q2oL au moment du recrutement a suggéré que la démangeaison, les troubles du sommeil et l'apparence physique sont les principaux facteurs affectant la qualité de vie chez les enfants avec la CU. Le score UAS7 a été réduit entre la première et la seconde visite de suivi (de 8.23 à 3,62) suggérant une bonne maîtrise des symptômes avec les recommandations de prise en charge actuelles.Les conclusions de notre recherche sur le CTCL ont démontré que 17 gènes (CCL18, CCL26, FYB, T3JAM, MMP12, LEF1, LCK, ITK, GNLY, IL2RA, IL26, IL22, CCR4, GTSF1, SYCP1, STAT5A, TOX) sont en mesure d'identifier les patients à risque de progression et distinguer le CTCL des imitateurs. Les gènes de la famille des cellules souches embryonnaires (ESC) sont exprimés dans le CTCL et certains de ces gènes (OCT4, EED, TCF3, THAP11, CHD7, TIP60, TRIM28) étaient absents dans les maladies bénignes.Conclusions : La fréquence relative de l'urticaire auto-immune chez les enfants est similaire à celle de l'adulte et, si confirmée par les études futures, la présence d'autoanticorps peut suggérer un meilleur prognostic avec une résolution plus rapide de la maladie. Le BAT peut aider à diagnostiquer la CU auto-immune et surveiller la réponse au traitement. Nos résultats d'expression des gènes dans le CTCL préparent le terrain pour le développement de l'approche personnalisée pour le diagnostic et le pronostic de ce cancer. </description><description>Introduction: Chronic urticaria (CU) is defined when hives occur for at least 6 weeks. When no identifiable cause can be found, it is classified as chronic spontaneous urticaria (CSU). Approximately 50% of patients are now considered to have an autoimmune etiology which can be established in vivo with the use of the autologous serum skin test (ASST) or in vitro with the Basophil Activation Test (BAT) measuring CD63 expression. Because of its chronicity, CU in children results in substantial impairment of health-related quality of life (QoL). While urticaria represents benign inflammation, Cutaneous T-Cell Lymphomas (CTCL) represents malignant inflammation that is driven by neoplastic CD4+ T cells in the skin. About 20% of patients with early stage will progress and succumb to their disease. Currently, it is not possible to predict which patients will progress. It is also challenging to diagnose CTCL as it mimics benign inflammatory dermatoses. It may be possible to identify a set of molecular markers that may be used to help prognosticate and diagnose this disease. Methods: We have created a cohort of 139 children affected by CSU. All patients were followed for 2 years. We have studied the utility of BAT to help diagnose and monitor response to treatment, evaluated the natural history and assessed for predictors of disease resolution using established validated tools including the weekly urticaria activity score (UAS7) and the Chronic Urticaria quality of life questionnaire (CU-Q2oL).  For CTCL research we used the RT-PCR and tested gene expression in 60 CTCL skin biopsy samples and in 11 patient-derived cell lines to discover diagnostic and prognostic markers and to gain additional insight in the molecular etiology of CTCL. We also tested the expression of Embryonic Stem Cell (ESC) genes in this cancer. Results: Based on the log-normal distribution of CD63 values in control subjects, the reference range and the cut-off for positive CD63 BAT values was established to be 1.2% to 1.8% (95%CI) and 1.8%, respectively. Children with CSU showed significantly elevated and significantly more increased BAT values as compared to healthy controls (Wilcoxon rank test p-value &lt;0.001). In contrast, no difference was found between BAT results in controls and PU patients. Higher disease activity and treatment resistance were associated with higher BAT values. Using the BAT we documented that 57% of children in our cohort had autoimmune CSU. The rate of disease resolution was 10.3% per year. Positive BAT and basopenia were statistically associated with earlier disease resolution. CU-Q2oL at time of recruitment suggested that itch, sleep impairment and physical appearance were the most important factors affecting QoL. The mean UAS7 at first follow up was 8.23 and reduced to 3.62 on next follow up suggesting an overall good control of symptoms with current management strategies.Our research findings on CTCL demonstrated that 17 genes (CCL18, CCL26, FYB, T3JAM, MMP12, LEF1, LCK, ITK, GNLY, IL2RA, IL26, IL22, CCR4, GTSF1, SYCP1, STAT5A, and TOX) are able to both identify patients who are at risk of progression and also distinguish CTCL from benign mimickers. Our findings for the first time demonstrated that many critical ESC genes are expressed in CTCL. Select ESC genes (OCT4, EED, TCF3, THAP11, CHD7, TIP60, TRIM28) were preferentially expressed in CTCL samples when compared to benign skin biopsies. Conclusions: Relative frequency of autoimmune urticaria in children is similar to adults and if proven in the future, may be a good prognostic factor predicting earlier disease resolution. BAT may serve as an effective laboratory tool to help diagnose autoimmune CSU and monitor response to treatment in moderate/severe cases.Our gene expression findings in CTCL, combined with other gene expression analyses, prepare the foundation for the development of personalized molecular approach toward diagnosis and prognostication of this cancer.</description><creator>Netchiporouk, Elena</creator><contributor>Denis Sasseville (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Elucidating pathogenesis and improving clinical management of benign cutaneous inflammation in urticaria and malignant inflammation in cutaneous T-cell lymphomas</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dg14j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xx60x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d2578</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le cancer du sein est le type de cancer le plus fréquent et la deuxième cause en importance de décès des suites du cancer chez la femme à travers le monde. Les tumeurs du sein sont classées en trois groupes thérapeutiques en function de l'expression du recepteur à l'estrogène (ER), à la progesterone (PR) et au facteur de croisssance épidermique humain 2 (HER2). Bien que l'instauration du ER, PR et HER2 comme marqueurs prognostics et predictifs dans le cancer du sein aie grandement contribué a l'amélioration des décisions thérapeutiques ainsi qu'à la survie des patientes, des milliers de femmes meurent chaque année des suites de leur maladie en raison d'une forme intrinsèque ou acquise de résistance aux médicaments. Alors que la plupart des groupes de recherche ont etudié la résistance thérapeutique induite par les oncogenes, nous proposons que les gènes suppresseurs de tumeurs pourraient avoir une plus grande influence dans le processus tumorigénique et possiblement une valeur clinique supérieure aux oncogènes pour prédire les réponses thérapeutiques. À l'aide d'une approche génomique non-biaisée, nous avons identifié une liste de gènes potentiellement suppresseurs de tumeur et mutés dans le cancer du sein, dont SPEN. Le gène SPEN code pour une protéine qui est impliquée dans la repression de la transcription médiée par des récepteurs nucléaires, y compris le ER. Compte tenu de ces données, nous avons proposé d'étudier les fonctions biologiques de SPEN controlées de façon 1) dépendante et 2) indépendante des hormones dans le cancer du sein. Nous rapportons la découverte de SPEN, un cofacteur du complexe transcriptionnel du ER, comme nouveau gène suppresseur de tumeur fréquemment muté dans le cancer du sein. Nos résultats démontrent que SPEN régule la survie des cellules et la croissance tumorale en réprimant l'expression des gènes dépendants du ER, notamment le PR, ainsi que des gènes associés à l'apoptose. De plus, notre étude apporte une preuve fonctionnelle et clinique que SPEN pourrait être employé comme biomarqueur prédisant la réponse des patientes ayant un cancer positif pour le ER au Tamoxifen et ce, possiblement dû à sa capacité de recruiter des histone déacetylases au niveau de l'ADN. Ayant démontré que SPEN atténue la signalisation hormonale dans le cancer du sein, nous avons ensuite entrepris de définir le programme transcriptionnel régulé par SPEN de façon indépendante des hormones. Cette étude nous a permis de découvrir que SPEN est co-exprimé avec un grand nombre de gènes associés au cil primaire, y compris le facteur de transcription, RFX3. Ces travaux ont conduits à l'identification de SPEN comme un nouveau régulateur de la formation des cils primaires dans les cancers du sein hormono-indépendants. Nous exposons aussi que SPEN contrôle la migration des cellules mammaires, mais uniquement de celles qui sont ciliées, ce qui suggère que SPEN coordonne le movement cellulaire par l'intermédiaire du cil primaire. Fait important, nous avons constaté que l'expression de SPEN est fortement predictive de la détection précoce de metastases chez les patients atteintes d'un cancer du sein négatif pour le ER. Les résultats presentés dans cette étude établissent donc SPEN comme corépresseur du ER, nouveau gène suppresseur de tumeur et biomarqueur potentiellement prédictif d'une réponse clinique au Tamoxifen chez les patientes atteintes d'un cancer du sein positif pour les récepteurs hormonaux. Aussi, les résultats rapportés dans cette étude démontrent que SPEN régule la formation du cil primaire, la migration des cellules et que sont expression est associée au développement de métastases chez les patientes ayant un cancer négatif pour le ER. En général, les données contenues dans cette thèse révèlent que SPEN est une protéine ayant un double rôle dans le cancer du sein et mettent en évidence que son expression pourrait avoir un potential pronostic et prédictif dans les cancers du sein hormono-dépendants et –indépendants.</description><description>Breast cancer is the most common type of cancer and the second-leading cause of cancer deaths in women worldwide. Breast tumors are classified into three distinct therapeutic groups based on the expression of the estrogen receptor (ER), progesterone receptor (PR) and human epidermal growth factor receptor 2 (HER2). The establishment of the ER, PR and HER2 as prognostic and predictive biomarkers in breast cancer has greatly improved treatment decisions and overall patient survival. However, thousands of women relapse and eventually die from their disease every year due to intrinsic or acquired resistance to therapy. While most studies have focused on oncogene-driven drug resistance, we proposed that tumour suppressor genes (TSG) might have a greater influence on the tumorigenic process and possibly a superior clinical relevance than oncogenes in predicting therapeutic responses. Using an unbiased genomic approach, we identified a list of candidate tumour suppressor genes mutated in breast cancer cells, including SPEN. The SPEN gene encodes a large protein that has previously been shown to repress transcription by nuclear receptors, including the ER. Given the latter, we proposed to examine the 1) hormone-dependent and 2) -independent biological functions of SPEN in breast cancer cells. We report the finding of SPEN, a cofactor of the ER transcriptional complex, as a novel tumour suppressor gene mutated in breast cancer that regulates cell survival and tumour growth by repressing the expression of ER-dependent genes, including the PR as well as apoptosis-related genes. In addition, our work provides functional and clinical evidence for SPEN as a candidate predictive biomarker of Tamoxifen response in ER-positive breast cancers, possibly due to its recruitment of histone-deacetylase enzymes to DNA. Having shown that SPEN attenuates hormonal signalling in breast cancer, we then investigated the hormone-independent transcriptional program regulated by SPEN in breast cancer cells and uncovered a significant enrichment for genes associated with the cilium, including the ciliogenic transcription factor, RFX3. This work led to the identification of SPEN as a novel regulator of primary cilia formation in hormone-independent breast cancers. We further demonstrated that SPEN regulates migration in ciliated breast cells exclusively, suggesting that it may coordinate cellular movement through primary-cilia dependent mechanisms. Importantly, we found that SPEN expression is strongly predictive of early metastasis in patients with ER-negative breast cancers. The findings reported in this study therefore establish SPEN as a corepressor of the ER, novel tumour suppressor gene and candidate predictive biomarker of Tamoxifen response in patients with hormone receptor positive breast cancers. Furthermore, they show that SPEN regulates primary cilia formation, cell migration and is associated with metastasis in patients with ER-negative breast cancers. Altogether, the data contained within this thesis reveal that SPEN has dual roles in breast cancer and that its expression levels are prognostic in both hormone-dependent and -independent breast cancers. </description><creator>Légaré, Stéphanie</creator><contributor>Mark Basik (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>A study of SPEN functions in breast cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dc457.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d2578</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sj88c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bien qu'il n'y ait pas de remède pour la plupart des maladies chroniques, celles-ci peuvent être contrôlées, par exemple, grâce à la thérapie médicamenteuse. Dans cette thèse, je me concentre sur le contrôle de l'hypertension, l'une des maladies chroniques les plus répandues, avec des conséquences très graves, mais qui a reçu peu d'attention dans la gestion des maladies chroniques, en général, et dans le domaine de la recherche opérationnelle, en particulier. Comme la mesure de la pression artérielle est un problème difficile, mais fondamental dans le contrôle de l'hypertension, je mène cette étude dans deux cadres qui sont distincts à la fois du point de vue théorique et empirique. Le premier cadre est basé sur la mesure sans bruit hypothétique de la pression artérielle. Cette analyse, en effet, constitue un point de repère pour la variante plus réaliste du problème dans le deuxième cadre. Après avoir formulé le problème en tant que processus de décision de Markov, j'identifie un ensemble de propriétés structurales intéressantes pour les politiques de prescription optimales. Dans le deuxième cadre, je détends l'hypothèse de mesures sans bruit, et propose un cadre de modélisation différente pour intégrer explicitement l'incertitude de mesure. Ce modèle est donc utilisé pour simultanément apprendre le véritable état de la pression artérielle du patient et caractériser les politiques optimales de traitement de celui-ci. Après avoir résolu un défi majeur dans l'intégration du bruit de mesure dans le modèle d'optimisation dynamique, je démontre les nouvelles politiques optimales, leurs différences avec les politiques optimales précédentes, et leurs renseignements sur les pratiques médicales. En incluant un ensemble de caractéristiques clés des patients dans les modèles analytiques, je montre le rôle de la personnalisation dans les prescriptions de médicaments.</description><description>Although there is no cure for most chronic diseases, they can be controlled, e.g. through medication therapy. In this thesis, I focus on the control of hypertension, one of the most prevalent chronic diseases which has very serious consequences, yet has received little attention in chronic disease management, in general, and in Operations Research (OR)/Management Science (MS), in particular. Since blood pressure measurement is a challenging, yet fundamental issue in hypertension control, I conduct this study within two frameworks which differ both on theoretical and empirical bases. The first framework is based on the hypothetical noise-free measurement of blood pressure. This analysis, indeed, constitutes a benchmark for the more realistic variant of the problem in the second framework. Having formulated the problem as a Markov Decision Process (MDP), I identify a set of interesting structural properties for optimal prescription policies. In the second framework, I relax the assumption of noise-free measurements, and propose a different modeling framework to explicitly incorporate the measurement uncertainty. This model hence is used to simultaneously learn the patient's true blood pressure state and characterize the optimal treatment policies. After resolving a key challenge in incorporating the measurement noise with the dynamic optimization model, I demonstrate the new optimal policies, discuss their differences with the previous optimal policies, and summarize their insights to medical practices. By including a set of key patient characteristics in the analytical models, I show the impact of personalization in the medication prescriptions.</description><creator>Zargoush, Abdolmanaf</creator><contributor>Nafiz Vedat Verter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Management</subject><title>An analytical framework for personalized treatment of chronic diseases with noisy measurement: application to hypertension management</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dc46h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sj88c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Desautels Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290d16h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Major depressive disorder (MDD) is a highly prevalent psychiatric condition affecting more than 350 million people worldwide and is a key risk factor for suicidal behaviors. Only a portion of individuals suffering from MDD die by suicide, nonetheless, worldwide, suicide accounts for more loss of life than do wars and homicides together. Much of the biological research in MDD and suicide over the last half century has aimed at elucidating molecular mechanisms underlying these conditions, with the ultimate goal of developing therapeutic agents to better treat depression and prevent suicidal outcomes. In hopes of better understanding molecular mechanisms, the field has turned to epigenetics to study functional genomic changes that may that underlie MDD and suicide. At first, a strong focus had been placed on investigating how 5-methylcytosine (5mC) may act to alter gene expression. Most recently, the rediscovery of 5-hydroxymethylcytosine (5hmC) has shed light on additional cytosine modifications that act together to exert their effects on gene expression. Here, we investigate methods to target 5hmC in post-mortem brain tissue of individuals with MDD who died by suicide. We determined the stability of both 5mC and 5hmC across multiple post-mortem intervals, thereby giving confidence to the use of this tissue for studies on cytosine modifications. Furthermore, we identified changes in 5mC and 5hmC in insulin signaling pathways, suggesting its dysregulation to be a putative biological mechanism associated with MDD and suicide. Together, although much work remains, our findings provide insight into additional targets that could be used as biomarkers or pharmaceutical agents to reduce the prevalence of MDD and decrease the rates of suicidality.  </description><description>La dépression majeure (DM) est une maladie mentale dont la prévalence est particulièrement élevée, affectant plus de 350 millions d'individus dans le monde. C'est un facteur de risque majeur pour le suicide, et même si les individus souffrant de dépression ne passent pas tous à l'acte, le suicide fait plus de victimes que les guerres et homicides réunis. Afin de développer de nouveaux traitements pour lutter contre la DM et le suicide, la recherche s'efforce depuis 50 ans à élucider les mécanismes moléculaires qui la sous-tendent. Les efforts se sont tournés vers la compréhension des mécanismes épigénétiques pour étudier les changements fonctionnels dans le génome liés à la DM et le suicide. L'accent fut d'abord mis sur la méthylation de l'ADN (5mC) comme modulateur de l'expression génique. Plus récemment, la redécouverte de l'hydroxyméthylation (5hmC) a pu mettre en évidence de nouvelles modifications des cytosines agissant de concert pour moduler l'expression des gènes. Le présent travail s'intéresse aux méthodes d'identification post-mortem des 5hmC dans le cerveau d'individus souffrant de DM et morts par suicide. Nous avons déterminé la stabilité des 5mC et 5hmC a différents intervalles après le décès, afin de justifier l'utilisation des tissus post-mortem pour l'étude des modifications des cytosines. De plus, nous avons identifié des changements quantitatifs des 5mC et 5hmC au sein de gènes participant aux voies de signalisation de l'insuline, suggérant que ces changements sont des marqueurs biologiques pertinents de la DM et du suicide. De façon générale, même s'il reste beaucoup de chemin à parcourir, nos résultats pointent vers de nouvelles cibles moléculaires comme biomarqueurs ou cibles pharmacologiques prometteuses pour prévenir la DM et réduire l'occurrence du suicide.</description><creator>Gross, Jeffrey</creator><contributor>Gustavo Turecki (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Characterizing 5-hydroxymethylcytosine in post-mortem human brain and major depressive disorder</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w494g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290d16h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zx045</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Il n'y a pas encore eu d'analyse de discours approfondie du séminaire de recherche des cycles supérieurs. Or les cycles supérieurs offrent un environnement distinct de l'école primaire ou secondaire qui ont été le site des recherches jusqu'à date. Par le biais de cet étude, nous décrivons certains mécanismes linguistiques qui sont utilisés pour négocier le sens en interaction. La négociation du sens est nécessaire pour garantir l'intersubjectivité—la compréhension partagée—condition nécessaire d'une activité communicative réussite. L'activité communicative figure comme le mode d'interaction privilégié dans le séminaire, conçu ici comme une communauté de pratique. La présente étude propose une méthodologie novatrice, élaborée dans une perspective ethnographique, qui emploie l'analyse déictique, (deixis : la coordination des actions et de la parole en situations communicatives) dans l'occurrence, l'utilisation de pronoms démonstratifs, pour capter les processus linguistiques mobilisés pour négocier le sens lors des interactions communicatives. Cette activité discursive s'avère nécessaire dans le contexte du séminaire de recherche où la majeure partie du discours est abstrait et indirect. L'objectif principal de cette étude était de recenser l'emploi du déixis par les participants dans le maintien de l'intersubjectivité et pour mobiliser les savoirs en interaction. La recherche a été guidée par les questions suivantes. (a) Comment les participants déploient-ils les ressources déictiques pour mobiliser les savoirs dans le séminaire de recherche ? (b) Comment le rôle du participant affecte-il son utilisation du déixis en interaction ? Par le biais d'une série d'analyses itératives et récursives, nous constatons que (a) les participants négocient le sens de leurs énoncés par une compréhension partagée de la situation communicative. (b) Le déixis est impliqué dans la mobilisation des savoirs. (c) Les actes de paroles déictiques servent à (se) situer, (s') orienter, (se) positionner, et coordonner idées et actions en interaction communicative. (d) Les séquences d'actes de paroles déictiques servent à accomplir des actions comme affirmer, maintenir la cohésion et cohérence du sens, subordonner une phrase, indiquer le mode ou la disposition, porter un jugement, clarifier, différencier, décrire, et montrer son (dés)accord. Enfin, (e) la variation entre participants dans leur exploitation des ressources déictiques semble être indicatrice de leur compétence pratique dans le domaine de la recherche qualitative et du rôle qu'il ou elle adopte dans la situation communicative. Ainsi elle représenterait leur compréhension actuelle de la situation et leur maîtrise du discours, qui peut être plus ou moins sophistiquée, tout comme leur performance déictique correspondante. La performance du déixis se distinguerait effectivement comme un composante importante d'une pratique compétente. L'étude du déixis dans des environnements d'apprentissage nous permettrait de capter les trajectoires d'apprentissage dans la communauté de pratique.</description><description>There are few discourse analyses of the graduate seminar even though graduate learning environment presents a very different interactional environment compared to the primary or secondary classroom, which has been the focus of most classroom discourse research to date. An outstanding problem in discourse analysis is how to analyze shared understanding and the present study proposes a novel methodology grounded in an ethnographic perspective based in the analysis of deixis, (deixis: coordinating actions and speech in communicative situations). Here we focus specifically on the use of demonstrative pronouns for capturing the linguistic processes involved in the negotiation of meaning in communicative interactions. The negotiation of meaning appears to be a central feature of seminar work that largely occurs through discourse, in which most of the talk is both displaced and abstract. The main objective of this study is to discover how participants use deixis to maintain a shared understanding and to negotiate meaning in communicative interaction. The research questions that guided this study are (a) How do participants employ deixis to negotiate meaning in the graduate research seminar? (b) How do participants' use of deixis vary according to the roles they adopt in the graduate research seminar? Through a series of analyses, we found that (a) Participants negotiate meaning through a shared understanding of situation. (b) Deixis is involved in the negotiation of meaning and the maintenance of shared understanding. (c) Deictic speech acts are used to situate, orient, position, and coordinate ideas and actions in communicative interaction. (d) Patterns of deictic speech acts enact discourse moves like positing, marking cohesion, subordinating an idea, introducing a complement, indicating mode/mood, making a judgment, clarifying, disambiguating, describing, and (dis)agreeing. Finally, (e) the differential deployment of deictic resources within the seminar situation varies as a function of a speakers' intent as manifested by the roles they adopt in the interaction. Thus, deixis use appears to be related to the participants' ongoing understanding of situation and their command of the discourse, which can be more, or less, sophisticated, and whose performance of deixis is correspondingly more, or less, sophisticated. Thus, the study of deixis in learning environments has the potential to capture learning trajectories in communities of practice.</description><creator>Lemay, David</creator><contributor>Mark Wesley Aulls (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Alenoush Saroyan (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Educational and Counselling Psychology</subject><title>Negotiating meaning: discourse in the graduate research seminar</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182n72c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zx045</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zh02h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the character of the bohemian artist in late-Victorian culture, with special focus on three fictional texts and one non-fictional account: George Moore's A Modern Lover (1883), George Gissing's The Emancipated (1890), George Du Maurier's Trilby (1894), and Arthur Ransome's Bohemia in London (1907). These texts frame countercultural painters and illustrators as possible saviours of modern art at the turn of the century. In each text, bohemian artists take the British art world by storm, infiltrating the bastion of middle-class aesthetics, the Royal Academy. In challenging the establishment's artistic conventions (particularly its preference for classical works) and its commercial marketplace, bohemian characters like Moore's Thompson, Gissing's Mallard, and Du Maurier's Little Billee produce offhand sketches and unfinished or careless paintings, working without working, or making art that remains in a liminal state between complete and incomplete. Their ambivalence towards artistic production reveals their suspension between a reluctance to participate in the commercial art market, and their need to do so to survive. In parallel with this conflict, all four texts end inconclusively, suggesting the potential of an avant-garde movement while remaining wary of its sustainability. Jed Esty's study of bildungsromans, Unseasonable Youth: Modernism, Colonialism, and the Fiction of Development (2012), argues that late-century novels of arrested development compromise the health of the British Empire. In a similar vein, I argue that these four künstlerroman critique the health of English art. My first chapter examines the bohemian collective in Moore's A Modern Lover, showing how this group rises and falls through its novel approach to artistic labour. My second chapter focuses on Gissing's solitary bohemian Mallard in The Emancipated who prizes his hallucinatory dreams over the paintings that he submits for exhibition. In my third chapter, I study Du Maurier's Trilby, analyzing how the on-the-spot illustrations of its protagonist Little Billee skewer bourgeois concepts of creative production. My fourth chapter on Ransome's Bohemia in London explores the bohemian painter's social escapes and the way they both invigorate and doom his artistic practices. A brief conclusion considers my texts in the context of other treatments of nineteenth-century creative labour, such as James Eli Adams' Dandies and Desert Saints (1995) and Andrew Dowling's Manliness and the Male Novelist in Victorian Literature (2001). Despite vital work from Mary Gluck, Elizabeth Wilson and Jerrold Seigel on bohemianism, the fin-de-siècle bohemian in English literature remains understudied, a neglect which this thesis corrects.  </description><description>Cette thèse examine le personnage de l'artiste bohémien présent dans la culture à la fin de l'époque victorienne, mettant un accent particulier sur trois textes fictionnels et un texte non-fictionnel: A Modern Lover (1883) de George Moore, The Emancipated (1890) de George Gissing, Trilby (1894) de George Du Maurier, et Bohemia in London (1907) de Arthur Ransome.  Au tournant du siècle, ces textes dépeignaient les peintres et les artistes contra-culturels comme des sauveurs potentiels de l'art moderne. Dans chaque texte, des artistes bohémiens captivent le milieu artistique britannique et infiltrent la Royal Academy, bastion de l'esthétique de la classe moyenne. En contestant les conventions artistiques de l'établissement (en particulier, la préférence pour les œuvres classiques) et le marché commercial, les personnages bohémiens tels que Thompson (Moore), Mallard (Gissing), et Little Billee (Du Maurier) créent des croquis désinvoltes et des tableaux inachevés ou insouciants. Ils travaillent sans travailler, ou bien ils créent de l'art qui demeure dans un entre-deux, un espace liminal entre achevé et inachevé. Leur ambivalence face à la production artistique démontre un conflit interne; ils sont déchirés entre leur hésitation à participer au marché commercial et leur besoin d'y participer pour survivre. Parallèlement, les quatre textes aboutissent à des fins imprécises et peu concluantes, indiquant le potentiel pour un mouvement avant-gardiste tout en demeurant à l'affut de sa pérennité. Dans son étude de bildungsromans, nommé Unseasonable Youth: Modernism, Colonialism, and the Fiction of Development (2012), Jed Esty soutient que les romans fin-de-siècle portant sur le ralentissement du développement compromettent la santé de l'Empire britannique. Dans cette même perspective, je soutiens que ces quatre künstlerromans critiquent la santé de l'art britannique. Mon premier chapitre examine le groupe de bohémiens dans l'œuvre de Moore, A Modern Lover, et illustre l'ascension et la chute de ce groupe à travers leur approche novatrice au travail artistique. Mon deuxième chapitre porte sur Mallard, le bohémien solitaire de Gissing dans The Emancipated, un personnage qui valorise ses rêves hallucinatoires plus que les tableaux qu'il présente à l'exposition. Mon troisième chapitre porte sur Trilby, l'œuvre de Du Maurier, et examine comment les illustrations sur place du protagoniste, Little Billee, attaquent les notions bourgeois de la production créative. Mon quatrième chapitre, portant sur Bohemia in London de Ransome, explore les évasions sociales du peintre bohémien et examine comment celles-ci servent simultanément à vivifier et à condamner ses pratiques artistiques. Pour conclure, je considère mes textes dans le cadre d'autres travaux de recherches sur le travail de création au XIXe siècle, tels que Dandies and Desert Saints (1995) de James Eli Adams, et Manliness and the Male Novelist in Victorian Literature (2001) de Andrew Dowling. Malgré le travail indispensable de Mary Gluck, Elizabeth Wilson, et Jerrold Seigel sur la bohème, le bohémien fin-de-siècle dans la littérature anglaise demeure un sujet de recherche fort peu étudié, une lacune que cette thèse contribue à corriger. </description><creator>MacDonald, John</creator><contributor>Peter Gibian (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Tabitha Sparks (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>English</subject><title>Ambivalent Ambitions: The fin-de-siècle Bohemian's Self-Division</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj2364796.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zh02h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k643b360m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Persons with stroke have deficits in community ambulation that may be related to difficulties in circumventing stationary and moving obstacles. A scoping review is undertaken to show that virtual reality (VR) based interventions are beneficial for balance and mobility rehabilitation post stroke, which may enhance community ambulation. To further advance VR tools for stroke rehabilitation, four research studies are conducted to compare obstacle circumvention strategies between chronic stroke and healthy individuals in response to stationary and moving obstacles (approaching head-on, 30° left and right). The first study proposes a new outcome measure – dynamic clearance (DC) – to characterize the dynamic interaction between an individual and the obstacle. DC is responsive to differences in circumvention strategies between stroke and healthy individuals and is more sensitive to variations in circumvention strategies than the commonly used outcome – minimum distance. In the second study, a mathematical model comprising of predictive and emergent components is described. The predictive component uses linear prediction that enables individuals to predict the minimum distance between themselves and the obstacle at all future spatial positions. The emergent component modelled using a differential games approach, aims at finding an optimal circumvention strategy while considering the influence of the obstacle, the target and the velocity of the individual evading the obstacle. At critical spatial positions in proximity of the obstacle, the predicted minimum distance (obtained from the predictive component) remains constant in both healthy and stroke individuals. It is also closely associated with the observed minimum distance, indicating that safe distance in proximity to the obstacle is regulated by the predictive processes. Obstacle influence varies with obstacle approach directions and preferred side of circumvention, especially in the stroke group, suggesting that the model can accommodate the continuum from normal to altered locomotor adaptations. The change in obstacle influence is associated with the observed DC, both of which are indicative of the dynamic interaction with the obstacle. The two processes may interact cooperatively such that predictive processes ensure preservation of safe distances from the obstacle while emergent processes guide efficient locomotor strategies. The third study contrasts circumvention strategies for different obstacle conditions between stroke (n=12) and healthy (n=12) individuals with respect to obstacle clearance. Both stroke and healthy individuals maintain a larger DC when obstacle approaches head-on as compared to being stationary. When the obstacles approach diagonally, two distinct sub-groups emerge amongst post-stroke participants: Vsame (circumventing to the same side as obstacle approach) and Vopp (circumventing to the opposite side of obstacle approach, a strategy similar to the control group). The Vsame group has greater functional limitations than the Vopp group and maintain larger DC. The fourth study compares postural coordination strategies used for circumvention in the same sample as the third study. In comparison with controls, persons with stroke use coordination strategies that enhance safety by initiating circumvention with a side step (increase in step width by the foot ipsilateral to the side of circumvention) and larger horizontal body segmental reorientations for stationary, head-on and diagonal obstacle approaches, suggestive of altered postural coordination. Individuals with stroke thus use a cautious approach to obstacle circumvention, especially in case of moving obstacles and use circumvention strategies that enhance safety and stability.</description><description>Les individus ayant subi un accident vasculaire cérébral (AVC) présentent des déficits demarche dans la communauté, possiblement en raison de difficultés à éviter des obstacles. Une revue de la littérature a montré que les interventions de réalité virtuelle sont bénéfiques pour l'équilibre et la réadaptation post-AVC, ce qui permettrait d'améliorer la marche dans la communauté. Afin de développer davantage la réadaptation post-AVC par la réalité virtuelle, quatre études de recherche ont comparé les stratégies de contournement entre des individus avec AVC chronique et des individus en santé en réponse à des obstacles stationnaires et en mouvement (approches de face, 30° à gauche et à droite). La première étude a permis de développer une nouvelle mesure de résultat appelée dégagement dynamique (DD) qui caractérise l'interaction dynamique entre l'individu et l'obstacle. Le DD a répondu aux différences de stratégies de contournement entre les individus avec AVC et ceux en santé et a été plus sensible que la mesure usuelle de distance minimale. La deuxième étude décrit un modèle mathématique englobant des éléments prédictifs et émergents. L'élément prédictif utilise deux caractéristiques prédictives linéaires permettant à un individu de prédire la distance minimale entre lui et l'obstacle. La composante émergente, modélisée selon l'approche de jeu différentiel, vise à trouver une stratégie de contournement optimale en marchant vers la cible tout en considérant l'influence de l'obstacle, la cible et la vitesse de l'individu évitant l'obstacle. La distance minimale prédite (obtenue de l'élément prédictif) est demeurée constante à proximité de l'obstacle chez les individus avec AVC et en santé. Cette distance prédite était étroitement associée à la distance par rapport à l'obstacle au point de croisement, indiquant que la distance sécuritaire à proximité de l'obstacle est régie par des processus prédictifs. L'influence de l'obstacle pouvait varier selon la direction de l'obstacle et la préférence quant au côté de contournement, suggérant que le modèle peut représenter l'ensemble du continuum d'adaptation motrice, de normale à altérée. Le changement d'influence de l'obstacle était étroitement associé avec le DD, tous deux reflétant l'interaction dynamique avec l'obstacle. Les processus prédictif et émergent pourraient interagir de telle façon que le premier assure la préservation d'une distance sécuritaire par rapport à l'obstacle et le second guide l'efficacité des stratégies locomotrices. La troisième étude compare les stratégies de contournement entre les individus avec AVC (n=12) et ceux en santé (n=12). Les deux groupes ont maintenu un DD plus large lorsque l'obstacle approchait de plein front comparativement à lorsqu'il était stationnaire. Lors de l'approche diagonale, deux sous-groupes ont émergé parmi les individus post-AVC: Vmême (contournement par le même côté que l'approche de l'obstacle) et Vopp (contournement du côté opposé à l'approche de l'obstacle, soit une stratégie similaire au groupe contrôle). Le groupe Vmême était caractérisé par de plus grandes limitations fonctionnelles et un plus grand DD comparativement au groupe Vopp . La quatrième étude compare les stratégies de coordination posturale utilisées pour contourner l'obstacle dans le même échantillon d'individus qu'à la troisième étude. Les individus avec AVC initiaient les contournements avec un pas de côté (augmentation de la largeur du pas par le pied ipsilatéral au côté du contournement) et avec une réorientation segmentaire horizontale plus large du corps pour les obstacles stationnaires et les approches de front et diagonales, suggérant une coordination posturale altérée. Les individus avec AVC se sont donc avérés être plus prudents dans l'approche de contournement d'obstacle, particulièrement pour les obstacles en mouvement, en utilisant des stratégies de contournements qui amélioraient la sécurité et la stabilité.</description><creator>Darekar, Anuja</creator><contributor>Joyce Fung (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Anouk Lamontagne (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Physical and Occupational Therapy</subject><title>Obstacle circumvention strategies for spatial navigation in healthy and post-stroke individuals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t180m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b360m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vx021h79f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Some materials when exposed to the atmosphere can exhibit a rise in temperature without requiring an external heat source. These materials are generally referred to as pyrophoric or self-heating substances. The handling, storage, and transportation of these products has been, and continues to be, a challenge. Reliably assessing the self-heating potential of these products is an essential first step. Over the years, a number of test methodologies have been developed and successfully used to "raise a red flag" when a material exhibits self-heating properties. A widely accepted test method recommended by United Nations is routinely used to certify the safety of shipping pyrophoric goods. Test work conducted at McGill University has shown that the U.N. approved test and other single stage testing methods can yield diametrically opposed test results when evaluating the self-heating properties of sulphides. Depending on the degree of oxidation (weathering), an active sulphide can exhibit a level of self-heating values ranging from less than 5J/g to 50J/g. Under the currently accepted analysis, a sulphide concentrate could be tested and shown to be negative (exhibiting minimal heating) which would be considered safe for shipping. If, however, that concentrate is stored over an extended period of time in a weathering favorable environment, the concentrate could oxidize and present a handling, storage, or shipping problem. To make the U.N. and other single stage self-heating procedure more reliable when testing of sulphides, it is suggested that a pre-weathering step is incorporated with the self-heating testing.The second study focuses on the transition of sulphide containing material from heating in Stage A (low temperature heating) to Stage B (mid-high temperature heating). With increasing sample temperature, sample moisture decreased leading to elimination of water which is a key reactant in stage A. Stage B reactions are independent from Stage A reactions and moisture is not required. It has been hypothesized that transition zone results from orthorhombic sulphur (stable below 95.3C) transforming into monoclinic (beta) sulphur (stable from 95.3C to 119.6C). FR-test technique was used to determine this transition zone. Past studies by F. Rosenblum have shown that transition from Stage A to Stage B is unclear. A study was undertaken to examine the relationship between the Stage transition and various factors including weathering duration, ambient temperature and initial element sulphur content of a sample. Results suggest that self-heating capacity measurements do not indicate whether a sample will progress to Stage B.</description><description>Lorsqu'ils sont exposés à l'atmosphère, certains matériaux peuvent présenter une élévation de température sans influence d'une source de chaleur externe. Ces substances sont généralement désignées sous le nom de substances pyrophoriques, ou auto-échauffantes. La manipulation, le stockage et le transport de ces matériaux constituent depuis de nombreuses années un défi qui se pose aujourd'hui encore. Évaluer de façon fiable le potentiel d'auto-échauffement de ces produits représente une première étape essentielle. Au fil des ans, plusieurs méthodologies de test ont été élaborées et employées avec succès afin de « sonner l'alarme » lorsqu'un matériau présente des propriétés auto-échauffantes. Une méthode de test largement reconnue et recommandée par les Nations Unies est habituellement utilisée pour certifier que les produits pyrophoriques sont transportés en toute sécurité. Cependant, une série d'essais menée à l'Université McGill a montré que le test approuvé par l'ONU, tout comme d'autres méthodes de test en une seule étape, pouvaient produire des résultats diamétralement opposés lorsqu'on les appliquait pour déterminer les propriétés auto-échauffantes des sulfures. En fonction de son degré d'oxydation (ou altération), un sulfure actif peut présenter un pouvoir calorifique d'auto-échauffement allant de moins de 5 J/g à 50 J/g. D'après l'analyse actuellement reconnue, un concentré de sulfure peut être testé négatif (montrant un échauffement moindre) et son transport jugé sûr. Cependant, si ce concentré est stocké pendant une période prolongée dans un environnement favorisant son altération, il peut s'oxyder et présenter des problèmes de manipulation, stockage ou transport. Afin de rendre le test de l'ONU et les autres procédures d'auto-échauffement à une étape plus fiables lors de l'évaluation des sulfures, il est donc suggéré d'intégrer une étape de pré-altération dans le test d'auto-échauffement.La seconde étude se penche sur la transition d'une substance contenant du sulfure de l'étape A (chauffage à basse température) à l'étape B (chauffage à moyenne température). L'augmentation de la température de l'échantillon provoque une réduction de son taux d'humidité conduisant à la disparition de l'eau, qui est un réactif-clé durant l'étape A. Les réactions intervenant durant l'étape B sont indépendantes de l'étape A et ne nécessitent pas d'eau. Il a été supposé que la zone de transition est causée par la transformation du soufre orthorhombique (stable en-dessous de 95,3°C) en soufre monoclinique (ou soufre bêta, stable entre 95,3°C et 119,6°C). La technique de test FR a été utilisée pour déterminer cette zone de transition. Des études passées menées par F. Rosenblum ont montré que la transition de l'étape A à l'étape B est ambigüe. Une étude a été entreprise afin d'examiner la relation entre la transition d'une étape à l'autre et de nombreux facteurs tels que la durée d'altération, la température ambiante, et la quantité de soufre initialement présente dans l'échantillon. Les résultats suggèrent que la mesure de la capacité d'auto-échauffement ne permet pas de déterminer si un échantillon va progresser à l'étape B.</description><creator>Moon, Sungjae</creator><contributor>James A Finch (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Mining and Materials</subject><title>Self-heating of sulphide ores: transition from stage A to B and evaluating reliability of U.N. test protocol</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hj161.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021h79f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xs55mf48p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le système visuel possède des ressources biologiques limitées afin de traiter l'ensemble des informations sensorielles qui lui parviennent. Conséquemment, le système visuel a développé un mécanisme qui priorise le traitement des stimuli comportementaux importants. Cette compétition entre les représentations neuronales des stimuli est établie soit d'une manière « top-down » ou « bottom-up ». La compétition bottom-up implique que les propriétés sensorielles des stimuli définissent leur priorité. En compétition top-down, des processus cognitifs de haut niveau déterminent quel stimulus devrait être priorisé. L'un des plus étudié processus top-down est celui de la sélection attentionnelle. Il reste à savoir si ce mécanisme de priorisation des stimuli visuels procède par l'amplification des représentations neuronales des stimuli comportementaux importants, par l'atténuation des stimuli non-importants, ou par une combinaison des deux. Cette thèse vise à répondre à ce débat actuel, avec un accent particulier sur les stimuli qui sont écologiquement valides (i.e. stimuli qui sont historiquement importants pour la survie et la reproduction d'une espèce).Premièrement, j'ai étudié si le cerveau assigne automatiquement priorité aux certaines stimuli qui sont écologiquement valides en utilisant la rivalité binoculaire. La rivalité binoculaire est l'alternation spontanée entre le percept conscient d'une de deux images présentées chacune à un seul œil. La durée pour laquelle un stimulus est perçu plutôt que l'autre est définie en partie par les propriétés saillantes de ce stimulus. La rivalité binoculaire a été utilisée dans les deux premiers chapitres de cette thèse afin de voir si la saillance bottom-up est influencée par la pertinence écologique des stimuli. D'abords, nous avons trouvé qu'un stimulus d'expansion visuel – un marqueur de collision potentiel – est perçu plus longtemps en rivalité binoculaire que d'autres stimuli de mouvement visuel. Ensuite, nous avons trouvé que le marqueur Duchenne – une subtile contraction des muscles para-oculaires signifiant l'honnêteté émotionnelle – est perçu plus longtemps seulement lorsque qu'il peut être perçu en conjonction avec le reste des traits faciaux pour des visages tristes ou heureux. En résumé, que ce soit en utilisant le mouvement ou bien les émotions, la pertinence écologique d'un stimulus impacte sa saillance visuelle, et conséquemment, sa priorisation en compétition bottom-up.En outre, j'ai investigué si l'amplification, l'atténuation, ou ces deux mécanismes étaient responsables de la compétition entre stimuli visuels dans un contexte top-down. En utilisant l'électrophysiologie unicellulaire chez le singe macaque dans la région corticale temporale médiale (MT), j'ai démontré que l'atténuation est le contributeur majeur au mécanisme de sélection attentionnel et que le décours temporel de cette atténuation est exponentiel. J'attribue la plus grande atténuation découverte dans ces expériences à l'utilisation d'une différente mesure de référence neuronale afin de calculer les indices de modulation attentionnelle. En fin, j'ai modélisé le mécanisme suppressif des neurones de la région MT et mis en relation ce modèle avec la performance du singe macaque à la tâche attentionnelle.Pris ensemble, mes résultats suggèrent que la pertinence écologique des stimuli visuels devrait être prise en compte dans l'élaboration des modèles comportementaux de la rivalité binoculaire et qu'une différente mesure de référence neuronale devrait être prise en compte dans les calculassions des indices de modulation attentionnelle. D'un intérêt particulier, plusieurs résultats obtenus dans cette thèse suggèrent qu'une tâche de rivalité binoculaire pourrait être un outil clinique non-invasif afin d'évaluer les mécanismes de suppression attentionnelle chez des populations de patients éprouvant des difficultés à filtrer la multitude de stimuli de notre environnement visuel (ex., autisme).</description><description>The visual system possesses a limited amount of biological resources to cope with the multitude of input it receives. As such, the visual system has evolved mechanisms that select which sensory stimuli need to be prioritized for further processing. Stimuli compete for neural representation in either a bottom-up or top-down manner. Bottom-up implies that properties of stimuli determine what should be prioritized and often refers to stimuli saliency. Top-down, on the other hand, refers to cognitive processes that take into account internal states to appoint which stimuli are most relevant. One of the most widely investigated top-down processes is attention, the process of selecting and modulating behaviorally relevant information at the expense of irrelevant information. It remains to be settled whether attention enhances behaviorally relevant stimulus representations, suppresses behaviorally irrelevant stimulus representations, or a combination of both. This thesis aims to assess this ongoing debate, with particular focus on stimuli that are ecologically relevant (i.e., stimuli that signal something significant for survival).Initially, I investigated whether the brain automatically assigns priority of processing to certain stimuli that are ecologically more relevant using binocular rivalry. Binocular rivalry is the spontaneous alternation between two images presented monocularly. The duration over which one stimulus is observed is driven, in part, by its salience. Binocular rivalry was used in the first two chapters to assess whether bottom-up salience was influenced by ecological relevance. First, expanding motion stimuli—a marker of potential collision and optic flow—is perceived longer than other types of motion stimuli. Second, the Duchenne eye wrinkle—a subtle facial feature signifying an intense and sincere emotional expression—is perceived for significantly longer only when it can be holistically processed in conjunction with the remainder of facial features for either smiling or sad faces. Therefore, whether using motion or emotion, a stimulus' ecological relevance indeed impacts its salience, bottom-up competition, and, ultimately, perception. Additionally, I addressed whether enhancement or suppression, or even both, were critical for neural modulations during top-down attention when motion stimuli competitively interact. Across two experiments on non-human primates, single electrode data was collected from the motion visual area medial temporal (MT). I not only show that suppression was the chief contributor during attention, but I also demonstrate the time course of this exponentially decaying suppression. The contribution of suppression to attentional selection was greater in our model compared with previous models due to the use of a different neuron reference response when computing attentional modulations. Finally, I model MT neurons' suppressive mechanism and relate it to the monkey's improved performance during longer periods of maintained attention. Taken together, my results provide insight into a stimulus property that has traditionally been neglected in models of binocular rivalry dynamics—ecological relevance—as well as into the neural mechanisms of attentional selection. Importantly, many of the findings in this thesis support binocular rivalry as a potential, non-invasive diagnostic and behavioral tool—especially for clinical populations that suffer impaired suppression (e.g., autism) and therefore are overwhelmed by the plethora of visual input surrounding us.</description><creator>Malek, Nour</creator><contributor>Julio Martinez Trujillo (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Physiology</subject><title>Competitive interactions between neural representations during binocular rivalry and attention</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n368s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mf48p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gf06g528b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bian is a concerto for solo sheng and chamber orchestra that takes the principles of Jingbian, a Chinese Buddhist tradition of transforming Buddhist sūtras into visual art forms and vernacular narratives, as its basic source of inspiration. This dissertation is in two parts consisting of the concerto in full score and an analysis of the work. The analysis begins by discussing the tradition of jingbian and its guiding principles, and situates Bian among other works drawing from the tradition, and ways in which elements from the Medicine Buddha Sūtra are used as a source for musical material in Bian. This is followed by a discussion of the work's flexible harmonic system, the distinct harmonic progressions of each section, the processes within each section that reflect the ritualistic and mystical nature of various sūtra elements, and the translation of abstract Buddhist concepts into music, inspired by visual symbolism and metaphors of the Buddhist tradition. The formal structure of the entire piece and of individual sections is described in relation to the narrative of the Medicine Buddha Sūtra, and how the form lends musical coherence to the work. Finally, the paper examines the effectiveness of the work's compositional approach to transforming Buddhist sūtra into musical representations, and points to the potential for future compositional exploration.</description><description>Bian est un concerto pour sheng et orchestre de chambre, qui prend son inspiration dans les principes du Jingian, une tradition Chinoise qui consiste à transformer les sūtras bouddhistes en art visuels et récits populaires. Cette thèse est structurée en deux parties, soit la partition complète du concerto et une analyse détaillée de l'œuvre. L'analyse débute par une discussion de la tradition du jingbian et de ses principes directeurs afin de situer Bian dans le contexte de cette tradition et de montrer comment des éléments du sūtra du Bouddha de médecine y servent de matériau musical. Suit une discussion du système harmonique général de l'œuvre, des progressions harmoniques propres à chaque section et des processus à travers lesquels chaque section reflète la nature rituelle et mystique de divers composantes des sūtras. L'analyse explique également comment des concepts bouddhistes abstraits (métaphores et symboles visuels) sont réimaginés sous forme musicale. La structure formelle de la pièce entière et de chaque section est ensuite présentée en relation avec la trame du sūtra du Bouddha de médecine de même dans son rôle d'assurer la cohérence musicale de l'œuvre. L'analyse se termine par une discussion de la capacité de cette approche compositionnelle à transformer les sūtras bouddhistes en représentations musicales et suggère des pistes d'exploration pour de futures compositions.</description><creator>Feria, Roger</creator><contributor>Christopher Harman (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Music</subject><title>Bian</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p7387.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g528b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x4011</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'intégrité du cytosquelette cellulaire est essentielle pour les fonctions physiologiques multiples requises pour le maintien de l'homéostasie tissulaire tel que la morphologie, la polarité, la contractilité, la division, la locomotion, ainsi que le trafic intracellulaire de molécules de signalisation. La régulation du cytosquelette est médiée par un ensemble collectif de protéines de liaison et de réticulation de l'actine, qui servent de médiateur à la ramification des filaments d'actine en réseaux étroitement organisés. Une classe majeure de protéines d'agrégation d'actine est représentée par la famille Fascin, qui comprend Fascin-1, puis Fascin), -2 et -3.Fascin fonctionne comme une protéine de liaison d'actine qui réticule l'actine corticale en faisceaux filamenteux parallèles et participe à l'ancrage des récepteurs membranaires au cytosquelette d'actine. Elle est principalement exprimée dans le système nerveux mais surtout principalement absente des cellules épithéliales normalement différenciés. Dans des conditions pathologiques telles que le cancer, Fascin est surexprimé, incluant des carcinomes du sein. De plus, dans de nombreux cas, une association entre sa surexpression et un mauvais pronostic du patient a été observée.Les études biochimiques et la localisation à grande échelle du génome utilisant ChIP-seq ont identifié Fascin 1 phosphorylée (pFascin) en tant que partenaire d'interaction de l'ARN polymérase II et qu'elle co-localise avec H3K4me3 sur la chromatine. Le profilage d'expression génique a identifié des gènes affectés par Fascin 1 incluant SLC3A2. En outre, l'analyse ChIP a révélé une perte significative de H3K4me3 chez des gènes cibles dans des cellules où l'expression de Fascin était faible. RbBP5, une sous-unité du complexe H3K4 histone méthyltransférase (HMT), interagit également avec Fascin 1 en soutenant son rôle dans l'établissement de H3K4me3 chez les gènes cibles impactant positivement la transcription. De plus, nous montrons que la régulation de SLC3A2 par Fascin affecte l'activation de mTORC1 par les acides aminés.De plus, nous montrons à travers des résultats préliminaires que la perte de Fascin, à travers la technologie CRISPR, a un impact négatif sur les niveaux de protéines des composants du complexe mTORC1 conduisant à l'induction de l'autophagie.Enfin, nous avons également constaté que les souris ayant perdues Fascin ne sont pas viables.En conclusion, nos résultats étayent des fonctions nucléaires et cytoplasmiques multiples, non encore décrite, pour Fascin dans la régulation de processus cellulaires primordiaux pour la biologie cellulaire in vitro et établissent l'essentialité du gène Fscn1 in vivo.</description><description>The integrity of the cell cytoskeleton is essential for multiple physiological functions required for the maintenance of tissue homeostasis, including cell shape and polarity, cell contractility, division, and locomotion, as well as intracellular trafficking of signalling molecules. The regulation of the cell cytoskeleton compartment is mediated by a collective set of actin binding and cross-linking proteins, which mediate branching of actin filaments into tightly organized networks. A major class of actin bundling proteins is represented by the Fascin family, which comprises Fascin-1 (henceforth referred to as Fascin), -2, and -3.Fascin functions as an actin-binding protein that cross-links cortical actin into filamentous parallel bundles and participates in the anchoring of membrane receptors to the actin cytoskeleton. It is primarily expressed within the nervous system while mainly absent from normally differentiated epithelium. In contrast, Fascin is upregulated in pathological conditions such as breast cancer and in many instances an association between its overexpression and poor patient prognosis has been observed.Here, we report a novel nuclear function for Fascin 1. Biochemical studies and genome wide localization using ChIP-seq identified phosphorylated Fascin 1 (pFascin) as an RNA polymerase II interacting partner that co-localizes with H3K4me3 on chromatin. Gene expression profiling identified genes affected by Fascin 1 including SLC3A2. Furthermore, ChIP analysis revealed a significant loss of H3K4me3 at target genes in cells where Fascin was depleted. RbBP5, a subunit of the H3K4 histone methyltransferase (HMT) complex, also interacts with Fascin 1 supporting the role of the latter in H3K4me3 establishment at target genes, and positively impacting transcription. Moreover, we show that Fascin-mediated regulation of SLC3A2 levels affects amino acid-mediated mTORC1 activation.Also, preliminary results show that loss of Fascin, through CRISPR technology, negatively impacts protein levels of components of the mTORC1 complex leading to induction of autophagy. Lastly, we found that total Fascin knockout mice were not viable as we were not able to generate homozygous knockouts.    In conclusion, our results support undescribed multiple nuclear and cytoplasmic function for Fascin in regulation of cellular processes primordial for the cell biology in vitro but also support the essentiality of the Fscn1 gene in vivo. </description><creator>Saad, Amine</creator><contributor>Moulay A Alaoui-Jamali (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Undescribed novel roles for fascin in cancer cell biology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tx68c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x4011</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bg257h47d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La schistosomiase est une maladie chronique débilitante et douloureuse qui affecte les organes viscéraux et affecte négativement la croissance et le développement des enfants. La maladie persiste dans les régions de pauvreté et dans 78 pays de régions tropicales et subtropicales ; elle est associée à une morbidité significative. La schistosomiase est une maladie de la pauvreté qui se rencontre dans les régions qui n'ont pas accès à l'eau potable propre. Les agents pathogènes de la schistosomiase sont les trématodes de l'espèce Schistosoma. La migration des larves et la persistance de l'infection chez l'hôte sont réglementés par l'interaction des neurotransmetteurs schistosomiques et leurs récepteurs associés, et du contrôle neuromusculaire de la motilité parasitaire. Le ciblage du système nerveux du schistosome à des fins thérapeutiques doit être davantage étudié, car la neurobiologie du parasite est peu connue. Un traitement idéal de la schistosomiase ciblerait spécifiquement le parasite sans nuire à la biologie de l'hôte. Nos travaux de recherche ont identifié une signalisation phénolamine chez Schistosoma mansoni, signalisation qui a été identifié dans pratiquement tous les «phyla» invertébrés, mais qu'on ne savait pas présent chez Schistosoma. L'identification de ce type de signalisation chez les schistosomes est une découverte importante dans le domaine, car cette signalisation est absente chez les vertébrés, y compris les humains. La signalisation OA représente donc un type de signalisation unique qui peut être spécifiquement ciblée pour guérir la schistosomiase. Nous avons utilisé l'immunolocalisation confocale pour déterminer que la phénolamine octopamine (OA) est répandue dans le système nerveux périphérique et central du parasite, et qu'elle se trouve dans les structures reproductrices femelles, les larves et l'embryon du schistosome ; ce qui démontre son importance en neurobiologie des schistosomes. La localisation de l'OA sur les neurones périphériques innervant la musculature suggère un rôle dans le contrôle neuromusculaire de l'OA. Pour valider cette hypothèse, nous avons effectué des études de motilité des phénolamines et des catécholamines qui sont apparentées. Nous avons démontré des effets dépendant à la concentration de l'OA, de son précurseur tyramine (TA) et de son métabolite synéphrine (SE) sur la stimulation de la motilité et l'allongement du parasite. Nous confirmons également des effets dépendant à la concentration sur la longueur et la motilité de la catécholamine dopamine (DA) des schistosomulums. Après avoir mesuré les effets sur la motilité de ces dérivés de tyrosine, nous avons testé des composés synthétiques sur des schistosomules in vitro, et identifié un antagoniste putatif ainsi qu'un agoniste de la signalisation OA. Nous avons également déterminé des effets dépendant à la concentration par un antagoniste DA connu. Ensuite, pour valider ces interactions, nous avons utilisé l'ARNi pour réguler négativement l'expression des gènes de signalisation liés à l'OA et à la DA et mesuré les changements du contrôle neuromusculaire. Nous avons observé des changements dans la fréquence des mouvements du corps et dans la longueur, la posture et la coordination chez les larves et les parasites adultes. Enfin, nous avons effectué une caractérisation préliminaire de deux protéines de signalisation OA, le récepteur Smp_150180 et l'enzyme de synthèse S. mansoni tyramine bêta-hydroxylase (SmTBH). Notre identification sans précédent de la signalisation phénolamine chez Schistosoma représente une nouvelle découverte en neurobiologie des schistosomes. La caractérisation de la phénolamine et de la signalisation de la catécholamine chez S. mansoni permet non seulement de mettre en évidence leur importance à la neurobiologie des schistosomes, mais aussi d'identifier ces types de signalisation comme cibles thérapeutiques potentielles au développement d'un schistosomicide afin d'enrayer cette maladie débilitante.</description><description>Schistosomiasis is a debilitating and painful chronic disease that affects the visceral organs and negatively affects the growth and development of school-aged children. The disease persists in regions of poverty in 78 countries in tropical and subtropical regions, and is associated with significant morbidity and mortality. Schistosomiasis is a "neglected" disease of poverty found in regions without access to clean freshwater. The causative agents of schistosomiasis are trematodes of the species Schistosoma. Preceding the chronic stage of infection, an initial 4-6 week acute stage is associated with the migrating larvae, preceding their transformation to adult-stage parasites. The parasite evades the immune response throughout the commencment and establishment of infection, and it has been reported that infection can persist for up to 40 years. The migration of larvae and the persistence of infection in the host are governed by the interaction of schistosome neurotransmitters with their associated receptors, and neuromuscular control of parasite motility. To target the schistosome nervous system for drug development, it must be further studied, as relatively little is known about the parasite's neurobiology. An ideal treatment for schistosomiasis would specifically target the parasite without adversely affecting host biology. Thus, in the work described here, we identify phenolamine signaling in Schistosoma mansoni, which has previously been identified in virtually all invertebrate phyla, but was not known to be present in schistosomes. The identification of this signaling pathway in schistosomes is a landmark discovery in the field of schistosome research, as this signaling is absent in vertebrates, including humans. Octopamine (OA) signaling, therefore, represents a unique signaling pathway that can be specifically targeted to cure schistosomiasis. We used confocal immunolocalization to determine that the phenolamine OA is widespread in the peripheral and central nervous system of the parasite (PNS and CNS), and that it is found in the female reproductive structures, in larvae and in the developing schistosome embryo, demonstrating its importance to schistosome neurobiology. The localization of OA to peripheral neurons innervating musculature suggests a role in neuromuscular control for OA. To verify a role in neuromuscular control, we performed motility studies of phenolamines and related catecholamines. We demonstrated concentration-dependent effects of OA, its precursor tyramine (TA) and its metabolite synephrine (SE) on stimulation of motility and lengthening of the parasite. We also confirm concentration-dependent effects on length and motility for the related catecholamine dopamine (DA) in schistosomula. Having measured effects on motility for these tyrosine derivatives, we tested synthetic compounds on schistosomula in vitro, and identified a putative antagonist as well as an agonist of OA-signaling in schistosomes, and determined concentration-dependent effects for a known DA antagonist. Next, to validate these effects, we used RNAi to downregulate expression of OA and DA-related signaling genes and measured changes in neuromuscular control. We observed changes in frequency of body movements and in length, posture and coordination in both larval and adult-stage parasites. Finally, we performed a preliminary characterization of two OA signaling proteins, the OA receptor Smp_150180 and the OA-synthesizing enzyme S. mansoni tyramine beta-hydroxylase (SmTBH, Smp_243830). Our unprecedented identification of phenolamine signaling in schistosomes provides new insight into the neurobiology of schistosomes. The characterization of phenolamine and catecholamine signaling in S. mansoni serves not only to highlight their importance to schistosome neurobiology, but also to identify these signaling pathways as drug targets for schistosomicide discovery and development to treat this debilitating disease.</description><creator>El-Sakkary, Nelly</creator><contributor>Paula Ribeiro (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Parasitology</subject><title>Study of «Schistosoma mansoni» nervous system: characterization of catecholamine and phenolamine signaling</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g529m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257h47d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053j76q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La sclérose en plaque (SP), une maladie auto-immune du système nerveux central, est la principale cause d'invalidité neurologique chez les jeunes adultes au Canada. L'effet de la SP est très profond et similaire pour les personnes de toutes nations, niveaux socioéconomiques, d'éducation, et emplois. Les manifestations de la SP varient d'une personne à l'autre, avec des symptômes allant d'altérations légères des sensations à un handicap sévère limitant les activités et la participation aux rôles du quotidien. Ces manifestations ont un impact sur la qualité de vie (QV). Les priorités des personnes avec la SP sont de rester indépendantes et de s'impliquer dans leur communauté et leurs soins de santé. Elles reconnaissent l'importance d'un mode de vie sain pour maintenir leur QV mais peu d'entre elles sont suffisamment actives physiquement pour rester en santé face à une condition dégénérative. Cela indique des lacunes entre l'information reçue  et la mise en action.Afin de combler ces lacunes et adresser le nombre de sujets importants pour celles-ci, un livre basé sur les principes de l'autogestion a été développé. L'autogestion est une tâche perpétuelle où les patients sont entrainés et encadrés afin de garder leur bien-être plutôt que leur maladie en avant-plan par le développement de cinq compétences-clés: résolution de problèmes, prise de décision, utilisation des ressources, formation d'un partenariat  patient-équipe de soin et prise d'action. Pour utiliser ces compétences, la personne doit développer ses habiletés à s'auto-évaluer, identifier et mettre en œuvre des stratégies pour s'améliorer ainsi que suivre ses progrès. Le premier objectif de cette thèse était donc de développer un livre d'autogestion nommé Getting on With Your Life With MS: A Guide To Taking Charge Of Your Health (GETONMS©)et optimiser son utilisation.Le développement et l'optimisation de GETONMS© sont présentés dans le manuscrit 1 intégré dans un processus en 10 étapes qui pourra permettre à d'autre d'utiliser cette méthodologie pour développer et améliorer du matériel enseignant l'autogestion. GETONMS© discute de 43 sujets importants pour la QV des gens avec la SP. Les cliniciens et chercheurs qui ont évalué le livre ont approuvé du contenu et du format et ont exprimé leur intérêt d'offrir le produit fini à leurs patients. Les évaluations préliminaires ont démontré que le contenu et le format de présentation correspondent aux besoins des utilisateurs et qu'aucun support n'est nécessaire pour utiliser GETONMS©.L'objectif suivant de cette thèse était de comprendre les processus par lesquels l'utilisation de GETONMS© produit un changement au niveau de la QV. Le manuscrit 2 a exploré la valeur attribuée au livre par des gens atteint de SP qui l'utilisent.  Le potentiel de GETONMS© à provoquer un déplacement de la réponse en QV sur une période de deux mois fut évalué. L'information obtenue par ces analyses a permis de concevoir une étude de faisabilité sur internet afin de rendre le livre le plus accessible possible.Le manuscrit 3 présente le protocole de cette étude de faisabilité randomisée en plus des caractéristiques à l'entrée dans l'étude des 23 premiers participants recrutés. Son objectif est d'identifier les forces et les limites de l'utilisation des médias sociaux pour le recrutement et l'inscription des participants avec la SP dans l'étude en ligne. Cette analyse provisoire fut menée à pour permettre de modifier le protocole au besoin. Celle-ci démontra que la stratégie de recrutement sur les médias sociaux permet d'accéder à un groupe de patients similaire à ceux recrutés en personne. Le recrutement s'est déroulé deux fois plus rapidement. Les trois manuscrits ainsi que le livre GETONMS© présentés dans cette thèse apportent des connaissances à la recherche en autogestion générale et au recrutement sur les médias sociaux et permettra la conception d'une étude évaluative confirmatoire sur l'utilisation de GETONMS©. Le livre sera publié bientôt.</description><description>Multiple sclerosis (MS), an auto-immune disease of the central nervous system, is the leading cause of neurological disability among young adults in Canada. The effect of MS is profound and is similar for people across nations, socioeconomic gradients, levels of education, and occupations. Its presentation varies widely from person to person, with symptoms ranging from mild sensory alterations to severe disability limiting activity and restricting participation in life's roles. These manifestations of MS have a direct impact on quality of life (QOL). The main priorities of people with MS are to remain independent and empowered to participate in their communities and their care. In order to maintain their QOL as high as possible, people with MS recognize the importance of maintaining a healthy life style, yet research shows that few are sufficiently physically active to maintain health in the face of a progressive disease. This indicates a gap between information (knowledge) and action, a gap that needs to be filled.  To bridge that gap and address the wide range of topics important to people with MS, a knowledge tool based on principles of self-management was developed. Self-management is a lifetime task where patients are coached to maintain wellness in their foreground perspective, rather than illness, through development of five core skills: problem solving, decision making, resource utilization, forming patient/health care provider partnership, taking action. To put those skills to use, a person needs to gain the ability to self-assess, identify and implement strategies to improve, and monitor progress. The first aim of this thesis was to develop a workbook for people living with MS entitled Getting On With Your Life With MS: A Guide To Taking Charge Of Your Health (GETONMS©) following the principles and skills of self-management and optimize its functionality. The development and optimization of GETONMS© is presented in Manuscript 1 along with a 10-stage process that would allow others to use this methodology to develop and refine self-management educational material for other patient populations. GETONMS©, presented in Chapter 5, is a workbook that covers 43 topics identified as important for the quality of life of people with MS. Clinicians and researchers who evaluated the workbook have approved of the content and format and showed interest in offering the final product to their patients. Preliminary evaluation showed that the content and format fit the needs of the users and little or no support is needed to use the workbook.The next objective of this thesis was to gain insight into the processes through which engagement with the workbook produces change in QOL. Manuscript 2 explored how people with MS valued GETONMS© as well as the potential of GETONMS© to produce a response shift in QOL over a 2 month period. The information gathered from the analysis of values and changes in QOL in the form of response shift helped design a feasibility study to be conducted on the internet in order to make the workbook accessible to as many as possible.Manuscript 3 presents the protocol for the randomized feasibility study as well as data from the first 23 subjects recruited to identify strengths and limitations of using social media to enroll people with MS into an internet-based study of self-management. This interim analysis was conducted to allow for modifications to the protocol to be made if needed. It showed that social media recruitment strategy reached a patient population similar to the traditional in-person recruitment sample but also recruited participants into the study over twice as fast. The three manuscripts and the GETONMS© self-management workbook presented in this thesis provide evidence towards global self-management research, social media recruitment, and will allow for the design of a main trial evaluating GETONMS©. It also produced a workbook that will be made available to people with MS soon.</description><creator>Bouchard, Vanessa</creator><contributor>Melissa Park (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Nancy Mayo (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Physical and Occupational Therapy</subject><title>Getting on with Your life with MS: Development, refinement and preliminary testing of a self-management workbook for people living with multiple sclerosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472z970.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053j76q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns064850m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The human papillomavirus (HPV) infects approximately 550,000 Canadians annually. Cancers of the cervix, mouth, genitals, anus, head and neck are caused by various strains of the HPV. The HPV also causes genital warts. The disease and economic burden of HPV infections is high. Three HPV vaccines are available: Cervarix®, Gardasil®, and Gardasil ® 9. Consistent with global practices in developed countries, these vaccines are currently publicly funded for girls and provided in school-based programs in all provinces and territories in Canada. As of September 2016, six provinces provide publicly funded school-based programs for boys.  Despite well-documented vaccine efficacy and effectiveness with minimal adverse effects, uptake of the HPV vaccines remains suboptimal in most countries, including Canada. Although HPV immunization rates have increased over the last decade, they remain significantly below the rates of other vaccine-preventable diseases. One of the main challenges for boys' uptake has been to help parents understand that the HPV vaccine is now available, recommended and effective for boys in reducing health risks for themselves and transmission to their partners.  With low HPV uptake rates in Canada, success of increased vaccination rates is contingent on parents' awareness, understanding and ultimately their decision-making process. Of the HPV vaccination research that has targeted parents of boys, most studies examined demographic and descriptive factors associated with vaccination intentions. While this research is informative, it treats decision-making as binary, when there are likely multiple stages of vaccination decision-making. Conceptualizing vaccine decision-making as distinct stages would allow us to examine those individuals who are vaccine hesitant, as well as parents who are not yet aware or engaged in HPV vaccine decision-making. Moreover, much of the existing research on the correlates and factors associated with vaccination intentions are unreliable, which is likely due to differences in the conceptualization of the factors and inconsistent and unstable measures. This in turn provides limited insight about leverage points of how to move individuals along the HPV vaccine decision-making trajectory and ultimately increase HPV vaccine uptake.This dissertation addresses some of these research gaps by using theory-based research, as well as the development of two psychometrically validated scales, an extended HPV and HPV vaccine knowledge scale and the HPV Attitudes and Beliefs Scale (HABS) to identify the factors that are associated with HPV vaccination decision-making among a nationally representative sample of Canadian parents of 9-16-year-old boys using a longitudinal design. The unique contributions of the four manuscripts in this thesis are that by conceptualizing HPV vaccine decision-making as a series of distinct stages, by using theory, psychometrically-tested and validated measures, as well as multinomial logistic regression models, we can have a greater understanding about what influences parents' HPV vaccine decision-making for their sons. This more nuanced understanding will help to better target our efforts to increase HPV vaccine uptake for boys. Future research directions and recommendations for better informed and targeted interventions are made.</description><description>Le virus du papillome humain (VPH) infecte environ 550, 000 Canadiens chaque année. Les cancers de col du l'utérus, de la bouche, des organes génitaux, l'anus, de tête et cou sont causées par diverses types du VPH. Le VPH provoque également des condylomes génitales. La maladie et le fardeau économique de VPH est élevé. Trois vaccins sont disponibles, Cervarix®, Gardasil®, Gardasil® 9. En accord avec les pratiques internationales dans les pays développés, ces vaccins sont actuellement financés publiquement pour les filles et fournis à l'école dans des programmes d'immunisation dans toutes les provinces et territoires au Canada. En septembre 2016, six provinces fournissent maintenant à l'école des programmes d'immunisation gratuite pour les garçons. Malgré l'efficacité des vaccins bien documenté et l'efficacité avec un minimum d'effets secondaires, le taux d'immunisation contre le VPH reste faible dans la plupart des pays, incluant le Canada. Bien que les taux de vaccination contre le VPH ont augmenté au cours de la dernière décennie, ils restent nettement en dessous du taux d'autres maladies évitables par la vaccination. L'un des principaux défis pour les garçons a été d'aider les parents et les adultes à comprendre que le vaccin contre le VPH est maintenant disponible, efficace et recommandé pour les garçons pour la reduction du risque de l'infection pour eux-mêmes et la transmission aux partners. Avec un faible taux de la vaccination du VPH au Canada, le succès de l'augmentation des taux de vaccination est dépendant sur la sensibilisation et la compréhension des parents et, finalement, leurs processus de décision. Parmi la recherche sur la vaccination contre le VPH dans la population des parents des garçons, la plupart des études examine les facteurs démographiques et descriptives associées aux intentions de vaccination. Bien que cette recherche est informatif, il permet de traiter la prise de décisions en tant que binaire, quand il y a probablement plusieurs étapes de la prise de décisions de vaccination. La conceptualisation de la prise de décision comme des étapes nous permettrait d'examiner ceux qui sont hésitants de vaccins, ainsi que les parents qui ne sont pas au courant ou engagés dans leur processus de prise de décisions. Aussi, la majeure des recherches sur les corrélats et les facteurs associés à la vaccination intentions sont variables, ce qui est probablement dû aux différences dans la différente conceptualisation des facteurs et les mesures instables. Cela donne un aperçu limité sur les points de levage que on doit adresser pour bouger les personnes sur la trajectoire de prendre leurs décisions, et en fin, de se faire vacciner.Cette thèse aborde certaines de ces lacunes de recherche en utilisant la recherche fondée sur la théorie ainsi que la développement de deux échelles validées sur ces propriétaires  psychométrique : une échelle du connaissance sur le VPH et une échelle des attitudes et croyances du VPH (HABS) pour identifier les facteurs associés à la prise de décisions pour la vaccination contre le VPH chez les parents garçons de 9-16 ans au Canada. Le caractère unique des quatres articles de cette thèse sont: de démontrer que le vaccin contre le VPH constitue la prise de décisions de plusieurs étapes, et qu'en utilisant la théorie et des mesures validées, ainsi que des modèles multinomiaux, nous pouvons avoir une plus bon compréhension de les facteurs qui influencent la prise de décisions pour les parents des fils. Cette compréhension plus nuancée aidera à mieux cibler les efforts d'augmenter le taux de vaccination contre le VPH pour les garçons. Des directions de la recherche et des recommandations pour améliorer l'information et des interventions ciblées sont effectuées. </description><creator>Perez, Samara</creator><contributor>Zeev Rosberger (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Psychology</subject><title>Parents' human papillomavirus vaccine decision-making: theory, measurement and models</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xf286.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064850m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wg30v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction : Les complications locorégionales dans le cancer de la prostate (CP) affectent la qualité de vie et peuvent nécessiter de nombreuses interventions médicales.    L'objectif était de comparer les complications locorégionales dans le cancer de la prostate résistant à la castration (CPRC) par le type de traitement local primaire reçu auparavant (radiothérapie externe (RTE) ou prostatectomie radicale (PR)). Méthodes : La cohorte consiste de patients qui sont décédés de CPRC entre 2001 et 2013 au Québec, et qui avait reçu un traitement local primaire (RTE ou PR).  Les bases de données administratives de la RAMQ et MED-ECHO ont été utilisés afin d'identifier les complications locorégionales tardives (procédures urologiques, procédures rectales mineures et autres procédures chirurgicales majeures) et les hospitalisations reliées au CP dans les deux dernières années de vie.  Les analyses principales ont été effectuées à l'aide de régressions logistique et binomiale négative multivariées.Résultats : La cohorte comprend 1189 patients; 535 (45%) et 654 (55%) patients ayant reçu la RTE et PR comme traitement local primaire.  La survie médiane à partir du traitement local primaire était de 7.1 ans dans le groupe RTE et de 7.2 ans dans le groupe PR.  Globalement, 46.4% des patients ont subi au moins une complication locorégionale dans les deux dernières années de vie (RTE : 47.1%, PR : 45.9%).  Selon l'analyse de régression logistique multivariée, la PR n'était pas associé à une réduction du risque de complications locorégionales lorsque comparée à la RTE (rapport des côtes (RC) 0.96, intervalle de confiance (IC) 95% 0.76, 1.22).  Les patients ayant reçu un traitement de sauvetage avaient deux fois plus de risque d'avoir des complications locorégionales (RC 1.98, IC95% 1.43, 2.74) comparé à ceux qui n'ont pas eu recours à un traitement de sauvetage.  Par contre, la PR était associée à un risque plus élevé d'hospitalisation relié au CP (RC 1.63, IC95% 1.23, 2.17) lorsque comparée à la RTE.  Les patients ayant utilisé un traitement CPRC (RC 3.96, IC95% 2.83, 5.53) et qui ont eu des complications locorégionales (RC 2.76, IC95% 2.05, 3.69) avaient aussi un risque plus élevé d'hospitalisation relié au CP.  Selon les modèles de régression binomiale négative multivariée, la PR n'était pas associée à un nombre de jours d'hospitalisation relié au CP plus élevé (rapport des taux (RR): 1.09, IC95% 0.90, 1.32) mais l'usage de traitement CPRC (RR 1.46, IC95% 1.20, 1.79) et les complications locorégionales (RR 1.66, IC95% 1.40, 2.03) l'étaient.  Conclusion : Avec une approche rétrospective populationnelle, le risque des complications locorégionales dans le CPRC n'était pas associé avec le type de traitement local primaire (PR ou RTE) dans cette cohorte.  Bien que la PR fût associée avec plus de chance d'hospitalisation relié au CP dans les deux dernières années de vie, elle n'était pas associée avec le nombre de jours d'hospitalisation relié au CP.  Il est évident que les complications locorégionales sont un fardeau important dans le CPRC puisqu'elles sont associées à un plus grand nombre de jours d'hospitalisation relié au CP et à un risque plus élevé de mortalité.  Donc, plus d'emphase devrait être mise sur la prévention et la gestion appropriée de ceux-ci.</description><description>Introduction: Late locoregional complications in prostate cancer (PCa) can impact quality of life and require numerous medical interventions.  The objective was to evaluate locoregional complications in castration-resistant prostate cancer (CRPC) by type of local primary treatment (external-beam radiotherapy (EBRT) or radical prostatectomy (RP)) previously received. Methods: The cohort consists of CRPC patients that died between 2001 and 2013 in Quebec, and who underwent previous local primary therapy (EBRT or RP). The RAMQ and Med-Echo administrative databases were used to identify late locoregional complications (urological procedures, minor rectal procedures and other major surgical procedures) and PCa-related hospitalizations occurring in the last two years of life.  Multivariable logistic regression and multivariable negative binomial regression analyses were performed. Results: The cohort is comprised of 1189 patients; 535 (45%) and 654 (55%) patients had received EBRT and RP as local primary treatment, respectively. The median survival from time of initial local treatment was 7.1 years in the EBRT group and 7.2 years in the RP group.  Overall, 46.4% of patients experienced at least one late locoregional complication in the last 2 years of life (EBRT: 47.1%, RP: 45.9%).  On multivariable logistic regression analyses, RP was not associated with a reduced risk of late locoregional complications compared to EBRT (odds ratio (OR) 0.91, 95% confidence interval (CI) 0.72, 1.16); however patients who received a salvage local treatment were two times more likely to have locoregional complications (OR 1.98, 95%CI 1.43, 2.74) compared to those who did not receive a salvage local treatment. RP was associated with greater odds of PCa-related hospitalization (OR 1.63, 95%CI 1.23, 2.17) relative to EBRT; as were the usage of a CRPC treatment (OR 3.96, 95%CI 2.83, 5.53) and the occurrence of a late locoregional complication (OR 2.76, 95%CI 2.05, 3.69).  For the number of PCa-related hospitalization days, RP was not found to be significant (rate ratio (RR) 1.09, 95%CI 0.90, 1.32); however use of a CRPC treatment (RR 1.46, 95%CI 1.20, 1.79) and late locoregional complications (RR 1.66, 95%CI 1.40, 2.03) were positive predictors of days of PCa-related hospitalizations. Conclusion: Using a retrospective population-based approach, the risk of late locoregional complications in CRPC was not associated with the type of local primary treatment (RP or EBRT) in this cohort. While RP was associated with greater odds of PCa-related hospitalization in the last two years of life, it was not associated with the number of PCa-related hospitalization days.  It is clear that locoregional complications are an important component of morbidity in CRPC given that they are associated with higher number of days of PCa-related hospitalization and higher risk of mortality.  More efforts should be devoted to the prevention and appropriate management of locoregional complications in CRPC.</description><creator>Hu, Jason</creator><contributor>Elena Dragomir (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Sylvie Perreault (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Surgery</subject><title>Impact of local primary treatment on locoregional complications in patients dying of castration-resistant prostate cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741v238.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wg30v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hs274</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le neuropaludisme est une encéphalite neurologique causée par le parasite Plasmodium falciparum chez l'humain; c'est la première cause de décès chez les enfants en Afrique subsaharienne. Nous décrivons ici une mutagenèse aléatoire du génome entier de souris par N-éthyl-N-nitrosourée (ENU) qui nous a permis d'identifier des gènes qui, lorsque désactivés, entraînent une résistance au neuropaludisme expérimental chez des souris infectées par Plasmodium berghei ANKA (PbA). Ces mutations protectrices touchent les gènes et les voies responsables des pathologies neuroinflammatoires, et les protéines correspondantes et voies associées pourraient constituer des cibles novatrices précieuses pour la recherche pharmacologique. Les méthodes de séquençage de l'ensemble du génome et/ou de l'ensemble de l'exome ont permis d'identifier des mutations disruptives récessives induites par ENU dans les gènes qui codent pour THEMIS et USP15 qui protègent les souris d'une neuroinflammation létale. Nous avons constaté chez les mutants homozygotes Themis I23N une importante diminution du nombre de lymphocytes T, et donc une diminution de la réponse pro-inflammatoire liée aux lymphocytes T, ce qui a un effet protecteur pour le modèle murin de neuropaludisme expérimental, mais un effet préjudiciable pour l'infection à M. tuberculosis. Contrairement au cas des mutants THEMIS, la résistance au neuropaludisme expérimental des mutants homozygotes Usp15 L749R n'était pas due à une immunodéficience cellulaire, mais plutôt à une atténuation de la production d'interférons de type 1 dans le cerveau, ce qui protégeait les souris de la neuroinflammation à la fois pour le neuropaludisme expérimental et pour l'encéphalite auto-immune expérimentale (EAE). À l'aide de méthodes biochimiques, génétiques et de séquençage de l'ARN, nous avons découvert que USP15, avec son partenaire de liaison l'ubiquitine ligase E3 TRIM25, régulait positivement la production d'interférons de type 1 pour favoriser la neuroinflammation. Comme THEMIS et USP15 ont aussi été identifiés comme facteurs de risque génétiques pour un certain nombre de maladies inflammatoires chez l'humain, nos études sur la souris confirment le rôle essentiel des gènes dans les mécanismes pathogènes communs des maladies inflammatoires chez l'humain. Enfin, dans une deuxième mutagenèse par ENU, nous avons découvert que la susceptibilité au neuropaludisme expérimental était régulée par une interaction épistatique entre les locus Berr8 du chromosome 4 et Berr7 du chromosome 1 chez des souris issues d'un croisement entre les souches B6 et 129S1. Notre étude soulève la possibilité que ce système à deux locus puisse être aussi impliqué dans d'autres maladies inflammatoires non reliées, chez l'humain. Dans l'ensemble, non seulement ces résultats contribuent-ils à la compréhension des mécanismes des maladies infectieuses et inflammatoires, mais ils proposent aussi de nouvelles cibles pour la recherche pharmacologique. L'effet protecteur de l'altération génétique contre la neuroinflammation pourrait être reproduit par l'inhibition pharmacologique de la cible correspondante pour soigner le neuropaludisme et potentiellement d'autres maladies inflammatoires chroniques chez l'humain.</description><description>Cerebral malaria (CM) is a neurological encephalitis caused by Plasmodium falciparum infection in humans and is the leading cause of death in children from sub-Saharan Africa. Here, we describe a genome-wide N-ethyl-N-nitrosourea (ENU) mutagenesis screen in mice that has identified genes that, when inactivated, cause experimental cerebral malaria (ECM)-resistance in Plasmodium berghei ANKA (PbA)-infected mice. Such ECM-protective mutations affect genes and pathways required for pathological neuroinflammation, and the corresponding proteins and associated pathways might represent valuable novel targets for drug discovery. Genome scans and/or whole exome sequencing approaches have identified disruptive recessive ENU-induced mutations in the genes that encode THEMIS and USP15 which protect mice from lethal neuroinflammation. We found that Themis I23N homozygous mutants exhibited a profound decrease in T cell numbers, and thus impaired T cell-dependent pro-inflammatory responses, which was protective in the mouse model of ECM but detrimental for M. tuberculosis infection. Unlike THEMIS mutants, ECM-resistance in Usp15 L749R homozygous mutants was not caused by a cellular immunodeficiency, but rather, resistance was linked to dampened type I interferon responses in the brain protecting mice from neuroinflammation in both ECM and experimental autoimmune encephalitis (EAE). Using biochemical, genetic and RNA-sequencing approaches, we found that USP15, together with its binding partner, E3 ubiquitin ligase TRIM25, positively regulated type I interferon responses to drive pathogenesis during neuroinflammation. Since THEMIS and USP15 have also been detected as genetic risk factors for a number of common human inflammatory diseases, our mouse studies validate the critical role that these genes play in common pathogenic mechanisms of human inflammatory diseases. Lastly, in a second ENU mutagenesis screen, we found that susceptibility to ECM was regulated by epistatic interaction between chromosome 4 (Berr8) and chromosome 1 (Berr7) loci in mice derived from B6 and 129S1 parental crosses. Our study raises the possibility that this two-locus system may also be relevant to other unrelated inflammatory conditions in humans. Overall, these findings not only contribute to our understanding of infectious and inflammatory disease mechanisms, but have also proposed novel targets of pharmacological interest. The neuroinflammatory-protective genetic alteration could be mimicked by pharmacological inhibition of the corresponding target to alleviate CM and possibly other chronic human inflammation conditions as well.</description><creator>Torre, Sabrina</creator><contributor>Philippe Gros (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Human Genetics</subject><title>Uncovering novel host factors driving pathological neuroinflammation in a mouse model of cerebral malaria</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn1071653.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hs274</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311r97q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Posterior capsular opacification (PCO) is the leading complication following cataract surgery. Understanding factors that contribute to PCO development is a significant public concern as treatment can lead to complications. PCO depends on the biocompatibility of the patient and the artificial lens; known as an intraocular lens (IOL), implanted within the capsular bag of the eye after cataract surgery. In order to prevent PCO, a better understanding of IOL characteristics, including design and material, and how it interacts with patients is required. Herein, this study investigates three main objectives: to invent a new objective PCO quantification system in post-mortem eyes, to validate this methodology, and to perform a retrospective multivariable analysis to determine which factors (IOL and patient-based) are least likely to result in PCO. The ultimate goal is to find the optimum IOL platform for patients.  In total, 180 post-mortem eyes with implanted IOLs were collected from the Minnesota Eye Bank, along with their clinical history, including date of cataract surgery and IOL model number. The capsular bag (CB) with the IOL implant was removed from all eyes to obtain digital images. PCO outcome was quantified on CB images using an objective, novel automated custom image analyzer. The software measured intensity and area of the opacification within the IOL optic edge, intra-optic edge (IOE= intensity/area), and the opacities found within the capsular bag just outwards of the IOL optic, known as Soemmering's ring (SR= intensity/area). Software-derived PCO outcomes were statistically analyzed with previously used subjective PCO grading to verify validity. Epidemiologic analysis determined which IOL characteristics and patient-related factors correlated with PCO. IOL factors included material, edge design, lens filter, decentration and time of IOL implantation. Patient factors included sex, age and diabetes mellitus, among others.The software PCO grading system correlated well with previous scoring methods. Multivariate analyses showed non-diabetic patients had less SR (P= 0.05). Individuals 50-80 years old compared to 80+ had lower SR PCO (P= 0.01). Square and frosted optic edge design had lower SR and IOE PCO rates compared to OptiEdge (P= 0.001, 0.03). Patients with an IOL implanted for less then 25 months had lower SR and IOE PCO. (P= 0.0001, 0.004). In order to generate a lens that does not develop PCO, it is critical to understand the IOL- and patient-related factors that lead to PCO development. Based on our data, the most susceptible patients are elderly and diabetic, and it may be preferable to implant a square and frosted edge lens. </description><description>L'opacification capsulaire postérieure (OCP) est la principale complication après une chirurgie de la cataracte. Les éléments qui contribuent au développement de l'OCP sont une préoccupation majeure du public car le traitement peut provoquer des complications. L'OCP dépend de la biocompatibilité du patient envers la lentille artificielle; appelée lentille intraoculaire (LIO). Celle-ci est implantée dans le sac capsulaire, remplaçant la lentille naturelle, après une chirurgie de la cataracte. Afin de prévenir l'OCP, une meilleure compréhension des caractéristiques des LIO, comme le design, le matériel et l'interaction lentille-patient est nécessaire. Cette étude observe trois objectifs principaux: créer un nouveau système de quantification objective de l'OCP dans les yeux obtenus post-mortem, valider cette méthodologie en la comparant à la méthode subjective, et réaliser une analyse rétrospective à plusieurs variables pour déterminer quels sont les facteurs (LIO et patient) les moins susceptibles de causer l'OCP. Le but ultime est de trouver les caractéristiques optimales de LIO pour les patients.Au total, 180 yeux avec des LIO implantées ont été recueillis post-mortem en provenance de la banque d'yeux du Minnesota, chacun comprenant l'historique clinique, la date de la chirurgie et le numéro de modèle de la LIO. Le sac capsulaire contenant l'implant LIO a été prélevé de chaque œil pour en obtenir des images digitales. La présence d'OPC a été quantifiée à partir des images de sac capsulaire à l'aide d'un logiciel d'analyse objective et automatisé développé dans le cadre de ce projet. Le logiciel mesure l'intensité et l'étendu de l'opacification du côté optique de la LIO, du côté intra-optique (BIO= intensité/zone), ainsi que les opacités dans le sac capsulaire juste à l'extérieur de la zone optique de la LIO, l'anneau de Soemmering (AS= Intensité/superficie). Les résultats d'OPC obtenu de façon automatisé ont ensuite été comparés à l'ancienne méthode d'évaluation subjective afin de vérifier la validité du logiciel d'analyse. Les données épidémiologique ont été évaluées afin de vérifier le lien entre les propriétés de la LIO et en relation avec l'OCP. Les propriétés de la LIO incluent le matériel, le design, le filtre à lentille, la décentration et le temps d'implantation de la LIO. Enfin, les facteurs épidémiologiques incluent entres autres le sexe, l'âge du patient et un diagnostic de diabète.Le système de classement de l'OCP du logiciel est en corrélation avec les méthodes de notation précédentes. Les analyses à plusieurs variables montrent que les patients non diabétiques ont moins d'opacités dans l'AS (P= 0.05). Les individus âgés de 50 à 80 ans comparés à ceux de 80 ans et plus ont une OCP inférieure (P= 0.01). Les LIO avec un design à bordure optique carrée et givrée présente des taux d'OCP, AS et BIO inférieurs par rapport au design OptiEdge (P= 0.001, 0.03). Les patients qui ont une LIO implantée pour une durée inférieure à 25 mois ont une OCP AS et BIO plus faible. (P= 0.0001, 0.004).Afin de générer une lentille qui ne développe pas d'OCP, il est essentiel de comprendre les éléments de la LIO et les facteurs liés au patient qui mènent au développement de l'OCP. Sur la base de nos données, les patients les plus sensibles sont les personnes âgées et les diabétiques; dans ces cas-ci, il peut être préférable d'implanter une lentille à bordure carrée et givrée.</description><creator>Mastromonaco, Christina</creator><contributor>Miguel Noel Burnier (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Pathology</subject><title>Intraocular lens biocompatibility: a novel, objective approach to understanding posterior capsular opacification</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wm799.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311r97q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vk41v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le diabète est une maladie en pleine expansion causée par une incapacité de l'organisme à réguler les taux de glucose. Il est associé aux pathologies des ilots de Langerhans pancréatiques qui secrètent l'insuline. Plusieurs traitements sont disponibles, tels que la transplantation des ilots et le ciblage des ilots par des médicaments spécifiques. La transplantation d'îlots souffre toutefois d'une pénurie de donneurs ainsi que de l'absence de méthodes fiables pour stocker les îlots in vitro. Par conséquent, de nouvelles méthodes de régénération des ilots sont en cours d'exploration dans le but de fournir une source illimitée de tissus pour la transplantation. La manipulation in vitro d'îlots humains intacts offre de nombreuses opportunités pour développer significativement les traitements contre le diabète.La sécrétion d'insuline étant un processus pouvant être activé électriquement, des outils alternatifs tels que la spectroscopie diélectrique peuvent être utilisés pour analyser la fonctionnalité des îlots en évaluant leur réponse diélectrique. Par ailleurs, d'autres paramètres affectant la fonctionnalité des îlots, tels que le couplage de jonctions intercellulaires, gagnent en reconnaissance. Les jonctions communicantes relient le cytoplasme des cellules adjacentes, ce qui permet l'échange d'ions. La spectroscopie diélectrique est sensible au flux ionique à travers les jonctions communicantes et peut donc sonder leur couplage, permettant ainsi une évaluation multifactorielle de la fonctionnalité des îlots.Une autre caractéristique qui peut être évaluée in vitro avec la spectroscopie diélectrique est la formation d'agrégats cellulaires. Ce processus est une étape importante dans la régénération des îlots puisque les agrégats cellulaires reflètent la morphologie des îlots et les interactions cellule-cellule. Une plateforme in vitro pour analyser l'agrégation cellulaire pourrait donc évaluer la capacité de divers protocoles à induire la formation de tissu semblable à un îlot.Ce travail présente de nouvelles plateformes in vitro, couplées à des simulations informatiques, pour l'évaluation de la fonctionnalité des îlots et la formation d 'agrégats cellulaires au moyen de la spectroscopie diélectrique. Tout d'abord, une plateforme microfluidique a été développée afin d'obtenir des spectres diélectriques en continu à partir d'îlots humains immobilisés et stimulés par glucose pour libérer de l'insuline. La réponse diélectrique améliorée est capable de détecter le couplage des jonctions communicantes, ce qui se traduit par une double dispersion dans les spectres diélectriques. De plus, la réponse diélectrique des îlots est sensible à la stimulation du glucose et peut traduire les activités cellulaires associées à la sécrétion d'insuline. Par la suite, une simulation d'un seul îlot par éléments finis a été développée afin d'identifier les effets des différentes activités cellulaires sur la réponse diélectrique. En particulier, la simulation a permis de modéliser la réponse diélectrique à l'augmentation de la capacitance de la membrane (associée à la sécrétion d'insuline), les variations dans le couplage des jonctions communicantes et le changement de conductivité du cytoplasme. Les résultats montrent que le couplage de la jonction communicante et la sécrétion d'insuline ont des effets distincts sur la réponse diélectrique des îlots. Du fait de ses propriétés d'agrégation cellulaire, la lignée cellulaire épithéliale mammaire MCF10A a été choisie comme modèle d'étude pour la caractérisation du processus de régénération des îlots. Les cellules MCF10A isolées s'agrègent après quelques jours, menant à une réponse diélectrique caractéristique, suivie en utilisant les paramètres d'ajustement de l'équation Cole-Cole.Le travail réalisé dans le cadre de cette thèse propose une méthode non invasive, simple et en temps réel pour évaluer la fonctionnalité des îlots et suivre la formation d'agrégats cellulaires. </description><description>Diabetes mellitus is a growing disease that is characterized by the body's inability to control blood glucose levels. This disease is associated with pathologies of the pancreatic islets of Langerhans, which secrete insulin. Several treatments are available, including islet transplantations and islet targeting drugs. Islet transplantations are plagued by donor islet shortages and the lack of reliable methods to store islets in vitro. Therefore, novel methods to regenerate islet are being explored to provide an unlimited source of tissue for transplantation. In vitro monitoring of isolated intact human islets provides many opportunities to further develop diabetes treatments. A critical parameter is islet functionality, which describes if the islet can maintain homeostasis by appropriately secreting various hormones. Given that insulin secretion is an electrically excitable process, alternative tools such as dielectric spectroscopy could monitor islet functionality by assessing their dielectric response. Moreover, other features that affect islet functionality, such as intercellular gap junction coupling, are gaining recognition. Gap junctions connect the cytoplasm of adjacent islet cells, allowing the exchange of ions. Dielectric spectroscopy is sensitive to ionic flow through gap junctions, and therefore can assess gap junction coupling, giving a multifactorial assessment of islet functionality.Another feature that can be monitored in vitro with dielectric spectroscopy is cellular aggregate formation. This process is an important step in regenerating islets, since cell aggregates reflect islet morphology and cell-cell interactions. An in vitro platform to monitor cell aggregation could screen the ability of various protocols to induce the formation of islet-like tissue. This work presents novel in vitro platforms, along with computer simulations, for dielectric spectroscopy assessment of islet functionality and cellular aggregate formation. First, a microfluidic platform was fabricated which continuously obtains dielectric spectra from immobilized human islets undergoing glucose stimulated insulin release. The enhanced dielectric response enables detection of gap junction coupling, which is reflected by a double dispersion in the dielectric spectra. Moreover, the islet dielectric response is sensitive to glucose stimulation, and may reflect cell activities associated with insulin secretion. Subsequently, a novel finite element simulation of a single islet was developed to identify the effects of different cellular activities on the dielectric response.  Specifically, the simulation modeled the dielectric response to increases in membrane capacitance (associated with insulin exocytosis), variations in gap junction coupling and changes in cytoplasm conductivity. The results show that each of these parameters has distinct effects on the dielectric response of islets, making this simulation a useful reference for dielectric spectroscopy analysis. Finally, a platform to monitor cellular aggregate formation is presented. Because it exhibits cellular aggregation, the MCF10A breast epithelial cell line is used as a model for the islet regeneration process. The single MCF10A cells aggregated over subsequent days, yielding a characteristic dielectric response, which were tracked using fitting parameters from the Cole-Cole equation. This work provides a non-invasive, simple and real time method to monitor islet functionality and cellular aggregate formation.</description><creator>Heileman, Khalil</creator><contributor>Maryam Tabrizian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Biomedical Engineering</subject><title>Development of dielectric spectroscopy platforms for in vitro monitoring and assessment of human pancreatic islet functionality and cellular aggregate formation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tf66v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vk41v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z709037v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>With remarkable molecular recognition properties, DNA is an excellent material for bottom-up self-assembly in nanotechnology. A prominent example is the remarkable control and complexity provided by DNA origami. However, this complexity requires large sequence space in design. This translates to high cost of starting materials and error-prone assembly; hundreds of oligonucleotides are necessary, with reduced sequence uniqueness within oligonucleotides. The focus of this thesis – developing minimalist approaches to structural DNA nanotechnology – therefore seeks to address these issues by creating structures of functional simplicity. Structural complexity and uniqueness would be designed only where necessary, as dictated by function or application. Another correlated aim is additional reduction of complexity in assembly processes. This forms the conceptual framework for research presented herein.Chapter 2 demonstrates utility of a long templating strand in assembling DNA nanotubes with minimalist 3D triangular rungs. The strand is prepared though enzymatic means, and allows periodic rung assembly with good size-control. These structures can organize gold nanoparticles (AuNPs), with potential application in nanophotonics and nanoelectronics. Furthermore, direct conjugation of AuNPs to prefabricated 3D rungs is shown to greatly streamline the assembly process. In Chapter 3, molecular biology tools enable sequential growth preparation of extended templating strands featuring exact sequence and size-control. Through these, well-defined arrays of double-crossover (DX) and triple-crossover (TX) tiles are assembled, featuring periodic patterning, or specifically designed aperiodicity. These 1D structures truly rival the functionality of DNA origami, whilst using significantly less sequence space. Subsequently, strategies in creating more complex 2D assemblies with sequentially grown templating strands are explored in Chapter 4. Lateral width is engineered into minimalist tiles; 1D DX tile structures are hierarchically assembled into higher-order arrays; and tile nanorings are formed from circular ligation of template strands. Chapter 5 then describes investigation of minimal approaches in the DNA-directed organization of AuNPs. Encapsulation of AuNPs into a minimal wireframe cube is attempted, and AuNP dimerization is shown through an extremely simplified pre-fabricated double-stranded DNA template, as well as through simple controlled poly-functionalization of larger AuNPs. These minimal assemblies and their preparation are expected to have numerous potential application given the multitude of interesting properties and applications relevant to AuNPs.Throughout this work, key concepts can be discerned – templation, prefabrication, multi-purpose components, and molecular biology tools. Though these concepts are by no means requirements for minimalism, we believe their application can help guide future development of minimalist strategies for structural DNA nanotechnology.</description><description>L'ADN, doté de remarquables propriétés en termes de reconnaissance moléculaire, est un excellent matériau pour les approches ascendantes (bottom-up) d'auto-assemblage en nanotechnologie. La complexité et la haute définition des origamis en ADN illustrent parfaitement ce concept. Cependant, la conception de ces structures requiert l'utilisation coûteuse de centaines d'oligonucléotides. De plus, les ressemblances indésirables entre séquences sont inévitables ce qui se traduit par un assemblage sujet à des erreurs. Le principal objet de cette thèse – le développement d'approches minimalistes pour les nanotechnologies en ADN- est de trouver des alternatives à ces problèmes en créant des structures fonctionnelles de façon simple. L'utilisation d'éléments complexes et uniques est limitée aux cas où ils sont strictement nécessaires à la fonction ou aux applications des structures réalisées. L'objectif de cette thèse est aussi de réduire la complexité du procédé d'assemblage. Ces éléments forment le cadre conceptuel des travaux de recherche présentés.Le chapitre 2 démontre l'utilité d'un long brin servant de patron dans l'assemblage de nanotubes en ADN dont les échelons sont des objets triangulaires minimalistes en trois dimensions. Ce brin est préparé avec des réactions enzymatiques et permet un assemblage périodique d'échelons dont la taille est bien contrôlée. Ces structures permettent l'organisation de nanoparticules d'or (NPos) ouvrant la voie à de potentielles applications en nanophotonique et en nanoélectronique. De plus, nous montrons que la conjugaison de NPos à des échelons 3D pré-fabriqués permettent de simplifier le procédé d'assemblage. Dans le chapitre 3, nous utilisons les outils de la biologie moléculaire pour la préparation par croissance séquentielle de longs brins dont la taille et la séquence sont parfaitement contrôlées. Grâce à ces derniers, l'assemblage de réseau de tuiles comme les double-croisées (DX) ou les triple-croisées (TX) est possible. Les motifs de ce réseau peuvent être conçus pour être périodiques ou inclure des irrégularités spécifiquement. Ces structures à une dimension rivalisent avec les origamis en ADN et ont l'avantage d'être conçues avec un nombre limité de séquences. Des stratégies pour créer des assemblages plus complexes en deux dimensions avec des brins préparés par croissance séquentielle sont ensuite explorées dans le chapitre 4. La seconde dimension est implémentée de façon minimaliste selon deux approches. Dans un premier temps, des structures 1D de tuiles DX sont assemblées hiérarchiquement en des réseaux plus étendus ; dans un second temps, nous montrons la formation de nano-anneaux en ligaturant circulairement les brins servant de patrons lors de l'assemblage. Le chapitre 5 décrit ensuite la recherche d'approches minimalistes pour l'organisation de NPos avec de l'ADN. Nous entreprenons en premier lieu l'encapsulation de NPos dans un cube dont le squelette est minimaliste. Nous montrons ensuite la formation de dimères de NPos grâce à de l'ADN double-brin préfabriqué ainsi que la poly-fonctionnalisation simple et contrôlée de NPos plus grandes. Les propriétés et applications des NPos sont nombreuses et variées. Nous pensons donc que les assemblages minimalistes décrits ont une multitude d'applications potentielles. Certains concepts clés peuvent être distingués dans ces travaux– utilisation de patrons pour les assemblages, préfabrication de composants avec des fonctions multiples, mise à profit des outils de la biologie moléculaire.  Ces derniers peuvent aider au développement de stratégies minimalistes pour les nanotechnologies en ADN structurelles.- Translation by Donatien de Rochambeau</description><creator>Lau, Kai Lin</creator><contributor>Hanadi Sleiman (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Chemistry</subject><title>Minimalist strategies for structural DNA nanotechnology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns064851w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z709037v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mm495</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The internet of things, gigabit wireless and tactile internet are examples of applications driving the current development of next generation communication technologies. Their underlying technological aspects, like sporadic access and fast dormancy, heterogeneous networks and ultra-low latency requirements deem a paradigm shift towards asynchronous non-orthogonal transmission necessary. The focus of this dissertation is symbol-asynchronous transmission on the uncoordinated (non-orthogonal) multiple access channel with single-user demodulation at the receiver. The main result herein is that an exact modeling of symbol-asynchronism and appropriate non-uniform signaling in such channels reveals the potential of multi-fold capacity increases over traditionally considered symbol-synchronous channels with uniform signaling, whose capacity has been established at 0.72 bits per channel use.  An exact channel model for symbol-asynchronous transmission by K users with single-user demodulation at the receiver is constructed and a frame-work to model the exact multi-user interference on the channel developed. Using this framework, the exact capacity of symbol-asynchronous transmission with binary signaling is derived to illustrate, for  a K-user channel, an increase of approximately 3 + 0.08K  bits relative to 0.72 bits per channel use. A method based on probability generating functions that allows computationally efficient evaluation of the multi-user interference distribution on the K-user channel for arbitrary user delays is developed. To study the channel capacity with practical constraints, the symbol-asynchronous multiple-access channel is considered with discrete-time finite channel outputs. With additional AWGN impairement on the channel, greater than two-fold capacity gains over 0.72 bits per channel use can be achieved if SNR is higher than 20 dB. M-ary signaling on the symbol-asynchronous multiple-access channel reveals multi-fold capacity increases in channel sum capacity relative to binary-signaling, with upto four-fold capacity increase achievable with m = 32. This is in marked contrast to no capacity increase achieved with uniform signaling on the symbol-synchronous channel. Soft-decision demodulators are designed and their usage with turbo and LDPC codes is simulated within a system architecture. Bit error rate curves show achievement of a throughput of 1.5 bits per channel use on the symbol-asynchronous channel with binary signaling. It is shown that with a maximal entropy n-bit quantizer, maximal throughput possible on the channel with quantized output increases with increasing n, with a six bit quantizer allowing operation within five percent of channel capacity on a fifty user channel. An analytical approach to evaluate the closed-form near-capacity MUI distribution is shown to generate results that perfectly match the MUI distribution obtained using probability generating functions and the numerically obtained MUI histogram. </description><description>L'internet des choses, le gigaoctet sans-fils et l'internet tactile sont des exemples d'applications qui poussent le développement actuel du standard de communication cellulaire prochaine génération. Leurs aspects technologiques sous-jacents, tels que l'accès sporadique et la dormance rapide, les réseaux hétérogènes et les exigences de latence ultra-faible rendent nécessaire un changement de paradigme vers la transmission non-orthogonale asynchrone. L'objectif de cette thèse est la transmission asynchrone au niveau des symboles sur le canal à accès multiple non coordonnée (non-orthogonal) avec démodulation pour utilisateur-simple au niveau du récepteur. Le résultat principal est qu'une modélisation exacte de l'asynchronisme au niveau des symboles et la signalisation non-uniforme convenable dans de tels canaux démontre le potentiel d'augmentations importantes de capacité par rapport aux canaux traditionnellement considérés comme synchrone au niveau des symboles avec la signalisation uniforme, dont la capacité a été établie à 0,72 octets par utilisation de canal.Un modèle de canal exact pour les transmissions asynchrones au niveau des symboles par K-utilisateurs avec démodulation mono-utilisateur au niveau du récepteur est construit et un système pour modéliser l'interférence multi-utilisateur exacte sur le canal développé. En utilisant ce modèle, la capacité de transmission exact asynchrone au niveau des symboles avec signalisation binaire est dérivée pour illustrer, pour un canal K-utilisateur, une augmentation d'environ 3 + 0.08K octets par rapport à 0,72 octets par utilisation de canal. Une méthode basée sur des fonctions génératrices des probabilités qui permet une évaluation numérique efficace de la distribution de l'interférence multi-utilisateurs sur le canal K-utilisateur pour des retards de l'utilisateur arbitraire est développé.L'évaluation de la capacité du canal avec des limitations apparaissant en pratique est considéré avec les sorties de canal finis. Avec une déficience AWGN supplémentaire sur le canal, des gains de capacité supérieure à deux fois plus élevée que 0,72 bits par utilisation de canal peuvent être atteints si le SNR est supérieur à 20 dB. Une augmentation multiple de capacité dans le canal somme des capacités avec la signalisation m-ary peut être atteint avec un maximum de quatre fois plus de capacité réalisable avec m = 32, par opposition à aucune augmentation de la capacité avec une signalisation uniforme sur le canal de synchronisation au niveau des symboles.Des démodulateurs soft-décision sont conçus et leur utilisation avec des codes turbo et LDPC est simulée dans une architecture de système. Des courbes de taux d'erreur d'octets montrent la réalisation de débit presqu'à capacité sur le canal asynchrone au niveau des symboles avec signalisation binaire. Il a été montré que, avec un quantificateur entropie maximal de n-octets, le débit maximal possible sur le canal avec des sorties quantifiées augmente avec l'augmentation de n, avec un quantificateur 6-octet permettant un fonctionnement à moins de 5% de la capacité de canal sur un canal cinquante utilisateurs. Une approche analytique afin d'évaluer la forme fermée presqu'à capacité de distribution MUI produit des résultats qui correspondent parfaitement à la distribution MUI obtenue en utilisant des fonctions génératrices de probabilité et l'histogramme MUI résous numériquement.</description><creator>Salman Ahmed Khan, Salman Ahmed</creator><contributor>Jan Bajcsy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</subject><title>Symbol-asynchronous multiple access channels with single-user demodulation/decoding</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hc361.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mm495</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w3763951h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction: Les problèmes de santé mentale et la consommation de cocaïne sont d'importants facteurs de risques pour le partage de matériel de consommation et pour la  transmission du VIH et de l'hépatite C parmi les utilisateurs de drogue. L'impact de différents marqueurs de problèmes de santé mentale sur le partage de matériel de consommation chez les consommateurs de cocaïne demeure toutefois peu compris. Objectifs: Parmi les participants à l'étude COSMO, une cohorte montréalaise de consommateurs de cocaïne, nous avons étudié : 1) l'association entre les symptômes de détresse psychologique et le partage de matériel de consommation et; 2) l'association entre les symptômes de détresse psychologique et le partage de matériel de consommation, en tenant compte des diagnostics primaires de troubles anxieux et de l'humeur.Méthodes: Des consommateurs de cocaïne fumée ou injectée ont été recrutés à Montréal, Canada,  entre Octobre 2010 et Septembre 2014. Les diagnostics primaires de trouble anxieux et de l'humeur durant l'année précédant le début de l'étude étaient établis à l'aide du Composite International Diagnostic Interview (CIDI). La sévérité de la détresse psychologique selon l'échelle de Kessler ainsi que  le partage de trois types de  matériel de consommation (pipes à crack; seringues; matériel d'injection excluant les seringues) étaient évalués à chacune des 5 visites de suivi à 3 mois d'intervalle. Objectif 1 : Des régressions logistiques multivariées ont été effectuées pour étudier l'association transversale entre la détresse psychologique et le partage de matériel de consommation en début d'étude. Objectif 2 : Des équations d'estimations généralisées multivariées ont été menées pour évaluer l'association longitudinale entre la détresse psychologique et le partage de matériel de consommation, tout en ajustant pour les diagnostics de troubles anxieux et de l'humeur en début d'étude.Résultats: Parmi les 605 participants en début d'étude, 29% répondaient aux critères de trouble de l'humeur, 44.7% répondaient aux critères de trouble anxieux, et 35% rapportaient une détresse psychologique sévère. Les taux de partage de matériel de consommation en début d'étude étaient de 67.5% pour les pipes à crack (parmi 536 fumeurs), 15% pour les seringues et 24.5% pour le matériel d'injection excluant les seringues (parmi 387 injecteurs). Les taux de prévalence de détresse psychologique  sévère ainsi que de partage de tout type de matériel de consommation ont diminué progressivement au cours des visites de suivi. Objectif 1 : Une association significative a été démontrée entre la détresse psychologique et le partage de seringues (Rapport de cote ajusté (RCA): 2.1, 95% CI: 1.1-3.8). Objectif 2: La détresse psychologique n'était associée à aucun type de partage de matériel d'injection après avoir ajusté pour les facteurs socio-démographiques et pour les diagnostics psychiatriques primaires. Les troubles anxieux primaires étaient associés au partage de seringues (RCA: 1.89, 95% CI: 1.17–3.03).  Aucun marqueur de trouble de santé mentale n'était associé au partage matériel de consommation autre que les seringues. Conclusion: Dans cette étude, nous avons évalué l'association entre la détresse psychologique, les diagnostics primaires  de troubles anxieux et de l'humeur et le partage de matériel de consommation. Nos résultats démontrent une association significative entre les troubles anxieux primaires et le partage de seringues. Ces résultats suggèrent qu'une amélioration du dépistage et du traitement des troubles anxieux dans le cadre des services préventifs offerts aux consommateurs de cocaïne pourrait contribuer à diminuer les taux de transmission du VIH et de l'hépatite C dans cette population. Davantage de recherche est nécessaire pour déterminer l'impact du traitement des troubles anxieux sur le partage de seringues chez les consommateurs de cocaïne. </description><description>Introduction: Mental illness and cocaine use are significant risk factors for the sharing of drug paraphernalia and the transmission of bloodborne viruses among drug users. Yet little is known regarding the impact of different manifestations of mental illness on drug paraphernalia sharing among cocaine users. Objectives: Using data from the COSMO study, a cohort of cocaine users in Montreal: 1) we examined the association between symptoms of psychological distress and drug paraphernalia sharing; 2) we examined the association between symptoms of psychological distress and drug paraphernalia sharing, while accounting for primary mood and anxiety disorders.Methods: Smoking and injecting cocaine users were recruited in Montréal, Canada, between October 2010 and September 2014. Diagnosis of primary mood and anxiety disorders in the year prior to baseline were assessed using the Composite International Diagnostic Interview (CIDI). The severity of psychological distress based on the Kessler scale and three categories of drug paraphernalia sharing (smoking material; needle; and injection material excluding needle) were assessed at baseline and at each of the 5 follow-up visits at 3-month intervals. Objective 1: We conducted multivariate logistic regressions to examine the cross-sectional association between baseline psychological distress and paraphernalia sharing. Objective 2: We used generalized estimation equations (GEE) to examine the longitudinal association between the severity of psychological distress and paraphernalia sharing, while accounting for baseline diagnosis of mood and anxiety disorders.  Results: Among 605 cocaine users at study entry, 29% and 44.7% met criteria for primary mood and anxiety disorders, respectively, and 35% reported severe psychological distress. The baseline prevalence of sharing was 67.5% for crack pipes (among 536 smokers), 15% for needle and 24.5% for injection material other than needle (among 387 injectors). The rate of severe psychological distress and of each type of paraphernalia sharing decreased over time. Objective 1: Cross-sectional multivariate analysis showed a significant association between psychological distress and needle sharing (Adjusted Odds Ratio (AOR): 2.1, 95% CI: 1.1-3.8), but not with sharing of other drug paraphernalia.  Objective 2: After adjusting for socio-demographic and primary psychiatric disorders, the association between psychological distress and any type of material sharing were no longer significant. Participants with primary anxiety disorders were more likely to share needles (AOR: 1.89, 95% CI: 1.17–3.03). No mental illness marker was significantly associated with the sharing of injection material other than needles.Conclusion: When symptoms of psychological distress, primary mood disorders, and primary anxiety disorders were assessed in relation with different types of drug paraphernalia sharing, we found that participants with primary anxiety disorders were more likely to share needles. Our results suggest a potential role of improving screening and treatment of anxiety disorders among cocaine users to decrease bloodborne virus transmission in this population. More research is necessary to determine the impact of treating anxiety disorders in active cocaine users to reduce needle sharing. </description><creator>Lévesque, Annie</creator><contributor>Julie Bruneau (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Gillian Bartlett-Esquilant (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Exploring the link between mental health and drug paraphernalia sharing among cocaine users</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tv21b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763951h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zh03s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Quatre mouvements de profil aéronautique ont été étudiées en utilisant des mesures de pression de surface, avec quatre modifications imposées de géométrie ou de cinématique. (1) Un profil NACA 0015 stationaire équipé d'un volet de bord de fuite (VBF) de 25% corde, incorporant des volets Gurney (VG) de différents hauteurs et perforations, a été étudié. (2) L'impact d'un VBF dévié dynamiquement, en conjonction avec un volet Gurney, sur un profil NACA 0015 soumis à un mouvement ramper a également été étudié. (3) Les effets d'un volet de bord de fuite dévié harmoniquement, actionné à différents moments et avec différentes amplitudes de déviation, sur un profil NACA 0015 oscillant ont été étudiés. (4) Finalement, un profil NACA 0012 avec une mouvement de translation, superposée par un mouvement oscillant, a été étudiée. Les mesures de pression de surface ont été supplémentées par des mesures de vélocimétrie d'image de particule, d'anémométrie à fil chaud, et de visualisations de fumée. Pour le profil stationaire, le VG et VBF combinés ont conduits à une augmentation significative de la portance, la traînée, et le moment de tangage par rapport à celle produite par VBF ou VG déployé indépendamment. L'efficacité maximale est produite avec le VG de plus petit hauteur. Pour le profil ramper, un actionnement plus tôt du VBF et une durée plus courte a entraîné à une plus grande portance maximale. L'ajout d'un volet Gurney au VBF dynamique a resulté à une augmentation supplémentaire de la portance maximale. Pour le profil oscillant, les changements observés dans les valeurs critiques aérodynamiques ont été produits principalement par la modification de la pression développée sur les surfaces inférieure et supérieure du volet. La formation et le détachement du tourbillon de bord d'attaque ont restés largement inaffectés par le fléchissement du VBF, quel que soit le temps d'actuation du volet. L'intensité du tourbillon de bord d'attaque a été plus grand pour les actionnements plus tardifs. Pour le profil translaté, les forces aérodynamiques sont demeurées pratiquement inchangées sur l'ensemble d'un cycle pour le mouvement d'oscillation hors-phase. L'oscillation en-phase a constamment produit  les meilleures performances de levage tout en souffrant d'un plus grand moment de tangage. Le déphasage entre les deux mouvements était le paramètre clé pour contrôler la génération des forces aérodynamiques.</description><description>Four separate airfoil motions were investigated using surface pressure measurements, incorporating four imposed geometric or kinematic modifications. (1) A stationary NACA 0015 airfoil equipped with a full-span 25% chord plain trailing-edge flap (TEF), incorporating Gurney flaps (GF) of different flap heights and perforations, was investigated. (2) The impact of a dynamically deflected TEF, in conjunction with a Gurney flap, on a NACA 0015 airfoil subjected to a constant ramping or pitch-up motion was also examined. (3) The effects of a harmonically deflected trailing-edge flap, actuated at different start times and deflection amplitudes, on an oscillating NACA 0015 airfoil were investigated. (4) Finally, a NACA 0012 heaving airfoil with a super-imposed oscillation motion was studied. The surface pressure measurements were supplemented with particle-image velocimetry, hot-wire measurements, and smoke-flow visualizations. For the stationary airfoil, the combined GF and TEF led to a significant increase in the lift, drag, and pitching moment coefficient compared to that produced by independently deployed TEF or GF. The maximum effectiveness occurred with the smallest flap height. For the ramping airfoil, an earlier TEF actuation and shorter duration resulted in a larger maximum lift. The addition of a Gurney flap to the dynamic TEF led to a further increase in the maximum lift.  For the oscillating airfoil, the observed change in the critical aerodynamic values were mainly produced by the drastic change in the pressure developed on both lower and upper surfaces of the flap. The formation and detachment of the leading-edge vortex were found to remain largely unaffected by the flap deflection, regardless of the flap actuation start time. The later the flap actuation the larger the change in the intensity of the leading-edge vortex. For the heaving airfoil, the aerodynamics were virtually unchanged over an entire combined motion cycle for the out-of-phase oscillation motion. The in-phase case persistently produced the best lift performance while suffering from a large nose-down pitching moment. The phase shift between the two motions was the key parameter to control the aerodynamic load generation.</description><creator>Su, Ying Yu</creator><contributor>Luc Mongeau (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering</subject><title>An experimental study of flapping flight through imposed motion on a symmetric airfoil</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sz566.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zh03s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zs25xc08k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ce mémoire présente la première application du modèle probabiliste de Bag of Words au contexte de la sclérose en plaques (SEP). Un modèle probabiliste a été utilisé pour représenter les lésions visibles dans des imageries par résonance magnétique (IRM) des patients comme des mots-clés dans une nouvelle représentation de Bag of Lesions. Dans ce contexte, l'apparence des lésions peut varier grandement en terme de taille, emplacement, forme, intensité et texture. La méthode du Bag of Lesions encode ces caractéristiques en utilisant un regroupement automatique d'un nombre arbitraire de traits de vision artificielles, tel que RIFT et LBP. Ces données sont combinées de manière probabiliste an de trouver différents types de lésions. Cette méthode présume que les patients avec des distributions de lésions similaires dans leurs cerveaux vont vivre des expériences de SEP similaires les uns aux autres et que ceci serait une méthode pour prédire l'activité future de la maladie. Lorsque les patients sont représentés par une certaine distribution de lésions, les lésions qui sont le plus prédictives des lésions futures sont automatiquement sélectionnées par une méthode d'élimination à l'envers. Une méthode est présentée pour déterminer automatiquement des groupes de patients en utilisant l'algorithme de Expectation Maximization pour trouver des regroupements de patients qui ont des similitudes dans leurs expériences de la maladie. Le modèle utilise des donnés provenant d'un essai clinique de multi-centres consistant de 1048 patients qui ont été examinés en quatre différentes modalités de IRM et testés en utilisant une validation à 50 reprises. Un classicateur Random Forest est entrainé pour prédire automatiquement les activités futures de la SEP dans les deux années suivantes en utilisant l'apparence des lésions des patients et atteint une sensitivité de 94% lorsqu'uniquement les prédictions les plus certaines sont utilisées. Ce classicateur est comparé aux Support Vector Machines (SVM) en utilisant une variété de noyaux, aux méthodes de Nearest Neighbor utilisant plusieurs types de distance, et au classicateur Naive Bayesian simplifié qui prend le nombre de lésions de différentes tailles comme intrant, et a démontré de meilleurs résultats que ces dernières méthodes. Finalement, une méthode combinant deux classicateurs, entrainés sur des patients de SEP traités et non traités, est présentée pour identifier automatiquement les répondeurs aux traitements spécifiques de SEP.</description><description>This thesis presents the first application of the Bag of Words probabilistic model to the context of Multiple Sclerosis (MS). A probabilistic framework was adopted to represent lesions visible in patients' Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) scans as codewords in a novel Bag of Lesions representation. In this context, lesions' appearance can vary widely in terms of size, location, shape, intensity and texture, and the Bag of Lesions encodes these characteristics using automatic clustering of an arbitrary number of computer vision features, such as RIFT and LBP. These are probabilistically combined to find types of lesions. This work uses the assumption that patients with similar distributions of lesions in their brains will experience MS similarly to each other, and a method for the automatic prediction of future disease activity is described. Once patients are represented by a distribution of lesions, the types of lesions that are most predictive of future lesion activity are automatically selected using a backwards elimination method. A method is presented to automatically determine groups of patients using the Expectation Maximization (EM) algorithm to find clusters of patients that experience the disease similarly. The model is learned on data from a large multi-centre clinical trial consisting of 1048 patients who were each scanned in four different MRI modalities, and tested using 50-fold cross validation. A Random Forest classifier is trained to automatically predict future MS activity up to two years in the future based on patients' lesions' appearance, and achieves a sensitivity of 94% when only the most certain predictions are counted. This classifier is compared to Support Vector Machines (SVM) using a variety of kernels, Nearest Neighbour methods using several distance metrics, and a simpler Naive Bayesian classifier that takes the number of lesions of different sizes as input, and shown to make better predictions. Finally, a method combining two classifiers, trained on untreated and treated MS patients, is presented to automatically identify responders to specific MS treatments.</description><creator>Doyle, Andrew</creator><contributor>Tal Arbel (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</subject><title>Probabilistic patient grouping and prediction of Multiple Sclerosis disease activity based on a Bag of Lesions brain image representation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z784f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xc08k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zx05f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Quartz crystal-based oscillators have been employed for timing and frequency references applications since the 1950s. However, the quartz fabrication process imposes limitations in terms of robustness, size, cost, and direct on-chip integration with Complementary Metal-Oxide Semiconductor (CMOS) circuits. An unmatched infrastructure investment in advanced semiconductor foundries has allowed for the introduction of a new silicon based timing references, the MicroElectroMechanical Systems (MEMS) resonator. These new devices are able to provide superior timing performance while at the same time setting new standards in terms of robustness, power consumption and miniaturization. This work describes the fabrication of wafer-level vacuum-encapsulated silicon resonators fabricated in MEMS Integrated Design for Inertial Sensors (MIDIS), a commercial pure-play MEMS process, provided by Teledyne DALSA Semiconductor Inc. (TDSI). MIDIS offers a 30 μm thick silicon device layer that is wafer-level vacuum encapsulated at 10 mTorr. The total leak rate equivalent is noted to be as low as 6.5 x 10−17 atm cm3/s, which provides an ultra-clean environment for the operation of the devices. The Lamé mode resonators developed in this work achieved a quality factor of 3.24 million at a resonance frequency of 6.89 MHz, resulting in the highest recorded f-Q product of 2.23e13 Hz for wafer-level vacuum-encapsulated silicon resonators. The device was integrated in a PCB based oscillator in order to build a high performance frequency reference that meets most Global System for Mobile Communications (GSM) specifications.Furthermore, low polarization voltage breath-mode ring resonators are presented here. The ring resonators are designed to operate with a low DC polarization voltage, starting at 5V, while providing a high frequency-Quality factor (f-Q) product. The vacuum packaging quality is evaluated using an automated testing setup over an extended time period. The fabricated devices had a resonant frequency of 10 MHz with the quality factor exceeding 8.4e4. Finally, this works presents wafer-level vacuum-encapsulated silicon resonators with transduction gap of 200 nm. The devices are fabricated in MIDIS where the default minimum transduction gap in the MIDIS process is 1.5 μm. A gap reduction technique that relies on arc-welding is introduced here. The prototype Lamé mode resonators are encapsulated in an ultra-clean 10 mTorr vacuum cavity that ensures long-term stability. The Quality factor was measured to be 1.37 million at a resonance frequency of 6.89 MHz. With the narrower gap, the motional resistance of the resonators is reduced by a factor of 10 times.</description><description>Les oscillateurs basés sur un cristal de quartz ont été employés depuis les 1950s pour les applications de chronométrage et de références de fréquences. Cependant, la méthode de fabrication de quartz impose des limites sur la grandeur, le coût, la robustesse et l'intégration sur puce directe avec les circuits de Complementary Metal-Oxide Semiconductor (CMOS). Un investissement d'infrastructure sans pareil dans les fonderies avancées de semiconductors a permis une introduction d'une nouvelle référence de chronométrage à base de silicium – le résonateur Microsystème électromécanique (MEMS). Ces nouveaux appareils sont capables de fournir une performance de chronométrage supérieure, tout en établissant de nouvelles normes de robustesse, consommation d'énergie et miniaturisation.Ce travail décrit la fabrication des résonateurs siliciums encapsulés sous vide au niveau wafer(en matière de, dans le domaine de, au point de vue de) qui sont faits grâce à MEMS Integrated Design for Inertial Sensors (MIDIS), un procès MEMS commercial fourni par Teledyne DALSA Semiconductor Inc. (TDSI). MIDIS fournit une couche d'appareil silicium avec une épaisseur de 30 μm qui est encapsulé sous vide au niveau wafer à 10 mTorr. L'équivalent taux de fuite total est noté d'être aussi bas que 6.5 x 10−17 atm cm3/s, qui crée un environnement "ultra-clean" pour l'opération des appareils. Les résonateurs 'Lamé mode' développés dans ce travail ont obtenu un facteur de qualité de 3.24 million à une fréquence de résonance 6.89 MHz; ceci donne un produit F-Q de 2.23e13, qui représente la valeur le plus élevé pour des résonateurs siliciums encapsulés sous vide au niveau wafer. L'appareil a été intégré dans un oscillateur fondé sur un circuit imprimé (PCB) pour construire une référence de fréquence au haute performance qui conforme à la majorité des demandes du Global System for Mobile Communications (GSM).De surcroît, cette œuvre présente également des résonateurs annulaires "breath-mode" avec une tension de polarisation réduite. Les résonateurs annulaires sont conçus pour opérer avec une tension de polarisation DC qui commence à 5V, tout en offrant un produit F-Q élevé. La qualité d'emballage sous vide est évaluée en utilisant une configuration de test automatisé sur une période de temps prolongée. Les appareils fabriqués ont eu une fréquence de résonance de 10 MHz, avec un facteur de qualité en haut de 8.4e4.Finalement, ce travail présente des résonateurs siliciums encapsulés sous vide au niveau wafer avec un écart de transduction de 200 nm. Les appareils sont fabriqués dans MIDIS, un procès qui a par défaut un écart de transduction minimum de 1.5 μm. Une technique qui repose sur le soudage à l'arc pour réduire l'écart est introduite à ce stade-ci. Les résonateurs prototypes de "Lamé mode" sont encapsulés dans une cavité à vide "ultra-clean" de 10 mTorr; ceci assure la stabilité à long terme. Un facteur de qualité de 1.37 million était mesuré à une fréquence de résonance de 6.89 MHz. En utilisant l'écart plus petit, la résistance motionnelle des résonateurs est réduite par un facteur de 10.</description><creator>Xereas, George</creator><contributor>Milica Popovich (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Vamsy Chodavarapu (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</subject><title>Wafer-level vacuum encapsulated resonators with low motional resistance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b361w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zx05f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s5051</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:01:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'hétérogénéité inter et intra-tumorale participe à la complexité de la biologie du cancer du sein. Le cancer du sein triple négatif (CSTN) est difficile à traiter en raison de son hétérogénéité au niveau moléculaire et manque de cibles thérapeutiques actionnables. L'hétérogénéité du microenvironnement tumoral des CSTN reste peu caractérisée malgré le rôle clé que ce dernier peut jouer dans la progression tumorale. De façon similaire, l'impact de l'hétérogénéité intra-tumorale sur la réponse thérapeutique et la survie des patients demeure inconnue.Afin d'élucider ces mécanismes, j'ai analysé le transcriptome du stroma tumoral isolé à partir de CSTN (n=57) ainsi que le profil d'expression cellulaire (n=33) d'une xénogreffe dérivée de tumeur de patient (XDP) résistante à la thérapie et arborant une hétérogénéité d'expression du récepteur HER2. Ce récepteur peut être ciblé de façon thérapeutique en clinique. L'analyse du stroma des CSTN a permis d'identifier quatre propriétés stromales associées aux cellules T (T), B (B), aux cellules épithéliales invasives épithéliales (E),  ou à une réaction desmoplasique (D). La méthode que j'ai développée, intitulée « STROMA4 », assigne un score faible, intermédiaire ou élevé pour chaque propriété à partir des profils d'expression génique du stroma ou de la tumeur globale. J'ai pu montrer que le « TNBCType », une méthode de sous-typage des CSTN ayant préalablement été publiée, sous-estime la complexité de certaines tumeurs. De plus, la stratification des patientes selon la méthode « STROMA4 » permet de prédire la réponse à la thérapie avec une meilleure sensibilité que la méthode « TNBCType ». La combinaison des différentes propriétés identifiées par la méthode « STROMA4 » génère une nouvelle stratification des CSTN. L'analyse de cette nouvelle classification a permis de montrer que seul 15 des 81 sous-types possibles sont représentés par une population plus grande qu'attendue. Cette approche combinatoire révèle que les propriétés B, T et E sont pronostiques seulement quand la propriété D est de faible score. Ceci pourrait expliquer, en partie du moins, la mauvaise prédiction des classificateurs existants.L'analyse des données provenant du séquençage ARN de cellules isolées d'une XPD hétérogène pour l'expression de HER2 identifie des sous-populations cellulaires distinctes et révéle, de façon dominante, un sous-type basal de cancer de sein. La classification hiérarchique non supervisée distingue deux sous-populations cellulaires majeures ayant des taux d'expression du récepteur  EGFR différentes au niveau de l'expression génique. Cette différence est validée au niveau protéique par immunohistochimie sur un échantillon de tumeur humaine réséquée au moment de la chirurgie de la patiente.  L'étude des différences entre les cellules à forte et faible expression de EGFR par scRNA-seq indique que les cellules ayant une expression élevée de EGFR arborent des propriétés de cellules « souches ». Ce résultat a été validée de façon expérimentale. La présence de cellules ayant un fort taux d'expression de EGFR dans ce modèle ainsi que dans d'autres modèles XPD, est associée à une sensibilité vis à vis de l'inhibition de EGFR.   L'analyse du stroma des CSTN, utilisant un modèle de classification multi-paramètrique, génère une classification simple qui récapitule l'hétérogénéité des CSTN. Cette classification permet de comprendre comment les différentes propriétés biologiques associées à la tumeur interagissent et affectent le pronostic. D'autre part, l'analyse des données du scRNA-seq identifie deux groupes de cellules avec des différences de (i) niveaux d'expression de EGFR, (ii) propriétés de cellules « souches ». Ces cellules sont également  associées avec une réponse à l'inhibition de EGFR. Ainsi, ce travail permet une meilleure compréhension de la contribution de l'hétérogénéité aux niveaux inter- et intra-tumoral à la complexité de l'écosystème du cancer et son effet sur la réponse à la thérapie</description><description>The management of breast cancer is complicated by inter- and intra-tumour heterogeneity. In particular, triple negative breast cancer (TNBC) is a difficult to treat, molecularly heterogeneous cancer subtype that lacks actionable targets. The heterogeneity of the TNBC microenvironment (stroma) has not been well characterized despite the key role that it may play in tumor progression. Similarly, the impact of intra-tumoral heterogeneity on therapeutic response and patient outcome remains largely unknown.To address these challenges I investigated the transcriptome of tumor-associated stroma isolated from TNBCs (n=57), as well as comprehensive single-cell gene expression profiling from a treatment-resistant breast patient-derived xenograft (PDX) displaying heterogeneity for the therapeutically targetable HER2 receptor (n=33 cells).Analysis of the TNBC stroma identified four stromal properties associated with T cells (T), B cells (B), invasive epithelial cells (E), or a desmoplastic reaction (D) respectively. My method, entitled STROMA4, assigns each sample as either low, intermediate, or high for each property independently in stromal or bulk expression profiles. I provide evidence that TNBCType, a previously reported subtyping scheme for TNBC, underestimates the complexity of some tumors, and show how stratification by the STROMA4 method can predict patient benefit from therapy with increased sensitivity. Combining the STROMA4 property assignments generates a novel TNBC subtyping scheme, and analysis of this subtyping scheme revealed that only 15 of 81 possible subtypes had larger than expected populations. This combinatorial approach revealed that the B, T and E properties are prognostic only when the D property is not high, providing a potential explanation for misprediction by existing classifiers. Analysis of single-cell RNA-seq (scRNA-seq) data from a PDX heterogeneous for HER2 expression identified distinct cellular subpopulations and revealed a predominantly basal breast cancer subtype. Unsupervised hierarchical clustering distinguished two major cellular subpopulations with differential expression of EGFR, which was validated immunohistochemically in the resected tumour. Further investigation into differences between the EGFR-high and -low cells in the scRNA-seq data indicated that EGFR-high cells were more "stem-like", which was then validated experimentally. The presence of EGFR-high stem cells in this PDX model, as well as in other PDX models, is associated with sensitivity to EGFR inhibition.Analysis of the TNBC stroma, using a multi-parameter classification model, produces a simple ontology that captures TNBC heterogeneity, and informs how tumor-associated properties and biologies interact to affect prognosis; while analysis of the scRNA-seq data identified two groups of cells with differential expression of EGFR and stem-like characteristics, which is associated with response to EGFR inhibition. Thus, this work adds to our understanding of the contribution of inter- and intra-tumoral heterogeneity to the complexity of the cancer ecosystem, and the effect it has on response to therapy.</description><creator>Mehdi Ismail Saleh, Sadiq</creator><contributor>Morag Park (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Michael Trevor Hallett (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Biochemistry</subject><title>A transcriptomic analysis of intratumor and stromal heterogeneity in breast cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sg193.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s5051</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):6475</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>