<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:04:08Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):16075" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945v432</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The risk of progressive collapse of reinforced concrete parking structures due to punching shear failure of a slab-column connection can be increased by the corrosion of the top flexural reinforcement and delamination caused by exposure to de-icing salts.  Although considerable research has been conducted regarding the punching shear failure of slab-column connections, there has been little research regarding the effects of corrosion of reinforcement and delamination on the punching and post-punching shear responses of the connections.  Three slab-column connections were designed, constructed, and tested at McGill University to study: (1) the effects of significant delamination on the punching and post-punching responses of the specimens, and (2) the effects of structural integrity reinforcement on the post-punching behavior of delaminated specimens.  A plastic sheet was cast below the top mat of reinforcement of each specimen to simulate extensive delamination of the reinforcement.  The experimental results were compared to the experimental results of companion specimens tested by others, predictions using the CSA A23.3-04 design provisions, and predictions from an analytical model developed for the post-punching response.  The presence of structural integrity reinforcement allowed for the development of a post-punching shear resisting mechanism, producing a significant increase in both the post-punching shear resistance and the ultimate deflection of the specimen.  Extensive delamination caused decreases in the pre-punching stiffness, punching shear resistance, and post-punching shear resistance of the specimens.  The analytical model provided relatively accurate predictions of the progressive breakout of each layer of reinforcement during the post-punching shear response for the specimens without delamination.  However, the predictions for the delaminated specimens were less accurate, probably due to the combination of damage from both delamination and from the progressive damage during breakout of the reinforcement.  The model under-estimated the ultimate deflection of the specimens.</description><description>Le risque d'effondrement progressif des structures de stationnement en béton armé causé par le poinçonnement en cisaillement d'un assemblage dalle-poteau peut être augmenté par la corrosion du lit d'armatures supérieures et la délamination, causée par l'exposition aux sels de déglaçage.  Bien qu'il y ait beaucoup de recherches déjà réalisées examinant le poinçonnement en cisaillement d'assemblages dalle-poteau, il a eu peu de recherches concernant les effets de la corrosion et de la délamination du béton sur le comportement du poinçonnement et du post-poinçonnement des assemblages dalle-poteau.  Trois assemblages dalle-poteau ont été conçus, construits, et testés à l'Université McGill pour étudier : (1) les effets de la délamination excessive sur le comportement du poinçonnement et du post-poinçonnement des spécimens, et (2) les effets de l'armature d'intégrité structurale sur le comportement post-poinçonnement des spécimens délaminés.  Une feuille de plastique était placée sous le lit d'armature supérieure de chaque spécimen pour simuler la délamination excessive de l'armature.  Les résultats expérimentaux ont été comparés avec ceux des spécimens témoins testés par d'autres, avec les prédictions de la norme CSA A23.3-04, et avec les prédictions d'un modèle analytique développé pour l'étude du comportement post-poinçonnement.  L'armature d'intégrité structurale a permis le développement d'un mécanisme de résistance post-poinçonnement, créant ainsi une augmentation significative de la résistance post-poinçonnement et de la déformation ultime des spécimens testés.  La délamination excessive a causé des réductions de la rigidité avant le poinçonnement, de la résistance au poinçonnement, et de la résistance post-poinçonnement des spécimens.  Le modèle analytique, pour la prédiction de chaque rang d'armature d'intégrité structurale et chaque rang d'armature supérieure, est relativement précis pour les spécimens sans délamination.  Toutefois, les prédictions du modèle pour les spécimens délaminés étaient moins précises, probablement en raison de la combinaison des dommages causés par la délamination et la détérioration progressive du béton au cours de l'arrachement de l'armature.  Cependant, le modèle sous-estime la déformation ultime des spécimens.</description><creator>Reilly, Julie</creator><contributor>Denis Mitchell (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Civil</subject><title>Effects of delamination on the response of slab-column connections in parking structures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2677029k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945v432</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322j291</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'appauvrissement des cellules B en périphérie est un traitement effectif chez les patients atteints de la SP et ce type cellulaire semblerait être un important médiateur lors des rechutes associés à la maladie. Toutefois, ils peuvent aussi induire les réactions inflammatoires compartimentées dans le SNC qui semblent être à la base des stades chroniques-progressifs de la maladie. La persistance des plasmocytes dans le SNC et les agrégations cellulaires riche en cellules B, cellules T et en cellules ressemblant aux CDFs dans les méninges des patients suggèrent que le SNC inflammé lors de la SP fonctionne comme étant un environnement favorisant les cellules B. Les facteurs qui contribuent à cet environnement permissif sont restés faiblement compris.Nous démontrons que les cellules gliales et leurs produits solubles peuvent supporter la survie des cellules B ainsi que les fonctions pertinentes à la SP, incluant l'expression des molécules co-stimulatrices et l'activation des cellules T, la sécrétion des cytokines effectrices et la production des immunoglobulines. Les produits solubles gliaux sont anormalement élevés dans la FCS des patients, nous avons donc supposé que le FCS de la SP pourrait supporter la  survie des cellules B. Nous démontrons que le FCS seul, en isolement de l'environnement cellulaire complexe du SNC de la SP inflammé, n'est pas capable de supporter la survie des cellules B in-vitro. Nous démontrons aussi que les produits solubles sécrétés par les CEs de la BHE et des méninges peuvent augmenter ou modérer la survie des cellules B et peuvent aussi augmenter l'expression de la molécule co-stimulatrice CD86.Nos observations suggèrent que les cellules gliales et les CEs résidants dans le SNC ainsi que leur produits solubles peuvent significativement contribuer à un environnement permissif pour les cellules B et peuvent aussi supporter leurs fonctions effectrices pertinentes à la SP dans le SNC inflammé de patients.</description><description>The therapeutic success of peripheral B-cell depletion strategies in MS patients has identified B cells as important contributors to new relapsing disease activity in the periphery. However, they may also drive the CNS-compartmentalized inflammatory processes thought to underlie the chronic-progressive stages of disease. The long-term persistence of plasma cells in the CNS of MS patients, and cellular aggregates rich in B cells, T cells and FDC-like cells that have recently been identified in the meningeal compartment, suggest the inflamed MS CNS may be a B-cell fostering environment. The factors that contribute to such a permissive environment, however, have remained poorly understood.Here, we demonstrate that glial cells and their soluble products can support B-cell survival and MS-relevant B-cell responses, including co-stimulatory molecule expression and T-cell activation, effector-cytokine secretion and immunoglobulin production. Glial-cell derived factors have been shown to be abnormally elevated in CSF of MS patients, and we hypothesized that MS CSF may be able to support B-cell survival in-vitro. We demonstrate that CSF alone, in isolation of the complex cellular environment of the inflamed MS CNS, is not sufficient to support B-cell survival in culture. We then considered CNS-resident ECs as another source of B-cell support, and we demonstrate that soluble factors secreted by BBB and meningeal ECs can either enhance or regulate B-cell survival, and increase expression of the T-cell co-stimulatory molecule CD86.Our observations suggest that CNS-resident glial and endothelial cells and their soluble products may significantly contribute to a B-cell permissive environment and support MS-relevant B-cell effector functions within the inflamed MS CNS.</description><creator>Kobert, Antonia</creator><contributor>Amit Bar-Or (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>CNS-resident cells support MS-relevant B-cell responses</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505400q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322j291</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x743m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les interactions prédateurs-proies se produisant entre les concurrents qui partagent une ressource représentent une configuration réseau alimentaire connu sous le nom de prédation « intraguilde » (IGP). La théorie dicte que l'IGP dans sa configuration la plus basique est instable, avec des critères stricts en matière de coexistence. Cependant les prédations intraguildes sont assez fréquentes dans la nature. Le principal objectif de ma thèse était de montrer comment les modifications des interactions IGP peuvent favoriser la persistance de ce réseau trophique. D'abord, j'ai analysé, de façon théorique, les effets de la commutation des proies par les prédateurs intraguildes sur la coexistence.  Je me suis ensuite concentré sur les prédations intraguildes dans un système de mytiliculture. J'ai évalué, de façon empirique, les facteurs pouvant modifier les pressions provenant de la prédation intraguilde et étant exercées par les moules sur le zooplancton (proie intraguilde). Mon modèle IGP qui inclut la commutation des proies a abouti à la coexistence sur une plus grande gamme de paramètres par rapport au modèle de base IGP. Dans mon système de mytiliculture, la structure « âge / stade » ainsi que les déplacements de niches ontogénétiques ont été identifiés comme des facteurs modifiant les interactions IGP et qui empêchent potentiellement le zooplancton (la proie intraguilde) d'être exclu. Cette recherche s'ajoute à la littérature sur les interactions IGP et donne un aperçu sur les mécanismes qui permettent à ces réseaux trophiques de persister.</description><description>Predator-prey interactions occurring between competitors that share a resource is a food web configuration known as intraguild predation (IGP). Theory dictates that IGP in its most basic configuration is often unstable, with strict criteria for coexistence of intraguild predator and intraguild prey. However, IGP is quite frequent in nature. The main objective of my thesis was to show how modifications to IGP interactions can promote the persistence of this food web configuration. First, I theoretically analysed how prey switching by the intraguild predator affected coexistence. I then focused on IGP in a mussel aquaculture system and empirically tested for factors modifying IGP pressures exerted by mussels on zooplankton intraguild prey. My IGP model with prey switching yielded coexistence over a greater range of parameters compared to the basic IGP model. In the mussel aquaculture system, age/stage structures and ontogenetic niche shifts were identified as factors that alter IGP interactions and potentially prevent the zooplankton intraguild prey from being excluded. This research adds to the literature on IGP interactions and provides insight on mechanisms that allow these food webs to persist.</description><creator>Duffy, Sean</creator><contributor>Gregor Fussmann (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Ecology</subject><title>Persistence in intraguild predation food webs: possible solutions to a paradox</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h5210.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x743m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87pv17z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis studies the dynamics of decision-making in a repeated auction game used as a basis for designing distributed resource management and task assignment mechanisms. We study the problem of coordinating a group of independent agents in a dynamic environment where individuals make sequential decisions based on their ever-changing knowledge set. We extend the auction-based coordination paradigm presented in previous works to implement long-term desired operational state of the multi-agent system. We model the agent coordination problem as a non-cooperative repeated game and propose its outcome as agents taking strategic actions conditional on their private information, their previous actions, and their beliefs about current state of the system. We present heuristic methodology as a means to find optimal bidding strategies in games with unknown parameters, i.e. when agents do not have any prior knowledge of their opponents and their preferences. We propose approximately optimal strategies as zeros of a differential operator which maps the bidding function space into a real vector space in games where additional details are known about the environment. We describe the decision-making in each stage of the game as the sequential stochastic approximation of the equilibrium strategies, and accordingly improve practical features such as robustness and stability of the proposed strategies. We consider the cost of monitoring the bidding history and submitting sequential bids and propose efficient bidding as attending stages that can improve one's overall performance in the game and staying out when one does not believe it can win the auctioned item. We specialize the proposed solutions for applications in persistent surveillance, online advertising, and distributed computing systems and compare their performance with those commonly used in practice.</description><description>Cette thése étudie la dynamique de prise de décision dans un jeu d'enchères répétées. Ce dernier est utilisé comme base pour la conception de gestion des ressources distribuées ainsi que dans les mécanismes d'affectation des taches. Notre problème porte sur la coordination d'un groupe d'agent indépendant dans un environnement dynamique dans lesquels les individus prennent des décisions séquentielles en fonction de leur état de connaissance en constante évolution. Nous étendons le paradigme de coordination des enchères, présentes lors de travaux antérieurs, afin de mettre en œuvre l'état opérationnel désire à long terme du système multi-agent. Nous modélisons le problème de coordination comme un jeu non coopératif répète et proposons ses résultats comme étant des agents, capable de prendre de prendre des mesures stratégiques selon les informations privées détenues, leur précédentes actions, ainsi que leur croyances sur l'état actuel du système. Nous présentons la méthodologie heuristique comme étant un moyen permettant de trouver des stratégies optimales d'appel d'offres dans les jeux a paramètres inconnus, à savoir lorsque les agents n'ont connaissance ni de leurs adversaire ni de leurs préférences. Nous proposons des stratégies optimales d'environ comme zéros d'un opérateur différentiel qui associe l'espace des fonctions d'appel d'offres dans un espace vectoriel réel dans des jeux ou les détails ajoutes sont connus de l'environnement. Nous décrivons la prise de décision à chaque étape des jeux comme étant des approximations séquentielles stochastique des stratégies d'équilibre, et ainsi améliorer les caractéristiques pratiques telles que la robustesse et la stabilité des stratégies proposes. Nous prenons en compte le cout de la surveillance, l'historique des enchères, les  séquences des enchères soumises, et proposons des enchères efficientes en tant que participant pouvant améliorer la performance globale du jeu, et évitant de participer lorsque l'on ne croit pas aux chances de réussite. Nous spécialisons les solutions proposes pour des applications dans la surveillance constante, la publicité en ligne, et les systèmes informatiques distribues et ainsi comparer leur performance avec celles utilisées en pratique.</description><creator>Danak, Amir</creator><contributor>Shie Mannor (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Learning of rational behavior in repeated auctions with entry and monitoring fees</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gp519.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pv17z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jd473097c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the era of big data, data sets have been growing very large, and interest for algorithms and computation framework that handle such large scales is increasing. The number of computing cores per chip has also increased. Instead of developing ingenious ways of speeding up convergences and obtaining better approximations for a smaller subclass of the problems, it is interesting to simply "throw more cores" at exact algorithms and get a speed-up which scales accordingly. This allows practitioners who are not specialists to use the algorithms more efficiently. The MapReduce framework is one of the most widely used paradigms for parallel computation, and we show how to cast the exact deterministic algorithms for our customized spatial model in this framework. Higher-order Markov random fields, i.e., Markov random fields with higher-order interactions, have been shown to be able to represent large-scale properties of typical spatial scenes via MCMC simulation. We present a Markov random field parametrization such that the specification of clique configurations that include higher-order interactions is included in a methodical fashion. This ought to be useful for a practitioner with respect to specifying the type of images desired. The general Markov random field model commonly requires approximation techniques due to its intractable normalization constant, and inference and simulation techniques for models with high dependence via MCMC tend to be time-consuming and may involve algorithms with sensitive convergence criteria. These algorithms are not suitable for practitioners or spatial modellers who are not well-versed in MCMC, and it is therefore more desirable for them to work with models that are able to reproduce spatial structures, while still being easier to wield. We construct variants of the Markov random field that seek to achieve the same goal, but whose inference and simulation is tractable without MCMC, and cast the latter in the MapReduce framework. We also consider the MapReduce formulation of MCMC simulation algorithms for Markov random fields in order to leverage the power of parallel computing. </description><description>Dans cette époque du "big data", les fichiers de données atteignent des tailles très importantes, et il y a un intérêt grandissant pour les algorithmes et les infrastructures de calcul adaptés à de telles quantités de données. Le nombre d'unités de calcul par puce électronique va lui aussi en grandissant. Au lieu de développer des méthodes ingénieuses pour accélérer la convergence et obtenir de meilleures approximations pour des classes de problèmes plus restreintes, il est intéressant de combiner l'utilisation d'algorithmes exacts avec une simple augmentation du nombre de coeurs ("cores") de microprocesseurs dédiés aux caluls et d'obtenir ainsi une accélération proportionelle. Ceci permet à des utilisateurs qui ne sont pas des spécialistes d'utiliser les algorithmes avec plus d'efficacité. Le "framework" MapReduce est un des paradigmes les plus utilisés pour le calcul parallèle. Nous montrons comment formuler les algorithmes de notre modèle spatial spécialisé dans cette infrastructure. On sait que les champs aléatoires de Markov avec des intéractions d'ordre élevé peuvent être utilisés pour représenter les propriétés à grande échelle de motifs spatiaux typiques par la simulation MCMC (Markov Chain Monte Carlo). Nous présentons une paramétrisation des champs aléatoires markoviens telle que la spécification des configurations de cliques qui comprennent des intéractions d'ordre supérieur à deux est prise en compte méthodiquement. Ceci sera utile à l'utilisateur qui voudra spécifier le type d'images qu'il désire produire. L'utilisation d'un champ aléatoire de Markov général requiert des approximations à cause de la constante de normalisation difficilement calculable en pratique, et les techniques d'inférence et de simulation pour les modèles avec dépendances d'ordre élevé par MCMC ont tendance à demander des temps de calculs prohibitifs, et sont parfois basées sur des algorithmes dont les critères de convergence sont sensibles aux données. Ces algorithmes ne sont pas adaptés aux besoins des utilisateurs et modélisateurs sans connaissances approfondies du MCMC. Il est donc préférable pour eux de travailler avec des modèles qui peuvent reproduire les structures spatiales, tout en étant plus faciles d'utilisation. Nous construisons des variantes du champ de Markov aléatoire avec les mêmes objectifs, mais pour lesquelles l'inférence et la simulation peuvent être accomplies sans recours au MCMC, et nous adaptons ces dernières au framework MapReduce. Nous nous intéressons également à la formulation dans MapReduce des algorithmes de simulation MCMC pour les champs aléatoires de Markov pour pouvoir faire usage de la puissance du calcul parallèle.</description><creator>Manggala, Putra</creator><contributor>Luc P Devroye (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Roussos G Dimitrakopoulos (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>On Markov random field models for spatial data: towards a practitioners toolbox</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386p116.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd473097c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:08612s17k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Owing to its unique structure, along with the inexhaustible renewability, cellulose has been a subject of scientific and commercial interest for over 150 years. However, given attractive structural properties, such as stiffness, hydrophilicity, stereoregularity, potential for chemical modifications and ability to form superstructures, utilization of this biopolymer is far below its potential. Over the past few years the number of research projects to modify cellulose fibers to make them more suitable for numerous applications has increased. Transforming hydrophilic cellulose fibers into hydrophobic, non-hygroscopic fibers could potentially lead to a variety of new products, such as flexible packaging, self-cleaning films and strength-enhancing agents in polymer composites. To achieve this, we choose two different routes to chemically modify the cellulose fibers. In first method, cellulose fibers were oxidized with peridoate oxidation to different extent to prepare reactive dialdehyde cellulose (DAC) derivatives. Because introducing too many charge groups leads to fiber disintegration, we decided to cross-link the fibers to prevent this. These DAC fibers were in turn successfully cross-linked with 1,12-diaminododecane using methanol as solvent. Next, the cross-linked fibers were amidated in another Schiff-base reaction with n-butylamine to introduce the hydrophobic non-polar aliphatic chains. The cross-linked fibers exhibited stronger structural stability and the fibers did not disintegrate upon further alkylation with butylamine. The fibers were characterized with FTIR, 13 C-NMR, SEM, TGA, X-ray, contact angle and water sorption measurements. This procedure yielded very hydrophobic fibers with contact angles as high as 145o. Moreover, they had very low moisture uptake and high thermal strength, which makes them suitable for many potential products specially to be used in composites.  The second method was based on intermediate carboxymethylation of cellulose with monochloroacetic acid, followed by subsequent substitution with an amine. The carboxylmethylated cellulose fibers (CCF) were cross-linked in an EDC assisted bioconjugation reaction with adipic acid anhydride (ADH). In order to alkylate the fibers and introduce aliphatic amine chains to the cross-linked fibers, a second carboxymethylation reaction was performed to introduce more charge groups to the cross-linked fibers to act as reactive sites for further alkylation reaction with butylamine. The resulting carboxymethylated cross-linked fibers were then reacted with n-butylamine to introduce non-polar aliphatic amine chains. The modified fibers were characterized by a variety of techniques, such as conductometric titration, infrared spectroscopy (FTIR), scanning electron microscopy (SEM), mechanical properties such as tensile strength and Young's modulus, water contact angle and water vapor transition rate (WVTR) measurements. </description><description>Grace à sa structure unique et son renouvellement quasi-inépuisable, la cellulose a été un sujet d'intérêt scientifique et commercial depuis plus de 150 ans. Toutefois, avec ses propriétés structurelles fascinantes, telles la rigidité, l'hydrophilie, la stéréorégularité, le potentiel de modifications chimiques et la capacité à former des superstructures, l'utilisation de ce biopolymère est bien en deçà de son potentiel. Au cours des dernières années, la recherche visant à modifier les fibres de cellulose pour les adapter à de nombreuses applications a augmenté. La transformation de fibres cellulosiques hydrophiles en fibres hydrophobes et non-hygroscopiques pourrait potentiellement mener à une variété de nouveaux produits, tels que des emballages flexibles, des films autonettoyants et des agents qui augmentent la résistance des composites polymériques. Pour atteindre ce but, nous avons choisi deux voies différentes pour modifier chimiquement les fibres de cellulose.Dans la première méthode, les fibres de cellulose sont oxydées à divers degrés par du periodate pour obtenir un dérivé réactif, le dialdéhyde de cellulose (DAC). Parce que l'introduction de beaucoup de groupements chargés mène à la désintégration des fibres, nous avons décidé, pour éviter cela, de réticuler les fibres. Les fibres de DAC ont donc été réticulées avec succès avec du 1,12-diaminododécane en utilisant du méthanol comme solvant. Ensuite, ces fibres réticulées ont été transformées en amides par une autre réaction de base de Schiff avec du n-butylamine qui a pour effet de greffer des chaînes hydrophobes aliphatiques non polaires. Les fibres réticulées se sont avérées avoir une stabilité structurel accrue et ne se sont pas désintégrées lors d'une alkylation plus poussée avec du butylamine. Les fibres ont été caractérisées par FTIR, 13 C-RMN, MEB, TGA, diffractométrie par rayons X, mesures de l'angle de contact et de sorption d'eau. Cette procédure a donné des fibres très hydrophobes avec des angles de contact plus élevés que 145o. De plus, elles ont une absorption d'humidité très faible et une résistance thermique élevée, ce qui les rend potentiellement adaptables à des usages dans de nombreux produits et tout spécialement dans les produits composites.La seconde méthode est basée sur la carboxyméthylation intermédiaire de la cellulose avec de l'acide chloroacétique, suivie d'une substitution ultérieure avec une amine. Les fibres de cellulose carboxyméthylées (CCF) ont été réticulées par une réaction de bioconjugaison classique utilisant l'EDC et l'anhydride d'acide adipique  (ADH). Une seconde réaction de carboxyméthylation est alors effectuée sur les fibres réticulées pour y introduire plus de groupements chargés qui pourrons ensuite servir de sites réactifs pour une réaction d'alkylation.  Cette réaction est accomplie  avec du n-butylamine et a pour résultat la greffe de chaînes non polaires aliphatiques. Les fibres modifiées ont été caractérisées par une variété de techniques, telles le titrage conductimétrique, la spectroscopie infrarouge (FTIR), la microscopie électronique à balayage (MEB),  les mesures de propriétés mécaniques telles la résistance à la traction et le module de Young, la mesure de l'angle de contact avec l'eau et la mesure du taux de transmission de la vapeur d'eau. </description><creator>Sabzalian, Zohreh</creator><contributor>Theodorus G Van de Ven (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Chemistry - Polymer</subject><title>Cross-linking and hydrophobization of chemically modified cellulose fibers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wh14p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612s17k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j333590n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La rhinosinusite chronique (RSC), une inflammation des sinus paranasaux, est un trouble commun avec une étiologie incertaine, qui affecte les voies respiratoires supérieures et les sinus paranasaux. Les biopsies des échantillons prélevés sur des patients atteints de RSC documentent la perturbation de l'architecture normale épithéliale, en plus d'une infiltration de cellules inflammatoires intense constituée principalement par des éosinophiles. La classification clinique actuelle de la RSC est basée sur la présence (CRSwNP) ou l'absence (CRSsNP) de polypose nasale, mais aucune différence consistente de l'aspect histologique caractérise ces deux groupes. Récemment, nous avons identifié des profils d'expression génique distincts dans des cultures de cellules épithéliales provenant de sujets atteints de la RSC ayant subis une chirurgie des sinus. Ces signatures moléculaires, qui diffèrent du phénotype clinique, peuvent aider à mieux différencier ce trouble que le phénotype clinique. Dans notre étude, nous avons étudié l'aspect histologique associé à ces deux différentes signatures moléculaires à partir de biopsies chirurgicales obtenus chez des patients atteints de la RSC et les sujets témoins. Les infiltrats cellulaires ont été identifiés par immunohistochimie (IHC), une coloration à l'aide de trois marqueurs: l'élastase de neutrophile (NE), le CD68 et la protéine basique majeure (MBP). L'état d'activation des macrophages dans les formes classiques et alternativement activés a été vérifié par une double-coloration pour les marqueurs CD68 et CD206. Les résultats ont été rapportés à la fois selon les critères cliniques habituels (CRSwNP et CRSsNP) et aussi en fonction de leur signature d'expression en deux groupes (CRS1, CRS2) et les sujets témoins. Les signatures d'expression ont été validées à l'aide de coloration immunohistochimique pour le marqueur le plus différentiellement exprimé, le CCL2.Les résultats ont montré des différences dans le nombre d'éosinophiles, macrophages et les cellules de neutrophiles chez les patients atteints de la RSC par rapport aux sujets témoins. Selon le critère classique, l'éosinophilie était plus élevée dans le groupe CRSwNP, mais pas très différent entre les deux groupes pour les neutrophiles ou les macrophages. En utilisant les signatures moléculaires pour assigner des groupes, l'éosinophilie était similaire entre les deux groupes, cependant, il y avait une augmentation significative du nombre de neutrophiles et de macrophages dans CRS1 comparativement à CRS2. Le groupe CRS2 avait une incidence plus élevée des macrophages alternativement activés, supportant le concept d'une inflammatoire basse, phénotype CRS2 immunotolérant. La validité de la signature moléculaire a été supportée par la démonstration du niveau accru de la protéine produite par l'expression de CCL2 dans CRS1 par rapport à CRS2.En somme, ces résultats mettent en évidence un phénotype moléculaire de la RSC qui se caractérise par une infiltration neutrophilique marquée, et une seconde qui est nettement moins inflammatoire, accompagnée par l'activation alternative des macrophages. Ceci suggère que ces signatures d'expression peuvent identifier de nouveaux mécanismes basés sur des phénotypes, qui diffèrent du phénotype clinique, et peuvent aider à fournir une meilleure compréhension du mécanisme physiopathologique et les phénotypes de la RSC.</description><description>Chronic Rhinosinusitis (CRS), an inflammation of the paranasal sinus cavities, is a common disorder of uncertain etiology that affects the upper airways and paranasal sinuses. Biopsy specimens had taken from CRS patients document disruption of the normal epithelial architecture, in addition to an intense infiltration of inflammatory cells, consisting mainly of eosinophils. Current clinical classification of CRS is based on the presence or absence of nasal polyposis; however, no consistent difference in histological aspect characterizes these two groups. Recently, we have identified distinct gene expression patterns in cultured epithelial cells obtained from surgical CRS subjects. These molecular signatures, which differ from clinical phenotype, may help better differentiate this disorder than clinical phenotype. In our current study we investigated the histological pattern associated with these two different molecular signatures in surgical biopsies obtained from CRS patients and control subjects. Cellular infiltrates were identified using immunohistochemistry (IHC) staining using three markers: neutrophil elastase (NE), CD68, Major basic protein (MBP). Macrophage activation status into classical and alternatively activated macrophages was verified by double-staining for CD68 and CD 206 markers. Results were reported both according to standard clinical criteria (CRSwNP and CRSsNP) and also according to their expression signature into two groups (CRS1, CRS2) and control subjects. Expression signatures were validated using immunohistochemical staining for the highest differentially expressed marker, CCL2. Results showed differences in the number of eosinophils, macrophages and neutrophils cells in CRS patients compared to the control subjects. Using conventional criterion, eosinophilia was higher in the CRSwNP group, but not greatly different for neutrophils or macrophages between the two groups. Using the molecular signatures to assign groups, eosinophilia was similar between both groups, however, there was a significant increase in the number of neutrophils and macrophages in CRS1 comparing to CRS2. The CRS2 group had a higher incidence of alternatively activated macrophages, supporting the concept of a less inflammatory, immunotolerant CRS2 phenotype. Validity of the molecular signature was supported by demonstration of increased levels of protein product of CCL2 expression in CRS1 compared to CRS2. Taken together, these results identify a molecular phenotype of CRS that is characterized by a marked neutrophilic infiltration, and a second one that is markedly less inflammatory, accompanied by alternative macrophage activation. This suggests that these expression signatures may identify novel mechanism-based phenotypes, which differ from the clinical phenotype, and can help in providing a better understanding of pathophysiologic mechanism and phenotypes of CRS.</description><creator>Al-Mot, Sawsan</creator><contributor>Sam Joseph Daniel (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Martin Yvon Desrosiers (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health Sciences - Immunology</subject><title>Molecular signatures as a new classification scheme for chronic rhinosinusitus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60d115s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j333590n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xd07gx274</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Neurons in sensory areas of our nervous system respond to sensory stimuli, but they are also modulated at the same time by both feed-forward and feed-back mechanisms. The history of prior sensory stimulation shapes the way neurons respond to future stimuli, a bottom-up plasticity effect known as adaptation. In addition, we can willfully employ top-down attention, which affects the activity of sensory neurons in a way that enables us to focus on a relevant task at hand. In this thesis, adaptation and attention are studied predominantly in the context of time and timing. Time is an elusive phenomenon perceived by the brain that plays an important role in many cognitive functions. Understanding bottom-up and top-down effects in a temporal context is a less studied area of neuroscience that is needed for a better understanding of brain's function, cognition, and possibly consciousness. An important feature of our study was to observe both phenomena in awake animals that were engaged in a relevant behavioral task.In addition to the usual characterization of the effects for spikes, we also analyzed the lower frequency voltage modulations in the brain known as the local field potentials (LFPs). Knowledge about the meaning of the LFPs provides a broader understanding of how the brain works. One advantage of LFPs is that they sum all kinds of neural activity for many neurons in the vicinity of the electrode tip, and hence they have the potential to be informative about the correlations among the activity of those neurons.In the first chapter, a brief introduction is presented on background information with a focus on choice-related modulations of neural activity. In the second chapter, the methods used in our experiments are introduced. In the third chapter, the neural correlates of detecting dysrhythmia is studied by analyzing the spiking activity of neurons in area MT. In the fourth chapter, the effects of adaptation and attention on the LFPs and also on the relationship between LFPs and spikes is presented. In the fifth chapter, the effects of adaptation on temporal dynamics of neural response in area MT and its possible role in a temporal illusion in humans is addressed. In the final chapter, the implications of our findings and future perspectives are briefly discussed.</description><description>Les neurones dans les zones sensorielles de notre système nerveux répondrent aux stimuli sensoriels, mais dans le même temps ils sont aussi modulés à la fois par des mécanismes feed-forward et feed-back. L'histoire de la stimulation sensorielle affecte la façon dont les neurones répondent à des stimuli à venir, un effet de plasticité connu sous le nom d'adaptation. En outre, nous pouvons employer volontairement l'attention, ce qui affecte l'activité des neurones sensoriels d'une manière qui nous permet de concentrer sur une tâche pertinente à portée de main.Dans cette thèse, l'adaptation et l'attention sont étudiés surtout dans le contexte de temps et le calendrier. Le temps est un phénomène insaisissable perçue par le cerveau qui joue un rôle important dans de nombreuses fonctions cognitives. Modulation neuronal dans un contexte temporel est un domaine moins étudié des neurosciences qui est nécessaire pour une meilleure compréhension de la fonction cérébrale, la cognition, et peut-être la conscience. Une caractéristique importante de notre étude était d'observer les deux phénomènes chez les animaux éveillés qui ont été engagés dans une tâche pertinente du comportement.En plus de la caractérisation usuelle des effets de potentiels d'action, nous avons également analysé les modulations de fréquence inférieure de tension dans le cerveau connue sous le nom des potentiels de champs locaux (LFP). La connaissance de la signification des LFP offre une plus large compréhension de la façon dont le cerveau fonctionne. Un avantage de LFP est qu'ils résument toutes sortes d'activités de neurones pour de nombreux neurones dans le voisinage de l'extrémité de l'électrode, et donc ils ont le potentiel pour être informatif sur les corrélations entre l'activité de ces neurones.Dans le premier chapitre, une brève introduction est présentée sur des informations d'arrière-plan avec un accent sur les modulations de l'activité neuronale liée à la décision. Dans le deuxième chapitre, les méthodes utilisées au cours de nos expériences sont introduits. Dans le troisième chapitre, les corrélats neuraux de la détection des troubles du rythme est étudié par l'analyse de l'activité neuronale dans l'aire MT. Dans le quatrième chapitre, les effets de l'adaptation et l'attention sur les LFP et aussi sur la relation entre LFP et les potentiels d'action est présenté. Dans le cinquième chapitre, les effets de l'adaptation sur la dynamique temporelle de la réponse neuronale dans l'aire MT et son rôle possible dans une illusion temporelle chez l'homme est présenté. Dans le dernier chapitre, les implications de nos résultats et perspectives d'avenir sont brièvement discutées.</description><creator>Sadeghi Ghandehari, Navid</creator><contributor>Erik Cook (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>The effects of adaptation and attention on temporal perception in the Middle Temporal area of behaving primate</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rh98d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gx274</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644w28m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, I examined multiple sulfur isotopes in two different systems: mass dependent fractionation and mass independent fractionation. Mass dependent sulfur isotopes elucidate low-temperature oxidative processes from pyrite nodules within Miocene lake sediments found in the Haughton impact structure on Devon Island, Nunavut. Mass independent samples are investigated for lithological and geographical controls on the pattern of 33S and 36S anomalies in Mesoarchaean samples from Northwestern Ontario. In mass dependent systems, the distribution of isotopes can be predicted based on the differences in mass of the various isotopes. Published studies of abiotic and biotic sulfur oxidation show negligible fractionation between starting sulfide and resulting sulfates.  Pyrite nodules are being oxidized in a polar desert environment to a variety of sulfates including gypsum, jarosite, and schwertmannite. Within individual nodules, fractionation between sulfate and sulfide range from -10.1 to +17.9 ‰. In addition, a two-component mixing between pyrite and bedrock sulfates divides the nodules into three types. The first two are explained by conventional oxidation and mixing; however, most samples cannot be described solely through mixing or oxidation. Measuring large fractionations in sulfide oxidation has implications for the study of 'biosignatures' such that an oxidizing environment, for example the surface of Mars, would be incompatible with the preservation of 'biosignatures'. In samples older than approximately 2.45 billion years, mass independent fractionation is observed in rock samples. These anomalous enrichments or depletions in 33S cannot be predicted solely on mass differences; rather they are attributed to photochemical reactions of SO2 in an oxygen poor atmosphere.  Within the Mesoarchaean the magnitude of these anomalous 33S measurements are considerably diminished compared to contiguous time periods.  Previous work has focused on changes in atmospheric chemistry to explain these minimum values. By looking at samples from Northwestern Ontario, the effect of lithology and geography are tested. In addition, a sulfur isotope database compiles the literature data. The range of multiple sulfur isotope data is extended as compared to the data from South Africa and Australia; however, the magnitude remains small when compared to adjacent time periods. Nevertheless, the isotope systematics of the Mesoarchaean, with this added dataset, follow the Archaean reference array which has previously not been used for the Mesoarchaean samples. Regarding lithology, chemically and biologically precipitated samples show large variation in anomalous 33S whereas clastic rocks remain close to zero. </description><description>Cette étude se penche sur le comportement des différents isotopes du soufre dans deux systèmes distincts : le fractionnement dépendant de la masse et le fractionnement indépendant de la masse. Les isotopes du soufre dépendants de la masse élucident les procédés oxydants de basse température dans des nodules de pyrite de sédiments lacustres d'âge Miocène trouvés dans la structure d'impact Haughton sur l'Île Devon. Les échantillons indépendants de la masse ont été étudiés afin d'évaluer les contrôles lithologique et géographique sur les anomalies en 33S et 36S d'échantillons Mésoarchéens du nord-ouest de l'Ontario. Pour les systèmes dépendants de la masse, la distribution des isotopes peut être prédite en fonction des différences de masse des isotopes. Les ouvrages publiés traitant de l'oxydation abiotique et biotique du soufre démontrent un fractionnement négligeable entre les sulfites d'origine et les sulfates résultants. Les nodules de pyrite ont été oxydées dans un environnement polaire désertique pour former différents sulfates, comme le gypse, la jarosite, et la schwertmannite. À l'intérieur des nodules, le fractionnement entre sulfates et sulfites varie de -10.1 à +17.9 ‰. De plus, un mélange à deux composants entre la pyrite et les sulfates du substrat rocheux divise les nodules en trois types. Les deux premiers sont expliqués par des procédés d'oxydation et de mélange conventionnels, bien que la plupart des échantillons ne peuvent être décrits uniquement en termes de mélange ou d'oxydation. La mesure de grands fractionnements associés à l'oxydation des sulfites a des implications pour l'étude de « biosignatures » puisqu'un environnement oxydant, par exemple la surface de Mars, serait incompatible avec la préservation de telles « biosignatures ». Pour les échantillons rocheux vieux de plus de 2.45 milliards d'années, on observe le fractionnement indépendant de la masse. Ces augmentations ou réductions anormales en 33S  ne peuvent pas être expliquées seulement par la différence de masse. Celles-ci sont plutôt attribuées aux réactions photochimiques du SO2 dans une atmosphère pauvre en oxygène. Au cours de Mésoarchéen l'ampleur de ces mesures anormales en 33S sont considérablement diminuées en comparaison avec les périodes de temps adjacentes. Les travaux antérieurs se sont concentrés sur les changements de la chimie atmosphérique pour expliquer le minimum.  En considérant des échantillons du nord-ouest ontarien, les effets lithologiques et géographiques sont testés. En plus, une base de données des isotopes du soufre compile les données de la littérature. La variation des données sur les multiples isotopes du soufre est étendue en rapport aux données du l'Afrique du Sud et de l'Australie. Par contre, l'amplitude du fractionnement demeure limitée en comparaison aux périodes adjacentes. Toutefois, la systématique isotopique du Mésoarchéen, avec ces données additionnelles, suit les valeurs de référence de l'Archéen alors que celles-ci n'avaient pas été utilisées jusqu'ici pour des échantillons Mésoarchéens. En ce qui concerne les effets lithologiques, les échantillons précipités lors de procédés chimiques et biologiques montrent de grandes variations en 33S anormal alors que les roches clastiques demeurent près de la valeur zéro.</description><creator>Rodzinyak, Kristyn</creator><contributor>Richard Leveille (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Boswell Wing (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Geochemistry</subject><title>An astrobiological exploration of mass dependent and mass independent sulphur isotope fractionation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149t216.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644w28m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3484zm32k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La protéine de groupe polycomb Bmi1 est essentielle pour la prolifération de nombreux types de cancers. En freinant l'expression du suppresseur de tumeur p53, Bmi1 est capable de prévenir l'apoptose et la sénescence. c-Myc, une autre oncogène, s'associe à Bmi1 pour stimuler la transformation et la tumorigenèse. Une enquête plus approfondie de l'interaction biologique fondamentale entre Bmi1 et c-Myc est crucial pour notre compréhension de leur capacité à promouvoir la tumorigène. Dans mon projet, j'ai démontré que c-Myc et Bmi1 interagissent directement et forment des foyers nucléaires. La surexpression de Max, un partenaire connu de Myc, perturbe l'interaction entre Bmi1 et c-Myc et empêche la formation de foyers nucléaires. Des résultats similaires ont été obtenus avec un autre membre de la famille Myc, L-Myc. En outre, j'ai constaté que HDAC3 interagi et se co-localise avec Myc. HDAC3 forme aussi des foyers nucléaires avec Bmi1 et l'ajout de Max abroge cette interaction. En plus du rôle bien établi de Bmi1 comme un régulateur épigénétique, il a été démontré récemment que Bmi1 fait partie d'une ubiquitine-ligase E3 complexe, connu sous le nom complexe Bmi1/RING1A ou B. Ce complexe contrôle la stabilité de nombreuses protéines. J'ai démontré que Bmi1 induit l'ubiquitination de L-Myc qui à son tour provoque la dégradation de celle-ci. Ces données proposent un nouveau mécanisme de règlementation pour la stabilité des oncogènes Myc. Les résultats de cette thèse fournissent un nouvel éclairage sur l'interaction biochimique de Bmi1 avec Myc et Max.</description><description>The polycomb group protein Bmi1 is an epigenetic regulator essential for the proliferation of many types of cancers. By impeding the expression of the tumor suppressor p53, Bmi1 is able to prevent apoptosis and senescence. c-Myc, a prominent oncogene, cooperates with Bmi1 to stimulate cellular transformation and tumorigenesis. Further investigation of the basic biological interplay between Bmi1 and c-Myc is crucial for our understanding of their tumorigenic ability. In my project I demonstrated that c-Myc and Bmi1 directly interact with each other and form nuclear foci. Overexpression of Max, a known partner of Myc, disrupts the Bmi1 and c-Myc interaction and prevents the formation of nuclear foci. Similar results were obtained with another member of the Myc family, L-Myc. Additionally, I found that HDAC3 interacts and co-localizes with Myc. HDAC3 also forms nuclear foci with Bmi1 and the addition of Max abrogates this interaction. In addition to the well-established role of Bmi1 as an epigenetic regulator, it has been recently shown that Bmi1 is part of an E3 ubiquitin-ligase complex, known as the Bmi1/RING1A or B complex. This complex controls the stability of many proteins. I showed that Bmi1 induces an L-Myc ubiquitination, which in turn causes the degradation of L-Myc. This data proposes a novel regulatory mechanism for the stability of the Myc oncogenes. The results of this thesis provide new insight into the basic biochemical interplay ofBmi1 with Myc and Max.</description><creator>Gocevski, Goran</creator><contributor>Xiang-Jiao Yang (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Interplay of Mye and Max with Epigenetic Regulator Bmi1</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72pb94m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zm32k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gm00x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The third generation (3G) smart phones have been widely commercialized in many parts of the world, and they have become popular communication devices, which aim to provide fast and reliable wireless transmission in people's daily life. Code-division multiple-access (CDMA) offers many key advantages including secure data transmission, resistance to jamming and interference, total bandwidth usage, which have made CDMA a key technology used in the current 3G standards. In addition, single-user demodulation and decoding (SUD) have been adopted by the receiver of 3G CDMA systems due to the low implementation complexity, and the combined throughput of such system is known to be limited to approximately 0.72 bits/chip ‎[44]. 3G CDMA systems face a common challenge: multi-user interference (MUI) which is introduced by the use of non-orthogonal user-specific spreading codes. Due to central limit theorem, MUI often converges to a near Gaussian distribution. It has been recently reported that by using non-uniform chip-level signaling in a single-user demodulated/decoded optical CDMA system, one can greatly reduce MUI by shaping it into a non-Gaussian distribution ‎[15]. The objective of this thesis is to examine the impact of non-uniform chip-level CDMA signaling in multi-user demodulation and decoding (MUD), which is the competing technology to the commonly used SUD. Since MUD attempts to recover information sent by all users simultaneously, it has a great potential to improve the combined system throughput, but the demodulation complexity usually turns out to be too high to handle in practice. We have discovered in this research that by properly designing a CDMA transceiver structure that incorporates non-uniform signaling, MUD demodulation complexity can be significantly cut down which brings a promising system performance. This leads to further improve the 3G CDMA system throughput by the use of MUD. By using tools from information theory, we have established a capacity-complexity trade-off for MUD CDMA. Consequently, we have designed appropriate non-uniform signaling to greatly reduce the MUD complexity while still retaining a large portion of the MUD capacity. The architecture of a reduced-complexity MUD CDMA system using non-uniform signaling has been presented. Simulations results showed that we could achieve a greatly improved combined system throughput, e.g., 1.2 bits/chip, with bit error rate (BER) curves converging at moderate signal-to-noise ratio (SNR). </description><description>Les téléphones intelligents de troisième génération (3G) ont été largement commercialisés et sont devenus des appareils populaires dans beaucoup de pays du monde, permettant une transmission sans fil rapide et fiable pour une utilisation quotidienne. Le multiplexage par division de codes (CDMA) s'est imposée comme une technologie clé pour ces systèmes 3G, incluant une transmission sécurisée, la résistance aux interférences, et une utilisation totale de la bande passante. Par ailleurs, la démodulation et le décodage uni-usager (SUD) ont été adoptés par les récepteurs 3G CDMA pour leur simplicité de mise en oeuvre. Ainsi, la capacité théorique d'un tel système est limitée à 0.72 bits par chip CDMA ‎[44]. Les systèmes CDMA 3G sont confrontés à un défi commun: l'interférence multi-usager (MUI), qui est introduite en raison de l'utilisation des codages d'étalement non-orthogonaux entre utilisateurs CDMA. En raison du théorème central limite, le MUI converge souvent vers une distribution Gaussienne. Il a été récemment rapporté qu'il était possible de réduire le MUI en une distribution non-Gaussienne, en utilisant la signalisation non-uniforme au niveau de chip dans un système CDMA optique en SUD ‎[15]. L'objectif de cette thèse est d'examiner l'impact de la signalisation non-uniforme pour la démodulation et le décodage multi-usager (MUD), qui est la technologie concurrente au SUD. Puisque le MUD récupère simultanément les informations transmises par tous les utilisateurs, il présente un important potentiel pour l'amélioration du taux de transmission combiné, au coût d'une complexité de démodulation trop élevé pour une utilisation pratique. Nous avons découvert dans cette étude que la complexité de la démodulation du MUD peut être réduite significativement par la construction d'un émetteur-récepteur CDMA qui incorpore la signalisation non-uniforme et présente des performances prometteuses. Cela ouvre la voie à une nouvelle amélioration du taux de transmission des systèmes CDMA 3G par l'utilisation du MUD. En utilisant les outils de la théorie de l'information, nous avons donc établi un compromis entre capacité et complexité pour aboutir à la conception de systèmes CDMA avec MUD. Grâce à ce compromis, la complexité de la démodulation du MUD peut être considérablement réduite, tout en conservant une proportion significative de la capacité de canal, pendant la conception de la signalisation non-uniforme. L'architecture d'un système CDMA avec MUD utilisant la signalisation non-uniforme est présentée. Ainsi, nous présentons des simulations qui ont montré qu'un taux de transmission grandement améliorée pouvait être atteint, p. ex. 1.2 bits par chip CDMA, avec des courbes de taux d'erreur (BER) qui convergent vers un rapport signal sur bruit (SNR) modéré. </description><creator>Feng, Yi</creator><contributor>Jan Bajcsy (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Design of non-uniform signaling and multi-user demodulation/decoding for CDMA systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149t22g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gm00x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2v23vx54m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Naturally occurring CD4+CD25High regulatory T cells (nTreg) have emerged as an essential component of self-tolerance. These cells arise in the thymus and represent 1-10% of CD4+ T cells in humans and mice. They constitutively express the FOXP3 transcription factor. The importance of FOXP3 for Treg cell differentiation and function is illustrated by the Immune-dysregulation, Polyendocrinopathy, Enteropathy, X-linked (IPEX) syndrome; a rare and severe systemic autoimmune disorder caused by mutations in the FOXP3 gene. Treg cell defects are suspected to underlie most other human autoimmune diseases. However the characterization of human nTreg cells has been hindered by the failure to discriminate them from other CD4+ T cells expressing similar markers in states of inflammation, as FOXP3 is expressed by non-suppressive T effector (Teff) cells upon activation. Thus the functional correlates of FOXP3 expression in human Treg cells are ill-defined. We hypothesize that human CD4+CD25HighFOXP3+ T cells represent a heterogeneous population comprised of several Treg and T cell subsets in which the expression of FOXP3 has different functional and phenotypic outcomes. Using a novel single-cell cloning approach, we show that indeed about 30% of memory FOXP3+ T cells are not suppressive, thus revealing a functional heterogeneity amongst CD4+CD25High T cells. These non-suppressive cells are phenotypically identical to their suppressive counterparts, but are found to down-regulate FOXP3 upon activation. By examining the transcriptome of these unstable FOXP3+ T cells, we show that they constitute a genuine, Treg-related, T cell subset, endowed with a specific gene expression signature. Moreover, we find evidence that the stability of the Treg lineage and FOXP3 expression are orchestrated by a higher-level of T-helper cell lineage regulation. Finally, we show that the IPEX-derived A384T mutation in FOXP3 abrogates the capacity of FOXP3 to elicit the suppressive function of Treg cells, while preserving its ability to control their phenotype. We thus provide the first demonstration of a functional dichotomy in the role of FOXP3 in human Treg cells. In conclusion, we demonstrate that FOXP3 is not an absolute marker of suppressive function in human T cells, precluding its sole use as a clinical marker for the monitoring of immunoregulation. Furthermore, we delineate subsets enclosed within FOXP3+ T cells which vary in function and stability, and characterize the hallmarks of these unstable FOXP3+ T cells. These findings will allow for the exploration of their contribution to immune homeostasis, and of their defects in autoimmune disorders.</description><description>Les cellules T CD4+CD25+++ régulatrices dites « naturelles » (nTreg) constituent une composante essentielle de la tolérance immune au soi. Ces cellules se développent dans le thymus, et représentent 1-10% des cellules T CD4+ périphériques chez l'humain et la souris. Elles expriment constitutivement le facteur de transcription FOXP3, dont l'importance dans la différenciation et la fonction des cellules Treg est illustrée par le syndrome d'IPEX (Immuno-dérégulation, Poly-endocrinopathie, Entéropathie, liée a l'X), une condition rare et sévère d'auto-immunité systémique, causée par une mutation du gène foxp3. Des défaillances des cellules Treg sont aussi soupçonnées d'être à l' origine de la plupart des autres maladies auto-immunes chez l'humain. Cependant, la caractérisation de ces cellules chez l'humain a été entravée par l'incapacité de les distinguer d'autres cellules T CD4+ exprimant des marqueurs similaires en état d'inflammation. En effet, FOXP3 est exprimé par les cellules T effectrices non-suppressives après activation. Ainsi, les corrélats fonctionnels de l'expression de FOXP3 dans les cellules Treg humaines sont mal définis. Nous émettons l'hypothèse que les cellules T CD4+CD25+++FOXP3+ humaines constituent une population hétérogène, composée de plusieurs sous-populations de cellules T et Treg, dans lesquels l'expression de FOXP3 a différentes conséquences fonctionnelles et phénotypiques.Grâce à une nouvelle approche de clonage cellulaire, nous démontrons que chez l'humain environ 30% des cellules T FOXP3+ ne sont pas suppressives, révélant ainsi une hétérogénéité fonctionnelle parmi les lymphocytes T CD4+CD25+++ humains. Ces cellules non-suppressives sont phénotypiquement identiques à leurs homologues suppressives, mais perdent l'expression de FOXP3 à l'activation. En examinant le transcriptome de ces cellules T FOXP3+ instables, nous montrons qu'elles constituent une population de lymphocytes T à part entière, apparentée aux cellules Treg, et dotée d'une signature d'expression génique spécifique. En outre, nous observons que la stabilité de la lignée Treg et de l'expression de FOXP3 sont orchestrés à un niveau supérieur de la régulation du lignage cellulaire. Enfin, nous montrons que la mutation A384T dans FOXP3, dérivée de l'IPEX, abroge la capacité de FOXP3 à générer la fonction suppressive des cellules Treg, tout en préservant sa capacité à contrôler leur phénotype. Nous offrons ainsi la première démonstration d'une dichotomie fonctionnelle dans le rôle de FOXP3 dans les cellules Treg humains. En conclusion, nous démontrons que FOXP3 n'est pas un marqueur absolu de la fonction suppressive dans les cellules T CD4+ chez l'homme, excluant la possibilité d'utiliser FOXP3 comme seul marqueur clinique pour le suivi de l'immuno-régulation. En outre, nous définissons des sous-populations parmi les cellules T FOXP3+ qui diffèrent en fonction et en stabilité, et déterminons les caractéristiques de ces cellules instables. Ces résultats permettront l'exploration de leur contribution à l'homéostasie immunitaire et de leurs défauts dans des maladies auto-immunes.</description><creator>d'Hennezel, Eva</creator><contributor>Ciriaco Piccirillo (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health Sciences - Immunology</subject><title>The role of FOXP3 in human CD4+CD25+ regulatory T cell phenotype and function</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602452q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vx54m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591c67c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Lung cancer is currently the most deadly malignancy in Canada, accounting for 27% of all cancer-related deaths.  Over 70% of patients with non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) are diagnosed at a late stage, with a 5-year survival below 10%.  In NSCLC, the two oncogenes that are most frequently mutated are the EGFR and KRAS genes.  While targeted therapies have been developed for patients with EGFR mutations, oncogenic KRAS mutations are so far not druggable.  KRAS is a small GTPase that acts as an on/off switch to activate multiple signalling pathways, including the PI3K/Akt pathway, the Raf-Mek-Erk pathway and the RalGDS/Ral pathway.  In the BrafCA mouse model of lung tumourigenesis, it was shown that the Cre-mediated expression of BrafV600E, activating the Raf-Mek-Erk pathway, causes the formation of adenomas that undergo widespread senescence at the benign stage.  However, oncogenic KRAS mutations in mice cause adenocarcinomas, which suggests that other pathways activated by KRAS cooperate with sustained RAF-MEK-ERK signalling to bypass the oncogene-induced senescence proliferation arrest.  To elucidate which pathways may cooperate with the Raf-Mek-Erk pathway to lead to lung adenocarcinomas, I created four effector domain mutants of KRASV12 (S35, G37, E38 and C40).  The S35 and E38 mutants bind to Raf proteins but not PI3K or RalGDS; the G37 mutant binds to RalGDS and not Raf or PI3K and the C40 mutant is specific to PI3K.  I designed lentiviral vectors that code for the KRAS mutants (V12, V12/S35, V12/G37, V12/E38 or V12/C40), or eGFP as a negative control, bicistronically with the Cre recombinase.  These lentiviruses were used to infect BrafCA/+ and wild-type mice.  The biggest tumours seen in BrafCA/+ mice received the KRASV12 virus, followed closely by KRASV12/C40, suggesting that the PI3K and Raf-Mek-Erk pathways cooperate to increase tumour growth.  There was a significant decrease in tumour penetrance in all conditions where any KRAS mutant was present compared to the eGFP control, suggesting that KRAS may directly activate effectors with tumour suppressive functions.  Moreover, tumours in wild-type mice were only seen with KRASV12 expression.</description><description>Le cancer du poumon est le cancer affichant la plus grande mortalité au Canada, comptant pour 27% des mortalités liées au cancer.  Plus de 70% des patients atteints du cancer du poumon non à petites cellules (CPNPC) sont diagnostiqués à un stade tardif, avec une survie à 5 ans en-dessous de 10%.  Les deux oncogènes les plus fréquemment mutés dans le CPNPC sont les gènes KRAS et EGFR.  Des thérapies ont été développées pour les patients dont le cancer a le gène EGFR muté, mais aucune médicamentation ciblée n'existe pour les mutations de KRAS.  KRAS est une petite protéine GTPase qui agit comme interrupteur marche/arrêt pour l'activation de plusieurs voies de signalisation en aval, dont les voies PI3K/Akt, Raf-Mek-Erk et RalGDS/Ral.  Dans le modèle murin de tumorigenèse pulmonaire BrafCA, il a été démontré que la mutation BrafV600E, activant la voie Raf-Mek-Erk, cause la formation d'adénomes qui subissent une induction de sénescence au stade bénin.  Des mutations du gène KRAS peuvent causer la formation d'adénocarcinomes, suggérant que d'autres voies de signalisation activées par KRAS coopèrent avec une signalisation soutenue de la voie Raf-Mek-Erk pour contourner l'apparition de sénescence d'induction oncogénique.Pour faire la lumière sur quelles voies de signalisation peuvent coopérer avec la voie Raf-Mek-Erk pour mener aux adénocarcinomes pulmonaires, j'ai créé quatre mutants de KRASV12 (S35, G37, E38, C40).  Les mutants S35 et E38 interagissent avec les protéines Raf mais pas PI3K ou RalGDS; le mutant G37 peux lier RalGDS mais pas Raf et PI3K; le mutant C40 est spécifique pour PI3K.  J'ai conçu des vecteurs lentiviraux codant pour ces mutants de KRAS (V12, V12/S35, V12/G37, V12/E38, V12/C40), ou l'eGFP comme contrôle négatif, de manière bicistronique avec la recombinase Cre.  Des souris BrafCA/+ et d'autres de type sauvage ont été infectées avec ces lentivirus.  Les plus grosses tumeurs observées étaient dans des souris BrafCA/+ ayant reçu le virus codant pour KRASV12, suivi de près par le mutant V12/C40, ce qui suggère que les voies PI3K et Raf-Mek-Erk coopèrent positivement dans la croissance tumorale.  Il y avait une diminution significative dans le nombre de tumeurs observées dans toutes les conditions où un mutant de KRAS était présent comparativement au contrôle eGFP, suggérant que KRAS pourrait activer directement des effecteurs avec des fonctions suppresseurs de tumeur.  De plus, dans les souris de type sauvage, des tumeurs n'ont été observées qu'avec l'expression de KRASV12.</description><creator>Vandal, Guillaume</creator><contributor>David Dankort (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>Defining the role of different KRAS effectors in the initiation and progression of lung cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n204266t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591c67c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v928r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The olfactory systems play a critical role in the survival and mating behavior of most terrestrial vertebrates. Two different classes of odorants, general odorants and pheromones, are processed by the olfactory systems and convey several cues in vertebrates such as the presence of danger or of food, as well as social and sexual cues. In both the main and accessory olfactory systems, axons of chemosensory neurons must coalesce in the olfactory bulbs and form stereotypic connections with second order neurons in structures termed glomeruli. The proper guidance to and convergence of olfactory axons into glomeruli and the formation of these stereotyped connections are essential for olfactory function. This thesis examines the role of the Slit and Robo families of axon guidance molecules in the guidance of vomeronasal sensory neuron (VSN) axons to their relay structure, the accessory olfactory bulb (AOB). It also focuses on the molecular mechanisms that regulate glomerular axonal coalescence in the accessory olfactory system and how the Kirrel family of transmembrane proteins are involved in this process.I report here that Robo-1 and Robo-2 are expressed in basal vomeronasal sensory neurons and that the Robo ligands, the Slits are expressed in the target region, the AOB. In Chapter 2, analysis of Robo-2 and Slit null show targeting defects of basal VSN axons to the anterior region of the AOB. I demonstrate that Slit-Robo-2 signaling is essential for the accurate guidance of basal vomeronasal sensory neuron axons to the posterior region of the AOB. In Chapter 3, I perform a detailed analysis of the spatio-temporal patterns of expression of Kirrel-1-3 and show that Kirrel-2 and -3 are expressed in four distinct patterns in vomeronasal sensory neurons. Furthermore, I show that Kirrel expression patterns generate a molecular diversity code that is required for the proper coalescence of vomeronasal axons into glomeruli of the AOB. Ablation of Kirrel-3 leads to altered glomerular formation, including large misshapen glomeruli in the posterior AOB. The perturbed glomerular layer is associated with behavioral defects, namely a loss of male-male aggression in kirrel-3-/- mice. This thesis therefore supports a role for proper wiring of the accessory olfactory system in the control of innate behaviors in the mouse.</description><description>Les systèmes olfactifs jouent un rôle critique dans la survie et le comportement reproducteur de la plupart des vertébrés terrestres. Deux classes d'odorants, d'odorants généraux, et de phéromones sont traitées par les systèmes olfactifs et transmettent une multitude d'indices chez les vertébrés, tel la présence de danger où de nourriture, en plus d'indices sociaux et sexuels. Dans le système olfactif principal, comme dans le système accessoire, des axones de neurones chimio-sensorielles doivent converger vers les bulbes olfactifs pour former des connections stéréotypiques avec des neurones de seconde classe en structures appelées glomérules. Le guidage appropriée vers les glomérules, la coalescence des axones olfactifs en glomérules, et la formation de ces connections stéréotypiques sont essentiels aux fonctions olfactives. Cette thèse examine le rôle des familles de molécules de guidage d'axones Slit et Robo dans le guidage des axones de l'organe voméro-nasal vers leur structure cible, le bulbe olfactif accessoire. La thèse se concentre aussi sur les mécanismes qui régularisent la coalescence glomérulaire axonale dans le système olfactif accessoire, et sur comment les protéines transmembranaires de la famille Kirrel sont impliquées dans le processus. Dans la présente thèse je démontre que Robo-1 et Robo-2 sont exprimés dans les neurones sensorielles voméro-nasals basal et que les Robo ligands, les Slits sont exprimés dans la région cible, soit le bulbe olfactif accessoire. Dans le chapitre 2, des analyses de souris sans Robo-2 et Slit montrent des défauts ciblant les axones des neurones sensorielles voméro-nasal basal à la région antérieure du bulbe olfactif accessoire. J'établis que le signalement de Slit-Robo-2 est essentiel afin de guider de façon précise les axones des neurones sensorielles voméro-nasals basal à la région postérieure du bulbe olfactif accessoire. Dans le chapitre 3, j'exécute une analyse détaillée des motifs d'expression spatiotemporels de Kirrel-1-3 et démontre que Kirrel-2 et -3 s'expriment en quatre motifs distincts dans les neurones sensorielles voméro-nasals. De plus, j'indique que les motifs d'expression de Kirrel génèrent un code de diversité moléculaire requit pour une fusion adéquate des axones voméro-nasal en glomérules du bulbe olfactif accessoire. L'ablation de Kirrel-3 mène à l'altération de la formation glomérulaire, incluant de larges glomérules difformes dans le bulbe olfactif accessoire postérieur. La perturbation de la couche glomérulaire est associée à des défauts comportementaux, en particulier à une perte d'agressivité male-male chez les souris kirrel-3-/-. Cette thèse supporte donc le rôle d'une connexion adéquate du système olfactif accessoire dans le contrôle des comportements innés chez les souris. </description><creator>Prince, Janet</creator><contributor>Jean-Francois Cloutier (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>The guidance and coalescence of basal vomeronasal sensory neuron axons to the accessory olfactory bulb</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55zc24j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v928r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514np89w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Movements are inherently variable. This property of behaviour is so glaring it can be proved with little more than a piece of paper and a pen. Attempting to repeatedly sign one's name in the same spot quickly yields a blob of ink instead of a legible, ever darkening signature. Even so, we rarely stumble over our words or mistakenly step off of cliffs. The nervous system has strategies for controlling unpredictable disturbances and countering predictable ones so that behavioural goals are, more or less, achieved. What causes movement variability in the first place and how does the nervous system achieve movement accuracy when confronted with it? This doctoral thesis presents a series of studies that examine the problem of making accurate limb and speech movements when faced with unpredictable and predictable disturbances of movement. Through a literature review, Chapter 1 explains where movement variability comes from by looking at the neural mechanisms that drive movement and the environmental perturbations that can disrupt it. Strategies for dealing with these unpredictable and predictable perturbations are then reviewed. These strategies are explored directly in later chapters using two model systems. In Chapter 2, it is hypothesized that patterns of reaching variability at the end of movements are closely related to patterns of limb "stiffness"—or a limb's resistance to displacement. Stiffness is easily manipulated in the arm by changing posture; this makes reaching an ideal system to manipulate stiffness and test this hypothesis. Over two experiments, patterns of limb stiffness are observed to predict patterns of movement variability at the end of reaching movements into circular targets. This relationship does not depend on the direction of movement, and is maintained across different postures and patterns of limb stiffness. In Chapter 4, it is hypothesized that individuals show differences in how they use sensory information to counter predictable environment perturbations of movement. The sensory systems that maintain accurate speech—auditory feedback from the sound of the voice and somatosensory feedback from the movement of the articulators—can be simultaneously and independently altered. This makes the speech production system ideal for testing this hypothesis. Over three experiments, the sound of the voice and the movements of speech are manipulated; individual differences are observed in response to these auditory and somatosensory perturbations. The more individuals counter one type of perturbation the less they counter the other.In light of these findings, Chapters 3 and 5 discuss the similarities and differences in the control of movement variability between the limb motor control and speech motor control systems. There are large individual differences in response to predictable perturbations of speech that are not observed in similar perturbations of limb movement. It is hypothesized that these speech-related individual differences are caused by differences in linguistic experience.</description><description>Les mouvements sont fondamentalement variables. Cette propriété de comportement est si flagrante elle pourrait être prouvée avec peu plus d'un morceau de papier et un style. Une de signer à plusieurs reprises son tentative descend pas des falaises nerveux a des stratégies ceux nom dans le même endroit produit rapidement une goutte d'encre au lieu d'une signature qui devient plus foncé et lisible. Cependant, on ne bute que rarement sur ses mots et on ne par mégarde non plus. Le système à contrôler des désordres imprévisibles et à s'opposer à qui sont prévisibles pour que les objectifs comportementaux soient plus ou moins achevés. Tout d'abord, qu'est-ce que la cause de la variabilité du mouvement et comment est-ce que le système nerveux achève l'exactitude quand il est confronté avec lui? Cette thèse de doctorat présent une série des étudies qui examinent le problème de faire des mouvements précis des membres et d'expression orale quand on est affronté avec les désordres du mouvement imprévisibles et prévisibles. À travers une analyse de la littérature, le premier chapitre explique d'où vient la variabilité du mouvement en observant les mécanismes neuraux qui actionnent le mouvement et les perturbations environnementales qui pourraient l'interrompre. Les stratégies pour faire face à ces perturbations imprévisibles et prévisibles sont ensuite examinées. Ces stratégies sont explorées directement dans les chapitres suivants en utilisant deux systèmes modèles. Dans le deuxième chapitre, on fait l'hypothèse que des tendances de la variabilité d'atteindre à la fin des mouvements sont intimement liées aux tendances de l'impédance (rigidité) musculaire – ou la résistance d'un muscle au déplacement. L'impédance est facilement manipulée dans le bras en changeant de posture ; par conséquent l'acte d'atteindre est un système idéal à manipuler l'impédance musculaire et tester cette hypothèse. Au cours de deux expériences, les tendances de l'impédance de membre sont observées pour prédire les tendances de la variabilité du mouvement à la fin des mouvements d'atteindre dans les cibles circulaires.Dans le quatrième chapitre, on fait l'hypothèse que les individus montrent des différences dans la façon dont ils utilisent de l'information sensorielle pour contrer des perturbations prévisibles environnementales du mouvement. Les systèmes sensoriels qui soutiennent l'expression orale précis – la rétroaction auditive du son de la voix et la rétroaction somatosensoriel du mouvement des articulateurs – pourraient être modifiés simultanément et indépendamment. À la suite, le système de production de la parole est idéal pour tester cette hypothèse. Au cours de trois expériences, le son de la voix et les mouvements de l'expression orale sont manipulés ; des différences individuelles sont observées en réponse à ces perturbations auditives et somatosensorielles. Le plus que les individus contrent un type de perturbation, ils contrent l'autre type moins. À la lumière de ces découvertes, les chapitres trois et cinq discutent des similarités et des différences dans le contrôle de la variabilité du mouvement entre les systèmes du contrôle moteur des membres et du contrôle moteur de l'expression orale. Il y a de grandes différences individuelles en réponse à des perturbations de l'expression orale qui ne sont pas observés dans les perturbations similaires du mouvement des membres. On fait l'hypothèse que ces différences individuelles liées à la parole sont causées par les différences dans l'expérience linguistique.</description><creator>Lametti, Daniel</creator><contributor>David J Ostry (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Psychology - Behavioral </subject><title>On the achievement of accuracy in limb movement and speech production</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bj47c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514np89w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1544bs96n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tm3+ ions provide amplification in a wide variety of wavelength bands,including 480 nm, 810 nm, 1480 nm, 1900 nm, and 2300 nm. This thesis presentsthe characteristics of lasers fabricated with Tm:ZBLAN fibre as the gain medium.First, a single-wavelength linear cavity fibre laser at 810 nm is presented. Dual-wavelength lasing and bistable behaviour are demonstrated in single cavity lasers,while dual-wavelength lasing, bistable behaviour and wavelength switching are demonstrated in cascaded cavity lasers. Second, single wavelengths fibre lasers at 1480 nm in linear and ring cavities are presented. A maximum power of 340 mW at 1476 nm was obtained. Dual-wavelength lasing at 1476 nm and 1487 nm is shown in cascaded cavity lasers. Finally, using bi-directional pumping in a cascaded cavity, dual-wavelengthlasing at 1487 nm and 1487.6 nm, with a record narrow spacing of 0.6 nm, isachieved.</description><description>Le gain des ions de Tm3+ peut être utilisé dans un variété de bandes de longueurs d'ondes, incluant entre autres 480 nm, 810 nm, 1480 nm, 1900 nm et2300 nm. Ce mémoire présente les caractéristiques de lasers fabriqués avec des fibres de Tm:ZBLAN comme médium de gain. Premièrement, un laser à fibre à longueur d'onde simple à 810 nm, fabriquéavec une cavité linéaire est présenté. Une oscillation à longueurs d'ondes doubleset une opération bistable sont démontrées dans des lasers à cavités simples, puisune oscillation à longueurs d'ondes doubles, une opération bistable et une interversionde longueur d'onde sont démontrées dans des lasers à cavités en cascade. Ensuite, des lasers à fibre à longueurs d'ondes simples à 1480 nm, dans descavités linéaires et annulaires sont présentés. Un maximum de 340 mW à 1476 nma été obtenu. Des oscillations à 1476 nm et 1487 nm, obtenues avec des lasers àcavités en cascade, sont montrés.Finalement, un laser à 1487 nm et 1487,6 nm, avec l'aide d'une cavité en cascadepompée bi-directionnellement, est démontré, atteignant un écart record de0,6 nm.v</description><creator>Frison, Blaise David</creator><contributor>Lawrence R Chen (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Physics - Optics</subject><title>Single and dual-wavelength lasing in the 800-820 nm and 1460 1520 nm bands in a thulium ZBLAN fibre laser</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580r23w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bs96n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988p544</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les principales fonctions de l'appareil urogénital sont le maintien de l'homéostasie ainsi que la reproduction, ce qui est essentiel à la fois à l'organisme et à la survie de l'espèce. Par sa complexité, le développement de l'appareil urogénital est vulnérable à plusieurs anomalies, certaines étant associées à une prédisposition plus élevée au cancer. Résultant d'une série d'affections hétérogènes, le cancer demeure un défit sérieux dû à notre connaissance limitée des processus cellulaires normaux. Les travaux décrits dans la présente thèse concernent l'étude du lien entre le développement d'un tissue et son mécanisme de transformation oncogénique. Plus précisément, nous nous sommes concentrés sur deux facteurs de transcription nécessaires au développement de l'appareil urogénital, Pax2 et Gata3, ainsi que leur rôle dans le contexte du cancer du rein et le cancer de la prostate.En ce qui attrait au cancer du rein, nous avons démontré qu'une cible en aval de Pax2, CnABP, est surexprimé chez la tumeur de Wilms et semble à l'origine de diverses caractéristiques cellulaires liées au développement de tumeurs. Nous avons découvert une fonction de CnABP dans la régulation de la voie de signalisation de Calcineurine, elle-même associée à la tumeur de Wilms. Dans la même étude d'expression génique par puces à ADN qui permit d'établir un lien entre Pax2 et la cible CnABP, nous avons identifié une cible additionnelle, le facteur de transcription Gata3. Il est intéressant de remarquer que Pax2 et Gata3 sont tous deux exprimés dans la prostate, le site de développement de tumeurs solides le plus fréquent parmi l'appareil urogénital. Par des études additionnelles, nous avons démontré que Gata3 est nécessaire au développement ainsi que l'homéostase de la prostate adulte. Fait à noter, l'expression de Gata3 se trouve réduite suivant la progression de tumeurs de la prostate aussi bien chez l'humain que chez la souris. Une fois l'expression de Gata3 soutenue dans un model murin de cancer de la prostate,  nous avons observé que Gata3 peut contrer la voie de signalisation PI3K/Akt afin d'entraver la progression de tumeurs médiée par la perte de Pten. Nos résultats démontrent que le rôle de Gata3 dans le cancer de la prostate est compatible avec sa fonction dans le contexte normal, dont la régulation de la différentiation terminale et maintien de l'intégrité des structures canalaires.En somme, les travaux présentés dans cette thèse nous permettent de conclure que les anomalies dans l'expression de facteurs de régulation du développement peuvent favoriser la transformation oncogénique de cellules normales. En conséquence, chacun de ces facteurs représente une opportunité de choix vers de nouveaux outils diagnostiques et thérapeutiques contre le cancer.</description><description>The complexity of its development makes the urogenital system vulnerable to a number of developmental defects, some of which are associated with a higher susceptibility to malignant transformation. Cancer, as a group of heterogenous disease, poses a serious challenge because of our limited understanding of normal cellular processes.  The main focus of my thesis is to understand the link between development of an organ and the process of malignant transformation. Specifically, we examined the role of Pax2 and Gata3 transcription factors in development and cancer of the urogenital system. In the kidney, Pax2 is essential for survival and specification of nephric progenitor cells and is turned off once the tissue has differentiated. We showed that a downstream target of Pax2, CnABP, is overexpressed in Wilms' tumors and promotes cellular characteristics compatible with oncogenic transformation. Unexpectedly, we uncovered a function for CnABP in regulating the Calcineurin signaling pathway, which has also been implicated in Wilms' tumor. The close relationship between Pax2 and Gata3 in the kidney led to the examination of their roles in the prostate, an organ site also highly susceptible to malignancy. The strong implication in the literature for the role of Gata3 in prostate cancer led to the discovery that this transcription factor plays an essential role during all stages of prostate development as well as maintenance of the adult gland. Importantly, we established that Gata3 is lost during prostate tumor progression in both human and mouse. By enforcing the expression of GATA3 in a mouse prostate tumor model, we demonstrated that GATA3 mutually antagonizes the PI3K/Akt signaling pathway to impede Pten-loss mediated tumor progression. Critically, the role of Gata3 in prostate cancer is compatible with its function in the normal context, in regulating terminal differentiation and integrity of ductal structure.From this work, we conclude that the inappropriate expression of developmental regulators can be conducive to malignant transformation. Thus, there is a great deal to be learned from development that can be applied to tumor biology. Ultimately, the aim of our research is to improve understanding of normal versus diseased states with the ultimate goal of discovering new diagnostic and therapeutic tools that are currently unavailable to cancer patients.</description><creator>Nguyen, Alana</creator><contributor>Maxime Bouchard (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>The role of Pax2 and Gata3 transcription factors in urogenital system development and cancer.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698c21v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988p544</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x744w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The obligate intracellular protozoan parasite Toxoplasma gondii, the causative agent of toxoplasmosis, is a highly ubiquitous pathogen that infects virtually any warm-blooded animal.  Although the infection generally remains asymptomatic in healthy individuals, the parasite invariably encysts.  It has been shown that T. gondii is able to achieve this goal at least by interfering with MHC-II antigen presentation to dampen the development of the CD4+ T helper cell response and gain a head start on the host adaptive immune system.  Previous reports have shown that T. gondii inhibits transcription of MHC-II and several other related genes, but the causative inhibitory molecules have yet to be identified.In an attempt to identify these molecules, a forward genetic screening strategy was initially elaborated, with a genome-wide insertional mutagenesis carried out in order to disrupt the genes encoding for the inhibitory molecules followed.  By specifically isolating mutants unable to inhibit MHC-II expression and antigen presentation by flow cytometry, isolation of the disrupted loci and database mining could have enabled the identification by of the encoded inhibitory molecules.  However, the screen was not carried out due to experimental limitations.Biochemical analyses were employed to further characterize the MHC-II inhibitory activity, revealing that this activity segregated with the high-speed supernatant (HSS) prepared from sonicated parasites and was enriched with increasing centrifugal speeds.  The inhibitory activity was protein dose-dependent and was completely abrogated when the HSS was treated with a broad-spectrum protease.  Subcellular fractionation revealed that the inhibitory activity was found in fractions enriched with secretory organelles, specifically rhoptries (ROP) and/or dense granules (GRA).  Furthermore, excreted-secreted antigens (ESA) from freshly egressed tachyzoites displayed inhibitory activity.  Proteins from ESA preparations were separated by a two-step fractionation using ion exchange chromatography followed size-exclusion chromatography, and analyzed by tandem mass spectrometry (MS/MS).  Database mining of the MS/MS results generated a list of possible candidates, the majority of which originated from secretory organelles.Although MHC-II expression was inhibited, low levels of MHC-II molecules were still detected in infected or lysate-treated cells.  Experimental results argued that the first layer of transcriptional regulation has to be complemented by a post-translational layer of interference in the host cell endocytic pathway, involving the MHC-II associated invariant chain (Ii), and peptide editor H2-DM.  Ii mRNA and protein levels were induced in T. gondii-infected cells, while MHC-II and H2-DM IFN-induced expression was down-regulated.  Ii accumulated in infected cells from 20 hour post-infection until host cell lysis, mainly in the ER.  In Ii KO cells, the absence of Ii restored the ability of infected bone marrow-derived dendritic cells to present a parasite antigen in the context of MHC-II, arguing that Ii acts as a dominant negative on MHC-II-restricted antigen presentation of endogenously acquired parasite antigens.  Keys host proteases, namely legumain, and cathepsins L and S, and the acidification of endosomal compartments were modulated by the parasite, pointing toward a wider manipulation of the host endocytic pathway by T. gondii.  Opposing expression patterns of Ii and H2-DM had a drastic effect in vivo not only on parasite dissemination towards lymphoid organs, CD4+ T cell activation, and IFNγ production during acute infection, but also on cyst numbers and survival at the chronic phase of the infection.  Altogether, these findings reveal a broader manipulation of host cell processes by T. gondii, and shed new light on the intricate interactions between intracellular pathogens and host cells, and their ability to subvert immune functions to establish successful infections.</description><description>Le parasite protozoaire intracellulaire obligatoire Toxoplasma gondii, l'agent causant la toxoplasmose, est un pathogène ubiquitaire capable d'infecter tout animal à sang chaud.  En dépit du fait que l'infection reste généralement asymptomatique chez les individus en bonne santé, le parasite s'enkyste inévitablement.  Il a été démontré que T. gondii est capable d'atteindre ce but en partie en interférant avec la présentation d'antigène par le complexe majeur d'histocompatibilité (CMH)-II pour diminuer le développement de la réponse des cellules T CD4+ et pour ainsi devancer la réponse adaptative du système immunitaire.  Il a été démontré que T. gondii inhibe la transcription de CMH-II et autres gènes liés, mais les molécules inhibitrices causatives restent inconnues.Pour identifier ces molécules, une stratégie pour un criblage génétique avait été élaborée.  Une mutagénèse insertionelle à travers le génome devait être conduite pour perturber les gènes codant pour ces molécules inhibitrices, suivie d'un tri par cytométrie en flux de cellules infectées avec des mutants.  En isolant les mutants incapables d'inhiber l'expression de CMH-II, l'isolement des locus génétiques et l'exploration des bases de données auraient pu permettre l'identification des molécules codées.  Cependant, ce criblage ne fut complété dû à des limitations expérimentales.  Des analyses biochimiques ont démontré que l'activité inhibitrice se retrouvait dans le surnageant d'haute-vitesse (HSS) préparé à partir de parasites soniqués, et était enrichie avec des vitesses de centrifugation croissantes.  L'activité inhibitrice était dose-dépendante de protéines et était complètement abrogée lorsque le SHV était préalablement traité avec une protéase.  Un fractionnement subcellulaire révéla que l'activité se retrouvait dans les fractions enrichies d'organelles sécrétoires (rhoptries et granules denses).  Aussi, des antigènes excrétés-sécrétés (ESA) obtenus de tachyzoïtes fraîchement lysés possédaient une activité inhibitrice.  Les protéines d'ESA furent séparées par fractionnement en deux étapes, commençant par une chromatographie par échange d'ions, suivi par une chromatographie d'exclusion par taille et analysées par spectrométrie de masse en tandem (MS/MS).  Les résultats obtenus furent comparés aux bases de données, et une liste fut dressée avec de candidats potentiels, la majorité d'entre eux provenant d'organelles de sécrétion.Malgré l'expression réduite, quelques molécules de CMH-II étaient détectés dans les cellules infectées ou traitées.  Nos résultats démontrent que la régulation transcriptionelle doit être complémentée par une interférence au niveau post-traductionel dans la voie endocytique de la cellule hôte qui implique la chaîne invariante associée au CMH-II (Ii) et l'éditeur de peptide H2-DM.  Les niveaux d'ARNm et de protéines d'Ii étaient induits dans les cellules infectées, alors que ceux de CMH-II et d'H2-DM étaient inhibés.  Ii s'accumulait dans les cellules infectées dès 20 heures post-infection, principalement dans le RE.  Dans les cellules Ii KO, l'absence d'Ii rétablit la capacité de cellules dendritiques à présenter un antigène du parasite dans le contexte de CMH-II, proposant ainsi qu'Ii agit comme un dominant négatif sur la présentation d'antigènes endogènes provenant du parasite.  Des protéases de l'hôte (légumaine, cathepsines L et S) et l'acidification des compartiments endosomaux étaient modulées par le parasite, révélant une manipulation plus étendue de la voie endocytique.  Les modes d'expression opposés d'Ii et H2-DM avaient un effet in vivo sur la dissémination des parasites vers des organes lymphoïdes, l'activation des cellules T CD4+, la production d'IFN, le nombre de kystes et la survie.  Collectivement, nos résultats montrent l'étendue des processus de manipulation par T. gondii, révélant de complexes interactions avec l'hôte et sa capacité de subvertir les fonctions immunitaires pour établir une infection chronique.</description><creator>Leroux, Louis-Philippe</creator><contributor>Armando Jardim (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Parasitology</subject><title>Subversion of MHC-II antigen presentation by «Toxoplasma gondii» involves parasite secretory organelles and the modulation of host immune effectors in the endocytic pathway</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741w269.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x744w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p838f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Gas6 is a vitamin K-dependent, secreted protein that amplifies platelet aggregation and secretion in response to platelet agonists. Gas6-/- mice are protected from experimentally induced lethal venous and arterial thromboembolism. This protection has been attributed to defective aggregation in platelets from Gas6-/- mice. However, this platelet phenotype was only observed when platelets were challenged by one agonist, ADP, and only at a concentration of 5.0 µM. This subtle platelet abnormality resulting in a rather dramatic clinical phenotype raises the possibility that Gas6 from a source other than platelets contributes to thrombus formation. We hypothesize that Gas6 derived from the vasculature plays a role in venous thrombus formation. Gas6-/- mice are protected against venous thrombosis induced by 0.37 M FeCl3 in the inferior vena cava (IVC). Bone marrow transplantation experiments generating mice with selective ablations of Gas6 from either the hematopoietic or vascular compartments demonstrate an approximately equal contribution by Gas6 from both compartments to thrombus formation. Platelet depletion in wild type or Gas6-/- mice followed by reconstitution with platelets from either WT or Gas6-/- mice confirm that Gas6 from compartments other than the platelet contribute to thrombosis development. Furthermore, Gas6-/- mice are hyporesponsive to FeCl3 mediated tissue factor induction in venous endothelium, as observed by immunofluorescence micoscopy and further validated by a functional assay. In addition, in vitro, Gas6-/- endothelial cells are hyporesponsive to thrombin mediated tissue factor mRNA induction. Taken together, these results suggest that vascular derived Gas6 contributes to thrombus formation in vivo and can partially be explained by the ability of Gas6 to promote endothelial tissue factor induction. We also begin to explore the involvement of the FOX family transcription factor FoxO1 as a downstream mediator of Gas6 induced expression of VCAM-1 during endothelial activation. These findings support the notion that vascular Gas6 may play a pathophysiologic role in venous thromboembolism</description><description>Gas6 est une protéine vitamine-K dépendante, sécrétée qui contribue à l'agrégation des plaquettes.  Les souris déficientes en Gas6 (Gas6-/-) sont protégées contre les thromboses artérielles et veineuses.  La résistance à la thromboses des souris déficientes en Gas6  était attribuée à une réponse plaquettaire défectueuse.  Cependant, la phénotype plaquettaire était observée uniquement avec le traitement des plaquettes avec une concentration faible de l'ADP (5.0µM).  Cette observation indique la possibilité d'une contribution de Gas6 d'une source distincte des plaquettes.  Nous faisons l'hypothèse que Gas6 dérivé d'une source vasculaire contribue à la formation d'une thrombus. Les souris Gas6-/- sont protégées contre la formation des thromboses dans la veine cave inférieure induite par 0.37 M FeCl3. En utilisant des greffes de moelle osseuse, nous avons généré des souris avec les déficits de Gas6 soit dans le compartiment vasculaire ou hématopoïétique.  La formation des thromboses dans les souris chimériques était intermédiaire entre les deux groupes contrôles.  L'épuisement des plaquettes dans les souris WT, suivi de la reconstitution avec des plaquettes Gas6-/- a confirmé les résultats obtenus par les greffes de moelle osseuse. En outre, l'induction du facteur tissulaire était atténuée dans les cellules vasculaires des souris Gas6-/-.  Additionellement, in vitro, les cellules endothéliales étaient aussi hypo réactives en ce qui concerne l'induction du facteur tissulaire.  Nos résultats suggèrent que Gas6 dérivé d'une source vasculaire contribue à la formation in vivo d'une thrombose, en partie dû a l'induction du facteur tissulaire.  Nous avons commencé à examiner l'hypothèse à savoir si la protéine FoxO1 est impliquée dans l'induction de VCAM-1 parmi les cascades de signalisation de Gas6.   Donc, en guise de conclusion nos résultats soutiennent l'idée que Gas6 vasculaire peut jouer un rôle physiopathologique dans la thrombose veineuse. </description><creator>Robins, Richard</creator><contributor>Mark D Blostein (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Physiology</subject><title>The role of vascular Gas6 in the pathophysiology of Venous Thrombosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tg62z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p838f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712mb45j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Spontaneous or self-heating of sulphides can occur under certain conditions of moisture, temperature and oxygen concentration.  This can lead to emission of toxic gases such as SO2 and if uncontrolled, to ignition. Research has established that self-heating divides into three stages: A (below 100 oC), B (above 100 oC) and C (above 350 oC).  The understanding is that conditions in stage A promote oxidation of sulphides to elemental sulphur which in stage B oxidizes to SO2.  A standard test based on air injections is used to measure stage A and stage B self-heating.  In this thesis, a mitigation method using hygroscopic reagents to control moisture has been tested on a pyrrhotite-rich material.  Water retention capacity was determined to select reagents for application in the standard self-heating test.  Tests showed that the water retention capacity correlated with mitigation of self-heating.  Two reagents that showed the best mitigating effect were silica gel and poly (acrylic acid sodium salt).It is hypothesized that temperature and relative humidity have an effect on elemental sulphur production in stage A.  To test, pyrrhotite (Fe1-xS) samples were exposed (weathered) at temperatures of 40 oC and 60 oC and relative humidities of 100%, 70% and 30% for 31 days.  The weathering apparatus and sulphur analysis method are described.  At the end of weathering (31 days), samples were subjected to stage B self-heating test.  Self-heating rate and total number of air injections until heating ceased were determined.  Both measurements showed that sulphur formed at 40 oC in stage A gave higher heating response than sulphur formed at 60 oC.  This observation raises two possibilities that are discussed: there are different types of sulphur formed at the two temperatures; and there is a factor other than just sulphur content that controls stage B self-heating.</description><description>L'autochauffage spontané des sulfures peut se produire sous certaines conditions d'humidité et d'oxygène.  Cela peut entraîner l'émission de gaz toxiques tel que le SO2. Si l'autochauffage n'est pas contrôlé, la combustion peut se produire spontanément.  La recherche a établi que l'autochauffage se divise en trois étapes, soit : l'étape A (en dessous de 100 oC), l'étape B (plus de 100 oC) et l'étape C (plus de 350 oC).  Nous comprenons que l'oxydation des sulfures en soufre élémentaire survient lors de l'étape A.  Le soufre élémentaire s'oxyde pour produire le SO2 dans l'étape B.  L'autochauffage lors des étapes A et B est mesuré en utilisant un test standard qui injecte l'air dans les échantillons.Dans ce mémoire, la méthode testée pour l'atténuation des sulfures autochauffantes consistait à contrôler l'humidité en utilisant des produits hygroscopiques sur des échantillons riches en pyrrhotite.  Le facteur de sélection des produits hygroscopiques utilisés lors des tests d'autochauffage était leur capacité de rétention d'eau.  Les tests ont montré qu'il y a une corrélation entre la rétention d'eau et l'atténuation d'autochauffage.  Le gel de silice et le polymère superabsorbant ont montré le meilleur effet d'atténuation.  L'hypothèse émise était que la température et l'humidité relative ont un effet sur la production de soufre élémentaire lors de l'étape A.  Pour vérifier l'hypothèse, l'échantillon de pyrrhotite (Fe1-xS) était exposé (érodée) à des températures de 40 oC et 60 oC  et à une humidité relative de 100%, 70%, 30% pendant 31 jours.  L'appareil d'érosion et la procédure d'analyse de soufre ont été décrits dans ce document.  Suite à l'étape A (31 jours), les échantillons étaient soumis lors de l'étape B à un test d'autochauffage.  Le taux d'autochauffage et le nombre total d'injections d'air avant que le chauffage cesse ont été déterminés.  Les deux mesures ont démontré que le soufre qui est formé à 40 oC lors de l'étape A a donné une réponse de chauffage plus élevée que le soufre qui est formé à 60 oC.  Cette observation permet de conclure à deux possibilités qui seront discutées : premièrement, des types de soufre différents se forment aux deux températures et deuxièmement, il y a un autre facteur d'autochauffage que la formation de soufre qui contrôle l'étape B. </description><creator>Jung, Sarah</creator><contributor>James A Finch (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</subject><title>Sulphide self-heating: moisture content and sulphur formation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g372q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712mb45j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sn88q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis explores architectural potential and experience in the theatre of Peter Brook (1925-). The importance of his thought, writings and theatrical creation in the twentieth and twenty-first centuries reaches far beyond the question of theatre. It prepares a ground for exploring the ethical and poetic dimensions of architecture. Refusing to reduce the role of theatre to making 'pictures,' Brook's theatre strives to offer us ephemeral experience in space and to engage us with the power of individual and communal imagination. What is explored and can be learned from Brook's theatre cannot be considered as a 'practical prescription' or methodology, but rather as a call to an incessant quest. It offers an entry to rethinking the role of architecture not as a finished design, but as a phenomenon that emerges through an 'event' and engages its inhabitants and their being in the world. The dissertation, seen through the lens of an architect, embarks on a journey into Brook's theatre in which it unravels crucial concepts from his discourse and theatrical experiments offering insights of great value to architects and architectural creation alike. The idea of "empty space," the relationship between visible and invisible, and the notion of 'Immediate Theatre' resonate throughout the investigation. Along the way, I study three theatrical plays: Orghast at the tombs of the Persian kings at Persepolis and Naqsh-e-Rustam (Iran, 1971); The Mahabharata at the Callet Quarry in Boulbon (France, 1985); and Eleven and Twelve at the theatre of Bouffes du Nord (Paris, 2009). The investigation reveals the unusual approach toward places of performance, the exploratory process of creation, and the audience's involvement in space/time. In the view of this thesis, Brook's theatrical creation invokes an architecture that temporalizes space and recognizes the 'present moment,' immersing its participants in a wholeness of narrative, play and place.</description><description>Cette thèse explore le potentiel offert à l'architecture par le théâtre de Peter Brook (1925-). L'importance de sa pensée, ses écrits et sa création théâtrale dans les vingtième et vingt-et-unième siècles atteint bien au-delà de la question du théâtre. Son travail nous donne un terrain fertile pour explorer les dimensions éthique et poétique de l'architecture. Refusant de réduire le rôle du théâtre à faire des images, le théâtre de Brook s'efforce de nous offrir une expérience éphémère dans l'espace et nous engage par le pouvoir de l'imagination individuelle et collective. Ce qui est exploré et qui peut être compris du théâtre de Brook ne peut pas être considéré comme une « recette » ou méthodologie, mais doit plutôt être perçu comme un appel à une quête incessante. Cette approche permet de repenser le rôle de l'architecture non pas comme une maquette, mais comme un phénomène qui émerge à travers un « événement » et engage ses habitants et leurs questions existentielles les plus fondamentales. Vu à travers de la lentille d'un architecte, la thèse examine les concepts cruciaux dans le théâtre de Brook, particulièrement les notions d'« espace vide », la relation entre le visible et l'invisible, et la notion de « théâtre immédiat ». Pour ce faire, j'étudie trois pièces de théâtre : Orghast, sur les tombes des rois de Perse de Persépolis et de Naqsh-e Rustam (Iran, 1971); Le Mahabharata, à la carrière Callet à Boulbon (France, 1985), et Onze et Douze, au théâtre de Bouffes du Nord (Paris, 2009). La recherche révèle l'approche inhabituelle vers les lieux de performance, le processus d'exploration de la création et la participation du public dans l'espace/temps. La création théâtrale de Brook apparaît comme une architecture qui induit le temps à l'espace et reconnaît le « moment présent », plongeant ses participants dans une plénitude du récit, du jeu et du lieu.</description><creator>Djavaherian, Negin</creator><contributor>Alberto Perez-Gomez (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Architecture</subject><title>Not nothingness: Peter Brook's "empty space" and its architecture</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g615g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sn88q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5999n691x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La demande croissante de terminaux sans fil multimode et multistandard alimente l'intérêt pour des convertisseurs analogique-numérique (CAN) qui soient largement reconfigurables en terme de bande passante et de résolution.  En outre, et pour des raisons d'efficacité  énergétique, l'alimentation de ces CANs  doit être modulable dans le but de maintenir une constante figure de mérite (FOM) dans tout l'espace de reconfigurabilité. Aussi, ces CANs doivent pouvoir être implémentés dans un technologie CMOS standard pour bénéficier d'un niveau d'intégration élevé de ses composants digitaux et analogiques ainsi qu'un plus faible cout de fabrication. Ceci dit, dans les technologies CMOS  nanométriques, la diminution des tensions d'alimentation et la diminution de la taille des dispositifs sont des éléments contraignant  la conception  des  CANs faible puissance. Cette thèse propose un CAN de type pipeline qui est reconfigurable sur une gamme continue de fréquences d'échantillonnage fs = 0.4 à 44 MS/s (bande passante de 0.2 à 22 MHz), pour les résolutions N = 10, 11, et 12 bits.  Fabriqué  dans une technologie digitale CMOS de 90-nm et 1.2-V, ce CAN est caractérisé par une faible consommation de puissance (FOM = 0.35 to 0.5 pJ/conversion step) sur tout son espace bande-resolution. Ainsi, ce CAN est  approprié pour de multiples standards sans fil et cellulaire allant du GSM au LTE/iMax  et 802.11g. Aussi, et en raison de son efficacité énergétique, ce CAN est attrayant pour diverses applications ce qui permet  des économies de développements ainsi qu'une rapide  mise sur le marché.Comparé à ce qui ce se fait aujourd'hui en terme d'efficacité énergétique (FOM &lt; 2 pJ/conversion step), par exemple CAN de type pipeline ou Delta-Sigma, ce CAN offre un large espace de reconfiguration bande-resolution tout en réalisant un FOM hautement concurrentiel sur tout le dit espace. Pour varier la tension  d'alimentation, la bande passante et la resolution du CAN sont reconfigurés en utilisant les méthodes dites de current-scaling  et de stage-bypass respectivement. Les techniques suivantes sont également introduites pour obtenir des performances faible puissance dans l'espace de reconfigurabilite du CAN et permettre son implémentation dans une technologie CMOS nanométrique basse tension:  1) calibration digitale de gain type background pour permettre la conception du CAN à l'aide d'amplificateurs opérationnels faible gain et faible puissance; 2) compensation pseudo-cascode pour les amplificateurs opérationnels à courants variables; 3) la conception de comparateurs dynamiques type switch-cap à faible charge d'entrée. </description><description>The growing demand for multi-mode/multi-standard wireless terminals is fuelling interest in analog-to-digital converters (ADCs) that are reconfigurable over a wide range of bandwidths and resolutions. Furthermore, for power-efficiency, these ADCs must be power-scalable (i.e., their power scales with their bandwidth and resolution), thereby maintaining a constant figure-of-merit (FOM) over their entire reconfigurability space. Such reconfigurable power-scalable ADCs must be implemented in a standard digital CMOS process, for higher integration of the analog and digital functions in a communication system and for lower fabrication costs. However, in nanometer CMOS technologies, the decreasing supply voltages and the shrinking devices with poor analog-signal-processing capabilities, complicate the design of low-power ADCs. This thesis proposes a pipelined ADC that is reconfigurable over a continuous range of sampling frequencies fs = 0.4 to 44 MS/s (bandwidths BW = 0.2 to 22 MHz), and over resolutions N = 10, 11, 12 bits. Fabricated in a 1.2-V 90-nm digital CMOS process, it achieves low power (FOM = 0.35 to 0.5 pJ/conversion step) over its full bandwidth-resolution space. Thus, this ADC is suitable for multiple wireless and cellular standards, ranging from GSM up to LTE/WiMax and 802.11g. Furthermore, owing to its power efficiency, this ADC is attractive for various applications over a wide bandwidth-resolution space, thereby saving on development costs and reducing the time-to-market. Compared to the state-of-the-art power-efficient (FOM &lt; 2 pJ/conversion step) reconfigurable pipelined or Delta-Sigma ADCs, this ADC provides a wide bandwidth-resolution reconfigurability space, while achieving a highly-competitive FOM over this entire space. For power scalability, the ADC bandwidth and resolution are reconfigured using current-scaling and stage-bypass methods, respectively. The following techniques are also introduced to achieve low-power performance for the ADC over its wide reconfigurability space, and to enable its implementation in low-voltage nanometer CMOS: 1) low-power digital background gain calibration to enable designing the ADC using low-gain/low-power opamps; 2) pseudo-cascode compensation for the low-power design of low-voltage current-scalable opamps; and 3) design of switched-capacitor dynamic comparators with low input loading.</description><creator>Taherzadeh-Sani, Mohammad</creator><contributor>Anas Hamoui (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Reconfigurable pipelined analog-to-digital converters in low -voltage nanometer CMOS</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128f60d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n691x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547w03h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La schizophrénie est un trouble mental complexe et dévastateur, considérée comme le résultat des facteurs environnementaux stressant et des troubles du système dopamine (DA). À la recherche de facteurs génétiques, les chercheurs utilisent des phénotypes intermédiaires, des différences cachées dans le fonctionnement de cerveau. La thèse suivante présente trois études examinant la transmission de DA ainsi que les phénotypes intermédiaires putatifs de la schizophrénie.Premièrement, l'effet de la dextroamphétamine (D-amp), un agoniste de DA, sur les tâches des mouvements oculaires a été étudié chez les participants sains. D-amp a réduit de la proportion des erreurs sur la tâche antisaccade mais n'a eu aucun effet sur la tâche saccade prédictive.  On peut donc conclure que les taux d'erreurs chez les antisaccades, un phénotype intermédiaire putatif, ont été réduit par agoniste dopaminergiques. Nous avons ensuite examiné l'effet d'un autre agoniste de DA, le méthylphénidate (MPH), sur les tâches oculomotrices.  Le MPH n'avait aucun effet  sur la performance de l'antisaccade. Il augmentait la proportion des saccades prédictives uniquement chez des conditions de choix d'horaire prévisibles ; ceci appuie l'hypothèse de l'effet du MPH sur les fonctions de synchronisation. Le médicament améliore également  une poursuite lisse et un phénotype intermédiaire oculomoteur putatif. Les différences entre les effets de la D-amp et le MPH sont considérées en termes de différences dans l'action des médications. Finalement, la réactivité du système DA a été évaluée avec l'aide d'une tâche de stress psychosocial chez des individus avec des risques élevés de schizophrénie et des participants sains.  La DA au repos ainsi que la libération de la DA ont été quantifié avec [11]C raclopride et la tomographie par émission de positions (TEP) en utilisant la tâche du stress d'imagerie de Montréal. Ont été également évalué la réactivité de l'axe HPA et le volume l'hippocampe.  Les individus avec des risques élevés avaient un pouvoir de fixation nettement plus faible que chez les participants sains, ce qui suggère un accroissement des niveaux de DA endogènes, cohérent avec les résultats chez les patients. Le stress induit par la libération de la DA ne différaient pas entre les groupes.  La libération de la DA a été corrélé négativement avec la libération de cortisol.  Même si le volume d'hippocampique a corrélé avec la libération de cortisol, elle n'a pas eu le même effet avec la libération de la DA. Les résultats indiquent un rôle de la DA dans les tâches des mouvements oculaires qui sont caractérisés comme étant des phénotypes intermédiaires putatifs pour la schizophrénie et suggèrent également que la dérégulation du système de la DA au repos pourrait être en soi un phénotype intermédiaire de la maladie.  </description><description>Schizophrenia is a complex and devastating mental disorder.  Genetic differences in brain function and environmental factors such as stress are thought to interact to produce the illness.  In searching for genetic factors, researchers have used endophenotypes, i.e. covert differences in brain function that manifest even in the absence of a precipitating stressor.  The present thesis presents three studies that look at dopamine (DA) transmission and putative endophenotypes for schizophrenia. In the first study, the effect of dextroamphetamine (D-amp), an indirect DA agonist, on eye movement tasks that may be endophenotypes for schizophrenia were studied in healthy controls.  As there is some indication that the effect of DA manipulations on cognitive performance depends on initial DA levels (Barch, 2004), participants were divided into those with high or low initial performance as a proxy of their baseline DA levels (Robbins &amp; Arnsten, 2009).  D-amp was found to reduce the proportion of errors on the antisaccade task for all participants; its effect on antisaccade latency depended on initial performance, increasing correct antisaccade latency in those who initially had short latencies, and decreasing it in those who initially had long latencies.  The drug had no effect on the predictive saccade task.  Thus, antisaccade error rates, a putative endophenotype were reduced by DA agonists across groups, while for antisaccade latency there was evidence of an impact of initial DA level.  In the second study, we examined the effects of another DA agonist, methylphenidate (MPH), on oculomotor tasks.  We found that MPH had no effect on antisaccade performance.  It increased the proportion of predictive saccades across all participants.  The increase in predictive saccades was seen only in conditions with predictable timing, supporting a hypothesized effect of MPH on timing functions (Ben-Pazi et al, 2006; Rubia et al, 2003).  Smooth pursuit, a putative oculomotor endophenotype, also improved with drug across all participants.  We consider the differences between the effects of D-amp and MPH effects in terms of differences in drug action and differences between studies in terms of the implementation of the tasks. In the third study, DA system reactivity was assessed with a psychosocial stress task in a population with putative differences in DA system functioning, i.e. individuals at elevated risk for schizophrenia and healthy controls.  Baseline DA and DA release were quantified with 11-C raclopride binding potential and positron emission tomography (PET) on separate days using the Montreal Imaging Stress Task and a non-stress control task.  HPA axis reactivity and hippocampal volume were also assessed.  Relatives had significantly lower binding potential than controls, suggestive of increased endogenous DA levels, consistent with findings in patients.  Stress-induced DA release did not differ between the groups.  DA release was negatively correlated with cortisol release.  Hippocampal volume did not correlate with DA release but did correlate with cortisol release.  Together, these findings indicate a role for DA in eye movement tasks that are putative endophenotypes for schizophrenia, and also suggest that DA system dysregulation at rest may itself be an endophenotype for the illness.  </description><creator>Allman, Ava-Ann</creator><contributor>Gillian O'Driscoll (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Psychology - Clinical</subject><title>Dopaminergic effects on putative endophenotypes for schizophrenia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82kb96d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547w03h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r467g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Semiparametric efficient methods in causal inference have been developed to robustly and efficiently estimate causal parameters. As in general causal estimation, the methods rely on a set of mathematical assumptions that translate into requirements of causal knowledge and confounder identification. Targeted maximum likelihood estimation (TMLE) methodology has been developed as a potential improvement on efficient estimating equations, in that it shares the qualities of double robustness (unbiasedness under partial misspecification) and semiparametric efficiency, but can be constructed to provide boundedness of parameter estimates, robustness to data sparsity, and a unique estimate.This thesis, composed primarily of three manuscripts, presents new research on the analysis of longitudinal and survival data with time-dependent confounders using TMLE. The ﬁrst manuscript describes the construction of a two time-point TMLE using a generalized exponential distribution family member as the loss function for the outcome model. It demonstrates the robustness of the continuous version of this TMLE algorithm in a simulation study, and uses a modified version of the method in a simplified analysis of the PROmotion of Breastfeeding Intervention Trial (PROBIT) where evidence for a protective causal effect of breastfeeding on gastrointestinal infection is obtained.The second manuscript presents a description of several substitution estimators for longitudinal data, a specialized implementation of a longitudinal TMLE method, and a case study using the full PROBIT dataset. The K time point sequential TMLE algorithm employed (theory previously developed), implemented nonparametrically using Super Learner, differs fundamentally from the strategy used in the first manuscript, and offers some benefits in computation and ease of implementation.  The analysis compares different durations of breastfeeding and the related exposure-specific (and censoring-free) mean counts of gastrointestinal infections over the first year of an infant's life and concludes that a protective effect is present. Simulated data mirroring the PROBIT dataset was generated, and the performance of TMLE was again assessed.The third manuscript develops a methodology to estimate marginal structural models for survival data. Utilizing the sequential longitudinal TMLE algorithm to estimate the exposure-specific survival curves for all exposure patterns, it demonstrates a way to combine inference in order to model the outcome using a linear specification. This article presents the theoretical construction of two different types of marginal structural models (modeling the log-odds survival and the hazard) and presents a simulation study demonstrating the unbiasedness of the technique. It then describes an analysis of the Canadian Co-infection Cohort study undertaken with one of the TMLE methods to ﬁt survival curves and a model for the hazard function of development of end-stage liver disease (ESLD) conditional on time and clearance of the Hepatitis C virus.</description><description>Des méthodes d'analyse causale semi-paramétriques et efficaces ont été développées pour estimer les paramètres causaux efficacement et de façon robuste. Comme c'est le cas en général pour l'estimation causale, ces méthodes se basent sur un ensemble d'hypothèses mathématiques qui impliquent que la structure causale et les facteurs de confusion doivent être connus. La méthode d'estimation par le maximum de vraisemblance ciblé (TMLE) se veut une amélioration des équations d'estimation efficaces: elle a les propriétés de double robustesse (sans biais même avec une erreur de spécification partielle) et d'efficacité semi-paramétrique, mais peut également garantir des estimés finis pour les paramètres et la production d'un seul estimé en plus d'être robuste si les données sont éparses. Cette thèse, composée essentiellement de trois manuscrits, présente de nouvelles recherches sur l'analyse avec le TMLE de données longitudinales et de données de survie avec des facteurs de confusion variant dans le temps. Le premier manuscrit décrit la construction d'un TMLE à deux points dans le temps avec une distribution de la famille exponentielle généralisée comme fonction de perte du modèle de la réponse. Il démontre à l'aide d'une étude de simulation la robustesse de la version continue de cet algorithme TMLE, et utilise une version Poisson de la méthode pour une analyse simplifiée de l'étude PROmotion of Breastfeeding Intervention Trial (PROBIT) qui donne des signes d'un effet causal protecteur de l'allaitement sur les infections gastrointestinales. Le deuxième manuscrit présente une description de plusieurs estimateurs de substitution pour données longitudinales, une implémentation spéciale de la méthode TMLE longitudinale et une étude de cas du jeu de données PROBIT entier. Un algorithme TMLE séquentiel à K points dans le temps est utilisé (théorie déjà développée), lequel est implémenté de façon non-paramétrique avec le Super Learner.  Cet algorithme diffère fondamentalement de la stratégie utilisée dans le premier manuscrit et offre des avantages en terme de calcul et de facilité d'implémentation.  L'analyse compare les moyennes de dénombrements du nombre d'infections gastrointestinales dans la première année de vie d'un nouveau-né par durée d'allaitement et avec aucune censure, et conclut à la présence d'un effet protecteur. Des données simulées semblables au jeu de données PROBIT sont également générées, et la performance du TMLE de nouveau étudiée. Le troisième manuscrit développe une méthodologie pour estimer des modèles structurels marginaux pour données de survie. En utilisant l'algorithme séquentiel du TMLE longitudinal pour estimer des courbes de survie spécifiques à l'exposition pour tous les patrons d'exposition, il montre une façon de combiner les inférences pour modéliser la réponse à l'aide d'une spécification linéaire. Cet article présente la construction théorique de deux différents types de modèles structurels marginaux (modélisant le log du rapport des chances de survie et le risque) et présente une étude de simulation démontrant l'absence de biais de la technique. Il décrit ensuite une analyse de l'Étude de la Cohorte Canadienne de Co-Infection à l'aide d'une des méthodes TMLE pour ajuster des courbes de survie et un modèle pour la fonction de risque du développement de la maladie chronique du foie (ESLD) conditionnellement au temps et à l'élimination du virus de l'hépatite C.</description><creator>Schnitzer, Mireille</creator><contributor>Robert William Platt (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Erica Moodie (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Biostatistics</subject><title>Targeted maximum likelihood estimation for longitudinal data</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02871060j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r467g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418r869</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:57:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The introduction of the Draft Bill to enact the new Code of Civil Procedure has revived the movement defending the partisan expertise and the institutional resistance against the common, single or judiciary expertise. This resistance is yet paradoxical. Firstly, the adversarial expertise has not always been practiced, but appeared in the late 19th century with the development of the judicial adversarial process and with the increase of lawyers' professional freedom. Secondly, French and English experiences show that no practical concern alleged by the partisan expertise proponents is actually insurmountable and allow considering an expertise process complying with the principle of contradiction and supporting a more cooperative view of the trial. Finally, no argument according to a formulation of civil justice as fairness can be reasonably advanced against the single expert process. On the contrary, civil justice as fairness militates for a single expert practice that meets the conditions of competence, impartiality, independence and publicity. For this reason, the real concern of lawyers and litigants should not be to defend the partisan expertise practice, but to plead in favour of a change in the practice that would respect the principle of contradiction and the conditions of civil justice as fairness.</description><description>Le dépôt de l'Avant-projet de loi instituant le nouveau Code de procédure civile a ravivé le mouvement de défense de l'expertise partisane et la résistance institutionnelle à l'encontre de l'expertise commune, unique ou judiciaire. Cette résistance est pourtant paradoxale. D'abord, l'expertise partisane n'a pas toujours été pratiquée, mais est apparue à la fin du 19e siècle avec le développement du processus judiciaire antagoniste et l'accroissement de la liberté professionnelle des plaideurs. Ensuite, les expériences étrangères de la France et de l'Angleterre démontrent qu'aucune préoccupation pratique alléguée par les défenseurs de l'expertise partisane n'est réellement insurmontable et permettent d'envisager un procédé d'expertise conforme au principe de la contradiction et soutenant une vision plus coopérative du procès. Enfin, aucun argument avancé selon une formulation de la justice civile comme équité ne peut être raisonnablement soutenu à l'encontre de l'expertise commune ou unique. Bien au contraire, la justice civile formulée comme équité milite davantage pour une pratique de l'expertise unique qui satisfait aux conditions de compétence, d'impartialité, d'indépendance et de publicité. Pour cette raison, la préoccupation véritable des juristes et des justiciables ne devrait pas être la défense de la pratique de l'expertise partisane, mais devrait être de plaider pour un changement de la pratique de l'expertise qui respecte le principe de la contradiction et les conditions de la justice formulée comme équité.</description><creator>Préville-Ratelle, Emmanuel</creator><contributor>Frederic Bachand (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>Le paradoxe de l'expertise partisane</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q516n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418r869</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):16100</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>