<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:29:35Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):37000" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591d27m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Multi-cellular organisms generate functional and morphological diversity in their cells through spatiotemporal regulation of gene expression. Gene expression is regulated through multiple mechanisms at the levels of transcription, translation, and degradation. During my PhD studies, I examined transcription factor-induced somatic-to-induced pluripotent stem cell reprogramming.  For this, I adopted two different strategies that are based on transcriptional regulation by post-translational modification and translational control by the translational repressor 4E-BP. Specifically, in the project described in Chapter III, I studied the role of sumoylation in controlling the transcriptional activity of KLF4, KLF2, and KLF5 during reprogramming and adipocyte differentiation. I also explored the role of Ubc9, the sole SUMO-conjugating enzyme, in reprogramming and adipogenesis. These results and a comprehensive review of related studies, presented in Chapter I, have helped me propose a model for the functional specificity of KLF family proteins. In the research project described in Chapter IV, I investigated the role of translational control in somatic cell reprogramming. This investigation uncovered a functional duality in 4E-BP-dependent translation during reprogramming that is controlled by the p53-p21 pathway. To introduce this chapter and to provide insights for future research, I summarize in Chapter II the current findings regarding the role of the PI3K/AKT/mTOR pathway--the main control of eIF4E-dependent translation--in regulating embryonic stem cell self-renewal and somatic-to-stem cell reprogramming. The results of this thesis may lead to a better understanding of the mechanism underlying cell type determination that has important application in regenerative medicine.</description><description>Les organismes multicellulaires génèrent la diversité fonctionnelle et morphologique de leurs cellules par une régulation spatiotemporel de l'expression de leur gène. L'expression de ces gènes est régulée par de multiples mécanismes au niveau de la transcription, de la traduction et de la dégradation. Pendant mon PhD, j'ai étudié la reprogrammation par des facteurs de transcription de cellules somatiques en cellules souches pluripotentes. Pour ce faire, j'ai adopté deux stratégies basées sur le control de la transcription par des modifications post-traductionnelles et le control de la traduction par le répresseur 4E-BP. Spécifiquement, dans le projet décrit dans le Chapitre III, j'ai étudié le rôle de la sumoylation dans l'activité transcriptionnelle de KLF4, KLF2, et KLF5 pendant la reprogrammation et la pendant la différentiation des adipocytes. J'ai aussi exploré le rôle d'Ubc9, la seule enzyme capable de conjuguer un groupe SUMO à une protéine, dans la reprogrammation et l'adipogenèse. Les résultats de cette étude et la révision d'études connexes présentés dans le Chapitre I m'ont aidé à proposer un modèle pour la spécificité fonctionnelle de la famille de protéines KLF. Dans le projet de recherche présenté au chapitre IV, j'ai étudié le rôle du contrôle de la traduction dans la reprogrammation somatique. Cette étude m'a permis de découvrir la dualité fonctionnelle de la traduction eIF4E-dépendante durant la reprogrammation cellulaire contrôlée par la voie p53/p21. Pour introduire ce chapitre et pour discuter de recherches futures possibles, j'ai résumé dans le chapitre II les connaissances actuelles concernant le rôle de la voie de signalisation PI3K/AKT/mTOR—la principale voie qui contrôle la traduction eIF4E-dépendante--dans la régulation de la reprogrammation de cellules somatiques en cellules souches et dans la régulation de l'auto-renouvellement des cellules souches embryonnaires. Les résultats de cette thèse pourraient mener à une meilleure compréhension des mécanismes responsables de la détermination cellulaire qui aura d'importantes applications dans la médecine régénérative.</description><creator>Tahmasebi, Soroush</creator><contributor>Xiang-Jiao Yang (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Transcriptional and translational control in cell fate determination</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193f01v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591d27m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75dh57j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Considering that civil aviation safety is one of the most important elements in all aviation-related activities, this thesis presents the state of compliance of aviation safety in the Russian Federation. In the former Soviet Union, the authorities made sure that the rest of the world knew that its territory was impenetrable. In the 1980s, their attack on the civilian flight KE 007 of the Korean Airlines, which lead to the crash of the aircraft and the death of innocent civilian passengers, demonstrated that when it came to guarding their territory, they showed little concern for the lives of innocent civilians. The first chapter focuses on how the Russian Federation managed the necessary transition from the Soviet-era system to a modernized aviation system with the objective of ensuring aviation safety. The second chapter presents the development of the ICAO Universal Safety Oversight Audit Programme since the 1990s and details the compliance of Russian air law with international standards and recommended practices related to aviation safety. The last chapter highlights the necessity for the European Union and Russia to have working arrangements to conduct safety assessments of foreign aircraft to ensure aviation safety. This chapter also highlights the advantages of concluding comprehensive air transport agreements between them to harmonize their aviation relations and to solve pending issues, such as improving market opportunities for both sides, compliance with Community law by including an EU Community carrier clauses in bilateral agreements with Russia, and implementation of a phase-out of trans-Siberian overflight payments.  </description><description>Considering that civil aviation safety is one of the most important elements in all aviation-related activities, this thesis presents the state of compliance of aviation safety in the Russian Federation. In the former Soviet Union, the authorities made sure that the rest of the world knew that its territory was impenetrable. In the 1980s, their attack on the civilian flight KE 007 of the Korean Airlines, which lead to the crash of the aircraft and the death of innocent civilian passengers, demonstrated that when it came to guarding their territory, they showed little concern for the lives of innocent civilians. The first chapter focuses on how the Russian Federation managed the necessary transition from the Soviet-era system to a modernized aviation system with the objective of ensuring aviation safety. The second chapter presents the development of the ICAO Universal Safety Oversight Audit Programme since the 1990s and details the compliance of Russian air law with international standards and recommended practices related to aviation safety. The last chapter highlights the necessity for the European Union and Russia to have working arrangements to conduct safety assessments of foreign aircraft to ensure aviation safety. This chapter also highlights the advantages of concluding comprehensive air transport agreements between them to harmonize their aviation relations and to solve pending issues, such as improving market opportunities for both sides, compliance with Community law by including an EU Community carrier clauses in bilateral agreements with Russia, and implementation of a phase-out of trans-Siberian overflight payments.  </description><creator>Brisson, Julie</creator><contributor>Paul Stephen Dempsey (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>Civil aviation safety in Russia: the state of compliance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p26770777.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75dh57j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67jw22p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Decision makers at every level of society, local, national and international, along with NGOs and civil society are committed to alleviating abject generational poverty.   In the context of what many refer to as the ‘feminization of poverty', my dissertation focuses on girls during their early adolescent years in order to uncover the barriers that are present and which prevent them from exiting a life of poverty.  By using participatory methodologies, in particular photovoice, we hear directly from ten girls between the ages of 10 – 14 who describe their experiences of living a life of poverty.  In my engagement with the girls what became apparent is the impact of pre-determined roles and responsibilities on girls living with poverty. Many of these are noticeably absent in capacity building, poverty and gender related literature.  Also absent in discussions related to girls living with poverty and capacity building is a spotlight on the influential role of cultural and societal norms resulting in the lower status of girls.  The impact of culture and societal norms becomes self-evident in discussions with the girls, particularly after the girls' conducted community-based interviews with their grandmothers, mothers or aunties.  Comprehensive data is often missing which includes specific barriers that emerge in a girl's life including attending school, achieving optimum health, accessing diverse economic opportunities, as well as achieving independence and empowerment.  In this study, the importance of obtaining data directly from girls living with poverty becomes evident.  For example, girls living intimately with poverty will identify barriers which may not be readily visible to researchers and decision-makers who do not share the same life experience.  Only by understanding the diverse barriers that are present in young adolescent girls' lives that prevent them from accessing capacity building opportunities like education and literacy will  decision makers be able to develop capacity building policies that will have a higher probability of being relevant, meaningful and high-impact.  And only when these capacity building policies have quality of life as key success indicators, can girls living with poverty access a higher quality of life – a clear objective for research and policies related to girls, capacity building and poverty. </description><description>Les décideurs à tous les niveaux de la société, locaux, nationaux et internationaux, de concert avec les ONG et la société civile, consacrent leurs efforts à réduire la pauvreté générationnelle abjecte. Dans un contexte que plusieurs décrivent comme la féminisation de la pauvreté, ma thèse se concentre sur des jeunes filles au début de l'adolescence, afin de découvrir quelles barrières sont présentes et les empêchent de se sortir d'une vie de pauvreté. Utilisant des méthodologies participatives, en particulier photovoice, nous entendons les récits de dix jeunes filles entre 10 et 14 ans qui décrivent leurs expériences de vie dans la pauvreté. Ce qui est ressorti de mes échanges avec ces jeunes filles est l'impact de rôles et responsabilités pré-déterminées sur les jeunes filles vivant dans la pauvreté. Plusieurs de ceux-ci brillent par leur absence dans la littérature scientifique sur le renforcement des capacités, la pauvreté et le genre. Est également absent des discussions reliées aux jeunes filles vivant dans la pauvreté et au renforcement des capacités un éclairage sur le rôle influent des normes culturelles et sociétales entraînant un statut plus bas chez les filles. L'impact des normes culturelles et sociétales devient évident au cours de discussions avec les jeunes filles, particulièrement après qu'elles aient réalisé des entrevues au sein de la communauté auprès de leurs grand-mères, mères ou tantes. Il manque souvent de données complètes incluant des barrières spécifiques qui émergent dans la vie d'une jeune fille, incluant fréquenter l'école, atteindre une santé optimale, avoir accès à des opportunités économiques diverses, atteindre l'indépendance et se prendre en main. Dans cette étude, l'importance d'obtenir des données directement de la part de jeunes filles vivant dans la pauvreté devient évidente. Par exemple, les jeunes filles vivant intimement dans un contexte de pauvreté identifieront des barrières qui ne sont pas nécessairement visibles pour des chercheurs et décideurs qui ne partagent pas la même expérience de vie. C'est seulement en comprenant les diverses barrières présentes dans la vie des jeunes filles, particulièrement au début de l'adolescence, qui les empêchent d'avoir accès à des opportunités de renforcement des capacités telles que l'éducation et l'alphabétisation que les décideurs pourront développer des politiques de renforcement des capacités qui auront une plus grande probabilité d'être pertinentes, significatives et d'avoir un grand impact. Et c'est seulement lorsque ces politiques de renforcement des capacités auront la qualité de vie comme indicateurs principaux de succès que les jeunes filles vivant dans la pauvreté auront accès à une meilleure qualité de vie - un objectif clair pour la recherche et les politiques reliées aux jeunes filles, au renforcement de capacités et à la pauvreté. </description><creator>Sajan Virgi, Zainul</creator><contributor>Claudia A Mitchell (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Social Sciences - Gender Studies</subject><title>Mozambican girls living with poverty speak out: a case of using participatory methodologies with very young adolescent girls to identify barriers to alleviating poverty</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cj533.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jw22p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8s45qd86n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Carbon nanotube–polymer nanocomposites have been the centre of intense studies for the past few years. With the superior properties of carbon nanotubes and the flexibility of polymers for different applications, extremely high expectations were set for this class of nanocomposites. Modelling studies showed significant potential, but the experimental investigations faced strict challenges to reach the predicted values. One of the main challenges is to obtain the optimum interaction between the nanotubes and the polymer matrix. The interaction influences the dispersion of nanotubes in the polymer and affects the overall properties of the nanocomposite. Therefore, the main objective of this research was to study the carbon nanotube–polymer interaction in nanocomposites. Based on a comprehensive review of the literature, molecular dynamics and atomic force microscopy were selected as the modelling and experimental techniques to study the interaction. In the modelling section, the interfacial properties of a single-walled carbon nanotube–poly(methyl methacrylate) nanocomposite were obtained through a three-phase simulation of a pull-out test. An interfacial binding energy of 0.39 kcal/molÅ2 was obtained from molecular dynamics simulation. On the other hand, in the experimental section, stepwise discretization method was proposed as a novel technique of interaction measurement using atomic force microscopy. Furthermore, a new interaction parameter, called interaction stress, was introduced to evaluate the interaction quality in nanocomposites. The stepwise discretization method was applied to a single-walled carbon nanotube–poly(methyl methacrylate) nanocomposite and a maximum interaction stress of 7 MPa was obtained. The results were, then, applied to classical contact theory and a nanoscale contact theory was developed. Furthermore, the interaction stress data were input to coarse grain simulations to obtain the interfacial properties of the nanocomposites. This new approach benefited from the flexibility of the coarse grain method and the reliability of the experimental data obtained from atomic force microscopy.  Based on the results of the coarse grain simulations, the interfacial binding energy of a single-walled carbon nanotube–poly(methyl methacrylate) nanocomposite was estimated as 0.44 kcal/molÅ2. This value was then compared with the interfacial binding energy obtained from molecular dynamics results (i.e., 0.39 kcal/molÅ2). The good agreement between the results of modelling and experimental approaches demonstrated the validity of the work and the robustness of the proposed methods and parameters.</description><description>Les nanocomposites avec des polymères renforcés de nanotubes de carbone ont été le centre d'attention de nombreuses études dans les dernières années. Les propriétés supérieures des nanotubes de carbone et la flexibilité des polymères à être utilisés dans de diverses applications ont créé de grandes attentes pour cette classe de nanocomposites. Des études de modélisation ont démontré un fort potentiel pour ces matériaux, cependant la validation expérimentale de ces propriétés prédites reste un défi. Une des principales difficultés est l'obtention d'une interaction optimale entre les nanotubes et la matrice polymère. Cette interaction influence la dispersion des nanotubes dans le polymère et affecte les propriétés globales du nanocomposite. De ce fait, l'objectif principal de ce travail de recherche a été l'étude de l'interaction entre les nanotubes de carbone et le polymère dans les nanocomposites. A partir d'une revue détaillée de la littérature, la méthode de dynamique moléculaire et la microscopie à force atomique ont été choisies comme techniques numériques et expérimentales pour étudier l'interaction. Dans la partie de modélisation, les propriétés d'interface d'un nanotube à paroi simple avec du poly(methyl methacrylate) ont été obtenues à partir d'une simulation d'un test d'arrachement en trois phases. Une énergie de liaison d'interface de 0.39 kcal/molÅ2 a été calculée par la simulation de dynamique moléculaire. Dans la section expérimentale, une méthode de discrétisation par étapes a été proposée en tant que nouvelle technique de mesure de l'interaction par microscopie à force atomique. De plus, un nouvel paramètre d'interaction, appelé contrainte d'interaction, a été introduit pour évaluer la qualité de l'interaction dans les nanocomposites. La méthode de discrétisation par étapes a été utilisée pour le nanocomposite de poly(methyl methacrylate) avec un nanotube de carbone à paroi simple, et une interaction maximale de contrainte de 7 MPa a été obtenue. Les résultats ont été ensuite utilisés pour la théorie classique de contact et une théorie de contact à l'échelle nano. Les données sur les interactions de contraintes ont été aussi utilisées comme entrées pour des simulations de dynamique moléculaire «gros grains» afin d'obtenir les propriétés d'interface des nanocomposites. Cette nouvelle approche bénéficie de la flexibilité de la méthode de dynamique moléculaire «gros grains» et de la fiabilité des données expérimentales obtenues par la microscopie à force atomique.  À partir des résultats de la méthode de dynamique moléculaire «gros grains», l'énergie de liaison d'interface d'un nanocomposite de nanotube de carbone–poly(methyl methacrylate) a été estimée à 0.44 kcal/molÅ2. Cette valeur a été comparée à l'énergie de liaison d'interface obtenue par la méthode de dynamique moléculaire (i.e., 0.39 kcal/molÅ2). La bonne corrélation entre les résultats basés sur des approches numériques et expérimentales démontre la validité de cette étude ainsi que la robustesse des méthodes proposées et des paramètres développés.</description><creator>Rahmat, Meysam</creator><contributor>Pascal Hubert (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical </subject><title>Carbon nanotube - polymer interaction in nanocomposites</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732df077.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qd86n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dx58z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>High-elevation Andean water storage is extremely important for water resources for the arid western coast of South America. Pampas (a subset of pàramos) are a freshwater reservoir in the Cordillera Blanca, Peru. These organic-rich clay systems buffer stream and river runoff to the Rio Santa and provide water to surrounding communities. More than 50% of dry season discharge from pampas is groundwater derived, however little is known about their geomorphology and subsurface sedimentology. Watertable measurements, streambed temperature sensors, and ground penetrating radar (GPR) were used to characterize the subsurface and develop a formational model for the Yanamarey and Quilcayhuanca pampas, Cordillera Blanca, Peru.  The water table in July 2009 was found on average to be 0.35 m and 0.57 m below the land surface at Quilcayhuanca and Yanamarey respectively. In the Yanamarey Pampa, streambed temperature sensors showed that upstream, water flows from the stream into the ground and further downstream, water flows upwards recharging the stream. From watertable measurements, a watertable map was produced that showed steeper watertable gradients further up valley. GPR was an effective tool for imaging the subsurface to a depth of 8 meters in the high permittivity material and delineated four stratigraphic units at both sites. In sequence the units are; dry sandy peat soils with pebbles at the surface, water saturated soil with sand and pebbles, linear stratified clay and glacial outwash intermixed with colluviums deposits. The identification of the subsurface sedimentary units allowed for the creation of formation models of both sites. The valley walls of Quilcayhuanca are steeper than Yanamarey, which caused more landslides and consequently more extensive colluvial deposits throughout the Quilcayhuanca valley subsurface. These connected colluvial deposits are likely the primary zone for groundwater flow and storage. </description><description>Les réservoirs hydrologiques des hautes Andes constituent une partie importantee des ressources d'eau de la région aride de la côte ouest de l'Amérique du Sud. Les Pampas, un sous ensemble des pàramos, représentent un des réservoirs d'eau fraîche de la Cordillère Blanche du Pérou. Ces systèmes riches en argile et en matière organique modulent le ruissellement des rivières et des cours d'eau, et offrent de l'eau fraîche aux communautés voisines. Plus de 50 % du volume d'eau provenant des Pampas durant la saison sèche sont d'origine souterraine, cependant peu d'études se sont penchées sur la géomorphologie et la sédimentologie de ces systèmes. Des relevés du niveau de la nappe, des mesures de température dans le lit de la rivière, et des profils obtenus a l'aide de radars a pénétration du sol (RPS) ont été utilisés pour décrire le sous-sol et développer un modèle pour expliquer le fonctionnement des pampas de Yanamarey et de Quilcayhuancas de la Cordillère Blanche.Le niveau de la nappe se situe en moyenne a 0,35 m et 0,57m de profondeur à Quilcayhuanca et Yanamarey respectivement. Dans le Pampa du Yanamarey, les capteurs de température du lit du cours d'eau mettent en évidence un flux d'eau positif de la rivière vers le sol dans la partie supérieure des pampas, ce flux s'inversant dans sa partie inferieure. La carte du niveau de la nappe, réalisées a partir des mesures effectuées sur le terrain, montrent que les gradients du niveau d'eau sont plus forts en amont du système . L'outil RPS c'est montré utile pour produire des images du soul-sol jusqu'à une profondeur de huit mètres dans le matériau à haute permittivité, distinguant quatre unités stratigraphiques. Du sol aux profondeurs nous trouvons: de la tourbe sèche avec des galets superficiels; du sol saturé en eau avec du sable et des galets; de l'argile stratifiée linéairement et finalement divers dépôts glaciaires et paraglaciaires. L'identification de la géologie souterraine a permis la création du modèle pour chacun des deux sites. Les flancs de la vallée de Quilcayhunca sont plus pentus que ceux du Yanamarey, ce qui induit plus de glissement de terrain et par conséquence, plus de dépôts paraglaciaires dans le sous-sol de la vallée du Quilcayhunca. Ces dépôts et leurs interconnections forment vraisemblablement le passage privilégié de l'eau souterraine et forment possiblement les zones de stockage primaires de ces systèmes.</description><creator>Maharaj, Laura</creator><contributor>Jeffrey McKenzie (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Geology</subject><title>Investigating proglacial groundwater systems in the Quilcayhuanca and Yanamarey Pampas, Cordillera Blanca, Peru</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kf86j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dx58z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7m01bq647</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Il est essentiel, chez les expériences modernes de physique des hautes énergies, de pouvoir comparer les résultats obtenus des cacluls Monte Carlo aux résultats provenant de données expérimentales. Le facteur d'échelle de l'efficacité du «b-tagging» (FE) permet de faire une comparaison légitime entre l'identification des b quarks dans des échantillons de données et des échantillons de Monte Carlo. Cette thèse présente une mesure simultanée du FE (pour l'algorithme SecVtx) et de la section efficace de la production de ttbarre, utilisant 5.6 fb^{-1} de données de collision ppbarre à √s = 1.96 TeV. Ces données furent accumulées par l'expérience «Collider Detector at Fermilab» (CDF).  La section efficace de la production de ttbarre fut établie à 7.26±0.47 pb, une valeur en accord avec les mesures antécédentes du collaboration CDF. La valeur du FE serré fut établie à 0.925±0.032 et 0.967±0.033 pour celle du SF lâche.  Celles-ci représentent, à date, par rapport à la précision, les meilleures mesures du FE de SecVtx faites à l'expérience CDF. </description><description>The ability to compare results between Monte Carlo and data is imperative in modern experimental high-energy physics analyses. The b-tagging efficiency Scale Factor (SF) allows for an accurate comparison of b quark identification in data samples and Monte Carlo. This thesis presents a simultaneous measurement of the SF for the SecVtx algorithm and the t t production cross section using 5.6 fb⁻¹ of pp̄ collision data at √s = 1.96 TeV collected by the Collider Detector at Fermilab (CDF) experiment. The t t cross section was measured to be 7.26±0.47 pb, consistent with prior CDF analyses. The tight SF value was measured to be 0.925±0.032 and the loose SF value was measured at 0.967±0.033. These are the most precise SF SecVtx measurements to be performed at CDF to date.</description><creator>Hussain, Nazim</creator><contributor>Andreas Warburton (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Physics - Elementary Particles and High Energy</subject><title>A simultaneous measurement of the b-tagging efficiency scale factor and the top-antitop production cross section at the Collider Detector at Fermilab</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440x80q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bq647</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059cc53w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Depuis l'Enquête de Nutrition Canada (1973), la littérature suggère que les Autochtones ont de faibles apports en vitamine D et détournent de la consommation d'aliments traditionnels. De plus, d'autres facteurs de risque comme l'âge, un indice de masse corporelle (IMC) élevé, l'ethnicité et la latitude prédisposent les populations autochtones à un faible statut en vitamine D. En outre, des études antérieures suggèrent que les enfants autochtones constituent un groupe à risque plus élevé pour une faible masse osseuse par rapport aux autres enfants Canadiens en fonction de la vitamine D. Ainsi, les objectifs de cette thèse ont été de (i) de déterminer la prévalence de la déficience, l'insuffisance et la concentration optimale en vitamine D chez les adultes et les enfants d'âge préscolaire Inuits; (ii) identifier les contributeurs à l'apport en vitamine D, y compris les aliments du marché et  les aliments traditionnels chez les adultes et les enfants d'âge préscolaire inuits et comparer l'apport habituelle en vitamine D á l'apport adéquat des adultes et des enfants d'âge préscolaire Inuits; (iii) identifier les facteurs prédictifs d'un statut optimal de la vitamine D chez les adultes et les enfants d'âge préscolaire Inuits ; et (iv) identifier les facteurs prédictifs associés à la densité osseuse des enfants d'âge préscolaire Inuits . Les données de cette étude ont été obtenues du 2007-2008 IHS, qui comprenait 2599 adultes (≥ 18 ans) et du CIHS, qui comprenait 388 enfants d'âge préscolaire (3 à 5 ans) sélectionnés aléatoirement. Pour l'objectif (i), le 25 (OH) D plasmatique ou sérique a été mesurée par la technologie Chemiluminesente (DiaSorin, de liaison). Pour l'objectif (ii), les apports habituels des adultes ont été estimés en utilisant l'information sur la variabilité intra-personne obtenue à partir d'une étude précédente, d'autre part, l'apport en vitamine D des enfants d'âge préscolaire a été ajustée pour un deuxième rappel de 24 h et une estimation de la dose de vitamine D ajusté a été calculé suivant les directives de l'Institut de médecine. Pour l'objectif (iii) et (iv), la régression logistique a été utilisée. En outre, pour objectif (iv), la densité minérale osseuse au niveau du talon a été estimée en utilisant le sonomètre d'ultrasons Sahara. Les résultats ont montré que le statut en  vitamine D chez les enfants d'âge préscolaire et les adultes Inuits était faible à la fin de l'été. Avec la diminution de la consommation d'aliments traditionnels, 14.1-64.7% des adultes et 61.4 des enfants d'âge préscolaire avaient des apports égaux ou supérieurs à l'apport adéquat  pour la vitamine D. Chez les adultes, les aliments traditionnels ont été le principal contributeur à l'apport en vitamine D, alors que chez les enfants d'âge préscolaire, l'apport en aliments traditionnels était trop faible pour établir des liens avec le statut en vitamine D. Toutefois le lait a été le principal contributeur à la vitamine D dans ce groupe d'âge. Les meilleurs prédicateurs d'un statut optimal en vitamine D chez les adultes inuits étaient l'âge et un tour de taille sain, tandis que pour les enfants d'âge préscolaire, l'apport en vitamine D au dessus de l'apport adéquat et le jeune âge étaient les meilleurs prédicateurs. Enfin, les meilleurs prédicateurs de la densité minérale osseuse plus élevée étaient un apport en calcium au dessus de l'apport adéquat, une latitude moins élevée et un IMC plus élevé. Il s'agit de la première évaluation du statut de la vitamine D de la population Inuite depuis 30 ans et de la densité minérale osseuse des enfants d'âge préscolaire. En conclusion, cette étude a identifié une prévalence élevée de faible statut en vitamine D chez les Inuits d'âge préscolaire et les jeunes adultes. Puisque les aliments traditionnels étaient positivement associés au statut de la vitamine D, une enquête plus approfondie, à travers les différentes saisons, devrait confirmer si ces observations sont cohérentes toute l'année.</description><description>Evidence since the Nutrition Canada Survey (1973) suggests that Aboriginal people have low intakes of vitamin D and are shifting away from the consumption of traditional foods (TF). Further risk factors including higher body mass index (BMI), ethnicity, and latitude status predispose Aboriginal populations to low vitamin D status. In addition, previous studies suggest that Aboriginal children, as a group, are at a higher risk for low bone mass compared to other Canadian infants as a function of vitamin D. Thus, the objectives of this thesis were to: (i) determine the prevalence of vitamin D deficiency, insufficiency and optimal concentrations in Inuit adults and preschoolers; (ii) identify contributors to vitamin D intake, including market foods (MF) and TF among Inuit adults and preschoolers and compare usual vitamin D intakes to the recommended adequate intake (AI) in Inuit adults and preschoolers; (iii) identify predictors of an optimal vitamin D status in Inuit adults and preschoolers; and (iv) identify predictors associated with a higher bone mineral density (BMD) in Inuit preschoolers. Data for this study were obtained from the 2007-2008 Inuit Health Survey (IHS), which included 2599 adults (≥ 18 years (y)) and from the Child Inuit Health Survey (CIHS), which included 388 preschoolers (3 to 5 y) who were randomly selected. For objective (i), plasma or serum 25-hydroxy vitamin D (25(OH)D) was measured by Chemiluminesent technology (DiaSorin, Liaison). For objective (ii), usual intakes of adults were estimated by using information on within person variability obtained from a previous study. Vitamin D intake of preschoolers was adjusted using  a second 24 hour dietary recall (24 h recall) and an estimation of the adjusted vitamin D intake was calculated following the guidelines by the Institute of Medicine. For objective (iii) and (iv), logistic regression was used. Also, for objective (iv), heel BMD was estimated using ultrasound Sahara Sonometer. Results showed that vitamin D status of Inuit preschoolers and adults was low at the end of summer. With the decreasing consumption of TF, 14.1-64.7% of adults and 61.4 of preschoolers met or exceeded the AI for vitamin D. In adults, TF was the major contributor to vitamin D intake, whereas in preschoolers, TF intake was too low to establish links to vitamin D status. However milk was the major contributor to vitamin D intake in this age group. The strongest predictors of an optimal vitamin D status among Inuit adults were older age and healthy waist circumference, while for preschoolers, vitamin D intake above the AI and younger age were the strongest predictors. Finally, the strongest predictors of BMD were higher BMI and MUFA intake plus lower latitude. This is the first assessment of vitamin D status of the Inuit population in 30 y and the first assessment of BMD in Inuit preschoolers. In conclusion, this research has identified a high prevalence of low vitamin D status in Inuit preschoolers and young adults. Since TF was positively associated with vitamin D status, further investigation across different seasons would confirm if these observations are consistent year-round.</description><creator>El Hayek, Jessy</creator><contributor>Hope Weiler (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Grace Egeland Hovda (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Health Sciences - Nutrition</subject><title>Correlates of vitamin D status in Inuit preschoolers and adults and correlates of bone mineral density in Inuit preschoolers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cv828.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059cc53w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j333650w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>RÉSUMÉTRPM7 (transient receptor potential melastatin), membre de la large famille des canaux ioniques des TRP, est exprimée de façon omniprésente dans toutes les cellules, et est active de façon constitutive. TRPM7 est composée de six domaines transmembranaires qui s'assemblent en tétramères pour former un pore central, perméable aux ions Mg2+ et Ca2+. TRPM7, et son homologue TRPM6, sont les seuls canaux ioniques connus pour le transport du Mg2+. L'hypertension, une maladie cardiovasculaire associée à de faibles niveaux en Mg2+ intracellulaire est aussi liée à de niveaux élevés d'aldosterone. Des recherches antérieures ont démontré que l'aldosterone augmente les niveaux d'ARNm de TRPM7 tandis que la quantité de protéines diminue dans les cellules vasculaires lisses du muscle. Afin de comprendre si TRPM7 peut être impliquée dans l'hypertension, nous nous sommes demandés si l'aldosterone pouvait réguler les courants associés à TRPM7, et si nous pouvions définir un mécanisme d'action qui pourrait expliquer une telle régulation. La technique du patch clamp a été utilisée sur des cellules HEK-293 inductibles exprimant de façon stable le phénotype humain de TRPM7.  Nous avons trouvé que les courants de TRPM7 sont augmentés après une stimulation de nuit avec de l'aldosterone, comparé à des cellules non stimulées. Lorsque le récepteur humain mineralocorticoid (hMR) est transfecté deux jours avant la stimulation par l'aldosterone, la réponse en courant est rehaussée. L'ajout de 10mM de BAPTA, un chélateur du Ca2+, dans la solution intracellulaire permet de doubler la réponse en courant dans ces cellules, ainsi que d'augmenter la réponse à l'aldosterone dans les cellules transfectées avec le récepteur hMR. Etonnamment, les niveaux de protéines de TRPM7 ne sont pas affectés, suggérant une redistribution des canaux ioniques déjà existants à la membrane. SGK-1, une kinase membre de la famille des serine-threonines a été proposée comme un possible médiateur de la réponse a l'aldosterone. En effet, après l'application d'un bloquer spécifique pour le SGK-1, une diminution des courants ainsi que de la quantité de protéines associées à TRPM7 a été observée. De façon générale, ces résultats démontrent que l'aldosterone est capable de réguler TRPM7 à travers une augmentation des courants. Cette réponse, qui semble être sous l'influence de SGK-1, utilise un mécanisme sensible aux niveaux de calcium intracellulaire.. </description><description>ABSTRACTTRPM7 (transient receptor potential melastatin), a member of the large TRP ion channel family, is ubiquitously expressed in cells and is constitutively active. It is comprised of six transmembrane domains that assemble into tetramers to form a central Mg2+ and Ca2+ permeable pore. TRPM7 and its homologue TRPM6 are some of the only channels known to carry Mg2+. Hypertension, a cardiovascular condition linked to low levels of intracellular Mg2+ is also associated with high levels of aldosterone. Previous results have demonstrated that aldosterone increases mRNA levels of TRPM7 whereas protein levels decreased in VSMCs. To understand if TRPM7 may be implicated in hypertension, we questioned whether aldosterone could regulate TRPM7 currents, and inquired for a possible underlying mechanism. Whole-cell patch clamp studies were conducted in inducible HEK-293 cells, stably expressing wild type TRPM7. We found that TRPM7 currents are enhanced after overnight stimulation with aldosterone compared to non-stimulated cells. When the mineralocorticoid receptor (hMR) is transfected two days prior aldosterone stimulation, this response is further increased. The introduction of 10mM BAPTA, a Ca2+ chelator, to the intracellular medium doubled the TRPM7 current in WT cells and also increased the response to aldosterone in cells transfected with the hMR receptor. Surprisingly, protein levels of TRPM7 do not vary, suggesting a redistribution of already existing channels to the membrane. SGK-1, a serine threonine kinase was suggested as a possible mediator of the response. In fact, when a specific blocker to SGK-1 is applied onto the cells, both current and total protein levels of TRPM7 are significantly decreased. Overall, these results demonstrate that aldosterone can regulate TRPM7 through an increase in total current. This response appears to be mediated by SGK-1 in a calcium sensitive manner. </description><creator>Miquel, Perrine</creator><contributor>Alvin Shrier (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Physiology</subject><title>Regulation of TRPM7 by Aldosterone</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vg62k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j333650w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xs55mh148</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tout d'abord, le rôle des équations de contraintes d'Einstein en physique est présenté. Ces équations font partie de la formulation du problème de Cauchy de la relativité générale, et doivent être satisfaites par la métrique, ainsi que par la courbure extrinsèque moyenne d'une surface de Cauchy. Déterminer la propagation de ces champs tensoriels par les équations d'évolution équivaut à la résolution de l'équation de champ d'Einstein. Les équations de contraintes d'Einstein consistent en un système de deux EDP couplées non-linéaires de deuxième ordre. Le travail d'Y. Choquet-Bruhat démontrant que le problème est bien posé, est résumé. S'ensuivent quelques brefs commentaires concernants les solutions globales. La méthode conforme est exposée. L'utilisation de cette technique combinée à la décomposition de York tranforme les équations de contrainte en une équation semi-linéaire elliptique et un système linéaire elliptique, ayant pour inconnues le facteur conforme et un champ vectoriel.L'essentiel de la présente thèse se concentre sur les questions d'existence et d'unicité des solutions des équations de contraintes d'Einstein sur les variétés compactes tridimensionelles sans frontière. À cet effet, la classification de Yamabe est un outil important. Une revue de la littérature est alors détaillée dans les cas où la courbure moyenne, qui est une donnée prescrite, est constante, ou 'proche-de-constante'. Puis vient une présentation qualitative d'articles récents traitant du cas où la courbure moyenne est 'loin-de-constante'. On s'attarde ensuite sur un cas spécifique étudié par D.Maxwell, dans lequel une famille de trois paramètres est utilisée pour passer d'un régime à l'autre sur une variété Yamabe-nulle. Une approche similaire est ensuite utilisée pour obtenir des résultats d'existence et d'unicité explicites sur une variété Yamabe-positive.  </description><description>The relevance of the Einstein constraint equations in physics is first presented. They arise in the initial-value formulation of general relativity, and must be satisfied by the metric and the extrinsic curvature of a Cauchy surface. Propagating the resulting tensor fields with the evolution equations is then equivalent to solving Einstein's field equation. The constraint equations consist of a system of two coupled nonlinear second-order PDEs. Well-posedness of the system is addressed, following the work of Y. Choquet-Bruhat. Some brief comments about global solutions are made.The conformal method is introduced. Using this approach, along with York splitting, the constraint equations now consist of a semilinear elliptic equation and a linear elliptic system that have to be solved for the conformal factor and a vector field.The main part of the thesis addresses the questions of existence and uniqueness of solutions to the Einstein constraint equations on three-dimensional compact Cauchy surfaces without boundary. The Yamabe classification turns out to be a key tool, and is presented. Then follows a thorough literature review of the results in the cases where the mean curvature, which is part of the prescribed data, is constant or near-constant. Recent articles on the case where the mean curvature is far-from-constant are discussed qualitatively. We then turn to a specific toy-model investigated by D.Maxwell where a family of three-parameters is used to consider different regimes on a Yamabe-null manifold. A similar approach is then used to explicitly work out some existence and uniqueness results on a Yamabe-positive manifold. </description><creator>Tcheng, Alexandra</creator><contributor>Gantumur Tsogtgerel (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics </subject><title>The Einstein constraint equations on compact 3-dimensional manifolds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182q35n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mh148</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cf95jg40h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ces dernières années, l'imagerie par micro-ondes est devenue un candidat possible pour la détection précoce du cancer du sein. En raison de la teneur en eau différentes, il existe un contraste diélectrique entre les tissus mammaires malins et ceux en bonne santé à des fréquences micro-ondes. En outre, les tumeurs du sein sont généralement relativement proches de la surface de la peau, permettant aux micro-ondes de faible puissance de pénétrer à travers les tissus avec une perte qui est suffisamment faible, afin de permettre une approche de détection de type radar. Bien que cette modalité d'imagerie est relativement nouvelle, et quelques prototypes ont été signalés, peux de publications envisages leur sécurité.Ce travail étudie l'exposition d'un sein à une source émettant des micro-ondes à une grande distance, fonctionnant de 0,434 à 9 GHz pour évaluer la sécurité d'un système d'imagerie radar de base. Les champs électromagnétiques dans un modèle 3-D numérique réaliste du sein, dérivés par résonances magnétiques (IRM), ont été calculés en utilisant la méthode des différences finies dans le domaine temporel (FDTD) avec l'aide de SEMCAD-X (Schmid &amp; Partner Engineering AG), un solveur FDTD 3-D. Il a été utilisé pour modeler le débit d'absorption spécifique résultant d'un tissu mammaire exposé à une onde plane. Les résultats expérimentaux sont présentés et discutés afin de déterminer s'ils sont conformes aux limites d'exposition de la Santé du Canada Code de sécurité 6.</description><description>In recent years, microwave imaging has become a possible candidate for the early detection of breast cancer. Due to the different water content, there exists a dielectric contrast between malignant and healthy breast tissue at microwave frequencies. In addition, breast tumours appear relatively close to the skin surface, allowing low-power microwaves to penetrate through the tissue with a loss that is acceptably low to permit for a radar-like detection approach. While this imaging modality is relatively new, and a few prototypes have been reported, not many publications consider its safety.  This work studies the exposure of a breast in the far field of radiofrequency sources operating in the 0.434-9-GHz range to assess the safety of a basic radar microwave imaging system. The electromagnetic fields inside a realistic MRI-derived 3-D numerical breast model has been computed using the finite-difference time-domain (FDTD) method with the help of SEMCAD-X (Schmid &amp; Partner Engineering AG), a 3-D FDTD solver. It was used to model the resulting Specific Absorption Rate (SAR) of the breast tissue exposed to a plane wave. Experimental results are presented and discussed to determine whether they comply with exposure limits from Health's Canada Safety Code 6.</description><creator>Vander Schueren, Michael</creator><contributor>Milica Popovich (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Safety assessment of microwave radar breast imaging in the 0.434-9 GHz range</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732df08h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jg40h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74cv83j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ecological forecasts under climate change are essential to inform biodiversity conservation plans but their non-falsifiable nature requires a thorough evaluation of their framework. Most ecological forecasts under climate change use ecological niche models that correlate environmental variables with the presence or regional density of a species, assuming that the current environmental niche occupied by a species can be used to anticipate its response to environmental change. Despite the large number of ecological forecasts under climate change that have been recently published, most of them are limited to predicting presence using climate variables as predictors. Here I evaluate the importance of incorporating non-climate predictors of regional density in ecological niche models. Given the greater spatial heterogeneity in regional density data compared to presence data, I used geographically weighted regression (GWR), an ecological niche model providing a spatially-explicit description of the influence of ecological predictors. I focused on North American beaver (Castor canadensis) regional density in Québec, Canada, and on human (Homo sapiens) populations in the United States and across the world because of the availability of accurate data on regional density patterns as well as potential non-climatic correlates of regional density. The influence of non-climate predictors of beaver regional density was very important in six commonly used ecological niche models. GWR models of beaver regional density performed as well as the other six ecological models used and the spatial representations of the influence of ecological predictors obtained with GWR models were broadly congruent with current ecological knowledge of beavers. Approximately half the variation in human regional density across the world was explained by GWR models based on climate conditions. Combining these GWR models with forecasted climate change models and forecasted demographic change models led to the first spatially-explicit, global human vulnerability index to climate change. There was a significant negative correlation between the predicted vulnerability to climate change and the per-capita CO2 emissions, suggesting a moral hazard in international climate change policies. The demographic trends in the United States during the 20th century were more strongly correlated with climate variables than socio-economical variables. Additionally, the regional demographic trends were such that the average climate conditions experienced by American citizen became hotter and drier throughout the century. The demographically driven temperature change was six times greater than the natural temperature change. Non-stationary ecological niche models of regional density represent a useful tool in the development of climate change forecasts and adaptation policy for biodiversity in general and human societies in particular.</description><description>Les prédictions écologiques dans un contexte de changements climatiques sont essentielles pour l'élaboration de plans de gestion de la biodiversité. Par contre, il est important de s'assurer qu'elles sont conçues de manière appropriée puisqu'elles sont scientifiquement infalsifiables. La majorité de ces prédictions utilise des modèles de niche écologique basés sur des corrélations entre la présence ou la densité régionale d'une espèce et des variables environnementales,  en supposant que la niche écologique actuelle d'une espèce peut nous permettre d'anticiper sa réaction face à des conditions environnementales différentes. Malgré le nombre important d'études sur le sujet, la plupart d'entre elles se limite à prédire la distribution d'une espèce en fonction de variables climatiques. J'évalue dans cette thèse l'importance de variables non-climatiques dans les modèles de niche écologique de densité régionale. Compte tenu que la densité régionale d'une espèce a une plus grande hétérogénéité spatiale que sa simple présence, j'ai utilisé des régressions pondérées géographiquement (RPG). Ces RPGs sont des modèles de niche écologique qui permettent de visualiser spatialement l'influence des variables utilisées pour modéliser la niche écologique d'une espèce. Mes analyses sont basées sur le castor (Castor canadensis) au Québec et sur les populations humaines (Homo sapiens) aux États-Unis et sur la planète parce que nous avons des données précises tant sur leur densité régionale que sur les facteurs environnementaux qui peuvent influencer leur densité régionale. Les densités régionales du castor étaient fortement influencées par des facteurs non-climatiques selon six modèles de niche écologique fréquemment utilisés. Les RPGs ont été aussi performant que ces six modèles de niche écologique et la représentation spatiale de l'influence des variables utilisées pour décrire la niche écologique du castor est en accord avec nos connaissances écologiques actuelles. Des RPGs basées sur quelques variables climatiques m'ont permis d'expliquer environ la moitié de la variation des densités régionales humaines sur la planète. J'ai créé le premier indice global et quantitatif des vulnérabilités humaines aux changements climatiques en combinant ces RPGs avec des prévisions démographiques des Nations-Unies. Les vulnérabilités prédites par mes modèles sont significativement négativement corrélées avec les émissions de CO2 per-capita; ce qui suggère un risque subjectif inhérent dans les négations internationales sur les changements climatiques. Les tendances démographiques aux États-Unis durant le 20ième siècle étaient plus fortement corrélées avec des variables climatiques qu'avec des variables socio-économiques. De plus, les tendances démographiques régionales ont fait que la température ressentie par les américains a augmenter au cours du dernier siècle. Ces changements de températures ressentie causés par les tendances démographiques régionales sont six fois plus important que les changements de températures d'origine naturelle. Les modèles de niche écologique spatialement non-stationnaire de densité régionale représente un outil important dans le développement de prédictions écologiques dans un contexte de changements climatiques et peuvent contribuer à l'amélioration des politiques d'adaptations aux changements climatiques tant pour la biodiversité que pour les sociétés humaines.</description><creator>Samson, Jason</creator><contributor>Dominique Berteaux (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Murray Mitchell Humphries (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Ecology</subject><title>Forecasting the impacts of climate change with non-stationary models of regional population density</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j3336515.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cv83j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547w56j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La contamination par hydrocarbures pétroliers a touché les sols arctiques ; Puccinellia angustata se développe dans ces habitats. L'élimination de l'hydrocarbure pendant les traitements de phytoremédiation dépend fortement des activités cataboliques des microorganismes associés à la racine. Cette recherche a comparé les microorganismes rhizosphériques de P. angustata établis dans les sols arctiques à différents niveaux de contamination par hydrocarbures pétroliers pour déterminer si cette espèce de plante a du potentiel pour la phytoremédiation. L'abondance, la diversité, et l'activité des communautés bactériennes du sol ont été examinées au moyen de comptages sur plaque et microscopiques, isolement de souches, empreinte digitale par DGGE du gène 16S rRNA, détection fonctionnelle du gène par PCR, essais de minéralisation des hydrocarbures en microcosme et quantification de TPH. Cette étude a été divisée en trois étapes expérimentales. Dans la première étape, une comparaison d'échantillons globales et d'échantillons plantés de cinq espèces végétales différentes a montré que P. angustata avait une plus grande accumulation de bactéries de dégradation de l'hydrocarbure que les échantillons plantés avec d'autres espèces végétales. Dans la deuxième étape, une comparaison entre la rhizosphère de P. angustata et des échantillons globales pris des sols arctiques pures (Pr), des sols arctiques contaminés par hydrocarbures et non-bio-réhabilités (NBr) et des sols arctiques contaminés par hydrocarbures et bio-réhabilités (Br), a révélé que la présence de P. angustata a augmenté l'abondance et l'activité des microorganismes de dégradation d'hydrocarbures dans deux sols (Pr et NBr), mais pas dans le Br, parce que ce sol avait reçu des fertilisations comme processus de bioremédiation. Dans la troisième étape, au moyen d‘essais en chambres de croissance où les conditions d'été du Haut-Arctique étaient simulées, P. angustata (avec et sans fertilisation par hydrogène) a été évaluée pour la phytoremédiation d'un sol contaminé artificiellement avec du diesel (10,000 mg Kg-1). Puccinellia a montré tolérance à la contamination par diesel et a augmenté les bactéries de dégradation d'hydrocarbures, en améliorant ainsi beaucoup l'élimination des TPH. Aussi, la rhizosphère de P. angustata avait une haute diversité bactérienne, contenant des membres de phylums Actinobacteria, Bacteroidetes, Firmicutes, Gemmatimonadetes et Proteobacteria. Ces conclusions indiquent que P. angustata stimule la microflore du sol qui est responsable de la biodégradation des hydrocarbures et, pourtant, pourrait aider la phytoremédiation des sols arctiques contaminés.Abréviations : PCR (Réactions en chaîne par polymérase), DGGE (Électrophorèse sur gel à gradient dénaturant),TPH (hydrocarbures pétroliers totaux)</description><description>Petroleum hydrocarbon contamination has reached Arctic soils, Puccinellia angustata thrives in such habitats. Hydrocarbon removal during phytoremediation treatments strongly depends on the catabolic activities of root associated microorganisms. This research compared the rhizospheric microorganisms from P. angustata established at Arctic soils under different degrees of contamination with petroleum hydrocarbons to determine if this plant species has phytoremediation potential. The abundance, diversity, and activity of soil bacterial communities were investigated by means of plate and microscopic counts, strains isolation, 16S rRNA gene DGGE fingerprinting, functional gene PCR detection, microcosm hydrocarbon mineralization assays, and TPH quantification. This study was divided in three experimental stages. In the first stage a comparison of samples vegetated by five different plant species as well as four bulk samples, showed that P. angustata had greater enrichment of hydrocarbon-degrading bacteria than samples vegetated by other plant species. In the second stage, a comparison between the rhizosphere of P. angustata and bulk samples collected at pristine (Pr), hydrocarbon-contaminated but non-bioremediated (NBr) and hydrocarbon-contaminated and bioremediated (Br) Arctic soils, revealed that the presence of P. angustata enhanced the abundance and the activity of hydrocarbon-degrading microorganisms in two soils (Pr and NBr) but not at Br since this soil was subjected to fertilizations as bioremediation process. In the third stage, via  growth chamber experiments, in which high Arctic summer conditions were simulated, P. angustata (with and without nitrogen fertilization) was assessed for phytoremediation of a soil artificially contaminated with diesel (10,000 mg Kg-1). Puccinellia showed tolerance to fresh diesel contamination and enhanced hydrocarbon-degrading bacteria that significantly increased the TPH removal. Also, the rhizosphere of P. angusatata had high bacterial diversity, encompassing members from Actinobacteria, Bacteroidetes, Firmicutes, Gemmatimonadetes and Proteobacteria phyla. These findings indicate that P. angustata stimulates soil microflora responsible for biodegradation of hydrocarbons therefore it has potential for phytoremediating contaminated Arctic soils.Abbreviation: PCR (polymerase chain reaction), DGGE (Denaturing Gradient Gel Electrophoresis), TPH (Total Petroleum Hydrocarbons).</description><creator>Ferrera Rodriguez, Ofelia</creator><contributor>Lyle Whyte (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Charles William Greer (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Microbiology</subject><title>Rhizosphere microbial communities of Puccinella angustata thriving in pristine diesel-contaminated Arctic soils</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hh404.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547w56j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042z24r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les origines de développement de la théorie de la maladie formalisent qu'un foetus s`adapte physiologiquement à des modifications faites à son environnement pour se préparer à la vie postnatale. La programmation in utero par la diète (limitation de protéines) et la physiologie (hypertension) augmentent la probabilité de maladies cardiovasculaires chez les adultes. Les testicules foetaux sécrètent de la testostérone et des récepteurs androgènes se manifestent dans les coeurs foetaux ce qui nous mène à penser que le coeur foetal pourrait répondre à la programmation par la testostérone. Nous théorisons que la progéniture de souris femelles traitées à la testostérone pendant leur grossesse sera programmée et manifestera des différences structurelles et fonctionnelles cardiaques. Un véhicule (huile de cacahuète) ou de la testostérone proprionate (TP) a été introduit à des souris C57B1/6n pleines par injection sous-cutanée pendant les jours de gestation (GD) 11-14 (20ug, 200ug/kg poids corporel (BW)) ou GD14-18 (2ug, 20ug, 200ug/kg BW). La testostérone gestationnelle dans la conception expérimentale était conforme pour masculiniser les organes reproductifs femelles à doses élevées, mais ne l'était pas à doses réduites. Des augmentations en AGD et des plus grands utérus sont observés chez les souris GD11-14 et GD14-18 traitées avec de la TP 200.0. Les femelles traitées avec de la TP 20.0 (aux deux temps d`injection) ont montré les plus grandes modifications cardiovasculaires tandis que celles traitées avec de la TP 2.0 au temps d'injection GD14-18 ont montré les plus grandes modifications dans le système cardiovasculaire mâle. Une virilisation du coeur de la souris femelle se manifeste pendantle traitement gestationnel à la testostérone et modifie la fonction cardiaque. Même des doses réduites qui n'influençaient ni les organes reproductifs ni la formation de tétons avaient des répercutions sur la fonction cardiaque. Les femelles sont programmées par les hormones masculines in utero et montrent des différences dans leur structure et fonction cardiaque ainsi que dans leur protéines 'calcium homeostasis'.</description><description>The developmental origins of disease theory hypothesizes that the fetus makes physiological adaptations in response to changes in its environment to prepare itself for postnatal life. In utero programming by diet (protein restriction), or physiology (hypertension) increases cardiovascular disease in adults. Fetal testes secrete testosterone and fetal hearts express androgen receptors leading to the idea that the fetal heart could respond to testosterone programming. We hypothesize that the adult female progeny of testosterone-treated pregnant mice will be programmed and display differences in cardiac structure and function.Pregnant C57Bl/6n mice were injected subcutaneously with vehicle (peanut oil) or testosterone propionate (TP) during gestational days (GD) 11-14 (20ug, 200ug/kg body weight (BW)) or GD14-18 (2ug, 20ug, 200ug/kg BW). Gestational testosterone in the experimental design was adequate to masculinise female reproductive organs at the higher but not at lower doses. TP treatment in GD11-14 and GD14-18 TP200.0 mice yield increases in anogenital distance (AGD) and heavier, larger uteri at sacrifice. TP 20.0 treated females (both injection times) showed the greatest changes in calcium homeostasis proteins, whereas TP 2.0 treated GD14-18 showed the greatest changes for treated males. Virilization of the female mouse heart occurs during gestational testosterone treatment and alters cardiac function. Cardiac function was affected even at doses that do not impact reproductive organs or nipple formation. The data are consistent with the hypothesis that females are programmed by exposure to masculanising hormones in utero and display differences in cardiac structure, function and calcium homeostasis proteins.</description><creator>Noiles, William</creator><contributor>Lorraine E Chalifour (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Physiology</subject><title>Gestational testosterone alters cardiac structure, function and calcium homeostasis protein expression in adult progeny</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182q36x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042z24r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xj929</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Laboratory research in rodents suggests that early exposure to methylphenidate (MPH) leads to altered sensitivity to the rewarding effects of stimulant drugs of abuse later in life and may have implications for drug-taking vulnerability. Netrin-1 is a family of guidance cue proteins that participates in the organization of neural circuits. During embryonic development through adulthood, both netrin-1 and its receptor DCC (deleted in colorectal cancer) are expressed in mesocorticolimbic dopamine (DA) brain regions. Studies conducted on dcc heterozygous rodents show a critical role for DCC expression in the development and function of the adult mesocorticolimbic DA system. Recently, variations in DCC expression, specifically in the ventral tegmental area (VTA), have been shown to be involved in adult stimulant-induced behavioral plasticity. Here we explored, 1) the effects of early adolescent MPH treatment on cocaine-reward in adulthood using conditioned place preference as a measure of drug-reward, and 2) whether early MPH treatment leads to alterations in DCC expression in mesocorticolimbic DA regions. Repeated exposure to MPH during early adolescence reduced sensitivity to the rewarding value of cocaine in adulthood. Remarkably this decrease in adult cocaine-reward was associated with a down-regulation of DCC expression in the VTA selectively. This is the first demonstration that developmental MPH treatment regulates netrin-1 DCC receptor expression in the adult brain and suggests that DCC regulation may be a mechanism by which exposure to stimulant drugs early in life induces enduring changes in sensitivity to their rewarding effects in adulthood.</description><description>La recherche chez les rongeurs suggère que l'administration de methylphenidate (MPH) durant le développement conduit à des réponses différentes aux effets de récompense des drogues stimulantes d'abus et peut aussi avoir des implications concernant la vulnérabilité d'abus de drogue plus tard dans la vie. Netrin-1 est une famille de protéines développementale fondamentale à l'organisation du system dopamine (DA) mésocorticolimbique. Durant le développement embryologique et pendant l'âge adulte, netrin-1 et son récepteur DCC, sont exprimés dans les régions mésocorticolimbiques. La recherche chez les souris avec des niveaux réduits de DCC suggèrent un rôle important de ces récepteurs durant le développement du cerveau et dans la plasticité du système DA mésocorticolimbique induite par les drogues stimulantes, particulièrement dans l'aire tegmentale ventrale (ATV). Durant cette étude, nous avons exploré 1) les effets de l'administration de MPH pendant l'enfance sur les effets de récompense de cocaïne durant l'âge adulte en utilisant un paradigme de préférence locative conditionnée, et 2) si les traitements MPH durant l'enfance mènent à des différences d'expression de DCC dans les régions DA mésocorticolimbiques. Nos résultats montrent que l'administration chronique de MPH pendant l'enfance réduit les réponses aux effets de récompenses de la cocaïne durant l'âge adulte. Remarquablement, cette diminution de réponse aux effets de récompense de cocaïne est associée à une réduction d'expression de DCC dans le ATV exclusivement. C'est la première étude qui montre que le traitement MPH durant le développement régularise l'expression de DCC dans le cerveau adulte et suggère un mécanisme par lequel l'administration de drogues stimulantes durant l'enfance pourrait  entrainer de différentes réponses aux effets de récompenses durant l'âge adulte.  </description><creator>Argento, Jessica</creator><contributor>Ana Cecilia Flores Parkman (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Health Sciences - Mental Health</subject><title>Effect of exposure to methylphenidate in early life on cocaine reward in adulthood: a possible role for netrin-1 receptors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k656f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xj929</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21tk68p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>     This quasi-experimental study implemented an original instructional unit in second language (L2) classrooms where the learners were taught (a) how to interact with each other (peer interaction), and (b) how to provide corrective feedback (CF) to each other (peer CF). This Second Language Acquisition (SLA) intervention was examined from three different viewpoints. First, from a psycholinguistic perspective, the effect of the intervention on learners' interactional patterns as well as its effects on their L2 development (i.e., grammatical knowledge and fluent spontaneous production) were investigated. Second, the learners' perceptions (referred to in this dissertation as learner perceptions) of the intervention relative to classroom dynamics were examined to ensure its ecological validity. Third, the construct of the target of instruction (i.e., interactional oral fluency) was scrutinized so as to ensure the validity of the testing used for measuring L2 development. This exploration was informed by theoretical and methodological frameworks from Language Testing (LT) research.     Four university-level required English classes in Japan participated (N = 167), each assigned to one of four treatment conditions. Of the two CF groups, one was taught to provide prompts and the other to provide recasts. A third group participated in only peer interaction activities and a fourth served as the control group. The three experimental classes were given (a) a peer-interaction awareness activity and (b) fluency-focused paired activities over one academic semester. In addition to the pre- and post-tests that examined accuracy and fluency development, all participants completed questionnaires designed to elicit their perceptions before and after the intervention. Selected learners were interviewed at the end of the semester as well. In order to explore the construct of interactional oral fluency and the validity of the measurements, speech samples were rated by human raters based on empirically-based rating scales developed specifically for this study.     The results revealed that, after one semester, participants used a greater number of interactional moves hypothesized to be conducive to L2 development. Also, the two CF groups improved overall accuracy as well as fluency measured as unpruned and pruned speech rates, whereas the peer-interaction-only group outperformed the control group only on fluency measures. It is argued that while peer interaction offered opportunities for repeated practice facilitating proceduralization, CF refined learners' ability to monitor both their own output and that of their interlocutors. The questionnaire and interview data showed that participants' perceptions changed over time in certain respects. Specifically, they believed in the effectiveness of peer interaction and peer CF from the onset and, thus, no significant change was observed with their belief pertaining to the effectiveness of the intervention. However, their feelings towards peer interaction showed positive change over time. Also, those who were taught how to provide CF to their classmates became more confident in providing CF. Finally, the correlation and regression analyses of the results of the speech rates, grammatical accuracy, and rated scores both in individual and interactional contexts showed that (a) the empirically-based rating scales were reliable, with the interactional samples yielding a weaker agreement rate; (b) the individual rated scores were not significantly correlated with those of interactional performance but highly correlated with unpruned speech rates; and (c) among the four fluency measures only the pruned speech rates were a significant predictor of the grammatical accuracy scores.</description><description>     Cette étude quasi-expérimentale a intégré un volet d'enseignement en classe d'une langue seconde (L2) dans lequel les apprenants ont appris (a) à interagir les uns avec les autres et (b) à fournir une rétroaction corrective (RC) les uns aux autres. Cette intervention a été examinée selon trois approches. Premièrement, dans une perspective psycholinguistique, l'effet de l'intervention sur les patrons interactionnels des apprenants et ses effets sur leur développement en L2 ont été étudiés. Deuxièmement, les perceptions des apprenants sur l'intervention relative aux dynamiques de salle de classe ont été examinées. Troisièmement, la construction de l'objet d'enseignement (c'est-à-dire, la fluidité dans les interactions à l'oral) a été étudiée afin d'assurer la validité du test utilisé pour mesurer le développement de la compétence en L2.     Quatre classes japonaises de mise à niveau en anglais à l'université ont participé (N = 167). Chaque classe s'est vue attribuée une des quatre conditions de traitements. Des deux groupes de RC, l'un a appris à fournir des incitations et l'autre à fournir des reformulations. Le troisième groupe a seulement participé aux activités d'interaction entre pairs et le quatrième a servi de groupe témoin. Les trois classes expérimentales ont reçu (a) une activité de prise de conscience sur les interactions entre pairs et (b) des activités en groupe de deux basées sur la fluidité à l'oral tout au long d'un semestre universitaire. En plus des pré- et des post-tests qui ont examiné le développement en termes de précision et d'aisance à l'oral des participants, ces derniers ont rempli des questionnaires établissant leurs perceptions avant et après l'intervention. De plus, des apprenants ont été choisis pour être interviewés à la fin du semestre. Afin d'explorer la construction de l'aisance des interactions à l'oral et de valider les mesures utilisées, les enregistrements ont été évalués par des examinateurs humains.     Les résultats ont révélé que, après un semestre, les participants ont utilisé un plus grand nombre d'interactions supposées contribuer au développement de l'acquisition de la L2. De plus, les deux groupes RC ont amélioré leur précision et leur aisance, évaluées par des mesures de taux de discours non élagués et élagués, tandis que le groupe d'interaction entre pairs a réalisé de meilleurs résultats que le groupe témoin uniquement sur les mesures d'aisance. Il a été supposé qu'alors que les interactions entre pairs offrent des occasions pour l'entrainement répété facilitant la mise en place des procédures requises, la rétroaction corrective a permis d'affiner la capacité des apprenants à contrôler leur propre production ainsi que celle de leurs interlocuteurs. Le questionnaire et les données enregistrées des interviews ont montré que les perceptions des participants ont évolué au fil du temps dans une certaine mesure. Plus particulièrement, les participants ont, dès le début, cru en l'efficacité des interactions et de la RC entre pairs. Cependant, leurs sentiments envers les interactions entre pairs ont évolué positivement à travers le temps. De même, ceux qui ont appris à fournir une RC à leurs camarades de classe sont devenus plus confiants dans cette tâche. Enfin, les analyses de corrélation et de régression des résultats des taux de discours, de l'exactitude grammaticale et des scores réalisés aussi bien en contexte individuel qu'interactionnel indiquent que (a) les échelles d'évaluation était fiables; (b) les scores individuels n'étaient pas significativement corrélés avec ceux des performances interactionnelles, mais fortement corrélés avec ceux des taux de discours non élagués; (c) parmi les quatre mesures d'aisance, seule la mesure taux de discours élagués s'est révélé être un facteur significativement prédictif des résultats d'exactitude grammaticale.</description><creator>Sato, Masatoshi</creator><contributor>Roy Lyster (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Education - Bilingual and Multicultural</subject><title>Peer interaction and corrective feedback: proceduralization of grammatical knowledge in classroom settings</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qr21s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21tk68p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cm73p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La production agricole est très dépendante du climat; par conséquent, les futurs changements climatiques globaux pourraient avoir des effets adverses sur la population mondiale en plein essor. L'objectif principal de cette étude était de prédire les conséquences du changement climatique sur l'agriculture. Puisque les projections climatiques actuelles utilisent des modèles de circulation générale à une échelle globale, un modèle statistique de réduction (MSR) a été utilisé pour réduire ces données à l'échelle locale, ce qui est essentiel pour des simulations de production agricole.En reliant les changements du climat locaux prédits (modélisation) aux propriétés du sol et les caractéristiques des cultures (études sur le terrain et en laboratoire), les seuils du contenu en humidité du sol pour la planification d'un horaire d'irrigation efficace ont été définis, et un modèle de besoin en irrigation (MBI) a été développé. En utilisant ce modèle, l'irrigation était déclenchée lorsque l'humidité du sol était de 24 ou 18 mm pour les pêchers croissant en sols sablonneux ou argileux, respectivement, et a été déclenchée à 56 mm pour les vignes croissant en sol argileux. Il était remarquable que le MBI a réduit le besoin en irrigation de 20 to 25% sans affecter le rendement en pêches (50 to 60 kg/arbre).Concernant les augmentations de températures et les variabilités de précipitations prédites, le scénario SDMS-HadCM3 A2 prédit les plus fortes hausses, environ 3.5 et 2.5oC en moyenne pour les températures mensuelles maximum et minimum, respectivement, pendant la saison de croissance (comparé à une période de base 1961-1990). De plus, des précipitations plus fréquentes (8 to 30%) et plus intenses (10 to 50% durant les mois de croissance ont aussi été prédites.Avec ces scénarios de changements climatiques futurs, le rendement en pêches irriguées pourrait augmenter de 5 to 20%, puisque la transpiration des arbres a atteint 0.8 kg/h (comparé à un maximum de 0.4 kg/h sans irrigation). De plus, avec l'irrigation, la fermeté des fruits, le meilleur indicateur du mûrissement et prédicateur du potentiel d'entreposage des pêches, devrait s'améliorer de 20% (valeur actuelle, 340 kPa).L'aspect le plus novateur de cette étude a été le développement du modèle MBI, qui a prédit l'irrigation optimale requise pour maintenir ou augmenter le rendement et la qualité des cultures tout en conservant l'eau. </description><description>Crop production is highly dependent upon weather; therefore, future climate change could adversely affect the burgeoning global population. The primary objective of this study was to predict the consequences of climate change on agriculture. Since current climate projections use general circulation models (GCMs) on a global scale, a statistical downscaling model (SDSM) was used to downscale these outputs into a local scale, essential for reliable crop model simulations.By linking predicted changes in local climate to soil properties and crop characteristics through field and laboratory studies, thresholds of soil moisture content for efficient irrigation scheduling were defined, and an irrigation requirements model (IRM) was developed. Using the IRM, irrigation was triggered when soil moisture was 18 or 24 mm for peaches grown in clay and sandy soils, respectively, and was also triggered at 56 mm for grapes grown in clay soils. It was noteworthy that the IRM reduced irrigation needs by 20 to 25% without affecting yield of peaches (50 to 60 kg/tree). Regarding predicted increases in temperatures and variability in precipitation, the SDSM-HadCM3 A2 scenario forecast the greatest increases, namely ~3.5 and ~2.5°C in average monthly maximum and minimum temperatures, respectively, during the growing season, compared to a 1961-1990 base period. Moreover, precipitation events were also predicted to be more frequent (8 to 30%) and intense (10 to 50%) during crop growing months.With these future climate change scenarios, irrigated peach yield could increase 5 to 20%, since actual tree transpiration reached 0.8 kg/h (compared to a maximum of 0.4 kg/h without irrigation). Furthermore, with irrigation, fruit firmness, the best indicator of ripening and predictor of peach storage potential, is expected to improve by 20% over the current value of 340 kPa.The most novel aspect of this study was development of the IRM, and its prediction of optimal irrigation needed to sustain or increase crop yield and quality, and concurrently conserve water. </description><creator>Doria, Rufa</creator><contributor>Chandra A Madramootoo (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Agriculture - General</subject><title>Impact of climate change on crop water requirements in Eastern Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mk45d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cm73p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vq09n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Un élément essentiel de la réponse immunitaire innée est l'activation rapide de "l'inflammasome". Les inflammasomes sont des complexes multi-protéiniques qui recrutent et activent la caspase-1, une caspase inflammatoire qui actionne le système immunitaire via la modification et la maturation de cytokines pro-inflammatoires. Les voies de signalisation menant à l'activation de l'inflammasome sont apparentées aux voies pro-apoptotiques initiées par la mitochondrie. Nous avons donc présumé que les protéines cellular inhibitor of apoptosis proteins (cIAPs), qui inhibent l'action des caspases apoptotiques et la mort cellulaire, réguleraient aussi l'activité de la caspase-1 et de l'inflammasome. Nous avons utilisé des méthodes de co-immunoprécipitation et de GST pull down pour démontrer que cIAP1 et cIAP2 se lient à la caspase-1. Nous avons identifié que cette interaction se fait entre le domaine BIR N-terminal de cIAP2 et le domaine CARD de la caspase-1. La co-expression avec cIAP2 amplifie la function catalytique de la caspase-1 ainsi que la mort cellulaire caspase-1-dépendente. Inversement, la déplétion des cIAPs par traitement SMAC mimetics ou par immunodéplétion réduit le niveau d'activation de l'inflammasome et son clivage la de pro-IL-1b dans des extraits cytosoliques de la lignée monocytique humaine THP-1. L'activation de l'inflammasome est aussi sévèrement inhibée dans les macrophages primaires de souris ciap2-/- qui produisent moins d'IL-1b en réponse aux stimuli agonists de l'inflammasome. De plus, l'injection d'alum ou de cristaux MSU, deux agonistes de l'inflammasome NLRP3, induit moins de recrutement de neutrophiles et de production d'IL-1b dans le péritoine des souris ciap2-/- que dans les animaux sauvages. En somme, ces résultats suggèrent que les protéines cIAPs se lient à la caspase-1 et régulent l'activation de l'inflammasome, amplifiant ainsi la réponse inflammatoire à l'invasion de pathogènes et aux signaux de danger. Une caractérisation plus approfondie de la fonction des IAPs dans l'immunité innée permettra de mieux définir leur potential thérapeutique dans le traitement des maladies inflammatoires.</description><description>A key host innate immune response to pathogens is the rapid activation of "inflammasomes". The inflammasomes are multi-protein complexes that recruit and activate inflammatory caspase-1, which alarms the system through the processing of proinflammatory cytokines to their biologically active forms. Because the inflammasome and mitochondrial apoptosis pathways are evolutionarily related, we hypothesized that cellular inhibitor of apoptosis proteins (cIAPs), negative regulators of apoptotic caspases and cell death, might also regulate caspase-1 and inflammasome activity. Using coimmunoprecipitation assays and in vitro pull-down experiments, we show that both cIAP1 and 2 bound to caspase-1. This interaction was mapped in cIAP2 to its 3 Nterminal BIR domains and the CARD domain of caspase-1. Co-expression of cIAP2 with caspase-1 significantly enhanced caspase-1 catalysis and caspase-1-dependent cell death. Conversely, cIAP depletion with SMAC mimetics or specific immunodepletion of cIAP2 from cytosolic extracts of the human monocytic cell line THP-1 reduced inflammasome activation and the consequent processing of pro-IL-1. In ciap2-/- bone marrow-derived macrophages (BMDM) cultured ex vivo, inflammasome activation was markedly inhibited and IL-1β secretion was consistently dampened in response to various inflammasome agonists. Moreover, ciap2-/- mice injected with either NALP3 agonists alum or MSU, showed decreased neutrophil recruitment into the peritoneal cavity and diminished induction of IL-1β in the peritoneal fluid compared to wild-type controls. Altogether, these results suggest that cIAPs bind to caspase-1 and regulate inflammasome activation, thus amplifying the inflammatory response following pathogen invasion or danger signals. Further characterization of the physiological action of IAPs in innate immunity will help define the potential therapeutic profiles of IAP antagonists in immune-mediated inflammatory disorders.</description><creator>McIntire, Christian</creator><contributor>Maya Saleh (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Microbiology</subject><title>Cellular inhibitor of apoptosis proteins (cIAPs) bind to caspase-1 and are required for inflammasome activation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zj70v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vq09n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x326z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Following the collapse of the Soviet regime, the post-communist states of Central and Eastern Europe faced the distinct issue of socialist propaganda permeating the public landscapes. In three unique cases, political elites in Russia, Lithuania, and Hungary established "statue parks" in order to formally display and contain a collection of communist statuary that previously stood in public streets. By doing so, the creators of the parks altered the ideological meaning attached to these monuments and reconstructed historical narratives about the communist past, while also providing an interesting destination for curious tourists. Through an interpretive comparison of these cases based on field research, this paper demonstrates the ability of elites to shape historical narratives in the public realm; while the statues contained in each park are quite similar, the interpretation of them is drastically different in each case. These differences, I argue, are the result of each state's distinct experience under communism and the diverging political goals of post-communist elites. To better understand the complexity of these narratives, I also evaluate the relative influence of state and non-state actors in shaping the statue parks over time. Overall, I find that the broadening of participation in the creation and maintenance of these parks – while demonstrating a democratic opening of the public memory process – may also lead to greater commercialization and trivialization of the past, as economic exigencies lead to tourist-oriented display techniques.</description><description>Depuis l'effondrement du régime soviétique, les États postcommunistes d'Europe centrale et d'Europe de l'est sont confrontés à la propagande socialiste imprégnant les paysages publics. Dans trois cas unique, les élites politiques en Russie, en Lituanie et en Hongrie ont créé des parcs statue afin de formellement établir et présenter une collection de statues communistes qui auparavant se retrouvaient dans les rues publiques. Ce faisant, les créateurs des parcs ont altéré le sens idéologique attaché à ces monuments et ont reconstruit les récits historiques sur le passé communiste tout en offrant une destination intéressante pour les touristes curieux. Grâce à une interprétation comparative de ces cas, sur la base de recherches de terrain, cet article démontre la capacité des élites à modeler les récits historiques dans le domaine public. Tandis que les statues contenues dans chaque parc sont assez similaires, l'interprétation est radicalement différente dans chaque cas. Ces différences, selon moi, sont le résultat de l'expérience distincte de chaque État sous le communisme et les objectifs politiques divergentes des élites postcommunistes. Pour mieux comprendre la complexité de ces récits, j'évalue aussi l'influence relative des acteurs étatiques et non étatiques dans l'élaboration des parcs statue au fil du temps. Dans l'ensemble, je trouve que l'élargissement de la participation à la création et l'entretien de ces parcs - tout en démontrant une ouverture démocratique du processus de la mémoire publique - peut aussi conduire à une plus grande commercialisation et la banalisation du passé puisque que les exigences économiques actuelles sont orienter pour attirer le plus grand public touristique possible.</description><creator>Dietrich, Megan</creator><contributor>Juliet Johnson (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Political Science - General</subject><title>Monuments on the move: post-communist statue parks in Russia, Lithuania and Hungary</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70n0444.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x326z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128nj88m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Lors de la maladie neurodégénérative de la sclérose latérale amyotrophique (SLA), le mauvais repliement et l'agrégation des protéines ont une incidence sur la mort des motoneurones. Les protéines du choc thermique (Hsp), lesquelles aident les protéines au mauvais repliement à se replier de nouveau ou encore ciblent ces dernières au niveau du protéasome pour leur dégradation, ont été étudiées comme source de traitement possible pour la SLA, non sans réussite. Parallèlement,  il a été démontré que le dysfonctionnement mitochondrial est un des événements pathogènes menant à la mort des motoneurones, les anomalies mitochondriales apparaissant avant qu'une agrégation ou un mauvais repliement des protéines significatif ne soit observé. Les mitochondries ont leurs propres Hsp pour les protéines se repliant dans la matrice, les Hsp60 étant l'exemple par excellence. Si on considère que l'expression intensifiée d'autres mitochondries comme les Hsp22 peut préserver la fonction motrice, empêcher la mort de motoneurones et augmenter la résistance au stress oxydatif dans un modèle vieillissant de Drosophila, il semble que la régulation positive des Hsp60 mitochondriales pourrait possiblement protéger les neurones contre la SLA. La présente étude avait pour but d'examiner la régulation positive des Hsp60 dans un modèle de moelle épinière dissociée atteinte de SLA familiale causée par une mutation du gène SOD1. L'intensification de l'expression des Hsp60 n'a pas contribué à préserver la viabilité des motoneurones, ni à rectifier le mauvais repliement ou l'agrégation des protéines SOD1, ni à prévenir l'arrondissement mitochondrial dans les motoneurones. Par conséquent, la régulation positive des Hsp60 mitochondriales n'est pas recommandée pour le traitement de la SLA.Entretemps, les mutations de l'encodage du gène pour les Hsp60 transmises selon le mode dominant ont été associées à la paraplégie spasmodique héréditaire SPG13 (HSPG13), une maladie au cours de laquelle la dégénérescence axonique cause la mort des motoneurones. On ne connait aucun autre mécanisme de mort cellulaire plus précis. Toutefois, étant donné la présence des anomalies mitochondriales dans grand nombre de maladies neurodégénératives, l'importance des mitochondries pour l'intégrité des axones et la localisation mitochondriale des Hsp60, le dysfonctionnement mitochondrial pourrait très bien constituer un tel mécanisme. Les Hsp60V72I, une mutation observée chez les patients atteints de HSPG13, ont pu être exprimées dans les motoneurones provenant de cultures de moelle épinière dissociée afin de servir de modèle pour de potentielles anomalies mitochondriales. L'expression des Hsp60V72I n'a pas mené à une baisse de viabilité chez les motoneurones, ni à une modification de la morphologie mitochondriale, ni à une détérioration des mesures fonctionnelles des mitochondries, incluant le potentiel de membrane (ΔΨ), la résistance au stress oxydatif et le transport axonal. Il se peut que les Hsp60V72I ne causent qu'un faible phénotype mitochondrial, ou encore qu'elles n'en causent aucun du tout. Cependant, l'expression d'un mutant à grave déficience en ATP-ase, soit les Hsp60D423A, n'est pas non plus parvenue à causer un dysfonctionnement mitochondrial dans ce modèle de culture. On ne sait toujours pas si l'absence de phénotype est révélatrice du rôle des Hsp60 dans les maladies touchant les motoneurones, ou si les résultats négatifs sont un artefact du modèle de culture, lequel était caractérisé par un niveau élevé d'expression endogène des Hsp60 de phénotype sauvage qui pourrait potentiellement masquer les effets de l'expression du mutant exogène Hsp60. Les études à venir devraient se pencher sur les effets mitochondriaux de l'expression des Hsp60V72I dans un contexte où le phénotype sauvage Hsp60 endogène est réduit, en utilisant par exemple les Hsp60 shRNA particulières aux souris.</description><description>In the fatal neurodegenerative disease, amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS), protein misfolding and aggregation are involved in motor neuron death.  Heat shock proteins (Hsp), which help refold misfolded proteins or target them to the proteasome for degradation, have been studied as a therapeutic target in ALS, with some success.  At the same time, it has been shown that mitochondrial dysfunction is one of the earliest pathogenic events leading to motor neuron death in ALS.  The mitochondria have their own Hsps, for protein folding in the matrix, an important example of which is Hsp60.  Given the finding that increased expression of another mitochondrial Hsp, Hsp22, preserved motor function, reduced motor neuron death and increased resistance to oxidative stress in a Drosophila model of aging, it is possible that the upregulation of mitochondrial Hsp60 might have similar neuroprotective effects in ALS.  The current study examined Hsp60 upregulation in a primary dissociated spinal cord culture model of familial ALS (fALS) due to mutation in the SOD1 gene.  Increasing Hsp60 expression failed to improve motor neuron viability, to ameliorate SOD1 protein misfolding/aggregation, and to prevent mitochondrial rounding in motor neurons.  Therefore, the upregulation of mitochondrial Hsp60 would not be an effective therapy for ALS.Meanwhile, dominantly-inherited mutations in the gene encoding for Hsp60 have been linked to hereditary spastic paraplegia SPG13 (HSPG13), a disease in which the axons of motor neurons degenerate.  Disease mechanisms are not known; however, given the importance of mitochondria to axonal integrity, and the mitochondrial localization of Hsp60, mitochondrial dysfunction seems a likely candidate.  Hsp60V72I, a mutation found in HSPG13 patients, was expressed in motor neurons in primary dissociated spinal cord culture to model potential mitochondrial abnormalities.  Hsp60V72I expression did not reduce motor neuron viability, alter mitochondrial morphology, or impair mitochondria on functional measures, including membrane potential (ΔΨ), resistance to oxidative stress, or axonal transport.  It is possible that Hsp60V72I causes no, or a weak, mitochondrial phenotype.  However, the expression of a severe, ATPase-deficient mutant, Hsp60D423A, also failed to induce mitochondrial dysfunction in this culture model.  Thus, these phenotypes might not manifest because of culture conditions or because they are masked by the high level of endogenous Hsp60.  </description><creator>Cooper, Laura</creator><contributor>Heather D Durham (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Mitochondrial heat shock protein 60: evaluation of its role as a neuroprotectant in familial amyotrophic lateral sclerosis and its mutation as a cause of hereditary spastic paraplegia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rz728.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nj88m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q811kp81s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aqueous chemistry of the reduction of selenious species by sodium dithionite, sodium sulfide, stannous chloride and sulfur dioxide/sulfite was studied. The resultant precipitates were characterized using different techniques, including scanning electron microscopy, X-ray diffraction and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy. In the case of sodium dithionite, the research showed that, at initial pH below 1.7 and dithionite stoichiometric excess above three, less than 0.5 ug/L remained in solution less than a minute after the addition of the reagent. However, it was found that the precipitate, mainly composed of red amorphous selenium, was not stable in the presence of the dithionite decomposition by-products and partially redissolved after several hours. In the case of the reaction involving selenious acid and sulfide ions, the results showed that, below a pH of approximately 7.0, the precipitation reaction was complete in less than 10 minutes at a sulfide to selenium ratio above 1.8 with less than 5 ug/L of soluble selenium remaining in solution. The precipitate was deduced to be a Se-S solid solution consisting of ring molecules of the following SenS8−n formula. However, above pH 7 the removal of selenium was incomplete due to formation of a stable colloidal suspension. In the case of industrial solutions, high dissolved sulfur dioxide content (&gt; 5g/L) decreases the effectiveness of the precipitation reaction. Concerning the removal of Se(IV) by tin(II), at an initial pH below 1.3 and molar ratios above two, less than 5 ug/L of selenium(IV) remained in solution after reduction. The reaction products, were determined to be composed of approximately equal amounts of tin selenide and tin dioxide with a small amount of selenium(IV) being adsorbed on the latter. Finally, it was found that Se(IV) can be reduced quantitatively at ambient temperature via a combination of sulfite reduction and ultra-acidification to a colloidal form that can be determined using turbidimetry. The developed technique was shown to be equally effective with real Se(IV)-bearing industrial solutions generated in a zinc concentrate roasting operation hence making the method particularly useful as on-line process monitoring and control tool.  </description><description>La chimie aqueuse des réactions de réduction entre les ions sélénieux et le dithionite de sodium, le sulfure de sodium et les ions stanneux ont été étudiées. Les précipités résultant de cette réaction ont été caractérisés par différentes techniques comme la microscopie électronique à balayage, la diffraction à rayons X et la spectrométrie de photoélectrons induits par rayons X. Dans le cas du dithionite de sodium, ce projet a démontré que, pour un pH initial inférieur à 1.7 et un ratio stœchiométrique de dithionite supérieur à trois, moins de 0.5 ug/L de sélénium(IV) restait en solution moins d'une minute après l'addition du réactif. Par contre, le précipité, formé en majorité de sélénium rouge amorphe, n'était pas stable en présence des composés issus de la réaction de décomposition du dithionite et était partiellement re-dissous après quelques heures. Dans le cas de la réaction entre l'acide sélénieux et le sulfure de sodium, les résultats indiquaient que pour un ratio molaire sulfur/sélénium plus grand que 1.8 et un pH sous 7.0 la réaction de précipitation était complète et moins de 5 ug/L de sélénium (IV) restait en solution. Aucune précipitation n'a été constatée pour un pH plus élevé que 9.5 et la réaction était incomplète pour un pH entre 7 et 9.5. Le précipité semblait être composé d'une solution solide Se-S formé de molécules circulaires répondant à la formule SenS8−n. Par contre, pour un pH plus élevé que 7, la précipitation du sélénium était incomplète à cause de la formation d'un précipité de sélénium colloïdal. De plus, dans le cas des solutions industrielles, de hautes concentrations de dioxyde de souffre dissous (&gt; 5g/L) diminuait l'efficacité de la réaction de précipitation.En ce qui concerne la réaction entre le sélénium(IV) et l'étain, pour un pH initial sous 1.3 et un ratio molaire étain/sélénium plus grand que deux, moins de 5 ug/L de sélénium restait en solution après la réaction. Les analyses ont révélé que le précipité était composé de parts approximativement égales de séléniure d'étain et de dioxyde d'étain et que ce dernier pouvait adsorber une petite quantité d'ions sélénieux. Finalement, ce projet a démontré que le sélénium(IV) peut être réduit, à la température ambiante, par une solution ultra-acide riche en sulfites. Une fois le sélénium précipité sous forme colloïdale, la concentration originale de celui-ci peut ensuite être déterminée par turbidimétrie. Par ailleurs, cette méthode est aussi efficace sur des solutions industrielles contenant du sélénium(IV) et peut donc être appliquée pour l'analyse en temps réel de cet élément.           </description><creator>Geoffroy, Nicolas</creator><contributor>George Demopoulos (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Metallurgy</subject><title>Selenium removal from aqueous solutions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gx81x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811kp81s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f5409</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation considers the sources of variation in the ability of nonstate military actors to both resist and recover from – in short, to survive – confrontations with much stronger conventional militaries. While much of the existing literature on civil war focuses on structural variables, such as initial material or social endowments, this dissertation argues that these resources are less important in determining a non-state actor's resilience than the relationships it builds in order to acquire them and the means it uses to do so.   “Resources” may be either material, (e.g., money and arms) or non-material (e.g., legitimacy and influence) and are acquired (from the civilian population and/or a foreign sponsor) through three possible strategies: coercion, service-provision, and marketing.  I argue that the first is least effective, as coercion tends to provide only short-term access to material resources, while marketing is the most effective, as it produces the most durable access to both material and non-material resources.  Service provision produces a mid-range outcome. Moreover, all three can have significant unintended consequences. I test the argument by comparing the performances of the PLO, Hizbullah and Hamas in their confrontations with Israel over the past four decades.  I conclude by considering the implications of my conclusions both for the study of nonstate actors more broadly, and for the dynamics of 21st century Iraq and Afghanistan.   </description><description>Cette thèse considère les facteurs de variation de l'habileté des acteurs militaires non-étatiques à résister à et à se remettre- en bref, à survivre à- des confrontations avec des militaires conventionnels comparativement beaucoup plus forts. Alors que la plus grande partie de la littérature sur les guerres civiles se concentre sur les variables structurelles telles que le matériel initial ou les atouts sociaux, cette thèse soutient que ces ressources sont moins importantes pour déterminer la résilience d'un acteur non-étatique que les relations qu'elles construisent afin de les acquérir ainsi que les moyens qu'elle utilise pour le faire. Les « ressources » peuvent  être  soit matérielles (par exemple, de l'argent et des armes) ou non-matérielles (par exemple, la légitimité et l'influence) et sont acquises (de la population civile et/ou d'un soutien étranger) à travers trois stratégies possibles : la coercition, la prestation de services, et le marketing.  Nous soutenons que le premier est le moyen le moins efficace, puisque la coercition tend à donner seulement un accès à court terme aux ressources matérielles, alors que le marketing est le moyen plus efficace, puisqu'il donne l'accès le plus durable à la fois aux ressources matérielles et non-matérielles. La prestation de service aboutit à un résultat intermédiaire.  Qui plus est, les trois peuvent avoir des conséquences inattendues.  Nous testons ces arguments en comparant la performance de l'OLP, du Hezbollah et du Hamas dans leur confrontation avec Israël au cours des quatre dernières décennies. Nous concluons en considérant la portée de nos conclusions pour l'étude des acteurs non-étatiques en général, ainsi que pour les dynamiques du 21ième siècle en Iraq et en Afghanistan.   </description><creator>Szekely, Ora</creator><contributor>Rex J Brynen (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Stephen Saideman (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Political Science - General</subject><title>Send lawyers, guns and money: the politics of militia survival in the Middle East</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193f024.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f5409</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s659j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Vitamin B12 (cobalamin, Cbl) is an essential coenzyme in mammals for two reactions: the conversion of homocysteine to methionine by the enzyme methionine synthase and the conversion of methylmalonyl-CoA to succinyl-CoA by the enzyme methylmalonyl-CoA mutase. In cells, cobalamin is converted to the two active coenzyme forms of the vitamin: methylcobalamin and 5'-deoxyadenosylcobalamin. Eight groups of patients have been described with intracellular disorders of cobalamin metabolism, named cblA-cblG and mut. Three groups of patients present with an inability to produce both methylcobalamin and 5'deoxyadenosylcobalamin: cblF, cblC and cblD. We located the gene responsible for the cblF type of cobalamin disorder to chromosome 6 by microcell-mediated chromosome transfer, leading to the discovery of the LMBRD1 gene. We identified three novel mutations in LMBRD1 among cblF patients. We reviewed phenotypic and genetic data on three cblD patients and were able to confirm previous genotype-phenotype correlations. We purified the MMADHC protein defective in the cblD group of cobalamin disorder and predicted that interactions with the protein defective in the cblC group occur in a domain homologous to a bacterial domain involved also in protein-protein interactions. </description><description>La vitamine B12 (cobalamine, Cbl) est une coenzyme essentielle chez les mammifères pour deux réactions : la conversion entre l'homocystéine et la méthionine par l'enzyme méthionine synthase et la conversion entre le méthylmalonyl-CoA et le succinyl-CoA par l'enzyme méthylmalonyl-CoA mutase. Dans les cellules, la cobalamine est transformée en ses deux formes coenzymatiques actives : la méthylcobalamine et l'adénosylcobalamine. Huit groupes de patients ont été décrits qui présentent des défauts intracellulaires de la voie métabolique de la cobalamine, nommés cblA-cblG et mut. Trois groupes de patients présentent une inhabilité à synthétiser la méthylcobalamine et l'adénosylcobalamine : cblF, cblC et cblD. Nous avons localisé le gène responsable de la forme cblF de désordre de cobalamine sur le chromosome 6 par transfert de chromosome par microcellules, menant à l'identification du gène LMBRD1. Nous avons identifié trois nouvelles mutations dans LMBRD1 chez des patients cblF. Nous avons passé en revue des données phénotypiques et génotypiques pour trois patients cblD et avons pu confirmer des corrélations génotype-phénotype observées auparavant. Nous avons purifié la protéine MMADHC défectueuse dans le groupe cblD et prédit que l'intéraction avec la protéine défective dans le group cblC implique le domaine homologue à un domaine d'une protéine bactérienne aussi impliqué dans des intéractions protéiques.</description><creator>Racine Miousse, Isabelle</creator><contributor>David Rosenblatt (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>James W Coulton (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>Investigations into the early steps of cobalamin metabolism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128nj89w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s659j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f7623h747</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Colorectal cancer (CRC) is a complex multi-step disease that involves both an intrinsic genetic component, and extrinsic environmental factors. Using a set of AcB/BcA recombinant congenic strains (RCS) derived from CRC-susceptible A/J and CRC-resistant C57BL/6J progenitors, we have identified and characterized a major locus on a 14Mb segment of chromosome 3, as controlling  azoxymethane-induced susceptibility to tumorigenesis in AcB/BcA strains, the Colon cancer susceptibility locus 3 (Ccs3).  In following studies, we further ascertained the close phenotype/genotype correlation in additional AcB/BcA strains, as well as in groups of backcross populations bearing unique recombinant chromosomes for the interval.  We reduced the Ccs3 interval to a 2.2Mb segment, containing 13 annotated transcripts, one of these genes coding for the NFkB p105 protein.  As it is involved in pathological inflammation in the gut, Nfkb1 is also expressed at high levels in A/J intestinal mucosa but at low levels in CRC tumors.  Sequencing of the 13 positional candidates identified a copy number variant (CNV) consisting of a strain-specific deletion of a 54bp duplication sequence near the Nfkb1 exon/intron junction of exon 15.  Loss of one of the duplicated 54 bp-repeat is associated with CRC susceptibility in A/J.  Finally, we observed the presence of additional genetic effects influencing the Ccs3-mediated CRC phenotype in AcB/BcA strains. Hence, we performed a linkage analysis by whole genome-scanning on 208 (B6 X A/J)F2 mice. These studies validated the effect of Ccs3 [LOD = 4.89] and identified an additional locus on distal chromosome 9 [LOD = 3.76], denoted Colon cancer susceptibility 5 locus (Ccs5).  Ccs5 modulates tumor multiplicity in F2 animals bearing at least one A/J-derived susceptibility allele at Ccs3, with A/J-derived Ccs5 susceptibility alleles being inherited in a recessive manner. In F2 mice, a strong additive effect is observed between susceptibility alleles at both loci.  Therefore, the work in this thesis also identifies a two-locus system (Ccs3, Ccs5) that regulates predisposition to CRC in mice.</description><description>Le cancer colorectal (CRC) est une maladie complexe résultant de l'interaction de composantes génétiques et environnementales.  Nous avons identifié, puis caractérisé, un important locus nommé Colon cancer susceptibility locus 3 (Ccs3) contrôlant la susceptibilité à l'induction de CRC des lignées AcB/BcA,  Les lignées de souris AcB/BcA recombinantes (recombinant congenic strains (RCS)) sont dérivées de la lignée A/J (susceptible à l'induction de CRC) croisée sur la lignée C57Bl/6J (résistante à l'induction de CRC),  Nous avons ensuite confirmé la corrélation entre le génotype/phénotype du locus Ccs3 de lignées AcB/BcA additionnelles, de même que la corrélation des groupes générés par rétrocroisement incluant certains animaux portant un chromosome recombinant pour la portion du locus Ccs3.  Cette approche a réduit l'intervalle physique correspondant à Ccs3 à un segment minimum de 2.2Mb.  Cette région contient 13 transcrits annotés, notamment celui encodant la protéine NFκB p105. Nous avons examiné l'expression du gène Nfkb1 : celui-ci est fortement exprimé dans la muqueuse intestinale des souris A/J mais très peu dans leurs tumeurs de côlon.  Le séquençage des 13 gènes candidat a identifié une variation du nombre de copies (CNV) d'une duplication de 54pb spécifique à une lignée A/J près du site d'épissage 3' de l'exon 15 de Nfkb1.  La perte d'une de ces copies est associée avec l'apparition de tumeurs intestinales chez la souris A/J.  Enfin, nous avons utilisé une approche génétique d'association par balayage du génome entier sur un total de 208 souris (B6 x A/J)F2 qui a confirmé l'effet majeur de Ccs3 [LOD = 4.89], et a détecté un locus additionnel dans la portion distale du chromosome 9 [LOD = 3.76], identifié Colon cancer susceptibility locus 5 (Ccs5).  Ccs5 module la multiplicité de tumeurs chez les animaux F2 porteurs d'au moins un allèle de susceptibilité A/J au locus Ccs3, héritée de manière récessive.  Nous avons donc identifié un système de deux loci (Ccs3, Ccs5) contrôlant la prédisposition au cancer colorectal chez la souris.</description><creator>Meunier, Charles</creator><contributor>Philippe Gros (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>Genetic control of susceptibility to carcinogen-induced colorectal cancer in mice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rt029.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623h747</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892g23h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette etude est une etude experimentale et numerique de la propagation des ondes de choc dans les suspensions polyphasiques. Des suspensions de particules sont utilisees comme un moyen d'obtenir un systeme dans lequel le contact initial entre les particules est limite et il y a un grand degre de variabilite parametrique. Les suspensions ont ete preparees dans l'ethylene glycol `a plusieurs fractions de volume (41%, 48% et 54%) de particules de carbure de silicium, des m´elanges qui se sont reveles etre rheoepaississantes dans les etudes rheologiques. La reponse dynamique des fluides rheoepaississents est etudiee dans une gamme des deformations pertinentes aux impacts balistiques.Une serie d'experiments d'impact de plaque ont ete menees pour obtenir les Hugoniots des chocs des differentes suspensions de particules a des vitesses dans l'ordre de 200-900 m/s. Les resultats experimentaux montrent une transition dans le comportement de propagation des ondes d'un regime de propagation domine par la compressibilite de la phase liquide de la suspension a un regime ou la reponse du melange devient dominee par les reseaux de contacts inter-particules. La transition dans le Hugoniots des choc des suspensions indique un choc induit par le raidissement de la suspension. Des mesures des contraintes longitudinales et laterales in situ sont en suspension dans la fraction volumique intermediaires a deux vitesses d'impact differentes demontrant une composante contrainte deviatorique a l'etat de stress au sein de la suspension.Des modeles analytiques et numeriques sont utilises pour demontrer la cause probable de la transition dans le comportement des suspensions, resultant de la variation de la fraction volumique de phase solide de la suspension avec des ondes de choc croissantes. Les resultats sont discutes en termes de developpement de contacts entre les particules etendu dans un mecanisme de compression induites par cisaillement classique analogue a un epaississement de suspensions denses. </description><description>The present study is an experimental and computational investigation of shock wave propagation in multiphase suspensions. Particle suspensions are used as a means of obtaining a system in which there is limited initial inter-particle contacts with a large degree of parametric variability. The suspensions were prepared in ethylene glycol at several volume fractions (41%, 48%, and 54%) of silicon carbide particles, mixtures that have been shown to be shear thickening in rheological studies. The dynamic response of the shear thickening fluids is investigated in ranges of deformation relevant to ballistic impacts.A series of plate impact experiments were conducted to obtain the shock Hugoniots of the various suspensions at particle velocities in the range of 200-900 m/s. The experimental results show a transition in the wave propagation behaviour from a regime of propagation dominated by the compressibility of the liquid phase of the suspension to a regime where the response of the mixture becomes dominated by inter-particle contact networks. The transition in the shock Hugoniots of the suspensions indicates a shock-induced stiffening of the suspensions. In situ longitudinal and lateral stress measurements are made in the intermediate volume fraction suspension at two different impact velocities demonstrating a deviatoric stress component to the stress state within the suspension.Analytical and numerical models are employed to demonstrate the likely cause of the transition in the behaviour of the suspensions, resulting from the variation in the solid phase volume fraction of the suspension with increasing shock wave strengths. The results are discussed in terms of the development of extensive inter-particle contacts in a compression-induced mechanism analogous to classical shear thickening in dense suspensions.</description><creator>Petel, Oren</creator><contributor>Andrew J Higgins (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical </subject><title>Response of shear thickening materials to uniaxial shock compression</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xq76d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892g23h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j6731818c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:03:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse examine l'utilité de l'oxyde de graphène réduit et de l'hybride oxyde de graphène réduit et nanotubes carbone en fonction d'une utilisation comme  électrode transparente. L'oxyde de graphène a été fabriqué par la méthode de Hummers modifié puis a été transféré sur un substrat arbitraire par la méthode de filtration avec suction à vide, et a été réduit chimiquement et thermiquement pour créer des feuilles d'oxyde de graphène réduit qui sont minces et qui couvrent une grande surface. Les feuilles ont été caractérisées par des mesures électriques, optiques, spectroscopiques, et topographiques. Les spectroscopies  Raman et par photoélectron induits par rayons-X ont été utilisées pour s'assurer que la fabrication de l'oxyde de graphène reduit a été obtenue. Les électrodes d'oxyde de graphène reduit montrent des résistances de feuille de 10– 100 kΩ/sq avec des transparences entre 60 – 90 %. Pour améliorer ces propriétés, des nanotube de carbone monoparois ont été introduits pendant le processus de filtration pour séparer les nanoplatelets d'oxyde de  graphène et pour éviter la déformation structurelle pendant la processus de réduction. Ce dopage de nanotubes a diminué la résistance de feuille par un facteur deux pour des proportion faibles de nanotubes avec l'oxyde de graphène, mais a augmenté la resistance pour les hautes proportions. Les électrodes d'oxyde de graphène reduit et les électrodes hybrides nanotubes/oxyde de graphène reduit ont été utilisées dans des dispositifs optoélectroniques organiques; spécialement des diodes électroluminescentes et des cellules solaires. Les diodes électroluminescentes organiques ont des rendements de courant inferieurs à 1 cd/A et les cellules solaire ont des rendements de puissance inferieurs à 1 % pour les deux types d'életrodes: oxyde de graphène réduit et hybrides.</description><description>This thesis explores the utility of reduced graphene oxide and hybrid reduced graphene oxide/single walled carbon nanotubes as a transparent electrode. Graphene oxide was fabricated using the modified Hummers method, transferred to arbitrary substrates by a vacuum filtration method, and reduced chemically and thermally thus creating thin, large area reduced graphene oxide films. Films were characterized electrically, optically, spectroscopically, and topographically. Raman and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy techniques were utilized to ensure successful fabrication of reduced graphene oxide. The reduced graphene oxide electrodes exhibit sheet resistances on the order of 10 – 100 kΩ/sq with transparencies between 60 – 90 %. To ameliorate these electronic properties, single walled nanotubes were introduced during the filtration process to separate the graphene oxide nanoplatelets and prevent structural deformation during reduction. This nanotube doping yielded a two-fold decrease in sheet resistance for low nanotube to graphene oxide ratios, but increased sheet resistance for higher nanotube to graphene oxide ratios. Reduced graphene oxide electrodes and nanotube/reduced graphene oxide hybrid electrodes were used in organic light emitting diode and organic solar cell applications. Organic light emitting diodes exhibited current efficiencies of about 1 cd/A and organic solar cells exhibited power conversion efficiencies less than 1 % for both reduced graphene oxide and hybrid electrodes.</description><creator>Chari, Tarun</creator><contributor>Ishiang Shih (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Ricardo Izquierdo (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Reduced graphene oxide based transparent electrodes for organic electronic devices</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sp53t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j6731818c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):37025</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>