<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:12:33Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):5725" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53wz267</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis is a test of Eric Nordlinger's Conflict Regulation in Divided Societies. Nordlinger's theory of how communal conflicts are regulated puts emphasis on the ability of elites to overcome hostility at the nonelite level in order to voluntarily regulate communal conflict, among themselves. If there is structured elite predominance and political security of elites with respect to second-rank leaders, elites are able to act on conflict regulating motives in order to regulate conflict through six conflict regulating practices. An alternative model, which nuts emphasis on the issues and on nonelite characteristics, is presented. The theory is tested using case studies of Austria, Lebanon, and Malaysia, three of the six cases Nordlinger uses to illustrate the theory. These case studies suggest that conflict regulation occurs in a manner more often closer to the alternative model than to Nordlinger's model.</description><description>The thesis is a test of Eric Nordlinger's Conflict Regulation in Divided Societies. Nordlinger's theory of how communal conflicts are regulated puts emphasis on the ability of elites to overcome hostility at the nonelite level in order to voluntarily regulate communal conflict, among themselves. If there is structured elite predominance and political security of elites with respect to second-rank leaders, elites are able to act on conflict regulating motives in order to regulate conflict through six conflict regulating practices. An alternative model, which nuts emphasis on the issues and on nonelite characteristics, is presented. The theory is tested using case studies of Austria, Lebanon, and Malaysia, three of the six cases Nordlinger uses to illustrate the theory. These case studies suggest that conflict regulation occurs in a manner more often closer to the alternative model than to Nordlinger's model.</description><creator>Olson, Lorayn Ellen.</creator><date>1977</date><subject>Social control.</subject><subject>Social conflict.</subject><title>Regulation of communal conflict : a test of Nordlinger’s theory using the cases of Austria, Lebanon and Malaysia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qs09g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wz267</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8p58pg467</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This is a thesis of vitalist poetry. The poems are divided into five sequences: each sequence explores one of the various phases of the vitalist quest. The desperation of the quest is shown to be in direct proportion to modern, technologically orientated life-styles. The quest is a quest for roots; vital roots, which are found in organic rather than technological environments. The quest is often realized by a regression to primitive life forms or to earlier time periods. The quest for vital roots can never fully succeed, because the regression to the past is never permanent: the quester must still confront the exigencies of the present. The introductory essay presents the history of vitalism, first seen as a biological movement: approaching World War I vitalist criteria are applied to philosophy. I then take the essential vitalist criteria and apply them to poetry, and show, by examining the poetry of D.H. Lawrence through Dylan Thomas to Ted Hughes, that there is a vitalist movement in modern poetry.</description><description>Cette thèse traite de poésie vitaliste. Les poèmes sont divisés en cinq parties. Chaque partie explore une des différentes phases de la recherche vitaliste. Ce besoin de recherche s'avère être en proportion directe avec les modes de vie modernes, orientées vers la technologie. C'est avant tout une recherche de sources; les sources vitales que'on trouve plutôt dans des environnements organiques technologiques. Cette recherche ressemble souvent à une régression vers des formes de vie plus primitives ou encore plus éloignées. Mais la recherche des sources vitales ne peut jamais réussir complètement car le retour au passé n'est jamais permanent. Le chercheur doit toujours répondre aux exigences du présent. Cet essai introductif raconte l’histoire du vitalisme, qui a d'abord été considéré comme un mouvement biologique. A  l’approche de la première guerre mondiale les critères vitalistes ont été appliqués à la philosophie. Je prendrai ensuite les critères vitalistes essentiels et les appliquerai à la poésie. Je démontrerai, en examinant la poésie de D.H. Lawrence a Ted Eughes, en passant par Dylan Thomas, que le mouvement vitaliste existe dans la poésie moderne.</description><creator>Lewis, Robert Joseph.</creator><contributor>Professor Alan Heuser</contributor><date>1977</date><subject>Poetry.</subject><title>The life and times of head : a book of poems with an introduction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t1736.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pg467</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d250b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Une synthèse de glycosides et de disaccharides a été connue et élaborée. Cette synthèse procède par la réaction d'un hydrate de carbone possédant un groupe hydroxyle a la position anomérique avec de l'anhydride trifluorométhanesulfonique en présence de collidine et d'ions bromures, réaction par laquelle un bromure de glycosyle est forme in situ. Les conditions réactionnelles permettent l'usage de groupes protecteurs instables a l'acide tel les acétals acycliques (p. ex. OCH(OC2H5)cH3), acétals cycliques ou groupement 0-trityle. Des D-glucosides, D-mannosides et D-ribosides ont été synthétisés par cette réaction. D'une part plusieurs disaccharides d'a-g-glucopyrannosyle ont été préparés avec des rendements élevés à partir de 2,3,4,6-tétra-Q-benzyl-D-glucose, d'autre part avec le 2,3,4,6-tétra-Q-acétyl-D-glucose, les produits sont des orthoesters dont un nouveau orthoester dimérique. Des glycosides ont également été obtenus par l'action de l'anhydride méthanesulfonique, tandis que les chlorures de méthanesulfonyle et de p-toluènesulfonyle conduisent aux chlorures de glycosyles. [...]</description><description>A synthesis of glycosides and disaccharides has been devised, based on the reaction of a carbohydrate derivative that bears a free anomeric hydroxyl group with trifluoromethanesulfonic anhydride in the presence of collidine and bromide ion, whereby a glycosyl bromide is generated in situ. Under the conditions employed, acid-sensitive blocking groups may be used including cyclic acetals, acyclic acetals such as OCH(OC2H5)cH3 , and Q-trityl. D-Glucosides, D-mannosidcs, and D-ribosides have been synthesized in this fashion. Several a-D-glucopyranosyl disaccharides have been prepared in high yield from 2,3,4,6-tetra-Q-benzyl-D-glucose, whereas with 2,3,4,6-tetra-O-acetyl-D-glucose the products are orthoacetates, including a novel dimeric orthoester. Methanesulfonic anhydride promotes glycosidation in the absence of bromide ions. Methanesulfonyl and p-toluenesulfonyl chlorides afford glycosyl chlorides. Two routes to l-Q-acyl-aldoses have been examined. These involve the reaction of a carboxylic acid with a 1,2-cyclic orthoester, or with a carbohydrate bearing a free anomeric hydroxyl group in the presence of tri fluoroacetic anhydride.</description><creator>Leroux, Jacques.</creator><contributor>Professor A. S. Perlin</contributor><date>1977</date><subject>Glycosides.</subject><title>Synthesis of glycosides, glycosyl halides and glycosyl esters</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v806h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d250b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dz010s60p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La matière de cette thèse représente un examen compréhensif des accords bilatéraux conclus par la Finlande dans le domaine des transports aériens. Après une revue des règlements de droit aérien international et national pertinents sont présentées dans une bonne mesure les circonstances spécifiquement finlandaises déterminant en grande partie le contenu des accords bilatéraux. La partie principale de cette thèse consiste en une analyse détaillée des divers accords sur les transports aériens auxquels la Finlande a souscrit. Certaines clauses des de ces accords, telles celles relatives à la fréquence et à la capacité font l’objet d’une étude minutieuse, alors que les autres sont examinées sur un plan plus général. La politique actuelle de la Finlande appliquée a la mise en œuvre de ses accords bilatéraux ainsi que les tendances futures probables de la politique finlandaise en matière de transports aériens internationaux sont ensuite discutées en détail. En conclusion, un bilan des accords bilatéraux finlandaises est établi et il est fait une tentative d’évaluer les conclusions à la lumière des besoins de la Finlande dans le domaine des transports aériens.</description><description>The substance of this thesis represents a comprehensive examination of bilateral air transport agreements concluded by Finland. Following a survey of the relevant international and national air law regulations, the specific Finnish circumstances which largely determine the content of the bilateral agreements are canvassed at some length. The main portion of the thesis consists of a detailed analysis of the individual air transport agreements entered into by Finland. Certain key provisions of these agreements, such as those relating to frequency and capacity, have been subjected to closer scrutiny, while the others are examined in more general terms. The current policies of Finland in the implementation of its bilaterals and probable future trends in international air transport policies of the country are next discussed in detail. In conclusion, a balance-sheet of the Finnish bilaterals is drawn up and an attempt is made to evaluate the findings in light of Finland’s needs in international air transport.</description><creator>Lehtonen, Lasse Oskari Johannes.</creator><date>1977</date><subject>Law</subject><title>The bilateral air transport agreements of Finland : a study in public international air law</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644v08x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010s60p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386m938</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis consists of four separate manuscripts. Manuscript I is an historical introduction and evaluative review of gender identity and gender role in schizophrenia. Manuscripts II and III revalidate parts of the Terman-Miles M-F Test and several nonverbal sex-differentiating tasks. The final manuscript compares recently-admitted affective disorders, noninstitutionalized controls, recently-admitted nonparanoid schizophrenics, and long-term nonparanoid schizophrenics. Appropriate gender differences emerge on tests of gender identity and gender-role adoption. And schizophrenics have neither a faulty gender-role knowledge nor a differential perception of gender-role reinforcement by parents or hospital staff. But schizophrenics do prefer more opposite sex roles.</description><description>Cette thèse consiste en quatre manuscrits séparés. Le manuscrit I est une introduction historique et une revue qui évalue l'identité des genres et du rôle des genres en schizophrénie. Les manuscrits II et III rendent valables des extraits des tests Terman-Miles M-F et plusieurs essais non verbaux de différentiation des sexes. Le dernier manuscrit compare les individus récemment admis pour désordres affectifs et pour schizophrénie non-paranoïde ainsi que les cas de schizophrénie non-paranoïde interne depuis un certain nombre d'années et enfin un groupe contrôle d'individus sains. Les différences convenables apparaissent dans deux tests d'identité de genres et deux tests d'adoption du rôle de genres. Aussi, les schizophrènes n'ont pas d'une mauvaise connaissance du rôle attribue aux différents sexes ni d’une perception différente du renforcement accompagnant ces rôles par les parents ou le personnel de l'hôpital. Mais les schizophrènes préfèrent le rôle du sexe oppose.</description><creator>LaTorre, Ronald A.</creator><date>1977</date><subject>Sex role.</subject><subject>Schizophrenia.</subject><title>Gender identity and gender role in schizophrenia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354h79x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386m938</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50gz701</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A mathematical approach to the scheduling of a cement plant using the discrete maximum principle is presented. The model takes into account the plant's power consumption, expected sales demand, and storage capacities. The plant storage silo levels are the state variables and the various operating departments constitute the control elements. The objective is to generate a daily operating schedule, over a period of one month that is in some sense optimal; that is, production is maximized while all operational priorities are met. The constraints on the state variables are transformed into control saturation constraints. Convergence of the two point boundary value problem is achieved by carrying out the simulation in backward time and conducting a search over the final values of the state. The technique produces feasible schedules which are near optimal.</description><description>On présente une solution mathématique de la cédule d'une cimenterie par la méthode du principe du maximum discrétisé. Le modèle utilisé tient compte de la consommation d'énergie, du niveau des ventes et de la capacité de stockage. Les variables d'état sont les niveaux des divers unités de stockage, et les commandes sent les variables décisionnelles d'opération des unités de production. Le but est de générer une cédule d'opération, valable pour une période d'un mois, qui soit optimale en un certain sens: plus précisément, il s'agit de maximiser le produit disponible à la fin du mois tout en respectant des contraintes sur la puissance consommée ainsi que certaines contraintes opérationnelles. Les contraintes sur les états sont transformées en contraintes sur les commandes. Le problème avec condition aux limites à deux points est résolu par une méthode de recherche dans l’espace des valeurs terminales de l'état. On produit des cédules qui sont pratiquement réalisables.</description><creator>Koffler, Ady.</creator><contributor>Dr. P. Bélanger</contributor><date>1977</date><subject>Cement plants.</subject><title>An optimal control approach to the scheduling of a cement plant</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q6760.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gz701</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cf95jd756</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ce travail étudie la langue du commerce au Canada français de 1841 à 1867. Pour commencer, il montre que les Anglais exercent une grande influence sur les Français au Canada en ce qui concerne le commerce en général. La question centrale qui se pose dans toute la thèse est la suivante : est-ce que cette prédominance des Anglais sur les Canadiens-français dans le commerce se reflète dans le vocabulaire du commerce? Dans chaque chapitre, un aspect de la langue commerciale est étudié afin de déterminer quelle sorte d’élément représente la langue anglaise dans la langue franco-canadienne. Le travail porte sur les différents commerces, métiers et professions, les produits commerciaux, les termes de mesure, les moyens de transport, et les termes généraux du commerce. La conclusion est que la langue anglaise pénètre très peu la langue franco-canadienne contrairement à ce que la situation du commerce pourrait laisser croire à priori.</description><description>This essay studies the language dealing with commerce in French Canada from 1841 to 1867. It starts by showing that the English greatly influence the French regarding business in general. The main question put forth throughout the thesis is the following: Does this English dominance over the French-Canadians in commerce reflect in the commercial vocabulary? In each chapter one aspect of the commercial vocabulary is studied to decide what sort of role the English language plays in the French language. The thesis deals with different businesses, trades and professions, commercial products, measurements, ways of transportation, and general terms. The conclusion is that the English language penetrates the French language in Canada quite little in spite of what the commercial situation itself would suggest.</description><creator>Jordan, Marilyn Trudy.</creator><date>1977</date><subject>Québec (Province) -- Commerce.</subject><subject>Language.</subject><title>La langue du commerce au Canada français (1841-1867)</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m200m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jd756</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d251m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The seasonal variation patterns of sorbitol and the related carbohydrates namely, fructose, glucose, sucrose and starch were compared in the leaves of Standard McIntosh, Spur McIntosh cultivar ‘Morspur' and Spur Red Delicious cultivar 'Bisbee' and in the fruit during development and storage at ± 1 Oc. of both Standard and Spur McIntosh. Analyses of the sorbitol and sugars by gas chromatography showed a gradual accumulation of sorbitol in leaves of the three cultivars during the active growth period (July). In general, sorbitol was the major carbohydrate constituent of the leaves throughout the period from active growth in June to dormancy in October. This suggests that sorbitol was the major photosynthetically derived carbohydrate and it has a central role in the carbohydrate metabolism in apple leaves. In the leaves of the three cultivars, sorbitol concentration did not differ significantly. The percentages of dry weight were, however, higher in both spur-type leaves than in those of Standard. [...]</description><description>Les variations saisonnières de la teneur en sorbitol et en autres glucides, tels que le fructose, le glucose, le sucrose, et l’amidon, ont été observées dans les feuilles et les fruits des cultivars McIntosh et Red Delicious. Les différents types comparés sont les types Standard et Spur(Morspur) de la McIntosh et le type spur (Bisbee) de la Red Delicious. Seuls les fruits de la McIntosh ont été étudiés, ceci au cours de leur croissance sur l'arbre, et de leur entreposage à ± 1 Oc. De l’analyse chromatographique des tissus prélevés, il ressort que le sorbitol s’accumule progressivement dans les feuilles des trois types à l'étude au cours de la période de croissance active (juillet). Tout au long de la saison, le sorbitol domine généralement les autres formes d'hydrates de carbone mesures. [...]</description><creator>Ismail, Hoda A.</creator><date>1977</date><subject>Apples.</subject><subject>Sorbitol.</subject><title>A comparative study of sorbitol and related carbohydrates in standard and spur strains of Malus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v8383106.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d251m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w9505291r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Corticotropin 1-39, 1-24, 1-16 amid and a-MSH all stimulated adrenal steroidogenesis but the activity decreased with chain length. In the mouse adrenal they also markedly enhanced glycolysis. The ratio of glycolysis to steroidogenesis was disproportionally high with a-MSH indicating a dissociation between the two responses. A striking species difference occurred in the responses to cAMP and cGMP: both stimulated adrenal steroidogenesis in the rat, while cGMP stimulated it in the rat but inhibited it in the mouse. AME, GMP, adenosine, guanosine and inosine, tested in the mouse, were glycolytically more active than cGMP, but less active than cAMP. They did not stimulate steroidogenesis. Nucleotides as well as peptides can therefore contribute non steroid-mediated components to adrenal glycolysis. [...]</description><description>Les composés corticotropin 1-39, 1-24, 1-16 amide et l'a-MSH stimulent la stéroïdogénèse, mais leur activité décroît avec la longueur de leur chaîne. Chez la souris, ils produisent aussi un accroissement marqué de la glycolyse dans les surrénales; Le rapport glycolyse-stéroïdogénèse est disproportionnellement élevé avec l'a-MSH, indiquant une dissociation des deux réponses. Les réponses au cAMP et au cGMP sont grandement dépendantes de l'espèce: tous deux stimulent la stéroïdogénèse dans les surrénales du rat, alors que le cGMP la potentialise chez le rat mais l'inhibe chez la souris. L'AMP, le GMP, l'adénosine, la guanosine et l'inosine, expérimentés chez la souris,  accroissent la glycolyse plus que ne le fait le cGMP, mais moins que le cAMP. Ils ne stimulent pas la stéroïdogénèse. Par conséquent, nucléotides et peptides peuvent contribuer à la composante de la glycolyse surrénalienne qui n'est pas médiée par les stéroïdes. [...]</description><creator>Hum, Wah-Tung.</creator><contributor>Dr. Harion K. Birmingham</contributor><date>1977</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Adrenal aerobic glycolysis : effects of steroids, nucleotides, and ACTH derivatives</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jd76g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w9505291r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zg92g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>On a développé un programme d'ordinateur pour prédire l'écoulement et les caractéristiques de transfert thermique d'un jet circulaire tourbillonnant à écoulement laminaire s’impactant normalement sur un plan fixe. Dans la méthode de calcul, on a utilisé les équations de Navier-stokes dans sa forme primitive (pression vélocité) at l'équation de l'énergie exprimées à l'aide de la méthode des différences finies hybride. On a étudié l'importance numérique du nombre de Reynolds, de la distance entre l'orifice du jet et la surface réceptrice, du diamètre de la plaque, du nombre de tourbillon, de la forme du profil axial et tourbillonnant de vitesse supposé à l'orifice ajuteur et de l'application d’une succion/soufflage au niveau de la surface réceptrice. [...]</description><description>The flow and heat transfer under an impinging semi-confined laminae swirling jet was studied numerically. The computer program was based on a hybrid upwind finite differencing scheme for solving the Navier-Stokes equations in their primitive form (velocities and pressure) together with the energy equation. A parametric study was made which included the effects of plate spacing, plate diameter, Reynolds number, swirl number, inlet axial and swirl velocity profiles and suction/blowing at the impingement plate. It was found that the jet spreads faster with the addition of swirl. The spreading is related to the swirl number and the inlet swirl velocity profile. The use of a flat inlet axial velocity also enhances the spreading to some extent. When the swirl number is sufficiently large, a toroidal recirculation region situated next to the impingement plate was observed. This closed region insulates the plate from direct heat transfer from the jet, therefore reducing the local Stanton number at the stagnation point significantly. [...]</description><creator>Huang, Bing.</creator><date>1977</date><subject>Heat -- Transmission.</subject><subject>Jets -- Fluid dynamics.</subject><title>Prediction of flow and heat transfer under a laminar swirling impinging jet</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05ff378.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zg92g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77fv052</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study deals with the organization of civil aviation in Bangladesh and the laws governing air transport activities of that country. Although Bangladesh is the eighth most populous country in the world, outside that region of Asia very little is known about it. For that reason the present author felt justified in introducing his thesis with a brief outline of the birth of Bangladesh, its physical environment, demography and general economic conditions. Chapter 2 provides an overview of the transport and communication systems. Chapter 3 examines the legal and managerial structure of Bangladesh Biman - the national air carrier. In Chapter 4 the degree of control by various government departments concerned with air transport is dealt with. Chapter S contains a review of the laws governing civil aviation activities in Bangladesh while chapter 6 provides a survey of air navigation facilities in the country. [...]</description><description>Cette étude traite de l’aviation civile au Bangladesh, et des règlements qui gouvernent les activités de transport aérien dans ce pays. Bien que le Bangladesh soit un des huit pays les plus peuplés du monde, on connait bien peu de chose à son sujet en dehors de ses frontières. C’est pour cette raison que l’auteur a jugé utile de placer dans l’introduction de sa thèse un bref historique de la naissance du Bangladesh, une description de la géographe, démographie et de ses conditions économiques. Le chapitre 2 donne un aperçu du réseau de transport et communications. Le chapitre 3 examine la structure juridique et administrative de ‘‘Bangladesh-biman’’ – la compagnie aérienne nationale. [...]</description><creator>Hossain, Ismail.</creator><contributor>Prof. Ivan A. Vlasic</contributor><date>1977</date><subject>Law</subject><title>Civil aviation in Bangladesh : organization-law-prospects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50gz719.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fv052</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jd472z881</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le sujet de cette thèse applique la théorie d’information à l'analyse et à la composition de la musique. Les sections initiales de la thèse introduisent le musicien à la théorie; elles décrivent six concepts de la théorie d'information choisis pour leur valeur dans l'application musicale. Ceux-ci comprennent  l'information, le processus "stochastic" (incluant les sources "ergodic" et les chaines Markov), l'entropie, la redondance, la capacité du canal et le bruit. Les sections qui suivent décrivent le champ des applications existantes et les sections conclusives traitent des critiques se rapportant à  de telles applications. Comme illustration, les démonstrations de la théorie d'information, se rapportant à l’analyse et à la génération, sont présentées l’incluant l'original d'une composition sur bande magnétique, basé sur les principes énoncés dans cette thèse.</description><description>The subject of this thesis is the application of information theory to the analysis and composition of music. Designed as an introduction to the theory for the musician, the initial sections of the thesis describe six concepts from information theory selected for their value in musical application. These are information, stochastic process (including ergodic sources and Markov chains), entropy, redundancy, channel capacity and noise. The next sections describe the range of existing applications and the concluding sections deal with the criticisms of such applications. As illustration, demonstrations of information theory analysis and generation are offered, including an original tape composition based on the principles outlined in this thesis.</description><creator>Gotfrit, Martin S. (Martin Stephen)</creator><date>1977</date><subject>Style, Musical.</subject><subject>Information theory in music.</subject><title>Style in music seen as restraint : an information theory approach</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qs107.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd472z881</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Communications</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hq37vq99j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le De ornatu spiritualium nuptiarum, traduction latine de Die qeestelike brulocht de Jean Ruysbroeck par Guillaume Jordaens, est une œuvre remarquable du bas moyen âge. Remarquable en elle-même et comme exemple de l'art de traduction, l'œuvre est importante aussi dans l'histoire de la théologie mystique, parce que c’est la version du texte de Ruysbroeck lue et censurée par Jean Gerson. En présentant l'édition critique de cette œuvre—le but principal ces recherches--on a pris l'occasion de clarifier les circonstances dans lesquelles la traduction vit le jour et sa position dans l'affaire Gerson-Ruysbroeck. L’édition se sert de onze manuscrits et l'imprime de 1512. Les complexités de la tradition textuelle de la Brulocht--qu'attestent non seulement l’édition Ruusbroec-Genootschap mais aussi les manuscrits néerlandais inédits et les traductions en dialectes germaniques et en latin--sont expliquées et respectées.</description><description>The De ornatu spiri tualiurn nuptiarum, William Jordaens's translation of John Ruysbroek's Die geestelike brulocht, is an outstanding work of late mediaeval Latin literature. Noteworthy both in itself and as an example of the art of translation, the text is also important in the history of mystical theology, for it is the version of Ruysbroek's treatise read and censured by Jean Gerson. The main purpose of the research presented here has been to produce a critical edition of the text itself, but opportunity has been taken to clarify the circumstances of its composition and its position in the Gerson-Ruysbroek controversy. The edition is based on eleven manuscripts and the printed edition of 1512. The textual complexities of the Netherlandic Brulocht—as reflected not only in the RuusbroecGenootschap edition but also in the unedited Netherlandic manuscripts and the Germanic and Latin translations—have been described and respected.</description><creator>Desoer, Bernard, d. 1999.</creator><date>1977</date><subject>Jordaens, William. De ornatu spiritualium nuptiarum.</subject><subject>Ruusbroec, Jan van, 1293-1381. Gheestelike brulocht.</subject><title>William Jordaens’s De ornatu spiritualium nuptiarum : a critical edition and introduction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579v788.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vq99j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82k9834</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In seven natural populations of Mytilus edulis, between Newfoundland and Virginia, oxygen consumption and shell growth were measured over a period of 15 months. Seasonal variation in oxygen consumption followed: the seasonal variation in temperature at each station (maximum in summer, minimum in winter), except at above optimum (20°C) temperatures. Latitudinal differences in oxygen consumption rates were also temperature related, with the warmest stations {southern) producing the highest rates throughout the year. Average shell growth followed a similar pattern to that of oxygen consumption, but with complications possibly caused by food availability, especially at midlatitude stations. Growth history and life table characteristics varied over the latitudinal range. No seasonal or latitudinal acclimation (Precht Type II) of oxygen consumption or growth was demonstrated.</description><description>La consommation d'oxygène et la croissance de la coquille ont été mesurées sur sept populations naturelles de Mytilus edulis vivant entre Terre-Neuve et la Virginie au cours d'une période de quinze mois. À chaque station, la variation saisonnière dans la consommation d'oxygène suit la variation thermique (maximum en été, minimum en hiver) sauf au-dessus d'une température optimale de 20°C. Les différences entre latitudes dans la consumation d'oxygène sont elles aussi liées à la température, les taux les plus élevés s'observant aux stations les plus chaudes (stations au sud). En moyenne la croissance de la coquille suit la même courbe que la consommation d'oxygène, mais avec des irrégularités qui s'expliquent peut-être par la disponibilité en nourriture, particulièrement pour les stations situées aux latitudes moyennes. Le déroulement de la croissance et les caractéristiques vitales varient dans l'intervalle de latitude. Aucune acclimation saisonnière ou latitudinale (type II de Precht) de la consommation d'oxygène ou de la croissance n'a été démontrée.</description><creator>Hum, Jennifer Roslyn.</creator><date>1976</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>Oxygen consumption and growth of Mytilus edulis on the Atlantic coast of North America, south of Newfoundland</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956j42m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k9834</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Marine Sciences Centre</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225d60f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le tassement d'une fondation reposant sur un milieu semi-infini d'argile remaniée, dans les conditions de déformation planaire, est simule en laboratoire. Les déplacements d'éléments traceurs et les mesures ponctuelles de pressions interstitielles au cours des essais favorisent une étude de comparaison et une critique des principales théories ou méthodes employées actuellement dans la pratique de la mécanique des sols et des fondations pour l'analyse des tassements. [...]</description><description>English abstract omitted.</description><creator>Garzon, Maurice M.</creator><contributor>Dr. R. D. Japp</contributor><date>1976</date><subject>Soil consolidation.</subject><subject>Foundations.</subject><title>A model footing study of consolidation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483m69f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225d60f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445cg892</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette étude avait pour but d’appliquer les principes de conditionnement opérant dans le cadre des sessions d’apprentissage de Basketball. Plus spécifiquement l’étude visait d’une part à augmenter les comportements appropriés et diminuer les comportements non-appropriés des étudiants, et d'autre part à améliorer les habilités en Basketball en utilisant des renforçateurs sociaux et matériels donnes par le professeur. [...]</description><description>The purpose of this study is to apply the principles of operant psychology within the scope of Basketball learning sessions. More specifically, the main objective was to increase the frequency of students' appropriate behavior and decrease the frequency of inappropriate behaviors, as well as to improve basic Basketball skills by using social and material reinforces provided by the teacher. [...]</description><creator>Der Sarkissian, Hratch.</creator><contributor>Dr. D. Q. Marisi</contributor><date>1976</date><subject>Basketball</subject><title>Modification de comportements sociaux en éducation physique par des renforçateurs extrinsèques</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237hv172.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cg892</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gf06g519c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Behavior modification methods have increasingly employed covertprocedures. However, objective measurement of covert processes continuesto pose a difficult problem for research.Comparison of saliva elicited by food stimuli presented externallywith the amount elicited when imagining the same food providedobjective measures of imagining and vividness of imagination.Covert conditioning was demonstrated by (1) inhibition of salivationafter paired presentations of stimuli in imagination and (2)change in weight after covert reinforcement.Covert conditioning.was significantly related to weight changebut contributed to only a small portion of the total variance in weightchange. Vividness of imagination was not related to treatment effects.Results supported the assumption that covert processes obey thesame principles as do observable processes. However, they did notsupport the assumption that conditioning is the'principal ingredientin covert behavior modification procedures or that vividness ofimagination is related to effectiveness of covert procedures.Results were more plausibly explained by covert self-modelingand social reinforcement.</description><description>Les méthodes d'évaluation du changement dans le comportement ont convergé de plus en plus sur l’étude des processus du covert. Cependant la mesure objective de ces processus continue de poser un problème difficile pour la recherche. La comparaison de la salive secrétée par des stimuli de nourriture présentes à la vue, avec la quantité produite sous l’influence de l’imagination de cette nourriture à donné des mesures objectives de l’imaginer et de la vivacité de l’imagination. Le conditionnement du covert a été démontré par (l) l'ingurgitation de salive après conjugaison de présentations de stimuli à l'imagination et (2) le changement de poids après le renforcement du covert. Le conditionnant du covert était définitivement en rapport avec le changement de poids, mais ne contribua qu’en une faible part à la variation totale du changement de poids. La vivacité de l'imagination n'avait rien à faire avec les effets du traitement. Les résultats obtenus ont confirmé la supposition admise que les processus du covert obéissent aux mêmes lois que celles des processus observables. Cependant, ils ne corroborent pas la supposition que le conditionnement soit le principal ingrédient de la modification des procédures de comportement du covert, ni que la vivacité de l’imagination influe sur l'efficacité des procédures du covert. Les résultats s'expliquent de façon plus plausible par l’auto modelage ou le renforcement social.</description><creator>Derby, Wilfrid N.</creator><contributor>Dr. Ernest G. Poser</contributor><date>1976</date><subject>Behavior modification.</subject><subject>Conditioned response.</subject><title>Behavioral concomitants of covert processes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75rb36m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g519c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354h80p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le but de cette thèse est de clarifier l'affinité littéraire souvent présumée entre Franz Kafka et Robert Walser. Les relations n'ont été décrites jusqu'à présent qu'en termes généraux. Mon essai est basé principalement sur l’analyse comparative d’un roman de chaque auteur (Amerika et Jakob von Guhten). Chaque roman et l'appréciation critique regardant chaque auteur sont analysés en profondeur dans les chapitres séparés, après quoi une conclusion finale originale est tentée. Quatre questions fondamentales qui s'entrecroisent déterminant la structure de ce travail. Elles se rapportent à: 1) la structure et les méthodes narratives, 2) la lutte des héros et le problème allié de la conscience, 3) le lien entre le héros et la société, et 4) le langage. Les conclusions révèlent une affinité entre les deux écrivains plus complexe qu'elle n'avait été estimée plus tôt. Jakob von Gunten contient un caractère subjectif inexistant dans l'œuvre de Kafka; l'enchainement de la narration, la conception de la lutte des héros en relation avec la société, et l'usage de la langue et de l'ironie par les deux auteurs tendent à être reliés.</description><description>English version omitted.</description><creator>Collins, Norbert J.</creator><date>1976</date><subject>Kafka, Franz, 1883-1924. Amerika.</subject><subject>Walser, Robert, 1878-1956. Jakob von Gunten.</subject><title>Franz Kafka’s Amerika and Robert Walser’s Jakob von Gunten : a comparative analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04ds086.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354h80p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of German</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j364x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Reichs Marine Amt (RMA) Chinapolitik marked the first attempt ofthe German navy to involve itself in international affairs. OfficialReich China policy was passive: the government did not interferein Oriental probelms and allowed any Sino-German links to beforged by the commercial community. The RMA had a two-foldreason for challenging this policy -- it wished to occupy astrategic FlottenstU.tzpunkt in North China from which the dominationof Shantung could eventually be directed. Despite officialopposition to this scheme, the RMA continued to plan for themilitary occupation of Kiaochow until the murder of the missionariesin November, 1897 forced the Reich to agree to intervention in North China. After the seizure, the RMA was able to gain administrativecontrol of the protectorate, largely because the "crisis of initiative"in the German government meant that resistence to this move wasalmost non-existent. Thus the government lost its grip on thedetermination of Sino-German affairs and the RMA realized itsgoals for the establishment of a navy-dominated sphere in the Orient.</description><description>La politique Chinoise du RMA marqua la première tentative de laMarine Allemande de s'engager dans des affaires internationales.La politique Chinoise-Allemande officielle etait passive; legouvernement n'intervenait pas dans des problèmes orientaux etpermetta toutes liaisons (Chinoise-Allemande) à être forgées parla communauté cornrnerciale. Le RMA avait deux raisons à seplier l'à-dessus pour defier cette politique, elle désirait occuperun Flottenstützpunkt stratégique dans la Chine du Nord d'ou ladomination de Shantung pouvait être dirigée. Malgré l'oppositionofficielle a ce plan, le RMA continua à planifier pour l'occupationmilitaire de Kiaochow jusqu'à l'assassinat des missionaires ennovembre, 1897 qui força le Reich à accepter l'intervention dans laChine du Nord. Après la prise de possession, le RMA était capablede gagner le control administratif du protectorat, en grande partieà cause de ''la crise de l'initiative" qui, au gouvernement allemandsignifiait que la resistance à ce mouvement n'existait pas. Ainsile gouvernement perdit control de la situation en determinant lesaffaires "(Chinoise-Allemande) et le RMA realisa ses buts pourl'etablissement de ses influences a la domination-Marine" enOrient.</description><creator>Waring, Patricia N.</creator><date>1975</date><subject>Germany -- History, Naval.</subject><subject>China -- History -- Guangxu, 1875-1908.</subject><title>The approach of the Reichs Marine Amt to Chinapolitik, 1894-1897</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p7298.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j364x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q524jr314</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A diagnostic index for a syndrome can be devised from the frequency of features in individuals with and without the syndrome. When logs of the weighted features are summed, the distribution of total log scores of those with the syndrome differs from that of controls, and is unimodal. If the syndrome etiology were unknown some suspects might not have the syndrome, and the distribution would be bimodal. To test this, suspects for a syndrome of known etiology (Down) were used to construct an index; the resulting distribution was bimodal. Scores of suspects without the syndrome (proven by karyotyping) simulated the control distribution. Results for an index based on individuals suspected of having a syndrome of unknown etiology (de Lange) were similar, suggesting that the suspects included patients with and without the syndrome, most of whom are categorized by the index.  The method can be profitably extended to other "idiopathic" syndromes.</description><description>Un index diagnostique pour un syndrome peut etre derivede la frequence des caracteristiques chez des individus avec ou sansle syndrome. Lorsque les logarithmes des caracteristiques pondereessont additionnes, la distribution des resultats logarithmiques totauxde ceux atteints du syndrome differe de celle des temoins et estunimodale. Si l'etiologie du syndrome etait inconnue, quelques suspectspourraient ne pas avoir le syndrome et la distribution seraitbimodale. Pour prouver ce point, des suspects pour un syndromed'etiologie connue (syndrome de Down) ont ete employes pour construireun index; la distribution resultante etait bimodale. Les resultatsdes suspects sans le syndrome (prouves par le karyotype) simulaient ladistribution controle. Les resultats pour un index base sur desindividus soup~onnes d'avoir un syndrome d'etiologie inconnue (syndromede De Lange) ont ete similaires, suggerant que le groupe de suspectscomprenait des patients avec et sans le syndrome, la plupart etantcategorise par l'index. La methode peut etre appliquee avec profita d'autres syndromes "idiopatiques".</description><creator>Preus, Marilyn Ione</creator><contributor>Fraser, F. Clarke (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1975</date><subject>Syndromes.</subject><title>Identification of dysmorphogenic syndromes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52jb43s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jr314</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:41687k70b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study focusses on the part played by viol consorts in the musical education of the Englsh under Elizabeth I and James I. Influence of major secular forces and forces related to religious developments are considered insofar as they bear on the central problem of the paper. Little evidence of viol consorts in public schools can be found, but choir schools did provide some instruction. Tutorials and apprenticeships in guilds were other avenues of instruction. Principal conclusion is that viol conaorts were an important part of devotional and recreational music in the homes of wealthy amateurs from the last decade of the sixteenth century.Before that time the vehicle was important in the education of professional musicians and child choristers. Recommendations are made for future research.</description><description>Dans cette étude nous faisons l’examen du rôle des consorts de violes de gambe en éducation musicale durant les règnes d’Elizabeth I et de James I. Nous considérons les influences des milieux profanes et religieux qui ont trait au sujet. La viole de gambe était rarement enseigne dans les écoles publiques mais se trouvait dans quelques collèges de chant. Les meilleures façons de parfaire ses études de l'instrument étaient d’une part de suivre des cours privés, et d'autre part de s'inscrire dans un corps corporatif. Comme conclusion nous déduisons que l’ensemble des violes jouait un rôle  important dans l’interprétation de la musique profane et religieuse dans les maisons des amateurs fortunés à la fin du seizième siècle et au début du dix-septième siècle. Avant ce temps l'ensemble des violes servait à l'éducation des musiciens professionnels et des jeunes chantres. Ce travail ouvre la porte à des études ultérieures.</description><creator>Morris, Stephen M.</creator><contributor>Stoltzfus, Fred (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1986</date><subject>Music -- Instruction and study -- England -- 17th century -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Viol ensembles -- 17th century -- Instruction and study.</subject><subject>Viol ensembles -- 16th century -- Instruction and study.</subject><subject>Music -- Instruction and study -- England -- 16th century -- History and criticism.</subject><title>Viol consorts and music education in Elizabethan and Jacobean England, (1558-1625)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440w23w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687k70b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924f26q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>If studied in its broadest sense, that is, as the invention or creation of pure imagination, the fantasy in the Philosophic Tales of Voltaire reveals two structures, one unconscious and one conscious.On the unconscious level, fantasy creates three visions of the world which approximately reproduce the divisions of time: past, present, and future. The framework of these imaginary worlds is strengthened by the creation of myths, images, and symbols which all pertain to a voltarian imagery. In addition, there is an evolution of fantasy which follows closely the evolution of the author's life and thought.On the conscious level, Voltaire uses many stylistic and narrative devices which give the story schematization and humor; the role of fantasy is therefore limited to provide the reader with entertainment and evasion of reality through laughter. Fantasy, then, is always subjected to reason in the Tales, a.nd it is under the cover of fantasy that Voltaire expresses his philosophy of life.</description><description>En prenant le mot "fantaisie11 dans son sens le pluslarge, c'est-a-dire invention ou creation de !'imaginationpure, et en l'appliquant aux Contes, cette etude a degagedes structures conscientes et inconscientes dans la fantaisiede Voltaire. Au niveau de l'inconscient, la fantaisie cree troisvisions du monde qui reproduisent en gros les divisions dutemps: passe, present et futur. Ces mondes imaginairessont renforces par la creation de mythes, d'images et desymboles issus de l'imaginaire voltairien. On observeaussi une evolution dans la fantaisie qui suit de pres l'evolutionde la pensee et de la vie de Voltaire.Au niveau de la creation consciente, Voltaire inventedans ses "contes philosophiques" une forme et un style particuliersqui tendent vers la schematisation du recit etl'humour; le role de la fantaisie se limite alors a procurerau lecteur un divertissement ou une evasion par le rire.En somme, la fantaisie est toujours au service de laraison dans les Contes, et c'est sous le voile de la fantaisieque Voltaire exprime son ideologie.</description><creator>Ruble, Michèle F.</creator><date>1975</date><subject>Voltaire, 1694-1778. Contes.</subject><title>La fantaisie de Voltaire dans ses contes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s7374.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924f26q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf268775m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse étudie les divers facteurs qui ont conduit au coup d'état militaire au Chili le 11 septembre 1973, qui a renversé le gouvernement démocratiquement élu de l'Unidad Popular de Salvador Allende. De façon plus précise, elle tente d'expliquer pourquoi les militaires chiliens ont réussi à mettre un terme à cette expérience de transformation systémique, - à ce qu'on appelait la "voie Chilienne vers le socialisme." Étant donné que cette thèse est une analyse du changement social, il est nécessaire de prendre une approche qui est à la fois historique et théorique. La première partie de ce  travail tente de présenter le contexte historique du coup militaire, et de décrire les facteurs internes et externes, {i.e. domestiques et étrangers) qui ont joué un rôle dans la lutte pour le pouvoir.  Dans cette discussion, le rôle des militaires chiliens est d'une importance toute particulière. La seconde partie de la thèse s'efforce d'analyser de façon théorique les raisons pour lesquelles la voie  chilienne a conduit, non pas au socialisme, mais à un coup militaire.</description><description>This thesis explores the various factors which led to the September 11, 1973 military coup in Chile, which overthrew the democratically elected Unidad Popular government headed by Salvador Allende. It  pecifically attempts to answer why the Chilean military was able to prevent the government from carrying through that particular experiment in systems transformation--or what has been referred to asthe "Chilean road to socialism. Since this thesis is an analysis of social change, it is necessary to approach the study both historically and theoretically. The first part of the study attempts to present the historical context of the military coup and describe the domestic and foreign factors involved in the struggle for power. Of particular importance in this discussion is the role of the Chilean  ilitary. The second part'of the thesis attempts to analyze in theoretical terms why the Chilean road led not to socialism but to the military coup.</description><creator>Orlov, Stephen Robert</creator><date>1975</date><subject>Chile -- History -- Coup d’état, 1973.</subject><subject>Coups d’état.</subject><title>Systems transformation and the military coup : the case of Chile</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jr32d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268775m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1j92g983c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le lactoserum est un sous-produit hautement polluant lors de la fabrication fromagere. Une levure lactique. Kluyveromyces marxianus, est capable d' hydrolyser Ie lactose. Dans la presente recherche cette levure a ete mise it profit afin de reduire Ie potential polluant de ce derive et de produire des bioingredients it haute valeur ajoutee, teis que: oligonucleotides (ON), oligosaccharides (OS) et oligopeptides (OP). Lorsqu' ajoutes aux produits alimentaires, ces composes (i) rehaussent la saveur; (ii) stabilisent les emulsions; (iii) stimulent Ie systeme immunitaire; (iv) abaissent Ie taux de lipoproteines de basse densite (un facteur de risque qui peut provoquer des maladies cardiovasculaires) et (v) previennent Ie developpement des bacteries infectieuses dans les instestins chez l'human et chez l'animal monogastrique. Le but principal de notre recherche etait d' etudier la fermentation du lactoserum par K. marxianus, suivie par des traitements enzymatiques, afin d' extraire les ON des autolysats des levures, les OS des parois cellulaires et les OP des milieux fermentes. Les fermentations ont ete conduites en 'fed-batch', permettant ainsi d'eviter Ie phenomene d' inhibition par Ie substrat lactose. [...] Apres determination des poids moleculaires. les sequences d' acides amines pour deux peptides specifiques ont ete elucidees et comparees avec celles des peptides bioactifs connus. La presence d'un site contenant la sequence de la p-Iactorphin (YLLF) suggere que ces OP peuvent avoir des proprietes antihypertensives. En bref, la fermentation du lactoserum par K. marxianus est une alternative efficace pour la production de trois categories de bioingredients it. haute valeur technologique et nutritionelle.</description><description>Whey discharge is the largest pollutant in the dairy industry. Kluyveromyces marxianus is a dairy yeast that can hydrolyze lactose, reduce the pollution potential of whey, and produce high added-value bioingredients such as: oligonucleotides (ON), oligo saccharides (OS), and oligopeptides (OP). When added to foods, these compounds. (i) act as immunopotentiators; (ii) lower the low density lipoprotein-cholesterol (a risk for cardiovascular diseases); (iii) promote protection against bacterial infections~ (iv) enhance food flavors; and (v) stabilize food emulsions. The objective of this study was to develop a whey fermentation process using K. marxianus followed by enzymatic treatments to extract ON (from yeast autolysates), OS (from yeast cell walls), and OP (from fermented medium). To prevent growth inhibition by concentrated medium, fermentations were carried out in fed-batch.[...] The conversion of soluble proteins into hydrophilic and hydrophobic OP could also be detected. Major OP were collected and analyzed by a triple stage mass spectrometer Model API-ill. On the basis of their molecular weights, two amino acids sequences were proposed and compared with known sequences of bioactive peptides. The presence of sites containing the sequence of ~-lactorphin (YLLF) suggests that these OP may have antihypertensive properties.In summary, whey fermentation by K. marxianus proved to be an effective process to produce high added-value bioingredients.</description><creator>Belem, Márcio Abdalla Freire</creator><contributor>Lee, Byong Hoon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Whey.</subject><subject>Kluyveromyces marxianus.</subject><subject>Oligonucleotides.</subject><subject>Oligopeptides.</subject><subject>Oligosaccharides.</subject><title>Production of bioingredients from Kluyveromyces marxianus var. marxianus grown on whey</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h427f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g983c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m440r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:49:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In comparison with Controls that were never reinforced, rats reinforced with electrical stimulation of the brain (ESB) on interval and ratio schedules were observed to initiate responding faster without priming before each daily session; they also continued to respond for intermittent ESBs with no apparent difficulty, and persisted at responding during extinction, showing spontaneous recovery from one session to the next.ESB-reinforced rats ran faster in a runway with short intertrial intervals (ITIs) than with long ITIs while water- and sucrosereinforced rats tended to run faster with longer ITIs but all rats ran slower on the first trial of each session than on the last trial of the preceding day's session. In both paradigms, preceding the onset of ESB with a signal seemed to result in better environmental control of the response. All of these results with ESB reinforcement were observed in rats maintained on ad libitum food and water and were therefore interpreted as demonstrating hehavior based on an expectancy. In a final experiment expectancy-based responding was observed in non-deprived rats with a history of responding for foodwhile food-deprived. Theories which suggest that a homeostatic imbalance or organismic need is required to motivate behavior are inadequate to deal with these data.</description><description>Des rats renforcés par stimulation électrique du cerveau (SEC) sur des programmes d'intervalle et de rapport commençaient à répondre plus vite sans stimulation de préparation avant chaque session quotidienne, comparativement aux contrôles non stimules; de plus, ils continuaient à répondre pour des SECs intermittentes sans difficulté apparente, et persistaient à répondre durant l’extinction, démontrant une récupération  spontanée d'une session a l’autre. […] Dans une dernière expérience, le taux de réponse has~ sur l'attente a  été observé chez des rats non privés, possédant une histoire de renforcement par nourriture, alors qu'ils 6taicnt en 6tat de privation. Los théories qui suggèrent qu'un état d'imbalance homostatique ou de besoin organismique est requis pour motiver le compartement sont inadéquate pour expliquer ces données. </description><creator>Beninger, Richard J.</creator><date>1977</date><subject>Brain stimulation.</subject><subject>Rats -- Behavior.</subject><subject>Reinforcement (Psychology)</subject><title>Electrical stimulation of the brain as a reinforcing stimulus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365766w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m440r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):5750</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>