<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:54:41Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):950" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h702q834c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Late blight, caused by Septoria apiicola Speg., is the most important disease affecting celery in Quebec. Biological control was investigated as an alternative to conventional chemical control of late blight. Two hundred and four bacterial isolates were collected from celery leaves, and muck and mineral soils of celery fields in south-western Quebec. Two experiments were conducted to screen the bacteria for antagonism toward Septoria apiicola: one on agar to test for inhibition of pycnidial formation, and the other on leaf disks to test for inhibition of germination of conidia. From these two experiments, 18 isolates were selected that prevented pycnidial formation in an inhibition zone $ ge$1.0 cm wide and reduced germination to below 30% of the control. These isolates were re-evaluated for inhibition of germination on leaf disks. A bacterial suspension (10$ sp7$ cells/ml) was incubated on leaf disks for 24 hours before a suspension of S. apiicola conidia (150,000 spores/ml) was applied, and the disks were incubated for 25 hours. Four isolates reduced germination to $ le$19% of the control. These isolates were tested on plants in a greenhouse. None of the isolates was able to reduce the number of late blight lesions compared to the control.</description><creator>Lovering, Nancy</creator><contributor>Kushalappa, A. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Septoria apiicola</subject><subject>Celery -- Diseases and pests -- Biological control.</subject><title>Collection and evaluation of bacteria for the biological control of late blight of celery : (Septoria apiicola Speg.)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kc71h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q834c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:np193c005</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of the study was to use small area analysis to estimate the attributable risk percent of tuberculosis incidence associated with AIDS incidence among Canadian-born males aged 20 to 49. Information on all incident cases of tuberculosis and AIDS between 1980 and 1991 in Vancouver and Edmonton was obtained from provincial registries. The relationship in each census tract between tuberculosis incidence among Canadian-born males aged 20 to 49 and AIDS incidence was examined using small area analysis. Covariates included tuberculosis incidence among the foreign-born and socioeconomic variables from the 1986 Canada census. In Vancouver, unemployment, tuberculosis incidence among the foreign-born, and AIDS incidence were significantly associated with tuberculosis incidence among the Canadian-born. In Edmonton, only unemployment was significantly associated with tuberculosis incidence among the Canadian-born. Small area analysis detected a measurable, although small impact of AIDS incidence on tuberculosis incidence among Canadian-born males aged 20 to 49 in Vancouver.</description><creator>Loo, Vivian G. (Vivian Grace)</creator><contributor>Menzies, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>The impact of aids on tuberculosis in Vancouver and Edmonton : a small area analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375z43f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193c005</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q524jq84z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this study, the synoptic and mesoscale environment of a case of severe convective outbreak over Alberta on 11-12 July 1985 are investigated using the state-of-the-art Mesoscale Compressible Community Model (MC2). The results of the control experiment confirm the conceptual model and the conclusion of Smith and Yau (1993a,b). A series of sensitivity experiments were conducted to study the effects of surface evapotranspiration, topography, shortwave heating and longwave cooling. The results of the sensitivity experiments are: (1) While increasing horizontal resolution of mesoscale models will likely improve the timing and location of the severe convective outbreak, the improvement in mesoscale forecast cannot be achieved by simply reducing the grid size. Realistic treatment of topography, surface processes, and model physics are essential to predict severe convective outbreak. (2) Local surface evapotranspiration was shown to be an important source of moisture. Without surface evapotranspiration, not enough moisture is transported to the foothills to feed the convection. As a result, the mountain-plain circulation became ineffective in initiating severe convection. (3) An often observed condition for severe convection, the presence of a strong capping lid, was found to be formed from two processes. One factor is the presence of radiative cooling at the surface. Another factor is the advection from the downslope flow and the accompanying diabatic warming. Strong surface heating is essential in eroding the lid over the foothills.</description><creator>Li, Cunqiang</creator><contributor>Yau, M. K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><title>A numerical study of the Mesoscale environment in a case of severe convective outbreak over Alberta</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053j150.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jq84z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859h582</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Depending on the legal tradition one belongs to, the price is or is not a material term of contract. In American law, the Uniform Commercial Code expressly authorizes the open price contract. On the contrary, the French Civil Code forbids it and renders such a contract void for indefiniteness. This situation does not favor the international relations since, in many cases, the national courts seized read the international contract or law through the lenses of domestic law or principles. To avoid these consequences, a great harmonization has been undertaken since 1929. This effort resulted first in the adoption of the articles 14 and 55 of the United Nations Convention on Contracts for the International Sale of Goods. However, these articles conflict with one another and this results in several possible interpretation by the national courts. A work of harmonization has been completed since then by UNIDROIT and resulted in the adoption of the General Principles of International Commercial Contracts. The purpose of this thesis is to criticize the open price system adopted by UNIDROIT and analyse the future of such a principle in the international and national settings. Because of their extreme divergence this study will compare the Uniform Commercial Code's open price system and the French civil code.</description><creator>Lecossois, Delphine</creator><contributor>Bell, G. F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Economics, Commerce-Business.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>La determination du prix : quelle harmonisation? quel avenir?</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w37639087.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859h582</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1c18dh782</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The crossover transport regime between the quantum Hall effect and the Aharonov-Bohm effect is studied in terms of Buttiker's approach of electrical conduction. Quantum Hall effect and Aharonov-Bohm effect are very important effects in mesoscopic physics and both demonstrate unambiguously that quantum mechanics is the dominant factor in nanoscale electrical transport problems. However, they belong to situations of different dimensionality and different strength of magnetic fields. Our goal is to reveal the physics at the crossover regime between the two and find the transport properties of this transition regime. We have computed Hall resistance of a four-probe box-shaped quantum dot with an artificial impurity confined inside. As the size of the impurity is increased, transport behavior changes from the usual quantum Hall regime to a regime dominated by strong Aharonov-Bohm (AB) oscillations. We observe directly the formation and coupling of the edge states and their effects on the Hall resistance, by varying a magnetic field. For a range of the impurity size, transport enters the crossover regime where quantum Hall and AB effects compete, and a peculiar approximate symmetry between various transmission coefficients lead to a Hall plateau before the quantum Hall regime is reached. This symmetry can be explained based on scattering matrix theory and a topological equivalence of the dominating transmission patterns where well defined edge states are formed. Finally we investigate the universality of the observed symmetry property in several other structures and find that within the scope of our calculation the symmetry is universal.</description><creator>Lei, Ming</creator><contributor>Guo, Hong (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Quantum hall effect in the presence of an antidot potential</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dc00w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dh782</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j7484</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Obliterative bronchiolitis (OB) is the leading cause of chronic irreversible lung graft failure. It is assumed by many to be caused by chronic rejection. We hypothesized that non-specific airway inflammation induced by factors such as foreign airway deposited particles, antigens and microbes is essential for the development of OB after lung transplantation (LTx). In this study, we examined the histological and immunohistological changes in allografted airways following transtracheal installation of foreign irritant particles. Inadequate immunosuppression of lung allografts leads to severe vascular changes consistent with chronic vascular rejection but fails to induce airway inflammation and OB. The addition of a nonspecific foreign irritant was necessary to induce diffuse airway inflammation and OB in our animal model. This suggests that a co-factor inducing airway inflammation, such as deposited foreign particles or infections, is likely necessary for the development of OB after lung transplantation. Cytokine expression reveals a link between the observed influx of airway inflammatory cells and IL-8. While bFGF is associated more with the proliferative phases of airway and vascular injury. These markers however are not predictive of either rejection or OB, due to the expression of both these markers in all three study groups. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Lee, Allan G. L.</creator><contributor>Shennib, Hani (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Is chronic nonspecific inflammation of the airway essential for the development of obliterative bronchiolitis after lung transplantation?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f561r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j7484</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xg846</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>When the Y chromosome of a Mus. musculus domesticus mouse strain is placed onto the C57BL/6J(B6) background, half of the XY (B6.Y$ rm sp{Dom})$ progeny develop as females, which ovulate very few eggs and fail to develop zygotes beyond the two-cell stage. In the present study, oocyte-cumulus complexes were isolated from ovaries of juvenile B6.Y$ rm sp{Dom}$ females, as well as XX and XO females for comparison, and matured and fertilized in vitro. The results indicate that (1) In vitro procedure yielded far more mature oocytes than through ovulation; (2) The oocytes underwent apparently normal nuclear maturation, but failed to develop after fertilization; and (3) Addition of FSH during oocyte maturation increased the percentage of fertilization and the first cell cleavage, but not further development. The oocytes from XO ovaries were comparable with those from XX rather than XY ovaries, suggesting that the presence of the Y chromosome is responsible for the infertility of the B6.Y$ rm sp{Dom}$ female.</description><creator>Lédée, Nathalie</creator><contributor>Taketo, Teruko (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>In vitro maturation, fertilization, and preimplantation development of oocytes isolated from B6.Y Dom sex-reversed and XO female mice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d203z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xg846</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cc89q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A powerful new class of microscope, the Atomic Force Microscope, has led to a deeper understanding of the nanoscale world. The Scanning Probe Microscopy group at McGill University has developed an AFM whose general design lends itself readily to imaging, spectroscopy, and manipulation on an atomic scale. There are many challenges to building such a system. A major concern is the isolation of the microscope from external vibration sources, such as building vibration, people walking and talking next to the microscope, etc. These vibrations are orders of magnitude larger than the precision needed to detect the small variations of an atomic surface. A number of measures were developed to provide the isolation needed, including a series damping plates that support the microscope. An electromagnet was developed as an addition to the microscope as an aid to investigate the magnetic properties of samples. The magnet design combines a maximum magnetic field of over 1 kiloGauss with a simple construction and wire winding. Using this magnet, we will be able to rotate sample magnetizations in situ to observe switching times and profiles.</description><creator>LeBlanc, Philip R.</creator><contributor>Grutter, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Physics, General.</subject><title>Design and characteristics of a general purpose atomic force microscope</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913r852.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cc89q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f7623f639</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A research project was undertaken to study the hydrology and water quality of a 26 km$ sp2$ intensive agricultural watershed over an 18 month period. Flow and precipitation data were used to establish hydrologic parameters for the watershed and to empirically model hydrologic processes. Water samples taken from the outlet of the watershed were analyzed for nitrate, phosphate, suspended sediment and atrazine. Water quality data were analyzed to establish temporal trends in pollutant concentration and load in the watercourse. The measured time of concentration was found to be consistent with a mean of 6.89 hours for the 25 storms profiled. The time to peak was found to vary linearly with storm duration. The event recession constant was measured to be 0.9715. Regression analysis was performed on measured hydrologic properties. The strongest relationship was found between the percentage of rainfall appearing as runoff versus the sum of the 72 hour antecedent rainfall plus the storm rainfall. Spring snowmelt was identified as a significant period of pollutant material export. All pollutant materials displayed seasonal variability in the export process. Temporal variability accounted for poor correlations between observed hydrologic and water quality parameters in the two seasons for which data were available. Peak pollutant concentrations were associated with high flow events. Maximum observed concentrations for nitrate, phosphate, suspended sediment and atrazine were 8.6 mg/l, 0.478 mg/l, 0.7 g/l, and 8.06 ug/l respectively.</description><creator>Lapp, Paul, 1968-</creator><contributor>Madramootoo, C. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>L'Assomption River Watershed (Québec)</subject><subject>Water quality -- Québec (Province) -- L'Assomption River Watershed.</subject><subject>Agricultural pollution -- Québec (Province) -- L'Assomption River Watershed.</subject><subject>Nonpoint source pollution -- Québec (Province) -- L'Assomption River Watershed.</subject><subject>Hydrology -- Québec (Province) -- L'Assomption River Watershed.</subject><title>The hydrology and water quality of an intensive agricultural watershed in Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wf87s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f7623f639</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227mr949</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This is a study of various methods for the analysis of the returned power measured by a laser ceilometer. The calibration constant of the ceilometer is computed, and used to solve for atmospheric optical extinction profiles, in various cases of haze and precipitation. Other methods of analysis, requiring simultaneous measurements with a UHF boundary layer profiler, are also used to find extinction profiles. A comparison between the extinction profiles found using the different analysis techniques is provided. The results indicate that the method of solution that uses the calibration constant of the ceilometer is the most accurate. This work is not a comprehensive study of all the different methods of solving for optical extinction profiles using ceilometer and radar measurements, although it provides solid groundwork for future research.</description><creator>Lamoureux, Marie-France, 1972-</creator><contributor>Rogers, R. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><subject>Physics, Optics.</subject><title>Quantitative interpretation of laser ceilometer observations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nk20k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mr949</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vn029</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the brief, high frequency, head rotations associated for example with the stepping jolts of normal locomotion, the vestibular semicircular canals accurately transduce instantaneous head angular velocity relative to space. However, during more prolonged rotations such as occur when walking along a curved pathway, the canal's biophysics lead to an exponential decay of the peripheral sensory signal with a human time constant on the order of 8 sec. Although this time constant is "neurally" augmented two or three fold in the brainstem, the decaying characteristic still incurs a progressively decreasing signal at this level in the CNS. The present study aimed to determine whether conscious human perception can correct for this form of error in the vestibular sensory signal. Vestibular perception was estimated from a perception-based motor read out using two complimentary approaches. The first employed gaze saccades (either eyes alone or eye + head) to recapture a remembered target position after a passive head rotation of up to 8 sec, all conducted in complete darkness (Vestibular Memory Contingent Saccades = VMCS). The second study called for continuous "visual" fixation on an imagined earth-fixed target in the dark during the turn (Gaze Stabilization). In both studies final gaze error provided an index of volitional motor response accuracy. The Results of both studies showed that final gaze position, and hence presumably vestibular perception, was on average not reduced from ideal (P $&lt;$ 0.01, 21 subjects) over the full range of rotational durations. However, the Gaze Stabilization study showed that slow-phase velocity of the compensatory vestibulo-ocular reflex (VOR) followed the expected brainstem signal decay. But this response error tended to be systematically corrected by internally generated saccades. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Lala, Prasun Kanti</creator><contributor>Segal, Bernard (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Jones, Geoffrey Melvill (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Psychology, Psychobiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Vestibular perception of prolonged rotational stimuli</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nn475.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vn029</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3484zj767</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A graph is a triangulation if it is planar and every face is a triangle. A triangulation is rooted if the external triangular face is labelled. Two rooted triangulations with the same external face labels are isomorphic if their internal vertices can be labelled so that both triangulations have identical edge lists. In this thesis, we show that in the set of rooted triangulations on n points with minimum degree four, there exists a target triangulation $E sbsp{n}{ *}$ such that any other triangulation $E sb{n} not=E sbsp{n}{ *}$ in the set can be transformed to $E sbsp{n}{ *}$ via a finite sequence of single and double diagonal transformations. Using this result with the reverse search technique, we present an algorithm for generating all non-isomorphic rooted triangulations on n points with minimum degree four. The triangulations are produced without repetitions in $O(n sp2)$ time per triangulation. The algorithm uses $O(n)$ space.</description><creator>Kong, Chiu Ming</creator><contributor>Avis, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Generating rooted triangulations with minimum degree four</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g943d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zj767</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jn542</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of this study was to investigate the cadmium (Cd) exposure level from traditional food in Fort Resolution, Northwest Territories. Cd concentration in the liver and kidney of caribou and moose exceeded the action level (1 $ mu$g/g) established by Agriculture Canada, but the frequencies of consumption of these foods were relatively low. Cd intakes from traditional food ranged from 0.01 to 1713 $ mu$g/day/person. Average Cd intakes from traditional food were estimated to be 10% and 6% of the Provisional Tolerable Weekly Intake (PTWI), 7 $ mu$g/kg body weight/person, for women and men, respectively. The major contributors to the total Cd intake on a population basis were moose liver for women, and flesh of moose and caribou for men. The average Cd inhaled from cigarette smoking was 21.1 $ pm$ 9.1 $ mu$g/day/person. Total Cd intakes from traditional food and smoking were estimated to be 24% and 20% of the PTWI for women and men, respectively. The total Cd intakes of smokers and nonsmokers were significantly different (p $&lt;$ 0.001). The total Cd intake via market and traditional food, and cigarette smoking was 246.4 $ mu$g/week which was lower than the PTWI, 500 $ mu$g/week. Another objective of this study was to investigate an effect of food preparation on Cd speciation in food. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Kim, Christine Ji-Hyun</creator><contributor>Chan, Laurie Hing Man (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Cadmium -- Environmental aspects -- Northwest Territories -- Fort Resolution.</subject><subject>Métis -- Northwest Territories -- Fort Resolution -- Nutrition.</subject><subject>Diet -- Northwest Territories -- Fort Resolution.</subject><subject>Tinne Indians -- Northwest Territories -- Fort Resolution -- Nutrition.</subject><title>Assessment of cadmium intake from the consumption of traditional food in Fort Resolution, Northwest Territories</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719p367.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jn542</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cj65k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research was carried out to identify salt tolerant potato genotypes in vitro among 131 tetraploid potato cultivars (Solanum tuberosum), 9 diploid simple hybrid clones (4 clones of S. chacoense $ times$ S. tuberosum, 4 clones of S. phureja/S. stenotomum $ times$ S. tuberosum, and 1 clone of S. tuberosum $ times$ S. tuberosum), 1 primitive cultivated diploid S. phureja/S. stenotomum accession, 12 tetraploid complex hybrids, and 13 diploid S. chacoense accessions. Four levels of NaCl (0, 40, 80, and 120 mM) were used. The cultivars, and the simple and complex hybrids were tested for salt tolerance at the vegetative stage in the nodal cutting bioassay. The thirteen S. chacoense accessions were tested for salt tolerance at the germination and early seedling growth stage, in a seedling bioassay. Eleven of these S. chacoense accessions were further tested at the vegetative stage, in the nodal cutting bioassay. There was a progressive decline in the morphological parameters measured, with increased salt levels, in the nodal cutting bioassay. The parameters were used collectively in ranking the different genotypes, averaged over three NaCl levels (40, 80, and 120 mM). Twenty potato cultivars, two clones of the simple hybrid S. chacoense $ times$ S. tuberosum, and one complex hybrid were all considered salt tolerant at the vegetative stage. Ranking of seven S. chacoense accessions was similar between early seedling growth and later vegetative stage. Two of these accessions were promising as sources of salt tolerance.</description><creator>Khrais, Tala</creator><contributor>Donnelly, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Salt-tolerant crops.</subject><subject>Potatoes -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Potatoes -- Effect of salt on.</subject><title>Evaluation of salt tolerance in potato (Solanum spp.)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gq28d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cj65k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5999n532j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Glycophosphatidyl-inositol (GPI)-linked carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA) family members, including CEA itself, are absent in rodents and seem to have evolved recently. We have shown previously that CEA-CEA binding required for intercellular adhesion involves a double reciprocal interaction between the N-terminal (N domain) and internal A3B3 domains of anti-parallel molecules on apposed cell surfaces. To answer the question of whether this binding mechanism also evolved with CEA, the adhesive binding mechanism for transmembrane biliary glycoprotein (BGP), presumably more primordial, was investigated. Since CEA and BGP can be expressed on the same cells, and can have opposite effects on the cell phenotype, heterotypic interactions between them were also of interest. A construct with a deletion (17 amino acids) in the N domain of BGP was created which is unable to mediate intercellular adhesion. This $ Delta$NBGP construct, along with BGP splice variant containing only the N domain and various chimeric CEA/NCAM (neural cell adhesion molecule) constructs, was used to establish the fact that both BGP-BGP and BGP-CEA binding are obligate N-N domain. Thus fundamentally different molecular adhesion mechanisms exist in the CEA family.</description><creator>Keyston, Rebecca</creator><contributor>Stanners, C. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Homotypic and heterotypic adhesion mediated by biliary glycoprotein, BGP</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mp324.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n532j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859h59b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Granule-laden astroglia accumulate with normal aging in several brain regions. Chronic treatment with cysteamine (CSH), a drug which depletes somatostatin (SS), produces accelerated astorcytic granule accumulation in rat hippocampus homologous to that observed in the aging brain. Behavioral tests performed following CSH administration have always been done with CSH present in the animals' systems and have shown cognitive deficits and decreases in locomotor activity, both of which have been attributed to the depletion of SS by CSH. Since chronic CSH exposure will also produce neuropathological changes in hippocampal astrocytes, we tested animals' spatial learning/memory and motor functioning at two time points following a chronic CSH treatment: (1) during CSH treatment to assess the effects of the drug itself, and (2) well after cessation of the drug to test the behavioral effects possibly associated with astrocytic neuropathology, not drug. A tendency toward a cognitive impairment was evident when rats were tested in a water maze 1 month following prolonged CSH treatment, but not during CSH exposure. On the other hand, when tested in locomotor activity boxes, only the animals tested during CSH treatment, not post-treatment, displayed a significant decrease in locomotion. Moreover, five weeks following CSH exposure, CSH-treated animals showed a significant increase in both the number of hippocampal astrocytic granules and SS levels; elevated SS concentration in the hippocampus is unlikely responsible for the seemingly detrimental effects of CSH on cognitive behavior since SS is antiamnesic. Taken together, these results suggest that CSH-induced cognitive deficits previously measured when CSH is in the animals' system may be influenced by concurrent locomotor deficits, and that CSH-induced astrocytic pathology may possibly be associated with a trend towards a deficit in cognition which is separate from the locomotor effects caused by the drug.</description><creator>Justino, Lisette</creator><contributor>Welner, S. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><subject>Psychology, Psychobiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Cysteamine-induced acceleration of a senescent glial phenotype : effects on cognition and locomotion</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gq29p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859h59b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zw56q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Despite the recognition that culturally diverse groups of children in low income areas are at elevated risk for future health problems, no dietary/nutritional studies have been reported on this population. Children aged 9-12 were sampled from schools selected on the basis of a poverty index and ethnicity. Nutritional information (24-hour recall, heights and weights) indicated children were growing well but a high proportion were overweight. A comparison of reported energy intake to calculated BMR indicated that overweight children under-estimated their intakes. Mean intakes met the Canadian RNIs except for calcium in 10-12 year old girls. Nutrient intake was related to family size, income and ethnic origin. Validation of two alternative tools to measure fat intake proved unsuccessful. In conclusion, dietary intake for these school children was adequate for all nutrients except calcium in 10-12 year old girls, but for approximately 40% of children, intake exceeded energy requirements.</description><creator>Johnson-Down, Louise</creator><contributor>Gray, Donald K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Diet -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Poor children -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Nutrition.</subject><subject>Lipids in human nutrition -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>A nutritional assessment of low income and multi-ethnic school children 9-12 years old and validation of alternative tools to measure fat intake</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b320n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zw56q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9c67wp77w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fibrinogen, thrombin receptor and heparin cofactor II are three major thrombin substrates recognized specifically through its exosite, a regulatory binding site. Based on the native protein sequences, four peptides were selected to study the specificity of exosite interactions on structural basis using transferred NOE methods. The binding sequences of all the peptides are identified and possible thrombin binding sites of thrombin receptor and heparin cofactor II peptides are speculated by comparing with known hirudin-thrombin complex structures. A new binding mode may exist in thrombin-fibrinogen contacts according to its exosite binding sequence and interaction patterns. In terms of the binding sequence, it suggested that the most important factor in thrombin exosite specific binding is the hydrophobic residues position rather than the analogous sequence.</description><creator>Hu, Song, 1969-</creator><contributor>Ni, Feng (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Health Sciences, General.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Thrombin exosite interactions studied by NMR spectroscopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fb449.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wp77w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hm50tt681</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Samples of Porites porites rubble were collected from across three fringing reefs which lie along a eutrophication gradient in Barbados, West Indies. The coral skeleton fragments were examined for clionid sponges. Data collected from the reef crest and fore reef zones and from across the range of distances and depths were pooled for each reef to compare indices of sponge abundance along the eutrophication gradient. Significant differences between the reefs were found for the proportion of rubble invaded (ANCOVA, p = 0.004), number of invasions per sample (ANCOVA, p = 0.002), and number of species per sample (ANCOVA, p = 0.018) but not for total surface area of sponge invasions per sample (ANCOVA, p = 0.064). All the indices demonstrated an increase with increasing eutrophication level. Clionids were found in nearly twice as many of the pieces collected from the most eutrophic site (41%) as from the least eutrophic (24%). Since clionids may be the principal bioeroders of coral reefs, an increase in their abundance due to excessive pollution likely results in greater bioerosion of affected reefs. The mean abundance of Type 3 corals was found to be positively related to the frequency of boring sponge invasion, suggesting that increased bioeroision may be partly responsible for community shifts toward Type 3 corals in polluted waters. One new variety and three new species of boring sponges of the genus Cliona were found. A new variety of C. amplicavata Rutzler is described, Cliona species 2 of MacGeachy is redescribed and Cliona species 4 and Cliona species 5 are described for the first time. Cliona species 5 may become an important bioeroder in Barbados and other Caribbean islands since it flourishes under high eutrophic conditions which are beginning to plague West Indian reefs. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Holmes, Katherine E. (Katherine Elizabeth)</creator><contributor>Reiswig, H. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Coral reef ecology -- Barbados.</subject><subject>Eutrophication -- Barbados.</subject><subject>Sponges -- Barbados.</subject><title>The effects of eutrophication on clionid (Porifera) communities in Barbados, West Indies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f800d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tt681</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558g25r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents two techniques for enhancing the volume coverage and temporal resolution of functional magnetic resonance brain imaging on conventional clinical scanners, namely, echo-shifting and retrospective temporal resolution selection (RTRS). The techniques are compared with conventional 2D gradient echo imaging on the bases of speed and sensitivity to functional changes, and the necessary theory is reviewed to develop physical models explaining the different properties observed. Acquisition, reconstruction, and analysis software packages for functional brain mapping are presented and demonstrated with visual stimulation. The echo-shifted sequence permitted acquisition of 3D maps of brain activity which could be better correlated with local anatomy than 2D maps, and the RTRS method provided physiological response curves with greatly increased temporal resolution.</description><creator>Hoge, Richard D.</creator><contributor>Pike, G. B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><title>Enhancement of volume coverage and temporal resolution for functional magnetic resonance brain imaging</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wf882.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558g25r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vx021h254</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Na$ sp+$-Pi cotransport across the brush border membrane is the rate limiting step in renal Pi reabsorption. To determine its precise role in the maintenance of Pi homeostasis, we cloned and characterized the renal-specific Na$ sp+$-Pi cotransporter/Npt2 gene and generated a gene targeting vector for the creation of a knockout mouse. The gene was cloned by screening a genomic DNA library with a rat Npt2 cDNA probe. The Npt2 gene is approximately 17kb and contains 13 exons and 12 introns. A targeting construct was generated by inserting 5$ sp prime$ and 3$ sp prime$ homologous arms of 2.1 and 2kb, respectively, into the pPNT vector and replacing 7.7kb of Npt2 with a neomycin resistance gene. The vector also contained the herpes simplex virus thymidine kinase gene for negative selection. After electroporation into embryonic stem cells, clones were picked following selection in G418 and FIAU. Of 100 doubly-resistant clones that were screened by Southern analysis, 6 positive clones were detected giving a targeting frequency of 6%.</description><creator>Hewson, A. Stacy (Allison Stacy)</creator><contributor>Tenenhouse, H. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Sodium cotransport systems</subject><subject>Hypophosphatemia, Familial</subject><subject>Mice -- Genetics</subject><title>Isolation and characterization of a mouse renal sodium phosphate cotransporter gene and construction of a gene targeting knock-out vector</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jd36h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021h254</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1j92g944p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>On July 27th, 1990, the U.S. Centers for Disease Control reported that a Florida dentist had transmitted the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) to five of his patients. These incidents raised many, previously unaddressed, questions regarding the ethical obligations of the HIV-infected health care worker (HCW), as well as the ethical responses to this difficult situation by patients and society. This paper attempts to address these questions from an ethical viewpoint examining risk of harm and the individual duties of the HCW, the patient and society as well as through analysis of policies regarding HIV-infected HCWs. These policies were written by the federal U.S. and Canadian governments as well as state and provincial health departments and registrars of medical associations in the U.S. and Canada. The policies were analyzed for five categories of requirements or recommendations with respect to: (1) notification of government and professional organizations or health care institutions and notification of patients of the HCW's HIV status, (2) mandatory HIV testing of HCWs, (3) work restriction for the HCW, (4) retrospective notification of the patient, and (5) monitoring compliance with the policy. It was found that, in their practical interpretation, the policies left room for a wide spectrum of interpretation possibly due to poorly defined risk of individual invasive procedures. This indicates the need to accurately determine the risks of HIV transmission, from HCW to patient, during specific medical interventions. It was concluded that certain policies, such as Health and Welfare Canada's Laboratory Centre for Disease Control (LCDC), policy and New York State Department of Health's policy allow enough flexibility to minimize risks of harm as well as to provide the possibility of a balance of the interests of all involved. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Hayes, Ann M., 1964-</creator><contributor>Gilmore, Norbert (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Political Science, Public Administration.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Health Care Management.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>Health care workers infected with the human immunodeficiency virus : an ethical analysis of U.S. and Canadian government and professional policies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418q218.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g944p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591b454</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the past decade, new concepts have emerged on the role of adhesion molecules in the communication, motility, differentiation, and survival of cells in the body. The traditional view on the role of cell adhesion molecules in cell differentiation and tissue architecture has changed following the discovery that some adhesion proteins, including CD44, are involved in tumor progression in both animal and human tissues. CD44 is a glycoprotein which has differently spliced isoforms with various combinations of up to 9 variant exons numbered v2 to v10. The aim of this study was to characterize CD44 transcripts associated with colorectal neoplasia. The hypothesis is that discrete transcripts of CD44 are generated during the progression from normal to carcinomatous colonic epithelium, contributing to determinant changes in cell adhesion. Our results showed: (i) a high level of expression of CD44 v8-v10 transcripts in all tumor cells by in situ hybridization technique, (ii) 4 transcripts of CD44v7 with 650, 740, 1000, and 1150 bases in RNA extracted from tumor cases and studied by RT-PCR followed by Southern blotting, and (iii) the 1150 transcript was the only one found in both carcinoma and polyps. This transcript has therefore the potential to be used as an early marker of progression in colorectal neoplasia. It is reasonable to suggest that these new transcript species generate protein isoforms with different adhesion properties, as compared to standard CD44.</description><creator>Haghighat, Roya</creator><contributor>Jothy, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Identification of unique CD44 variant transcripts in human colon cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hb861.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591b454</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mp33d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of this work was to determine whether adult rat cerebral cortical gray matter membranes possess neurite growth inhibitory activity and to characterize this, if present. Tissue culture substrates of detergent extracted cortical gray matter membrane proteins inhibited neurite outgrowth from NG108-15 cells. Cortical gray matter membranes also caused growth cone collapse of embryonic rat dorsal root ganglion neurons. The inhibitory activity was both heat and trypsin sensitive suggesting the involvement of protein(s). Western blots and enzyme treatments indicate that known inhibitors are unlikely to contribute to this activity. The activity did not bind specifically to either Concanavalin A, peanut agglutinin, or wheat germ agglutinin. Ion-exchange chromatographic separation of the extracts suggests the presence of multiple inhibitory molecules. These results suggest that adult rat cortical gray matter contains neurite growth inhibitory activity, possibly due to contributions from several as yet uncharacterized inhibitory molecules.</description><creator>Ghosh, Alak, 1970-</creator><contributor>David, Samuel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>The identification of neurite growth inhibitory activity in the adult rat CNS gray matter</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mh56h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mp33d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ht24wm314</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:13:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Accurate alias analysis is critical for optimizing/parallelizing compilers that support languages with pointers. Efficient techniques have been developed to calculate aliases introduced by pointers to named memory locations (typically on the stack). However, practical and effective techniques for detection of aliases induced by heap-based dynamic data structures, have yet to be developed. In this thesis, we present a new and practical approach for analyzing the alias properties of heap data structures. The important features of our approach include: (i) we analyze heap-directed pointers after resolving the points-to relationships of stack-directed pointers, (ii) we use a storeless model and estimate the heap structure by abstracting the relationships between heap-directed pointers, and not by explicitly abstracting the heap as a graph, and (iii) we employ a hierarchical approach and design different abstractions to solve the problem at different levels of complexity. We present a hierarchy of three practical abstractions for analyzing heap data structures, namely connection, direction and interference matrix abstractions. These abstractions respectively capture the following boolean relationships between any two given heap-directed pointers: (i) if they can point to the same heap data structure, (ii) if an access path exists between the heap objects they point to, and (iii) if they can access a common heap object. Connection matrix information helps detect pointer accesses to completely disjoint data structures. The other two abstractions work together to identify if the given program builds tree-like or dag-like structures. We have implemented context-sensitive interprocedural analyses for these abstractions in the framework of the McCAT C compiler. For each abstraction, we first present basic analysis rules applicable to any language that supports pointers. We then describe C specific features of the analyses. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Ghiya, Rakesh</creator><contributor>Hendren, Laurie (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Practical techniques for interprocedural heap analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q3566.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wm314</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):975</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>