<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:21:06Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33100" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:th83m108m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Plasmodium falciparum is the most important causative agent of human malaria. The present study focuses on the identification and characterization of pfgcn20, a novel-member of the ATP-binding cassette protein gene family in P. falciparum. In a PCR-based cloning strategy, I employed redundant oligonucleotides directed against sequences encoding the highly conserved Walker motifs within the ATP-binding cassette, and the resulting amplified DNA fragments were used for library screening and gene walking experiments that resulted in the molecular isolation of the pfgcn20 gem. The pfgcn20 gene spans 2448 nucleotides and was predicted to encode a 95.5 kilo-daltons hydrophilic protein, PFGCN20, with two conserved ATP-binding sites but no predicted membrane spanning domains. Pfgcn20 a localized on chromosome 11 and was shown to be expressed as a 3.3 kilobase mRNA transcript. The predicted PFGCN20 protein shows significant sequence homology to a subgroup of ATP-binding canette proteins related to the Saccharomyces cerevisiae translational regulator Gcn20p, to yeast and fungi EF-3 elongation factors, and to a subfamily of ATP-binding subunits of bacterial ATP-binding cassette transporters. However, no clear function for PFGCN20 could be inferred from these homology searches. A PFGCN20 specific polyclonal antibody was generated in rabbits and used to reveal that PFGCN20 is expressed as a 95 kilo-dalton protein throughout the entire cycle of the erythrocytic stage of P. falciparum. Localization studies showed that during the ring stage, PFGCN20 is present mainly in the parasite cell either in the cytoplasm and/or in discontinuous electron dense compartments at the cell periphery. In contrast, during the trophozoite and schizont stages, PFGCN20 was found to be transported into the host cell cytoplasm where it was associated with membranes of the tubovesicular membrane system and the erythrocytic plasma membrane. In addition, a fraction of PFGCN20 appeared in the red cell cytoplasm in a membrane-free form. These results suggest that at least part of PFGCN20 function is related to physiological processes in the cytoplasm of infected red cells. In the final chapter of my thesis, I have analyzed the functional homology between PFGCN20 and Gcn20p, by expression of PFGCN20 in the B2511 S. cerevisiae GCN20 deletion strain. Similar to Gcn20p, overproduction of PFGCN20 in H2511 (Deltagcn20) partially restored yeast cell tolerance to, an inhibitor of histidine biosynthesis, 3-amino-1,2,4-triazole. Expression of truncated pfgcn20 and chimeric pfgcn20/GCN20 constructs revealed that the N-terminal segment (211 acids) of PFGCN20 is sufficient for the restoration of partial 3-amino-.1,2,4-triazole tolerance of H2511 (Deltagcn20 ) cells. From my combined results, I have derived the working hypothesis that PFGCN20 may function as translational regulator within the plasmodial cell and fulfills a second possibly transport-related, function in the cytoplasm of infected red blood cells. However, whether PFGCN20 truly represents an example of a bi-functional ATP-binding protein must be evaluated by additional experimental work.</description><creator>Bozdech, Zbynek.</creator><contributor>Schurn, Erwin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Identification and characterization of PFGCN20, an ATP-binding cassette protein from Plasmodium falciparum</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r9675332.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m108m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tx31qk48f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>To investigate interactive effects of dietary fatty acid composition and energy restriction on body lipid metabolism and its regulation, rats were fed for 10 weeks diets varying in fat type and energy intake level. Energy deficiency was achieved by removing carbohydrate from the diets while keeping fat and other nutrient intakes constant. Tissue fatty acid deposition was influenced by the interaction between the dietary fat source and body energy balance. Less total fatty acids were deposited in livers of the ad libitum beef tallow-fed animals than the other fat feedings. However, such difference no longer existed when energy intake was restricted. Similarly, less energy supply eliminated the higher docosahexaenoic acid and lower arachidonic acid contents associated with the fish oil feeding in hepatocyte membrane phosphatidylchohne, phosphatidylserine and sphingomyelin. Tissue lipogenesis was also examined as a function of the interaction of dietary fatty acid composition and energy restriction. Comparable absolute cholesterol synthesis rates were observed in livers of the food restricted animals fed different types of dietary fat, although the synthesis rates were different among the dietary fat groups fed ad libitum. Energy restriction increased the triglyceride-fatty acid synthesis rates in the intestine of the fish and safflower oil-fed groups, but not in that of the olive oil- and beef tallow-fed animals. Plasma leptin concentrations were 60% higher in the ad libitum-fed fish and safflower oil groups as compared with those in the beef tallow diet group, despite smaller perirenal fat mass and fat cell size in the fish oil-fed animals. Energy restriction decreased plasma leptin levels of the fish and safflower oil-fed rats, but not those in the beef tallow-fed animals. Taken together, these results demonstrate that the structural, functional and regulating aspects of tissue lipid metabolism were influenced by an interaction between dietary fatty acid composit</description><creator>Cha, Ming Chuan, 1955-</creator><contributor>Jones, Peter J. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Rats -- Metabolism.</subject><subject>Oils and fats, Edible.</subject><subject>Reducing diets.</subject><subject>Hyperlipidemia.</subject><subject>Lipids -- Metabolism.</subject><title>Effects of dietary fat selection and energy restriction on tissue lipid metabolism : structure, function and regulation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719n94x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qk48f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf268686x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A project was developed to determine the feasibility of using liquid hog manure as a nutrient source (Nitrogen) for the potato crop. A survey of liquid hog manure storage facilities on Prince Edward Island (P.E.I.) provided a sampling technique and the range of nutrients found on hog farms. It was concluded from the data that there were large differences between farms and on farm manure sampling was required to determine accurate nutrient applications. An infrastructure was designed, constructed and tested for storage, handling and the application of liquid hog manure at the Harrington Research Farm, Crops and Livestock Research Centre, Charlottetown, P.E.I. Data from the first of two three year experiments determined that the placement of liquid hog manure under the sown potato row and beside the row (0.23 m) provided yields better than manure placed between the sown rows. These yields were not different for the extra Nitrogen fertilizer treatment. The second field experiment examined the placement of liquid hog manure by various injector designs between the rows after the potato crop was planted. Potato tuber yield data over the three years indicated no differences among injector design nor between the injector treatments and the treatment which received the extra Nitrogen fertilizer. Over both experiments there was a decline in the severity of Rhizoctonia ( Rhizoctonia solani) in one year for plots receiving manure compared to those which received only inorganic fertilizer. There were no differences in the incidence or severity of scab (Streptomyces scabies) over the study. In general liquid manure can be used as nutrient source for the potato crop on P.E.I.</description><creator>Campbell, Allan J.</creator><contributor>Borrington, Suzelle (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Swine -- Manure -- Handling.</subject><subject>Farm manure, Liquid.</subject><subject>Liquid fertilizers -- Application -- Equipment and supplies.</subject><subject>Potatoes -- Fertilizers.</subject><title>Design and evaluation of liquid swine manure injectors for potato nutrient placement</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf2686876.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268686x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j6731567p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Real-time control strategies were developed for biological systems requiring exposure to a number of different redox environments. The approach taken was to develop control strategies under static redox conditions, and then merge them into a unified scheme. The anoxic system studied consisted of the removal of oxidized nitrogen by Pseudomonas denitrificans. A control strategy that was based on detecting an inflection point in the transient ORP signal was applied. The inflection point was detected by searching for a minimum in the first derivative. Using this approach, all of the nitrate and nitrite was removed each cycle. Aerobic removal of toluene, performed by Pseudomonas putida, was then studied. In this system, the optimal strategy involved the second derivative of the transient ORP signal, and resulted in toluene removal efficiencies on the order of 95% per cycle. Finally, an attempt was made to automate a process requiring exposure to both anoxic and aerobic environments. In this system, oxidized nitrogen was removed under anoxic conditions, while carbon removal continued under an aerobic environment. Both processes were mediated by Pseudomonas denitrificans. This attempt was only partially successful. While little oxidized nitrogen remained at the end of the anoxic cycle, a significant amount of nitrite reappeared in the medium upon exposure to aerobic conditions. This result served to indicate the importance of the transition zone, and the difficulties associated with controlling sequential environments.</description><creator>Brown, Wayne A.</creator><contributor>Cooper, D. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Environmental.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Real-time control strategies for cyclical biological reactors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xg61w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j6731567p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43nz89d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Salinity problems seriously affect agricultural production by reducing crop yield and arable land. The evaluation of potato genotypes (Solanum spp.) for their salinity (NaCl) tolerance in conventional field trials is time consuming and labour intensive. The results are often confounded by many field and environmental variations. In vitro bioassays can overcome some of these difficulties by providing faster, more convenient and dependable methods for screening and selection of salt tolerant potato genotypes. The objective of this research was to develop in vitro bioassay methods for screening and selection of salt tolerant potato. Under in vitro NaCl stress conditions, seed germination, early seedling growth, and single-node cutting bioassays were used to evaluate salinity tolerance. The selected genotypes were further tested with three in vitro bioassays (single-node cuttings, root tip segments, and microtuberization). The rankings of potato cultivar salinity tolerance were similar in these bioassays. The single-node cutting bioassay was recommended because it was simpler to perform than the root tip segment and microtuberization bioassays and did not exclude certain genotypes as did the microtuberization bioassay. The in vitro bioassay rankings were compared with yield ranking in field lysimeters. In both the in vitro and in vivo saline stress experiments, cvs. Kennebec and Russet Burbank were more salt tolerant than Norland. The tubers and microtubers harvested from previous experiments were tested in the greenhouse to investigate salinity carry-over effect for seed tuber production. There was no apparent residual carry-over effect found. Microtuber yield increase in the presence of low NaCl concentration was induced primarily by specific ion (Na+), and not osmotic effects. This research clearly indicated that in vitro bioassays are relatively simple, rapid, convenient, repeatable, and agree with the field lysimeter results. They can be used to substitute for f</description><creator>Zhang, Yanling, 1955-</creator><contributor>Donnelly, D. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Biological assay.</subject><subject>Salt-tolerant crops.</subject><subject>Potatoes -- Effect of salt on.</subject><title>Development of in vitro bioassays for determination of salinity tolerance in potato (Solanum spp.)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w032471n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43nz89d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b784g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of this work was to study proliferative growth of airway smooth muscle (ASM) cells from Fisher rats, a highly inbred strain known to have an increased amount of ASM in vivo, and airway hyperresponsiveness, when compared to control Lewis rats. Airway hyperresponsiveness is a hallmark of asthma, and ASM provides the contractile force which narrows or closes the airways during asthmatic episodes. Growth of ASM in asthma and animal models of asthma is well documented, and is likely to be a crucial determinant of an excessive airway response to contractile agonists. However, the mechanisms of ASM growth in asthma are unknown. Because ASM cells proliferate when exposed to inflammatory mediators, ASM growth in asthma has been assumed to be a sequel of inflammation of the airways. This thesis now presents data supporting an alternative hypothesis for the evolution of increased smooth muscle mass in asthma. Studies on highly inbred rats suggest that enhanced responsiveness of ASM cells to mitogens is a genetically determined phenotype, and may thus predispose to an increased mass and contractility of ASM in vivo. Thus, an inborn susceptibility for enhanced ASM growth may lead to airway hyperresponsiveness. The proliferative response to mitogenic stimulation in ASM cells from hyperresponsive Fisher rats was enhanced when compared to the response of ASM cells from control Lewis rats. This enhancement was inherent to ASM cells, persisting over multiple passages in culture, and the mechanisms responsible were operative in G0 or G1 of the cell cycle. An enhanced proliferative response of Fisher ASM cells was selectively induced by a subset of the growth factors examined. These included fetal bovine serum (FBS), epidermal growth factor (EGF), and the AA or AB isoforms of platelet-derived growth factor (PDGF). The growth response of Fisher ASM cells to other mitogens tested was not enhanced with respect to Lewis ASM cells, indicating that the mechanisms responsible for e</description><creator>Zacour, Mary E.</creator><contributor>Martin, James (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Studies on the growth of smooth muscle from the airways of hyperresponsive rats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fn49f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b784g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hb44h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The host/parasite association between the pulmonate snail Stagnicola elodes and the digenean Plagiorchis elegans was examined with a view to identifying some of the biotic and abiotic factors that govern parasite egg development, infectivity and survival, the dynamics of cercarial production, as well as host susceptibility to infection, growth, reproduction and mortality. Plagiorchis elegans eggs passed with the feces of the hamster (Mesocricetus auratus) experimental definitive host were unembryonated. Between 0 and 30 C, the rate of embryonation continued to increase with temperature, whereas infectivity and survival were optimal between 10 to 20 C. Light adversely affected embryonation. Parasite acquisition increased with the intensity of exposure and sexual maturity. Infection invariably enhanced pre-patent host growth in a dose-dependent manner. Cercarial production increased with time and reached a plateau. Snails infected prior to sexual maturity released more cercariae than mature individuals. Heavily infected snails tended to die prematurely regardless of age at infection and parasite dose, thereby reducing their total production of cercariae to levels below those of more lightly infected individuals. Even light infections castrated the snail host. Snails infected when immature never reproduced, whereas reproductive snails ceased egg production within days of infection. Similar effects were observed in the incompatible snail host Biomphalaria glabrata, although no cercariae were ever produced. Both enhanced growth and parasitic castration are attributable to the mother sporocyst.</description><creator>Zakikhani, Mahvash.</creator><contributor>Rau, M. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Plagiorchiidae.</subject><subject>Cercariae.</subject><subject>Lymnaeidae -- Parasites.</subject><subject>Biomphalaria glabrata -- Parasites.</subject><title>Plagiorchis elegans in the molluscan intermediate host : infection, susceptibility, growth, reproduction, mortality and cercarial production</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pj08q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hb44h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tn668</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, we provide a necessary and sufficient condition for Lp boundedness of a class of oscillatory integrals with Calderon-Zygmund (C-Z) Kernel and establish weighted norm inequalities for them. We also prove some weighted norm inequalities for a class of oscillatory integrals with rough kernel. Finally, we discuss the question of the sharpness of certain weighted weak type inequalities for standard C-Z operators.</description><creator>Zhang, Yan, 1963-</creator><contributor>I. Klemes (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Boundedness of certain oscillatory integrals on weighted Lp spaces and some results on weighted weak Hp for 0 &lt; p &lt; 1</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t804c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tn668</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43nz905</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The subject of this thesis is a technology, the motor vehicle, that greatly affected our society. Between 1900 and 1930, motorization progressed rapidly in the Montreal area as the motor vehicle became a dominant mode of urban transportation. But to reach such a status, the new technology needed more than an increasing number of people adopting it. Because the street was already occupied by different users, automobile drivers had to impose the motor car on it. Above all, it was with tramway promoters that they had to "negociate". This negotiation related to both the space available in the street and the movement of vehicles. Concerning space, the omnipresence of tramways and their installations along with the parking of motor vehicles, particularly in the downtown area of Montreal, led to suggestions of wide boulevards and subway systems as possible solutions. The fact that tramways had priority in traffic and could not be passed by motor vehicles constituted major obstacles for motorists anxious to benefit from the motor car. By the end of the 1920s, conflicts were so intense that the notion of progress was used to promote both the motor vehicle and the tramway. These conflicts over the sharing of streets had other implications. First, different sections of Montreal's elite favoured one technology over the other. On the one hand, motorists were well organized. At the same time, tramway concerns were determined to protect their monopoly. This animosity within the elite was intensified by antimonopoly feelings and by dissatisfaction with tramway service. Finally, traffic problems multiplied with motorization: deaths, accidents, law suits and downtown congestion. Traffic became an important preoccupation leading to an increase in police forces and the establishment of numerous organizations dedicated to traffic management. The popular classes of Montreal were not excluded from these conflicts among the elites. Generally speaking, the entire population was forced to take sides with one group of promoters or the other. Motorization then appears as a factor of division within social classes as well as a phenomenon transcending the barriers between them.</description><creator>Veilleux, Denis.</creator><contributor>Young, Brian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Automobiles -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History.</subject><subject>Street-railroads -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History.</subject><subject>Urban transportation -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History.</subject><subject>Local transit -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History.</subject><title>La motorisation, ou, "La rançon du progrès" : tramways, véhicules-moteurs et circulation (Montréal, 1900-1930)</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zq25h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43nz905</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d504rn05d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work was aimed at obtaining high quality dried strawberries using microwaves to assist convection air of 2 m/s at 30--45°C. Preliminary trials with whole strawberries were unsuccessful. Fruits would cook rather than dry at low microwave power levels, and burst at higher powers. This was due to the inhibition of moisture movement by the waxy cuticle. Slice and pureed strawberries dried, but were of lower quality than freeze-dried A treatment consisting of dipping the berries in a solution of ethyl oleate and sodium hydroxide was studied. Such treatments are used in industry to reduce the skin resistance to moisture diffusion. Result showed that the treatment greatly enhanced the drying rates of whole berries in convection and microwave regimes. A 1% concentration of ethyl oleate was sufficient for maximum reduction of drying time, and it is possible that even lower concentrations could be used for strawberries. Rehydration was similar to that of the dipped and freeze-dried samples, but the microwaved samples were a bit softer, and had less aroma, colour and flavour. Osmotic dehydration was then studied as a technique of binding flavours and aromas and of reducing the time required for finish drying with microwaves. These studies were performed on strawberries and blueberries. Results showed berries that were dipped and then osmotically dehydrated for 24 h in sucrose, yielded a microwave-dried final product that was equal to the freeze-dried one in terms of quality, and this, with a much lower time for finish drying. The shrinkage ratio of strawberries has a straight line relation to the moisture ratio. The reduction in equivalent diameter is well-described by a reciprocal logarithmic function. The results of these major aspects of the research suggest that microwave-drying could be a viable and more rapid alternative to freeze-drying when berries are first subjected to a pretreatement of ethyl oleate and partial dehydration by osmosis. It was also found that if microwave energy is applied in continuous mode, the initial applied power should not exceed 0.2 W g--1, otherwise burning may occur. It is also recommended that osmotic dehydration be limited to not much longer than 24 hours, since off-odours, develop. The results apply to convective regimes with inlet air temperatures of 45°C and inlet velocity of 2 m/s.</description><creator>Venkatachalapathy, Kamadenahally.</creator><contributor>Raghavan, G. S. V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Strawberries -- Drying.</subject><subject>Microwave drying.</subject><subject>Blueberries -- Drying.</subject><title>Combined osmotic and microwave drying of strawberries and blueberries</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xk34b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rn05d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53jz937</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The mouse Splotch phenotype is characterized by specific defects in neural tube closure, neural crest cell migration, and skeletal myogenesis, and results from loss-of-function mutations in Pax-3, a transcription factor expressed within a subset of neural and mesodermal lineages. A hypomorphic allele termed Splotch-delayed produces milder neural tube defects and neural crest cell deficiencies than other Splotch locus mutations. We found that this unique phenotype is associated with a glycine to arginine mutation of the ninth amino acid of the Pax-3 paired domain. We also identified and characterized two alternatively spliced Pax-3 isoforms termed Pax-3/Q+ and Pax-3/Q--. These isoforms differ solely by the presence or absence of a single glutamine residue in the linker which joins the two DNA-binding subdomains of the Pax-3 paired domain, and are co-expressed throughout the early stages of mouse embryogenesis. Preliminary biochemical studies suggested that the novel Pax-3/Q-- isoform possessed enhanced C-terminal subdomain-mediated DNA-binding activity. In follow-up studies, we generated derivatives of a classical paired domain binding site (CD19-2/A) in order to further characterize the distinct DNA-binding properties of the two naturally occurring Pax-3 isoforms. We found that the presence of a 5 '-TT-3' dinucleotide at positions 15 and 16 of the paired domain recognition sequence promoted high affinity binding by both Pax-3 isoforms. However, with a guanine at position 15, only the Q-- isoform retained high affinity binding to the derivatives tested, suggesting that the presence of the additional glutamine residue in the Q+ isoform restricts the sequence specificity of the Pax-3 paired domain. Altogether, these studies demonstrate that the C-terminal subdomain makes an important contribution to the DNA-binding activity of the Pax-3 paired domain, and highlight the importance of the paired domain linker region in modulating the interaction of Pax proteins with t</description><creator>Vogan, Kyle J.</creator><contributor>Gros, Philippe (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Mechanisms governing DNA recognition by murine Pax-3</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pv36m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53jz937</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wh739</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Field and controlled environment experiments were performed to assess the preemergence activity of the fungal pathogen, Phomopsis convolvulus Ormeno to control Convolvulus arvensis L. (field bindweed). A granular barley formulation of the fungal inoculum applied onto the field soil surface resulted in dramatic aboveground biomass reductions of both C. arvensis seedlings (94--100%) and regrowth from established plants (53--98%). Under field conditions, surface applications of the granular formulation resulted in greater biomass reductions (93--100%) compared with soil incorporation of the granules (31--97%). Rate of soil applied granules of P. convolvulus did not affect the level of weed control and 90--100% C. arvensis biomass reductions were obtained for all rates used (30 g, 20 g, and 10 g 0.25m--2 plot). The use of two different planting substrates in controlled environment studies led to major differences in C. arvensis disease development. With an inoculum application on the day of sowing, 81% mortality was obtained for seedlings grown in a sandy loam field sod compared with 50% of seedlings grown in a prepared peat moss medium. The susceptibility of C. arvensis biotypes from various geographic locations to P. convolvulus was similar following post-emergence, foliar inoculum applications. Significant above-ground (65--100%) and new root growth (56--72%) biomass reductions of established plants were obtained for two selected biotypes (Greece, USA-Montana) subjected to a preemergence granular inoculum application. In the presence of spring wheat (Triticum aestivum L.), field efficacy of P. convolvulus was enhanced and aboveground biomass of inoculated C. arvensis plants was reduced by 98% compared with inoculated C. arvensis plants grown in pure stand.</description><creator>Vogelgsang, Susanne.</creator><contributor>Watson, A. K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Phytopathogenic fungi.</subject><subject>Phomopsis convolvulus.</subject><subject>Bindweed -- Biological control.</subject><title>Pre-emergence efficacy of Phomopsis convolvulus Ormeno to control field bindweed (Convolvulus arvensis L.)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752j52j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wh739</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kc39r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A study of the Taiwanese leather tanning industry is the basis of a critical reflection on the anthropological literature surrounding Chinese enterprises and a familistic "Chinese entrepreneurial ethic" which supposedly constrains their growth. Data gathered through historical research and in-depth interviews show that the growth of firms in the industry has not been inhibited by a familistic "entrepreneurial ethic." The structure of the industry has been far more influenced by Taiwan's history of incorporation into the world economy and the policies of modernizing governments, both under Japanese (1895--1945) and GMD rule (1945--present). The establishment of a market-friendly institutional context on Taiwan, including private property rights and contract law, has made it possible for some firms to grow from small family enterprises into relatively large corporations. At the firm level, organization of production into family or corporate firms is less influenced by a Chinese cultural essence than by the degree of capitalization available to firms and the type of product they produce. The "entrepreneurial ethic" thesis not only fails to account for the empirical reality of the Taiwanese tanning industry. In the Taiwanese context, the discourse on Chinese family firms has political implications in terms of class, gender and nation on Taiwan. First of all, focus on the family has overlooked class- and gender-based inequalities in such enterprises. in chapters five through seven, therefore, this thesis draws attention to the roles of workers and women in the contemporary Taiwanese economy. Secondly, studies. of Taiwanese society as a reflection of Chinese culture neglect controversies within Taiwan about "Taiwanese identity" and national sovereignty. Chapter eight is thus an discussion of the competing nationalist discourses employed by the state and Taiwanese entrepreneurs. In conclusion, it is argued that cultural explanations of economic behavior have political implications which should be rendered transparent in the social scientific literature.</description><creator>Simon, Scott, 1965-</creator><contributor>Bossen, Laurel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Family-owned business enterprises -- Taiwan</subject><subject>Women-owned business enterprises -- Taiwan</subject><subject>Tanneries -- Taiwan</subject><title>Not all in the family : class, gender and nation in the industrialization of Taiwan</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j3334076.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kc39r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v717t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Swelling equilibrium and kinetics of two commercial superabsorbent gel particles---sodium polyacrylate spheres and polyacrylamide-co-potassium acrylate grains---were studied in water and in sand at room temperature. Equilibrium experiments involved swelling gel particles at different depths in saturated sand columns packed with different sand sizes. Kinetic experiments were performed in a two-dimensional cell; both gel particle size and sand particle size were varied. Water flow in gel-conditioned sand was also investigated in columns and the two-dimensional cells for different gel dosages. The equilibrium swelling degree of gels in saturated sand was less than in water; decreasing sharply with depth in the first few centimeters, independent of sand particle size, then decreasing gradually with depth. A model was developed to describe equilibrium swelling in sand using the Flory model for polymer gels and a Cavity-Expansion model for frictional sand. For individual gel particles the kinetic relationship between the fractional approach to equilibrium and the square root of time was sigmoidal for swelling in water and in saturated sand. This relationship was described by a model based on Fick's first law which accounted for the movement of the boundary of the gel and the time variation of the polymer volume fraction at the surface. When water was distributed from the top of a uniform gel-conditioned bed, a gel layer formed on the surface. The gel particles, initially in the sand, were set free by the impact of the water. The released gel particles settled less rapidly than the denser sand particles. One minute after the initial disturbance of the dry sand-gel mixture, the water-borne particles settled on the surface to form a swelling gel layer. In the water flow experiments the advance of the wetting front was impeded, while surface movement increased, with increasing gel dosages. Two models were developed to describe flow in gel-conditioned sand: Swelling Soil model and Instantaneous Equilibrium model. Both models were based on Darcy's law and accounted for the movement of solids.</description><creator>Singh, Jaspreet, 1969-</creator><contributor>Weber, M. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Physical behavior of superabsorbent hydrogels in sand</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pf657.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v717t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:00000188b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Interior-point methods have not only shown their efficiency for linear and some nonlinear programming problems, but also for cutting plane methods and large scale optimization. The analytic center cutting plane method uses the analytic center of the current polyhedral approximation of the feasible region to add a new cutting plane. In this thesis, analytic center cutting plane and path-following interior-point methodologies are used to solve the following problems: (1) convex feasibility problems defined by a deep cut separation oracle; (2) convex optimization problems involving a nonlinear objective and a constraint set defined implicitly by a separation oracle; (3) variational inequalities involving a nonlinear operator and a convex set explicitly defined; (4) variational inequalities involving an affine operator and a constraint set defined implicitly by a deep cut separation oracle; and (5) variational inequalities involving a nonlinear operator and a constraint set defined implicitly by a deep cut separation oracle. Here, the oracle is a routine that takes as input a test point. If the point belongs to the feasible region, it answers "yes", otherwise it answers "no" and returns a cut separating the point from the feasible region. Complexity bounds are established for algorithms developed for Cases 1, 2 and 4. The algorithm developed for Case 3 will be proven to be convergent, whereas, in Case 5, the developed algorithm will be shown to find an approximate solution in finite time.</description><creator>Sharifi Mokhtarian, Faranak.</creator><contributor>Goffin, Jean-Louis (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Operations Research.</subject><title>Analytic center cutting plane and path-following interior-point methods in convex programming and variational inequalities</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mp02d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000188b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26z013v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this work we investigate the order of vanishing of L( s, chi) and L(s, f) (resp. rchi and rf) at the centre of the critical strip, where chi is a Dirichlet character and f is a newform of weight 2 and level N (f ∫ ∈ S2(N)^new). We show that on average rf or r chi are not large. Precisely: (1) We generalise Murty's results on the analytic rank of J0(N) to arbitrary levels N: under the RH for all L(s, f) then lim sup N→∞ f∫S2(N)new rf dim S2(N) ≤ 3/2. (2) We prove that the triangle function max(1 - |u|, 0) is the best function when using the explicit formulas the way Brumer and Murty did. (3) We compute an explicit bound for the second moment of the harmonic rank of J0(N). We prove that under the RH for L( s, f) and the Linnik-Selberg conjecture we have the bound f∫S2(N)new r2f 4π〈f,f〉 ≤ 31/12+o(1) as N → ∞. (4) We show on higher moments that f∫S2(N)new rkf ≪ dim S2(N), subject to the RH. (5) We improve on the constant 32 above to 1 when N is prime, thus proving that 50% of newforms with root number -1 have a non-vanishing L-function at s = 1 (conditional on the RH for L( s, f) again). (6) We show that assuming the RH for L(s, f) there is, for each N sufficiently large, a newform in S2(N)new so that L(1+it0,f) = 0 with |t0|≤4/log N.</description><creator>Sica, Francesco.</creator><contributor>Murty, Ram (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>The order of vanishing of L-functions at the center of the critical strip /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j3860863b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z013v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vd66w147q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A total of 114,351 Holstein first lactation records collected by the Quebec Dairy Herd Analysis Service (DHAS-PATLQ) between September, 1979 and January, 1994 were used to study the effects of adjusting records for linear and quadratic effects of 90- and 305-d feed intake measures (total energy, total protein and total dry matter) on estimation of heritabilities of and genetic correlations among yield and composition traits. Genetic parameters of feed intake measures, relationships between feed intake and age and weight at calving, and feed conversion efficiency traits were also examined in a series of studies. A sire model fitted by REML estimated heritabilities of 305-d milk, fat and protein yields, fat and protein percents as .45 +/- .04, .48 +/- .04, .44 +/- .03, .92 +/- .06, and .88 +/- .05, respectively. Correction of 305-d records for differences among cows in feed intake levels reduced heritabilities of milk, fat and protein yields to .35 +/- .03, .52 +/- .04, and .38 +/- .03, respectively. Heritabilities of composition traits (fat and protein percents) remained unchanged. Genetic and phenotypic correlations for yield traits were also reduced (48--170%, and 16--51%, respectively) which may indicate that genetic associations between yield traits are less than what we believed them to be. Heritabilities of 305-d total energy, total protein, total DM intake, grain energy, grain protein, grain DM, base energy, base protein, and base DM were .30 +/- .03, .24 +/- .02, .35 +/- .03, .23 +/- .02, .23 +/- .02, .23 +/- .02, .31 +/- .03, .26 +/- .02, and .40 +/- .03, respectively. Genetic correlations between feed intake measures were very high; they were approaching unity in some cases. Therefore, any one of these feed intake measures can represent the others. A multi-trait REML analysis estimated heritabilities of age and weight at first calving as .11 +/- .01 and .37 +/- .03, respectively. Age at calving was negatively associated with yield traits and with total e</description><creator>Ageeb, Abdel Gadir Ahmed.</creator><contributor>Hayes, J. F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Holstein-Friesian cattle -- Québec (Province) -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Holstein-Friesian cattle -- Feed utilization efficiency -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Milk yield -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>Genetic relationships among feed intake measures, feed conversion efficiency, and milk production traits in Holsteins using field recorded data</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hb462.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w147q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988m76r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis describes the preparation, characterization and biological study of block copolymer aggregates as drug delivery vehicles. A novel method is described for the synthesis of biodegradable and biocompatible copolymers of polycaprolactone-b-poly(ethylene oxide). The copolymers and their aggregates are then characterized with special attention given to properties which are of most interest to applications in drug delivery such as copolymer composition, thermal behavior, critical water content, critical micelle concentration, partition coefficient of hydrophobic solubilizates, morphology of the aggregates and in vitro biocompatibility. The polycaprolactone-b-poly(ethylene oxide) copolymer micelles are first explored as a delivery vehicle for the neurotrophic agents FK506 and L-658,818. The in vitro delivery and biological activity of the micelle-incorporated drugs are confirmed in PC12 cell cultures. The in vivo biological distribution of the micelle-incorporated FK506 was assessed in Sprague Dawley rats both 6 and 24 hours following intravenous administration. Also, the biological activity of the micelle-incorporated FK506 was shown to be retained in vivo using the sciatic nerve crush model of peripheral neuropathy in Hanover Wistar rats. The question of whether or not the cellular internalization of the polycaprolactone- b-poly(ethylene oxide) micelles proceeds by an endocytotic mechanism is addressed in PC12 cell cultures. Finally, the polycaprolactone- b-poly(ethylene oxide) micelles are explored as a delivery vehicle for dihydrotestosterone. We report on several of the physico-chemical characteristics of the micelle-incorporated dihydrotestosterone as well as in vitro delivery in HeLa cells which have been cotransfected with the MMTV-LUC reporter gene and the androgen receptor.</description><creator>Allen, Christine Jane.</creator><contributor>Eisenberg, Adi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacy.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Pharmaceutical.</subject><title>Polycaprolactone-♭-poly(ethylene oxide) copolymer micelles : physico-chemical characterization and application in drug delivery</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mp06h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988m76r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bk128c63t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although more and more women are present in university, feminist scholars contend that we have been and often still are viewed as "other" in this context. This position of "outsider" can problematize academic discourse for women writers. This qualitative study explores the search for authority as academic writers among twelve re-entry women graduate students. This quest is explored as a social process within the university setting. The study argues that re-entry graduate women encounter the problem of "authority" at several levels: in their experience of self as academics; in their experience of the academic milieu; and in their relation to texts (their own and others). The data show that the lived experience of graduate studies confers on re-entry women an identity of not belonging and thus undermines their sense of authority as academics which they seek. Thus authority and identity, like writing itself, are revealed as social processes. This study tells the story of the re-entry women's academic experiences, of their anticipation and disappointment, indeed devastation when they encountered sexism, ageism and racism. Although the study highlights the difficulties these women have in university, it also shows how positive social relations with professors and other colleagues can have a profound impact on re-entry women. It makes clear that these women thrive on social support, that they value the professor who affirms their identity as becoming academics, who helps them achieve not only the knowledge of an expert but also the stance and the voice---in short, to develop their sense of authority.</description><creator>Anderson, Linda, 1942-</creator><contributor>Jackson, Nancy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Adult education of women.</subject><subject>Women college students.</subject><title>Authority, identity, and writing : a feminist perspective</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mp057.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128c63t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354h054</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A numerical method is described for determining the derivatives of the scattering parameters of an arbitrary 3D microwave device with respect to changes in model geometry. The new technique is based on the adjoint variable method as applied to finite element analysis, but does not require the separate calculation of an adjoint solution. The new technique is applied to the optimization of the design of microwave components, using a derivative-based, quasi-Newton method. The derivatives of the scattering parameters of three devices are computed and compared to analytical or finite difference values. The agreement is very good. The three devices are: a length of short-circuited waveguide, an E-plane miter-bend, and a waveguide transformer. The short-circuited waveguide length is then optimized to achieve a specified phase of the reflection coefficient. The miter-bend and the transformer are optimized for minimum return loss. All optimizations reached the (local) optimum solution after only 4--12 computations of the field.</description><creator>Akel, Hatem.</creator><contributor>Webb, J. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>An improved adjoint method for design of microwave devices with 3D finite elements /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qb57s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354h054</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:th83m110n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During lactation, control of the activity of the hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal (HPA) axis is adjusted in that tonically elevated glucocorticoid secretion is observed concurrently with blunted ACTH secretion following exposure to various stressors. Although a decline in the level of CRF mRNA has been reported in neurons of the paraventricular nucleus (PVN) known to control ACTH secretion, the mechanisms underlying stress hyporesponsiveness during lactation are still largely unknown, In these studies we tested the hypothesis that pituitary responsiveness to secretagogues was altered and that central noradrenergic (NA) inputs to hypothalamic CRF neurons were modified during lactation in the rat. First, at the level of the pituitary the involvement of corticotrope sensitivity changes was examined in mid-lactating and virgin females. Results demonstrate that both virgin and lactating females show a significant ACTH response to a high stress-level dose of CRF but the magnitude of the response was greater in virgin compared to lactating females. Second, to understand the importance of brainstem NA afferents in mediating the stress response during lactation we performed 6OH-DA lesions over the PVN. In virgin females, 6OH-DA lesions caused a significant reduction in the ACTH and corticosterone (B) responses to 5 min swim stress, but lesioning did not affect stress-induced ACTH levels in lactating females. Finally, participation of central NA changes to some aspects of behavior was characterized during lactation. The acoustic startle response (ASR) was examined in groups of cycling and lactating female rats in early-, mid-, or late-lactation. Overall results suggest that brainstem NA inputs to the PVN act to facilitate ACTH stress response in virgin, but not lactating females. The absence of this facilitation is partially due to a reduced endogenous secretion (as demonstrated under basal conditions) and to a series of modifications in alpha-adrenoreceptor number, synthesis, and function that cause a decreased responsiveness to NA in parvicellular CRF neurons. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Bond-Toufexis, Donna.</creator><contributor>Walker, Dominique (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Noradrenergic and pituitary mechanisms underlying the stress and behavioral changes during lactation in the rat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dt82d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m110n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rw182</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis addresses the expression, regulation, and functional aspects of NOS in normal and developing skeletal muscles, and their role in contractile dysfunction of respiratory muscles associated with septic shock. Normal skeletal muscles of mammalian species express only ecNOS and nNOS to varying degrees. NOS activity in these muscles is mainly Ca2+/calmodulin-dependent and it associates with fast-twitch muscle fibers in rat and mice, but no such correlation exists in other species. Therefore, NOS activity is not the only factor that specifies contractility of skeletal muscles. In developing skeletal muscles, there is a transient increase in NOS Ca2+-dependent activity and the expressions of cNOS isoforms are upregulated. This coincides with skeletal muscle differentiation and maturation. Despite the negative influence of NOS activity on skeletal muscle contractility, little inhibition is observed on force generated by the developing diaphragm. Therefore, NO may regulate other processes than contraction in developing skeletal muscles. The in-vivo induction of iNOS protein and mRNA in skeletal muscles of septic rat is matched by a parallel induction in GTP-cyclohydrolase-I, the rate-limiting enzyme for BH4 biosynthesis. NOS Ca2+ -independent activity increases several fold mainly in the respiratory muscles. In addition, the expressions of cNOS enzymes are upregulated in septic rat muscles. During 24 hrs of endotoxemia of rats, iNOS is induced by 6 hrs, peak by 12 hrs and disappear by 24 hrs after LPS injection. nNOS and ecNOS expression is upregulated by 6 hrs and remained higher than control values after 24 hrs of LPS injection. The regulation of NOS isoforms is matched by an increase in total and Ca2+/calmodulin-independent NOS activity. Furthermore, peroxynitrite was detected in septic respiratory muscles, and nitrated proteins were detected in these muscles 12 hrs after LPS injection. Submaximal force generated by diaphragm strips was significantly inhibit</description><creator>El-Dwairi, Qasim.</creator><contributor>Hussain, S. N. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Magder, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Anatomy.</subject><title>Functional aspects of nitric oxide synthases in skeletal muscle</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k890b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rw182</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xd07gv344</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Diaz-Perez, Maria-Jose.</creator><contributor>Wainer, I. W. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Price, G. B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Quantitative structure-activity relationship (QSAR) study of the effect of steroids on DNA replication</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719n956.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gv344</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82k889k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Lacasse, Roger.</creator><contributor>Barrette, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>Hadron production in 10.8 A.GeVc Au+Au collisions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483k921.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k889k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1831cm70b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:37:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Amba Dongar complex, India, consists of calciocarbonatite, ankerite-dominated ferrocarbonatite and numerous nephelinitic bodies intruded into Late Cretaceous quartz sandstones and Deccan basalts. Ankeritic (mottled) and calcite +/- barite +/- ankerite (multiphase) melt inclusions were observed in apatite hosted by calciocarbonatite. Mottled inclusions start melting at temperatures of 610°C and are completely molten at temperatures &gt;800°C. The onset of melting, of multiphase inclusions, is at 680°C, and final melting occurs above 1100°C. Based an the coexistence of mottled (ankeritic) and multiphase (calcitic) inclusions, a model is proposed for the genesis of calciocarbonatite and ferrocarbonatite that calls upon separation of immiscible ankeritic and calcitic liquids from a parent carbonate melt. Primary fluid inclusions, in apatite hosted by calciocarbonatite, and in quartz of the surrounding fenitized sandstones, record a complex evolution of aqueous fluids. The fluids (orthomagmatic) were trapped at temperatures between 1000 and 260°C, at pressures ranging from 12.5 kbars to 500 bars, respectively, while fenitizing fluids ranged in temperature 260 to 120°C, and were trapped at &lt;500 bars pressure. The low temperature phase behaviour of all inclusions indicates that the fluids are NaCl-, KCl-bearing brines with salinities between 15 and 1.5 wt.%. The compositions of decrepitate residues indicate that early fluids were dominated by SO4 2- and HCO3-, and had low Na/Na+K ratios (&lt;0.5) More evolved fluids display an increasing dependence an Cl -, over SO42- and HCO3 -, and are increasingly depleted in K relative to Na. The replacement of quartz by potassium feldspar in fenites was accompanied by significant losses of Si and additions of K, Al, Ca, Ba, Fe, La, Ce, F, Rb, Sr, Y and HREE. The water-rock ratio during fenitization was ≈722. The Phalaborwa complex, South Africa (2060 Ma) consists of a large intrusion of pyroxenite which was later cored by phoscorite and subsequently intruded by banded (early) and transgressive (late) carbonatites. The carbonate rocks are host to 400 Mt of early bornite and late chalcopyrite ores. Solid-vapour and solid-liquid-vapour melt inclusions are present in phoscorite and transgressive carbonatite. The solids comprise calcite, a magnesian silicate and magnetite +/- Cu-Fe sulphide, while the fluid is a saline Mg-, Fe- and S-bearing NaCl-KCl brine (≈22 wt.% NaCl eq.). Solid-vapour inclusions in phoscorite produce immiscible carbonate and silicate liquids between 680 and 800°C. Melt inclusions in transgressive carbonatites produce only one liquid between 550°C to 670°C and homogenize above 750°C. Liquid immiscibilty was important in removing Si from the carbonate-rich melt, however, silicate and carbonate rocks are not related by liquid immiscibility. Fractionation is considered to have been the dominant process in forming the complex Two episodes of fenitization were discerned in surrounding granites and gneisses, from chemical and mineralogical changes, and were associated with emplacement of pyroxenite and carbonatite. Both events were accompanied by significant gains in K, Ca, Ba, Mg, Fe, Sr, Th and LREE, and losses in Si and Na. The presence of Cu-bearing sulphides in solid-vapour inclusions hosted by phoscorite indicates that Phalaborwa magmas were enriched in Cu before emplacement Solid-liquid-vapour inclusions provide the first evidence of a separate magmatic aqueous fluid phase at Phalaborwa and support interpretation of a hydrothermal origin for copper mineralization in transgressive carbonatite.</description><creator>Palmer, David A. S.</creator><contributor>Williams-Jones, A. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Geochemistry.</subject><title>The evolution of carbonatite melts and their aqueous fluids : evidence from Amba Dongar, India, and Phalaborwa, South Africa</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375z12f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cm70b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33125</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>