<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:48:51Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):41375" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42n8744</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>CEGEPs (Colleges d'enseignement general et professionnel) were designed with the aim of developing intellectual abilities in young adults. The purpose of this study was to describe the cognitive and affective abilities of CEGEP students at the beginning and end of CEGEP and to measure the change in these abilities. Comparing student cognitive and affective abilities at the beginning of, during and at the end of CEGEP, according to known measures of student development, would establish what changes occur during the college years, and would thereby promote a more thorough understanding of the students which CEGEPs serve. The cognitive development of CEGEP students was assessed by examining the three broad areas of development most focused on at the college level: reading, writing, and critical thinking skills. Affective development was studied by examining the moral reasoning and ego development of CEGEP students and students' attitudes toward knowledge and learning. The research design for the study was an interrupted time series on male and female students in three college programs: Science, Social Science, and Commerce. The experimental sample consisted of 334 students who entered CEGEP in 1985 in these programs. The students were selected at random and administered a series of cognitive and affective measures upon entry to college as part of the college's assessment procedure. The students were retested at the end of the first year of CEGEP and at the end of the second year of CEGEP. Samples were also selected in May 1986 and May 1987 to control for history, selection, maturation, and testing effects. The findings suggest that students' cognitive and affective abilities increase while attending CEGEP, but that most students do not begin college with the complex intellectual abilities required for academic success. Students in all programs made significant gains in vocabulary, comprehension, writing, critical thinking, moral reasoning, and ego development. Changes also occurred in certain attitudes toward knowledge and learning. Male and female students differed in critical thinking and ego development, but did not differ in vocabulary, comprehension, writing, or moral reasoning. Differences among programs were found in vocabulary, comprehension, critical thinking, and moral reasoning, but were not found in writing or ego development.</description><creator>Bateman, Dianne</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Junior college students -- Québec (Province) -- Case studies</subject><subject>Cognitive learning -- Case studies</subject><title>A longitudinal study of the cognitive and affective development of CEGEP students /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451j23h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42n8744</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r6362</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The problem of fault diagnosis in digital circuits is composed of two sub-problems: Fault detection (identifying that a fault is present) and fault location (identifying the failure responsible for faulty behaviour). Tests using randomly or pseudo-randomly selected input stimuli have been suggested both as a means of reducing the costs associated with generating deterministic tests and as a means by which circuits could test themselves (built-in self-test). The majority of research into random testing has dealt only with its fault detection properties. Fault location has typically been treated as a dictionary search problem, or ignored altogether. This dissertation proposes a new approach to fault location in randomly or pseudo-randomly tested digital circuits. Faults will be isolated by a hierarchical sequence of steps, each of which identifies a particular property of the fault which has occurred. The method uses available circuit information to aid in location. The advantages of this method include greatly reduced dictionary generation costs, the ability to locate a fault without searching an entire dictionary, and the ability to partially characterize unmodelled faults. In addition, a hierarchical approach allows dictionaries to be constructed in a demand-driven fashion, avoiding unnecessary work for faults which do not occur in practice, and reducing the costs of changes in the test set. Sample applications of the proposed location technique are given, for use in both random compact testing and built-in self-test. Experimental results are presented to demonstrate the performance of the method.</description><creator>Aitken, Robert Campbell</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>A hierarchical method of fault diagnosis with built-in self-test applications /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50gw89b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r6362</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r635s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study explored the teaching of agriculture in Kenya's primary schools. It sought in particular to determine how the principles of "modern" agriculture may be taught effectively. Previous studies on education and agricultural productivity have ignored the mechanisms through which schooling affects the acquisition of agricultural knowledge and skills. This study attempted to bridge this gap. To do so field work was carried out in four schools and their catchment areas in Kiambu and Kwale districts of Kenya. The data stemmed from field notes, tape recorded lesson transcripts, interviews and questionnaires as well as an exhaustive review of prior studies and government documents. The findings indicate that the schools offer possibilities for effective teaching of the principles of "modern" agriculture. However, whether or not the school will play this role well or poorly depends largely on the improvement in general of the quality of primary schooling. This task involves increasing school resources, modification of the agricultural curriculum, improvement of teacher training, change in teaching methods and assessment policies.</description><creator>Abagi, Jared O. (Jared Okwach)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Education, Primary -- Kenya</subject><subject>Agricultural education -- Kenya</subject><title>Primary schooling and agricultural education in Kenya : can principles of "modern" agriculture be taught effectively in schools?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pn633.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r635s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43nx69q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The preparation of a novel complex, ferric bromopyruvate, is described. In solutions from which most of the carbonate has been removed, ferric bromopyruvate can be used both as an iron and pyruvate source for the full iron saturation of apotransferrin. Using ferric bromopyruvate as an iron donor, iron incorporation into human apotransferrin is biphasic; the N-terminal domain is saturated three times faster than its homologous C-terminal iron binding site. Following the reaction of apotransferrin with ferric bromopyruvate, 4 moles of pyruvate per mole of transferrin are covalently bound. Based on the effect of acetylation on pyruvate and iron binding, it is suggested that lysyl residues could be the target of pyruvate bonding. However, the reaction of pyruvate with other positively charged amino acid residues cannot be excluded. The possible sites of pyruvate binding within the N-terminal domain of human serum transferrin are discussed. Covalent attachment of pyruvate to cationic amino acid residues decreased both in vitro and in vivo iron release, preferentially from the N-terminal domain of transferrin. The decreased rate of iron incorporation from iron-pyruvate-transferrin complexes by rabbit reticulocytes caused a lower iron incorporation into heme. It is suggested that an impairment of iron release from transferrin may decrease the rate of heme synthesis in reticulocytes. In vitro studies on the iron removal from iron-pyruvate-transferrin complexes showed that pyrophosphate can remove iron from this complex at an acid pH to a similar extent to the cellular mediated iron release from this complex. Based on this data, a model for the intravesicular iron release from transferrin is proposed.</description><creator>Pulido-Cejudo, Gabriel</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Chemical and biological properties of iron-pyruvate-transferrin complexes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c353h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43nx69q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945r493</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis the behavior of fully grouted, untensioned cable bolts and their application to the stabilization of underground openings are investigated. The study program undertaken involves field, laboratory and numerical studies which aim to improve understanding of the role of passive cable bolting in rock mass support. The higher residual load carrying capacity of the cable and the grout-aggregate mix is compared with that of the conventional grout (cement + water). Based on the variational approach, an analytical model has been developed to calculate the distribution of shear bond stress along the embedded length of a cable bolt. A parametric study is then undertaken to illustrate the support behavior of cable bolts with different grout compositions. A special finite element for the cable bolt was formulated and integrated into existing finite element code called MSAP2D, in order to allow the simulation of cable bolts in underground excavations. A practical example is presented to demonstrate the effect of cable bolts on the stability of the opening. The simulation is carried out using the newly developed numerical model with cable bolt simulation capability.</description><creator>Rajaie, Hossein</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Experimental and numerical investigations of cable bolt support systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn106z83f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945r493</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60cx036</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis investigated melodic memory and perception in patients with unilateral left (LT) or right (RT) temporal-lobe lesions and in normal control (NC) subjects. Experiment I examined learning and 24-hour retention of unfamiliar tunes and nonsense words. Both temporal-lobe groups were impaired in learning the tunes and the words. Long-term retention of these stimuli showed that subjects with a RT lobectomy were more impaired in recognizing the tunes than the words, while subjects with a LT lobectomy were more impaired in recognizing the words than the tunes. This study demonstrated the differenting roles of the right and the left temporal lobes in long-term retention of musical and verbal information, respectively. Experiment IIa and IIb investigated memory for songs (words sung to a tune). Recognition of the melodic component resulted in a deficit for both RT and LT groups, but the nature of the impairment seems to be related to the side of the lesion. Patients with LT lobectomy showed deficits in tune recognition mediated by words, but not for tunes sung without words. Patients with RT lobectomy were impaired in tune recognition, whether or not words were sung to the tunes. On the other hand, the well-known verbal memory deficit was shown after a LT lobectomy when the words actually form part of the stimulus as well as when the words are spoken. In experiment III two melodic discrimination tasks were created to test the hypothesis that the RT and the LT lobes are specialized for global and local information processing, respectively. The results showed that impairments under both experimental conditions regardless of the side of the temporal lobectomy suggest that the two temporal lobes are involved in the processing of contour and interval information.</description><creator>Samson, Séverine</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Memory.</subject><subject>Temporal lobes.</subject><subject>Auditory perception.</subject><title>Contribution of the left and the right temporal lobes to melodic memory and perception</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hq39h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cx036</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hq408</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Canadian Radio-television and Telecommission Commission (CRTC) is the body which regulates communications activity in Canada. It has become almost a cliche to say that in addition to simply formulating regulations, the Commission has also been the dominant policy-maker in the communications field. The allegation has been made that the CRTC is "out of control", usurping a policy-making role more properly exercised by elected government officials, while also defying their attempts to constrain its behaviour. It has further been argued that this Commission usurpation and defiance has meant that both the minister and Parliament have little or no influence to direct the agency. The study demonstrates that the Commission has often acted as a policy-maker but that this role has been in response to the existence of a policy vacuum and lack of leadership from elected government. Furthermore, the agency has assumed a policy-making role not through an act of usurpation but with the tacit consent of elected officials. For these officials, the CRTC performs a useful function "insulating" them from the need to make a decision (and accept responsibility) on policy issues which often involve difficult political choices. The study also shows that the agency's "political masters", Cabinet and Parliament, possess a variety of both formal and informal control mechanisms which effectively prevent the CRTC from maintaining a policy position independent from government.</description><creator>Hall, Richard, 1957-</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Broadcasting policy -- Canada</subject><subject>Canadian Radio-Television and Telecommunications Commission</subject><title>The CRTC as a policy-maker, 1968-1982 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d494j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hq408</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fb494920t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Rhabdomyosarcoma is a class of malignant neoplasms composed of cells histologically resembling fetal striated muscle. It is the most common soft tissue tumor of children, adolescents, and young adults. In this Thesis, I demonstrate that the rhabdomyosarcoma tumor class is delimited in molecular genetic terms by the expression of the MyoD gene, and that loss of alleles on chromosome 11 distinguishes between the embryonal and alveolar subtypes. The elucidation of this genotypic distinction resolved the paradox between phenotypic variation and an apparent histogenetic relatedness between and among rhabodmyosarcomas. It also allowed for the construction of a two-tiered scheme for the unequivocal differential diagnosis of rhabdomyosarcoma and its subtypes. MyoD is syntenic to but distinct from Rd, a locus consistently involved in the etiology of the embryonal subtype. Abnormal segregation of alleles on chromosome 11p in both familial and sporadic embryonal rhabdomyosarcoma results in retention of only paternal alleles in tumors and supports a model of tumorigenesis involving unlinked modifier loci which inactivate Rd, perhaps by genome imprinting. Uniform loss of heterozygosity at loci on chromosome 11 in phenotypic variants of embryonal rhabdomyosarcoma that show simultaneous differentiation into another neoplastic tissue type implies that mutation at Rd is one of the earliest somatic events.</description><creator>Scrable, Heidi</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Molecular genetics of childhood rhabdomyosarcoma</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bf677.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494920t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c827n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Regulation of tubulin gene expression in embryos of the sea urchin Lytechinus pictus has been experimentally investigated by use of cloned recombinant tubulin DNA and anti-tubulin antiserum. Tubulin synthesis appears to be autogenously regulated at the level of tubulin mRNA stability by the level of unpolymerized tubulin; i.e., the more unpolymerized tubulin, the less stable the tubulin mRNA. Destabilization of tubulin mRNA requires continued protein synthesis. Most of tubulin stored in eggs is unpolymerized; during embryogenesis the mass of tubulin per embryo changes little, but unpolymerized tubulin is increasingly polymerized into microtubules. There is a transcriptional stimulation of tubulin genes at the time of ciliogenesis but thereafter autoregulation by the ontogenetic decrease of the level of unpolymerized tubulin plays a predominant role for an increasing accumulation of tubulin mRNA. Deciliation results in a transient enhancement of transcription of tubulin genes, which is independent of the level of unpolymerized tubulin and does not require protein synthesis.</description><creator>Gong, Zhiyuan.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Genetic regulation.</subject><subject>Sea urchins -- Embryos.</subject><title>Regulation of tubulin gene expression in sea urchin embryos</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831ck66j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c827n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8623hz43g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis describes a study of the effect of microstructure on the thermal stability of poly(vinyl chloride), PVC, vinyl chloride-ethylene, VC-E, and vinyl chloride-propylene, VC-P, copolymers obtained by chemical modification of PVC. The VC-E copolymers, with an ethylene content between 1.1 and 21 mole %, are random copolymers with approximately the same degree of polymerization as the original PVC. A decrease in the number of defect sites is observed with extent of reaction. Concomitantly, the syndiotacticity increases. The VC-P copolymers, with propylene content of ca. 0.1%, also have less labile chlorines than the homopolymer since these react preferentially. The thermal stability of solid state samples was studied, at temperatures between 150 and 190$ sp circ$C under a nitrogen atmosphere, using a conductimetric method to measure evolved HCl. The thermal stability of the modified samples is improved relative to that of the initial homopolymers. For the VC-E copolymers, a linear relationship is observed between the rates of degradation and the number of labile chlorines, total double bonds and the degree of syndiotacticity. The role of syndiotacticity on the thermal degradation behavior is confirmed in results obtained with two unmodified PVC samples, with a similar number of defect sites but different syndiotacticity. The more syndiotactic resin shows a higher thermal stability. The average polyene sequence length is independent of the ethylene concentration. Thus, the ethylene units do not interfere in the development of polyene sequences. The VC-P copolymers also show improved thermal stability as compared to that of PVC. However, the improvement is less than that of the VC-E copolymers, due to a lower extent of substitution of labile sites. PVC previously saturated with HCl shows a markedly increased rate of degradation reflecting the autocatalytic role of HCl. For the PVC coated samples, a decrease in the degradation rates with decreasing PVC film thickness is observed due to more efficient removal of HCl. The PVC mixtures with Chromosorb W or silica gel exhibit a decrease in the dehydrochlorination rate constants with decreasing PVC content. The inert substrate acts as a diluent and avoids agglomeration of the samples and thus facilitates the removal of HCl.</description><creator>Velazquez, Alberto</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>Microstructure and thermal stability of PVC and chemically modified PVC</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w032376t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623hz43g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rp37k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Injection molded Short Glass Fiber Reinforced Thermoplastics (SFRTP) are widely used in industry because of advantages in material properties, availability, economics and ease of processing. The thermo-mechanical history experienced by the material during processing produces significantly anisotropic microstructural and consequently mechanical properties, varying not only spatially, but directionally. This work attempts to examine quantitatively various aspects of microstructure and the effect of processing conditions in SFRTP. The matrix phase properties, such as crystallinity, morphology and molecular orientation distribution, as well as the fiber phase microstructure such as concentration, length and orientation distributions have been analyzed quantitatively, and explained. Experimental techniques, including optical and electron microscopy, differential scanning calorimetry, Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy, thermo-gravimetric analysis, etc. have been used. The results indicate complex changes in microstructure from skin to core in the injection molded samples. Both matrix and fiber phase microstructures are affected by the basic thermal and flow processes that occur during the injection molding process. A first order model has been developed to predict fiber orientation distributions, which agree well with the experimental results.</description><creator>Singh, Peter</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Plastics Technology.</subject><title>Molding behaviour and microstructure of injection molded short glass fiber reinforced polypropylene composites</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472x12g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rp37k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mj743</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, we establish tight bounds on the maximum size of maximum hidden sets, minimum guard sets, and minimum partitions and covers of polygons, using link-visibility. These results unify and generalize the guard set results (and combinatorial method) of Chvatal and O'Rourke. Our method also provides tight bounds on independent and dominating sets in triangulation graphs, and almost-tight bounds on the size of hidden sets, guard sets, covers, and partitions of polygon exteriors. We also prove that, using link-visibility, the optimization problems of finding maximum hidden sets, minimum guard sets, or minimum covers are NP-hard. Link-visibility is an extended notion of visibility arising from robotics and motion planning problems. Hidden sets are sets of points in a polygon such that no two points of the set are visible, and guard sets are sets such that each point of the polygon is visible to some point in the guard set. Both maximum hidden set sizes and minimum guard set sizes can be used as polygon shape complexity measures.</description><creator>Shermer, Thomas C.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Visibility properties of polygons</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xv74v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mj743</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72p7894</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Continuous phasing is a technique for cell culturing that is able to reveal metabolic responses during the cycle of cell growth and division. This is accomplished by the correspondence between the periodic addition of a limiting nutrient and the time required for the growth of a generation of cells. The utility of the technique was greatly improved by the development of a feedback system to control the period of nutrient addition. The production of the biosurfactant surfactin was studied using Bacillus subtilis ATCC 21332. The feedback control system was effective in optimizing the period of nutrient addition, resulting in an increase in the production rate of surfactin by at least a factor of ten in comparison to batch culture. The inherent stability of the new technique also provided a means for characterizing the dynamic response of microbial cultures to changes in the environment.</description><creator>Sheppard, John D.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Feedback control and the continuous phasing of microbial cultures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988k63g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p7894</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g0901</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, the effect of geometrical roughness of a non-deformable road surface on the mobility performance of a pneumatic tyre is investigated. A system function which represents the theoretical relationship between the drawbar-pull and the random traction surface geometry is developed in the frequency domain, associated with the energy conservation law. Prior to the analysis, measurement of road profile is achieved using an ultrasonic distance detector, and characterization of the stochastic road profile is evaluated by a power spectral density function. Further to this, the resulting drawbar-pull and tractive efficiency for a given slip rate, applied torque, tyre characteristics (as a function of inflation pressure) and vehicle moving velocity are evaluated through the above-mentioned system function. The enveloping function, describing the modification effect of the original road profile by a flexible tyre, is also experimentally investigated. Systematic laboratory tests are carried out by using four pseudo-random rough traction surfaces, for comparison and verification of the theoretical predictions. Through combined theoretical and experimental investigations, the following conclusions are obtained: (1) As the traveling speed increases, tractive efficiency is gradually decreased. (2) Higher slip rates give less tractive efficiency, however, an optimum slip rate between 2% and 10% provides the highest efficiency. (3) Tractive efficiency increases hyperbolically with an increase in the inflation pressure of the tyre. (4) A substantial decrease in tractive efficiency is obtained when the condition of the road surface becomes sufficiently rough that the road would be classified as "poor" or rougher under the ISO recommendations, at a speed of 5 m/s (18 km/h).</description><creator>Eiyo, Fumiharu</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Effect of off-road surface roughness on tyre performance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526d08s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g0901</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d504rm04x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The processing conditions for carbothermal reduction of silica to silicon nitride was found to be sensitive to several key processing parameters: namely the intimacy of mixing of carbon and silica, the temperature, the specific high surface area of carbon, the nitrogen gas purity and the action of the nitrogen gas passing through the reactants. Sol-gel processing was found to provide superior mixing conditions over dry mixing, which allowed for complete conversion to silicon nitride at optimum carbon:silica ratios of 7:1. The ideal reaction temperature was found to be in the range of 1500$ sp circ$C to 1550$ sp circ$C. Suppression of silicon oxynitride and silicon carbide was achieved by ensuring that: (a) the nitrogen gas was gettered of oxygen, and (b) that the gas passed through the reactants. Thermodynamic modelling of the Si-O-N-C system showed that ordinarily the equilibrium conditions for the formation of silicon nitride are very delicate. Slight deviations away from equilibrium leads to the formation of non-equilibrium species such as silicon carbide caused by the build-up of carbon monoxide. Reaction conditions such as allowing nitrogen gas to pass through the reactants beneficially moves the reaction equilibrium well away from the silicon carbide and silicon oxynitride stability regions. The particle size of silicon nitride produced from carbon and silica precursors was of the order of 2-3 $ mu$m and could only be reduced to sub-micron range by seeding with ultra-fine silicon nitride. It was shown that the mechanism of nucleation and growth of unseeded reactants was first nucleation on the carbon by the reaction between carbon, SiO gas and nitrogen (gas-solid reaction), and then growth of the particles by the gas phase reaction (CO, SiO, N$ sb2$).</description><creator>Durham, Simon J. P.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><title>Carbothermal reduction of silica to silicon nitride powder</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c1212.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rm04x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8s45q9683</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A comparative diagnostic study of upper-air persistent atmospheric events, as simulated by a general circulation model (GCM) and as observed, is presented. We start with an overview of the several theories that attempt to explain such phenomena. Particular emphasis is put on the model approach of Shutts (1983). We next show that the spatial distributions of persistent events is qualitatively similar in the GCM and observational data. The North-Atlantic events are extracted and a rotated empirical orthogonal function (REOF) analysis is done on the resulting data sets. The two REOF sets that are thus obtained are shown to greatly resemble one another. Both explain roughly 50% of their original data's variance. The relationships between the modes within a set are presented, so as to understand their probable combined evolution. The fourth chapter contains an evaluation of Shutt's theory. There, the third chapter's results are used to isolate a particular class of events, namely the strong +ATL2 dipoles. The time-tendencies associated to short time-scale synoptic waves are evaluated, using an E-vectors approach, taking care to distinguish between the onset, mature and demise phases of the events. It seems that these synoptic waves have a significant impact of the average life-cycle of this +ATL2 type of events, whether they be simulated by a GCM or obtained from a NMC set of analyses.</description><creator>Dugas, Bernard</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>Persistent circulation anomalies in observations and in a general circulation model</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bc273.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45q9683</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945r514</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The prediction of mean end-to-end delay of multiple packet messages is the focus of this thesis. The models established are of great importance to network designers as they provide the basis for meeting user requirements for time delays and for network throughput. Two distinct models are developed depending upon the traffic load requested by network users. The first model considers traffic conditions in which the traffic demand heavily loads the computer network. Mean end-to-end message delays are computed by assuming the existence of product form solution of the obtained closed queueing network model. Heuristics are developed and are validated via simulation to render the computation feasible and to extend the solution method to non product form networks. Under light traffic conditions, clusters of packets resulting from message segmentation may enter the computer network. To this end, algorithms are developed to determine the network performance measures of closed queueing networks in which bulk transitions are possible. A second message delay model is then developed to take into account the clustered arrival of packets to the network. All models and heuristics are validated via simulation. Finally, the appropriate length of the packets into which a message should be segmented is addressed. The performance tradeoff between message delay and throughput is discussed. Boundaries delimiting the packet size to meet user requirements are established for delay and throughput.</description><creator>Evéquoz, Claude</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Message delay models of packet-switching networks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k796s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945r514</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j96021409</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Mavropoulos, L. T.</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Austenite</subject><subject>Niobium alloys</subject><subject>Steel alloys</subject><subject>Boron steel</subject><title>The synergistic effect of niobium and boron on recrystallization in hot worked austentite /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z601g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j96021409</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pg976</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Gauthier, Laurent</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Farm management -- Databases.</subject><subject>Farm management -- Computer programs.</subject><title>Development and use of a database and program package for farm production management</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r639w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pg976</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17ct701</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Ferland, Mark B.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Infant psychology.</subject><subject>Infants -- Development.</subject><subject>Auditory perception in children.</subject><title>Infants' categorization of melodic contour</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vh49n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17ct701</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53jx77n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Dyck, Elmer.</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Religion, General.</subject><title>Canon and interpretation : recent canonical approaches and the Book of Jonah</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935373q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53jx77n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mm968</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Tomascik, Tomas.</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Corals -- Growth.</subject><subject>Corals -- Barbados</subject><subject>Scleractinia -- Barbados.</subject><subject>Eutrophication -- Barbados.</subject><title>The effects of eutrophication on the growth rates, reproductive potential and community structure of the inshore reef-building corals in Barbados, West Indies /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956g61d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mm968</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Oceanography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892b54p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Simons, Lloyd D.</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Number theory.</subject><subject>Hilbert algebras</subject><subject>Galois theory</subject><title>The structure of the Hilbert symbol for unramified extensions of 2-adic number fields /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17ct72k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892b54p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2j62s556x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Sanielevici, S. (Sergiu)</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Quantum chromodynamics</subject><subject>Particles (Nuclear physics)</subject><title>Phenomenological implications of calculations in nonperturbative QCD</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tv832.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s556x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150k00t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Tobin, John M. (John Michael)</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Biomass energy</subject><subject>Rhizopus arrhizus.</subject><title>The uptake of metal ions by rhizopus arrhizus biomass /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w0323773.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150k00t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):41400</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>