<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:52:24Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):250" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3n2041129</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Activation of GABA$ rm sb{B}$ receptors inhibits spontaneous and evoked neuronal activity in different regions of the central nervous system, including the nucleus tractus solitarius (NTS), the projection site of pulmonary vagal afferent fibres. These studies were designed to test the hypothesis that GABA$ rm sb{B}$ receptors in the NTS modulate the vagally mediated cardiorespiratory reflexes. Experiments were conducted on 53 spontaneously breathing, urethane-anesthetized (1.2-1.6 g/kg) and atropinized (0.2 mg/kg) rats. Tracheal pressure, tidal volume, mean arterial blood pressure, and the integrated diaphragmatic electromyogram (DiEMG) were recorded. The medulla was prepared for bilateral NTS injection of 110 nl of saline (vehicle), and 60 pmol baclofen, and 2.8 nmol CGP35348, a GABA$ rm sb{B}$ receptor agonist and antagonist, respectively. Injection sites were confirmed histologically. Results support the hypothesis, but suggest that the cardiorespiratory pattern and the vagally mediated reflexes are not tonically controlled by GABA$ rm sb{B}$ receptors under the present conditions. The different effects of baclofen on inspiratory time and expiratory time suggest a difference in the distribution of GABA$ rm sb{B}$ receptors in neuronal networks controlling each of these respiratory phases. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Seifert, Erin.</creator><contributor>Trippenbach, Teresa (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Modulation of the vagally mediated cardiorespiratory reflexes by medullary GABAB receptors in rats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qk785.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n2041129</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv935495z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>ET sc A is expressed predominantly in myocardium and smooth muscle. Fusion plasmids of luciferase and the 5$ sp prime$ flanking region of the human ET sc A gene were transfected into rat vascular smooth muscle cells (A10), primary cultures of porcine aortic smooth muscle cells (PSMC), a pluripotential embryonal cell (P19) induced to differentiate to a myocyte lineage, and COS7 cells. Binding studies showed no ET receptors in COS7 while the others expressed high levels of ET sc A. Mock transfected cells expressed negligible levels of luciferase activity (RLU). Transfection with the region $-$848 to +92 bp of ETA (relative to transcriptional initiation) resulted in several hundred fold increase in activity with the highest levels seen in cells expressing ET sc A (Mean $ pm$ SEM: PSMC = 4748 $ pm$ 521 RLU, A10 = 6670 $ pm$ 304 RLU, COS7 = 1268 $ pm$ 212; PSMC vs. COS7 p = 0.0035, A10 vs. COS7 p = 0.001). Deletion from $-$848 to $-$625 (including a CARG box) resulted in a 20-60% loss of promoter activity (p = 0.01). Further deletions to $-$116 increased activity 2 fold (p = 0.05) suggesting the presence of a weak negative regulatory element. Two strong positive regulatory elements: the first one whose deletion led to a loss of 80% of promoter activity, was identified between $-$116 and $-$38; and the second one was identified between +90 and +200 in an area which exhibited $&gt;$80% homology between the human and the murine gene. In conclusion: (1) The region between $-$848 bp and +92 bp of the human ET sc A directs the expression of a reporter gene to significantly higher levels in myocytes normally expressing the receptor compared to non-expressing cells, (2) weak negative and strong positive regulatory cis-acting elements have been identified in this region.</description><creator>Schipper, Mitchell.</creator><contributor>Magder, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Expression of the endothelin-A receptor gene during differentiation : analysis of promoter function</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m379r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935495z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rb68xd697</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effects of agricultural development on wood turtles (Clemmys insculpta) were investigated in Quebec during 1994 and 1995. Age structures, growth, and mutilation rates were compared between an agricultural population and a reference site in an undisturbed forest. Turtles in the 0-4 year age class were absent from samples taken at the agricultural site. Overall, 23% less juveniles were encountered at the agricultural site. In addition, relatively fewer adults were captured from the 20+ age class. Shell injuries were twice as common at the agricultural site when compared to the forest site; whereas, limb amputations were twice as frequent at the forest site. Although shell injuries inflicted by predators occurred with similar frequencies at both sites, there were 2.7 times more fractures resulting from anthropogenic sources at the agricultural site. Multiple limb loss occurred only at the forest site. Tail amputations occurred with similar frequencies at both sites. Casts of pleural scute annuli revealed that turtles at the agricultural site had significantly lower growth rates during their second decade of life. Females at the forest site were significantly larger for all measurements recorded; whereas, males differed only with respect to carapace and plastron lengths. Agricultural development may have resulted in reduced growth, recruitment, and predation rates, as well as increased adult mortality.</description><creator>Saumure, Raymond A.</creator><contributor>Bider, J. Roger (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Wood turtle -- Wounds and injuries -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Wood turtle -- Habitat -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Wood turtle -- Age.</subject><subject>Wood turtle -- Growth.</subject><title>Growth, mutilation, and age structure of two populations of wood turtles (Clemmys insculpta) in southern Québec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569634r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xd697</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:td96k464q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A large organization that has many projects to manage may want to build a model that gives an overview of the common and variable parts of its projects' processes. This action is process model generalisation. The McGill Software Engineering Laboratory has developed a technique and a tool to achieve that. The work described in this thesis consisted of reengineering the tool to give it a longer life expectancy and to make it part of a future client-server architecture suitable for developing a suite of process management tools. The tool was effectively reengineered and this helped the laboratory define the architecture better. Also, some lessons about software maintenance were learned.</description><creator>Sarrazin, Pierre, 1971-</creator><contributor>Madhavji, Nazim H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Engineering, Industrial.</subject><subject>Operations Research.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Reengineering a process model generalisation tool</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827d60k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k464q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924d71b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Motivated by Geographical Information Systems (GIS) applications, we introduce a new data model for mutually nested objects. Combining features from relational as well as object-oriented database systems, our data model is efficient for queries involving multiple access patterns. By maintaining symmetrical relationships between entities, we allow nesting to be formulated dynamically at the query level rather than the data model level, thus dissociating the data structure from the access method. In addition, we do not favor one access pattern over another by clustering data in one particular manner, giving therefore flexibility and performance to our system. In order to integrate nesting into the relational algebra, we propose an extension to Relix, which is an academic database management system. We then show how those modifications can be used in a wide variety of queries, provide an algorithm to translate nested queries into flat relational expressions, and finally show that similar improvements can be applied to SQL allowing nested queries to be expressed more naturally.</description><creator>Saliba, Walid.</creator><contributor>Merrett, Timothy H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Information Science.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Queries on mutually nested objects, motivated by GIS applications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rn28q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924d71b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43p0168</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The application of elliptic curves to the field of cryptography has been relatively recent. It has opened up a wealth of possibilities in terms of security, encryption, and real-world applications. In particular, we are interested in public-key cryptosystems that use the elliptic curve discrete logarithm problem to establish security. The objective of this thesis is to assemble the most important facts and findings into a broad, unified overview of this field. To illustrate certain points, we also discuss a sample implementation of the elliptic curve analogue of the El Gamal cryptosystem.</description><creator>Saeki, Mugino.</creator><contributor>Avis, David (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Crepeau, Claude (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Elliptic curve cryptosystems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42n9864.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p0168</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4f16c463z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>To investigate the localization and targeting of sodium channels in neurons, an efficient means of gene delivery will need to be established. Two amplicon-based viral approaches and a recombinant whole virus approach were attempted in order to package and express RIIA sodium channel tagged with a c-myc epitope (RIIA-myc) with the ultimate purpose of developing a Herpes virus-based model system for targeting studies. Immunofluorescent staining of transfected epithelial cells was carried out to demonstrate that constructs created for use in these HSV-based approaches were capable of a high level of expression of RIIA-myc. Measurements of $ beta$-galactosidase reporter gene expression observed in cultured cells infected with RIIA amplicon virus suggested successful packaging of amplicon DNA. However, RIIA-myc expression from amplicon virus was not apparent, which may suggest recombination events occurred upon packaging of constructs. Difficulties in selection for recombinants with acyclovir prevented the recombinant whole virus approach from being pursued.</description><creator>Sadl, Virginia.</creator><contributor>Dunn, Robert J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Herpes simplex virus.</subject><subject>Genetic recombination.</subject><subject>Sodium channels.</subject><title>Herpes virus-based packaging systems for gene delivery of the RIIA sodium channel</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t3985.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c463z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053j10m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this work is to design a system for the visualization of geographical terrain in three dimensions. The input of such a system is the contour map of the region to be visualized. Several approaches to solve this problem can be found in the literature. Our approach is based on surface reconstruction or interpolation. We achieve the reconstruction of the terrain surface by pairwise triangulation of map contours in adjacent height levels. The large data size in this application dictated the use of an optimal triangulation algorithm. The algorithm we employed (by G. Toussaint) runs in $O(n(1+t sb0)$ time with $t sb0&lt;n$ (where n is the number of vertices of the polygon being triangulated, and $t sb0$ is a measure related to the shape complexity of the polygon). Also, we implemented several data processing steps to convert the map data from its original ASCII based format into a format that facilitates the application of the triangulation algorithm. Moreover, we employed line generalization techniques to get rid of redundant data and reduce its size. The output of the triangulation is a polyhedral terrain ready for visualization. Finally, we present an efficient output sensitive hidden-line removal algorithm (by Preparata and Vitter) designed specifically for terrain visualization. This algorithm is the final component of our terrain visualization system.</description><creator>Saadé, Elie S.</creator><contributor>Merrett, Timothy H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Triangulating contours in large maps</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f552s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053j10m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qf85nd09c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The splotch (sp) mutation has been identified as a mutation in the paired box gene, Pax-3. Heterozygous mice carrying this mutation are phenotypically normal, with the exception of a white spot on their bellies. Homozygous embryos do not live to birth, and suffer from a wide range of developmental defects, all of which result from delayed neural tube closure, or inadequate neural crest cell migration. Most notably, homozygotes have an increased rate of spina bifida with or without exencephaly. Retinoic acid (RA), which has been shown to be very important in the development of a number of systems, was shown to cause a selective mortality of the homozygous splotch embryos when administered maternally at day 9 p.c. (Moase and Trasler, 1987). Since cellular retinoic acid binding protein (CRABP) is localized to the tissues which are affected by both the splotch gene, and retinoic acid teratogenesis, its expression patterns in the developing splotch embryo were examined. It was found that the distribution of CRABP mRNA is normal, but its expression levels are excessive in splotch homozygous day 9 mouse embryos.</description><creator>Roundell, Jennifer.</creator><contributor>Trasler, D. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Carrier proteins.</subject><subject>Mice -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Mice -- Cytology.</subject><subject>Neural tube -- Abnormalities.</subject><subject>Tretinoin.</subject><title>Cellular retinoic acid binding protein (CRABP) mRNA expression in splotch mutant mouse embryos</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719p25q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nd09c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3197xn66r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Factors affecting catch, trap fishing power and reef fish trappability were investigated by experimental fishing with Antillean fish traps on west coast fringing reefs in Barbados. Commercial (small mesh) traps caught significantly more fish (by number and weight), caught significantly smaller fish, and caught a higher proportion of immature fish, than large mesh traps. Fishing power was significantly higher for commercial traps than for large mesh traps. These catch differences between trap types have serious implications for the management of the reef fish resource by the imposition of larger mesh sizes in the commercial fishery. The squeezability hypothesis and the visual image hypothesis were investigated as explanations for the lower fishing power of large mesh traps. The lower fishing power of large mesh traps results primarily from lower catch rates of fish in the 5.5-6.0 cm body depth size class. This result is strong support for the squeezability hypothesis as an explanation for the lower fishing power of large mesh traps. Differences in the visual images of traps created by structural differences and biotic differences did not produce definitive differences in ingress rates to traps, suggesting that the visual image hypothesis is an inadequate explanation for the lower fishing power of large mesh traps. The trappability of reef fish differed substantially between species, but trappability differences were not correlated with species mobility, activity of the species in traps, gregariousness, or capacity of the species to squeeze through meshes. Predator-prey effects on trappability were negligible, but trappability was negatively correlated with percent reef cover of the substratum and with substratum rugosity. This suggests that traps are more attractive to fishes in areas where natural structural complexity is lower. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Robichaud, David.</creator><contributor>Hunte, Wayne (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Fisheries -- Barbados.</subject><subject>Fish traps -- Barbados.</subject><title>Factors affecting catch, fishing power and trappability in the Barbados trap fishery</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r299b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xn66r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sf58k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Each of two detectors used in our Positron Emission Mammography (PEM) system consists of four 36mm x 36mm x 20mm bismuth germanate (BGO) detector blocks coupled to a crossed-wire anode photomultiplier tube (PMT). To achieve a high spatial resolution, the crystal blocks have been finely pixelated using a diamond saw. In each detector, 36 x 36 1.9mm x 1.9mm crystal elements are coupled directly to the PMT window and, on the opposite face of the blocks, 35 x 35 elements are offset by 0.9mm along both the x- and y-axes of the PMT. Techniques developed for the successful machining and surface-preparation of the detector blocks are described. Results indicating the detector block performance in terms of spatial and energy resolution are presented. As part of a system calibration routine, a novel method for crystal element identification has been developed. This robust and reproducible algorithm succeeds in identifying 59 x 49 crystal elements on each detector face. The results are used to generate a Look-Up-Table (LUT) that is accessed during data acquisition for the effective correction of spatial distortion inherent in the detectors. Crystal identification also facilitates an improvement of the capability for accurate energy discrimination, since the detector gain and energy resolution are considered on an element-by-element basis by accessing an energy LUT. Employing a third LUT, which contains the relative efficiencies of individual crystal elements results in a significant improvement in detector uniformity.</description><creator>Robar, James L.</creator><contributor>Thompson, C. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Construction and calibration of detectors for high-resolution metabolic breast cancer imaging</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fn70p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sf58k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150m044</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Growth cones from rat dorsal root ganglia plated on laminin make transient adhesions through punctate integrin clusters called point contacts. We used immunocytochemistry to investigate if point contacts represent a specialized adhesive structure linking integrin clusters to the cytoskeleton. The cytoskeletal proteins vinculin, paxillin and talin colocalized with $ beta1$ integrin in a subpopulation of point contacts restricted to the lower membrane of the growth cone, in the central domain and at filopodial tips. The kinases p125$ sp{ rm FAK}$ and pp59fyn associated with the vinculin-positive clusters. The Rho GTPases were also present in growth cones, but only RhoB colocalized with point contacts at filopodial tips. Point contacts share some cytoskeletal and signalling proteins with focal contacts, which are the adhesion sites of non-neuronal cells. In fact, migrating glia and fibroblasts in culture had both focal and point contacts. We propose that point contacts are specialized for adhesion of highly motile structures.</description><creator>Renaudin, Agathe.</creator><contributor>McKerracher, Lisa (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Immunocytochemical characterization of point contacts in neuronal growth cones</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr172022q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150m044</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b532j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Microwave-Assisted Process (MAP$ sp{ rm TM}$) is an enhanced extraction technology patented by Environment Canada. MAP uses microwaves to rapidly transfer target compounds from one phase to another by selectively heating the phase containing the target compounds. This thesis presents the results of research performed to determine whether the MAP technique can be further developed into a large-scale soil treatment process that overcomes the limitations of conventional remediation technologies. The dielectric properties of several mixtures of acetone and hexane over a temperature range from 25$ sp circ$C to 50$ sp circ$C were measured. The dielectric constants of these mixtures were found not to vary significantly with temperature. A study of microwave absorption by heterogeneous mixtures showed that adding a solid material to a low dielectric constant solvent resulted in energy being preferentially absorbed by the solid. The results of laboratory extraction tests showed that the ability of the MAP technique to extract contaminants was affected by the organic matter content of soil, particularly in the presence of water. Use of a closed-vessel system yielded a 60% to 175% increase in the extraction of PAHs from a low organic-content soil relative to that achieved in an open-vessel system. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Punt, Monique M.</creator><contributor>Raghavan, G. S. V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Soil remediation.</subject><subject>Soils -- Organic compound content.</subject><subject>Extraction (Chemistry)</subject><title>Microwave-enhanced extraction of organic contaminants from soil</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n204113k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b532j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806185z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thermal conductivity $ kappa$ of the high-temperature superconductor $ rm YBa sb2Cu sb3O sb{7- delta}$ has been the subject of numerous investigations in recent years. Previous measurements show that $ kappa$: (1) exhibits a large peak in the superconducting state; (2) is anisotropic in the basal plane of the orthorhombic crystal structure. The main two subjects of this thesis are: (1) the origin of the peak and (2) a detailed investigation of the anisotropy. In order to investigate the relative contribution of electrons and phonons to the heat conduction in YBCO, we have measured the thermal and electrical conductivities of high-quality twinned and detwinned crystals, with different levels of Zn-doping (from 0% to 3%). We found that the peak was rapidly suppressed by the impurities. Two scenarios are used to explain our results, attributing the effect to decrease in the carrier mean free path of either the electrons or the phonons. As for the anisotropy between the a-axis and the b-axis, only two previous studies had previously been done. We find some new striking features: (1) a peak appears in $ kappa sb{chain}$ below 50 K, revealed as a result of our using of higher purity samples. (2) this peak is similar to that of $ kappa sb{a}$ below $T sb{c} (i.e., kappa sb{plane}),$ which we take as the evidence for the growth of superfluid density in the chains below 60 K. We discuss these results in terms of a model of single-electron tunneling between chains and planes.</description><creator>Pu, Song, 1968-</creator><contributor>Taillefer, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Heat transport in the high-temperature superconductor Yttrium Barium copper oxide</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074x20b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806185z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773x67n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The nature of the rehearsal mechanism that supports short-term memory span (STM), and the role of lexical and semantic knowledge in list recall was evaluated. Forty university students (aged 17-29 years) recalled lists of words varied in syllable-length (SL), articulatory duration (AD), phonological similarity (PS), semantic relatedness (SR) and frequency of occurrence (FO). Auditory and visual presentation, vocal and picture-pointing recall, and concurrent articulation conditions were included. Nonword recall was evaluated using stimuli varied in SL and PS was also evaluated using a repetition task. Word length effects were found for word stimuli varied in SL but were absent or reversed for stimuli varied in AD. A non-articulatory basis for rehearsal is suggested. The influence of long-term semantic and lexical knowledge in recall is inconclusive due to a lack of SR. Nonword repetition ability reflects STM capacity in adult subjects and correlates with other measures of STM span.</description><creator>Pollock, Susan, 1965-</creator><contributor>Waters, Gloria S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Psychology, Experimental.</subject><subject>Psychology, Cognitive.</subject><title>The role of articulatory-phonological and lexical-semantic factors in short-term memory span /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns0647783.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773x67n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451k60v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Genetic predisposition to insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus (IDDM) involves one or more loci within the class II region of the major histocompatibility complex (MHC). The strongest MHC-linked determinants of disease susceptibility have been associated with polymorphisms in both the $ alpha$ and $ beta$ chain subunits of HLA-DQ (human) and I-A (mouse) class II molecules. Specifically, protection against IDDM development is associated with the presence of aspartic acid at position 57 of the $ beta$ chain while non-aspartic acid residues are found in diabetogenic $ beta$ chains. In humans, the greatest risk of disease development is observed in individuals with Arg 52$ rm sp+ alpha/Asp 57 sp- beta$ heterodimers. The BB rat is a useful system in which one can identify and characterize the genes necessary for the onset of IDDM. Although sequence data have been reported for various alleles of these class II genes, the effect of polymorphisms in the rat MHC is not nearly as well characterized as it is in humans or the NOD mouse. The rat MHC (RT1) contains two expressed class II loci, RT1.B and RT1.D, each encoding two class II molecules: RT1.B $ alpha$ and $ beta,$ and RT1.D $ alpha$ and $ beta.$ This study determined the nucleotide sequences of relevant regions from the RT1.B and RT1.D $ alpha/ beta$ genes in five rat strains (ACI, BB, Buffalo, Lewis, and Wistar-Furth) of varying susceptibility to IDDM to examine the role of specific polymorphisms in predisposition to disease. The data show that BB and Wistar-Furth rats (RT1$ sp{ rm u}$ haplotype) have identical class II sequences at all of the regions examined. Although no unique $ alpha$ chain sequences were found to associate with IDDM, we did confirm the association of aspartic acid at position 57 of RT1.B$ beta$ with susceptibility to diabetes. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Pointer, Rohan.</creator><contributor>Finks, Abraham (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>MHC-linked genetic susceptibility to insulin-dependent diabetes mellitus (IDDM) in the BB rat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qp025.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451k60v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rq692</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Roots of silver maple (Acer saccharinum L.) trees from downtown Montreal and the municipal nursery in Terrebonne were sampled to determine their vesicular-arbuscular mycorrhizal (VAM) colonization levels. Soil was analyzed to determine the concentration of various soil nutrients, pH, and bulk density. It was found that trees from downtown Montreal grow in soils with lower phosphorus and magnesium, and higher copper, zinc, sodium, pH and bulk density than nursery trees. Downtown tree health, in terms of % dieback, was positively correlated with soil phosphorus, potassium, calcium, the phosphorus:copper ratio and negatively correlated with soil copper, zinc, bulk density and tree age. It is suggested that tree health and survival are associated with tree location. Older and healthier trees grow on streets that provide larger soil volumes. Downtown trees had significantly higher VAM colonization levels (44.9%) than those from the nursery (36.1%). The colonization level in downtown trees was positively correlated with the phosphorus:copper ratio and tree age, and negatively correlated with soil potassium. It is hypothesized that downtown trees living under the most stress will be those with the highest VAM colonization. Under controlled conditions 81.5% of the variability of % VAM infection of silver maple seedlings could be explained by soil zinc, phosphorus, copper, sodium, and potassium. Zinc, phosphorus and copper negatively affected VAM colonization, while a slight positive effect of sodium and potassium was found. This suggests that VAM colonization in downtown trees may be affected by soil factors, but the effects may be masked by other conditions, such as water stress, light, or size of root systems.</description><creator>Pezzente, Mauro.</creator><contributor>Hamel, Chantal (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Cote, Benoit (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Vesicular-arbuscular mycorrhizas -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Plant-fungus relationships -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Maple -- Soils -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Maple -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Trees in cities -- Environmental aspects -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>Effects of urban environmental conditions on the symbiosis between vesicular-arbuscular mycorrhizal fungi and silver maple (Acer saccharinum L.)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676x728.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rq692</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67jt18p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A research study was undertaken to determine the predictive capability of the AGNPS model with respect to surface runoff, peak flow, and sediment yield produced by rainfall-runoff events on a 26 km$ sp2$ watershed in Quebec. Precipitation, stream discharge, surface runoff, and suspended sediment concentrations were monitored for rainfall-runoff events occurring from 1994-96, inclusive. Data describing stream patterns, topography, soil type, and land use were collected and input to the model. Seven rainfall-runoff events were used for model calibration. Five storms were used to validate the model. Calibration curves were developed to correlate the antecedent precipitation index (API) to the SCS curve number. For model calibration, coefficients of performance of 0.05, 0.43, and 0.12 were obtained for surface runoff, sediment yield, and peak flow, respectively. For model validation, coefficients of performance (CP$ rm sp prime sb{A}$) of 0.02, and 0.01 were obtained for surface runoff, and sediment yield, respectively. Peak flow was generally overpredicted and yielded a CP$ rm sp prime sb{A}$ of 2.07. A sensitivity analysis showed API and associated curve numbers to be the most sensitive input parameters. USLE factors were also sensitive. The surface condition parameter and Manning's n had negligible influence on model output. The hydrograph shape factor toggle parameter showed extreme sensitivity. A simulation of best management practices on the basin estimated soil loss reductions of 15 to 25% for storms of varying magnitudes if a 4-year crop rotation implementing conservation tillage were to be adopted.</description><creator>Perrone, Jim T.</creator><contributor>Madramootoo, C. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Water quality -- Québec (Province) -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Hydrologic models.</subject><subject>Watersheds -- Québec (Province) -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Hydrological forecasting -- Québec (Province) -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Hydrologic modeling of an agricultural watershed in Quebec using AGNPS</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n3161.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jt18p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dp38j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The System of National Accounts inadequately reflects levels of, or changes in, the natural resource base. Natural Resource Accounts are designed to redress this shortcoming. A wealth account for Quebec agricultural land was constructed, taking an inventory of land with capability for agriculture and monetizing the stocks. The changes to the wealth account over a 15 year period represented a loss to the resource base of $260 million and an average annual charge against net farm income of $17.3 million. Prices for the valuation exercise were determined with the use of a Hedonic Pricing Model. The estimated implicit prices for the classes of the Canada Land Inventory revealed premiums for differences in productivity between the classes. Regional variables that accounted for many non-agricultural effects were also highly significant.</description><creator>Patterson, Katherine Liza.</creator><contributor>Thomassin, Paul (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Farms -- Valuation -- Québec (Province) -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Sustainable development -- Québec (Province) -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Agricultural resources -- Valuation -- Québec (Province) -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Wealth accounts for agricultural land : a hedonic pricing approach</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x109w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dp38j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vd472</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The function of the Escherichia coli Ner like protein (Nlp) was investigated by identifying genes which Nlp may regulate. To identify these genes, lac Z gene fusions were generated in a strain of E. coli whose own nlp gene had been interrupted by a luxAB tet insertion. Each clone within this gene fusion collection had the lac Z gene integrated into a random location on the E. coli chromosome. Clones in which the lac Z gene had inserted within a gene regulated by Nlp were predicted to have a different lac Z phenotype on X-gal plates depending on the presence or absence of Nlp expressed from a plasmid borne copy of the nlp gene. Of the 3360 clones screened, 5 were found to have an altered lac phenotype in the presence of Nlp. Three of these clones were found to have lac Z expression induced by Nlp, one was found to be repressed by Nlp, and one clone died upon Nlp expression. These putative Nlp-responsive genes were subcloned into pBR322 to facilitate their identification. Restriction map analysis, double stranded DNA sequencing and single stranded DNA sequencing were used to identify the Nlp responsive genes. Genes that responded to Nlp overexpression were: o80 ('glycosol hydrol F5'), plsB (which encodes a glycerol-3-phosphate acyltransferase), cscB (which encodes a sucrose permease), pgi (which encodes glucose-6-phosphate isomerase), and nuoF (which encodes the F subunit of NADH dehydrogenase). (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Paterson, Lisa.</creator><contributor>DuBow, M. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Escherichia coli genes regulated by the transposable coliphage Ner like protein-NLP</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dv11n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vd472</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hh63sx802</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The focus of this thesis was on the economic feasibility of three food processing projects. They involved freezing of pork loin and fish using cryogenic freezing and stored at $-$18, $-$12 and $-$7$ sp circ$C, and modified atmosphere packaging (MAP) of pork loin using a combination of nitrogen and carbon dioxide gases, chitosan dip and stored at 5, 10, and 15$ sp circ$C. A production plan with similar layout and capacity was adopted for the Montreal area. The benefit-cost analysis (BCA) of each project was carried out assuming that each plant operated approximately 2000 hours per annum at full capacity. Net present value (NPV) and benefit cost ratio (B/C ratio) at 8% discount rate, and internal rate of return (IRR) were determined for each project. The calculations show the NPV of $2.4 million, $1.8 million, and $3.4 million; B/C ratio of 1.09, 1.09, and 1.10; IRR of 15 %, 13 %, and 18 % for frozen pork loin, frozen fish and MAP pork respectively. All IRRs were higher compared to the 1995 return rates of TSE of 9.7 % and the average return of capital of 8.8 % for some food and beverage industries. These economic values are sensitive to changes in working hours, price of raw materials and finished products. It is also found that MAP products could be stored at temperatures up to 15$ sp circ$C. Frozen products could be stored at temperatures of $-$12$ sp circ$C and below only if the length of distribution chain can be reduced. This would decrease electricity costs up to 36% at each level of distribution. It can be concluded that the three projects are economically profitable.</description><creator>Owusu-Manu, Michael.</creator><contributor>Gunjal, Kisan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Fishery processing -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Pork industry and trade -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Fishery products -- Preservation -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Pork -- Preservation -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>Economic feasibility of minimally processed pork and fish in Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977x01v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sx802</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720f920</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two experiments were carried out to assess the nutritional potential of food wastes to be transformed into duck meat. In both experiments, 600 day-old unsexed White Pekin ducklings were randomly distributed into 6 different dietary treatment groups. In both experiments, the ducks receiving food wastes had significantly ($ rm P&lt;0.05$) more total body fat than did the control. This was most likely due to the quantity of dietary fat ingested by the ducks. The results reported in this thesis indicate that it is possible to raise Pekin ducks to market weight using food wastes as the only source of feed. To meet the consumer demand of leaner carcasses, the food wastes with a high fat content should be included in a limited amount in the ration. The recycling of industrial food wastes into animal products could be considered an important step toward a sustainable agriculture system in Quebec. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Normand, Luc.</creator><contributor>Chavez, E. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Touchburn, S. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Ducks -- Feeding and feeds -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Ducks -- Feed utilization efficiency -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Waste products as feed -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>Recycling of agro-industrial food wastes into feed for Pekin duck meat production towards a sustainable agriculture in the province of Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz8061867.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720f920</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04dr543</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Selection and adaptation paradigms have been jointly employed in the derivation of a theoretical model of firm evolution. This construct enabled researchers to explore: "why are there so many different kinds of organizations?". In that, evolutionary influences and adaptive firm behaviour were simultaneous forces that shape the survival of organizational forms over time. Such a notion was applied towards a dynamic programming context. This dynamic programming model was translated into a computer simulation such that an empirical representation of firm evolution was depicted. The results from four computer simulations confirmed the selection and adaptation propositions described in this research. The simulations found evolutionary forces to be significant determinants to differentiating firm survival. While, adaptive firm behaviour only served to prolong organizational survivability with in the confines of the selection forces of the market. Future organizational research should focus on expanding the dimensions of strategic adaptation, strategic, voluntarism, niche width dynamics, organizational inertia theory and organizational slack. By addressing these areas, a more comprehensive depiction of organizational evolution could be attained.</description><creator>Ng, Desmond.</creator><contributor>Goldsmith, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Westgren, Randall (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Organizational change -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Microeconomics.</subject><subject>Organizational behavior -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Micro-economic evolution of the firm : an organizational ecology perspective</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b533t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dr543</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wj018</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cellular adhesion interactions involved in invasion and migration are crucial to cancer metastasis. Neoplastic tissue explants were cultivated in three-dimensional collagen lattices and monitored for the detachment of coordinated locomoting tumor cell clusters. Blocking monoclonal antibody treatment (10ug/mL) against the $ beta sb1$ and $ alpha sb2 beta sb1$ integrin receptors on cluster surfaces allowed the functional evaluation of these receptors during metastatic invasion. Clusters in treated wells exhibited a loss in migratory persistence, reduction in cluster motility and a greater amount of "stops" during migration as compared to control wells for both anti-$ beta sb1$ and anti-$ alpha sb2 beta sb1$ respectively. These results suggest that $ beta sb1$ integrins, and more specifically, $ alpha sb2 beta sb1$ play a significant role in maintaining normal cell-cell and cell-matrix interactions during metastatic invasion. Preliminary investigations using the anti-cancer drug, Taxol, against clusters within collagen matrices revealed a significant decrease in the total distance traveled, average speed and persistence, implicating its efficiency against certain cancers. The use of 3-D collagen systems for cell communication studies on locomoting tumor cell clusters may reveal novel and potentially important mechanisms involved in metastatic invasion as well as facilitate future assessment of potential anti-neoplastic drugs.</description><creator>Muradali, Sheri.</creator><contributor>Noble, P. B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Invasion and migration of clusters in oral carcinomas within three-dimensional collagen matrices : the effects of blocking b1 and a2b1 integrin function</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kj27p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wj018</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v493k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:03:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis investigated the epidemiology of atopy in Kenyan children. Analysis was based on data gathered on 599 rural and 567 urban children, as part of a research program on childhood asthma focussing on the impact of urbanization. Atopy was more frequent in urban than rural children (22.9% vs 14.7%). The unadjusted odds ratio for urban rural differences in atopy was 1.75, 95% CI 1.30 to 2.36. Urban children were also younger, taller, weighed more and were breastfed for shorter periods compared to rural children. They were also more likely to have a family history of allergic disease but were less likely to share their bed, use allergenic mattresses and live in homes with pets and smokers. When the urban rural differences were adjusted for these differences in the distribution of personal, environmental and socio economic characteristics, the odds ratio fell to 0.81 and became nonsignificant (95% CI 0.50 to 1.33). Therefore, the urban rural difference in the prevalence of atopy in Kenyan children appear to be due to the differences in the distribution of the relevant risk factors.</description><creator>Mungai, Mary.</creator><contributor>Becklake, M. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Sociology, Public and Social Welfare.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>The epidemiology of atopy in Kenyan children /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rk12n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v493k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Occupational Health</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):275</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>