<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:28:47Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34875" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn9998290</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The concept of matter as it is treated in the philosophical systems of Aristotle, Thomas Aquinas, and John Duns Scotus is examined, partly to ascertain the influence which the original Aristotelian concept of matter had on the two medieval thinkers, and partly to determine which of these two thinkers remained more faithful to the original Aristotelian concept. An analysis is carried out of the views of the three philosophers regarding the ontological status of matter; the intelligibility of matter; the issue of the real distinction between matter and form; the role played by matter in individuating composite substances; and its role in defining composite substances and determining their essences. Finally, the views of Aquinas and Scotus regarding the theory of universal hylomorphism and the theory of the plurality of forms are discussed and compared. It is shown that, while most of the Franciscan philosophical tradition up to Scotus's time was far more influenced by Platonist than by Aristotelian principles, Scotus, though a Franciscan, was much closer to Aristotle than to Plato in his views regarding matter. In fact, the few deviations from the original Aristotelian concept found in Scotus's theory can be ascribed to theological concerns. It is argued, furthermore, that Scotus's views on the concept of matter are far closer to the original Aristotelian theory than our analysis shows Aquinas himself to be.</description><creator>Massobrio, Simona Emilia</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Thomas, Aquinas, Saint, 1225?-1274 -- Views on matter</subject><subject>Aristotle -- Contributions in concept of substance</subject><subject>Aristotle -- Contributions in concept of matter</subject><subject>Duns Scotus, John, ca. 1266-1308 -- Views on matter</subject><title>Aristotelian matter as understood by St. Thomas Aquinas and John Duns Scotus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811km30w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn9998290</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278v86c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sons of male alcoholics (SOMAs) are at increased risk for the development of alcoholism, and are apparently characterized by other abnormalities. It is possible that one or more of these abnormalities might serve as a marker for the alcoholic predisposition. Research described in this thesis, conducted in the hopes of identifying such a marker, was designed (1) to separate the relative pharmacological and psychological effects of acute alcohol intoxication upon neuropsychological functioning; (2) to investigate the neuropsychological function of SOMAs with a multigenerational family history of male alcoholism; (3) to examine the relationship between SOMAs' neuropsychological function and their cardiovascular hyper-reactivity to threat of and aversive stimuli; and (4) to investigate the relationship between a number of cardiovascular response patterns and voluntary weekly alcohol consumption. These studies are linked conceptually, within the context of a general theory of information-processing and action.</description><creator>Peterson, Jordan Bernt</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Children of alcoholics</subject><subject>Alcoholism -- Psychological aspects</subject><title>Potential psychological markers for the predisposition to alcoholism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149r27f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278v86c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v692t792s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The choice behaviour of winter beach vacationers to the Caribbean is modelled with an experimental multiattribute research technique, the discrete choice experiment. Hypothetical destination scenarios are defined using ten variables, each having three levels. The variables refer to the accommodation, its price, its distance from the beach, the airport and various tourist services. These scenarios are located in one of five Caribbean islands. Distance to beach and price are the most significant variables, and only hotel size is not. Estimates of the relative utility of each of the attributes make the approach relevant for destination planning. Segmentation by socio-demographic characteristics and past vacation behaviour makes the research relevant for destination marketing. Choice probabilities can be estimated for any of the scenarios. The discrete choice experiment can contribute to narrowing the paradigmatic split between destination-oriented and market-oriented tourism research. It is also attractive to applied tourism research because simulation constitutes a convenient tool for managers and decision-makers.</description><creator>Haider, Wolfgang</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Tourism.</subject><title>The choice behaviour of Caribbean winter beach vacationers : an experimental study in the Ottawa area</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j2782.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t792s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1831cm603</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>While the sixteenth-century transculturation of tobacco was an event of momentous significance in European and Amerindian history, no thorough, anthropological analysis of its effects has heretofore been attempted. This may be attributed partly to traditional acculturation models which have tended to emphasize only changes inflicted on native populations and have often failed to contextualize natives and newcomers within a single bilateral, historical trajectory. This study surveys the effects of smoking on European culture and on colonial activities in America. This is followed by an extensive scrutiny of ethnohistoric and archaeological evidence relating to the use of pipes and tobacco at all socio-political, economic and ideological levels of contact between Europeans and North American Indians. While sharing the pipe fortified native institutions and served as a lubricant in relations between two very different peoples, it eroded the intellectual boundaries between "savagery" and "civilization." The final chapters of the study trace the reactions to this erosion in both academic and popular discourse.</description><creator>Von Gernet, Alexander D.</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Indians of North America -- Tobacco use</subject><subject>Europe -- Civilization -- Effects of smoking on.</subject><subject>Colonies -- America -- Effect of smoking on</subject><title>The transculturation of the Amerindian pipe tobacco smoking complex and its impact on the intellectual boundaries between 'savagery' and 'civilization', 1535-1935</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xt34z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cm603</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dt65r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation constitutes the first monograph devoted to Qalawun's life and reign based on the contemporary and original data found in the Arabic chronicles of the period. An historiographical approach has brought to light information regarding the career of this sultan and has revealed contemporary historians' perceptions of his role as sultan. On the basis of an analysis of several aspects of the political and administrative, economic and social structure of the empire, which reflects the emphasis of the sources on the activities of the sultan, we concluded that centralization of sovereignty was enhanced during Qalawun's reign. But, whereas the historians attribute this development to the sultan's political convictions, analysis of the events they record indicates that other factors--most significant of which was the superimposition of the Mamluk system on the political, economic and social structure of Egypt and Syria--largely explain this trend.</description><creator>Northrup, Linda.</creator><contributor>Donald P. Little (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1982</date><subject>Mamelukes.</subject><subject>Egypt -- Kings and rulers.</subject><subject>Egypt -- History -- 1250-1517.</subject><subject>Qalāwūn, Sultan of Egypt and Syria, d. 1290.</subject><title>A history of the reign of the Mamluk Sultan al-Manṣûr Qalâwûn (678-689 A.H./1279-1290 A.D.) /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78td76w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dt65r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h618k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study presents methodology for technical and economic performance analysis of conventional grinding circuits supported by two industrial cases. A review of the strengths and weaknesses of Bond work index and population balance modelling approaches to plant circuit analysis discloses the need to refine work index determinations, and to establish a system of more meaningful ball mill circuit performance parameters. The statistical reliability of carefully determined rod mill work index efficiency ratings is presented. Technical and economic performance improvements through rod mill speed and feed water rate adjustments are presented. Parameters which separately characterize overall ball mill circuit classification and breakage efficiency are presented. Their relationships with circuit design and operating variables and overall circuit efficiency and economy are discussed. The particle size dependence of flotation is used to estimate the value of the grinding circuit product, and thus to integrate grinding into the overall economics of a flotation concentrator.</description><creator>McIvor, Robert E. (Robert Emmett)</creator><date>1988</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Technoeconomic analysis of plant grinding operations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v952j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h618k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8p58pf550</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis endeavors to render anarchist thought more appropriate to contemporary political life. It attempts to show that what is needed is not an overarching theoretical system, but rather explorations of new organisational forms. I will try to demonstrate that supported by anarchistic trends in social theory, anarchical organisational forms are taking place to some extent in practice. These transformations, it is maintained, are a desirable political response to contemporary technological change.</description><creator>Roy, Remi</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Anarchism</subject><subject>Social systems</subject><title>Anarchism and civil society</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f758m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pf550</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3197xn31n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It has been proposed that CD4+ T cells and cell-mediated immunity play a central role in corneal allograft rejection. Two subsets of CD4+ T cells, Th1 and Th2 cells, are known to cross-regulate each other through their cytokine pattern and the immune response might be directed predominantly in one or the other direction. As such, it has been hypothesized here that predominant Th1 type immune response could lead to corneal allograft rejection, and that previous inflamed corneal beds (high-risk eyes) might augment the Th1 response and thus accelerate the graft rejection. Reverse transcription of mRNA followed by polymerase chain reaction amplification was used to determine the relative gene expression in ocular tissues (cornea and iris/ciliary body) obtained from syngeneic grafts, low- and high-risk allografts. Compared with the syngeneic grafts, mRNA analysis of the low- and high-risk allografts showed a significantly decreasing expression pattern for the Th3 cytokine TGF-beta2, an early peak followed by a decline in the Th2 cytokines IL-4 and IL-10 expression, and a progressively increasing expression of the Th1 cytokines IL-2 and IFN-gamma and the proinflammatory cytokines IL-1beta and TNF-alpha, which paralleled the course of graft rejection. Prevascularization of the recipient eye (high-risk) significantly accelerated the rejection of corneal allografts and the mRNA levels of the Th1 cytokines IL-2 and IFN-gamma and proinflammatory cytokines IL-1beta and TNF-alpha in high-risk allografts were significantly higher and peaked faster than that in low-risk allografts. In vivo gene transfer using plasmid DNA encoding cytokines is an attractive alternative to modulate the Th1 inflammatory reaction and immune response. This has led to the hypothesis that transferring the gene encoding Th2 cytokine IL-10 into the recipient could prevent or reduce the subsequent corneal allograft rejection through the suppression of Th1-mediated alloimmune response. Intramuscular injection with in vivo electroporation of IL-10 plasmid DNA was administered at one week before and at one week after corneal transplantation. Corneal allograft survival was significantly prolonged and the rejection rate was significantly reduced after gene therapy with IL-10 plasmid DNA, compared with that in control groups treated with the empty plasmid vector. In IL-10 treated rats, the mRNA expression for the Th1 cytokines IL-2 and IFN-gamma was depressed, and the IL-10 mRNA expression was significantly increased. However, graft survival was not permanent. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Wang, Wen-Hua, 1965-</creator><contributor>Burnier, Miguel N., Jr. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Ophthalmology.</subject><title>Cytokine gene expression and gene therapy in experimental corneal graft rejection</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386m04c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xn31n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vj38b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis comprises three essays on market microstructure, focusing on the issues of insider trading, asymmetric information and market liquidity. The first essay examines the effects of the mandatory disclosure regulations on the trading behavior of informed traders. Specifically, we compare the (perfect Bayesian) equilibrium when disclosure is mandatory to the equilibrium when insiders do not have to disclose their trades. We show that under mandatory disclosure the market becomes more efficient and more liquid, making the uninformed traders unambiguously better off. We also show that in order to conceal part of his information, under mandatory disclosure the insider may trade against his information, and, at the same time, add a random---"noise"---component to his trade order. As a result, insiders may end up buying (selling) when his information indicates the asset is overvalued (undervalued). This provides a rationale for contrarian trading. The second essay examines trading behavior, price behavior and the informational efficiency and the informativeness of the price process in the equilibrium of a strategic trading game when some investors receive information before others. We show that the early informed investor may trade against his information to maintain his information superiority over the market. Under some conditions, subsequent price changes are positively correlated. We also find that the price process is less efficient and less informative than would be the case where there is no late-informed trader. The third essay analyzes the infra-day behavior of market liquidity of the Toronto Stock Exchange which uses a computerized limit-order trading system. Along with previous studies, we show that the U-shaped infra-day pattern of spread does not depend on the market architecture. In addition, we confirm that bid-ask spread and market depth are two dimensions of market liquidity. Liquidity providers use both dimensions to deal with adverse selection problems. We also examine how price volatility and trading volume affect market liquidity. Price volatility is inversely related to market liquidity but trading volume is directly related to liquidity. High trading volume implies high liquidity trades and as a result, liquidity providers decrease (increase) ask (bid) price and/or increase depth at each quote.</description><creator>Vo, Minh Tue, 1965-</creator><contributor>Greenberg, Joseph (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Microeconomics</subject><subject>Securities</subject><subject>Stock exchanges</subject><title>Insider trading, asymmetric information, and market liquidity : three essays on market microstructure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848s182.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vj38b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591b00s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In contrast with the procedural orientation of Athenian law in his day, Aristotle thinks that the lawcode should include principles which explain the rules of the lawcode and guide the interpretation of these rules in difficult cases. It should be determined by majority vote whether the decisions and proposals of political experts are consistent with the principles of the lawcode. Aristotle's views on practical explanation support his views on political deliberation. Someone has a techne rather than mere empeiria if he can give an account of the principles of an art and is able to explain the results of his deliberations in the art in terms of the principles. Such explanation does not have the same status as apodeixis in the epistemai, in that such an explanation cannot demonstrate that a conclusion follows necessarily from the principles of the art. However, a person who has experience in the art is able to evaluate deliberative options based on such arguments. Aristotle has an account of practical intellection which, like Plato's, is theory-based. Aristotle's account is an adjustment of Plato's account in the light of Isocrates' criticisms of Plato. Aristotle combines the accounts of Plato and Isocrates---the emphasis of the one on explanation and the emphasis of the other on practical principles. Aristotle's views on practical intellection allow him to solve a problem associated with Plato's proposals in the Laws, which resemble in important respects Aristotle's own proposals. Plato intends in the Laws to introduce an arrangement on which the polis is governed by non-philosopher citizens educated by the lawcode. However, because of his views on practical intellection, Plato is forced to put the 'Nocturnal Council' in charge of 'preserving the laws'. Because of his views on practical intellection, Aristotle can accept that the majority can be in charge of preserving the law. Aristotle's views on practical intellection also allow him to say that one ought to spell out the principles of the lawcode and privilege them in the interpretation of the law---which is different from the Athenian, procedural approach to the law---even though no universally true claims are possible on practical issues.</description><creator>Vlahovic, Denis</creator><contributor>Deslauriers, Marguerite (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Menn, Stephen (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Sociological jurisprudence -- History.</subject><subject>Aristotle</subject><subject>Law -- Philosophy -- History</subject><title>The sovereignty of the lawcode in Aristotle /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xg51n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591b00s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720f45m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, we add a new vectorial particle to the standard model, a new particle that has the special property of having a vacuum state breaking Lorentz invariance and, therefore, CPT invariance. At the level of energy of the world we live in, this particle is expected to be in this vacuum state and we therefore should see around us some phenomenon that do not respect Lorentz invariance that comes from the interaction of this vectorial particle with ordinary matter. This thesis is presented in two parts. In the first part, we write every possible term involving our new vectorial field with ordinary matter while, in the second part, we calculate the effects of some of those terms and look at any experimental evidence for the calculated effects.</description><creator>Tremblay, Luc, 1969-</creator><contributor>Burgess, Clifford (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>Effects of a particle spontaneously breaking Lorentz invariance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719n81v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720f45m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440v20v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We apply the methods of statistical mechanics and field theory at finite temperature to understand phenomena in intermediate and high energy heavy-ion collisions. In the intermediate energy scenario we concentrate on the pervasive phenomena of multifragmentation. We introduce various extensions of the recently proposed Recursive Statistical Multifragmentation Model (RSM model). In particular, we devise a novel Monte-Carlo technique to improve the treatment of the excluded volume in the model. We consider extensions to account for Coulomb effects and inclusion of isospin degrees of freedom. We then devise a consistent decay formalism to account for the change in isotope ratios due to decay of particle unstable clusters produced in such systems. We demonstrate how, with the above mentioned extensions, populations of various intermediate mass fragments observed in experiments may be explained. We then focus on the possible observation of critical phenomena in experiments, and provide a criticism of the parametrization techniques currently used by practitioners in the field. We demonstrate how such techniques may lead to misleading interpretations and identifications of critical phenomena. In high energy heavy-ion collisions, we focus on the ongoing search for the Quark-Gluon-Plasma (QGP). The QGP is formed for a very short time and hence its presence is inferred through indirect signatures. In this thesis, we concentrate on the electromagnetic signatures of such a plasma. We demonstrate how the explicit breaking of charge conjugation invariance by the QGP may lead to the appearance of processes hitherto considered absent due to symmetry considerations. These processes allow for gluons to fuse to form lepton pairs and turn out to be comparable, in certain regions of parameter space, to the tree level rate for lepton pair formation from quark anti-quark annihilation. We then investigate the issue of collinear and infrared divergences in two-loop dilepton production rates. This is done by calculating the imaginary part of the retarded two-loop self-energy of a static vector boson in a plasma of quarks and gluons. We recombine the various cuts of the self-energy to generate physical processes. We demonstrate how cuts containing loops may be reinterpreted in terms of interference between O(alpha) tree diagrams and the Born term along with spectators from the medium. We apply our results to the rate of dilepton production in the limit of dilepton invariant mass M &gt;&gt; T. We find that all infrared and collinear singularities cancel in the final result obtained in this limit.</description><creator>Majumder, Abhijit</creator><contributor>Das Gupta, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Gale, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Physics, Nuclear.</subject><title>Matter under extreme conditions : theoretical studies in two energy regimes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214q70v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440v20v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:765372740</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A haptic display is capable of representing the virtual interaction between a tool and a deformable body in order to simulate the contact between them. This capability requires computations to be performed in real time in order to generate the force of the virtual interaction that closely resembles the force applied to the tool during actual mechanical interaction. Reasonable approximations must be made to make this possible. This thesis presents an algorithm for real time calculation of tool force-displacement response of contact interaction with a deformable body, during which the body is locally deformed and cut. The tool responses of contact interaction with a simulated body (with no cutting) are evaluated by interpolation of pre-calculated force-deflection responses each representing the response of contact interaction between a given tool and the body itself. The pre-calculated responses are prepared and stored during a preprocessing step. The interpolation approach ensures continuity of the rendered forces although these are obtained from pre-calculated responses at a set of discrete surface points. The process of cutting is reduced to three possible interaction modes: deformation, rupture, and cutting. During deformation the tool work is fully recoverable. The tool force is evaluated by pre-calculated responses obtained by measurements from tests performed on the body used in conjunction with reasonable approximations. During cutting, the tool work equals to energy spent on crack formation. The tool force is calculated from the fracture toughness of the body and the area of a crack extension defined by the tool motions. During rupture, the tool work is zero. The crack extension in the body is evaluated from the pre-calculated tool responses. Concerning the stability of contact interaction, a multi-rate multi-process strategy is introduced in which a high rate process computes the rendered forces from a buffered passive force-deflection model while a variable rate process updates the buffer such that the potential strain energy does not increase at the moment of buffer update.</description><creator>Mahvash Mohammadi, Mohsen</creator><contributor>Hayward, Vincent (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Haptic rendering of tool contact and cutting</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tw78d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/765372740</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78td775</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Six studies were conducted to examine the influence of various cognitive and social factors underlying children's suggestibility. In Study 1, a misinformation paradigm was used to assess if the addition of visual information to verbal reminders increases preschool children's accurate and inaccurate recall of an experienced event. The results showed that the presentation of pictorial information with verbal reminders increased children's susceptibility to misinformation; however, generation of guided visual imagery produced the same misinformation effects as simple verbal reminders. Study 2 examined the influence of guided visual imagery on kindergarten and grade 3 children's reports of an entire event. Children were interviewed three times about a true and false event. Half of the children were given guided imagery instructions the other half were asked to think about the events. The kindergartners were more susceptible to false event creation than the third-graders. Guided imagery did not increase the rate of false reporting, but the kindergartners who formed visual images of the false event included more false details in their false reports. Studies 3a and 3b examined the effects of timing and repetition of suggestive interviewing on kindergarteners' recall. The results showed that repetition of misinformation only increased suggestibility when the misinformation was temporally close to both the event and memory test. The long-term consequences of suggestive interviewing were assessed in both Studies 1 and 3a. The relative misinformation and facilitation effects were unchanged when the children were re-interviewed approximately five months after the initial memory test. Studies 4a and 4b examined the association between psychosocial and cognitive variables and interrogative suggestibility (Study 4a), susceptibility to misinformation (Study 4a), and false event creation (Study 4b). The results of Study 4a showed small but significant correlations between interro</description><creator>Melnyk, Laura Ellen</creator><contributor>Bruck, Maggie (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Recollection (Psychology)</subject><subject>Memory in children</subject><subject>Mental suggestion</subject><title>The influence of imagery, timing, and individual differences on the accuracy of children's recall /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708z37g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78td775</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q524jq415</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Metacognition is the monitoring, evaluating, and correction of one's own performance while engaged in an intellectual task. It has been explored within educational psychology in various cognitive and academic domains, for example, general problem solving, physics, reading, writing, and mathematics, and with different populations including children who are gifted, children who have learning disabilities, as well as children who have intellectual delays. Research in these areas has demonstrated that the use of metacognition differs with different levels of ability. Metacognition has rarely been mentioned in the psychomotor literature. It is not known whether children of different psychomotor abilities use metacognition differently. This study used a think-aloud protocol to compare the active use of metacognition in children with different psychomotor abilities---high skill (N = 8), average (N = 9), developmental coordination disorder (DCD) (N = 5)---during a novel motor task. Children with DCD did not verbalize fewer or different metacognitive concepts than either the average or high skill children, however, relative to their counterparts, a significant proportion of the concepts verbalized by children with DCD were found to be inappropriate or inaccurate. These findings reflect ineffective metacognitive processing by children with DCD during a psychomotor task. In general, the results of this study parallel those found in the cognitive domain. This study showed that children with differing psychomotor abilities also demonstrated differences in use of metacognition.</description><creator>Martini, Rose</creator><contributor>Wall, A. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Shore, Bruce M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Psychomotor disorders in children</subject><subject>Metacognition in children</subject><title>Metacognitive processes underlying psychomotor performance in children identified as high skilled, average, and having developmental coordination disorder (DCD)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128ng27g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jq415</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c534fq55r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The changes that affected Iranian women's lives after the coming of Islam in the seventh century were similar to the changes that occurred in their lives after the Islamic Revolution of 1979. In both cases these changes were largely wrought by men. Iranian women have been actively involved and have participated fully in diverse religious, political, and social contexts since the eighteenth century, but frequently without due acknowledgment. In the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries the belief that education was a pillar of freedom began to gain popularity among Iranian women. The efforts of women to secure an equal place with men in the nation's educational institutions received support from a number of women writers and poets in the form of protests and petitions. It was through this process that Iranian women learned the importance of education in freeing them from patriarchal bondage. The twentieth century, however, witnessed the destruction of most of Iranian women's hopes and quests. Different Iranian governments enacted a series of important laws and regulations touching on "women's issues." Most of the time, however, these governments failed to consider the voices, positions and demands of women concerning these "issues." In the last two decades, under the Islamic Republic, male authority figures continue to determine women's rights, identity, education, employment, and so on. Changes which affected the status of Iranian women came in the form of different religious decrees and laws that were justified by the argument that they all complied with the Quran and the hadiths. Iranian women have refused to abandon their quests for an improved or even equal status. Among these women, there are those who still believe that equality can be achieved under the Islamic Republic. Women such as Rahnavard and Gorgi are relying on a "dynamic jurisprudence" that would lead to "Islamic justice." There are also other women who argue that in order to bring about true social justice, women's oppression and subordination in any form must be eliminated. They find such injustice ingrained in the existing culture. Women such as Kaar and Ebadi are making women and those in power aware of the need to achieve a "civil society," based on "social justice" through the process of "revealing the law." This group is hoping that a gradual cultural revolution brought about by women will lead to the establishment of "such justice."</description><creator>Derayeh, Minoo</creator><contributor>Ghosh, Ratna (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Women -- Education -- Iran</subject><subject>Women -- Iran -- Social conditions</subject><title>High hopes and broken promises : common and diverse concerns of Iranian women for gender equality in education and employment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xw63j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fq55r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773x318</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation assesses whether intense visual stimulation can act as a stressor to migraine sufferers between attacks, and whether subjective and psychophysiological reactions to these stimuli can clarify how migraine attacks may be triggered. The first study assessed thresholds of light-induced discomfort and pain in migraine sufferers and non-migrainous controls during a non-headache period. Two instruction sets were compared to assess whether information presented to participants would affect thresholds. The results showed that migraineurs had significantly lower thresholds for light-induced pain. However, this effect was most apparent in those who had heard the negatively biased instructions reinforcing the need to control contextual factors when assessing subjective phenomena such as visual discomfort. The second study assessed subjective and psychophysiological responses of female migraine sufferers and female controls during exposure to visual stimuli incorporating spatial and temporal characteristics that are most likely to be bothersome to migraineurs. Two control stimuli were included to assess responses during similar, but theoretically less aversive conditions. Migraine sufferers had higher heart rate and more frequent electrodermal responses than controls at all points of the study, including baseline and recovery. However, while migraineurs reported higher anxiety during the intense conditions, and reported more visual and somatic complaints than controls during various viewing conditions, they did not show heart rate, heart rate variability or electrodermal changes that would suggest clear changes in autonomic function in response to aversive visual stimulation. The third study assessed ambulatory electrocardiograms to investigate whether autonomic changes would be evident in the period leading up to, during or following a migraine. Three individuals were assessed on a day when they experienced a naturally occurring headache, and on a day when they were not. No obvious pattern of autonomic change was detected before or after headache, although there was some evidence that a pattern of increased heart rate and decreased vagal tone may accompany headache. In summary, the results confirm that migraine sufferers are more sensitive to intense visual stimulation than controls, but do not support the contention that exposure results in widespread autonomic changes. Since interictal visual discomfort is a common in migraine, further research is needed to clarify how it can be incorporated into models of migraine pathophysiology.</description><creator>Crotogino, Jennifer</creator><contributor>Ditto, Blaine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Migraine</subject><subject>Vision disorders</subject><subject>Psychophysiology</subject><title>Visual stress in migraine : subjective and psychophysiological responses to intense visual stimulation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mx04k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773x318</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zg186</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis we examine the effect of hormone replacement therapy (HRT) on the risk of colorectal cancer. Also examined are the effects of oral versus transdermal estrogen replacement therapy, methods of defining estrogen exposure, selection bias, and trends in the use of HRT over the last two decades. A nested case-control study was conducted using records from Saskatchewan Health's administrative databases. Information on covariates not available from the databases was collected during interviews, from a subgroup of subjects. Incidence density sampling was used to age match controls (four per case, N = 12,116) to each of 3,059 cases accrued in the province from 1981 to 1998. Short and long durations of HRT use (&lt;5 years and ≥5 years) were associated with odds ratios (OR) of 0.86 (0.76--0.97) and 0.78 (95% CI: 0.64--0.86), respectively. Stratification according to history of having had a screening sigmoidoscopy did not eliminate the observed protective effect. Important differences were not seen between more recent HRT use (&lt;5 and &lt;10 years), compared with more distant past use (≥5 and ≥10 years). The use of various definitions of estrogen exposure produced ORs ranging from 0.78 to 0.99 which are similar to results from almost two dozen observational studies conducted over the past two decades indicating that this is an important source of variability that needs to be considered. The study of independent effects of oral and transdermal estrogens revealed a protective effect of transdermal estrogen that was much greater than that of oral estrogen and which has not previously been reported. A protective effect remained when women who had used oral estrogen only were used as the reference group. Data pertaining to lifestyle factors collected by interview appeared not to alter ORs for HRT and colorectal cancer. However, due to extremely low response rates in the interview phase of the study, 30% among cases and 18% among controls, we were unable to conclude whether or not confounding was eliminated. An important finding of research is the strong observed protective effect of transdermal estrogen replacement therapy. This demonstrates the importance of taking into consideration the mode of estrogen delivery in studies where the associations between HRT use and health outcomes are examined.</description><creator>Csizmadi, Ilona</creator><contributor>Collet, Jean-Paul (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>The effect of hormone replacement therapy on the risk of colorectal cancer in postmenopausal women /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483k90g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zg186</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tw79p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We compute the eigenvalues of the first few Hecke operators Tp (N( p ) ≤ 100) for all Hilbert modular forms on Q5 of parallel weight 2 and level of norm less than 500. This is done by exploiting the Jacquet-Langlands correspondence which allows us to transfer such computations to forms on the (totally definite) Hamilton quaternion algebra over Q5 . We use these computations to test numerically a conjecture of Oda on periods of Hilbert modular forms.</description><creator>Dembélé, Lassina</creator><contributor>Darmon, Henri (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Explicit computations of Hilbert modular forms on Q(square root 5)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698907m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tw79p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rg13w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Retinoic acid (RA), the major biologically active form of vitamin A, is required for normal development of the mouse embryo. In particular, RA is necessary for the correct anteroposterior specification of the embryonic axis. Exposure to RA at certain stages of development leads to premature truncation of the vertebral column, accompanied by spina bifida. In contrast, embryos that are homozygous null for RARgamma do not exhibit these defects, indicating that this receptor specifically mediates this teratogenic effect. Differential display PCR and suppression subtractive hybridization were employed using the RARgamma null embryos in an attempt to identify downstream targets that may be involved in the formation of these abnormalities. As a result of this process, a full-length cDNA molecule encoding a novel member of the aldo-keto reductase family (AKR1A4) was cloned. Although RA does not regulate the expression of this gene, its developmental expression pattern and substrate specificity suggests a potential role for this enzyme in the protection of certain rapidly growing embryonic structures from harmful metabolites. A precise level of RA signaling is also required for proper specification of vertebral identity. Exposure to excess RA during the early stages of gastrulation results in posterior homeotic transformations of several vertebrae. These transformations are correlated with shifts in the anterior boundaries of Hox expression. In contrast, the loss of functional RARs leads to anterior vertebral transformations. Although retinoic acid response elements have been identified in Hox promoters, it is likely that RA regulates the expression of some Hox genes through intermediary factors. Cdx1 is a homeobox-containing transcription factor that influences vertebral patterning in a manner similar to RARs, and is directly regulated by RA in the mouse embryo. Analysis of an allelic series of RARgamma/Cdx1 null mutant mice demonstrated that Cdx1 and RARgamma act synergistically to pattern certain cervical vertebrae. In addition, Cdx1 is required for the full effect of RA treatment on the vertebral column. However, Cdx1 does not mediate all of the effects of RARgamma as the incidence of a thoracic to cervical vertebral transformation is significantly higher in RARgamma/Cdx1 double mutants as compared to either single null mouse.</description><creator>Allan, Deborah M.</creator><contributor>Lohnes, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Retinoic acid and mouse development : identification of retinoic acid receptor target genes involved in axial patterning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77ft00g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rg13w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cc49r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis addresses long- and short-term neurotrophin modulation of basal forebrain cholinergic neurons (BFCNs), focusing on acetylcholine (ACh) release and choline acetyltransferase (ChAT; the enzyme responsible for ACh synthesis) activity. (1) Initially, ACh release was characterized from primary embryonic basal forebrain cultures. Release was vesicular, dependent upon extracellular choline and regulated by negative feedback via M2-like muscarinic receptors. (2) The next step was to determined the long-term (24--96 hour) effects of nerve growth factor (NGF), brain derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF), neurotrophin-4 (NT-4) and neurotrophin-3 (NT-3) on ChAT activity, ACh content, high-affinity choline uptake, constitutive and K+ stimulated ACh release. These experiments showed differential capacities of NTs to enhance cholinergic markers (NGF &gt; BDNF &gt; NT-4 &gt; NT-3) and that the various markers, although related, respond differentially to NGF. This is important because previously, direct relationships between these markers were largely assumed. (3) The acute effects of NTs on BFCN functional markers were also determined, and there was an activity dependent increase in ACh release. Short exposures (5--60 min) to NGF (0.1--100 ng/ml) robustly enhanced spontaneous ACh release (up to over 3-fold of control) without a persistent increase in ChAT activity. To our knowledge, this is the most potent enhancement of basal forebrain ACh release ever reported. The increases were TrkA NGF receptor and calcium dependent, but were not dependent upon de novo protein synthesis or cAMP. Further, even a brief (5--60 min) exposure to NGF increased ACh release (approximately 2-fold) for at least 4 h following its removal in a long term potentiation-like fashion. This property of inducing prolonged ACh release was shared with the other NTs (NGF &gt; BDNF &gt; NT-4 &gt; NT-3). (4) The relationship between the fast and long-term actions of NGF on ACh release/ChAT activity. Inhibition of protein s</description><creator>Auld, Daniel Scott.</creator><contributor>Quirion, Remi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Nerve growth factor modulation of basal forebrain neuron acetylcholine release : new perspectives on a classic interaction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515p953.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cc49r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10wr888</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>From an economic perspective, globalization is dismantling national barriers to entry and is transforming domestic markets into a global market. To meet the challenges posed by the integration of markets, corporations are joining forces with their former competitors to expand their presence in the global market. Rapid growth in transnational mergers to create global corporations is one of the key features of globalization. As multinational corporations are uniting, so should antitrust agencies that regulate them. Antitrust agencies around the world are realizing that the consumers whom they are mandated to protect are being adversely affected by decisions made beyond their national borders. By using the "effects" test, countries bring within their jurisdiction review of any merger or acquisition involving foreign companies with significant revenue or assets within their jurisdiction. The proliferation of merger control laws, in the absence of a mechanism to coordinate the transnational merger review, places an unnecessary burden on merging parties, and runs the risk of divergent outcomes, which at times cause friction among nation-states. Both to alleviate unnecessary burdens imposed on corporations and to reduce inefficiencies produced by the disparate review of a single transnational merger by several countries, this thesis proposes an International Merger Control Regime integrated into the WTO. The proposal focuses on ways to operationalize a "Lead Jurisdiction" model of oversight rather than on the creation of a new supranational decision-making agency. WTO dispute settlement and arbitration would be used to resolve conflicts arising out of the inability of a Lead Jurisdiction to arrive at an outcome satisfactory to other significantly affected jurisdictions.</description><creator>Wilson, Joseph, 1968-</creator><contributor>Janda, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>Globalization and the limits of National merger control laws : gaps in global governance and the need for an international merger control regime</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z9031571.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wr888</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440v22d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation examines lawyers and lawyering in post-Soviet Georgia. It suggests that the collapse of the Soviet Union triggered a rapid de-professionalization of lawyers. The monopoly of the Soviet-era Bar was broken, the number of law graduates multiplied, many of the objective conditions for lawyering (such as functioning courts) were simply absent and most jurists employed by state enterprises lost their jobs. In other words, lawyers were left with little control over their markets or work. But there has also been a growing movement towards the professionalization of lawyers since 1991. Intriguingly, the key to understanding the new professionalism lies not with the reconstruction of state-mandated monopolies (indeed for several years there was simply no law regulating the Bar), but rather with lawyers' attempts to control a market through means firmly lodged in culture and the politics of the post-Soviet transition. These means include a traditional reliance on reputation and networks. Comparisons are also made here to the legal professions in Armenia and Azerbaijan, revealing similar findings and rounding out this thesis as a regional study. The empirical findings, which are based on fieldwork carried out in Transcaucasia between 1998 and 2001, have implications for studies of the legal profession and the rule of law in transition societies.</description><creator>Waters, Christopher P. M.</creator><contributor>Macdonald, Roderick (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>History, European.</subject><subject>Law.</subject><title>Counsel in the Caucasus : the fall and rise of Georgia's legal profession</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s4063.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440v22d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qt61b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It has been argued that patients with frontal lobe lesions are impaired in temporal context memory and, more generally, in retrieving the source of one's knowledge or ideas. Furthermore, it has been speculated that a failure to retrieve source information may result in an increased susceptibility to distortions of episodic memories in patients with frontal lobe lesions. The precise role of the frontal cortex, however, in source or episodic retrieval is not clear. Does this region of cortex play a primary role or a secondary, executive role in the processing of such memories? Studies of patients with temporal lobe lesions have also shown impairments in episodic memory, including difficulties in the retrieval of source information. An important issue, therefore, is whether these two brain regions make different contributions to the processing of source information and to the retrieval of episodic memories. In the present experiments, patients with unilateral excisions restricted to frontal cortex or to the anterior temporal lobe were compared on various tasks examining source memory performance and the accurate retrieval of episodic information. The results of these studies failed to support the general contention that patients with frontal cortex excisions have source (or temporal context) memory impairments. Instead, differences between these patients and normal control subjects appeared to be contingent on whether strategic organizational or control processes were necessary for efficient processing of episodic information. The memory of patients with left temporal lobe excisions, on the other hand, was significantly impaired for both content and source information in most tasks. Furthermore, these subjects showed high rates of inaccuracies and distortions of memory. The false memories of this patient group were attributed to a combination of their poor memory for the specific items of the task and their over-reliance on semantic "gist" or on inferential knowledge about the events. Patients with right temporal lobe excisions were generally less severely impaired on the verbal memory tasks compared with those with left-sided lesions, but were impaired in their memory for the contextual aspects of an event.</description><creator>Thaiss, Laila Maria.</creator><contributor>Petrides, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Frontal lobes</subject><subject>Memory disorders</subject><subject>Temporal lobes</subject><subject>Memory -- Physiological aspects</subject><title>A comparison of the role of the frontal cortex and the anterior temporal lobe in source memory and in the accurate retrieval of episodic information /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kp742.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qt61b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278v896</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:48:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase (MTHFR) synthesizes 5-methyltetrahydrofolate, a methyl donor for conversion of homocysteine to methionine. A common thermolabile variant causes mild MTHFR deficiency, induces mild hyperhomocysteinemia when plasma folate levels are low and increases risk for neural tube defects (NTD) and pregnancy loss. To increase our understanding of Mthfr regulation, the 5' and 3' regions of the mouse cDNA and gene were characterized. These studies revealed two major promoters, an internal coding exon in the 5'UTR, alternative transcriptional and translational start sites and alternative splicing and polyadenylation. These data suggest that Mthfr regulation is likely to be complex. To investigate the role of Mthfr in NTD, several approaches were taken. First, folate and MTHFR co-factor, flavin adenine dinucleotide, were shown to stabilize normal and thermolabile MTHFR during heat inactivation, suggesting that folate might prevent hyperhomocysteinemia in individuals with thermolabile enzyme through protein stabilization. Next, in situ hybridization of neurulating mouse embryos showed that Mthfr is expressed in the forebrain, hindbrain, branchial arches, blood vessels, gut, and importantly, in the ventral part of the neural tube. Mthfr+/- mice were then used as a model of mild deficiency to address the effects of maternal and embryonic Mthfr deficiency on development. When combined with inadequate dietary folate, Mthfr +/- pregnant females showed a two-fold higher rate of pregnancy loss than Mthfr+/+ pregnant females. As well, a percentage of day 10.5 embryos from only the Mthfr+/- pregnant females were underdeveloped by 2 days. These effects were not apparent when dietary folate was sufficient, consistent with a genetic-nutritional interactive effect. Finally, folate metabolism was investigated in an NTD model, the curly-tail (ct) mouse, since the ct defect and Mthfr were mapped in close proximity. However, Mthfr sequence in ct mice was simila</description><creator>Tran, Pamela.</creator><contributor>Rozen, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Homocysteine -- Metabolism.</subject><subject>Neural tube -- Abnormalities.</subject><subject>Mice -- Molecular genetics.</subject><subject>Folic acid deficiency.</subject><subject>Methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase</subject><subject>Hyperhomocysteinemia -- etiology.</subject><title>Regulation of mouse methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase (Mthfr) and its role in early development</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053h70v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278v896</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34900</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>