<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T00:53:31Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):13175" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kx15h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ultra Wideband (UWB) is a rapidly growing technology for digital wireless communications. UWB utilizes low power, ultra short, pulses and is specifically suited for short-range, high-rate indoor wireless communications as well as fine localization applications. The attractive properties of UWB are a direct consequence of its very wide bandwidth that also implies an extremely high Nyquist sampling rate, so digital processing of UWB signals requires the use of fast and efficient, and therefore, expensive, Analog to Digital Converters. UWB systems are commonly used in indoor environments in which propagation is characterized by long but sparse multipath channels. Multi-path channels cause inter symbol interference (ISI) and introduce distortion to the received signal. To counter the effects of the channel, the channel impulse response must be accurately estimated at the receiver. There are two main estimation approaches for UWB channels: Compressed Sensing (CS)-based and Adaptive Filter (AF)-based. The former combine sampling and compression into a single linear measurement process that operates at sub-Nyquist rate by capitalizingon the sparsity of UWB signals. The latter, uses Least-Mean-Square filtering principles to obtain low complexity channel estimation methods. The problem we consider in this thesisis the estimation of a long sparse multi-path channel in an UWB system. We focus on systems that use Pulse Position Modulation (PPM) that is one of the most commonly used modulation schemes in UWB systems. We review CS and AF based methods and then we propose new AF-type methods specifically for the estimation of sparse multi-path channels with PPM inputs. The main idea behind the proposed methods is to estimate the long channel in sections in order to reduce the computational cost and improve the estimation performance. Finally, we present simulation results showing the superior performance of the proposed algorithms.</description><description>Ultra Wideband (UWB) est une technologie en croissance rapide de communications numériques sans fil. UWB utilise une faible puissance, ultra court, impulsions et est spécifiquement adapté à courte portée, haut-débit sans fil intérieure communications ainsi que lalocalisation fine applications. Les propriétés intéressantes de UWB sont une conséquence directe de son très large bande passante, ce qui implique également un taux extrêmement élevé Nyquist (taux d'échantillonnage, traitement numérique des signaux UWB requiert l'utilisation de rapide et efficace, et donc, cher, convertisseurs analogiques-numériques. UWB systèmes sont couramment utilisés dans les environnements intérieurs dont la propagation est caractérisé par un long mais clairsemée multipath canaux. Multi-canaux chemincause intersymbol causant des interférences (ISI) et introduire de distorsion du signal reçu. Pour contrer les effets du canal, le canal réponse impulsion doit être estimée avec précision au niveau du récepteur. Il existe deux principales approches estimation pour UWB canaux: Comprimé de télédétection (CS)-fondée et filtre adaptatif (AF)-fondée. L'ancienne moissonneuse-batteuse d'échantillonnage et de compression dans une seule mesure linéaire processus qui fonctionne en sous-fréquence Nyquist en capitalisant sur la faible densité dessign aux UWB. Ce dernier, utilise moins Mean Square filtrage principes pour obtenir une faible complexité canal méthodes d'estimation. Le problème que nous considérons dans cette thèse est l'estimation d'un long sparse multi-chemin canal d'un système UWB. Nous nous concentrons sur les systèmes qui utilisent Pulse Position Modulation (PPM) qui est l'un des plus couramment utilisé schémas de modulation en systèmes UWB. Nous revoir CSet AF fondées sur des méthodes et ensuite nous proposer de nouvelles AF-type méthodes spécifiquement pour l'estimation des sparse multi-chemin canaux avec PPM entrées. L'idée principale derrière les méthodes proposées est d'estimer le long canal en sections afin de réduire les coûts informatiques et améliorer les méthodes d'estimation des performances. Enfin, nous présentons les résultats de simulation montrant la supériorité de la performance des algorithmes proposés.</description><creator>Vala, Maryam</creator><contributor>Ioannis Psaromiligkos (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Estimation of sparse channels in IR-UWB systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79408140t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kx15h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343w388</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>While great efforts have been made in the electrical utility industry to engineer various stranded conductors with enhanced strength and vibrational characteristics, research devoted to understanding the complex mechanical behavior of complete conductors has been scarce, especially from a computational mechanics perspective. In the meanwhile, the long-lasting problem of conductor fretting fatigue becomes increasingly critical for overhead line design and maintenance, especially with the world-wide aging of electrical transmission grids. Aging of conductors contributes to significant degradation of their local fatigue strength, leading to drastic reduction of their service life.  However, the complex mechanical response of stranded conductors cannot be well predicted by either experimental testing or simplified theoretical models, owing to the physical complexity introduced by their multi-layer stranded geometry, nonlinear material properties, substantial frictions among the wires and between the wires and hardware clamping systems, as well as the comprehensive contact interactions amongst their components.  Simplified beam models and coarse 3-D models of earlier computational studies also fail to calculate the accurate stress variations inside a conductor strand and capture the stress gradients near the contact interfaces. Moreover, the estimations of fretting fatigue life are very dependent on the high accuracy of the stress predictions in the conductor wires.  Therefore, reliable high-fidelity computational models have been long expected for a better understanding of the contact damage of transmission line conductors under both design and fretting fatigue conditions. The main objective of this thesis is to study the complex stress states and relevant influencing factors of stranded electrical conductors, using finite element analysis approaches. The research was carried out in three stages. First of all, a study focused on the finite element (FE) modeling of an optical ground wire (OPGW) cable strand for its detailed stress analysis. A refined 3-D FE model including all essential nonlinear characteristics was successfully constructed.  As a result, a high-fidelity physics-based macroscopic modeling methodology was developed for detailed and accurate computational stress analysis of stranded conductors. A 795 kcmil Drake ACSR conductor was then selected as a benchmark conductor to investigate the tensile strength and critical stress states of a complete conductor under extreme design conditions. Furthermore, a sensitivity study explored the relative importance of friction effects among conductor wires on the mechanical response.A large scale 3-D FE stress analysis model with comprehensive nonlinearities was developed and implemented to simulate an actual ACSR fretting fatigue test. The computational results showed good agreement with some experimental measurements and field observations reported in the open literature.  Based on the accurate stress analysis, a practical multi-axial fatigue lifing methodology was developed to estimate local fretting fatigue strength of electrical conductors.  Subsequently, a parametric study was performed to examine the influence of fretting amplitudes on the mechanical response of the conductor-clamp system.In conclusion, this research shows the reliability and significance of using reliable FE modeling in predicting the complex response of stranded conductors, which has contributed to fill some of the current knowledge gaps.  Furthermore, the computational modeling and lifing approaches developed in this thesis provide a different perspective from existing practices and may become a starting block of further exploration of the mechanisms of conductor fretting fatigue and future development of improved fatigue lifing methods for the increasingly aging overhead transmission line conductors.</description><description>Malgré les efforts déployés par l'industrie des lignes de transport d'électricité pour la conception de conducteurs toronnés de haute résistance mécanique, la recherche dédiée à la compréhension physique du comportement mécanique des conducteurs s'est faite plus rare, surtout du point de vue de la mécanique computationnelle. Le problème du vieillissement des conducteurs de lignes aériennes à haute tension, en particulier celui de l'usure en fatigue des brins et torons, n'est toujours pas complètement compris ni donc résolu. Le vieillissement des conducteurs se manifeste par une dégradation importante de leur résistance locale à l'usure en fatigue, réduisant par le fait même leur vie utile et la robustesse mécanique de l'ensemble de la ligne. Il faut reconnaître que les études expérimentales et les modèles théoriques simplifiés ne peuvent pas prédire le comportement mécanique détaillé des conducteurs toronnés à cause de la complexité physique de ces câbles: torons et brins multicouches, matériaux inélastiques non-linéaires, effets des frictions substantielles entre les brins, torons et les surfaces des accessoires d'attache, ainsi que les interactions de contact entre ces éléments.Les travaux rapportés dans la thèse procèdent en trois étapes principales, décrites ci-après. La première partie consiste à préparer un modèle de section de câble de garde à fibre optique (CGFO) de construction complexe et d'en faire l'analyse détaillée sous déplacement axial contrôlé. Cette étape a servi à établir les bases de la méthodologie proposée, lesquelles sont discutées de manière exhaustive. La deuxième partie de la recherche porte sur la modélisation raffinée du conducteur de ligne ACSR 795 kcmil qui porte le nom de code « Drake », sélectionné comme cas de référence pour étudier la résistance en traction et les états de contraintes complexes du conducteur sous des conditions de conception extrêmes de conception. sensibilité a également exploré l'importance relative des effets frictionnels entre les brins du câble sur les contraintes calculées par le modèle. Finalement, un modèle détaillé 3-D est créé pour simuler les conditions précises d'un essai typique de fatigue en flexion pour le conducteur « Drake » jumelé à une pince de suspension. Le modèle retient toutes les non-linéarités du problème d'un point de vue mécanique.  l'auteur suggère une méthode pratique pour évaluer la résistance locale en fatigue multiaxiale des conducteurs du type ACSR au droit des points de contact des pinces de suspension. Cette méthode est relativement simple d'application (une fois les analyses de contraintes disponibles) et donne des résultats en accord avec les valeurs recommandées par les manufacturiers pour le câble « Drake ». Par la suite, une étude paramétrique est faite pour vérifier l'influence de l'amplitude des mouvements de glissement sur les états de contraintes déterminés dans le conducteur dans la région de contact avec la pince sous l'effet d'un cycle complet de chargement flexionnel. En conclusion, cette recherche démontre la faisabilité et la pertinence de l'usage des méthodes computationnelles avancées pour l'analyse des contraintes d'un problème complexe comme celui des conducteurs toronnés multicouches. La méthodologie de construction des modèles est une contribution scientifique importante qui permet d'améliorer notre compréhension du comportement mécanique des conducteurs sous charges extrêmes ou dans des conditions de fatigue flexionnelle. La méthode proposée pour l'estimation de la résistance à l'usure en fatigue est également utile pour l'industrie des lignes de transport et pour les manufacturiers de câbles et il est envisageable que cette recherche servira de tremplins à plusieurs autres études computationnelles pertinentes sur les conducteurs de lignes afin d'améliorer leur fiabilité et leur robustesse mécanique.</description><creator>Qi, Gang</creator><contributor>Ghyslaine McClure (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Applied Mechanics</subject><title>Computational modeling for stress analysis of overhead transmission line stranded conductors under design and fretting fatigue conditions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kr37b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343w388</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603r1985</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A Compton-scattering detector for imaging gamma rays for security purposes has been designed, built and tested. The imager is affordable, durable, portable, and has a wide field of view. The goal of this project was to develop an imager capable of quickly locating gamma-ray sources in the several hundred keV - several MeV range, that is sufficiently portable to be transported around urban environments. The design uses long bars of NaI(Tl) as the detection medium for both its scatter and absorber planes. Each bar is read out by a pair of photomultiplier tubes (PMTs) placed on opposite sides. Pulse-height sharing between the PMTs is used to reconstruct the longitudinal position of the interaction in the bars. The detector design was optimized using GEANT4 simulations. Decreasing the attenuation length of the bars was shown to significantly improve the position resolution and only slightly worsen the energy resolution of an interaction in the scintillator bar; thus a procedure to produce scintillator bars with a specified attenuation was developed. For the best scatter bar, of size 20 x 20 x 200 mm, an energy resolution of 8.0% +/- 0.2% (FWHM) and a position resolution of 5.7 +/- 0.1 mm was measured at 662 keV. For the best absorber bar, of size 40 x 40 x 400 mm, an energy resolution of 7.9% +/- 0.1% (FWHM) and a position resolution of 8.5 +/- 0.1 mm was measured.The performance of a reduced-scale imager using four of the proposed seven absorber bars has been tested. Sources with gamma-ray energies ranging from 392 keV to 1274 keV, located 9 m away, were successfully imaged using a chi-squared minimization procedure. No degradation in imaging performance was observed for source angles up to 40 degrees off axis. The data from the Cs-137 (662 keV) source was converted to obtain an equivalent exposure of a 10 mCi source located 40 m away; the source could be located in 60 seconds with an uncertainty of less than a degree.Other important results include measuring the Angular Resolution Measure (ARM) and efficiency at 662 keV; an ARM width of 2.96 +/- 0.03 degrees, and an efficiency of (1.95 +/- 0.02) x 10^(-3) was obtained.</description><description>Un détecteur à diffusion Compton pour l'imagerie de rayons gamma pour des raisons de sécurité a été conçu, construit et testé. Ce détecteur, en plus d'être abordable, durable et portable, possède un large champ de vision. Le but de ce projet était de développer un imageur capable de localiser rapidement les sources de rayons gamma dans la gamme d'énergie allant de centaines de keV à plusieurs MeV, et qui est suffisamment portable pour être transporté dans des environnements urbains. Le concept repose sur la détection des gamma grâce à l'utilisation de longues barres scintillatrices de NaI(Tl), choisies principalement pour leurs propriétés optiques telles que l'absorption et la diffusion. Chaque barre est accompagnée d'une paire de tubes photomultiplicateurs (PMs) placés de chaque côté. L'amplitude des signaux enregistrés par les deux PMs est utilisée pour reconstruire la position longitudinale des interactions dans les barres.Le concept du détecteur a été optimisé à l'aide de simulations GEANT4. En réduisant la longueur d'atténuation des barres, la résolution spatiale a été améliorée de façon significative, tout en n'affectant que très peu la résolution en énergie; ce qui a nécessité le développement d'une nouvelle technique de production de barres scintillatrices avec une longueur d'atténuation spécifique. Pour la barre ayant une diffusion optimale, d'une longueur de 20 x 20 x 200 mm, une résolution en énergie de 8.0% +/- 0.2% (FWHM) et une résolution spatiale de 5.7 +/- 0.1 mm ont été mesurées à 662 keV. Pour la barre ayant une absorbtion optimale, d'une longueur de 40 x 40 x 400 mm, une résolution en énergie de 7.9% +/- 0.1% (FWHM) et une résolution spatiale de 8.5 +/- 0.1 mm ont été mesurées.    La performance d'un modèle réduit du détecteur, n'utilisant que quatre des sept barres scintillatrices originalement proposées, a été testée. Des sources radioactives produisant des rayons gamma d'énergies entre 392 keV et 1274 keV, placées à une distance de 9 m, ont pu être imagées avec succès à l'aide d'une technique de minimisation du khi carré. Aucune détérioration de la performance de l'image n'a été observée pour des sources situées à des angles inférieurs à 40 degré de l'axe de visée du détecteur. Les données d'une source Cs-137 (622 keV) ont été converties en une exposition équivalente à une source de 10 mCi située à une distance de 40 m; cette source pouvant être localisée en 60 secondes avec une précision supérieure à 1 degré. D'autres résultats importants furent de mesurer la Mesure de la Résolution Angulaire (MRA), ainsi que l'efficacité à 662 keV: une valeur de 2.96 +/- 0.03 degré pour l'MRA et de (1.95 +/- 0.02) x10^(-3) pour l'efficacité ont été obtenues.</description><creator>MacLeod, Audrey</creator><contributor>David Hanna (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Physics - General </subject><title>Development of a compton-scatter gamma-ray imager</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn00b2032.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r1985</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nx99r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dans cette thèse, nous établissons les bases selon lesquelles les senseurs chimiques à base de graphène pourront être développés. Le graphène combine plusieurs caractéristiques idéales pour la potentiométrie et la sensibilité aux charges en surface. Ces deux caractéristiques sont essentielles pour des applications de senseurs chimiques. Depuis lors, les interactions entre le graphène et le substrat ont masqués la réponse des senseurs chimiques à base de graphène. Nous démontrons l'utilité de polymères hydrophobe comme substrat pour des transistors à effet de champ (FET) à base de graphène afin d'éliminer les interactions entre le substrat et le graphène. Les dispositifs à base de parylène démontrent une stabilité du point de neutralité dans le voltage de grille, des mobilités supérieures (10000 cm2/Vs) ainsi que moins d'hystérèse que les dispositifs avec une grille à base d'oxyde de silicium. Nous démontrons quantitativement que l'électrochimie entre l'eau adsorbée, le graphène et le substrat est responsable du dopage p dans les FETs à base de graphène et d'oxyde de silicium. Nous identifions le couple redox eau/oxygène comme responsable de cette réaction et nous mesurons la cinétique de cette réaction. Les études fondamentales mentionnées ci-haut permettent le développement de senseurs chimiques à base de graphène dans des conditions ambiantes ainsi qu'en solution. Nous démontrons que des échantillons de large taille de FETs à base de graphène avec une couche de parylène passivé et une couche fonctionnelle de polyethyleninine (PEI) augmentent la sensibilité au CO2. Le dopage aux électrons du graphène, causé par la protonation des groupes aminés dans le PEI, est modulé par la formation d'espèces chargées négativement par l'absorption de CO2. Le mécanisme de dopage de charge est général et la densité du dopage peut être déterminée par les caractéristiques des FETs à base de graphène.Finalement, nous investiguons le comportement des FETs à base de graphène en solution. Nous présentons des techniques électrochimiques afin de mesurer la position du niveau de Fermi dans le graphène en fonction de changement du pH. Nous démontrons que des dispositifs sans PEI ne sont pas sensibles aux changements de pH à cause de l'absence de sites en surface capables de participer à la protonation et la dé-protonation nécessaire pour être sensible au pH. Nous présentons finalement une technique pour augmenter la sensitivité des FETs de graphène aux changements de pH en utilisant une fine couche de Ta2O5 sur la surface du graphène.</description><description>In this thesis, we establish the foundations on which graphene based chemical sensors can be developed. Graphene combines several ideal characteristics for potentiometry and charge probing at surfaces which are essential for chemical sensing applications. Hitherto, graphene/substrate interactions have masked the response of graphene based chemical sensors. We demonstrate the use of hydrophobic polymers as a substrate for graphene field effect transistors (FETs) as a means to eliminate undesired graphene/substrate interactions. Parylene gated devices exhibit stable neutrality point gate voltage under ambient conditions, higher mobilities (~10,000 cm2/V.s), and less hysteresis than that observed in graphene FETs with a typical silicon oxide gate. We show quantitatively that electrochemistry involving adsorbed water, graphene, and the substrate is responsible for p-doping in silicon oxide gated graphene FETs. We identify the water/oxygen redox couple as the underlying mechanism for this reaction and capture its kinetics.The aforementioned fundamental studies of graphene permit the development of improved graphene FET based chemical sensors in atmosphere and in solution. We demonstrate that large-area, graphene FETs with a passive parylene substrate and a polyethyleneimine (PEI) functional layer have enhanced sensitivity to CO2 gas exposure. The electron doping of graphene, caused by protonated amine groups within the PEI, is modulated by the formation of negatively charged species generated by CO2 adsorption. The charge doping mechanism is general, and quantitative doping density changes can be determined from the graphene FET characteristics. Finally, we investigate the behavior of graphene FETs in a solution. We present electrochemical techniques to probe the graphene's Fermi level position versus changes in pH. We show that bare graphene devices are not sensitive to changes in pH due to the absence of surface sites available to participate in the protonation and deprotonation process necessary for pH sensing. We finally provide a technique to increase the sensitivity of graphene FETs to changes in pH by utilizing a thin Ta2O5 layer on the graphene surface.</description><creator>Sabri, Shadi Saleem</creator><contributor>Thomas Szkopek (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Surface potentiometry with graphene field effect transistors for sensing applications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43p153m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nx99r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gk762</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Communication complexity studies how many bits a certain number of parties need to communicate with each other in order to compute a function whose input is distributed among those parties. Although it is a natural area of investigation based on practical considerations, the main motivation comes from the myriad of applications in theoretical computer science.This thesis has three main parts, studying three different aspects of communication complexity.1. The first part is concerned with the k-party communication complexity of functions F:({0,1}^n)^k -&gt; {0,1} in the 'number on the forehead' (NOF) model. This is a fundamental model with many applications. In this model we study composed functions f of g. These functions include most of the well-known and studied functions in communication complexity literature. A major goal is to understand which combinations of f and g lead to hard communication functions. In particular, due to important circuit applications, it is of great interest to understand how powerful the NOF model becomes when k is log n or more. Motivated by these goals, we show that there is an efficient O(log^3 n) cost simultaneous protocol for sym of g when k &gt; 1+log n, sym is any symmetric function and g is any function. This class of functions includes some functions that were previously conjectured to be hard and our result rules this class out for possible very important circuit complexity applications. We also give Ramsey theoretic applications of our efficient protocol. In the setting of k &lt; log n, we study more closely functions of the form majority of g, mod_m of g, and nor of g, where the latter two are generalizations of the well-known functions Inner Product and Disjointness respectively. We characterize the communication complexity of these functions with respect to the choice of g. As the main application, we answer a question posed by Babai et al. (SIAM Journal on Computing, 33:137--166, 2004) and determine the communication complexity of majority of qcsb, where qcsb is the "quadratic character of the sum of the bits" function. 2. The second part is about Fourier analysis of symmetric boolean functions and its applications in communication complexity and other areas. The spectral norm of a boolean function f:{0,1}^n -&gt; {0,1} is the sum of the absolute values of its Fourier coefficients. This quantity provides useful upper and lower bounds on the complexity of a function in areas such as communication complexity, learning theory and circuit complexity. We give a combinatorial characterization for the spectral norm of symmetric functions. We show that the logarithm of the spectral norm is of the same order of magnitude as r(f)log(n/r(f)) where r(f) = max(r_0,r_1), and r_0 and r_1 are the smallest integers less than n/2 such that f(x) or f(x)parity(x) is constant for all x with x_1 + ... + x_n in [r_0, n-r_1]. We present some applications to the decision tree and communication complexity of symmetric functions. 3. The third part studies privacy in the context of communication complexity: how much information do the players reveal about their input when following a communication protocol? The unattainability of perfect privacy for many functions motivates the study of approximate privacy. Feigenbaum et al. (Proceedings of the 11th Conference on Electronic Commerce, 167--178, 2010) defined notions of worst-case as well as average-case approximate privacy, and presented several interesting upper bounds, and some open problems for further study. In this thesis, we obtain asymptotically tight bounds on the trade-offs between both the worst-case and average-case approximate privacy of protocols and their communication cost for Vickrey Auction, which is the canonical example of a truthful auction. We also prove exponential lower bounds on the approximate privacy of protocols computing the Intersection function, independent of its communication cost. This proves a conjecture of Feigenbaum et al.</description><description>La complexité de communication étudie combien de bits un groupe de joueurs donné doivent échanger entre eux pour calculer une function dont l'input est distribué parmi les joueurs. Bien que ce soit un domaine de recherche naturel basé sur des considérations pratiques, la motivation principale vient des nombreuses applications théoriques.Cette thèse comporte trois parties principales, étudiant trois aspects de la complexité de communication.1. La première partie discute le modèle 'number on the forehead' (NOF) dans la complexité de communication à plusieurs joueurs. Il s'agit d'un modèle fondamental en complexité de communication, avec des applications à la complexité des circuits, la complexité des preuves, les programmes de branchement et la théorie de Ramsey. Dans ce modèle, nous étudions les fonctions composeés f de g. Ces fonctions comprennent la plupart des fonctions bien connues qui sont étudiées dans la littérature de la complexité de communication. Un objectif majeur est de comprendre quelles combinaisons de f et g produisent des compositions qui sont difficiles du point de vue de la communication. En particulier, à cause de l'importance des applications aux circuits, il est intéressant de comprendre la puissance du modèle NOF quand le nombre de joueurs atteint ou dépasse log n. Motivé par ces objectifs nous montrons l'existence d'un protocole simultané efficace à k joueurs de coût O(log^3 n) pour sym de g lorsque k &gt; 1 + log n, sym est une function symmétrique quelconque et g est une fonction arbitraire. Nous donnons aussi des applications de notre protocole efficace à la théorie de Ramsey.Dans le contexte où k &lt; log n, nous étudions de plus près des fonctions de la forme majority de g, mod_m de g et nor de g, où les deux derniers cas sont des généralisations des fonctions bien connues et très étudiées Inner Product et Disjointness respectivement. Nous caractérisons la complexité de communication de ces fonctions par rapport au choix de g.2. La deuxième partie considère les applications de l'analyse de Fourier des fonctions symmétriques à la complexité de communication et autres domaines. La norme spectrale d'une function booléenne f:{0,1}^n -&gt; {0,1} est la somme des valeurs absolues de ses coefficients de Fourier. Nous donnons une caractérisation combinatoire pour la norme spectrale des fonctions symmétriques. Nous montrons que le logarithme de la norme spectrale est du même ordre de grandeur que r(f)log(n/r(f)), avec r(f) = max(r_0,r_1) où r_0 et r_1  sont les entiers minimaux plus petits que n/2 pour lesquels f(x) ou f(x)parity(x) est constant pour tout x tel que x_1 + ... + x_n à [r_0,n-r_1]. Nous présentons quelques applications aux arbres de décision et à la complexité de communication des fonctions symmétriques.3. La troisième partie étudie la confidentialité dans le contexte de la complexité de communication: quelle quantité d'information est-ce que les joueurs révèlent sur leur input en suivant un protocole donné? L'inatteignabilité de la confidentialité parfaite pour plusieurs fonctions motivent l'étude de la confidentialité approximative. Feigenbaum et al. (Proceedings of the 11th Conference on Electronic Commerce, 167--178, 2010) ont défini des notions de confidentialité approximative dans le pire cas et dans le cas moyen, et ont présenté plusieurs bornes supérieures intéressantes ainsi que quelques questions ouvertes. Dans cette thèse, nous obtenons des bornes asymptotiques précises, pour le pire cas aussi bien que pour le cas moyen, sur l'échange entre la confidentialité approximative de protocoles et le coût de communication pour les enchères Vickrey Auction, qui constituent l'exemple canonique d'une enchère honnête. Nous démontrons aussi des bornes inférieures exponentielles sur la confidentialité approximative de protocoles calculant la function Intersection, indépendamment du coût de communication. Ceci résout une conjecture de Feigenbaum et al.</description><creator>Ada, Anil</creator><contributor>Denis Therien (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Hamed Hatami (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>Communication complexity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jf49s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gk762</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602434s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The participation of patients in making decisions about their care has become paramount given the emphasis on person-centred care. It is deemed especially appropriate in the context of palliative care, where decisions involve a lot of uncertainty and are heavily influenced by personal values. Yet, the literature observing the process of making decisions with patients remains scarce in palliative care. The concept of shared decision-making has been defined in different ways. In this thesis, shared decision-making is conceptualized as the process of constructing patient participation in decision-making through discourse during clinical interactions. The research question guiding this study is: How do patients and health care providers discursively construct patient participation in palliative care decisions in a hospital-based palliative care team? This qualitative study combines discursive psychology with ethnographic methods from organizational ethnography. The field research lasted one year, and the interactions between six family physicians, two pivot nurses, and 18 patients were observed longitudinally. Data generation included observations, and audio-recordings of consultations where decisions were being made.Palliative care providers possess communication skills that can help reverse the documented tendency to delay decision-making conversations about palliative care options, which constitutes a barrier to involving terminally-ill patients in decisions about their care. Data analysis first consisted of identifying the discourses that initiated decision-making exchanges, and the arguments used to justify broaching difficult palliative care decisions. The timing and nature of referral to palliative care influenced whether the only remaining decisions concerned symptom management before an imminent death, and whether patients were still able to participate in decision-making. Participating health care providers introduced decision-making needing immediate attention, such as symptom control, with a straightforward discourse directly addressing and eliciting patients' presenting complaints. When decisions entailed discussing an impending death, initiating the decision-making process required a different discourse. This was accomplished indirectly by palliative care providers by probing the patients' understanding of the disease process, or directly when providing a justification for initiating a difficult discussion, such as expressing concern about the likelihood of complications. While approaching decisions about symptom management was a routine part of palliative care providers' work, patients implicitly retained control over whether they would engage in preparation for their death.The analysis then consisted of looking for the interpretive repertoires constructing patient participation in decision-making; interpretive repertoires are familiar lines of argument used to justify actions or opinions. Patients and their healthcare providers seldom addressed their decision-making roles explicitly. Rather, they constructed patient participation in palliative care decisions in a covert manner. Four interpretive repertoires were identified as constructing patient participation in this organizational context, namely (1) exposing uncertainty, (2) co-constructing patient preferences, (3) affirming patient autonomy, and finally (4) upholding the authority of health care providers. The analysis addressed how patients and health care providers could use these repertoires to negotiate their respective roles in decision-making and exert power over this process during the clinical encounter. Involving patients in the decision-making process gave legitimacy to decisions that profoundly shaped the timing and cause of death of patients. Reflecting on the discourse of decision-making promotes awareness of the clinical and ethical stances that are taken everyday when approaching decisions about end-of-life care.</description><description>La participation des patients à la prise de décision à propos de leurs soins est primordiale étant donné l'emphase mis sur la médecine centrée sur la personne. C'est particulièrement approprié dans le contexte des soins palliatifs, puisque les décisions qui y sont prises comportent beaucoup d'incertitude et sont influencées par les valeurs des patients. Pourtant, peu de chercheurs ont observé directement le processus de prise de décision avec les patients en soins palliatifs. Il existe différentes définitions du concept de prise de décision partagée. Dans cette recherche, nous le définissions comme le processus discursif de construction de la participation des patients aux prises de décisions. La question de recherche qui guide cette étude est : Comment la participation des patients à la prise de décision est-elle construite de manière discursive par des patients et des professionnels de la santé dans le contexte d'une équipe de soins palliatifs hospitalière? Cette étude qualitative combine la méthodologie de la psychologie discursive et les méthodes ethnographiques issues de l'ethnographie organisationnelle. Le travail de terrain sous-jacent à l'étude a été effectué sur une période d'une année en observant de manière longitudinale les interactions entre six médecins de famille, deux infirmières pivots et 18 patients. La production des données inclut des observations et des enregistrements audio de consultations contenant des prises de décisions.L'analyse des données de cette étude consiste, premièrement, à identifier les pratiques discursives qui débutent les échanges cliniques à propos des décisions en soins palliatifs. L'organisation des soins a un impact sur les pratiques discursives débutant la prise de décision. Si les patients sont référés très tard dans la trajectoire de la maladie, les décisions prises concernent surtout les soins de confort dans le contexte d'une mort imminente, et les patients ne sont souvent plus aptes à participer à ces décisions. Le personnel soignant ayant participé à cette étude aborde les décisions ayant besoin d'attention immédiate, comme le contrôle de symptômes, en explorant les plaintes des patients. Lorsque les décisions portent sur le futur et sur la mort des patients, entamer les processus de décision implique un discours différent. Ceci est accompli par les soignants indirectement en explorant la compréhension de leur condition par les patients, ou directement en offrant une justification pour initier ces décisions difficiles, par exemple en mentionnant les risques de complications possibles. L'étude met en évidence le fait que de discuter des symptômes immédiats représente un rôle pris pour acquis pour les soignants, alors les patients contrôlent implicitement le processus de préparation à la mort. L'analyse comprend aussi une recherche des répertoires d'interprétation qui construisent la participation des patients à la prise de décision, c'est à dire les arguments offerts de manière récurrente pour construire et justifier cette participation. Les patients et les professionnels de la santé ne discutent pas de leurs rôles respectifs dans la prise de décision de manière explicite. Ces rôles sont plutôt négociés et accomplis de manière voilée. Quatre répertoires d'interprétation ont été identifiés : (1) l'exposition de l'incertitude, (2) la co-construction des préférences des patients, (3) l'affirmation de l'autonomie des patients, et (4) le maintien de l'autorité du personnel soignant. L'analyse a aussi exploré de quelle façon les patients et le personnel en soins palliatifs utilisent ces répertoires pour donner de la légitimité à des décisions qui façonnent le déroulement de la mort des patients. Porter une réflexion sur le discours de la prise de décision partagée contribue à une prise de conscience des positions cliniques et éthiques qui sont prises implicitement tous les jours lorsque les décisions en fin de vie sont abordées.</description><creator>Bélanger, Emmanuelle</creator><contributor>Danielle Groleau (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Rosario Rodriguez (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health Sciences - General</subject><title>Patient participation in palliative care decisions: an ethnographic discourse analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741v904.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602434s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p096b38n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sarcopenia (muscle loss) and dynapenia (loss of strength) are risk factors for disabilities, falls and loss of autonomy with aging. The essential amino acid leucine is a signaling molecule that stimulates mRNA translation, protein synthesis and insulin secretion, making it a potential anabolic agent. This thesis assessed the effect of leucine added to a meal on whole-body leucine balance, myofibrillar and sarcoplasmic proteins and on total plasma protein fractional synthesis rates (FSR) in 13 older women.  The design was a randomized, double-blind crossover versus an isonitrogenous meal. A possible effect of sarco-dynapenia on these variables was tested (n=7 with sarco-dynapenia, n=6 controls). Greater whole-body leucine balance (intake – oxidation, measured by dilution of stable isotope [1-13C]leucine), after the meal+leucine was contributed by enhanced myofibrillar protein synthesis, measured by incorporation of [2H5]-phenylalanine. Sarcoplasmic and total plasma protein FSR were equally stimulated by both meals. There was no effect of sarco-dynapenia on any of these protein kinetic responses. Data suggest that additional leucine stimulates myofibrillar protein synthesis and greater total retention.  The anabolic capacity was maintained in women with sarco-dynapenia who could benefit from such an intervention. Future studies will determine whether long-term leucine supplementation translates into improved muscle mass, strength and function.</description><description>La sarcopénie (perte de muscle) et la dynapénie (perte de force) sont des facteurs de risque d'incapacités, de chutes et de perte d'autonomie liés au vieillissement.  L'acide aminé essentiel leucine est une molécule signalétique qui stimule la traduction de l'ARNm, la synthèse protéique et la sécrétion d'insuline, ce qui en fait un agent anabolique potentiel.  Cette thèse a évalué les effets de l'ajout de leucine à un repas sur le bilan global de leucine et les taux de synthèse des protéines myofibrillaires, sarcoplasmiques et plasmatiques totales, chez 13 femmes âgées.   L'étude avait un devis chassé-croisé, randomisé, à double insu versus un repas sans leucine ajoutée (total d'azote identique). Un effet possible de la sarco-dynapénie sur ces variables a été testé (n=7 femmes sarco-dynapéniques versus n=6 contrôles).  Les taux de synthèse de protéines myofibrillaires (mesurés par incorporation de la [2H5]-phenylalanine) ont davantage augmenté suite au repas+leucine, contribuant à augmenter le bilan global de leucine (apport - oxidation, mesurée par la dilution de 1-[13C]leucine).  La synthèse des protéines sarcoplasmiques et plasmatiques a été stimulée également par le repas avec ou sans leucine ajoutée.  La présence de sarco-dynapénie n'a exercé aucun effet sur ces réponses des cinétiques de protéines.  Les résultats suggèrent que l'ajout de leucine à un repas stimule la synthèse protéique myofibrillaire et la rétention globale de leucine.  La capacité anabolique des femmes âgées sarco-dynapéniques était préservée; celles-ci pourraient donc bénéficier d'une telle intervention.  Il reste à démontrer, dans de futures études, si la supplémentation à long terme de leucine résulte en une augmentation de la masse, la force et la fonction musculaire.  </description><creator>Nasrah, Rima</creator><contributor>Stephanie Chevalier (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health Sciences - Nutrition</subject><title>Muscle and plasma protein synthesis in response to a leucine-enriched meal in sarco-dynapenic older women</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xj12c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p096b38n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb397c62h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le récepteur de Coxsackievirus et d'Adenovirus (CAR) est une molécule d'adhésion qui est impliquée en plusieurs fonctions telles que le développement neuronal et cardiaque, la formation des jonctions serrées, ainsi que la suppression de l'invasion et de la migration de certaines  cellules tumorales. La protéolyse des molécules d'adhésion cellulaire, ainsi que d'autres protéines de la membrane plasmique peut servir comme mécanisme de renouvellement et aussi peut avoir des conséquences sur la signalisation cellulaire. La protéolyse effectuée par les métallo-protéases, par exemple les membres de la famille « A Disintegrin and Metalloprotease » (ADAM), génère un fragment soluble du domaine extracellulaire du substrat, tandis que le complexe  préséniline/gamma-sécrétase libère un fragment intracellulaire du domaine cytoplasmique (par un processus nommé RIP) qui peux être transporté au noyau et qui peux ainsi affecter  l'expression génique. Les données préliminaires de notre laboratoire suggèrent que le domaine extracellulaire de CAR est clivé, et le fragment qui en provient subit le processus RIP. Durant ces travaux, nous avons identifié ADAM10 comme étant la protéine qui clivait CAR, basé sur plusieurs approaches expérimentales dont l'utilisation des shRNA contre ADAM10 , l'inhibition de son activité enzymatique et son  surexpression. Le clivage peptidique in vitro et l'analyse spectrométrique de masse suggèrent que les acides aminés 224-227 de CAR sont impliqués dans le clivage du domaine extracellulaire. Ce clivage est obligatoire pour que CAR subisse le processus RIP, afin que le domaine intracellulaire de CAR puisse entrer dans le noyau.  Le clivage du domaine extracellulaire de CAR n'a pas de conséquence sur l'effet inhibiteur de CAR sur la migration des cellules de gliome. En plus, le domaine intracellulaire de CAR libéré à la suite du processus RIP, n'inhibe non plus la migration des cellules de gliome, ce qui suggère que la protéolyse de CAR bloque cette fonction anti-tumorale de la protéine.  Par contre, durant le développement neuronal, l'activité des métallo-protéases est nécessaire pour l'effet de CAR sur l'extension des neurites. En conclusion,  CAR appartient au groupe de protéines membranaires qui sont clivés par les métallo-protéases ainsi que la préséniline/gamma sécrétase. Ce phénomène a des conséquences sur la fonction de CAR.</description><description>The Coxsackievirus and Adenovirus Receptor (CAR) is a cell adhesion molecule involved in various functions including neuronal and heart development, contribution to epithelial cell tight junction integrity, and suppression of glioma migration and invasion. Proteolysis of cell adhesion molecules, and a wide variety of other proteins, serves as a mechanism for protein turnover and may also have consequences on cellular signaling. Proteolysis by metalloproteases such A Disintegrin and Metalloprotease (ADAM) family members results in ectodomain shedding of substrates, while the presenilin/gamma-secretase complex mediates regulated intramembrane proteolysis (RIP), releasing from the plasma membrane intracellular domain fragments which may enter the nucleus after RIP and affect gene expression. Preliminary data from our laboratory suggested that CAR ectodomain is shed and that the remnant fragment is RIPped. In this study, we identified ADAM10 as a sheddase of CAR using assays involving shRNA knockdown and rescue, overexpression of wild-type ADAM10 and inhibition of ADAM10 activity by addition of its prodomain. In vitro peptide cleavage and mass spectrometry analyses suggested the involvement of CAR amino acids 224-227 in its ectodomain shedding. Ectodomain shedding is a prerequisite for RIP of CAR, and free CAR intracellular domain enters the nucleus. Modulation of ectodomain shedding did not affect CAR's inhibitory function in glioma migration. Furthermore, free CAR intracellular domain cannot inhibit glioma cell migration, suggesting that proteolysis of CAR ultimately abolishes this function and promotes tumorigenesis. On the other hand, in developing neurons, metalloprotease activity is required for CAR-mediated neurite outgrowth. Thus, CAR belongs to an increasing list of cell surface molecules that undergo ectodomain shedding and gamma-secretase-mediated RIP, and these proteolytic events can have a consequence on CAR function. </description><creator>Houri, Nadia</creator><contributor>Josephine Nalbantoglu (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Proteolytic processing of the cell adhesion molecule coxsackievirus and adenovirus receptor (CAR)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vp31z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397c62h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sd81g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis challenges the liberal skepticism towards homeschooling as a legitimate form of education provision. Drawing on the work of Shelley Burtt and critiquing that of Meira Levinson, I argue that an exposure to diverse life choices in not a necessary precondition for autonomy and that "comprehensive" educations such as homeschooling can be autonomy-fostering environments. I examine Amy Gutmann's theory of democratic education as a method for safeguarding individual liberty while ensuring conscious social reproduction and from it I argue that democratic education does allow for the permissibility of homeschooling. I then look more closely at the reality of homeschooling and the potential pragmatic and ideological benefits of it to liberal-democratic society. In conclusion, I call for an increased openness between states and homeschooling families in order to benefit the development of democratic citizens. </description><description>Cette thèse met au défi le scepticisme libéral envers l'enseignement à domicile comme forme légitime d'éducation. En m'appuyant fortement sur les ouvrages de Shelley Burtt, et en critiquant ceux de Meira Levinson, je propose que d'être exposé à une variété de choix de vie n'est pas une condition préalable à l'autonomie et que des éducations « compréhensives » tel que l'enseignement à domicile peuvent être des environnements qui favorisent l'autonomie. J'analyse la théorie d'éducation démocratique d'Amy Gutmann comme mesure de protection de la liberté individuelle tout en assurant la reproduction sociale consciente et j'en conclus que l'éducation démocratique permet effectivement l'enseignement à domicile. J'examine ensuite plus profondément la réalité de l'enseignement à domicile et les avantages pratiques et idéologiques potentiels qu'il peut apporter à la société libérale démocratique. En conclusion, je préconise une plus grande ouverture entre l'état et les familles de l'enseignement à domicile afin de favoriser le développement de citoyens démocratiques.</description><creator>Jager, Amanda</creator><contributor>Kevin Michael McDonough (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Education - Philosophy of</subject><title>Educating for autonomy: a case for the broader acceptance of homeschooling within liberal democratic societies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m2777.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sd81g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n870zt958</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ce mémoire étudie la position des tziganes dans l'Empire ottoman du seizième siècle en engageant avec les défis matériaux, historiographiques  et conceptuels formidables qu'entraine cette entreprise. Ces défis proviennent des sources limités sur les tziganes, des récits variables de la recherche contemporaine sur leur histoire, et l'emploi  de concepts contestés comme la marginalité, l'ethnicité et la race sans aucun effort de problématisation, contextualisation ou historicisation. Le premier chapitre discute les défis théoriques et  conceptuels à travers plusieurs études sur les marginalisés, tandis que le deuxième chapitre fait connaître les défis documentaires en introduisant les matériaux historiques et leurs limitations. Ici je concentre sur les documents judiciaires et la manière dans laquelle on les a exploités dans l'historiographie ottomane jusqu'à présent, et ca parce que les documents d'Üsküdar qui datent des années 1530-1585 représentent le noyau de ce mémoire. Enchainant avec ce survol des sources, les troisième et quatrième chapitres constituent une macroanalyse du paysage social et morale. Une tentative est faite ici à localiser les tziganes  dans ce paysage. À ce point, le mémoire tourne vers le plan micro, sans pour autant devenir une micro-histoire en soi. Dans le cinquième chapitre, la cour régionale d'Üsküdar et ses documents judiciaires sont introduits ainsi que certains problèmes qui se présentent dans l'étude des tziganes à travers le prisme de ces documents. Le sixième chapitre représente le cœur de mon argumentation et c'est ici ou sont liés les différents fils du mémoire. Une lecture des documents judiciaires dans le contexte des kanunnames, registres mühimme et la recherche publiée sur les registres tahrir, montre l'hybridisme et la diversité à l'intérieur de la communauté tzigane. Après cette démonstration de la diversité au sein de cette catégorie dite «tzigane», le septième chapitre tente d'analyser comment l'état impérial ottoman  a su intégrer ce que j'appelle une communauté mobile dans son système administrative. Par une considération de leurs  politiques, surtout ceux de l'imposition, de l'installation et de l'incorporation de plusieurs tziganes balkaniques aux rangs des forces auxiliaires militaires – müsellems --  tout en leur refusant d'entrée dans le corps Janissaire. Je maintiens que la politique d'état ottomane vis-à-vis les tziganes dans les Balkans et  l'Anatolie durant le seizième siècle n'était ni uniforme ni astucieux. Les autorités n'avait qu'une vue singulière et monolithique des tziganes. Un des principales conclusions du mémoire est que le statut légal, social, et économique des tziganes dans l'Empire ottoman à cette époque était d'une complexité qui dépasse nos caractérisations de marginalité ou tolérance. L'interaction des tziganes avec l'état, ainsi qu'avec la société ottomane, était simultanément hostile et symbiotique. </description><description>This dissertation explores the position of Gypsies in the sixteenth century Ottoman Empire in an engagement with the formidable material, historiographical and conceptual challenges that this venture entails. These challenges stem from the limitations of the sources on Gypsies, the variety of narratives produced in contemporary scholarship on the history of Gypsies and deployment of contested concepts such as "marginality," "ethnicity" and "race" with almost no problematization, contextualization and historicization. Chapter one discusses theoretical and conceptual challenges through looking at various studies on those positioned on the margins, chapter two deals with the material challenges and introduces the historical sources and their limitations. Here I pay particular attention on the court records and how they have been used in Ottoman historiography up until now, as the court records of Üsküdar extending from 1530 – 1585 constitute the backbone of this dissertation. Following this methodological overview of the sources, Chapter three and four are a macro analysis of Ottoman social and moral landscapes. Here an attempt is made to position Gypsies within this contested landscape. Then the thesis takes a rather micro turn, though it should not be considered as a micro-history. In chapter five, Üsküdar's local court and its records are introduced as well as some of the problems encountered in studying Gypsies through the prism of these court records. Chapter six is where my argument comes together and binds the various parts of the dissertation. Reading the court records in communication with the kanunnames, mühimme registers and published research on the tahrir registers, it is an attempt to demonstrate hybridity and diversity within the community of Gypsies. After demonstrating this diversity within the category 'Gypsy', chapter seven attempts to analyze how the Ottoman Imperial state appropriated what I call a "community in motion" at various levels into its administrative system. Through considering the state's various policies especially those regarding taxation, settlement and the incorporation of many Gypsies in the Balkans within the structure of the auxiliary military forces – müsellems - yet at the same time (ideally) excluding them from joining the Janissary corps, I argue that the Ottoman state policy vis a vis Gypsies in the sixteenth century Balkan and Anatolia was neither uniform nor did the ruling authorities have a singular and monolithic view of Gypsies. One of the main conclusions of this dissertation is that the legal, social and economic status of Gypsies in the Ottoman Empire in the sixteenth century is much more complicated than what can merely be characterized as marginalization or toleration. The interaction of the Gypsies, both with the state and with the Ottoman society at large, was simultaneously both hostile and symbiotic.</description><creator>Çelik, Faika </creator><contributor>Turgay, A. Uner(Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>History - Middle Eastern</subject><title>"Community in motion": Gypsies in Ottoman imperial state policy, public morality and at the Sharia court of Üskudar (1530s-1585s) </title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j67317338.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zt958</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fb494c65k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La progranuline est une glycoprotéine qui a initialement été identifiée et décrite dans notre laboratoire. Elle est impliquée dans le cancer, l'immunomodulation, la réparation des tissus et les maladies neurodégénératives et agit comme un facteur de croissance; de plus, elle stimule la prolifération et la migration cellulaires et atténue l'apoptose. Nous avons émis l'hypothèse que l'un des rôles importants de la progranuline est en tant que protéine de stimulation et réglementation lors du remodelage de tissus. Dans cette thèse nous démontrons dans un contexte physiologique lors de la guérison des plaies, characterisee par l'induction rapide de la progranuline dans la plaie. Ni les fibroblastes dermiques en repos, ni l'endothélium vasculaire ne produisent de la progranuline. Cependant, dans les plaies, ces deux types de cellules montrent une induction rapide de la progranuline une fois qu'elles ont été activées pour la réparation tissulaire. L'ajout de la progranuline aux plaies dermiques augmente le nombre de capillaires dans la plaie. La progranuline stimule la division des fibroblastes et des cellules endothéliales, ainsi que leur migration à travers les matrices de collagène. Elle incite également les cellules endothéliales à former des structures tubulaires sur le Matrigel, récapitulant la formation de structures luminales endothéliales lors de l'angiogenèse in vivo. De plus, la progranuline est présente dans les cellules endothéliales dans des cas de cancers très vascularisés et dans le placenta. Nous proposons donc que la progranuline puisse réglementer l'angiogénèse et la formation vasculaire. Une des limites de cette hypothèse est le manque de modèles animaux permettant de tester les rôles vasculaires de la progranuline in vivo. L'angiogénèse est un processus compliqué. Il ne peut donc pas être supposé que la capacité de la progranuline à stimuler les cellules endothéliales in vitro puisse être également appliquée au tissu intact in vivo. Pour répondre à cette critique, nous avons élevé des souris qui expriment la progranuline dans leurs cellules endothéliales. Étant donné que les cellules endothéliales forment des structures bien définies in vivo, l'angiogenèse modifiée en raison de l'expression ciblée de la progranuline pourrait être marquée par une croissance ou une morphologie anormales des vaisseaux sanguins in vivo. En bref, nous avons utilisé un vecteur Tie2-promoteur/amplificateur pour créer un vecteur spécifique à l'endothélium qui vise Tie2-Pgrn. Trois lignées Tie2-Pgrn ont été générées, désignées PgrnHi, PgrnMid, and PgrnLo pour refléter le nombre de copie de Tie2-Pgrn. L'expression et la spécificité endothéliales de la construction Tie2-Pgrn ont été confirmées par qRT-PCR et l'immunohistochimie. Les trois lignées de souris Tie2-Pgrn montrent une mortalité à la naissance, ainsi qu'une corrélation linéaire négative avec le nombre de copie Tie2-Pgrn. La mort des embryons Tie2-Pgrn a eu lieu après E17.5 et a continué pendant trois jours post partum, après quoi les souris qui ont survécu ont tendance à arriver à maturité et semblent normales. Les vaisseaux sanguins affectés sont très élargis, à paroi mince et présentent généralement une couverture clairsemée de cellules murales. L'hémorragie est courante, allant de petites hémorragies focales à une hémorragie interne massive dans les cavités du corps. Il n'y a pas d'anomalies vasculaires dans les embryons âgés de 10.5 jours, ce qui implique que la phase précoce du développement vasculogène des vaisseaux sanguins ne fut pas altérée par l'expression ciblée de la progranuline dans les cellules endothéliales. Les premières anomalies vasculaires ont été détectées à E15.5, caractérisées par une hémorragie focale dans le cerveau et la peau. Nous concluons que le ciblage spécifique de l'endothélium par la progranuline confirme l'hypothèse selon laquelle la progranuline est suffisante pour influencer la formation vasculaire in vivo.  </description><description>Progranulin is a secreted glycoprotein that was initially identified and characterized in our laboratory. It has roles in cancer, immunomodulation, tissue repair and neurodegenerative disease. Progranulin acts like a growth factor, it stimulates cellular proliferation, migration and blunts apoptosis. We have hypothesized that one of progranulin's major roles is as a stimulatory regulatory protein during tissue remodeling. This is exemplified in a physiological context in wound healing, when progranulin is rapidly induced in the wound. Neither quiescent dermal fibroblasts nor vascular endothelia produces progranulin, however, in wounds both cell types show a rapid induction of progranulin expression once they are activated for tissue repair. Adding progranulin to dermal wounds increases the numbers of capillaries in the wound. Progranulin stimulates fibroblasts and endothelial cell to divide and migrate through collagen matrices. It also stimulates endothelial cells to form tubular structures in Matrigel, recapitulating the formation of luminal endothelial structures during angiogenesis in vivo. Progranulin is also present in endothelial cells in highly vascularized cancers and in the placenta. We proposed therefore that progranulin may regulate angiogenesis and vascular formation. A limitation to this hypothesis has been a lack of animal models with which to test the vascular roles of progranulin in vivo.  Angiogenesis is a complex process with both positive and negative regulation. It could not, therefore be assumed that the ability of progranulin to stimulate endothelial cells in vitro applied also to the intact tissue in vivo. To address this criticism we constructed mice that express progranulin specifically in their endothelial cells. Since endothelial cells form well-defined structures in vivo, altered angiogenesis due to the targeted expression of progranulin could be assessed by abnormal growth or morphology of blood vessels in vivo. Briefly, we used a Tie2-promoter/enhancer vector to create an endothelial-specific Tie2-Pgrn targeting vector. Three Tie2-Pgrn lines were generated, designated PgrnHi, PgrnMid, and PgrnLo to reflect the Tie2-Pgrn copy number. The expression and endothelial specificity of the Tie2-Pgrn construct was confirmed by qRT-PCR and immunohistochemistry. All three Tie2-Pgrn mouse lines show increased mortality at birth, and show a negative linear correlation with Tie2-Pgrn copy number. Death of Tie2-Pgrn embryos occurred after E17.5 and continued for three days post partum, after which mice that survived tended to reach maturity and appeared normal. Affected blood vessels are highly expanded, thin-walled and typically show sparse coverage with mural cells. Hemorrhage is common, ranging from small focal hemorrhages to massive internal bleeding into the body cavities. There were no vascular abnormalities in E10.5 embryos, implying that the early vasculogenic phase of blood vessel development was not altered by targeted expression of progranulin in endothelial cells. The earliest vascular abnormalities were detected at E15.5, consisting of focal hemorrhage in the brain and skin. We conclude that the endothelial-specific targeting of progranulin confirms the hypothesis that progranulin is sufficient to influence vascular formation in vivo. </description><creator>Toh, Huishi</creator><contributor>Andrew Bateman (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery </subject><title>The role of progranulin in blood vessel formation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655k80p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494c65k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n009w569b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>While learning about cues that predict danger is fundamental to survival, so too is learning about when these same cues no longer present a threat.  In Pavlovian fear conditioning, pairing a previously neutral stimulus (tone) with an aversive outcome (shock) results in a conditioned fear response.  The ability of a stimulus to elicit fear is gradually reduced if that stimulus is no longer accompanied by an aversive consequence.  The diminishing fear response that occurs when, for example, the tone is repeatedly presented without the shock, is known as extinction.  The experiments presented in this dissertation characterize temporal factors involved in both extinction learning and retrieval of extinction memory and explore the mechanisms driving the persistence and loss of these memories.  Chapter 2 examines whether extinction conducted shortly after initial fear learning leads to a permanent loss of fear.  One disadvantage of using spontaneous recovery as a measure of memory return is that the state of the original memory cannot be definitively verified.  Using a paradigm that makes positive predictions for the presence and absence of memory, we find that immediate extinction does not lead to memory erasure.  This suggests that even when extinction is conducted within the time window of consolidation, a new extinction memory is formed that inhibits expression of the original fear.  In Chapter 3, it is shown that recall of fear extinction follows a non-monotonic function.  Shortly after successful extinction there is significant spontaneous recovery.  Conversely, a delay closer to 24 hours produces less recovery and better extinction retention.  The results indicate that the recovery from extinction observed shortly after extinction training is likely due to the aversive experience of extinction itself and reflects a retrieval failure.  Chapter 4 explores the mechanisms involved in the maintenance of extinction memory.  This chapter employs the use of an inhibitory peptide that disrupts the stability of GluA2-containing AMPA receptors at the postsynaptic membrane.  Infusions of this peptide into the infralimbic cortex after extinction lead to spontaneous recovery.  This suggests that GluA2-containing AMPA receptor trafficking in the infralimbic cortex is necessary for the long-term persistence of extinction.  Similarly, use of this peptide in the hippocampus suggests that memory in this structure is involved in the contextual control of extinction.  Finally, Chapter 5 builds on the results of Chapter 4 and presents a forgetting mechanism that accounts for the loss of extinction memory with time (spontaneous recovery).  Maintaining GluA2-containing AMPA receptors at the synapse in the infralimbic cortex prevents the normally observed recovery of fear.  Overall, the studies in this thesis suggest that extinction is a highly complex learning phenomenon.  The relationship between extinction learning and the return of fear is dynamic and dependent on different mechanisms such as the timing of extinction, timing of extinction recall, and the expression of postsynaptic AMPA receptors within the infralimbic cortex and hippocampus.  In Chapter 6 these ideas are discussed further.  </description><description>Pour survivre, il est impératif d'apprendre les signes qui prédisent un danger, mais il est également essentiel de pouvoir déterminer quand ces indices ne représentent plus une menace. Dans le conditionnement de peur Pavlovien, l'association d'un stimulus initialement neutre (un son) avec un événement aversif (un choc électrique) provoque une réponse de peur conditionnée. La capacité d'un stimulus à évoquer la peur se réduit progressivement quand ce stimulus n'est plus associé à l'événement aversif. Lorsque la réponse de peur conditionnée diminue, par exemple quand le son est présenté plusieurs fois sans le choc, on parle alors d'extinction.  Les études présentées dans cette thèse caractérisent les facteurs temporels impliqués dans l'apprentissage et le rappel de l'extinction, et explorent les mécanismes qui sous-tendent la persistance et la perte de ces souvenirs. Dans le Chapitre 2, nous nous demandons si l'extinction réalisée immédiatement après un apprentissage de peur conditionnée résulte en une perte permanente de réponse de peur. L'un des désavantages à utiliser la récupération spontanée comme mesure de réapparition du souvenir est qu'il est impossible de vérifier de façon définitive l'état du souvenir d'origine. En utilisant un protocole avec des prédictions positives pour la présence ou l'absence de souvenir, nous observons qu'une extinction immédiate n'efface pas le souvenir. Ceci suggère que même lorsque l'extinction a lieu pendant la fenêtre temporelle de la consolidation, un nouveau souvenir d'extinction est formé et va inhiber l'expression du souvenir de peur initial.Dans le Chapitre 3, nous démontrons que le rappel du souvenir d'extinction suit une fonction non-monotone. En effet,  peu après une extinction réussie, on observe une récupération spontanée. Avec un délai d'environ 24h, en revanche, on note moins de récupération et au contraire une meilleure rétention de l'extinction. Ces résultats indiquent que la récupération spontanée observée juste après l'extinction est probablement due à l'expérience aversive de la procédure d'extinction en soi, et reflète un échec du rappel du souvenir. Le Chapitre 4 explore les mécanismes impliqués dans la maintenance du souvenir d'extinction. Pour cela nous avons utilisé un peptide inhibiteur qui dérègle la stabilité des récepteurs GluA2-AMPA au niveau de la membrane post-synaptique. Des infusions de ce peptide dans le cortex infra-limbique après une extinction causent une récupération spontanée. Ceci suggère que le trafic des récepteurs GluA2-AMPA est nécessaire à la persistance au long terme du souvenir d'extinction. De la même façon, l'utilisation de ce peptide dans l'hippocampe suggère que le souvenir présent dans cette structure est impliqué dans le contrôle contextuel de l'extinction.Enfin, dans le Chapitre 5, nous utilisons les résultats du Chapitre 4 pour proposer un mécanisme d'oubli qui permettrait d'expliquer la perte du souvenir d'extinction avec le temps (récupération spontanée).  Le maintien des récepteurs GluA2-AMPA à la synapse dans le cortex infra-limbique empêche la récupération de la réponse de peur observée habituellement.Globalement, les études de cette thèse suggèrent que l'extinction est un phénomène d'apprentissage extrêmement complexe. Le rapport entre l'apprentissage de l'extinction et le retour de la réponse de peur est dynamique et dépend de différents mécanismes tels que le moment où l'extinction est réalisée, le moment où le souvenir d'extinction est rappelé, et l'expression post-synaptique des récepteurs AMPA dans le cortex infra-limbique et l'hippocampe. Dans le Chapitre 6, ces idées sont discutées de façon plus approfondie. </description><creator>Archbold, Georgina</creator><contributor>Karim Nader (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Psychology - Experimental</subject><title>Extinction and the return of fear: a dynamic relationship dependent on timing of training, timing of recall, and postsynaptic AMPA receptor stability</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278x63g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w569b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3484zm009</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The high complexity of optimal detection for spatial multiplexing MIMO systems motivates the need for more practical alternatives. Among many suboptimal schemes reported in the literature, very few can be proven to provide close to optimal performance with low fixed complexity. In this thesis, we consider a class of list-based detectors that first generate a list of candidate decision vectors, and then the best candidate in the list is chosen as the final decision. First, we perform a diversity analysis of such schemes and derive sufficient conditions for achieving optimal performance asymptotically. We then introduce the Sel-MMSE-OSIC algorithm that employs list-based detection and a diversity maximizing channel partition procedure that yields asymptotic optimality. Then we propose the MMSE-ISTP scheme which is an improved asymptotically optimal fixed complexity algorithm that provides substantial complexity reductions over Sel-MMSE-OSIC. This scheme is based on simplified channel partition and efficient tree based list detection. Simulations results show that Sel-MMSE-OSIC and MMSE-ISTP yield performances that are nearly indistinguishable from optimal at almost all SNR levels for space uncorrelated systems. To achieve further reductions in complexity for large constellation sizes, a variable complexity version of the MMSE-ISTP scheme is proposed. The resulting algorithm is a variable complexity scheme that operates on a very small subset of candidates, and employs an improved channel partition preprocessing that not only reduces complexity but also guarantees high SNR optimality over space uncorrelated channels. Simulations results confirm that the proposed scheme provides significant complexity reductions over conventional variable complexity detection schemes.</description><description>La haute complexité associée à la méthode optimale de détection pour les systèmes MIMO utilisant le multiplexage spatial motive la recherche d'alternatives plus pratiques. Parmi les nombreuses méthodes non optimales proposées dans la littérature, très peu peuvent théoriquement guarantir une performance quasi-optimale avec une complexité fixe et relativement basse. Dans cette thèse, nous considérons une classe de détecteurs utilisant une liste, qui premièrement génèrent une liste de vecteurs candidats et ensuite choisissent le meilleur candidat dans cette liste comme décision finale. Dans un premier temps nous faisons une analyse de diversité pour ces méthodes et dérivons des conditions suffisantes pour atteindre asymptotiquement une performance optimale. Nous introduisons ensuite l'algorithme Sel-MMSE-OSIC qui emploie une méthode de détection utilisant une liste et une méthode de partition du canal à diversité maximale permettant l'optimalité asymptotique. Après, nous proposons l'algorithme MMSE-ISTP qui apporte des réductions substantielles de complexité comparé à l'algorithme Sel-MMSE-OSIC tout en ayant une complexité fixe et étant asymptotiquement optimal. Cette méthode est basée sur une simplification de la partition du canal et une méthode de détection efficace utilisant une liste générée à partir d'un arbre de détection. Les résultats des simulations par ordinateur démontrent que Sel-MMSE-OSIC et MMSE-ISTP délivrent des performances pratiquement indissociables de la performance optimale pour tous les rapports signal-sur-bruit pour des canaux non corrélés dans l'espace. Pour atteindre des reductions additionnelles de complexité pour les grandes constellations, une version de MMSE-ISTP à complexité variable est ensuite proposée. L'algorithme qui en résulte est un algorithme à complexité variable qui opère sur un nombre réduit de candidats et emploie une méthode de partition du canal améliorée qui non seulement réduit la complexité mais aussi guarantit l'optimalité pour des rapports signal-sur-bruit élevés pour des canaux non corrélés dans l'espace. Les résultats des simulations par ordinateur confirment que l'algorithme proposé permet des réductions significatives de la complexité comparé aux techniques à complexité variable conventionnelles. </description><creator>Radji, Djelili</creator><contributor>Harry Leib (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Asymptotic optimal detection for MIMO communication systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967696j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zm009</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fm50k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction: The estimated incidence of biliary complications after OLT ranges from 10-40% but the absence of a standardized classification system prevents accurate documentation. We propose a structured classification for biliary complications following choledocho-choledochal anastomosis (CCA) at non living-related OLT. The classification is based on 3 major components and anatomic location: strictures (intrahepatic, common hepatic or anastomotic), leaks (anastomotic, non-anastomotic) and filling defects. The initial steps in proposing this classification are to test its reliability and validity. Methods: The study population consisted of OLT recipients from the McGill University Health Centre who underwent transplantation between 2004-2011. Reliability was determined using formal reliability testing including inter-rater reliability and test-retest reliability. The classification scheme was validated by analysis of the relationship between classification elements and important clinical outcomes (including diagnostic studies, need for revisional surgery, repeat transplantation, number of post-transplant hospital admissions, the total number of hospital admission days and graft and patient survival). Results: A total of 184 patients, including 76 patients with biliary complications, were included. Both inter-rater reliability and test-retest reliability showed high levels of agreement with kappa statistic greater than 0.8 for all classification elements. The proposed classification components showed a strong relationship with the selected clinical outcomes. Poorer clinical outcomes were observed with strictures when compared to leaks or filling defects. Within the differing types of strictures, increasing severity of the complications was demonstrated with higher level biliary lesions, further supporting validity of our classification method. The relationship between stricture components of the classification and days of hospital admission exemplifies the validation method; adjusted rate ratio (95% confidence interval) for days of hospital admission for anastomotic, common duct and bilateral intra-hepatic strictures was 2.01 (1.84- 2.18), 3.80 (3.42-4.21) and 7.05 (6.46- 7.70) respectively. Conclusions: The proposed classification of biliary complications shows excellent reliability and good construct validity. The significant difference in clinical outcomes between different classification components demonstrates the appropriateness of the chosen components. The classification components reflect the relative severity of the different complications, further supporting validity. Given small numbers in this preliminary study, larger numbers are needed to further validate the classification</description><description>Introduction: L'incidence estimée de complications biliaires après transplantation hépatique varie de 10-40%, mais l'absence d'un système de classification normalisé empêche une documentation précise. Nous proposons une classification structurée des complications biliaires après anastomose cholédocho-biliaire lors d'une greffe hépatique. La classification est basée sur trois éléments principaux et leur localisation anatomique: les sténoses (intra-hépatique, canal hépatique commun ou anastomose), les fuites (anastomose, non anastomotique) et les débris cannulaires. Les étapes initiales afin d'évaluer cette classification sont d'en mesurer la fiabilité et la validité. Méthodes: La population étudiée était composée de patients receveurs de greffe hépatique au Centre universitaire de santé McGill qui ont subi une transplantation entre 2004 et 2011. La fiabilité a été déterminée en utilisant des tests de fiabilité formelle, y compris la fiabilité « inter-évaluateurs » et la fiabilité « test-retest ». Le système de classification a été validé par l'analyse de la relation entre les éléments de classification et les résultats cliniques importants (y compris les études diagnostic, les chirurgies de révision, une re-transplantation, le nombre d'admissions à l'hôpital après la greffe, le nombre total de jours d'hospitalisation, et les durées de survie du greffon et du patient). Résultats: Un total de 184 patients, dont 76 patients présentant des complications biliaires, ont été inclus dans l'étude. La fiabilité inter-évaluateurs et la fiabilité test-retest ont montré des niveaux élevés d'accord avec valeurs de Kappa supérieures à 0,8 pour tous les éléments de la classification. Les composantes de la classification proposée ont montré une forte corrélation avec les résultats cliniques évalués. Les pires issues cliniques ont été observées plus souvent avec des sténoses qu'avec des fuites biliaires ou des débris dans le canal hépatique. En ce qui concerne la localisation des complications biliaires, une augmentation de la gravité des complications a été démontrée avec un niveau de lésion biliaire cranial, confirmant en sus la validité de la classification proposée. La relation entre les composantes des sténoses de la classification et le nombre de jours d'hospitalisation confirme la validation; les rapports de taux ajusté (intervalle de confiance à 95%) pour les jours d'hospitalisation quant à la localisation au niveau de l'anastomose, du canal hépatique commun ou en intra hépatique bilatéral: respectivement de 2,01 (1,84 à 2,18), 3,80 (3,42 à 4,21) et de 7,05 (6,46 à 7,70). Conclusions: La classification proposée des complications biliaires montre une excellente fiabilité et une très bonne validité. La différence significative entre les résultats cliniques reliés aux différentes composantes de la classification démontre la pertinence des composantes choisies. Ces composantes de la classification reflètent la gravité relative des différentes complications, ce qui soutient par surcroit la validité de la classification. Compte tenu du petit nombre de patients dans cette étude préliminaire, un plus grand nombre de patients sera nécessaire afin de valider d'avantage la classification.</description><creator>Neville, Amy Anne</creator><contributor>Elham Rahme (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Jeffrey S T Barkun (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery </subject><title>The development and validation of a classification system for biliary complications following orthotopic liver transplantation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526g620.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fm50k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ms35tc556</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation is centered on the Grande Bibliothèque (GB) which opened in Montreal in the spring of 2005, and was a library project of unprecedented scale in the city. The Grande Bibliothèque project unfolded during a significant moment in the cultural history of Québec, in which contemporary technological changes were, and are still, exerting transformative pressures on traditional models of the library. These same technologies have come to play an increasingly important role in the formation, circulation and reproduction of cultural practices and identities more broadly. As a case study, the GB is an instance of the many trends that are currently shaping libraries, including their changing historical narratives, their innovative architectural designs, their adjustment to new and emerging media technologies and the implications of the changing meanings of the book and reading. The aim of this research has been to consider the role that the library plays as a communications medium and cultural technology in a period when emerging digital and network media are destabilizing traditional notions of libraries and their role as democratic, public institutions. In other words, this dissertation considers how broader understandings of the library, which is treated as a medium of communication in its own right, have shifted dramatically over the last several decades. The 21st century library can be seen as an emerging medium that seeks to not only preserve and disseminate collective memory and culture, but also to provide access to spaces and networks of knowledge, culture and interaction that together renovate the library's traditional role as a democratic institution. The library has become a central nervous system for new and emergent media technologies, a space that centralizes increasingly decentralized networks and systems, and a place in which new and emergent media technologies have not only found a home, a place where they can be contained, but a space in which the encounter between citizens and public knowledge and culture is staged. </description><description>Cette thèse a pour objet principal la Grande Bibliothèque (GB) qui ouvrait ses portes à Montréal au printemps 2005. La création de cette bibliothèque, projet de grande envergure sans précédent à Montréal, marque un moment important dans l'histoire culturelle du Québec, où de nombreux changements technologiques ont eu, et continuent d'avoir, un effet transformateur sur le modèle traditionnel de la bibliothèque. D'une façon plus générale, ces mêmes technologies jouent un rôle de plus en plus important dans la formation, la diffusion et la reproduction des pratiques et des identités culturelles.En tant qu'étude de cas, la GB met en relief de nombreuses tendances qui sont actuellement en train de révolutionner la conception contemporaine de la bibliothèque: ainsi, cet exemple rend visible l'évolution des récits historiques présentés par les bibliothèques d'aujourd'hui, ainsi que leurs conceptions architecturales innovatrices. Enfin, l'étude des différentes modalités de leur adaptation aux technologies nouvelles et émergentes permet une réflexion poussée au sujet de l'évolution des significations du livre et de la lecture. L'objectif de cette recherche est donc d'examiner le rôle que la bibliothèque occupe dans une période où les technologies émergentes déstabilisent et la notion même de bibliothèque et son rôle en tant qu'institution publique démocratique. Pour se faire, la bibliothèque est considérée à la fois comme moyen de communication et comme technologie culturelle. En d'autres termes, en abordant la GB comme un moyen de communication en soi, cette thèse met en lumière les changements spectaculaires subis par le modèle de la bibliothèque au cours des dernières décennies.La bibliothèque du 21e siècle est appréhendée comme un médium émergent qui vise, d'une part, à préserver et à diffuser la mémoire et la culture collective et, d'autre part, à donner accès à des espaces et à des réseaux de connaissances, de culture et d'interaction qui, pris ensemble, revitalisent le rôle traditionnel que la bibliothèque occupe en tant qu'institution démocratique. Ainsi, la bibliothèque est devenue à la fois une sorte de système nerveux central pour les technologies nouvelles et émergentes, un espace qui centralise des réseaux et des systèmes de plus en plus décentralisés, un point de ralliement pour les technologies nouvelles et émergentes et, enfin, un espace où citoyens et connaissances se rencontrent.</description><creator>Mickiewicz, Paulina Maria</creator><contributor>Darin Barney (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Mass Communications</subject><title>The bias of libraries: Montréal's Grande Bibliothèque</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h284w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tc556</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bg257j13s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ce projet soutient que Jean 6:51c–58 contient les affirmations christologiques plutôt que eucharistiques. Bien que les chercheurs aient souvent vu le « Discours du Pain de Vie » comme un ajout tardif de la théologie eucharistique à l'évangile soi-disant anti-sacramentel de Jean, je propose que le récit de la consommation dans cette péricope fasse de Jésus «l'égal de Dieu». Alors que Jésus exhorte ceux qui l'entourent à consommer sa chair et boire son sang, il s'identifie au dieu qui l'a mis sur terre pour mourir en sacrifice. La série d'énoncés dans Jean 6:51c–58 entraîne l'identification de Jésus avec Dieu en raison des attentes culturelles communes du monde méditerranéen antique entourant le sacrifice héroïque. Dans le contexte d'une relation narrative antagoniste, le sacrifice et le repas sacrificiel servent à identifier un héros avec un dieu. Le Jésus de Jean met en relief sa soumission à la volonté de Dieu, qui, depuis le début de l'Evangile est décrit comme ayant mis Jésus sur la terre pour mourir. En fait, la mort de Jésus est évoquée tout au long de Jean. Bien que Gregory Nagy ait déjà démontré le modèle d'antagonisme dans la littérature homérique et dans les pratiques de culte de l'époque, je suis l'évolution de ce trope à travers les romans grecs, où l'antagonisme, la mort et les repas se rejoignent dans le récit. Les héroïnes romantiques sont associées aux divinités, sont sacrifiées, et sont consommées. Si l'antagonisme et l'association sont des tropes très distincts à l'époque d'Homer, rendu à l'Ère Commune, ils se trouvent au niveau de la narrative où des héroïnes d'une beauté divine sont juxtaposées avec l'horreur de leurs sacrifices humaines. Les romans sont donc une lentille à travers laquelle on peut voir Jean 6:51c–58. À la lumière de Chéréas et Callirhoé, les Éphésiaques, Leucippé et Clitophon, et les Éthiopiques, on constate que Jean, et non par la dépendance littéraire directe, mais plutôt en faisant dans le milieu littéraire de la Méditerranée antique, manipule ce trope d'association et d'antagonisme, et de cette manière établit Jésus comme Dieu dans Jean 6:51c–58, où le sacrifice, la consommation, et la divinité se croisent de même. </description><description>This project argues that John 6:51c–58 makes christological rather than eucharistic claims. While scholars have often viewed the "Bread of Life Discourse" as a later addition of eucharistic theology to John's supposedly anti-sacramental gospel, I propose that the narrative of consumption in this pericope functions to make Jesus "equal to God." The moment when Jesus exhorts those around him to eat his flesh and drink his blood is when Jesus identifies himself with the God who put him on earth to die a sacrificial death. The series of statements in John 6:51c–58 brings about the identification of Jesus with God because of shared cultural expectations in the ancient Mediterranean world about the nature of heroic sacrifice: sacrifice, and the accompanying sacrificial meal, establish the identification of a hero with a deity when the hero and deity have an antagonistic relationship in narrative. John's Jesus emphasizes his submission to the will of God, who from the start of the gospel is described as having put Jesus on earth to die. Indeed, Jesus' death is alluded to throughout John. While the pattern of antagonism in narrative and association in cult has previously been demonstrated in Homeric literature and historical cult practice in the work of Gregory Nagy, I trace the development of this trope through the Greek romances, where antagonism, death, and meal collide in narrative. The romantic heroines are associated with divinities, are sacrificed, and are consumed. In other words, where antagonism and association as tropes occur in distinct realms in Homer's time, by the Common Era, association and antagonism both occur at the level of narrative, juxtaposing divinely beautiful heroines with their horrific human sacrifices. The novels are therefore a lens through which to view John 6:51c–58. In light of Chaereas and Callirhoe, An Ephesian Tale, Leucippe and Clitophon, and An Ethiopian Story, it becomes apparent that John, not through direct literary dependence but through participation in the literary milieu of the ancient Mediterranean, manipulates this trope of association and antagonism, and in doing so, establishes Jesus as God in John 6:51c–58, where sacrifice, consumption, and divinity likewise intersect.</description><creator>Warren, Meredith</creator><contributor>Ellen Aitken (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Religion - Biblical Studies</subject><title>My flesh is meat indeed: theophagy and christology in John 6:51c-58</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kr38m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257j13s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p8065</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction: La thromboembolie veineuse (TEV) pédiatrique est un phénomène rare mais dont les séquelles peuvent être dramatiques. Selon la littérature, l'incidence est estimée entre 0.07 et 0.49 TEV par 10 000 enfants/année et la risque de récidive se situe entre 5.5 et 18.5%, toutefois, la qualité et le nombre d'études concernant le sujet demeure un facteur limitatif pour une meilleure compréhension de cette complication. Objectifs: Décrire le taux d'incidence de la TEV pédiatrique selon l'age ainsi que la tendance dans le facteur temps; de déterminer le taux de récidive ainsi que décrire les facteurs de risque de récidive et de mortalité. Méthodologie: En utilisant la base de données Med-Écho, une cohorte rétrospective des enfants âgés entre 1-17 ans (inclusif) avec un diagnostic d'un première TEV dans la province de Québec entre le 1 janvier 1994 et la 31 décembre 2004 a été établi. Une estime basée sur le résultat des recensements provinciaux a été utilisée pour standardiser et calculer les taux d'incidence. Le taux décrit annuellement et en trois catégories de temps, a été évalué en utilisant la méthode de Régression Linéaire Poisson pour établir si une tendance existe. Le taux de récidive et de mortalité ont été détermines et une analyse univariable du modèle de Cox et le « Log Rank » ont été utilises pour établir quels facteurs de risque seront incorporés dans le modèle finale de multivariable de Cox.Résultats: Au total, nous avons observé 487 épisodes de TE chez des enfants âgés entre  1 et 17 ans. Le taux d'incidence de TEV pédiatrique ajusté pour la distribution d'age de la population, calculé en utilisant des estimations basées sur les recensements provinciaux, est de 0.29 TEV par 10 000 personnes-années (intervalle de confiance à 95% (IC) 0.26-0.31). Le taux d'incidence ajusté pour variation en catégories d'age des femmes comparativement aux hommes est 1.75 fois plus élevé (IC à 95% 1.46-2.10) et est statistiquement significatif, avec des taux respectifs de 0.37 et 0.21 par 10 000 personnes-années. L'analyse de l'incidence de TEV pédiatrique entre 1994-2004 ne démontre aucune différence significative pendant cette période. Le taux de récidive est  de 2.77 (IC à 95% 2.2-3.4) par 1000 personnes-mois (risque de 16%). La récidive est associée avec le diagnostic d'une maladie chronique, incluant la maladie inflammatoire intestinale, la fibrose kystique, l'anémie falciforme, le lupus, et le syndrome néphrotique (le hazard ratio (HR) 2.3; IC à 95% 1.2-4.3), la présence d'une ligne centrale (HR 1.9; IC à 95% 1.0-3.3) ainsi qu'une une thrombose du système portal comme premier épisode de TEV (HR 4.1; IC à 95% 1.5-11.0).  La mortalité à tout cause est 6.4%, estimation de HR pour plusieurs facteurs de risque par modèle de Cox hazard était indécisif.  Conclusion: Le TEV pédiatrique est plus fréquente que la littérature ne le suggère, et sa tendance ne semble pas avoir change entre 1994 et 2004. Les femmes semblent avoir une incidence accrue par rapport aux hommes dans ce groupe. Le taux de récidive dans notre cohorte se situe à la limite supérieure des résultats des études précédentes. Le taux de récidive est plus élevé chez les enfants atteints d'une maladie chronique, avec une ligne centrale ou un diagnostic initial de TEV du système portal. La mortalité de notre cohorte est inferieure à ce que la littérature suggère. Nos résultats soulignent la nécessite d'entreprendre de nouvelles études afin de déterminer l'usage de prophylaxie chez les enfants a haut risque de TEV et/ou de récidive. </description><description>Background: Pediatric venous thromboembolism (VTE), although rare, is associated with significant morbidity and mortality.  Published incidence and recurrence rates in children vary widely with incidence rates ranging from 0.07 to 0.49 VTE per 10 000 children/year and recurrence risks ranging from 5.5% to 18.5%. There is currently a paucity of studies evaluating temporal incidence trends, as well as risk factors for recurrence.   Objectives: To describe the age-adjusted incidence rate of pediatric VTE and its trend over time, to determine VTE recurrence rate and overall all-cause mortality following VTE, and to determine predictors of VTE recurrence and all-cause mortality.   Methods: A retrospective population-based cohort of all children (ages 1-17 inclusive) with a first time diagnosis of VTE in the province of Quebec between January 1st, 1994 and December 31st, 2004 was obtained from a comprehensive administrative hospital database (Med-Echo). Provincial census estimates were used to calculate age-standardized incidence rates (IR) of pediatric VTE.  The incidence rate trend was then analyzed over the eleven-year study period using Poisson linear regression with time as both a continuous (yearly) and categorical (time periods) variable. Rate of VTE recurrence and all-cause mortality were determined. Univariate Cox-proportional hazards models and log rank testing were used to assess which risk factors would be incorporated into the final multivariate Cox-proportional hazards model evaluating risk of VTE recurrence and all-cause mortality. Results: In total, 487 incident cases of VTE in children 1-17 years of age were documented. Based on the estimated provincial census person-years during the study period, the age-standardized IR was 0.29 VTE per 10 000 person-years (95% confidence interval (CI) 0.26-0.31).  Females had a statistically significant higher VTE incidence rate (per 10 000 person-years) than males, 0.37 and 0.21 per 10 000 person-years, respectively with an incidence rate ratio comparing females to males, adjusted for age group of 1.75 (95% CI 1.46-2.10). Trend analysis showed no statistically significant change in the age-standardized IRs over the 11-year period. The VTE recurrence rate was 2.77 (95% CI 2.2-3.4) per 1000 person-months (overall risk of 16%). Recurrence was associated with the presence of a chronic disease, defined as a diagnosis of inflammatory bowel disease, cystic fibrosis, lupus, sickle cell disease or nephrotic syndrome, (hazard ratio (HR) 2.3; 95% CI 1.2-4.3), presence of a central vascular line at time of initial VTE (HR 1.9; 95% CI 1.0-3.3) and portal vein thrombosis as the initial VTE presentation (HR 4.1; 95% CI 1.5-11.0).  Overall all-cause mortality was 6.4%, hazard modeling of known risk factors for VTE was inconclusive for mortality.  Conclusions: Pediatric VTE is more frequent than previously described, however its incidence appears to be stable over time. Females are more prone to VTE than males in this age group. Risk of recurrence in our cohort is at the higher end of previously reported values, and is higher in those with a pre-existing chronic illness, central vascular line or with an initial diagnosis of portal vein thrombosis. All-cause mortality was lower in our cohort than previous large studies of VTE in this age group. Our findings highlight the need for future studies to address sex differences in the incidence of pediatric VTE to help determine effective primary thromboprophylaxis strategies in children at high risk for VTE, as well as determine effective secondary prophylaxis strategies in children at high risk for VTE recurrence.</description><creator>Sabapathy, Christine A</creator><contributor>Susan Kahn (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Vicky Tagalakis (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</subject><title>A population based cohort study: the epidemiology of pediatric venous thromboembolism in Quebec, Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859j944.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p8065</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128nj021</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation argues for a reconsideration of the function of bodies in Caravaggistic painting, and in Utrecht Caravaggism more particularly. It examines the role of the human figure in the work of Caravaggio and the Utrecht Caravaggists in light of the distinct narrative mode within which Caravaggistic painting operates. The issues explored in this dissertation formulate a response to seventeenth-century criticism regarding the treatment of bodies in Caravaggistic pictures, and the purported loss of narrative meaning. This study thus describes how Caravaggistic bodies perform and enact narrative in a way that subverts normative forms of visual narration in Italian Renaissance and Baroque art. The project as a whole aims to provide a counterpart to our understanding of Caravaggism as a style founded on contrasts of light and dark and realistic representation. I move away from thinking about these characteristics as stylistic choices, and consider them instead as narrative means that are meant to highlight the performative function of bodies in creating narrative content. My study draws on forms of entertainment to illustrate how the human figure, through performance, both produces significations and engages beholders in narrative processes. Another objective of this project is to underline identity as a key factor in the shaping of Utrecht Caravaggism, as well as an important agent in Caravaggistic narrative. On the one hand, I explain in what ways Caravaggism renews a relationship between the cities of Rome and Utrecht that was so important to the visual and artistic identity of Utrecht in the sixteenth and seventeenth centuries. On the other hand, my work shows how identity functions within Caravaggistic painting as a pictorial and rhetorical device. To this end, Chapters Three and Four map out a new vision of the relationship between Caravaggistic painting and viewers by focusing on the mode of address employed by Caravaggistic half-length figural painting. Hence, my approach to the subject of bodies and performance in Caravaggism posits narrative not simply as a visual form but as a site between representations and viewers. Within this contiguous space, pictorial bodies and identities and their equivalent in the real world become imbricated. My interpretation of Caravaggistic painting, and of Utrecht Caravaggism more precisely, therefore seeks to reconcile a pictorial mode that appears to negate space and time with narrative invention and intention. </description><description>Cette thèse propose de reconsidérer la fonction du corps humain dans la peinture caravagiste et, plus particulièrement, dans le Caravagisme utrechtois. Elle examine le rôle de la figure humaine dans l'œuvre de Caravage et dans l'œuvre des Caravagistes d'Utrecht compte tenu du mode de narration distinct qu'emploie la peinture caravagiste. Les thèmes envisagés ici sont inspirés par les critiques émises au dix-septième siècle au sujet de la représentation du corps humain dans la peinture caravagiste et selon lesquelles celle-ci nuit à la fonction narrative de la peinture. Cette étude décrit comment l'approche caravagiste subvertit les règles albertiennes de narration en refusant de situer les représentations dans le temps et dans l'espace, et en se concentrant de préférence sur la figure humaine, qu'elle met en avant-plan. De façon générale, ce projet offre une interprétation complémentaire à la conception du Caravagisme en tant que style préconisant les vifs contrastes de lumière et le réalisme pictural. Plutôt que d'envisager ces traits caractéristiques comme choix stylistiques, ils sont ici considérés pour leur capacité à souligner la fonction narrative du corps humain. Afin de mettre en évidence le rôle performatif de la figure humaine dans la narration figurative, cette étude s'appuie, entre autres, sur l'examen de formes contemporaines de divertissement. Cette approche permet de retracer les processus narratifs que la figure humaine engendre dans la peinture caravagiste et qui impliquent le spectateur dans la création de sens.     Cette thèse a pour autre objectif de souligner un facteur clé dans l'essor du Caravagisme à Utrecht: la notion d'identité. Cette dernière revêt un intérêt particulier pour cette étude parce qu'elle joue également un rôle essentiel au sein du développement narratif dans la peinture caravagiste. Les chapitres qui suivent révèlent, d'abord, que le caravagisme permet de renouer les relations entre Rome et Utrecht qui furent indispensables à la constitution d'une identité visuelle et artistique pour Utrecht aux seizième et dix-septième siècles. Ensuite, ils démontrent l'utilisation de la notion d'identité comme dispositif pictural et rhétorique dans la peinture caravagiste. À cette fin, les troisième et quatrième chapitres dressent un nouveau portrait des liens que la peinture caravagiste cherche à tisser avec ses spectateurs. Typiquement caravagesques, les personnages grandeur nature, représentés à mi-corps attirent particulièrement l'attention des observateurs. La façon dont ils s'adressent aux spectateurs constituent donc le sujet de ces deux derniers chapitres.     Les thèmes de la corporalité et de la théâtralité dans l'art caravagiste demandent d'envisager la narration non pas uniquement comme forme visuelle, mais aussi comme lieu d'échange entre image et spectateur. Les corps dépeints sont souvent poussés aux confins de l'espace pictural de sorte que la fiction s'imbrique avec la réalité. Ainsi, cette thèse souhaite expliquer que ce mode pictural qui semble vouloir nier l'espace et le temps met en branle sa propre méthode narrative par laquelle le spectateur est appelé à participer à la création de sens. </description><creator>Del Re, Sonia Loredana</creator><contributor>Bronwen Wilson (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Engeline Vanhaelen (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Art History</subject><title>Re-forming images: Utrecht, Carvaggio and the body</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04ds859.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nj021</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dz52x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Russia's ambivalent geo-political and socio-cultural position, as a self-avowed intermediary between the East and the West, shaped its double identity and played an important role in the creation of Russia's own Oriental Other. This dissertation examines the political and cultural resonance of nineteenth-century Russian art songs with oriental or Asian subjects, both within and outside of Edward Said's theoretical construct of "Orientalism." It also addresses how Russian art song composers adapted, transformed and assimilated music drawn from ethnographic sources published during the century. By contextualizing nineteenth-century Russian Orientalism through an analysis of folksong collections, ethnographies, and art songs this study addresses the very formation of the Russian image of Otherness in conjunction with the construction of a specifically Russian national and musical identity. Drawing on an extensive yet under-analyzed and under-theorized repertoire of Russian folk and art songs with oriental subjects, as well as a host of writings by Russian literati, travelers, ethnographers, and ordinary individuals about the music and culture of Russian oriental minorities, this dissertation reveals the changing nature of the theory, practice, and creation of nineteenth-century Russian music with oriental subjects, as well as the diverse and often contradictory representations of oriental Others and the extraordinary complexity of the colonizer-colonized relationship in Russia.</description><description>La position géopolitique et socioculturelle ambivalente de la Russie, en tant qu'intermédiaire autoproclamé entre l'orient et l'occident, a formé sa double identité et cela a joué un rôle important dans la création de son propre Autre Oriental. Cette thèse examine l'influence politique et culturelle de plusieurs mélodies russes du dix-neuvième siècle ayant des sujets orientaux ou asiatiques, à la fois à l'intérieur comme à l'extérieur du contexte « d'orientalisme » d'Edward Said. Elle analyse également la manière dont les compositeurs de mélodies russes ont adapté, transformé et assimilé la musique provenant de sources infographiques publiées tout au long du siècle. En contextualisant l'Orientalisme du dix-neuvième siècle à l'aide d'analyses de collections de chansons folkloriques, d'ethnographies, et mélodies russes, cette étude s'intéresse à la formation même de l'image russe de l'Autre conjointement à l'édification d'une identité nationale et musicale spécifiquement russe. Basée sur un répertoire abondant – bien que peu analysé et théorisé – de mélodies russes ayant des sujets orientaux, de même que plusieurs écrits d'érudits, de voyageurs, d'individus ordinaires et d'ethnographes russes à propos de la musique et de la culture des minorités orientales russes, cette thèse met en lumière la nature changeante de la théorie, la pratique et la création de la musique russe du dix-neuvième siècle ayant des sujets orientaux, de même que les représentations variées et souvent contradictoires de l'Autre oriental et l'extraordinaire complexité de la relation colonisateur-colonisé en Russie. </description><creator>Issiyeva, Adalyat</creator><contributor>Steven Huebner (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Music</subject><title>Russian orientalism: from ethnography to art song in nineteenth-century music</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63t026v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dz52x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ff365846m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Butler's Theorems, with one minor exception, are resolved: in a 2-categorical setting. His Adjointness theorems are all proved correct, after one tiny modification. Then, using a condition on adjoint squares, twenty-two of his Tripleability theorems are proved correct; th~ee are proved false. The other theorem is still unresolved, but it is of very minor importance.</description><description>Les theoremes de Butler, a l'exception d'un seul de peu d'importance, sont resulus dans un contexte 2-categorique.Tous ses theoremes d'adjonction sont demontres etre valides apres une modification minime. Ensuit~ utilisant une condition de carres adjoints, vingt-deux de ses Theoremes de monadicite sont demontres et trois autres sont refutes. La validation ou refutation d'un seul de ses +heoremes, de peu d'importance, demeure en suspense.</description><creator>Power, A. J. </creator><contributor>Kelly, Max (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Barr , Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1984</date><subject>Categories (Mathematics)</subject><subject>Butler, William.</subject><subject>Functor theory.</subject><subject>Triples, Theory of.</subject><title>Butler’s theorems and adjoint squares</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zm01k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff365846m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x920g117j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le but de cette etude etait de developper un modele mathematique pour la simulation par ordinateur des processus hydrometallurgiques. La formulation du modele a ete faite pour un systeme de reaction de trois phases fortement exothermique, Ie processus d'oxidation sous pression applique au traitement des minerais et des concentres refract aires d'or. Les etapes suivies au cours de cette etude necessitaient premierement l'identification experiment ale de la cinetique intrinseque des deux principaux mineraux d'or, l'arsenopyrite et la pyrite, et par la suite, Ie developpement de modeies de reacteurs decrivant Ie comportement isothermique et non-isothermique de reacteurs en discontinu et de reacteurs en sene continus a Petat d'equilibre. L'emphase a ete donnee al'identification des conditions d'alimentation pouvant produire une operation autothermique.Les principales caracteristiques du modele developpe sont: la combinaison de deux equations d'equilibre de la masse et de la chaleur, la description de la performance non-isothermique de reacteurs en serie continus, Ie traitement d'un con centre d'unmeiange des deux mineraux, l'emploi de fonctions [...]</description><description>The object of the present thesis was the development of a mathematical model suitable for computer simulation of hydrometallurgical processes. The model formulation was made for a strongly exothermic three-phase reaction system, namely the pressure oxidation process as applied to the treatment of refractory gold ores and concentrates. The steps followed during the course of this work involved first, the experimental identification of the intrinsic kinetics of the two principal refractory gold minerals, arsenopyrite and pyrite, and second, the development of reactor models describing the isothermal and non-isothermal behaviour of batch and multi-stage continuous reactors at steady state. Emphasis was given to the identification of feed conditions for autothermal operation.The key features of the developed model are the coupling of both mass and heat balance equations, the description of the non-isothermal performance of a multistage continuous reactor, and the treatment of a two-mineral mixture concentrate. In addition, continuous functions are used to describe the size distribution of reacting particles and gas-liquid mass transfer rate limitations are assessed.The model predictions were in good agreement with pilot-plant scale industrial data. Simulation runs of alternative reactor configurations and feed compositions elucidated the impact of the size of the first reactor stage, the rate limiting regime, and the sulphur content of the feed on the attainment of autogenous performance.</description><creator>Papangelakis, Vladimiros George</creator><contributor>Demopoulos, G. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1990</date><subject>Mining.</subject><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Mathematical modelling of an exothermic pressure leaching process</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42nc25t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920g117j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g158bm734</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Laboratory of Hygiene, Department of National Health and Welfare, at the request of the Directors of the Provincial Laboratories, undertook to supply each of these laboratories with H and O suspensions of the following species in the genus Salmonella: S. typhosa, S. paratyphosa A, S. paratyphosa B, S. paratyphosa C, and S. cholerae-suis var. Kunzendorf, to be used in their routine widal tests.</description><creator>Bailey, W. Robert</creator><contributor>Murray, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Bacteriology.</subject><title>The effect of pH on the agglutination of H and O suspensions of Salmonella typhosa in human and rabbit antisera</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qg55s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bm734</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hj85f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Few of the people who paid a tester to attend Elizabeth’s coronation in 1558 could have realized that they were entering upon one of the most glorious periods in English history, the spacious days of Queen Elizabeth. They did not know that a new era was being born - the era of the defeat of the great Armada and the force of His Most Catholic Majesty, the era of Drake on the seas, Bacon in science, Gilbert and Harvey and their discoveries, Shakespeare in the drama.</description><creator>Ashley, Leonard R.</creator><contributor>Duthie, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>English.</subject><title>George Peele : the man and his work</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k144w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hj85f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xj13n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Montaigne qui a le don d'être toujours nouveau et inattendu a, on serait tenté de dire, le don de l'ubiquité morale et philosophique aussi, de sorte que des esprits de tendances opposées ont pu se réclamer de lui avec la même facilité, et peut-être avec la même justification. La littérature sur Montaigne est volumineuse, et les commentaires en sont nombreux, de sorte qu'il faut beaucoup d'invention pour pouvoir trouver quelque chose de nouveau à dire sur notre auteur.</description><creator>Ariano, A. A.</creator><contributor>Lariviere, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Montaigne, Michel de, 1533-1592 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Montaigne et les nouvelletés</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752m21z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xj13n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7m01bp90n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:05:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>To interpret the permeability phenomena which are exhibited by cellulose, a knowledge of its structure and certain physical properties is essential. Although the present study is concerned with cellophane, which is a regenerated form of cellulose, it is preferable first to consider these aspects in native cellulose, and subsequently to describe the changes which occur as a result of regeneration.</description><creator>Archer, William Lucas</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1950</date><subject>Cellophane -- Permeability.</subject><title>Permeability of cellophane to liquids and vapours</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pt954.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bp90n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):13200</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>