<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:48:46Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):41350" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603qz19x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effects of lichen ground cover (predominantly Cladina stellaris) on the growth of Picea mariana at Schefferville, Quebec and Pinus sylvestris at Kevo, Finland, was investigated in situ. Effect on seedling establishment was inferred through examining status quo conditions. While contiguous mat cover precluded establishment, its margins provided ameliorated conditions suitable for establishment. Moss covered areas were the most preferred sites. At Schefferville, ten perturbations involving fertilization, lichen removal, polyethylene overlays, and aqueous lichen extract application were effected on sixteen experimental plots. Branch elongation, needle nitrogen and bole diameter were statistically analyzed as functions of various monitored edaphic conditions. Leader elongation and needle nitrogen was measured at Kevo. Lichen presence over the term of both studies showed net beneficial effect on the trees; lichen extracts had significant detrimental effects. Seed germination was suppressed by lichen presence but enhanced by lichen induced low soil pH when in contact with the soil.</description><creator>Cowles, S. (Sidney William)</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Taiga ecology -- Québec (Province) -- Schefferville.</subject><subject>Taiga ecology -- Finland -- Kevo.</subject><subject>Conifers -- Growth.</subject><subject>Lichens.</subject><subject>Scots pine.</subject><subject>Black spruce.</subject><title>Effects of lichen ground cover on conifer growth in northern taiga</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zh56j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603qz19x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6q182k97t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The development of a more rational design procedure to predict not only ultimate tieback capacities in cohesive soils, but associated tieback displacements as well, requires a basic understanding of short-term and long-term tieback behavior. In view of the above, a series of full-scale and model tieback tests were conducted on instrumented and non-instrumented straight-shafted, postgrouted, and single-underreamed tiebacks anchored in different cohesive soils. In addition, laboratory shear strength tests were conducted on soil-soil samples and grout-soil samples to allow a better interpretation of field and model results. A better understanding of (1) the load-transfer mechanism of each type of tieback and (2) both time-independent and time-dependent component movements has led to the development of a physical model to describe short-term and long-term tieback behavior in a cohesive soil.</description><creator>Ludwig, Harald.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Shoring and underpinning.</subject><subject>Anchorage (Structural engineering)</subject><subject>Clay.</subject><title>Short-term and long-term behavior of tiebacks anchored in clay</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354g04n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182k97t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752h47g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The quantitative effects of increasing the organic matter contents of three soils upon their susceptibility to compaction, the recovery of tilth after compaction and the fertility of the soils were investigated. These effects were further studied on the production of bush bean (Phaseolus vulgaris). Soil consistency limits, soil water status, applied pressure and organic matter contents were used to predict shear strength, penetration resistance and water retention characteristics of compacted soils, with the aim of meeting the widespread demand for possible techniques of soil compaction prediction. Soil compaction increased the ability of the soils to retain moisture, increased penetration resistance, shear strength and decreased the available water capacity of soils. On the other hand, organic matter increased the ability of the soils to retain moisture, expanded the available water capacity and decreased the penetration resistance and shear strength of compacted soils. Although soil compaction increased the stem diameter of bush bean; the height, yields and root dry matter of the crop decreased with higher compaction levels. On the contrary, higher organic matter levels increased the plant and yield parameters of the crop.</description><creator>Ohu, John Olutunde.</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Peat.</subject><subject>Plants -- Effect of soil compaction on.</subject><subject>Soil stabilization.</subject><subject>Soil productivity.</subject><title>Peatmoss influence on strength, hydraulic characteristics and crop production of compacted soils</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816n28k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752h47g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c534fp726</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An accurate response function for a superconducting solenoid beta spectrometer for electrons up to 5.5 MeV has been found using Monte Carlo calculations and measurements of standard spectra. Experimental conditions affecting the response function have been studied and corrections for source scattering and pileup devised. An anomalous shift in the electron energy calibration caused by the magnetic field has been discovered and explained. The beta spectrum of ('32)P, ('90)Y, ('28)Al, ('42)K, ('38)Cl and ('88)Rb have been studied. Systematic uncertainties in endpoint, branch intensity and shape factor measurements have been estimated. A beta spectra analysis program has been written to calculate endpoints, branch intensities and shape factors in a multi-branch spectrum. The beta spectra of ('141)La, ('142)La, ('139)Ba, ('141)Ba, ('142)Ba, ('138)Cs and ('139)Cs have been studied. Q(,(beta))-values, intensities for all branches and some shape factors have been measured. The shape factor of the ('20)F beta spectrum has been measured. The value found for the linear coefficient, a = 0.006 (+OR-) .002 (mc('2))('-1), supports the "weak magnetism" predictions of the Conserved Vector Current theory.</description><creator>Hetherington, Donald Wordsworth.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Beta decay.</subject><subject>Spectrometer.</subject><subject>Beta ray spectrometry.</subject><title>Precise beta spectrometry using a Ge(HP) detector in a magnetic field</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pt51h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fp726</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vk76p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis investigates how children learn the first and the second person pronouns in English. In the first phase two cross sectional studies, which examined production and comprehension in children between 16 months and 36 months of ages, were conducted to determine what types of hypotheses children entertain about the semantic rules of the pronouns. In the second phase an intervention experiment was conducted to determine whether children benefit from observing speech not addressed to them for discovering the correct rules. This hypothesis was evaluated by comparing the effects of two different intervention programs: One providing children with opportunities to observe the shifting reference of personal pronouns in speech addressed to others and the other not providing such opportunities. The results suggest that even children under two years old can learn the correct rules of personal pronouns from speech not addressed to them.</description><creator>Oshima-Takane, Yuriko.</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Infant psychology.</subject><subject>Child psychology.</subject><subject>English language -- Pronoun.</subject><subject>Language acquisition.</subject><title>The learning of pronouns /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s328x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vk76p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988k694</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A method is presented for the determination of interface topography of multi-layered crustal models from gravity or magnetic data. The technique is developed within the framework of discrete linear inverse theory and exploits the quasi-linearity of the problem to derive a simple cost-effective algorithm suitable for use on large gridded data sets. Variation of auxiliary parameters allows a suite of acceptable models to be produced rapidly and appraised in the light of available geological and geophysical evidence. When independent knowledge concerning the behaviour of specified interfaces is available, the incorporation of such data in the form of linear equality constraints is outlined. The proposed method is applied to Curie isotherm and Moho mapping in the Abitibi greenstone belt.</description><creator>Pilkington, Mark.</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Magnetic prospecting.</subject><subject>Topographical surveying.</subject><subject>Geomagnetism -- Maps.</subject><title>Determination of crustal interface topography from potential fields</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mg23r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988k694</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988k70w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Hydrogen oxidation by Azospirillum brasilense Sp7 was studied in N(,2)-fixing and NH(,4)('+)-grown batch cultures. The K(,m) for H(,2) of O(,2)-dependent H('3)H oxidation in whole cells was 9 uM. The rates of H('3)H and H(,2) oxidation were very similar, indicating that the initial H(,2) activation step in the overall H(,2) oxidation reaction was not rate-limiting and that H('3)H oxidation was a valid measure of H(,2)-oxidation activity. Hydrogen-oxidation activity was inhibited irreversibly by air. In N-free cultures the O(,2) optima for O(,2)-dependent H(,2) oxidation, ranging from 0.5-1.25% O(,2) depending on the phase of growth, were significantly higher than those of C(,2)H(,2) reduction, 0.15-0.35%, suggesting that the H(,2)-oxidation system may have a limited ability to aid in the protection of nitrogenase against inactivation by O(,2). Oxygen-dependent H(,2) oxidation was inhibited by NO(,2)('-), NO, CO, and C(,2)H(,2) with apparent K(,i) values of 20, 0.4, 28, and 88 uM, respectively. These inhibitors also affected methylene blue-dependent H(,2) oxidation, presumably by acting on the hydrogenase directly. The CO inhibition was easily reversible; the NO(,2)('-) and NO inhibitions were irreversible; and the C(,2)H(,2) inhibition was not readily reversible. Hydrogen-oxidation activity was 50 to 100 times higher in denitrifying cultures when the terminal electron acceptor for growth was N(,2)O rather than NO(,3)('-), possibly due to the irreversible inhibition of hydrogenase by NO(,2)('-) and NO in NO(,3)('-)-grown cultures. THe expression of the H(,2)-oxidation system was independent of nitrogenase expression, did not require added H(,2) (and probably not endogenous H(,2)), was not affected by low concentrations of carbon substrates (less than 30 mM malate), and required low O(,2) concentrations (microaerobic or anaerobic conditions).</description><creator>Tibelius, Karl H.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Hydrogenase.</subject><subject>Azospirillum -- Physiology.</subject><subject>Oxidation, Physiological.</subject><title>Hydrogen oxidation in Azospirillum brasilense</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p5393.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988k70w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bc34h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sixty-six chronic low back pain sufferers, recruited through the media, were randomly divided into three groups. Following an assessment consisting of psychological questionnaires, pain monitoring and measurement of paraspinal electromyogram (EMG), one group received paraspinal EMG biofeedback, and a second group received a placebo treatment. The third group received no intervention. Two further assessments were carried out on all groups immediately after and three months after treatment. All groups showed significant reductions in pain, anxiety, depression and paraspinal EMG, but there were no differences among the groups. A regression analysis failed to identify subject characteristics which predicted positive outcome in the biofeedback group, but the Evaluative scale of the MPQ and hypnotizability were significant predictors of outcome for the placebo group. The results are discussed in terms of a general placebo effect of participating in research designed to reduce pain. It is concluded that paraspinal EMG biofeedback is not an effective treatment for chronic low back pain in a non-hospitalized population.</description><creator>Bush, Clarissa.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Electromyography.</subject><subject>Backache.</subject><subject>Biological control systems.</subject><title>Electromyograph biofeedback and the treatment of chronic low back pain</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pb18j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bc34h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75r866x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The growth of sub-state nationalism in the 1960's provoked considerable academic speculation. The case of Scotland was a prominent focus of interest. One neglected area however, was the systematic study of S.N.P. strategy on two issues--North Sea oil and devolution--it is argued that small producers face particular problems in establishing themselves in the marketplace. From the standpoint of 'rational choice' theory, the party was unable to maintain a rational orientation to the electorate even under the most favourable circumstances. The constraints on rational behaviour ultimately isolated the party from the mass of the electorate, and it experienced what amounted to a 'reverse process' of maturation from relative rationality to relative irrationality. This growth cycle suggests that there are particularly severe problems afflicting the leaderships of such parties which need further study.</description><creator>Levy, Roger Peter.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Scotland -- Politics and government -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Scottish National Party.</subject><subject>Nationalism -- Scotland.</subject><title>Reshaping the nationalist appeal : public opinion, party strategy and the S.N.P.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644s24w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75r866x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hq46x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two characteristics prevail in the works of Natalia Ginzburg: the tendency towards reduction and the tendency towards repetition. Reduction and repetition resemble each other; they are analogous, complementary; both are efficient and dramatic means to express a reality which is partial and incomplete and to underline the inherent obscure suffering which results from that reality. Although Natalia Ginzburg does not belong to any of the various literary trends (and, in particular, not to neo-realism which coincides chronologically with the beginning of her career), she interprets a sorry and limited world and bears sensitive witness to its loneliness, to its "male di vivere". In this sense, Natalia Ginzburg's works, although not in the mainstream of literary currents, touch the heart of modern literary sensibility. This is, in brief, the thrust of my thesis.</description><creator>Wienstein, Jen.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Ginzburg, Natalia -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>L'opera di Natalia Ginzburg</title><language>ita</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mv96w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hq46x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Italian</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311q062</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of the first part of this study was to observe and describe the profile of test-day somatic cell counts throughout a lactation in individual cows, and to examine the correspondence between such profiles and various lactation measures of cell count presently available. The objective of the second part of the study was to obtain estimates of the genetic and phenotypic parameters of lactation measures of cell count in different lactations, possibly for use in a breeding program. In the first part of the study, the lactation cell count profiles of eighteen Holstein heifers of the Macdonald College Herd were individually examined. Weekly cell counts were expressed as deviations from the herd test-day average and plotted against week of test. A labile cell activity was found for most of the plotted lactations. The cellular responsiveness of cows facing external challenges seemed a trait peculiar to each individual. Lactation measures of cell count were unable to give good descriptions of cell count profiles of individual cows. However, they were better expressions of the lactation cell count performance than single test-day observations. In the second part of the study, monthly cell count observations were obtained between February, 1977, and February, 1982, for the Holstein cows in herds enrolled on the official option of the Quebec Dairy Herd Analysis Service. Maximum likelihood, I-MINQUE (iterative Minimum Norm Quadratic Unbiased Estimation), and multivariate REML (Restricted Maximum Likelihood) procedures were used for the estimation of genetic and phenotypic parameters. Repeatabilities of log test-day cell counts and log of test-day cell counts corrected for milk yield varied between 0.36 and 0.42 in first, second, third, fourth, and fifth and later lactations. Repeatabilities of test-day cell counts (cells/ml) in the five lactation groups varied between 0.17 and 0.25. Repeatabilities of lactation expressions for cell count between lactations ranged from 0.13 to 0.44. Heritabilities of lactation expressions of cell count were low and varied from 0.06 to 0.14 in the five lactation groups examined; however, the genetic correlations between lactations were very close to unity, 0.90 to 0.97.</description><creator>Monardes, Humberto Gonzalo.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Mastitis -- Prevention.</subject><subject>Dairy cattle -- Diseases.</subject><subject>Somatic hybrids.</subject><subject>Milk -- Composition.</subject><title>Genetic and phenotypic parameters of lactation cell counts in different lactations of Holstein cows</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17ct75d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311q062</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429996j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We have observed the electronic transitions within the ('4)T(,1g) ground state of Co('2+) in MgO by Raman spectroscopy. We identified the (GAMMA)(,6g) (---&gt;) (GAMMA)(,8g)('1) transition at 305 cm('-1) and the (GAMMA)(,6g )(---&gt;)(, )(GAMMA)(,8g)('2) transition at 930 cm('-1); the (GAMMA)(,6g )(---&gt;)(, )(GAMMA)(,7g) transition is not seen and is lost in the two-phonon band. We also observed an impurity induced vibration mode at 280 cm('-1), in resonance with the acoustic phonon branches at the surface of the Brillouin zone. The position of the electronic levels cannot be explained by crystal field theory, with the spin-orbit interaction to second-order included. We have calculated the effect of a dynamical Jahn-Teller interaction and have shown, for the first time, the necessity to include the coupling to the T(,2g) mode, in addition to the coupling to the E(,g) mode, although Co('2+) in MgO is a weak Jahn-Teller system. We also used Raman spectroscopy to observe the vibrational modes of (beta)-In(,2)Se(,2). We observed, for the first time, the layer to layer shear mode(E(,2g)('2)), at 19 cm('-1). The position of this peak and the others, at 42(E(,1g)('1)), 117(A(,1g)('1)), 179(E(,2g)('1)), 181(E(,1g)('2)) and 231 cm('-1)(A(,1g)('2)), follows the trend of the vibrational spectra of (beta)-Ga(,2)S(,2) and of (beta)-Ga(,2)Se(,2) {65}. Using the linear chain model, we calculated the shear force constants and deduced the position of the doublet (E(,2g)('1) and E(,1g)('2)) with very good agreement with the experimental values.</description><creator>Trudel, Jacques, 1948-</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Magnesium crystals</subject><subject>Indium compounds -- Spectra</subject><subject>Cobalt -- Spectra</subject><title>Raman spectroscopy of Co2+ in MgO and of b- In2Se2</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w805j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429996j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445cf01q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Human leukemia cell K562 in culture displayed an absolute requirement for folate, proliferating at optimal rate only when the total intracellular folate concentration was greater than 1.5 uM. This critical intracellular concentration was maintained by extracellular 5-formyltetrahydrofolic acid or 5-methyltetrahydrofolic acid at a 100-fold lower concentration than folic acid. Growth rate of folate-deficient cells was proportional to intracellular concentration of fully-reduced, non-methylated folate but not to intracellular 5-methyltetrahydrofolate concentration. Growth of folate-deficient cells was stimulated by inosine but not by thymidine, suggesting that the primary cause of growth restriction in these cells was purine deficiency. Serine stimulated, and glycine inhibited, growth of K562 cells, likely by modulating the supply of one-carbon units for folate metabolism. Folate-deficient cells were larger in size than folate-replete cells, but megaloblastic morhology was not observed. DNA content of folate-deficient cells was predominantly characteristic of cells in S or G2/M phases of the cell cycle.</description><creator>Watkins, David.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Folic acid -- Metabolism</subject><title>Effects of folates and products of folate metabolism on proliferation of human leukemia cell line K562 in culture</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jc16t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cf01q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10wq971</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We present storage organization schemes and a tuple density model of a relation, for the efficient processing of information in a relational database. The underlying concept used in the design of the storage schemes and the density model is that of a multidimensional array. These organizational schemes are: Multidimensional Paging, Dynamic Multipaging, and two dynamic multidimensional hashing schemes, DMHL and DMHE. The DMHL and DMHE schemes are the respective extensions of linear hashing and extendible hashing for multidimensional data organization. Storage mapping functions for extendible arrays are developed as the page addressing functions in the dynamic multidimensional structures. Performance of the multipaging schemes are examined through empirical studies. We show how relations are structured with these organizational methods to provide symmetric access to the data on any combination of attributes. Further we derive size estimation formulae for the result of the various relational operations using the density model.</description><creator>Otoo, Ekow J.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Data structures (Computer science)</subject><subject>Database management.</subject><subject>Information retrieval -- Data processing.</subject><title>Low level structures in the implementation of the relational algebra</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q714p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wq971</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fh852</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Maturation and aging-associated changes in membrane transport of sheep reticulocytes of the high-K('+) and low-K('+) genotypes were studied. The results indicate that during short term (less than 10 days) in vitro maturation, there is a progressive decrease in ouabain-sensitive Na('+),-K('+)-pump activity (('86)Rb('+) uptake in low-K('+) cells) and Na('+)-ATPase activity (high-K('+) cells). However, during long term (several weeks) in vivo maturation in which HbC was used as a marker of newly formed reticulocytes, kinetic changes, as well as a decline in total activity, were observed. The effect of metabolic depletion on the maturation-associated loss of two membrane transport functions was also studied using in vitro incubation. Both Na('+)-dependent glycine transport and the Na('+),K('+)-pump, estimated from measurements of the number of ('3)H-ouabain binding sites per cell, were decreased during maturation. ATP also enhanced the decrease in both activities when a 'reconstituted' vesicle system comprised of inside-out vesicles plus cell lysates was incubated at 37(DEGREES)C. Associated with this ATP-dependent loss of activity was an increase in the amount of concomitantly measured ninhydrin-positive material. It is concluded that the loss of certain functions during reticulocyte maturation is retarded by metabolic depletion. Membrane vesicles of distinct sidedness were prepared from sheep reticulocytes. Using these vesicles the Na('+)-dependent glycine transport system was found to be symmetrical with respect to: (a) the Na('+) dependency of glycine transport, (b) the ability to accumulate glycine against a concentration gradient, (c) the Na('+): glycine stoichiometry, i.e. two Na('+) ions are transported per molecule of glycine, and (d) the apparent Michaelis-Menten constants for Na('+) and glycine.</description><creator>Weigensberg, Andrew Mark.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Transport systems of sheep reticulocytes and their changes during cell maturation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zr476.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fh852</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290b24s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigates the agronomic and economic feasibility of utilizing stony lands for crop production in South-Western Quebec where stoniness is the major constraint. Field experiments conducted on stony soils indicated significant differences in yields of grain corn and silage corn between stone treatments. With oats, however, there were no significant differences in yields. Regression analysis of bare land values indicated an inverse relationship between size of stony land and unit price. A similar relationship also existed for land clearing and reclamation machinery costs for different farm sizes. Linear programming optimization for farms within two agricultural sub-zones showed that variation in net income is due to economies of scale, differences in yields and subsidy arrangements. For small farms, additional subsidy is required to make them economically attractive. Post-optimal procedures indicated that the base solutions are more sensitive to crop yields and prices than reclamation costs. The study concludes that crop production on stony lands is feasible within the parameters defined and that it might be more economical for an operator to develop under-utilized reserves of stony lands rather than purchase prime land at current market prices.</description><creator>Seecharan, Randolph.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Land use, Rural -- Québec (Province) -- Economic aspects.</subject><subject>Land capability for agriculture -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Farms -- Québec (Province) -- Valuation.</subject><subject>Reclamation of land -- Québec (Province) -- Economic aspects.</subject><title>Planning the use of stony lands in south-western Quebec : a feasibility study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vk787.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290b24s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Renewable Resources</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vk77z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Three drainage experiments were conducted on a newly developed organic soil where three cultural methods were superimposed. Measurements of carrot yields, subsidence, water table fluctuations, subsurface drain performance, hydraulic conductivity and soil bulk density were made. Rotovating the soil produced higher carrot yields than plowing or disking during the first year. The seven-year subsidence totalled 515 mm and depended mostly on organic soil depth. Hydraulic conductivity values did not change after five years of drainage. Bulk density of the top 0.20 m increased by 71% in 6 years, whereas the values down the profile increased between 3.3 and 16.2%. The effect of two water table depths (WTD), 0.6 and 0.9 m, in an organic soil on soil water tension, subsidence swelling and carrot yields was studied in undisturbed cores in the greenhouse. Carrot yields were reduced by the 0.9 m WTD. Subsidence with the 0.9 m WTD was more than double that of the 0.6 m WTD. Raising the water table near the surface caused the soil to swell. Hydraulic conductivity, bulk density, fiber content and drainable porosity were measured in undisturbed organic soil profiles. Values from all four properties decreased with increasing depth.</description><creator>Millette, Jacques Armand, 1948-</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Reclamation of land -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Soil productivity -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Soil permeability -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Histosols -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>Evolution of a newly reclaimed organic soil in southwestern Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v6195.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vk77z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s096p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The nonlinear visoelastic behavior that accompanies large transient deformations in high molecular weight polymer melts and concentrated solutions is not at all well-understood, because equipment suitable for the investigation of such phenomena have not been available. This lack of understanding has limited the advancement of plastics processing technology, because the deformations that occur in polymer processing often take the melt well into the nonlinear regime. Furthermore, it has not been possible to test constitutive equations formulated to describe nonlinear phenomena. A new rheometer, equipped with a specially designed shear stress transducer, has been developed to examine the nonlinear viscoelastic behavior of polymeric liquids. Deformations that can be generated include interrupted shear and large amplitude oscillatory shear. Using the new instrument, a thorough study was made of the rheological behavior of polyisobutylene at 22(DEGREES)C. The results obtained from these experiments were used to evaluate the predictive ability of a constitutive equation recently proposed by Mewis and De Cleyn.</description><creator>Soong, Su Syin.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Viscoelasticity.</subject><subject>Polymers -- Viscosity.</subject><subject>Polymer melting.</subject><title>A parallel plate viscoelastometer for molten polymers /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603qz20p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s096p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xs394</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Yield stresses and r-values were measured as a function of inclination with respect to the rolling direction on thirty-one steels selected from high strength low alloy (HSLA), Al-killed (AKDQ), interstitial free (IF1 and IF2) and rimmed (RIM) types. Modul-r and electromagnetic acoustic (EMAT) techniques were employed to determine the elastic anisotropy in terms of the angular variation of Young's modulus and the ultrasonic velocities, respectively. Orientation distribution functions (ODF's) were also measured for these steels in their as-received states and after deformation in tension and in drawing. The various initial textures and their evolutions along the latter strain path are analyzed in terms of the 4- and 6-ear behaviours commonly observed during the forming of cylindrical cups. The series expansion method was employed for predicting the elastic and plastic anisotropies from the initial texture data. Comparison with the experimental measurements of Young's modulus indicates that the so-called elastic energy method can accurately reproduce the elastic anisotropy if the single crystal elastic constants are appropriately chosen within their ranges of uncertainty. The systematic evaluation of various grain interaction models for predicting the polycrystal plastic anisotropy reveals that the "pancake" relaxed constraint model is a more accurate predictor of the behaviour than the Taylor, Sachs-Kochendorfer, or other relaxed constraint models. The best quantitative agreement is obtained when the critical resolved shear stress (CRSS) ratio for glide on the $ {112 } langle 111 rangle$ and $ {110 } langle 111 rangle$ systems is 0.95 (except for the AKDQ and IF2 grades, for which values of 0.90 and 1.0, respectively, are preferred). The ODF coefficients of order greater than 4 were evaluated and calculated non-destructively from the anisotropy of the ultrasonic velocities of the lowest order symmetrical Lamb (S$ sb{ rm o}$) and shear horizontal (SH$ sb{ rm o}$) waves propagating in the rolling plane. The elastic energy method was employed, together with a decomposition of the texture into the principal preferred orientations. The calculated pole figures based on the ODF coefficients obtained in this way are similar to those derived from complete X-ray data. It is shown that the plastic properties of commercial deep drawing steels are predicted more accurately when the 4th and 6th order ODF coefficients are employed than when only the 4th order ones are used.</description><creator>Daniel, Dominique</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Prediction of elastic and plastic anisotropy in deep drawing steels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182k894.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xs394</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bc26t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The role of mobile phase modifiers in supercritical fluid chromatography (SFC) and their effect on the separation process were investigated. A study of the influence of temperature and density on chromatographic behaviour in supercritical carbon dioxide and four modified carbon dioxide mobile phases demonstrates the importance of both density and mobile phase composition in controlling retention characteristics. The information gained from these studies was used to develop methodology for the separation and detection of a series of phenothiazinone compounds and an assay for L-615,919, 4-chloro-3H-phenothiazin-3-one, in plasma. The development of an analytical method for the analysis of sorbitan trioleate in pharmaceutical formulations demonstrates a unique application of SFC with flame ionization detection (FID) that is not possible by other chromatographic techniques. The feasibility of an electrochemical detection system for SFC has been demonstrated. The design and construction of an electrochemical detector with a platinum ultramicro working electrode and factors influencing its performance are described.</description><creator>Di Maso, Marie</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Chemistry, Analytical.</subject><title>Mobile phase modifier effects and electrochemical detection in supercritical fluid chromatography</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930bx84v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bc26t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085k90n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Propene metathesis on Re$ sb2$O$ sb7$/$ gamma$-Al$ sb2$O$ sb3$ catalyst was selected for characterizing the simultaneous effects due to multicomponent physisorption, diffusion and reaction under ambient conditions. Analytical solutions to mathematical models for single component physisorption-diffusion systems were validated by comparing against experimental data obtained in a previous work. The accuracy of the numerical solution, obtained by orthogonal collocation within the method of lines, was evaluated by comparing against the analytical solutions. The single-component models were extended to the multicomponent system. Multicomponent physisorption equilibria were predicted by applying the Ideal Adsorbed Solution theory. The effective diffusivities for ethene, propene and 2-butene were calculated from Knudsen, molecular and surface diffusivities. The pore and surface tortuosity factors were estimated from the porosity data. The reaction rate expression was based on the carbene mechanism. Transient experiments were performed in a Berty reactor under computer control, implemented in FORTH (programming language), under interrupt-driven multi-tasking mode. The original reactor impeller was modified to provide improved mixing performance. Active Re$ sb2$O$ sb7$/$ gamma$-Al$ sb2$O$ sb3$ catalysts were prepared and characterized for BET surface area, pore size, surface morphology (SEM) and composition (ESCA). Ethene metathesis was observed under ambient conditions over Re$ sb2$O$ sb7$/$ gamma$-Al$ sb2$O$ sb3$ catalyst. Toth and Extended Langmuir isotherms were fitted to pure component physisorption data. The predictions from the distributed variable models, compared reasonably with the transient experiments for physisorption-diffusion with single, binary and ternary component systems. The reaction kinetics was identified by solving the inverse problem in conjunction with data from transient experiments. The constrained Levenberg-Marquardt techniques with QR and singular value decompositions were employed for solving the inverse problem. Nonisothermal model equations were also solved. The model predictions were evaluated against transient experiments under conditions different from those used for estimating the parameters.</description><creator>Gomes, Vincent G. (Vincent Gracias)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Physisorption and diffusion in propene metathesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn009z54r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085k90n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97kr17k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A comprehensive analysis is carried out concerning the procedures and the problems applicable to fine-particle liberation studies employing two-dimensional image analysis, especially those employing backscattered electron imagery (BEI). It is found that BEI imagery, while presenting the most cost-effective method for automated liberation studies, is prone to errors on the data collection level. Specifications are provided for sample preparation and equipment setup, allowing errors to be minimized. A processing algorithm is developed for cleaning BEI images prior to data compilation, and statistical tests for data integrity are evaluated. It is found that the recalculated sample grade, the most commonly used test of data integrity, is inadequate and misleading. Some alternative methods of data evaluation are presented. The statistical basis of data reduction and data interpretation is reviewed. The effects of stereological bias upon two dimensional liberation data are assessed using a simple geometrical model, whereupon it is found that relatively simple translations may be made between uncorrected and corrected data. A case study of fine particle liberation and circuit assessment is presented using samples from the copper/lead separation circuit of Brunswick Mining and Smelting, Bathurst, N.B.</description><creator>Hill, Gregg S.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Applications of two-dimensional image analysis to mineral liberation studies (Brunswick Mining and Smelting, Bathurst, N.B.)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nr69h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kr17k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rf55z853c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The cAMP binding protein CABP1 isolated from Dictyostelium discoideum consists of two subunits, CABP1A and CABP1B, which are produced from a single gene by an unusual splicing mechanism. To characterize this mechanism, an actin-CABP1 fusion gene was constructed and introduced into D. discoideum cells by DNA-mediated transformation. Analysis of these cells demonstrated that the transcripts derived from the fusion gene were properly processed to generate both CABP1A and CABP1B. However, when the 5$ sp prime$ splice site in the gene was mutated to conform to the D. discoideum consensus, only CABP1B was produced. These results suggest that the splicing event is regulated by the 5$ sp prime$ splice site. By screening a cDNA library under conditions of reduced stringency with a sequence encoding CABP1, clones which code for two closely related molecules were isolated. Hybrid selection experiments indicated that these cDNAs encode polypeptides with molecular weights of 34,000 (p34) and 31,000 (p31), both of which are recognized by anti-CABP1 antibodies. Similar to the two subunits of CABP1, these two molecules appear to be encoded by a single gene and are probably generated by the same splicing mechanism described above. The CABP1 and p34/31 genes probably arose by duplication. Disruption of the gene which encodes p34 and p31 demonstrated that these two polypeptides appear to play a role in both growth and development of D. discoideum.</description><creator>Bain, Gerard</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Dictyostelium discoideum -- Growth.</subject><title>Characterization of two polypeptides encoded by a single gene in Dictyostelium discoideum</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m245q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55z853c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526d07h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The interaction between non-spherical nuclear charge distribution and the electric field gradient is described. Expressions for the energy levels (I = 1), the nuclear quadrupolar resonance, NQR, transition frequencies and line shape are derived. The general equations to obtain the inverse line width parameter, T$ sb2 sp star,$ from the self-quenched super-regenerative oscillator, SRO, NQR spectra are derived and tested. The construction and operation of the $ sp{14}$N Sullivan and Dean SRO spectrometers are described. Limits in the sensitivity of the SRO to yield T$ sb2 sp star$ data are discussed. The operation and the constraints in obtaining line width data from a pulsed-FT spectrometer are given. The temperature dependence of $ sp{14}$N NQR frequencies, T$ sb2 sp star$ and line widths of series of anilines and hexamethylenetetramine are reported. The NQR frequency and the contribution of static and dynamic effects to the line width are discussed as a function of temperature. The observed phase transitions are discussed.</description><creator>Trepanier, Roland J.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Chemistry, Analytical.</subject><title>14N nuclear quadrupole resonance investigations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pd63g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526d07h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:td96k330p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:09:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We have developed new techniques, which enable us to study the kinetics of phase transitions in situ. By resistive self heating of samples, heating rates of over 10$ sp4$ K/s have been achieved. Our methods allows us to acquire x-ray diffraction patterns as quickly as every 3 ms. We have used these new techniques of time resolved x-ray diffraction experiments to study the crystallization kinetics of amorphous NiZr$ sb2,$ CoZr$ sb2,$ FeZr$ sb2$ and Ni$ sb{36.5}$Zr$ sb{63.5}.$ The experiments were performed at beamline X20C National Synchrotron Light Source. We have mostly focussed on the crystallization behaviour at high temperatures and therefore faster kinetics. We have found many new results and unexpected metastable phases in these systems. Most of these phases would not be seen using conventional techniques showing the importance of in situ time resolved structural measurements to study the kinetics of phase transitions.</description><creator>Yang, Yong Suk Tony.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Time resolved X-ray studies of crystallization in Zr-based glasses</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pg95n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k330p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):41375</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>