<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:03:48Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):16000" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50h0826</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis describes our advances in the preparation of lipophilic fluorogenic probes for the specific imaging of reactive oxygen species (ROS) in the lipid membrane of live cells.  The work revolves around a simple design involving the preparation of a two segment receptor-reporter type free radical scavenger-fluorophore probe (an off-on fluorogenic antioxidant indicator).  The receptor segment in the probe mimics the structure and activity of the naturally occurring antioxidant α-tocopherol.  A covalently tethered lipophilic fluorophore serves the purpose of reporting, via emission enhancement, structural changes at the receptor end following its reaction with free radicals.In this thesis we initially explore the off/on molecular switch mechanism operating in the first generation fluorogenic probe we prepared, a Bodipy-Trolox adduct that we named B-TOH.  Through mechanistic studies including oxygen uptake, laser flash photolysis, electrochemistry, and DFT calculations we were able to establish that photoinduced electron transfer (PeT) occurs from the receptor to the reporter segment.  Molecular imaging of lipid peroxyl radicals in model lipid membranes and in live cells are next reported and we lay out the potential and drawbacks for utilizing B-TOH towards monitoring lipid peroxyl radicals in the lipid membrane of live cells.  The information gained in these two chapters allowed us to determine the reporter (fluorophore) electrochemical and spectroscopic requirements that need to be met in order to modulate the sensitivity of B-TOH.  We subsequently describe the preparation, spectroscopic, and electrochemical characterization of a family of 16 new Bodipy dyes with tuneable redox potentials and versatile functional groups.  Electron withdrawing or donating groups (Et, H, Cl or CN) at positions C2 and C6 enabled tuning the redox potentials within a ca. 0.7 eV window without significantly affecting either the HOMO-LUMO gap or the absorption and emission spectra.  Hydroxymethyl or formyl groups at the meso (C8) position in turn provided functionality for covalent tethering to receptors and biomolecules of interest.  The dyes can thus be coupled to both electrophiles and nucleophiles.  We subsequently generate two new fluorogenic probes (second generation) where we exploit the new Bodipy chromophores synthesized.  We further optimize the linker moiety between receptor and reporter segment in order to control the chemical reactivity of the probes.  The development of a high-throughput fluorescence assay for monitoring kinetics of peroxyl radical reactions in liposomes is described where the evolution of the fluorescence intensity over time provides a rapid facile method to conduct competitive kinetic studies in the presence of α-tocopherol and analogues We additionally explore the selective targeting of cell organelles, specifically mitochondria (third generation probes).  A chapter is devoted to describe the synthesis and mechanistic studies of mitochondria-targeting probes.We conclude this thesis with a chapter dedicated to Conclusions and New directions.  The new probes here described will allow a non-invasive spatial and temporal monitoring of the oxidative state in live cell on an organelle level.  We may foresee that imaging studies with specific sensors will ultimately enable us to better understand vital links between the chemistry and the biology of ROS.</description><description>Cette thèse discute de la préparation et du développement de sondes fluorescentes pour l'imagerie spécifique des espèces réactives de l'oxygène (ERO) dans les membranes de cellules vivantes.  Le travail est centré sur une conception simple impliquant la préparation d'une sonde piégeuse de radicaux libres en deux segments récepteur-reporteur (un indicateur antioxydant fluorescent arrêt-marche).  Le segment récepteur de la sonde mimique la structure et l'activité de l'antioxydant naturel α-tocophérol.  Un fluorophore lipophile lié par un lien covalent rapporte, à l'aide d'une augmentation de la fluorescence, les changements structurels du côtè récepteur suite à sa réaction avec des radicaux libres.Cette thèse explore initialement le mécanisme de fonctionnement de l'interrupteur arrêt / marche moléculaire dans la sonde de première génération que nous avons préparée, un produit d'addition Bodipy-Trolox que nous avons nommé B-TOH.  Par l'entremise d'études mécanistiques incluant l'absorption d'oxygène, la photolyse éclair au laser, électrochimie et calculs sur la théorie de la fonctionnelle de la densité, nous étions capable de déterminer que le transfert d'électron photoinduit se produit du segment récepteur au segment reporteur.  L'imagerie moléculaire de radicaux peroxydes lipidiques dans les membranes lipides modèles et dans les cellules vivantes sont ensuite rapportées et nous mentionnons les inconvénients potentiels reliés à l'utilisation de B-TOH à l'évaluation de radicaux peroxydes lipidiques dans la membrane lipide de cellules vivantes.  L'information acquise durant ces deux chapitres nous a permis de déterminer les exigences électrochimiques et spectroscopiques du reporteur (fluorophore) qui doivent être remplies afin de moduler la sensibilité de B-TOH.  Par la suite, nous décrivons la préparation ainsi que la caractérisation spectroscopique et électrochimique de 16 nouvelles molécules Bodipy avec des potentiels d'oxydoréduction variables et groupes fonctionnels polyvalents.  Des groupes donneur ou accepteur d'électrons (Et, H, Cl ou CN) aux positions C2 et C6 permettent de changer le potentiel d'oxydoréduction dans une fenêtre de ca.  0.7 eV sans changer significativement ni l'écart HOMO-LUMO ni les spectres d'absorption ou d'émission.  Des groupes hydroxymethyl ou formyl à la position méso (C8) quant à eux fournissent la fonctionnalité requise pour la formation de liens covalents avec des récepteurs et molécules biologiques d'intérêts.  Ces molécules fluorescentes peuvent donc être couplées non seulement aux électrophiles mais, également aux nucléophiles.  Nous générons ensuite deux nouvelles sondes fluorescentes (deuxième génération) en exploitant les nouveaux chromophores Bodipy synthétisés. Nous optimisons davantage le groupe caractéristique lieur entre les segments récepteurs et reporteur afin de contrôler la réactivité chimique des sondes. Le développement d'une analyse à haut débit qui suit la cinétique de la réaction des radicaux peroxydes dans des liposomes est décrite où l'évolution de l'intensité de la fluorescence avec le temps nous fournie une méthode rapide et facile pour mener des études cinétiques compétitives dans la présence de α-tocophérol et ses analogues.Nous explorons additionnellement le ciblage sélectif d'organelle cellulaire, spécifiquement des mitochondries (sonde de troisième génération).  Un chapitre est dévoué à la description de la synthèse et aux études mécanistiques de sondes cibleuses de mitochondrie.  Nous concluons cette thèse par un chapitre dédié aux conclusions et aux nouvelles directions.  Les nouvelles sondes décrites ici permettront l'évaluation spatiotemporelle et non-invasive de l'état d'oxydation de cellules vivantes au niveau des organelles.  Nous pouvons prévoir que des études d'imageries avec des sondes spécifiques vont éventuellement nous permettre de mieux comprendre des liens vitaux entre la chimie et la biologie des ERO.</description><creator>Krumova, Katerina</creator><contributor>Gonzalo Cosa (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Chemistry - Organic</subject><title>Development of novel fluorogenic antioxidants for imaging reactive oxygen species in live cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d3523.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50h0826</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x484s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The ability of wetlands to sequester carbon has given them a considerable amount of attention, especially in light of global climate change.  To date, many wetland studies have focused on peatlands, however very few studies have been conducted on marshes. This study used the eddy covariance (EC) technique to measure net ecosystem carbon exchange (NEE) and energy exchange at a temperate freshwater cattail marsh near Ottawa, Canada.  The objectives of the study were to use a four year dataset to determine the environmental controls on the variability of carbon and water vapour exchange.  The annual cumulative NEE was on average -246  ± 31 gCm-2yr-1 ranging from -216 to -260 gCm-2yr-1.  The variability in accumulation between years was a result of the timing of spring and fall transitions in the carbon uptake and the length of the growing seasons, each of which were determined by prevailing weather conditions.  Evaluation of the interannual variability indicated that the marsh may be sensitive to carbon (C) losses through enhanced respiration under warmer autumn periods.  Maximum daily average values of evapotranspiration (ET) reached 10.75, 9.07, 11.70 and 8.36 mm day-1 in 2005, 2006, 2007 and 2008, respectively.  Bowen ratio values varied seasonally with values well below unity during the growing season (May to October) illustrating the dominance of latent heat.  Evaluation of the evaporative fraction and Priestley-Taylor α indicated the seasonal importance of ET and mid-season high values of the decoupling coefficient (Ω) indicated that the marsh ET is radiatively driven owing its smooth aerodynamic surface and abundance of water.  Overall, the marsh ecosystem was a large annual sink for CO2 as compared to other wetland ecosystems and ET rates were highly dependent on radiative input.</description><description>La capacité des milieux humides à séquestrer du carbone a beaucoup attiré l'attention, notamment dans le contexte des changements climatiques.  À ce jour, bien que plusieurs études aient été menées sur les tourbières, très peu portent sur les marais.  Cette étude a utilisé la technique de covariance des turbulences afin de mesurer l'échange écosystémique  net (EEN) de CO2 et l'échange d'énergie d'un marécage de quenouilles de l'est de l'Ontario, Canada.  Les objectifs de cette étude étaient d'utiliser un ensemble de données de quatre ans afin de déterminer les contrôles environnementaux sur la variabilité des échanges de carbone et de vapeur d'eau.  Le EEN annuel cumulé était en moyenne de -246 ± 26,8 gCm-2a-1 allant de -216 à -260 gCm-2a-1.  La variabilité de l'accumulation entre les années était le résultat de la synchronisation du printemps et de l'automne au niveau de l'absorption du carbone et de la longueur des saisons de croissance, chacune ayant été déterminée par les conditions météorologiques qui prévalaient.  L'étude de la variabilité interannuelle a indiqué que le marécage pourrait être sensible aux pertes de C causées par une augmentation de la respiration au cours de périodes plus chaudes d'automne.  Les valeurs moyennes quotidiennes maximales d'évapotranspiration (ET) ont atteint 10,75, 9,07, 11,70 et 8,36 mm jour-1 en 2005, 2006, 2007 et 2008 respectivement.  Les valeurs du rapport de Bowen variaient selon la saison, avec des valeurs bien en dessous de l'unité pendant la saison de croissance (mai à octobre), illustrant la dominance de la chaleur latente.  Une évaluation de la fraction d'évaporation et du facteur α de Priestley-Taylor indiquaient l'importance saisonnière de l'ET et les valeurs élevées de mi-saison du facteur de découplage (Ω) indiquaient que l'ET du marais est dominé par les radiations en raison de sa surface aérodynamique lisse et de l'abondance d'eau.  Dans l'ensemble, l'écosystème du marais était un grand puits de carbone annuel par rapport aux écosystèmes de tourbière et les taux d'ET étaient fortement dépendants de l'apport radiatif.</description><creator>Crombie, Stephanie</creator><contributor>Ian Brett Strachan (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Atmospheric Sciences</subject><title>Carbon and water vapour exchange in a temperate fresh water marsh</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752m46t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x484s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf2688852</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>PCZ prophylaxis has proven highly effective in preventing invasive fungal infections, despite relatively low serum drug concentrations. However, high tissue levels of this agent have been reported in treated patients. Therefore, we hypothesized that intracellular levels of antifungal agents are an important factor in determining the success of fungal prophylaxis. To examine the effect of host cell-associated antifungals on the growth of medically important molds, we exposed lung epithelial cells to antifungal agents and removed extracellular drug prior to in vitro infection. Epithelial cells exposed to PCZ and its parent molecule itraconazole, but not other antifungals, were able to inhibit fungal growth for at least 48 hours and were protected from damage caused by infection. Cell-associated PCZ levels were 40 to 50-fold higher than extracellular levels and the drug was predominantly detected in cellular membranes. Fungistatic levels of PCZ persisted within epithelial cells for up to 48 hours. Further co-localization studies using fluorophore conjugated PCZ determined that PCZ concentrates within the endoplasmic reticulum of both host and fungal cells and persists long after drug exposure.  Finally, during in vitro infection of PCZ loaded cells, there is a rapid transfer of PCZ from host membrane to fungal membranes. We propose a mechanism where PCZ transfers from host membranes to fungal membranes including the endoplasmic reticulum (ER), where it accumulates to inhibit the ER membrane bound target enzyme CYP51a.  Therefore, the concentration of PCZ in mammalian host cell membranes mediates its efficacy in prophylactic regimens and likely explains the observed discrepancy between serum antifungal levels and efficacy. </description><description>La prophylaxie à l'aide de PCZ est éfficace pour prévenir les infections fongiques invasives, malgré les faibles concentrations sériques.  Cependant, des fortes concentrations de PCZ sont trouvés dans les tissus des patients. Nous formulons donc l'hypothése que les concentrations intracellulaires d'antifongiques sont une facteur important pour déterminer le succès des régimes prophylactiques. Pour éxaminer l'effet des concentrations intracellulaires sur des champignons médicale, on a exposé des cellules épithéliales à des concentrations difféerents d'antifongiques pour quelques heures, et qu'on a ensuite enlevé avant d'infecter les cellules avec des spores. Les cellules exposées au PCZ ou à l'itraconazole, mais pas les autres antifongiques, étaient capables d'inhiber la croissance des fongique et prevenir le dommage cellulaires. Les concentrations intracellulaires de PCZ étaient 40 à 50 fois plus élevés que les concentrations extracellulaires, et le PCZ était concentré dans les membranes cellulaires. Des concentrations fongistatiques de PCZ ont persisté dans les cellules pour plus que 48 heures. Par ailleurs, des études de localiaation ont démontré que le PCZ se concentre dans le réticulum endoplasmique des fongi et des cellules épitheliales. Finalement, au cours de l'infection, PCZ est transferé des membranes cellulaires aux fongi, où il s'accumule pour inhiber sa cible, le CYP51a. Donc, l'éfficacité de PCZ pourrait s'éxpliquer par son accumulation dans les membranes cellulaires, expliquant ainsi la descordance entre les niveaux sérumiques et l'éfficacité contre les champignons.</description><creator>Campoli, Paolo</creator><contributor>Arnold Scott Kristof (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Donald Sheppard (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Microbiology</subject><title>Concentration of antifungal agents within host cell membranes: a new paradigm governing the efficacy of prophylaxis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n204265j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf2688852</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547w027</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les téléphones intelligents et les appareils mobiles semblables nous fournissent une occasion sans précédent de recueillir des données à propos du comportement humain. Puisqu'ils font partie intégrante de notre vie quotidienne, ces appareils ont accès à des informations privilégiées concernant les personnes avec qui nous communiquons, les endroits où nous nous trouvons, et les façons dont nous passons notre temps. Cependant, sans outils d'analyse adéquats et la capacité de traiter de grandes quantités de données et de grands nombres d'usagers, ces données ont une valeur limitée. Cette thèse présente des outils capables d'extraire des informations concernant les activités et l'emplacement d'une personne à partir des données amassées par les capteurs intégrés dans les téléphones intelligents de consommation courante. Nous présentons un algorithme de comparaison de séries temporelles et nous démontrons que sur un grand nombre de problèmes de référence, la performance de cet algorithme est comparable, et souvent supérieure, à celle des approches de pointe alors que l'algorithme est suffisamment efficace pour être éxécuté en temps réel sur un téléphone intelligent moyen. Nous présentons la reconnaissance des activités et de la démarche en tant qu'applications de cet algorithme, et démontrons que sa performance sur ces tâches dépasse celle des approches de pointe. Concernant la détection de l'emplacement, nous présentons une étude approfondie des signaux wifi dans des environnements dynamiques non-stationnaires, et concluons qu'un nouveau modèle multinomial est préférable au modèle gaussien standard utilisé pour modéliser les mesures de la force des signaux wifi sur un terminal mobile. Nous présentons un algorithme de groupement pour signaux wifi qui utilise un modèle multinomial sous-jacent, et démontrons que sur un ensemble de données de grande taille, la performance de cette approche se compare favorablement à celle du modèle Gaussien standard lorsque qu'elle est confrontée à la tâche d'identifier des emplacements physiques à partir de données wifi. En basant notre approche sur le processus hiérarchique de Dirichlet, le nombre d'emplacements identifiables varie en se basant sur les données, et n'a pas besoin d'être spécifié au préalable. Ceci permet de localiser un appareil mobile en temps réel de façon précise, à l'intérieur comme à l'extérieur, d'une façon qui, contrairement aux approches existantes, protège la vie privée de l'usager. Même les informations détaillées ont une valeur limitée si on ne dispose pas de la capacité de les communiquer à l'usager de façon significative. Nous présentons donc un cadre pour traduire les données amassées par les capteurs en descriptions des évènements qui se produisent lisibles par les êtres humains. Ce cadre est évalué sur des corpora d'une taille combinée de 150 Go composé de données amassées par les capteurs de 38 usagers sur une période de 14 mois, et il permet de visualiser de larges quantités de données ainsi que de produire des rapports exacts, en langage naturel, des évènements dont la trace est extraite des données.</description><description>Smartphones and similar mobile devices present an unprecedented opportunity to collect data about human behaviour. Integrated into daily life, devices are privy to information about who we communicate with, where we are, and how we spend our time. However, without the proper tools for analysis and the ability to scale up to large amounts of data and large numbers of users, this data is of limited value. This thesis presents tools for extracting information about activities and location from sensor data available on commodity smartphones. We present an algorithm for comparing time series and demonstrate on a large number of benchmark problems that it is competitive with, and often exceeds, the performance of existing algorithms, while being efficient enough to run in real time on a standard smartphone. Activity and gait recognition are presented as applications of our approach, and the performance on these tasks is shown to exceed that of state-of-the-art approaches. For location detection, we present a thorough study of wifi signals in dynamic, nonstationary environments, and conclude that a new multinomial model is preferable to the standard Gaussian model used to model wifi measurements on a mobile terminal. We present a clustering algorithm for wifi signals that uses an underlying multinomial model, and demonstrate on a large dataset that this approach performs favourably on the task of identifying physical locations from wifi data. By basing our approach on the hierarchical Dirichlet process, the number of identifiable locations scales based on the data, and does not need to be prespecified. This allows for accurate, real-time localization of a mobile device both indoors and outdoors, in a manner that, contrary to existing approaches, protects the privacy of the user. Even detailed information is of limited value without the ability to convey it to the user in a meaningful way. We present a framework for translating from sensor data into human-readable descriptions of the events taking place. This framework is evaluated on a corpora of 150 GB of sensor data recorded from 38 users over 14 months, and provides for convenient visualization of large amounts of data and accurate reporting, in natural language, of events transpiring in the data.</description><creator>Frank, Jordan</creator><contributor>Doina Precup (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Shie Mannor (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>Efficient computational methods for understanding human behaviour from mobile phone data</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365861q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547w027</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62fc836</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La caractérisation de la variation génétique a mis l'accent sur les loci d'expression de caractères quantitatifs(eLCQ); cependant, l'évaluation directe des variations régulatrices en cis nécessite des approches allèle-spécifique (cis-rSNPs). La mesure de l'expression allélique (EA) est très efficace puisque les perturbations environnementales et les influences en trans sont réduites. Les résultats indiquent que les différences d'EA peuvent affecter jusqu'à 30% des loci chez un individu. Les polymorphismes responsable de telles variations peuvent être identifiés par cartographie des différences d'EA en utilisant des puces de génotypage Illumina. Ainsi, plus de 50% de la variance en EA de la population est expliqué par la cartographie des cis-rSNPs. Des études ont montré que ces cis-rSNPs ont été impliqués dans des différences de liason de facteurs de transcription (FT). Celà suggère que l'étude du mode d'action de ces FT pourrait être approfondie par l'utilisation comme outil des polymorphismes dans la population. Nous avons appliqué cette approche au FT NF-κB et analysé les conséquences de l'inactivation de ce gène à l'échelle du genome. Des données récentes montrent l'implication de NF-κB dans la réponse immunitaire et son motif de liaison à l'ADN est retrouvé enrichi dans les cellules lymphoblastoïdes humaines (LCL), surtout au niveau des promoteurs et des activateurs transcriptionnels. Nous avons croisé les cis-rSNPs cartographiés dans des LCLs des populations HapMap YRI et CEU, ainsi que des SNPs de contrôles, avec des données d'immunoprécipitation de chromatine suivi de séquençage à haut débit (ChIP-seq) utilisant l'anticorps NF-κB du projet ENCODE et accessible au public. Des analyses préliminaires des régions contenant les cis-rSNPs candidats ont montré un enrichissement des sites de liaison pour le facteur NF-κB par rapport aux sites contrôles. En effet, 39% des sites candidats sont situés dans un site de liaison pour NF-kB. Afin d'étudier le rôle potentiel des cis-rSNPs sur l'EA différentielle, nous avons réalisé des expériences d'induction de TNF-α couplé à l'inhibition de NF-κB dans les LCLs suivie par l'analyses de l'EA sur des puces de génotypage Illumina 5M. Nous avons ensuite comparé ces données avec la cartographie de cis-rSNPs dans des LCLs générée dans notre laboratoire.Nos données sont composées de cis-rSNPs associés à l'EA différentielle de loci suite à la perturbation de NF-κB et classés par valeur p (pv; top10= les 10 valeurs les plus significatives) et ont été croisées avec des données accessibles au public. Ces données sont composées des coordonnées de pics de ChIP-seq et des sites de liaison TRANSFAC pour le facteur NF-κB et de ses co-régulateurs transcriptionnels connus. Les loci montrant des différences d'EA suite à la perturbation de NF-κB et avec 1 ou plusieurs des cis-rSNPs (« top3 » pv) hétérozygotes dans les individus étudiés étaient aux nombre de 581. La recherche de ces cis-rSNPs « top 3 » dans les sites de liaison (pics de ChIP-seq) dans les LCLs ou dans un site de TRANSFAC pour NF-κB ou pour un de ses co-régulateurs transcriptionnels montrent un enrichissement significatif (64% des loci) avec un ratio supérieur à 5 par rapport aux SNPs de contrôles.L'analyse bioinformatique suggère que les SNPs identifiés sont essentiels pour la liason de NF-κB. Une étude complémentaire à consisté à perturber le FT SNAI1 probablement associé au gène WNT4 et présentant un rôle important dans les fibroblastes (FB). Cependant, nous n'avons pas été en mesure de reproduire l'effet de SNAI1 sur WNT4 in vivo.Nous avons ensuite comparé les rôles régulateurs de NF-κB et de SNAI1 dans les LCLs et les FBs respectivement (par inactivation de ces gènes). Nous avons observé que NF-κB a un effet régulateurs sur environ 33% des loci dans les LCLs contre seulement 2 % pour SNAI1 dans des FBs.Cette étude supporte l'utilisation de perturbations de l'expression de FT pour étudier le rôle clé de FTs régulateurs dans un type cellulaire donné.</description><description>Characterization of human genetic variation has focused on expression quantitative trait loci (eQTL) mapping; however, direct assessment of cis-regulatory variation requires allele-specific approaches. Measuring allelic expression (AE) on a genome-wide scale appears more powerful as environmental and trans-acting influences are minimized. Results indicate that allele-specific differences in transcript expression within an individual can affect up to 30% of loci. The underlying variants can be identified by mapping differences in AE on Illumina BeadChips. Over 50% of population variance in AE is explained by mapped cis-rSNPs. Studies show that these cis-rSNPs have been implicated in differences in transcription factor (TF) binding, suggesting that TF action can be further investigated using population variation as a tool. In this thesis, these approaches have been extended to explore allele-specific TF binding using the model NF-κB by monitoring the consequences of gene knockdown in a genome-wide manner. NF-κB has been shown to be involved in the immune response and the NF-κB motif is enriched in lymphoblastoid cell lines (LCLs), mainly in promoters and strong enhancer elements. We intersected mapped candidate cis-rSNPs detected in LCLs in our above experiments as well as matched control SNPs from HapMap YRI and CEU populations with publicly available NF-κB Chromatin Immunoprecipitation (ChIP)-seq experiments from the ENCODE project. Preliminary analysis of regions surrounding candidate cis-rSNPs were enriched in NF-κB binding sites versus matched controls, with 39.0 % of top SNPs overlapping at least one NF-κB ChIP-seq peak. To elucidate the impact of candidate SNPs on AE imbalances, we performed TNF- α induction coupled to inhibition of NF-κB in LCLs followed by AE analysis on Illumina HumanOmni5-Quad BeadChips. We used in house mapped cis-regulatory variants in the LCL population merged with data from the aforementioned experiment. Our data set, which consisted of loci associated to top 10 cis-rSNPs ranked by p-value (pv; top10= 10 most significant p-values) that showed diminished AE upon perturbation of NF-κB were overlapped with publicly available data. This data consisted of ENCODE ChIP-seq peaks and TRANSFAC binding sites for NF-κB and known cooperative TFs of NF-κB. Loci that had an AE change at greater than 3 SNPs upon perturbation of NF-κB and were associated to top heterozygous SNPs (rank 1, 2, 3) yielded 581 cases out of ~1700. Analysis of top 3 ¬cis-rSNPs described showed a significant difference of over 5-fold between case and control SNPs, such that 64% of loci had a top 3 heterozygous SNP that was found in an LCL specific TF ChIP-seq peak or TRANSFAC binding site for NF-κB or a known cooperative TF of NF-κB. Bioinformatics analysis suggests that identified SNPs are essential for NF-κB binding. A case study was also done in order to perturb the TF SNAI1 because we had a strong hypothesis for the association of SNAI1 and WNT4, as well as, evidence for its role in fibroblasts (FBs). We were not able to reproduce the effect of SNAI1 on WNT4 in vivo. Upon comparison of the regulatory role of NF-κB and SNAI1 in LCLs and FBs, respectively; we observed that NF-κB had a regulatory effect on approximately 33% of loci in comparison to only approximately 2% of loci for SNAI1 in FBs. This study illustrates that key regulatory TFs, such as NF-κB in LCLs, can be globally studied at a single base resolution in living cells using a combination of perturbation and sensitive measurements with allelic resolution. </description><creator>Schiavi, Alicia</creator><contributor>Tomi Markku Pastinen (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>Direct assessment and validation of allele specific transcription factor binding in the human genome</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vg00k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fc836</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bk128f573</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les entraineurs de niveau élite passent un temps important à créer une vision, établir un plan saisonnier, concevoir des programmes d'entrainement, et travailler avec leurs entraineurs adjoints (Côté &amp; Salmela, 1996; Vallée &amp; Bloom, 2005). La capacité des entraineurs de sport d'équipe à travailler avec leur entraineurs adjoints est considérée comme un élément essentiel à leur succès (Bloom, 1997).  Le rôle des entraineurs adjoints inclut le soutien à l'entraineur chef dans l'organisation, la planification des entrainements, et les instructions lors des compétitions (Reynaud, 2005). La littérature a démontré que les entraineurs en chef influencent le comportement et l'approche de leurs entraineurs adjoints par leurs orientations et conseils (Bloom, Durand-Bush, Schinke, &amp; Salmela, 1998; Côté, 2006). Au football, les entraineurs adjoints sont particulièrement importants en raison du grand nombre de joueurs et la spécialisation des nombreuses positions. En conséquence, les entraineurs chef au football prennent beaucoup de temps et  mettent des efforts considérables à la sélection et au développement de leurs entraineurs adjoints. Le but de l'étude actuelle était double. Elle avait d'abord pour but d'examiner les critères utilisés par les entraineurs chef dans la sélection de leurs entraineurs adjoints ainsi que d'analyser la progression de carrière de l'entraineur adjoint et par le fait même ses rôles et ses responsabilités au football canadien. Des entretiens ouverts semi-structurés ont été menées avec 6 entraineurs chef de football universitaire canadiens qui avaient été identifiés à priori par un panel d'experts en football canadien. Les entraineurs dans cet échantillon ont remporté de nombreux prix individuels (i.e., l'entraineur de l'année), ont eu du succès avec leurs équipes (i.e., gagner la Coupe Vanier), et sont reconnus pour leurs programmes solides à la fois dans la salle de classe et dans leurs communautés. Les entraineurs en chef ont dit rechercher des assistants qui se soucient de leurs athlètes, qui préconisent la loyauté et l'éducation, et qui possèdent un fort leadership. De plus, les entraineurs chef choisissent des assistants qui possèdent une grande connaissance du football reflétée par leur succès comme athlète et comme entraineur adjoint. Ils ont aussi décrit l'importance d'embaucher des entraineurs adjoints qui ont différents domaines d'expertise  Ces résultats représentent l'un des premiers portraits empiriques des connaissances utilisées par les entraineurs en chef dans le but de sélectionner leurs entraineurs adjoints. Par ailleurs, cette étude fournit une information nouvelle sur les principaux rôles et responsabilités des entraineurs adjoints. Ces résultats sauront intéresser et profiter à la fois aux entraineurs en chef et entraineurs adjoints.</description><description>Elite level coaches spend a considerable amount of time creating a vision, establishing a seasonal plan, training, and working with assistant coaches (Côté &amp; Salmela, 1996; Vallée &amp; Bloom, 2005). Expert team sport coaches' ability to work with their assistant coaching staff has been noted as a key element of their success (Bloom, 1997). Assistant coaches' roles include helping with team organization, practice planning, and coaching during competitions (Reynaud, 2005). Research has shown head coaches influence their assistant coaches' behaviours and approaches through mentoring and guidance (Bloom, Durand-Bush, Schinke, &amp; Salmela,1998; Côté, 2006). In football, assistant coaches are particularly important due to large roster sizes and the specialization of playing positions. As a result, head football coaches spend considerable time and effort selecting and developing their assistant coaches. The purpose of the present study was twofold: to examine the criteria head coaches used in selecting their assistant coaches and to examine the career progression, and coaching roles and responsibilities of head assistant football coaches in Canada. Semi structured open ended interviews were conducted with 6 successful Canadian head University football coaches who were identified by a panel of experts familiar with this sport. The sample of coaches won numerous coaching awards (e.g., coach of the year), had team success (e.g., winning Vanier Cup), and were recognized for strong programs in both the classroom and their communities. Head coaches looked for assistants who cared about their athletes, had important personal values concerning loyalty and education, and possessed strong leadership skills. In addition, head coaches chose assistants who possessed a large base of football knowledge from their success as both an athlete and as an assistant coach. In addition, they described the importance of hiring assistant coaches who had different areas of expertise from their own. These results represent one of the first empirical accounts of the knowledge used by head coaches for selecting assistant coaches. In addition, this study represents new information on the primary roles and responsibilities of head assistant coaches. These results will be of interest and benefit to both head coaches and assistant coaches.</description><creator>Rathwell, Scott</creator><contributor>Gordon Bloom (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Social Sciences - Recreation</subject><title>Head coaches' perceptions on the the selection and development of the assistant coach</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43p175n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128f573</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78tg61p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse comporte trois essais qui explorent de nouvelles méthodes pour l'extraction d'informations à partir des données sur les options. Nous examinons aussi les effets de la liquidité dans le marché des options.Dans le premier essai, nous proposons une nouvelle approche pour extraire la prime de risque sur les actions (equity premium) implicite dans les options. Par la suite, nous examinons la capacité de cette prime de risque implicite à prédire les rendements du marché. Notre approche ne nécessite pas la connaissance du facteur d'actualisation stochastique (pricing kernel) et n'impose aucunes restrictions sur les préférences des investisseurs. Nous supposons l'existence d'un continuum d'options call et put et démontrons que la prime de risque implicite peut être déduite à partir des rendements espérés d'un portefeuille d'options. Une étude empirique des options sur l'indice S&amp;P 500 révèle les conclusions suivantes : (i) la prime de risque implicite prédit les rendements du marché ; (ii) la performance de la prime de risque implicite est meilleure que celles des variables communément utilisées dans la littérature ; (iii) la prime de risque implicite est positivement liée aux rendements futures et négativement liée aux rendements actuels, comme la théorie le prédit.Dans le deuxième essai, nous examinons les effets de l'illiquidité sur les rendements des options. Il est bien connu que l'illiquidité est un déterminant important des rendements des actions et des obligations. Nous démontrons l'existence de primes de risque liées à l'illiquidité dans le marché des options sur actions. Une augmentation de l'illiquidité de l'option entraine une diminution du prix actuel de l'option et une augmentation du rendement espéré de la stratégie de couverture delta-neutre (delta-hedged). Ce résultat est statistiquement et économiquement significatif et cohérent avec le fait que les pourvoyeurs de liquidité ont une position nette longue dans le marché des options. Ce résultat est robuste aussi bien pour les options call que les options put, et ceci en utilisant différentes approches empiriques. Il est aussi robuste au contrôle de différentes variables spécifiques aux compagnies, et aussi à l'illiquidité de l'actif sous-jacent. Pour les options à long terme, nous démontrons l'existence d.une prime de risque liée à un facteur de liquidité.Dans le troisième essai, nous démontrons que dans les modèles multifactoriels de tarification des actifs, les prix du risque liés aux facteurs qui sont une fonction non linéaire du rendement du marché peuvent être directement obtenus à partir des options sur indice. L'application de ce résultat général au cas du risque de « co-skewness » montre que le prix de ce risque est égal à la différence entre le deuxième moment sous la mesure physique et le deuxième moment sous la mesure risque-neutre. De la même manière, on démontre que le prix du risque de « co-kurtosis » est égal à la différence entre le troisième moment sous la mesure physique et le troisième moment sous la mesure risque-neutre. Le signe des estimés de ces prix de risque sont cohérents avec la théorie et la valeur des primes de risque obtenues en utilisant ces prix de risque est raisonnable. Mais aussi, en utilisant ces prix de risque, nous améliorons la performance des modèles qui incorporent les risques de « co-skewness » et de « co-kurtosis ». La performance de ces modèles est aussi supérieure à celle du CAPM ou encore celle du modèle de Fama-French.</description><description>This thesis consists of three essays that explore alternative approaches to extracting information from option data, and, along somewhat different lines, examine the channels through which liquidity is priced in equity options.The first essay proposes a novel approach to extracting option-implied equity premia, and empirically examines the information content of these risk premia for forecasting the stock market return. Our approach does not require specifying the functional form of the pricing kernel, and does not impose any restrictions on investors' preferences. We only assume the existence of put and call options which complete the market, and show that the implied equity premium can be inferred from expected excess returns on a portfolio of options. An empirical investigation of S&amp;P 500 index options yields the following conclusions: (i) the implied equity premium predicts stock market returns; (ii) the implied equity premium consistently outperforms variables commonly used in the forecasting literature both in- and out-of-sample; (iii) the implied equity premium is positively related to future returns and negatively related to current returns, as theoretically expected.The second essay studies the effect of illiquidity on equity option returns. Illiquidity is well-known to be a significant determinant of stock and bond returns. We are the first to report on illiquidity premia in equity option markets using a large cross-section of firms. An increase in option illiquidity decreases the current option price and predicts higher expected delta-hedged option returns. This effect is statistically and economically significant, and it is consistent with existing evidence that market makers in the equity options market hold net long positions. The illiquidity premium is robust across puts and calls, across maturities and moneyness, as well as across different empirical approaches. It is also robust when controlling for various firm-specific variables including a standard measure of illiquidity of the underlying stock. For long term options, we find evidence of a liquidity risk factor. In the third essay, we demonstrate that in multifactor asset pricing models, prices of risk for factors that are nonlinear functions of the market return can be readily obtained using data on index returns and index options. We apply this general result to the measurement of the conditional price of coskewness and cokurtosis risk. The price of coskewness risk corresponds to the spread between the physical and the risk-neutral second moments, and the price of cokurtosis risk corresponds to the spread between the physical and the risk-neutral third moments. Estimates of these prices of risk have the expected sign, and they lead to reasonable risk premia. An out-of-sample analysis of factor models with coskewness and cokurtosis risk indicates that the new estimates of the price of risk improve the models. performance. The models also robustly outperform competitors such as the CAPM and the Fama-French model.</description><creator>Karoui, Mehdi</creator><contributor>Ruslan Goyenko (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Peter Christoffersen (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Economics - Finance</subject><title>Three essays in asset pricing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h314d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tg61p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Desautels Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21tk02k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La présente thèse aborde le développement d'une nouvelle analyse et technique de recherche pour des resonances massives dans les distributions angulaires des états finaux dits photon+jet parmi les données récoltées en 2012 parle détecteur ATLAS du LHC. Une nouvelle variable angulaire développée sur mesure pour le canal photon+jet a d'ailleurs été définie afin de pouvoir distinguer le bruit de fond du signal plus efficacement. La sensitivité de cette observable a été optimisée en utilisant des échantillons Monte Carlo de quarks excités ainsi que du programme JetPhox. Une classification optimale en terme de masse a aussi été dérivée à partir de la mésure de la résolution de masse. Des travaux sont en course afin de publier l'analyse.</description><description>This thesis outlines developments towards a new analysis and search technique for heavy resonances in angular distributions of photon+jet final states for the 2012 data set from the ATLAS detector on the LHC. In particular, a new angular variable tailored to the photon+jet channel was defined which distinguishes between background and expected signals, the corresponding angular observable sensitivity was optimized using ATLAS excited quark samples and JetPhox MC samples, and an optimal mass binning scheme was derived from the measured mass resolution. Ongoing work is being done to publish the analysis.</description><creator>Keyes, Robert</creator><contributor>Andreas Warburton (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Physics - Elementary Particles and High Energy</subject><title>New angular search for exotic physics in the photon+jet final state using the ATLAS detector on the LHC</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dk21b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21tk02k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:05741w24r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Reproductive timing often affects reproductive success. Plants and animals in a multitude of habitats time reproduction to coincide with environmental conditions that are conducive to fertilization or offspring growth and survival. Many marine organisms time the release of planktonic larvae with large amplitude nocturnal tides.  These conditions sweep the newly hatched offspring away from shore, and high densities of predators, while diurnally feeding predators are inactive. Experimental work has supported the hypothesis that these strong cycles of reproduction are driven by the avoidance of predators. However, how planktonic predation risk varies across interacting environmental cycles remains unclear. I used tethered adult and larval brine shrimp to assess the risk of predation across diel, tidal amplitude and seasonal cycles (upwelling vs. nonupwelling). The proportion of prey items lost was higher during the day than at night for larvae, but showed the opposite trend for adults. On the Pacific coast of Panama, the pattern of higher diurnal predation on larvae remained consistent across seasons, but risk increased overall during upwelling. Thus, the release of larvae at night should indeed increase early larval survival. Matching reproductive timing with particular times in environmental cycles may be hampered by the inverse effect of temperature on developmental rate. For brooding organisms that reproduce across seasonal changes in temperature, changes in incubation period will result in errors in timing of larval release if adjustments to temperature are not made.  Using laboratory and field experiments, I examined the effect of temperature and temperature variation on the timing of larval release of two species of fiddler crabs both of which usually release larvae during large amplitude nocturnal tides. I found that Uca terpsichores maintained timing in the field during low but constant temperature but made errors in timing when temperature varied during incubation. Uca deichmanni maintained accurate and precise timing of larval release in the field despite variable temperature but released larvae late in cold conditions in the lab. To determine whether these species reduce temperature-induced timing errors by shifting when they mate, I measured courtship intensity across seasonal temperature changes at field sites with different thermal properties. Both species exhibit strong cycles of courtship linked with tidal amplitude that result in their strong cycles of larval release. I found that courtship cycles and tidal amplitude for U. deichmanni remained strongly correlated across spatial and temporal differences in temperature. In contrast, the relationship between courtship and tidal amplitude for U. terpsichores changed across sites and with seasonal temperature variation. U. terpsichores respond to temperature variation by changing when they mate while U. deichmanni do not. Predictions for the effect of climate change on seasonal upwelling of cold water include increased variability and increased intensity in upwelling. The predictive nature of adjustment by U. terpsichores means that they may be more vulnerable to timing errors with increased temperature variability while behavioural adjustments by U. deichmanni during incubation may make them more vulnerable to increased intensity of upwelling. The combination of timing errors that result from upwelling induced temperature variation and the seasonal increase in predation risk during upwelling may have significant impacts on early larval survival.</description><description>Le moment de reproduction a souvent une influence sur le succès reproducteur. Chez les plantes et les animaux, plusieurs espèces provenant de divers habitats synchronisent leur reproduction avec les conditions environnementales favorables à la fertilisation ou à la croissance et la survie de leur progéniture. Plusieurs organismes marins adaptent la libération de leurs larves planctoniques aux marées nocturnes de plus grande amplitude. Lors de ces marées, les larves récemment écloses sont éloignées du rivage, où l'on retrouve la plus forte densité de prédateurs potentiels, et échappent également aux prédateurs diurnes. Jusqu'à présent, des études expérimentales ont soutenu l'hypothèse que les périodes de reproduction étaient déterminées par l'évitement des prédateurs. Cependant, malgré l'importance des effets de la prédation sur le rythme de vie des organismes marins, l'impact d'autres facteurs environnementaux cycliques pouvant avoir des effets sur le risque de prédation n'a pas été démontré. Afin d'étudier cette possibilité, j'ai utilisé des artémies adultes et au stade larvaire comme proies afin d'évaluer le risque de prédation à travers les cycles journaliers, saisonniers et d'amplitude des marées (remontée d'eau vs. non-remontée d'eau). Mes résultats ont démontré que la proportion de proies perdues lors de ces expériences variait de façon significative entre le jour et la nuit, ainsi qu'entre le type de proie (adulte ou larve). Pour les adultes artémias, le risque de prédation était plus grand la nuit que durant le jour ; contrairement aux larves où leur risque de prédation était plus grand le jour. Sur la côte Pacifique du Panama, le cycle journalier des larves artémias  s'est maintenu de manière constante à travers les saisons mais le risque de prédation a augmenté durant la période de remontée d'eau. En conséquence, le taux de survie des larves primitives devrait augmenter si les périodes de reproduction sont contrôlés avec précision.  Cependant, le fait de synchroniser le cycle de reproduction avec des périodes optimales dans des cycles environnementaux peut être entravé par l'effet inverse que la température peut avoir sur le rythme de développement. Pour les espèces ovipares se reproduisant à l'année, donc sujets à des variations de température, des ajustements doivent être faits quant à la période d'incubation, sinon cela pourrait entraîner des erreurs au niveau du moment propice à la libération des larves. En combinant des expériences en laboratoire et sur le terrain, j'ai examiné l'effet de la température et des variations de température sur le moment de libération des larves de deux espèces de crabes violonistes qui normalement libèrent leurs larves lors des marées du printemps. Mes résultats ont montré que, sur les sites de recherche, l'espèce Uca terpsichores a maintenu le  bon moment de libération des larves lors des périodes constantes de basses températures, mais que des erreurs ont été observées lorsque le changement de température se produisait durant la période d'incubation. La seconde espèce, U. deichmanni, a su maintenir le bon moment de libération des larves sur les sites de recherche, et ce malgré des changements de température, mais un délai dans la libération des larves  a été observé dans des conditions de basse température en laboratoire. Afin de déterminer si ces deux espèces réduisent l'effet des erreurs causées par les changements de température sur la libération des larves en modifiant le moment de l'accouplement, j'ai mesuré l'intensité de la parade (cour) durant les changements saisonniers de température dans plusieurs sites de recherche ayant différentes conditions thermiques. Les résultats montrent que le cycle de cour des deux espèces est fortement lié aux cycles et aux amplitudes des marées et il semble que cela ait un effet important sur le moment de libération des larves. </description><creator>Kerr, Kecia</creator><contributor>Frederic Guichard (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Rachel Collin (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Ecology</subject><title>Timing it right: reproductive timing during variable temperature and implications for risk of predation on larvae</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246w54d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741w24r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483n762</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le sujet de cette thèse concerne la mise en œuvre d'une analyse numérique visant à optimiser les techniques de mélange utilisées dans les applications industrielles. Dans cette recherche, nous simulons tout d'abord le mélange d'une quantité scalaire à partir d'un modèle classique d'écoulement fluide appelé "sine flow". Ensuite, nous présentons une amélioration de ce modèle et rapportons une analyse très complète de nos résultats. L'écoulement "sine flow" est non-linéaire, bidimensionnel et semi stationnaire car entre chaque intervalle de temps, l'orientation des champs de vitesse subit une rotation de 90 degrés. Nous appelons "protocole de mélange" le nombre et la durée des changements d'orientation des champs de vitesse au cours d'une même simulation. Nous montrons que l'optimisation du mélange des champs scalaires dépend directement du choix du protocole de mélange. Pour quantifier la qualité du mélange du scalaire nous utilisons un paramètre appelé "mix-norm" qui est la variance du scalaire mélangé calculée sur l'ensemble des échelles spatiales des champs scalaires. Dans cette thèse, nous rappelons tout d'abord les difficultés que peut induire la conception d'un mélangeur optimal. Un mélangeur optimal est capable de fournir un mélange homogène indépendamment de la distribution initiale des champs scalaire à mélanger. Nous démontrons que les performances du modèle "sine flow" ne sont ni optimales ni uniformes mais qu'elles peuvent être grandement améliorées en optimisant de façon dynamique le protocole de mélange. Cette optimisation est contrôlée en modulant un paramètre appelé "switching time horizon" qui, lorsque sa valeur est égale à 1 caractérise le plus simple protocole de mélange possible. Nous démontrons que celui-ci est particulièrement efficace en comparaison avec des protocoles plus complexes et plus couteux en termes de ressources informatiques. Dans un second temps, nous montrons que le modèle "sine flow" est très loin de simuler un mélangeur optimal. Toutefois, nous montrons qu'une extension du modèle "sine flow", que nous appelons modèle "Fourier sine flow", ore des possibilités importantes d'optimisation. En effet, ce nouveau modèle "Fourier sine flow" génère un champ de vitesse dont les profils sont représentés par une série de Fourier. Le calcul des amplitudes et des déphasages des modes de Fourier sont des paramètres modulables qui peuvent être utilisés pour maximiser la qualité du mélange. Finalement, nous démontrons que l'utilisation de ce nouveau modèle produit des résultats très réalistes lorsque la puissance énergétique nécessaire a la mise en mouvement de l'écoulement fluide est correctement quantifiée et contrainte lors de la simulation. Ainsi, nous mettons en évidence le rapport coût/efficacité de ce nouveau modèle et de sa capacité à optimiser un mélange en termes de temps total, d'énergie et de ressources informatiques nécessaires. Nous présentons et discutons des résultats les plus pertinents et parfois même inattendus. Ce travail ore une perspective réaliste pour l'optimisation d'un mélangeur utilisant les écoulements laminaires et il apporte une orientation possible au développement de nouveaux mélangeurs ou à l'optimisation des mélangeurs actuellement utilises dans l'industrie.</description><description>In this thesis, we design and test several mixing optimization strategies with the scope of improving current, and designing novel, industrial mixing devices. As a case study, we use numerical simulation to characterize, redesign and optimize a prototypical mixing device, the sine flow, which stirs a mixture on a two-dimensional domain alternating orthogonal, piecewise-steady, nonlinear velocity fields. As a measure of the quality of mixing and as a cost function for the optimization strategies, we use the mix-norm, an average multi-scale measure of the scalar variance over different coarse graining of the mixing domain. First, we address the conceptual problem of designing a mixing device able to deliver an optimal and uniform mixing performance for different initial configurations of the mixture. We show that the performance of the sine flow is not optimal nor uniform, but it can be greatly improved by optimizing on-line its stirring protocol. We demonstrate that the simplest form of the protocol optimization is competitively effective with respect to more complex and computationally expensive optimizations. Second, we consider a more challenging problem, the problem of designing an optimal mixer, i.e. a mixing device whose performance is uniform with respect to a large set of initial and operating conditions. We show that the sine flow is far from being an optimal mixer, however, it is possible to obtain an optimal mixer by redesigning the actuating system of the sine flow and coupling the optimization of the stirring protocol with a simple optimization of the stirring velocity fields. Third, we consider  the optimization of the profile of the stirring velocity fields. To this end, we introduce the Fourier sine flow, an extension of the sine flow that enables the generation of stirring velocity fields whose profiles are represented by a Fourier sine series. This novel mixing device allows us to optimize the velocity profiles by computing the amplitudes and phase shifts of the Fourier modes so that the synthesized stirring velocity field maximizes the mixing quality by the end of a stirring iteration. We demonstrate that this optimization produces realistic results only if the power input needed to generate the stirring flow is properly constrained. Subsequently, we characterize the cost-efficiency of the velocity profile optimization in terms of the total time, energy and computational cost needed to obtain a desired level of homogenization of the mixture and present some insightful and unexpected results. Our work puts in a realistic perspective the optimization of mixing in laminar regimes, providing guidance for the development and enhancement of industrial mixers.</description><creator>Gubanov, Oleg</creator><contributor>Luca Cortelezzi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical </subject><title>On the optimization of mixing in laminar regimes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vv447.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483n762</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5999n689w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les cadres à contreventements concentriques en acier (CCC) sont parmis les systèmes de résistance de forces sismiques (SRFS) les plus utilisés au Canada et à travers le monde. Dans les édifices uniétagaires, ces contreventements sont souvent couplés avec une diaphragme flexible en acier comme méthode de transmission des forces sismiques à travers du SRFS. Les charges sismiques sont déterminés en utilisant le NBCC 2010, et la conception et les détails pour le CCC sont donnés par le CSA S16-09. La philosophie du conception des capacités est utilisé, où un élément fusible est choisi dans un SRFS – pour CCC, les contreventements – est conçu et détaillé pour écouler dans l'évènement d'un fort mouvement du sol. La norme CSA S16-09 assure que l'élément fusible démontre la quantité nécessaire de ductilité et de dissipation d'énergie pour résister aux grandes déformations imposées par le séisme. Les éléments structuraux qui sont autour de l'élément fusible sont protégés de telle manière que le système de résistance de gravité reste élastique après un tel séisme, afin que les occupants ont le temps d'évacuer. Les provisions sismiques du NBCC et S16 ont grandement évolué au cours des cinquante dernières années. En particulier, la conception des capacités n'a pas été employé pendant les années 1960 à 1970. En tant que tel, il devient difficile de prédire le comportement sismique des structures existantes conçues et construites dans cette période.  Ce rapport examine la performance des structures conçues avec le NBCC 1965 et la norme CSA S16-65 en utilisant le logiciel d'analyse structurelle opensees. La précision du modèle est réalisée en synchronisant les paramètres materiels obtenus par des testes physiques de spécimens existantes avec la modèle de OpenSees. Des analyses incrémentale dynamique sont faits sur 32 structures prototype. Sept critères de faillite, incluant la fracture au section-nette, cisaillement des boulons, bloc de cisaillement, portance et une limite sur le déplacement sont utilisés pour déterminer le niveau de performance pour les structures prototypes en utilisant une methodologie similaire avec celle du FEMA-P695.</description><description>Concentrically-braced frames (CBFs) are among the most common seismic force resisting systems (SFRSs) used in Canada and across the world. In single-storey applications, these braces are often paired with a flexible steel diaphragm as a means of effectively transferring the seismic forces through the SFRS. Seismic loads are determined using the 2010 NBCC, while the design and detailing requirements for CBFs are provided by the CSA S16-09 Standard. The capacity design philosophy is used, in which one element in the SFRS is designed to undergo large inelastic deformations in the event of a strong ground motion; for a CBF, this fuse element is chosen as the braces. The CSA S16-09 ensures that the fuse element exhibits the necessary amount of ductility and energy dissipation to withstand the large deformations imposed by the earthquake. Structural elements surrounding the fuse element are protected in such a way that the gravity load resisting system remains elastic after such an earthquake so that occupants have time to evacuate.  The seismic provisions in the NBCC and S16 have greatly evolved over the past fifty years. In particular, the capacity design philosophy was not employed in design between 1960 and 1970. As such, it becomes difficult to predict the seismic performance of existing structures designed and constructed within that time period. The seismic performance of structures designed using the 1965 NBCC and CSA S16-65 is examined using the open-source structural analysis software OpenSees. Model accuracy is achieved through the calibration of the material parameters obtained through the physical testing of existing brace specimens with the OpenSees model. Incremental dynamic analyses are performed on 32 prototype structures. Seven failure criteria for net-section fracture, bolt shear, block shear, bearing failure and drift limitations are used to determine the performance level of the prototype structures using a methodology similar to that found in FEMA-P695.</description><creator>Caruso Juliano, Anthony</creator><contributor>Colin Andrew Rogers (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Civil</subject><title>Performance of seismically deficient existing braced steel frame structures with flexible diaphragms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bm980.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n689w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dw97f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Un objectif principal de l'analyse fonctionnelle et prédictive de l'ARN est d'obtenir sa structure tridimensionnel à partir de sa séquence. Pour résoudre ce problème, plusieurs méthodes ont été développées durant les dernières années, telles la décomposition cyclique, l'assemblage de fragments et la simulation de dynamiques moléculaire. Cependant, leurs capacacités prédictives restent limitées. Nous avons mis au point un nouvel outil, RNA-MoIP, permettant d'incorporer l'information des motifs locaux nouvellement accessibles dans des bases de données pour la prédiction de structures d'ARN. Nous montrons que notre approche (i) améliore la prédiction des paire de bases canoniques (ii) identifie la meilleure structure secondaire dans un ensemble de sous-optimaux et (iii) prédit des structures 3D précises pour de large molécules d'ARN.</description><description>The prediction of RNA three-dimensional structures from its sequence only is a milestone to RNA function analysis and prediction. In recent years, many methods addressed this challenge, ranging from cycle decomposition and fragment assembly to molecular dynamics simulations. However, their predictions remain fragile and limited to small RNAs. In this work, we introduce RNA-MoIP, a new framework incorporating the novel local motif information available in databases for the prediction of RNA structures. We show that our approach (i) improves the accuracy of canonical base pair predictions, (ii) identifies the best secondary structures in a pool of sub-optimal structures, and (iii) predicts accurate 3D structures of large RNA molecules.</description><creator>Reinharz, Vladimir</creator><contributor>Jérôme Waldispuhl (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>Towards 3D structure prediction of large RNA molecules: an integer programming framework to insert local 3D motifs in secondary structure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hd324.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dw97f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227mt462</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La famille de protéines fibuline est composée de huit membres, se situant dans la matrice extracellulaire, associée aux fibres élastiques et aux membranes basales. Les fibres élastiques confèrent l'élasticité requise aux organes, tels que les artères majeures, les poumons et la peau. La formation des fibres élastiques requiert la coordination de nombreuses protéines. Les souris knockout ont impliqué les fibulines courtes (fibuline-3, -4, et -5) dans la formation, la stabilisation, et le fonctionnement des fibres élastiques.Les fibulines courtes recombinantes ont été exprimées par les cellules HEK293 et purifiées par chromatographie d'affinité métallique. Les trois protéines migrent en  plusieurs bandes sur les gels de SDS-PAGE. Le séquençage de l'extrémité N-terminale de ces bandes a démontré que les trois protéines sont coupées dans le linker du premier domaine de facteur de croissance épidermique lié au calcium. Cet effet de plusieurs bandes est en partie causé pas la N-glycosylation et la multimérisation des fibulines courtes. Un effet similaire se produit après l'incubation des fibulines courtes avec certaines métalloprotéinases matricielles. La protéolyse de fibuline-3 est presque complètement inhibée par l'addition de doxycycline (un inhibiteur de tous les métalloprotéinases matricielles) aux cellules HEK293.Les fibroblastes dermiques humains adhèrent  fortement aux fibulines courtes, ce qui a été mesuré avec la coloration des cellules au cristal violet. Les fibroblastes pulmonaires humains et les cellules musculaires lisses de veine ombilicale et d'artère ombilicale adhèrent  un peu moins fort. Les fibulines courtes interagissent aussi avec l'héparine immobilisée, en la présence de calcium. Ceci suggère que les fibulines courtes peuvent adhérer au sulfate d'héparane à la surface des cellules.</description><description>The fibulin family comprises eight extracellular matrix proteins associated with elastic fibers and basement membranes. Elastic fibers provide necessary tissue recoil to organs, including large arteries, lung, and skin, and elastogenesis requires the coordinated effort of many proteins. Knockout mouse studies have implicated fibulin-3, -4, and -5 (collectively referred to as the short fibulins), in elastic fiber assembly, stabilization, and function.Recombinant human full-length short fibulins were expressed in human embryonic kidney cells, and purified by immobilized metal ion affinity chromatography. All three members consistently appear as multiple bands on protein gels. N-terminal protein sequencing revealed that all three proteins are readily cleaved within the atypical N-terminal linker region of the first calcium-binding epidermal growth factor domain. This multiple band pattern is also in part caused by the N-glycosylation and multimerization of the short fibulins. A similar band pattern was produced by incubation of the short fibulins with select matrix metalloproteinases. Fibulin-3 proteolysis was almost completely inhibited in cell culture with doxycycline (a broad-spectrum matrix metalloproteinase inhibitor) supplementation.Human skin fibroblasts adhered strongly to the short fibulins, as measured by crystal violet attachment assays. Human lung fibroblasts and human umbilical vein and artery smooth muscle cells adhered slightly less. Calcium-dependent binding of the short fibulins to immobilized heparin in solid phase binding assays suggests that these fibulins may bind cell-surface heparan sulfate.</description><creator>Djokic, Jelena</creator><contributor>Dieter Reinhardt (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health Sciences - Dentistry</subject><title>Molecular properties of fibulin-3, -4 and-5</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rs41s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mt462</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf268886b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les expériences faites sur les animaux sont fondamentales à la recherche préclinique. La recherche sur les animaux vise tout d'abord à améliorer la santé et le bien-être des être humains. La recherche scientifique biomédicale sur les animaux constitue un sujet controversé qui soulève plusieurs questions éthiques. D'un côté, les expériences sur les animaux semblent acceptables éthiquement parce qu'elles contribuent à l'amélioration des intérêts de l'être l'humain. Alternativement, beaucoup considèrent qu'utiliser les animaux comme objets et les faire souffrir pour le bien de l'être humain, bafoue les droits moraux des animaux, et est, de ce fait, considéré comme non éthique. Jusqu'à présent, il n'existe toujours pas de consensus concernant la légitimité éthique des expériences menées sur les animaux en laboratoires, et le nombre d'animaux utilisés dans les projets de recherches précliniques a augmenté ces vingt dernières années. Ainsi, on voit poindre un fort mouvement social et académique qui prône une réforme de l'utilisation des animaux dans la recherche biomédicale. Cependant, il existe toujours certains types de recherches précliniques, comme la recherche sur le cancer, qui ne peuvent se passer des animaux et qui continuent à les utiliser afin d'obtenir des résultats scientifiques valides. Or, les expériences sur le cancer sont contraignantes et exigeantes pour les sujets animaux. Un malaise moral s'est crée chez de nombreux chercheurs et activistes concernant ces expériences justement. De plus, des inquiétudes ont été soulevées sur l'application concrète et la pertinence des données émanant de sujets animaux à des tests cliniques sur les humains. Ainsi, ces inquiétudes sont abordées dans une nouvelle réforme in-vivo­ le "Companion Animal Model (CAM)", où les animaux de compagnie qui développent spontanément le cancer, sont utilisés comme sujets de recherches au stade préclinique. Les considérations et complications éthiques du CAM n'ont toutefois pas été analysées en profondeur dans la littérature, mais l'utilisation des animaux de compagnie comme sujets de recherche commence malgré tout à être reconnu dans les normes de recherche à ce stade. Cette thèse discute des avantages et limites pragmatiques du CAM, et considére aussi certaines obligations éthiques supplémentaires que les scientifiques devraient prendre en compte afin de respecter la relation propriétaire-animal de compagnie. En plus, nous voyons que certains autres problèmes éthiques sont susceptibles de se poser, si l'on suit les enseignements du CAM. La discussion éthique de cette thèse est basée sur les relations humains-animaux et les droits, intérêts, obligations, et responsabilités du propriétaire, de l'animal de compagnie, et des scientifiques. Finalement, cette thèse encourage une discussion éthique encore plus approfondie concernant le CAM avant que ne soit formalisées des politiques ou des directives</description><description>Animal experimentation is a fundamental part of pre-clinical research. Among primary goals of animal research is to benefit the health and wellbeing of humankind. Animal experimentation in biomedical scientific research is a contentious topic in research ethics. On one side, animal experimentation is considered to be ethically acceptable because it benefits human interests. Alternatively, many consider reifying and inflicting pain on animals for humanity's gain as violating animal moral rights, and thus it is deemed unethical. There remains no clear-cut universal consensus regarding the ethical legitimacy of animal use in laboratories, and the number of animals used in pre-clinical research has grown in the last two decades. This has resulted in a strong movement urging for reforms to current animal models in biomedical research. However, some types of pre-clinical research cannot replace animal models, and continue to need them for proper scientific results, such as cancer research. Cancer research is extremely strenuous and demanding on animal subjects. Consequently, numerous researchers and animal activists have developed moral malaise regarding experimental animal use in pre-clinical cancer research. Further concerns have emerged regarding transferability and relevancy of data gathered from experimental animal subjects to human clinical trials. Accordingly, a novel in-vivo reform to address these concerns is the Companion Animal Model (CAM), where pets who spontaneously develop cancer are used as pre-clinical cancer research subjects. While the use of pets as subjects is starting to be recognized in the pre-clinical research field, the ethical considerations and complications associated with the CAM have not been explored in depth. This thesis discusses the pragmatic benefits and limitations of the CAM, as well as suggests additional ethical responsibilities that researchers should uphold to respect the owner-companion animal relationship. Further, certain potential ethical complications that may emerge when using the CAM are introduced. The ethical discussion is based on owner-companion animal and researcher-animal relationships, as well as the moral rights, interests, obligations, and responsibilities of the owner, companion animal, and researchers. Finally, this thesis encourages further ethical discussion regarding the CAM prior to any policy or guideline formalization.</description><creator>Touyz, Sarah</creator><contributor>Carolyn Ells (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health Sciences - General</subject><title>The "Companion animal model": an ethical discussion on using pets with spontaeous cancer in pre-clinical cancer research</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qd312.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268886b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dj52w820x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Quelles sont les causes qui mènent du désordre à l'ordre ? Comment des états effondrés peuvent-ils être reconstruits ? Quelles sont les causes de l'émergence et des succès de mouvements Islamiques dans ces états en déliquescence ? Cette thèse propose une explication d'économie politique de la formation de l'état à partir des restes de l'effondrement de celui-ci. En observant deux cas classiques d'états déliquescents - l'Afghanistan et la Somalie - cette thèse présente un processus endogène de transformation politique et sociale qui a mené à l'émergence de régimes Islamistes faibles, mais centralisés. La thèse présente deux processus causals spécifiques de la formation d'un état Islamiste à partir d'un état effondré : en premier lieu, un processus au long terme de transformation de l'identité Islamique à l'intérieur de la communauté d'affaires, utilisée comme mécanisme de réduction des coûts de transaction et d'amélioration de l'accession aux marchés; en second lieu, un calcul stratégique à court terme du coût d'exploitation lors de chantages à la protection de chefs de guerre, comparativement au coût de financement d'une alternative politique. La recherche, qui est basée sur des enquêtes de terrain en Afghanistan, au Pakistan, au Kenya, en Somalie et aux Emirats Arabes Unis, examine les moteurs de l'Islamisme dans les états défaillants, et propose des chemins alternatifs à la création d'états.</description><description>What causes order out of disorder? How can states that have failed, be reconstituted? What causes the emergence and success of Islamic movements in these failed states? This dissertation offers a political economy explanation of state formation out of collapse. Looking at two classic cases of state failure – Afghanistan and Somalia – it presents an endogenous process of social and political transformation that led to the emergence of weak, but centralized Islamist regimes. This dissertation lays out two specific causal processes of Islamic state formation out of collapse: first, a long-term phenomenon of Islamic identity transformation within the business community, as a mechanism to reduce transaction costs and improve access to markets; and second, a short-term strategic calculation of the cost of operating under warlord protection rackets versus the cost of financing a political alternative. Based on original qualitative and quantitative field research from Somalia, Kenya, Pakistan, Afghanistan and the United Arab Emirates, the research examines the economic drivers of Islamism in failed states, and proposes alternative paths to state-building.</description><creator>Ahmad, Aisha</creator><contributor>Stephen Saideman (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Political Science - General</subject><title>Between the mosque and the market: an economic explanation of state failure and state formation in the modern muslim world</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bg212.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w820x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cf44s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le chargement mécanique est crucial dans la modulation de la physiologie et de l'architecture de l'os. Des expériences antérieures ont indiqué la communication intercellulaire entre les ostéoblastes lors de la stimulation mécanique. Ces résultats suggèrent l'implication d'un médiateur soluble. L'adénosine triphosphate (ATP) extracellulaire fonctionne comme des molécules de signalisation dans de nombreux processus de régulation cellulaire. Celle-ci semble être un candidat à risque. L'ATP agit sur les ostéoblastes via les récepteurs P2. Ici, la concentration d'ATP pour chacun de ces récepteurs P2 a été modélisée mathématiquement pour mieux comprendre leur rôle. Le processus de dégradation de l'ATP et la diffusion de l'ATP,  adénosine diphosphate (ADP) et adénosine monophosphate (AMP) ont aussi été modélisés.  Avec le luminomètre, nous étions capables de mesurer avec succès l'ATP par dosage de la luciférase de luciole. Des images de haute résolution de la détection d'ATP ont été obtenues avec un dispositif à transfert de charge (CCD). Enfin, l'indentification locale avec une pointe de microscopie à force atomique (MFA) est appliquée mécaniquement pour stimuler un ostéoblaste. Les résultats préliminaires sur l'imagerie en temps réel de la libération d'ATP à partir d'ostéoblastes sont présentés.</description><description>Mechanical loading is crucial in modulating the physiology and architecture of bone. Previous experiments indicated intercellular communication among osteoblasts upon mechanical stimulation, suggesting the involvement of a soluble signal mediator.  Extracellular adenosine triphosphate (ATP) functions as signaling molecules in many cell regulation processes, therefore appears to be a prone candidate.  ATP acts on osteoblasts through multiple P2 receptors.  To provide insights on the roles of individual receptors, we modeled ATP concentration dependence for different P2 receptors.  Next, the process of ATP degradation and the diffusion of ATP, adenosine diphosphate (ADP) and adenosine monophosphate (AMP) are modeled.  To conﬁrm the predictions of the model, we initiated experiments to measure ATP release from mechanically stimulated osteoblasts.  Fireﬂy luciferase assay successfully measures ATP using a luminometer and a charge coupled device (CCD) camera. Local indentation with a AFM cantilever is applied to mechanically stimulate an osteoblast. Preliminary results on real time imaging of ATP release from osteoblasts are reported.</description><creator>Xing, Shu</creator><contributor>Peter H Grutter (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Svetlana Komarova (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biophysics - General</subject><title>Intercellular communication between bone cells induced by mechanical stimulation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gh40k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cf44s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n583xz66s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>G protein-coupled receptors (GPCRs) comprise the largest group of cell surface receptors, translating environmental signals into cellular responses via cognate G protein partners. Contrary to our initial understanding, most GPCRs do not function in living cells as monomers, but most likely dimers, or even larger arrays of receptors. Standard drug design approaches rely on the notion that drugs binding the two receptors in a given dimer likely function independently of one another. However, this view has been challenged by recent work showing that ligand binding at both receptors can modulate dimeric receptors via allosteric communication. While one receptor may actually be needed to drive signalling, the other acts to control or modulate these signals, without a direct signalling outcome itself. Based on the notion of allosteric modulation within homo- and heterodimers, I tested and compared changes in signalling downstream as well as at the level of the receptor-G protein-effector (RGE) complex in response to different combinations of ligands at each protomer. Using a combination of calcium, cyclic adenosine monophosphate, and mitogen-activated protein kinase signalling assays, I have demonstrated functional interactions for a putative D2 dopamine receptor, oxytocin receptor heterodimer (D2R/OTR), in HEK 293 cells. Immunoprecipitation, bioluminescence resonance energy transfer (BRET) and confocal microscopy experiments reveal D2R and OTR do in fact form a heterodimer in vitro, which may explain the nature of these potential allosteric functional interactions. Using BRET, I assessed the RGE complex conformational dynamics in HEK 293 cells for two other heterodimers, β2-adrenergic receptor with cannabinoid CB1 receptor (β2AR/CB1R) and β2AR/OTR, in order to determine how they manifest in parallel to signalling events themselves. These studies reveal functional interactions can occur in terms of signalling complex conformation. Thus GPCR signalling can be modulated by its partner receptor at the level of downstream effector signalling or at the level of the signalling complex itself. With that said, putative heterodimers need to be reanalyzed in vivo for their allosteric properties, which may explain some of the side effects of so many drugs, and may have implications in drug design.</description><description>Les récepteurs couplés aux protéines G (RCPG) constituent le plus grand groupe de récepteurs de la surface cellulaire, qui traduisent les signaux environnementaux en réponses cellulaires via leurs protéines G associées. Contrairement à notre compréhension initiale, la majorité des RCPG ne fonctionnent pas en tant que monomères, mais possiblement en tant que dimères ou même oligomères. Les approches actuelles de conception de médicament estiment que lors de la liaison d'un médicament aux deux récepteurs d'un dimère quelconque, ces derniers fonctionnent potentiellement indépendamment l'un de l'autre. Cependant, cette notion a été reconsidérée par une étude récente montrant que la liaison d'un ligand aux deux récepteurs peut les altérer par voie de communication allostérique. Alors qu'un premier récepteur peut être requis pour initialiser la signalisation, un second peut contrôler ou modifier ces signaux, n'ayant pas nécessairement une signalisation directe comme résultante. Dans l'étude suivante, basée sur la notion de modulation allostérique au sein d'homodimère et d'hétérodimère, les changements de signalisation en aval ainsi qu'au niveau du complexe récepteur/protéine G/effecteur (RGE) ont été étudiés et comparés en réponse à différentes combinaisons de ligands pour chaque protomère. En utilisant une combinaison d'essais de signalisation de calcium, d'adénosine monophosphate cyclique (cAMP) et de protéine kinase activée par des agents mitogènes (MAPK), une interaction fonctionnelle entre le récepteur dopaminergique D2 et le récepteur de l'ocytocine (D2R/OTR) a été démontrée dans les cellules HEK 293. Des expériences d'immunoprécipitation, de transfert d'énergie de résonance par bioluminescence (BRET) et de microscopie confocale ont révélé la présence d'hétérodimère entre le D2R et l'OTR in vitro, ce qui pourrait expliquer la nature des interactions fonctionnelles allostériques. En utilisant la technique de BRET, la dynamique fonctionnelle du complexe RGE dans les cellules HEK 293 a été examinée chez deux autres hétérodimères, soit celui composé du récepteur adrénergique β2 et du récepteur cannabinoïde CB1 (β2AR/CB1R) et l'hétérodimère β2AR/OTR, afin de déterminer comment ils traduisent les évènements de signalisation. Ces études démontrent donc qu'une interaction fonctionnelle peut survenir sur le plan de la conformation du complexe de signalisation. Par conséquent, la signalisation d'un RCPG peut être modulée par son récepteur partenaire au niveau des effecteurs ou au niveau du complexe de signalisation lui-même. Pour cette raison, il serait impératif de réanalyser in vivo les propriétés allostériques d'hétérodimères putatifs, ce qui pourrait expliquer certains effets secondaires d'une multitude de médicaments et ce qui pourrait impliquer des changements majeurs dans la façon de concevoir de nouveaux médicaments. </description><creator>Altosaar, Katrin</creator><contributor>Terence Hebert (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Dimer-dependent allosteric modulation within GPCR signalling complexes can influence signalling diversity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dz81c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xz66s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9c67wr35s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les revêtements métalliques sacrificiels à base de zinc et cadmium sont utilisés pour protéger les composants en acier contre la corrosion. Les préoccupations environnementales et de la santé ont limité l'utilisation du cadmium car les bains de d'électrodéposition au Cd sont normalement à base de cyanure et en plus le Cd est cancérigène. Cette thèse examine le revêtement Zn-Ni pour remplacer le Cd et les revêtements à base de Cd pour utilisation dans l'industrie aérospatiale, ainsi que pour remplacer le Zn dans l'industrie automobile. Les caractéristiques étudiées sont les propriétés tribologique, la résistance à la corrosion et la tribocorrosion, ainsi que la susceptibilité à la fragilisation par l'hydrogène.La tribométrie in situ a révélé que les revêtements Zn-Ni on une résistance supérieure à l'usure adhésive par rapport aux revêtements cadmium. La micro-dureté des revêtements Zn-Ni était plus élevé que les celle des revêtements Zn et Cd. La dureté de la piste d'usure des revêtements Zn-Ni témoigne la formation d'une tribo-couche écrouie.Les revêtements Zn-Ni ont une plus grande résistance à polarisation après l'essai d'usure comparés aux revêtements Zn et Cd. La perte de masse due à l'usure améliorée à la corrosion était moins que pour les revêtements Zn et Cd. Les revêtements Zn-Ni sont un substitut approprié pour les revêtements Cd lorsque les surfaces sont soumises à l'usure et la corrosion simultanée. L'effet du traitement thermique et de la passivation au chrome trivalent sur la corrosion des revêtements Zn-Ni est également décrit. Les revêtements Zn-Ni démontrent une plus grande résistance à la polarisation lors des essais d'immersion comparés aux revêtements Cd. Les revêtements Zn-Ni offrent une meilleure protection à la corrosion sacrificielle en raison des faibles taux de corrosion, et sont de ce point de vue un substitut approprié de revêtements Cd.Au cours de l'électrodéposition de métaux, l'hydrogène se dégage par électrolyse. L'hydrogène peut soit diffuser vers l'extérieur et se piéger à l'interface entre le substrat en acier et le revêtement, soit migrer vers l'intérieur dans l'acier provoquant une fragilisation retardée lorsque le composant est soumis à une contrainte. Cette étude rapporte deux variables principales pour le Zn, Zn-Ni, et les revêtements Cd: (i) la quantité d'hydrogène absorbé par le revêtement et le substrat, mesurée par désorption thermique sous vide, et (ii) la perméabilité du matériau de revêtement à l'hydrogène, mesurée par perméation électrochimique. Les résultats sont analysés en corrélant les caractéristiques de la microstructure du matériau de revêtement et de l'interface entre le revêtement et le substrat en acier. Pour le Zn-Ni, le procès de revêtement ainsi que le matériau de revêtement, ensemble diminuent le risque de fragilisation par l'hydrogène en: (i) introduisant une quantité minimum d'hydrogène lors du processus d'électrodéposition, et (ii) par la facilité avec laquelle l'hydrogène peut être extrait par traitement thermique grâce à la présence de fissures dans le revêtement.Mots-clés: Zn-Ni, Cd, Cd-Ti, Zn, tribologie in situ, tribocorrosion, perméation de l'hydrogène.</description><description>Sacrificial metallic coatings, such as those based on Zn and Cd are used to protect steel components against corrosion. Growing environmental and health concerns have limited the use of Cd in any form since Cd plating bath is cyanide based and Cd compounds are carcinogenic.  This thesis investigates Zn-Ni as a potential replacement for Cd and Cd based alloy coatings used in aerospace industries and Zn in automotive industries with respect to their tribological, corrosion and tribocorrosion resistance and hydrogen embrittlement susceptibility.  In situ tribometry and additional ex situ analyses revealed that Zn-Ni coatings had superior resistance to adhesive wear compared to cadmium coatings. The microhardness of Zn-Ni coatings was higher than Zn and Cd coatings.  Hardness on the wear track of Zn-Ni coatings showed the formation of strain hardened tribo layer.  Zn-Ni coatings had higher polarization resistance after wear testing as compared to zinc and cadmium coatings.  The mass loss due to wear enhanced corrosion was less with Zn-Ni than with Zn and Cd coatings.  Zn-Ni coatings are a suitable replacement to Cd coatings when the surfaces are subjected to simultaneous wear and corrosion.  Zn-Ni coatings had higher polarization resistance after the 24 hour immersion tests compared to zinc and cadmium coatings.   Zn-Ni coatings offer better sacrificial corrosion protection because of low corrosion rates, and are a suitable replacement for Cd coatings. The Passivated Zn-Ni coatings showed lower corrosion resistance when heat treated due to localized damage of passive films while there was no effect of heat treatment on corrosion resistance of as plated Zn-Ni coatings.  During the electrodeposition of metals, hydrogen is evolved due to electrolysis. The evolved hydrogen may diffuse outward and become trapped in the substrate/coating interface or migrate inward into the steel lattice causing delayed embrittlement when the component is subjected to stress. This study reports two principal variables for Zn, Zn-Ni, and Cd coatings: (i) quantity of hydrogen absorbed by the coating and substrate, by vacuum thermal desorption (ii) permeability of the coating material to hydrogen, by electrochemical permeation. The findings were analyzed in correlation with microstructural characteristics of both the coating material and the coating/substrate interface. With Zn-Ni, both coating process and coating material combined to significantly reduce the risk of internal hydrogen embrittlement by: (i) introducing the least amount hydrogen during the electrodeposition process, and (ii) by the ease with which hydrogen can be extracted by baking due to the presence of cracks in the coating.Keywords: Zn-Ni, Cd, Cd-Ti, Zn, EIS, insitu tribology, tribocorrosion, hydrogen permeation, TDS</description><creator>Kankoduthavanitham Rajagopalan, Sriraman</creator><contributor>Stephen Yue (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Materials Science</subject><title>Characterization of electrodeposited Zn-Ni alloy coatings as a replacement for electrodeposited Zn and Cd coatings</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k597g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wr35s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m039k8720</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The fundamental motivation for the work in this thesis is the analysis of the optimal control of hybrid systems on Riemannian manifolds using the language of differential geometry. Hybrid systems theory constitutes one of the major frameworks within which one may model and analyze the behaviour of large and complex systems; in particular, the optimal control of hybrid systems has been a focus of research over the last decades resulting in the important generalization of Minimum (Maximum) Principle of classic optimal control to hybrid systems.  In the work of Shaikh and Caines (2007) and their predecessors, a formulation for a class of optimal control problems for general hybrid systems with nonlinear dynamics and autonomous or controlled switchings at switching states and times is proposed.  In this thesis we extend the framework of Shaikh and Caines (2007) to a general class of hybrid systems defined on Riemannian manifolds. Due to the  formulation generality, this class of hybrid systems covers a vast range of practical examples arising in such different areas as mechanical systems, chemical processes, air traffic control systems and cooperative robotic manipulator systems. In this thesis, a formulation for general hybrid systems on  differentiable Riemannian manifolds is first presented. In the case of autonomous switchings, switching manifolds are modelled by  embedded orientable submanifolds of the ambient state manifold and consequently hybrid optimal control problems are defined for hybrid systems in this general setting.   Second, the classic Minimum Principle is extended to the Hybrid Minimum Principle (HMP) yielding the optimality necessary conditions for hybrid systems at the optimal switching states and times. The  HMP statement in this thesis is obtained by employing the so-called needle control variation in the control value space. This class of control variations results in state trajectory variations along the nominal state trajectory in the ambient state manifold where the optimality conditions are derived by analyzing the cost function variation with respect to state variations. Third, in order to optimize switching states and times, numerical optimization algorithms (Gradient Geodesic-HMP, Newton Geodesic-HMP) are formulated by employing the HMP equations on general Riemannian state manifolds.  The convergence analysis for the proposed algorithms is based upon the LaSalle Invariance Theorem. Technically these algorithms generalize the standard steepest descent and Newton methods in Euclidean spaces to Reimannian manifolds by employing the notion of Levi-Civita connections.  Fourth, the derivation of the HMP results for hybrid systems on Riemannian manifolds is carried out for hybrid systems on Lie groups. The group structure of the ambient state manifold gives rise to a special form for the adjoint processes and Hamiltonian functions as the solutions for the optimality equations. In this thesis hybrid optimal control problems on Lie groups are only considered for the class of left invariant systems, however, the analysis can be easily modified to right invariant systems.  In the setting of left invariant hybrid systems on Lie groups, the Gradient Geodesic-HMP and Newton Geodesic-HMP algorithm are modified into algorithms called the Gradient Exponential-HMP and Newton Exponential-HMP algorithms. The fifth and last part of the thesis focuses on the problem of optimization of autonomous hybrid optimal control problems with respect to the geometrical features of switching manifolds. Such features include first order and second order information on the switching manifolds such as curvature tensors and normal differential forms. </description><description>La motivation première du travail accompli dans cette thèse est l'analyse du contrôle optimal de systèmes hybrides sur les variétés riemanniennes en utilisant le language de la géométrie differentielle. La théorie des systèmes hybrides constitue un des cadres majeurs dans lequel on peut modeler et analyser le comportement de systèmes grands et complexes; en particulier, le contrôle optimal de systèmes hybrides a été le centre d'intérêt des recherches dans les décennies précédentes ayant comme résultat une importante généralisation du Principe Minimum (Maximum) du contrôle optimal classique aux systèmes hybrides.Le travail de Shaikh et Caines (2007) et leurs prédécesseurs propose une formule pour une classe de problèmes de contrôle optimal pour les systèmes hybrides généraux avec des dynamiques non linéaires et autonomes ou des commutations contrôlées aux états et temps de commutation. Cette thèse élargit le cadre de Shaikh et Caines (2007) à une classe générale de systèmes hybrides définis sur les variétés riemanniennes. En raison de la nature générale de la formulation, cette classe de systèmes hybrides couvre un vaste éventail d'exemples pratiques survenant dans différents domaines tels que les systèmes mécaniques, les procédés chimiques, le contrôle des systèmes de navigation aérienne, ainsi que les systèmes de manipulation de la robotique coopérative. Premièrement, cette thèse présente une formulation pour le cas des systèmes hybrides généraux sur les variétés riemaniennes différentielles. Dans le cas des commutations autonomes, les variétés de commutation sont modélisées par les sous-variétés prolongées et orientables de la variété d'état ambiante et conséquemment, les problèmes de contrôle optimal hybrides sont définis pour les systèmes hybrides dans ce contexte général. Deuxièmement, le Principe Minimum classique est étendu au Principe Minimum Hybride (HMP), produisant les conditions nécessaires d'optimalité pour les systèmes hybrides aux états et temps optimaux de commutation. L'énoncé du Principe Minimum Hybride (HMP) dans cette thèse est obtenu en utilisant la commande de variation d'aiguille, ainsi nommée, dans l'espace de valeur de contrôle. Cette classe de variation donne des variations de trajectoire au long de la trajectoire d'état nominale dans la variété d'état ambiante. Les conditions d'optimalité sont obtenues en analysant la variation de la fonction de coût en respectant les variations d'état. Finalement, la dernière partie de la thèse met l'accent sur la question d'optimisation des problèmes de contrôle optimal autonomes hybrides en ce qui concerne les caractéristiques géométriques des variétés de commutation. De telles caractéristiques comprennent des informations de premier et de second ordre sur les variétés de commutation telles que les tenseurs de courbures et les formes différentielles normales.</description><creator>Taringoo, Farzin</creator><contributor>Peter Edwin Caines (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Control and optimization of hybrid systems on Riemannian manifolds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827g29h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k8720</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75rc526</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La plupart des ARN messager mitochondriaux dans les parasites de la famille des trypanosomatides nécessite l'édition de l'ARN par insertion ou délétion de l'uridine, un processus médié par l'ARN guide (ARNg) et catalyser par des complexes multi protéiques appelés éditosomes. De récentes études ont montré que les six protéines de liaison oligonucleotide/oligosaccharide (KREPA1-A6), font partie du même groupe d'éditosome où ils forment un réseau d'interactions essentiels pour la stabilité des éditosomes. Certains de ces éditosomes s'associent aussi à l'ARN. Cette thèse explore l'interaction ARN-protéine de la protéine de liaison OB, KREPA4, pour obtenir une meilleure compréhension de son rôle dans l'organisation structurelle et fonctionnelle des éditosomes. KREPA4 est une protéine de liaison à l'ARN, essentielle pour l'intégrité du complexe d'éditosome et pour la survie du parasite Trypanosoma brucei. La protéine recombinante KREPA4 se lie à l'ARNg avec une préférence pour la queue oligo (U) à l'extrémité 3' de l'ARNg. La seule autre protéine présentement connu comme ayant une interaction directe avec KREPA4, est une autre protéine de liaison OB, KREPA6. KREPA4 possède à son extrémité N-terminale, deux régions de basse complexité (LCRs) prédites en plus du domaine de liaison OB à son extrémité C-terminale. Différentes parties d'une ou de deux de ces régions pourraient être impliqué dans les interactions de KREPA4 à l'ARN et à la protéine au sein du complexe d'éditosome. Dans la première partie de cette thèse, Je présente une étude examinant les propriétés de liaison à l'ARNg de la protéine KREPA4. Afin de cartographier le domaine de liaison à l'ARN, nous avons créé des mutants de délétion de la protéine KREPA4 et évalué leur affinité de liaison à l'ARNg ainsi que leur spécificité par des expériences de compétitions ou de retard sur gel. Nos résultats ont montrés que le domaine prédit à l'extrémité C-terminale OB de la protéine KREPA4 est responsable de la forte affinité de liaison de cette protéine à l'ARNg via l'interaction avec la queue oligo (U) de l'ARNg. Nous avons aussi montré que la structure en tige-boucle de l'ARNg contribue à l'affinité et à la spécificité de l'interaction entre KREPA4 et l'ARN par la liaison aux LCRs de l'extrémité N-terminale de KREPA4. De plus, nous avons testé KREPA4 pour la présence d'une possible activité d'annelation et nous avons trouvé la fonction d'annelation qui est associe avec le domaine prédit OB, ce qui représente le premier rapport d'une telle activité pour un composant essentiel du complexe d'édition de l'ARN. La deuxième partie de cette thèse est consacrée à une étude caractérisant des interfaces d'interactions protéiques de KREPA4 dans le complexe d'éditosome. Nous avons déterminé qu'une α-hélice prédite du domaine prédit OB de KREPA4 est nécessaire pour son interaction avec KREPA6. Un anticorps ciblant l'α-hélice de KREPA4 ou les mutations de cette région peut éliminer son association avec KREPA6, alors qu'un fragment peptidique correspondant à l'α-hélice peut interagir indépendamment avec KREPA6, supportant ainsi l'identification de l'interface KREPA4-KREPA6. Nous avons également établi que le domaine OB prédit de KREPA4, indépendant de son interaction avec ARNg, est responsable de l'intégration stable de KREPA4 dans les éditosomes. Par conséquent, si KREPA4 interagit avec KREPA6 dans la région α-hélice de son domaine OB, l'ensemble du domaine OB est nécessaire pour son intégration dans un éditosome fonctionnelle, possiblement par le biais d'interactions protéine-protéine additionnelles. Dans l'ensemble, ces études ont conduit à l'identification et la caractérisation de la liaison des ARNs et des interfaces d'interactions protéiques de KREPA4, et a également révélé la fonction d'annelation d'ARN de cette protéine. Par conséquent, ce travail offre une nouvelle perspective sur les interactions moléculaires possibles de KREPA4 dans l'éditosome.</description><description>Most mitochondrial mRNAs in trypanosomatid parasites require uridine insertion/deletion RNA editing, a process mediated by guide RNA (gRNA) and catalyzed by multi-protein complexes called editosomes. The research presented in this thesis began at a time when many of the proteins in the editosome complexes and some of their functions and interactions had been identified. However, little was known about how these proteins assemble and work together. Recent studies have established that the six oligonucleotide/ oligosaccharide binding (OB)-fold proteins (KREPA1-A6), are a part of the common core of editosomes where they form a network of interactions essential for the stability of the editosomes and some of them also bind the substrate RNA. This thesis explores the RNA and protein interactions of an OB-fold protein KREPA4 to gain better understanding of its role in the structural and functional organization of editosomes. KREPA4 is an RNA binding protein essential for the integrity of editosome complex and survival of Trypanosoma brucei. Recombinant KREPA4 binds to gRNA with a preference for the gRNA 3ʹ oligo(U) tail. The only other protein, with which KREPA4 is currently known to have a direct interaction, is another OB-fold protein, KREPA6. KREPA4 has two predicted low compositional complexity regions (LCRs) at its N-terminus, besides the predicted OB-fold domain at the C-terminal end. Different parts of one or both of these regions may be involved in the RNA and protein interactions of KREPA4 within the editosome complex, and these possibilities have been investigated in this thesis. In the first part of the thesis, I examined the gRNA binding properties of KREPA4. To map the RNA-binding domain, I created deletion mutants of KREPA4, and evaluated their gRNA-binding affinities as well as specificities by gel shift RNA binding and competition experiments. My results demonstrate that the predicted C-terminal OB-fold of KREPA4 is responsible for high-affinity binding of this protein to gRNA via interaction with the gRNA oligo(U) tail. I also show that the stem-loop structure of gRNA contributes to the affinity and specificity of KREPA4-RNA interaction by binding to the N-terminal LCRs of KREPA4. Furthermore, I tested KREPA4 for the presence of a possible RNA annealing activity and found the annealing function to be associated with the predicted OB-fold, representing the first report of such activity for a core component of the RNA editing complex. The second part of this thesis is devoted to a study characterizing the protein interaction interfaces of KREPA4 in the editosome complex. By screening a series of N- and C-terminally truncated KREPA4 fragments, I determined that a predicted α-helix of KREPA4 OB-fold is required for its interaction with KREPA6. An antibody against the KREPA4 α-helix or mutations of this region can eliminate association with KREPA6; while a peptide fragment corresponding to the α-helix can independently interact with KREPA6, thereby supporting the identification of KREPA4-KREPA6 interface. I also established that the predicted OB-fold of KREPA4; independent of its interaction with gRNA, is responsible for the stable integration of KREPA4 in the editosomes, and editing complexes co-purified with the tagged OB-fold can catalyze RNA editing. Therefore, while KREPA4 interacts with KREPA6 through the α-helix region of its OB-fold, the entire OB-fold is required for its integration in the functional editosome, possibly through additional protein-protein interactions. Overall, these studies have lead to the identification and characterization of RNA binding and protein interaction interfaces of KREPA4, and also revealed the RNA annealing function of this protein. Therefore, this work provides new insight into the possible molecular interactions of KREPA4 within the editosome, thus contributing significantly to the emerging picture of the structural and functional organization of the editosome complex.</description><creator>Kala, Smriti</creator><contributor>Reza Salavati (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Parasitology</subject><title>Identification and characterization of RNA binding and protein interaction domains of the key editosome protein KREPA4</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94ht24h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75rc526</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848v07z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Rab5 and Rab7 GTPases are key regulators of endosome to lysosome trafficking, whose activities are positively regulated by Rab Guanine nucleotide Exchange Factors and negatively regulated by GTPase Activating Proteins (GAP). In this thesis, the nematode Caenorhabditis elegans was used as a model system to study regulation of Rab GTPase-mediated endosomal trafficking, for simple genetics and easy visualization of organelles under Differential Interference Contrast (DIC) and confocal optics.  It was previously demonstrated that TBC-2 functions as a RAB-5 GAP. Loss of tbc-2 activity results in the formation of enlarged late endosomes in the intestine that require the activities of RAB-5, RAB-7 and components of the homotypic fusion and vacuole protein sorting (HOPS) complex. TBC-2 colocalizes with RAB-7 on late endosomes, and requires RAB-7 for membrane localization. My hypothesis is that RAB-7 recruits TBC-2 to late endosomes to inactivate RAB-5 and possibly RAB-7 itself, to facilitate early to late endosome maturation. The vh8 mutant was previously identified in the lab as a suppressor of the tbc-2(-) phenotype and displaces GFP::RAB-7 from vesicular membranes. It is possible that vh8 encodes for a potential RAB-7 GEF.  To investigate the molecular identity of vh8, I tested candidate genes by RNAi. While none of the candidates appear to be vh8, I did find that the HOPS core complex is required for the tbc-2(-) phenotype. ARL-8, and its human homolog arl8b, have recently been shown to be important for late endosome to lysosome trafficking. To investigate whether ARL-8 is required for TBC-2 mediated early to late endosome trafficking, I performed RNAi experiments. The results of which suggest that ARL-8 functions downstream of TBC-2.  ARL-8 is required for the tbc-2(-) large late endosome phenotype, but is not required for membrane localization of either TBC-2 or RAB-7.In mammalian cells, the Rac1 GTPase is able to bind Armus, a human homolog of TBC-2. That raises the possibility that RAB-7 recruits CED-10/Rac1 via TBC-2.  However, I observe that in tbc-2(tm2241) mutant animals, CED-10 is still localized to vesicles. It suggests that CED-10 might be recruited to membrane via other mechanism. Active CED-10 is also crucial for phagocytosis and clearance of apoptotic cell corpses. CED-10 can be activated by the CED-5/CED-12 complex, which is proposed to be recruited and activated by PI(3,5)P2. Work from this thesis suggests that the active state might not be a requirement for CED-10 localization, as ced-5 RNAi does not change the localization of CED-10.</description><description>Les GTPases Rab5 et Rab7 participent à la régulation du traffic des endosomes. L'activité de ces protéines est régulée positivement par les "Rab Guanine nucleotide Exchange Factors" (GEF) et régulée négativement par les "GTPase Activating Proteins" (GAP). Dans ce projet, le nematode Caenorhabditis elegans a été utilisé comme modèle pour étudier la régulation du traffic endosomal médié par les Rab GTPase car celui-ci est un bon modèle génétique et permet une visualisation des organites à l'aide de microscopie à constraste d'interférence différentielle et de microscopie confocale. Il a été démontré dans la passé que TBC-2 fonctionne en tant que GAP pour RAB-5. La perte de l'activité de tbc-2 résulte en la formation d'endosomes tardifs élargis dans les intestins des nématodes, qui requièrent normalement l'activité de RAB-5, RAB-7 et des constituants du complexe "homotypic fusion and vacuole protein sorting" (HOPS). TBC-2 se retrouve avec RAB-7 sur les endosomes tardifs et nécessite RAB-7 pour sa localisation sur la membrane. Notre hypothèse était que RAB-7 recrute TBC-2 aux endosomes tardifs pour inactiver RAB-5 et possiblement RAB-7, ce qui facilite la maturation des endosomes en endosomes tardifs.    Le mutant vh8 a préalablement été identifié dans le laboratoire en tant que suppresseur du phénotype tbc2(-) et cause le déplacement de GFP::RAB-7 des membranes vésiculaires.  Il est possible que vh8 exprime un potentiel GEF de RAB-7. Pour trouver l'identité moléculaire de vh8, nous avons testé les gènes candidats à l'aide d'ARN d'interférence (ARNi).  Malgré qu'aucun des candidats ne semblaient être vh8, nous avons découvert que le complexe central de HOPS est nécessaire au phénotype tbc-2(-).  ARL-8 et son homolog humain arl8b ont récessement été démontrés comme étant importants dans le traffic des endosomess tardifis aux lysosomes.  Pour vérifier si ARL-8 est requis dans le traffic des endosomes médiés par TBC-2.  Nos travaux à l'aide d'ARNi suggèrent qu'ARL-8 fonctionne en aval de TBC-2. ARL-8 est nécessaire à l'apparition du phénotype tbc-2(-), mais n'est pas requis pour la localisation de TBC-2 et RAB-7 à la membrane.    Dans les cellules de mammifères, la GTPase Rac1 peut se lier à Armus, un homologue humain de TBC-2. Ceci suggère que RAB-7 pourrait recruter CED-10/RAC1 par l'entremise de TBC-2.  Par contre, nous observons que chez les nématodes tbc-2(tm2241), CED-10 est toujours localisé sur les vésicules. Ceci suggère que CED-10 pourrait être recruté à la membrane par d'autres mécanismes.  Un CED-10 activé est aussi nécessaire à la phagocytose et à la dégradation des corps cellulaires apoptotiques. CED-10 peut être activé par le complexe CED-5/CED-12, qui est possiblement recruté et activé par PI(3,5)P2.  Nos travaux suggèrent par contre que l'activation de CED-10 n'est pas obligatoire à sa localisation, car l'ARNi de ced-5 ne change pas la localisation de CED-10.</description><creator>Wang, Xiaolin</creator><contributor>Christian Rocheleau (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Analysis of candidate regulators of TBC-2 and endosome maturation in «Caenorhabditis elegans»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xd245.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848v07z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:76537452c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les Andes Tropicales forment une des régions du monde présentant la plus grande biodiversité, mais l'origine de cette biodiversité reste peu connue. Depuis longtemps, une des hypothèses proposées pour l'expliquer suggère que la diversification eut lieu par vicariance et allopatrie dans les refuges forestiers du Pléistocène. Cependant, d'autres études récentes suggèrent que la surrection l'élévation des Andes, entre le Miocène et le Pliocène, a créé les conditions favorables à une spéciation aussi bien allopatrique que écologique. Dans cette étude, j'ai testé ces hypothèses ainsi que d'autres processus (par exemple l'hypothèse du centre d'origine vs. l'hypothèse du centre d'accumulation) qui pourraient expliquer les patrons actuels de diversité tropicale. Plus précisément, j'ai utilisé une approche combinant des outils génétiques, des données écologiques et des informations phylogénétiques au niveau des espèces pour répondre aux questions concernant les causes de la diversification dans deux groupes différents de papillons mimétiques néotropicaux: Heliconius cydno et les deux genres d'Ithomiinae, Hyalyris et Hypothyris. Les résultats de mes travaux appuient un modèle de diversification complexe étroitement lié à l'élévation finale des Andes. Dans les deux cas (Hyalryis-Hypothyris et H. cydno), la colonisation des flancs des Andes a été accompagnée d'un changement de mimétisme. En outre, dans le cas des Hyalryis il y a eu une forte corrélation entre les variations d'altitude et les changements dans les patrons de couleur. Ainsi, le fort isolement écologique, induit par des différences adaptatives locales dans les patrons mimétiques des ailes, joue un rôle important dans l'apparition de la divergence. D'une façon générale, mes résultats soutiennent l'idée selon laquelle la spéciation est un processus cumulatif, où la combinaison de plusieurs barrières d'isolement avec des différences phénotypiques importantes rend possible la divergence des populations malgré le flux génétique.</description><description>The Tropical Andes is one of the most biodiverse regions in the world, yet the origin of this diversity remains poorly understood. One long-standing hypothesis proposes that diversification occurred due to vicariance and allopatry in Pleistocene forest refuges. In contrast, recent studies suggest that the uplift of the Andes, during the Miocene-Pliocene boundary, provided opportunities for both allopatric and ecological speciation. In the present study I tested these hypotheses as well as other process (i.e. center of origin vs center of accumulation hypotheses) that might explain current patterns of neotropical diversity. In particular, I used population genetic tools, ecological data and species-level phylogenetic information to address questions about the underlying causes of diversification in two different groups of neotropical mimetic butterflies: Heliconius cydno and the two Ithomiinae genera Hyalyris and Hypothyris. My results support a complex model of diversification extremely entwined with the final uplift of the Andes. In both cases (Hyalryis-Hypothyris and H. cydno), colonization of the Andes slopes was accompanied by mimicry shifts. Moreover, in the case of Hyalryis there was a strong correlation between altitudinal switches and color pattern shifts. Thus, strong ecological isolation, driven by locally adaptive differences in mimetic wing patterns and habitat use, played an important role in promoting divergence. In general, my results support the idea that speciation is a cumulative process, where the combination of multiple isolation barriers with major phenotypic and ecological difference, facilitates population divergence despite gene flow.</description><creator>Arias Mejia, Carlos</creator><contributor>Eldredge Bermingham (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Daniel J Schoen (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>Patterns of diversification in neotropical butterflies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687m77g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537452c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53x039p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Lactobacillus est un genre diversifié de bactéries d'acide lactiques avec de nombreuses souches qui sont utilisées pour la fermentation des aliments. Compte tenu de leur utilisation historique dans les aliments et la capacité de certaines souches de réduire les nitrates, ces bactéries sont des candidats parfaits pour leur utilisation comme probiotiques. Ici, un lactobacille exprimant  une réductase du  nitrate a été isolé à partir d'une bibliothèque de candidats bactériens et une méthode a été développé pour quantifier son niveau d'activité enzymatique.  Une étude animal a été faite pour déterminer les effets in vivo des bactéries exprimant l'enzyme de réduction du nitrate dans un modèle d'hypertension induit par le L-NAME ( NG- nitro-L-arginine methyl ester).  Les résultats indiquent que la souche sélectionnée ne réduit pas l'hypertension bien qu'elle puisse possiblement réduire le nitrate sanguin en nitrite. En outre, la sécurité alimentaire du Lactobacillus fermentum NCIMB 702342 a été validée. L'identité au niveau de l'espèce a été obtenue par des techniques génétiques et métaboliques et a confirmé que la souche était un Lactobacillus fermentum. Bien que L. fermentum NCIMB 702342 a été démontré résistant à la clindamycine, la souche était sensible à 7 autres antibiotiques. De plus, la formation de métabolites et d'agents antimicrobiens n'a pas été observée.En résumé, L. fermentum NCIMB 702342 a été isolé à partir d'une bibliothèque de souches candidates pour son activité de réduction du nitrate, une méthode d'analyse a été développé pour quantifier l'activité enzymatique, une évaluation  in vivo de sa capacité à réduire l'hypertension a été faite et la sécurité alimentaire préliminaire a été évaluée. Mots-clés: Lactobacillus fermentum, le dépistage des bactéries, réduction du nitrate, validation de la sécurité</description><description>Lactobacillus is a diverse genus of lactic acid bacteria with many strains that have been used for food fermentation. Given their historic use in foods and the ability of some strains to reduce nitrate, these bacteria are perfect candidates as a promising probiotic for treating metabolic disease. Herein, a nitrate reductase active lactobacillus was isolated from a library of candidate bacteria and an assay was developed to quantify its enzymatic activity. Moreover, a study was conducted to assess the strain's nitrate reductase activity in vivo following induced hypertension using NG-nitro-L-arginine methyl ester (L-NAME) in an animal study. The results indicated that the probiotics did not result in attenuation of hypertension; however, the isolated strain, L. fermentum NCIMB 72023, may potentially reduce systemic nitrate to nitrite. Furthermore, safety validation was performed on Lactobacillus fermentum NCIMB 702342. Species-level identity was achieved through metabolic and genetic techniques and confirmed that the strain was a Lactobacillus fermentum. Although L. fermentum NCIMB 702342 was found to be resistant to clindamycin, the strain was susceptible to 7 other antibiotics. Furthermore, formation of metabolic by-products and antimicrobial agents were not observed. In summary, L. fermentum NCIMB 702342 was isolated from a library of candidate strains for its nitrate reductase activity, an assay was developed to quantify it enzymatic rate, an in vivo strain efficacy trial was conducted, and preliminary in vitro safety were assessed. Keywords: Lactobacillus fermentum, bacterial screening, nitrate reductase, safety validation</description><creator>Sulemankhil, Imran</creator><contributor>Satya Prakash (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Biomedical</subject><title>Isolation, «in vivo» characterization, and safety validation of nitrate reductase active «Lactobacillus fermentum» NCIMB 702342 and its implications in addressing metabolic disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mt47b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53x039p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1j92gb854</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les maladies cardiovasculaires sont la première cause de mortalité, particulièrement dans le monde occidental. L'infarctus du myocarde (IM) suivie par l'insuffisance cardiaque congestive représente les majeures causes de cette mortalité. La plupart de ces patients subissent une chirurgie de pontage ou une angioplastie, suivie par la mise en place d'un stent, afin d'améliorer l'oxygénation du sang et sa circulation. Bien que les stents fournissent des bénéfices cliniques excellents, ils sont associés à de nombreux inconvénients tels que, une moindre biocompatibilité, une thrombose, un blocage du stent et une resténose intrastent (ISR). Cette thèse à pour objectifs de: 1) formuler des implants cardiaques supérieurs pour une thérapie myocardique efficace en utilisant des cellules souches mésenchymateuses - dérivées de tissus adipeux xénogéniques génétiquement modifiés - micro-encapsulées et 2) développer de nouveaux stents bioactifs intra-vasculaires en utilisant des stents polymériques dont la surface soit imprégnée de microsphères polymériques contenant un vecteur baculovirus afin d'inhiber l'ISR. En ce qui concerne la thérapie du myocarde, cette thèse a pour objectif de développer des systèmes de délivrance de microcapsules adaptés pour une délivrance de cellules souches efficace. La procédure de préparation, les caractéristiques structurelles et physiques des capsules, y compris la stabilité mécanique, la libération contrôlée, le stockage à long terme, la nature immuno-protectrice ont été étudiés et comparés aux systèmes de microcapsules établis antérieurement. Des études ont été réalisées sur des modèles animaux atteints d'IM aigu pour évaluer le potentiel in vivo. Les résultats ont montré la faisabilité de ce système en tant que nouvel outil thérapeutique pour des applications cardiovasculaires. Ce système permet d'améliorer la rétention de cellules viables au niveau du site de transplantation, de promouvoir la vasculogénèse myocardique, de réduire la surface des cicatrices et d'atténuer la progression de la dysfonction cardiaque. De plus, deux nouveaux nano-complexes pour la délivrance de gènes ont été développés en utilisant des baculovirus recombinants issus de cellules d'invertébrés spécifiques (Bac) hybridés à des nanoparticules (NP) et NPs de dendrimères polycationiques. Ainsi, cette thèse souligne les avantages de l'utilisation de cellules souches micro-encapsulées qui expriment des protéines angiogéniques fonctionnellement actives. Ceci a des implications dans la réparation du myocarde. De plus, la thèse identifie les nano-complexes Bac comme de nouveaux systèmes de délivrance de gènes avec des applications potentielles en thérapie génique directe et thérapie génique combinée aux cellules souches.Afin d'atteindre le second objectif, la thèse vise à améliorer la ré-endothélialisation des stents déployés en inhibant simultanément l'hyperpasie intimale par la surexpression du VEGF dans le système vasculaire en utilisant de nouveaux stents à élution du gène Bac. Pour cela, des Bac revêtus de dendrimères ont été formulés dans des microsphères polymériques dégradables pour éviter l'inactivation du sérum et permettre une libération contrôlée. Ils ont été intégrés couche par couche à la surface de stents hydrogels revêtus de fibrine pour une délivrance locale de gènes au site de déploiement. Les stents préparés ont été caractérisés et optimisés in vitro pour une procédure de délivrance de gènes appropriée. Quatre mois de données in vivo de l'artère fémorale canine dénudée par un ballon ont confirmé l'efficacité préclinique du stent développé. Pour conclure, cette thèse met en évidence l'immense potentiel de ces implants thérapeutiques comme la prochaine génération de dispositifs biomédicaux avec des applications dans les domaines cardiovasculaires et apparentés. D'autres études seront effectuées pour déterminer leur efficacité clinique.</description><description>Cardiovascular diseases are one of the major causes of death, particularly in the Western world. The main cause of this mortality is myocardial infarction (MI) followed by congestive heart failure. Most of these patients undergo bypass surgery or angioplasty followed by stenting to improve blood supply and oxygenation. Although stents are excellent in providing clinical benefits, they have serious disadvantages resulting in limited biocompatibility, thrombosis, and in-stent restenosis (ISR). On the other side, despite the promising early results with stem cell based myocardial therapy, harvesting and delivering autologous cells from elderly patients still poses logistic, economic, and timing constraints resulting in sub-optimal effects. This thesis aims to: 1) formulate superior cardiac implants for effective myocardial therapy using microencapsulated genetically modified xenogeneic adipose tissue derived mesenchymal stem cells and 2) develop a new bioactive intravascular stent using baculovirus vector-containing polymeric microspheres impregnated on a polymeric stent surface to inhibit ISR. First, the thesis aims to develop suitable polymeric microcapsules for efficient myocardial transplantation of adipose stem cells. The preparation procedure, the structural and physical characteristics of the microcapsules were investigated and compared with earlier established microcapsule systems. Studies were performed in animal models with acute MI to evaluate the in vivo potential. Results show the feasibility of this system as a new class of therapeutic tool for cardiovascular applications which can enhance viable cell retention at transplant site, promote myocardial vasculogenesis, reduce scar area and attenuate progression of cardiac dysfunction. To further enhance the therapeutic efficacy, stem cells were genetically modified before microencapsulation with two newly developed nanohybrid gene delivery systems using angiogenic gene carrying insect cell-specific recombinant baculoviruses (Bac) and nanoparticles (NP). Taken together, the thesis highlights the advantages of using microencapsulated genetically modified stem cells and identifies Bac nanocomplexes as novel gene delivery systems with potential applications in direct gene therapy and combined stem cell-gene therapy.To achieve the second objective, the thesis attempts to enhance re-endothelialization of deployed stents while simultaneously inhibiting intimal hyperplasia by overexpression of VEGF angiogenic genes in the vasculature using novel baculovirus based stent. The prepared stents were characterized and optimized in vitro for favorable gene delivery procedure. Four months in vivo data from balloon denuded canine femoral artery confirmed the pre-clinical efficacy of the developed stent. Overall, this thesis highlights the immense potential of these therapeutic implants as the next generation of biomedical devices with wider applications in cardiovascular and related fields. Further studies will investigate their full potential for clinical trials.</description><creator>Paul, Arghya</creator><contributor>Satya Prakash (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Engineering - Biomedical</subject><title>Novel biotherapeutic devices: studies with stem cells, nanohybrid viral vectors and microcapsules for cardiovascular applications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p26770289.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92gb854</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nz24w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:56:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La végétation exerce des contrôles puissants sur le fonctionnement des écosystèmes. Comprendre les effets des perturbations sur les motifs de revégétalisation à court et long terme est donc un élément crucial dans la compréhension des effets des changements climatiques sur l'Arctique. Les paysages Arctiques qui reposent sur des dépôts massifs de glace souterraine et de pergélisol riche en glace sont essentiellement instables et montrent souvent des signes de subsidence dus au dégel dans le passé et dans le présent. Les glissements rétrogressifs dus au dégel sont des traits caractéristiques du retrait progressif des glaces et ont tendance à entrer dans des cycles d'activités, pouvant amener des changements drastiques au paysage. Les motifs cycliques des perturbations et stabilisations reliées à ces glissements dus au dégel donnent comme résultat un  paysage de toundra inégal où les unités géomorphologiques  reflétant l'étape de stabilisation et le moment de la perturbation sont facilement identifiables. Ce projet mène une enquête sur la revégétalisation naturelle et les motifs de succession suite à des perturbations dues à des glissements rétrogressifs  dus au dégel sur l'Île Herschel au Yukon. Vue le réchauffement prévu dans le future, la présence et superficie des glissements dus au dégel sur l'Île Herschel et du Versant nord du Yukon sont prévus d'augmenter. Les objectifs de recherche de ce projet sont de déterminer les caractéristiques diagnostiques des surfaces perturbées,  de décrire la succession de la végétation suite au glissement dû au dégel, et de créer une base de données référant à la végétation qui pourra servir lors de comparaisons futures. Sept sites ont étés choisis pour ce projet, représentant des zones non-perturbées ainsi que des zones de glissements dus au dégel stabilisés depuis 250 ans, 20 ans, et 10 ans. La présence des espèces, la diversité et la couverture ont été utilisés afin de décrire la communauté végétale. Les données sur le pourcentage de couverture végétale ont étés analysés avec le positionnement multidimensionnel non-métrique (NMDS), le multi-response permutation procedures (MRPP), et la classification ascendante hiérarchique (CAH). Les espèces indicatrices ont été identifiés selon leur classe d'âge, et pour chacune le pH, le contenu de matière organique, la profondeur de la couche active et la teneur en eau pondérale du sol sont présentés. Les résultats indiquent que les communautés végétales et caractéristiques du sol distinctes sont associées à chaque classe d'âge, la différentiation la moins importante ayant lieu à l'intervalle des sites de 10 et 20 ans. L'observation qu'après 250 ans la zone de glissement stabilisée ne supporte plus la même communauté végétale que les zones non-perturbées de la toundra a des implications importantes pour notre compréhension des relations biotiques complexes dans l'Arctique de l'ouest. Ces résultats suggèrent que si le réchauffement climatique futur mène à une augmentation des glissements rétrogressifs dus au dégel, la composition des espèces sera modifiée et certaine espèces végétales pourraient devenir plus rare. </description><description>Since vegetation exerts strong controls on local ecosystem processes, understanding the effects of disturbance on short-term and long-term revegetation patterns is a critical component of understanding the effects of climate change on the Arctic. Arctic landscapes underlain by massive ground ice and ice-rich permafrost are inherently unstable and often display evidence of past and present thaw subsidence. Retrogressive thaw slumps are permafrost thaw features which are progressively backwasting and tend to go through cycles of activity, resulting in dramatic changes to the landscape. The cyclic pattern of disturbance and stabilization related to these thaw slumps results in a patchy tundra landscape where there are easily identifiable geomorphic units reflecting the stage of stabilization and the time since disturbance. This research investigates natural revegetation and patterns of succession following permafrost disturbance by retrogressive thaw slumps on Herschel Island, Yukon. With future warming expected, the presence and areal extent of thaw slumps on Herschel Island and the Yukon North Slope are predicted to increase. The research objectives of this work include determining the diagnostic features of disturbed surfaces, describing the vegetation succession following thaw slump disturbance, and creating a baseline vegetation dataset for future comparison. Seven sites were chosen for the study, representing undisturbed areas in addition to 250 year old, 20 year old, and 10 year old stabilized thaw slumps. Species presence, diversity, and cover are used to describe the plant community. Percent cover vegetation data are analyzed using non-metric multidimensional scaling (NMDS), multi-response permutation procedures (MRPP), and hierarchical clustering analysis (HCA). Indicator species are identified for each age class, and the pH, organic matter content, active layer depth, and gravimetric water content of each age class' soil are presented. Results indicate that distinct vegetation communities and soil characteristics are associated with each age class, with the least differentiation occurring between the 10 and 20 year old sites. The observation that after 250 years the stabilized slump area does not support the same vegetation community as the undisturbed tundra has important implications for the complex biotic relationships of the Western Arctic. These findings suggest that if future climate warming leads to an increase in the number of retrogressive thaw slumps, the species composition of the area will be altered and certain plant species may become scarcer.</description><creator>Cray, Heather</creator><contributor>Wayne H Pollard (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Physical Geography </subject><title>A characterization of vegetation patterns related to retrogressive thaw slumps on Herschel Island, Yukon Territory, Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fq479.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nz24w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):16025</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>