<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:11:11Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):5400" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p278d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:43:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La dégradation des sols est un problème mondial qui menace la productivité et la résilience des agroécosystèmes. Des technologies respectueuses de l'environnement doivent être développées pour améliorer la qualité des sols et pour promouvoir une agriculture durable. L'utilisation du biochar, un produit riche en carbone et produit à partir de résidus forestiers, a été proposée pour atteindre les objectifs d'amélioration des sols et d'atténuation des changements climatiques. L'objectif de cette étude était de déterminer les effets de l’utilisation de deux types de biochars et de deux taux d’application sur la productivité de la pomme de terre et sur les indicateurs physico-chimiques de la qualité du sol. L’hypothèse principale était que l'application du biochar affecterait positivement la structure du sol, les propriétés hydriques du sol et la fertilité des sols. De plus, une deuxième hypothèse prédisait que ces changements de la qualité du sol entraineraient des rendements supérieurs pour la production de pommes de terre. Une expérience en champ a été établie en octobre 2015. Cinq traitements ont été organisés dans un modèle de blocs latins avec cinq répétitions. Les traitements étaient un contrôle non traité, et des combinaisons factorielles de deux types de biochar (Airex et Maple Leaf) et deux taux d'application (10 et 20 t ha-1). Des échantillons de sol et de tissus végétaux ont été prélevés et analysés au cours de l’été 2016, et les rendements de pommes de terre ont été mesurés au moment de la récolte. Les deux biochars ont amélioré la stabilité des agrégats du sol et réduit la densité apparente du sol. Le biochar n'a par contre pas affecté de manière significative les propriétés hydriques du sol. Le biochar a augmenté le pH du sol, tout en augmentant la teneur en matière organique, et les concentrations de potassium et de phosphore du sol. Aucune différence significative n’a été observée en ce qui a trait aux rendements des pommes de terre. Les résultats de cette expérience suggèrent que les biochar non spécialisé produit à base de bois affectent la qualité du sol d’une manière similaire à d’autres amendements organiques (augmentation du pH, réduction de la densité apparente, augmentation de la stabilité des agrégats et augmentation de la concentration de certains nutriments dans le sol). Ils suggèrent également que le biochar n’augmentera pas nécessairement le rendement dans un système de culture de pommes de terre bien géré.</description><description>Soil degradation is a global issue that threatens the productivity and resilience of agroecosystems. Environmentally-sensitive technologies must be developed to improve soil quality for sustainable crop production. The use of biochar, a carbon-rich alternative end product for forestry residues, has been proposed to counteract soil degradation, improve soil quality and help the agricultural sector to mitigate climate change. The objective of this study was to determine the effects of biochar type and biochar application rate on potato crop response and on physico-chemical indicators of soil quality in a potato cropping system. It was hypothesized that biochar application would positively affect soil structure, soil moisture regimes and soil fertility. Further, it was hypothesized that these changes in soil quality would lead to higher potato yields. A fully phased rotational field experiment was established in October 2015. Five treatments were arranged in a Latinized block design with five replicates. The treatments were an untreated control and a factorial combination of two biochar products (Airex and Maple Leaf), amended at two application rates (10 and 20 t ha-1). Soil and plant tissue samples were analyzed during the growing season, and potato yields were measured. Eight months after they were applied, both biochar products improved soil aggregate stability and lowered soil bulk density, but biochar did not significantly affect the soil moisture regimes. Biochar raised soil pH, while increasing soil organic matter, soil potassium, and soil phosphorus contents. No difference was found between potato yields in the control plots and the biochar-amended plots. Results from this experiment suggest that wood-based biochars that are not manufactured to address specific soil quality issues will affect soil quality in a manner similar to other organic amendments (increase the pH, lower bulk density, increase aggregate stability, and improve the concentration of some soil nutrients). They also suggest that biochar will not necessarily increase yield in a well-managed potato cropping system.</description><creator>Delisle, Jonathan</creator><contributor>Asim Biswas (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Joann Karen Whalen (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Effect of biochar on soil quality and potato productivity in New Brunswick, Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w706w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p278d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806247r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:43:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Asthma is a heterogenous disease characterized by chronic inflammation and airway remodeling. The severity of airway remodeling is associated with a more severe form of asthma. There is increasing interest in the epithelial to mesenchymal transition process and mechanisms involved in the differentiation and repair of the airway epithelium, especially as they apply to severe asthma. Growing evidence suggests that EMT could contribute to airway remodeling and fibrosis in asthma. Severe asthmatic patients with remodeled airways have a neutrophil driven inflammation. Neutrophils are an important source of TGF-β1, which plays a role in recruitment and activation of inflammatory cells, ECM production and fibrosis development, and is a potent inducer of EMT. As there is little data examining the contribution of neutrophils and/or their mediators to the induction of EMT in airway epithelial cells, the objective of this study was to better understand the potential role of neutrophils in severe asthma in regards to EMT. We used an in vitro system to investigate the neutrophil-epithelial cell interaction. We obtained peripheral blood neutrophils from severe asthmatic patients and control subjects, and examined for their ability to induce EMT in primary airway epithelial cells. Our data indicate that neutrophils from severe asthmatic patients induce changes in morphology and EMT marker expression consistent with the EMT process when co-cultured with bronchial epithelial cells. TGF-β1 levels in the culture medium were also increased compared to co-cultures of non-asthmatic neutrophils and epithelial cells. As an inducer of EMT and an important source of TGF-β1, neutrophils may play a significant role in the development of airway remodeling and fibrosis in severe asthmatic airways.</description><description>L'asthme est une maladie hétérogène caractérisée par une inflammation chronique et un remodelage des voies aériennes. La gravité du remodelage des voies aériennes est associée à un type d'asthme plus sévère. Les patients atteints d'asthme sévère ont une morbidité élevée et représentent des coûts disproportionnés de soins de santé. Il y'a de plus en plus d'intérêt pour le processus EMT et les mécanismes impliqués dans la différenciation et la réparation de l'épithélium des voies aériennes, en particulier dans le contexte d'asthme sévère. De nombreuses études suggèrent que l'EMT peut contribuer au remodelage des voies aériennes, participant ainsi au développement de l'asthme et de la fibrose. Certains groupes de patients asthmatiques sévères à voies aériennes remodelée ont une inflammation menée par des neutrophiles sans éosinophilie. Les neutrophiles sont une source importante de TGF-β1, qui est un inducteur puissant de l'EMT, et joue un rôle de recrutement et d'activation des cellules inflammatoires, de la production d'ECM et du développement de la fibrose. A jour, il n'y a pas d'études analysant spécifiquement la contribution des neutrophiles et de ses médiateurs à l'induction de l'EMT dans les cellules épithéliales des voies aériennes. L'objectif de cette étude était de mieux comprendre le rôle des neutrophiles dans l'asthme sévère dans le cadre de l'EMT. Nous avons développé un système in vitro nous permettant d'étudier l'interaction neutrophile-cellule épithéliale en examinant les neutrophiles asthmatiques sévères de sang périphérique pour leur capacité à induire EMT dans les cellules épithéliales primaires des bronches. Nos données indiquent que les neutrophiles asthmatiques sévères induisent des changements dans la morphologie et l'expression de marqueurs EMT cohérent avec le processus EMT lorsqu'ils sont co-cultivés avec des cellules épithéliales. Les quantités de TGF-β1 dans le milieu de culture ont aussi été augmentées par rapport aux co-cultures de neutrophiles non asthmatiques et de cellules épithéliales. En tant qu'inducteur de l'EMT et une source importante de TGF-β1, les neutrophiles peuvent avoir des implications importantes pour le développement du remodelage des voies respiratoires et de la fibrose dans les voies respiratoires asthmatiques sévères.</description><creator>Haddad, Alexandre</creator><contributor>Mara S Ludwig (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Qutayba Hamid Al Heialy (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Neutrophils: potential role in EMT in severe asthma</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bk71c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806247r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87pt067</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:43:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dialogue systems enable humans to interact with computers in constrained domains using only natural language. However, such systems are typically specialized for a few tasks and do not scale to diverse domains. One approach to address this problem is to use deep neural networks to model human-human dialogue. The availability of large datasets of human-human conversation has allowed these models to produce reasonable responses across a wide array of domains.Despite these successes, neural dialogue models remain difficult to evaluate due to the large potential diversity of responses. When evaluating dialogue systems, it is useful to make a distinction between goal-oriented dialogue systems and non-goal-oriented dialogue systems. Goal-oriented dialogue systems are focused around performing some well-defined task and the quality of a system relates to how well this task is performed. On the other hand, non-goal-oriented dialogue systems are not focused around a single task and their evaluation can remain independent from any notion of task completion.In non-goal-oriented dialogue, metrics that compare system responses to a single reference response from a corpus have been adopted. This thesis identifies the limitations of these metrics and shows they do not correlate with human evaluations. Building upon this analysis, a model is proposed to automatically evaluate dialogue responses that is shown to have significant correlation with human scores.When working in goal-driven domains, task completion is a common metric used for evaluation. However, in large domains, it is infeasible to define every possible goal or their measures of success. In this thesis, a method is proposed to predict task completion without requiring any domain-specific knowledge.Through these contributions, this thesis facilitates long-term development, deployment, and validation of dialogue systems in diverse domains.</description><description>Les systèmes de dialogue permettent aux humains d'interagir avec les ordinateurs dans des domaines contraints en utilisant seulement le langage naturel. Cependant, ces systèmes sont généralement spécialisés pour quelques tâches et ne s'adaptent pas à divers domaines. Une approche pour résoudre ce problème est d'utiliser des réseaux de neurones profonds pour modéliser des dialogues humains. La disponibilité de grands ensembles de données de conversations humaines a permis à ces modèles de produire des réponses raisonnables à travers un large éventail de domaines. Malgré ces succès, les modèles de dialogues en réseaux de neurones restent difficiles à évaluer en raison de la grande diversité de réponses possibles. Lors de l'évaluation des systèmes de dialogues, il est important de différencier entre les dialogues orientés vers un objectif et les dialogues non orientés vers un objectif. Les systèmes de dialogues orientés vers un objectif doivent exécuter une tâche bien définie et la qualité du système est liée à la performance atteinte sur cette tâche. D'autre part, les systèmes de dialogue non orientés vers un objectif ne se concentrent pas sur une seule tâche et leur évaluation peut rester indépendante de toute notion d'achèvement de tâche. Dans les dialogues non orientés vers un objectif, des mesures qui comparent les réponses du système à une seule réponse de référence venant d'un corpus ont été adoptées. Cette thèse identifie les limitations de ces mesures et montre qu'elles ne sont pas en corrélation avec les évaluations humaines. En s'appuyant sur cette analyse, un modèle est proposé pour évaluer automatiquement les réponses de dialogue, et se révèle avoir une corrélation significative avec les scores humains. Dans des domaines orientés vers un objectif, l'achèvement des tâches est une mesure commune utilisée pour l'évaluation. Cependant, dans des domaines plus larges, il est impossible de définir tous les objectifs possibles et leurs mesures de succès. Dans cette thèse, une méthode est proposée pour prédire l'achèvement des tâches sans nécessiter de connaissances spécifiques par rapport au domaine. Grâce à ces contributions, cette thèse facilite le développement, le déploiement et la validation à long terme des systèmes de dialogue dans divers domaines.</description><creator>Noseworthy, Michael</creator><contributor>Joelle Pineau (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Evaluation of neural dialogue models in large domains</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zt04t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pt067</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289m47x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:43:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mutations in the MEN1 tumor suppressor gene cause the Multiple Endocrine Neoplasia type 1 disorder. Menin, the MEN1 gene product, is expressed in many tissues, including osteoblasts, where its normal function remains poorly understood. Here, we examined the role of menin at early stages of the osteoblast lineage through conditional knockout of the Men1 gene in mice using the Cre-LoxP recombination system: Prx1-Cre; Men1f/f, Osx-Cre; Men1f/f and OC-Cre; Men1f/f represent the deletion of menin in the mesenchymal stem cell, osteoblast progenitor, and mature osteoblast, respectively. Skeletal phenotyping performed at 6 months demonstrated significantly reduced BMD and femur length in the Prx1-Cre; Men1f/f and Osx-Cre; Men1f/f strains. By 3- dimensional micro-CT imaging, all three strains of knockout mice showed decreased trabecular bone volume, altered trabecular structure, and decreased cortical bone thickness. Femur stiffness and ultimate force were reduced in Prx1-Cre; Men1f/f mice assessed by 3-point bending test. Primary calvarial osteoblasts of all strains of knockout mice were deficient in mineralization as assessed by Alizarin red staining, and had altered gene expression profiles. Osteoblasts from heterozygous (Osx-Cre; Men1+/f) mice were intermediate in this respect. Serum biochemistries were unaffected. By contrast, whereas OC-Cre; Men1f/f mice exhibited reduced numbers of osteoblasts, increased osteocyte density and decreased osteoclast number, Prx1-Cre; Men1f/f and Osx-Cre; Men1f/f mice had marked increases in osteoclast number and unaltered number of osteoblasts. This is consistent with in vitro and in vivo findings of increased RANKL/OPG mRNA ratios supporting increased osteoclastogenesis signaled by the osteoblasts/osteocytes in these earlier menin knockout models. We conclude that osteoblast menin plays a crucial role in bone development and maintenance of bone mass in vivo, and may serve as a potential gain-of-function therapeutic target for low bone mass disorders such as osteoporosis. Haploinsufficiency of osteoblast menin may contribute to the more severe bone phenotype of the hyperparathyroidism of MEN1 patients relative to that of sporadic primary hyperparathyroidism.</description><description>Les mutations dans le gène suppresseur de tumeur MEN1 provoquent le trouble de type 1 de néoplasie endocrinienne multiple. Menin, le produit du gène MEN1, est exprimé dans de nombreux tissus, y compris les ostéoblastes, où sa fonction normale reste mal comprise. Ici, nous avons examiné le rôle de la menine aux premiers stades de la lignée des ostéoblastes par knock- out conditionnel du gène Men1 chez la souris en utilisant le système de recombinaison Cre-LoxP: Prx1-Cre; Men1f/f, Osx-Cre; Men1f/f et OC- Cre; Men1f/f représentent la suppression de la menine dans la cellule souche mésenchymateuse, le progéniteur ostéoblastique et les ostéoblastes matures, respectivement. Le phénotypage squelettique effectué à 6 mois a démontré une réduction significative de la BMD et de la longueur du fémur dans les souches Prx1-Cre, Men1f/f et Osx- Cre, Men1f/f. Par imagerie micro-CT tridimensionnelle, les trois souches de souris knock-out ont montré une diminution du volume osseux trabéculaire, une structure trabéculaire altérée et une diminution de l'épaisseur osseuse corticale. La rigidité du fémur et la force ultime ont été réduites chez les souris Prx1-Cre; Men1f/f, évaluées par un test de flexion à 3 points. Les ostéoblastes calvaires primaires de toutes les souches de souris knock-out étaient déficients en minéralisation, évalués par la coloration d'Alizarine Red et avaient des profils d'expression génique altérés. Les ostéoblastes provenant de souris hétérozygotes (Osx-Cre; Men1+/f) étaient intermédiaires à cet égard. Les profils biochimique seriques étaient inaltérés. En revanche, alors que les souris OC- Cre; Men1f/f présentaient un nombre réduit d'ostéoblastes, une densité accrue d'ostéocytes et une diminution du nombre d'ostéoclastes, les souris Prx1-Cre; Men1f/f et Osx-Cre; Men1f/f ont enregistré une augmentation marquée du nombre d'ostéoclastes et d'un nombre inchangé d'ostéoblastes. Ceci est cohérent avec les résultats in vitro et in vivo des rapports accrus d’mRNA RANKL / OPG qui favorisent une ostéoclastogénèse accrue signalée par les ostéoblastes / ostéocytes dans ces modèles précédents de menine knock-out. Nous concluons que la menine ostéoblastique joue un rôle crucial dans le développement de l'os et le maintien de la masse osseuse in vivo et peut servir de cible thérapeutique potentielle de « gain of fonction » pour l'ostéoporose. La Haploinsufficience de la menine ostéoblastique peut contribuer au phénotype osseux plus sévère de l'hyperparathyroïdie des patients MEN1 par rapport à l'hyperparathyroïdie primaire sporadique.</description><creator>Abi-Rafeh, Jad</creator><contributor>Geoffrey N Hendy (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Studies on the role of menin in bone development and maintenance «in-vivo»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wj49f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289m47x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644v028</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:43:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Focal adhesions are protein complexes that anchor cells to the extracellular matrix. In order to migrate, the growth and disassembly of these structures must be regulated spatially and temporally across the cell. For example, to process forward, there is a formation of new adhesions at the leading edge of the cell and a disassembly of mature adhesions at the rear. To maintain controlled cell movement, adhesion dynamics are tightly regulated by signalling proteins and structural cytoskeletal components. One protein of interest is paxillin, an adaptor protein within the adhesion, whose phosphorylation at serine residue 273 is crucial for maintaining fast adhesion assembly and disassembly. Paxillin is known to bind a GIT1-βPIX-PAK1 complex, which increases the local activation of the small GTPase Rac. Our goal is to understand the behaviour of this system and how it relates to adhesion assembly/disassembly processes using quantitative methods. We developed mathematical models of the dynamics of the small GTPases Rac and Rho as determined by paxillin phosphorylation at serine 273. Using total internal reflection fluorescence microscopy, we captured time-lapse images of fluorescently labelled paxillin localized to adhesions at the bottom membrane of the cell. From the experimental data, we aim to classify adhesions based on their assembly and disassembly rates and to characterize their sizes and kinetics. Markov models of adhesion classes will be developed to explore how these classes evolve over time and how paxillin phosphorylation regulates adhesion assembly and disassembly. This will give insights into how key signalling components downstream of paxillin phosphorylation aid in generating cell motility. </description><description>Les adhésions focales sont des complexes de protéines qui ancrent les cellules au matrice extracellulaire. Leurs croissance et démontage doivent être régulés spatialement et temporellement à travers une cellule afin de la permettre de migrer. Par exemple, de nouvelles adhésions doivent être formées sur le côté menant de la cellule pour qu’elle avance, pendant que les adhésions matures se désassemblent au côté arrière.Les dynamiques des adhésions sont fermement contrôlées par des protéines de signalisation et des éléments du cytosquelette afin de règlementer le mouvement cellulaire. Paxillin est une protéine pertinente qui fonctionne en tant qu’adaptatrice dans les adhésions. La phosphorylation de la sérine 273 de Paxillin est nécessaire pour maintenir une bonne vitesse d’assemblage et démontage des adhésions. Paxillin peut aussi se lier au complexe GIT1-βPIX-PAK1, qui augmentent à son tour l’activation locale des petite GTPase Rac. Le but de cette étude est d’utiliser des méthodes quantitatives afin de comprendre le comportement de ce système et comment il est associé à l’assemblée\démontage des adhésions. Nous avons développé un modèle mathématique du dynamisme des petite GTPase Rac et Rho dépendant sur l’état de phosphorylation de la sérine 273 de Paxillin. À l'aide de la microscopie de fluorescence par réflexion totale interne, nous avons pris des images accélérées de Paxillin marqué par fluorescence situé dans la membrane inférieure de la cellule. À partir des résultats expérimentaux, nous visons à classifier les adhésions dépendamment de leur vitesse d’assemblée\démontage, tout-en caractérisant leurs tailles et cinétiques. Des modèles Markov des catégories d’adhésions seront développés afin d’explorer comment ces différentes catégories évolues au fil du temps et comment la phosphorylation de Paxillin contrôle l’assemblée et le démontage des adhésions. Cela donnera un aperçu de la façon dont les principaux composants de signalisation en aval de la phosphorylation de du Paxillin contribuent à générer la motilité cellulaire.</description><creator>Tang, Kaixi</creator><contributor>Anmar Khadra (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Claire Brown (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Mathematical model of paxillin phsphorylation at serine 273 and its effect on Rac, Rho, and adhesion dynamics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j67316464.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644v028</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gq69n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:43:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this dissertation, I argue that Dostoevsky’s notion of the underground, which originates in his novella Notes from Underground, informs the literary representations of various undergrounds – the political, the literary, and the rock underground –  in the twentieth and twenty-first centuries. The primary texts studied are Dostoevsky’s writings of 1864-1880, Leonid Andreyev’s short stories, the poetry and essays of Viktor Krivulin, Vladimir Makanin’s novel Underground, or A Hero of Our Time  (1994), and the texts of Siberian punk rock (Egor Letov, Konstantin Riabinov).  My theoretical framework includes Mikhail Bakhtin’s analysis of discourse in Dostoyevsky; the key concepts of philosophy of existentialism (absurd, angst, metaphysical rebellion); the analysis of holy foolishness and buffoonery in cultural studies (Sergei Ivanov, Tatiana Goricheva, Mikhail Bakhtin); the psychological and sociological theory of ressentiment; and the approaches to space in literary semiotics and phenomenology (Yuri Lotman; Gaston Bachelard).  The examination of the underground in various discourses from Dostoevsky to punk rock reveals uniform patterns, which allows me to formulate a general definition of the underground as a discursive model. The underground is 1. a philosophical attitude that questions the existing human condition and suggests rebellion against an imperfect universe; 2. a psychological pattern based on ressentiment that manifests itself as, or transforms into, provocation, aggression, buffoonery, and anguish; and 3. a literalized metaphor: the symbolic subterranean space imbued with the mythological connotations of the underworld and associated with both chaos/death/decay and resurrection/salvation/revelation. The persistence of this three-fold model of the underground throughout various discourses developed by the opposition to the mainstream suggests its applicability for further studies of this phenomenon. </description><description>Dans cette thèse, nous soutenons que la conception du « souterrain » de Dostoïevski, qui tire son origine du roman Notes d’un souterrain, met en lumière les représentations littéraires de divers undergrounds – l’underground politique, l’underground littéraire et l’underground du rock – au XXe et XXIe siècles. Les principaux textes étudiés sont ceux de Dostoïevski, écrits entre 1864 et 1880, les nouvelles de Leonid Andreïev, les poèmes et les essais de Viktor Krivulin, le roman Underground ou un héros de notre temps (1998) de Vladimir Makanine, ainsi que les textes issus du punk sibérien (Egor Letov, Constantin Ryabinov). Notre approche méthodologique est basée sur l’analyse du discours de Dostoïevski qu’a menée Mikhail Bakhtine,  sur les concepts clés de la philosophie de l’existentialisme (l’absurde, l’angoisse, la rébellion métaphysique), sur la vision de la bouffonnerie et des iourodivy dans les études culturelles (Sergei Ivanov, Tatiana Goricheva, Mikhail Bakhtine), sur la théorie psychologique et sociologique du ressentiment, ainsi que sur les études de l’espace dans la sémiotique littéraire et la phénoménologie (Youri Lotman, Gaston Bachelard). L’examen de l’underground dans divers discours – de Dostoïevski au punk rock – révèle des modèles uniformes, ce qui nous permet de formuler une définition générale de l’underground comme modèle discursif. L’underground est 1. une attitude philosophique qui remet en question la condition humaine existante et suggère une rébellion contre l’univers imparfait; 2. un modèle psychologique fondé sur un ressentiment qui se manifeste, voire se transforme, en provocation, agression, bouffonnerie et angoisse; et 3. une métaphore littéralisée – l’espace souterrain symbolique imprégné des connotations mythologiques du monde souterrain et associé à la fois au chaos/mort/décadence et à la résurrection/relèvement/révélation. La persistance de ce modèle triple de l’underground à travers divers discours sur l’opposition au courant dominant suggère son applicabilité pour d’autres études de ce phénomène.</description><creator>Ivantsov, Vladimir</creator><contributor>Lyudmila Parts (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>The concepts of the underground in Russian literary and (counter) cultural discourse: from Dostoevsky to Punk Rock</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d245g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gq69n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Languages, Literatures, and Cultures</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z709028w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:43:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the 18th century, drama slowly broke away from its courtly tradition and found an increasing echo in Paris and other regions of France. With the broadening of its audience came a growing interest in drama itself. The unprecedented production of writings about the world of theatre, such as the memoirs written by its community, which are often overlooked by literary critics, can serve as evidence of this phenomenon. At least two motives can be isolated from the meta-discourse (discourse about discourse) found in these memoirs: (1) to defend the reputation of drama as a practice, which at the time was still met with harsh criticism, and (2) perpetuate the legacy of the characters otherwise condemned to oblivion by the fleeting nature of dramatic performances (Chapter I). Although the memorialists of this corpus are not concerned with history, as it was the case in the 16th and 17th centuries, they ought to acquire a certain social capital. In their texts, the memorialists chosen for this study refer to their modest background and the social emancipation enabled by their profession (Chapter II). Shifting away from the teaching of rhetoric, the theorization of drama contributed to its appreciation by the public. In the light of a dramatic literature eager to remain as authentic as possible, by expecting actors to pour their own feelings into the characters, these biographies appear to be the ideal ground to explore the practice of theater as it incorporates both personal and theoretical considerations (Chapter III). The abundance of memoirs related to the performing arts world emphasizes the importance of the corpus in the media landscape of the time and justifies the relevance of this study. The main focus of this analysis will be on five actors (Clairon, Dazincourt, Dumesnil, Lekain and Préville), two influential playwrights (Goldoni and Marmontel) and one theatre director (Monnet).</description><description>Le théâtre du XVIIIe siècle s’affranchit lentement d’une pratique de cour, trouvant une place toujours plus grande à Paris et en province. Dès lors, le public s’accroît tout comme son intérêt pour le fait théâtral. Témoignage éloquent de cette « théâtromanie », les écrits portant sur le monde de la scène connaissent un essor inédit auquel participent les Mémoires des hommes et des femmes de théâtre, corpus à peu près ignoré par la critique littéraire. Les commentaires métadiscursifs (les discours qui traitent du discours) des Mémoires permettent d’éclairer au moins deux intentions communes à tous leurs auteurs : celle de défendre la réputation du théâtre, encore chargée d’opprobre au XVIIIe siècle, et celle d’asseoir la mémoire de ces personnages promis à l’oubli en raison de l’éphémérité attachée au théâtre (Chapitre I). S’ils n’entrent plus en dialogue avec l’Histoire comme c’était le cas aux XVIe et XVIIe siècles, les mémorialistes du corpus doivent en revanche disposer d’un certain capital social. Tous les Mémoires des praticiens du théâtre font montre de leur ascendance modeste et d’une émancipation sociale que la scène leur a permise (Chapitre II). La valorisation de l’interprétation théâtrale se déploie aussi à partir de sa théorisation, qui se détache de l’actio rhétorique. À l’aune d’un théâtre qui cherche un maximum d’effet de vérité, notamment en demandant aux acteurs de réinvestir leurs propres sentiments dans ceux de leurs personnages, il semble que les Mémoires soient un lieu d’exploration privilégié afin de penser la pratique du théâtre, puisqu’ils mêlent les considérations personnelles et théoriques (Chapitre III). Les Mémoires des hommes et des femmes de théâtre sont pour le moins nombreux, ce qui signale l’importance du corpus dans le paysage médiatique de l’époque, de même que la pertinence de cette étude. Cette dernière se penche essentiellement sur cinq acteurs (Clairon, Dazincourt, Dumesnil, Lekain et Préville), deux dramaturges influents (Goldoni et Marmontel) et un directeur de théâtre (Monnet).</description><creator>Blais, Michaël</creator><contributor>Frederic Charbonneau (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>De la mise en scène de soi : les mémoires des hommes et des femmes de théâtre au XVIIIe siècle</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z0764.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z709028w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rk64d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:43:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ce travail étudie la transmission d'une onde de détonation CJ au travers une surface qui délimite deux régions de densités différentes. Associé à la détonation qui est transmise, il y a une onde de choc ou d'expansion qui est réfléchie, ainsi qu'une surface de contact qui sépare les deux gaz. Le problème est abordé initialement de manière analytique. On constate que, si la détonation passe vers un milieu à densité moins élevée, une forte détonation est transmise et une onde d'expansion est réfléchie. Si au contraire, la détonation passe vers un milieu à densité plus élevé, une détonation CJ avec une onde d’expansion derrière elle sont transmise, et une onde de choc est réfléchie. Le problème est ensuite abordé en effectuant des simulations numériques qui prennent en compte de l'epaisseur de la zone de réaction de la détonation. Elles incluent un processus transitoire qui se produit suite à l'intéraction de la détonation avec la surface qui délimite les deux régions de densités. Après ce processus de relaxation transitoire, les ondes s'approchent asymptotiquement de leur état final dans le nouveau milieu. Les états finaux obtenus ont été comparés à la solution analytique. Ils se sont avérés en accord qualitativement et quantitativement. </description><description>The present study investigates the transmission of a CJ detonation wave across a density interface. Associated with the transmitted detonation there is a reflected shock or expansion wave and a contact surface that separates the gases on each side of the contact surface initially. The problem is first studied theoretically. It is found that if there is a density decrease there is a transmitted strong detonation wave and a reflected expansion wave. If there is a density increase there is a transmitted CJ detonation wave with an expansion wave behind it and a reflected shock wave. Numerical simulations are then performed using two chemical kinetic models. They contain a transient process that occurs subsequent to the interaction due to a finite reaction zone thickness. After the transient relaxation process, the waves asymptotically approach their final state in the new medium. These final states are compared to the theoretical solution and are found to agree well qualitatively and quantitatively.</description><creator>Tang Yuk, Kelsey</creator><contributor>John H S Lee (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Transmission of a detonation across a density interface</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544br94w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rk64d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085n75z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:43:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Studies of microbial sulfate reduction (MSR) have examined the correlation between cell-specific sulfate reduction rate (csSRR) and S isotope fractionation. Despite being subject to environmental, strain-specific and metabolic differences, csSRR is negatively correlated with δ34S and is considered a major influence on depletion of 34S during MSR. In this study csSRR was varied via nutrient limitation by forcing Desulfovibrio vulgaris Hildenborough to fix N¬2 as the sole N source, and also by translation limitation via a sub-lethal dose of an antibiotic (chloramphenicol) that interferes directly with ribosome function. Our nutrient limitation experiments showed not only a decrease in growth rate and csSRR but also a significant increase in the magnitude of S isotope fractionation with ε34S values averaging -7.40 ‰ measured for the N limited experiments vs. -5.52 ‰ for the control experiments representing a 35% increase in fractionation. However, while translation inhibition was successful at reducing growth rate from 4.28 to 1.10 day-1 and csSRR from 44.4 to 18.8 fmol*cell-1*day-1, it had no impact on S isotope fractionation which maintained an average ε34S value of -5.10‰. Differences in relative rates of csSRR may reflect differences in the ratio of ribosomal to sulfate reduction proteins, and are theorized to be responsible for the marked difference in fractionation responses of the translation and nutrient limited experiments. These proposed explanations are rationalized in a conceptual model for fractionation during dissimilatory sulfate reduction, and are supported by new measurements of 15N during nitrogen fixation by D. vulgaris Hildenborough. </description><description>Les études sur la réduction de sulfate par microbes (RSM) ont examiné la corrélation entre la vitesse de réduction de sulfate (VRS) et le fractionnement des isotopes de S. Malgré les effets environnementaux, métaboliques et les effets spécifiques à l’espèce, la VRS est corrélé négativement avec δ34S et est considéré comme l’influence majeur sur ce dernier durant la RSM. Notre étude limite les variations en température, alimentation de carbone, alimentation d’énergie et en effets spécifiques à l’espèce durant la RSM avec D. vulgaris Hildenborough afin de limiter l’influence sur le fractionnement d’isotopes de S sur la VRS. La VRS a été varié par limitation de nutriments en forçant DvH de fixer N2 comme seule source de N, et par limitation de translation par une dose non-mortel de chloramphénicol, un antibiotique qui interfère directement avec le fonctionnement des ribosomes. Nos résultats démontrent que la limitation de nutriments a résulté en une réduction de vitesse de croissance et une croissance signifiant de magnitude de fractionnement. Des valeurs de ε34S à un moyen de -7.40‰ ont été détecté pour les exemples limités de nutriments versus -5.52‰ pour leurs contrôles. Cela représente une croissance en fractionnement de 35%. Pourtant, l’inhibition de translation a réduit la vitesse de croissance de 4.28 à 1.10 jour-1 et le taux de réduction de souffre par cellule de 44.4 à 18.8 fmol*cellule-1*jour-1 mais n’a pas eu d’effet signifiant sur le fractionnement qui a maintient une ε34S  moyenne de -5.10‰. Les différences en motifs de fractionnement versus VRS sont interprétées d’avoir être produit par des différences en distribution de ressources cellulaires. En particulier, les différences relatives de VRS et de la proportion de protéines dédiés aux ribosomes versus dédiés à la réduction de sulfate sont théorisé d’être responsable pour la différence marquée en fractionnement entre les échantillons limités en nutriments et en translation. Nos explications proposées sont aussi supportées par un modèle, déjà publié, de fractionnement durant la RSM. En tout, ces résultats représentent des indices important pour la séparation de la VRS et le fractionnement des isotopes de S durant la RSM et peuvent pointer à des nouvelles directions pour l’exploration des contrôles sur le fractionnement des isotopes de S. En addition, nous avons aussi mesuré les valeurs de δ15N durant la fixation d’azote par D vulgaris Hildenborough. Ces résultats n’étaient pas seulement utiles pour l’interprétation de nos résultats pour les échantillons limité de nutriments, mais représentent aussi les premières valeurs publiées pour le fractionnement de N pendant la fixation d’azote par un organisme anaérobique.</description><creator>Lin, Ying Ran</creator><contributor>Peter Douglas (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Boswell Wing (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Testing the role of sulfate reduction rates in controlling S isotope fractionation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jt741.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085n75z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m039k7618</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:43:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'insécurité alimentaire (IA) est un problème social et de santé important. Malgré les signes d'effets néfastes sur la santé de l’IA chez les personnes vivant avec le VIH, on sait peu de choses au sujet des conséquences de l’IA liées à l’infection par le VIH sur la santé des personnes co-infectées par le VIH-hépatite C (VHC). La population co-infectée par le VIH-VHC présente des caractéristiques uniques, dont des taux élevés de consommation de drogues injectables (UDI) ainsi qu’une morbidité et une mortalité plus élevées liées aux problèmes hépatiques.  L'objectif général de ce travail est d'évaluer l'association entre l’IA, la charge virale du VIH et la numération de cellules CD4 chez les personnes co-infectées par le VIH-VHC, de déterminer si la présence de symptômes dépressifs exerce un effet médiateur sur ces résultats, et de quantifier l’effet direct contrôlé (controlled direct effect) de l’IA ne passant pas par les symptômes dépressifs. Premièrement, des revues systématiques de la littérature ont été menées sur l'association entre l’IA, la charge virale du VIH et la numération de cellules CD4 chez les personnes vivant avec le VIH. Les résultats de la méta-analyse indiquent que les personnes accablées par l’IA étaient en effet plus susceptibles d'avoir une charge virale du VIH détectable au contrôle et une numération de cellules CD4 plus faible par rapport aux personnes qui n'étaient pas en insécurité alimentaire. Deuxièmement, l'association entre l’IA, la charge virale du VIH et la numération de cellules CD4 chez les personnes co-infectées par le VIH-VHC a été évaluée en utilisant les données de la sous-étude « Sécurité alimentaire et VIH-HCV» de la Cohorte Canadienne de Co-infection (CCC). Un modèle structurel marginal pondéré selon la probabilité inverse a été utilisé pour tenir compte des facteurs potentiels de confusion variant dans le temps (time-varying confounders). Les résultats ont démontré que l’IA était fréquente chez cette population et était associée à la fois à une charge virale détectable et à une numération inférieure des cellules CD4. Troisièmement, nous avons estimé si la présence de symptômes dépressifs avait un effet médiateur sur la charge virale du VIH et la numération de cellules CD4. Les résultats ont démontré que la présence de symptômes dépressifs module (mediate) seulement l’effet entre l’IA et la charge virale du VIH. Enfin, une analyse de médiation stochastique a été menée pour quantifier l’effet direct contrôlé exercé par l’IA sur la charge virale du VIH et sur le taux de CD4 en utilisant les symptômes dépressifs comme médiateur. Dans un but de comparaison, l’analyse de l’effet direct contrôlé de l’IA sur la charge virale du VIH et sur le taux de CD4 a aussi été réalisée en utilisant l’adhérence au TARc comme médiateur. Les résultats ont démontré qu’une intervention sur ces médiateurs peut atténuer l'effet néfaste de l’IA sur la charge virale du VIH et sur le taux de CD4. Cependant, l’effet ne peut être éliminé complètement par l’intervention, même en considérant une intervention hypothétique dont l’efficacité est de 100%. Grâce à ce travail, nous avons identifié l’IA comme étant un facteur de risque important d’une charge virale du VIH détectable au contrôle et d’une numération plus faible de CD4 chez les personnes co-infectées par le VIH-VHC. Traiter les causes de l’IA peut aider à améliorer à la fois les états de santé reliés au VIH et au VHC. En outre, les analyses de médiation ont montré d'autres cibles potentielles d’intervention clinique afin de réduire les effets nocifs de l’IA sur la charge virale du VIH et sur la numération des cellules CD4.</description><description>Food insecurity (FI) is a significant social and health problem. Among the general population, FI is known to be associated with poor self-rated health, hypertension and depression. Among people living with HIV, FI may also have HIV-related consequences, such as poor adherence to combined antiretroviral treatment (cART), poor viral control, and poor immune recovery. Despite the evidence of adverse health impacts of FI among HIV infected people, little is known about the HIV-related health outcomes of FI among HIV-hepatitis C virus (HCV) co-infected people. The HIV-HCV co-infected people have some unique characteristics, including higher rates of injection drug use (IDU) and liver related morbidity and mortality. Therefore, findings from HIV mono-infected people may not be generalizable to HIV-HCV co-infected persons. The overall goal of this work is to assess the association between FI and both HIV viral load and CD4 count among people co-infected with HIV-HCV; to determine if the presence of depressive symptoms mediates the effect of FI on these outcomes; and to quantify the controlled direct effect of FI that does not pass through depressive symptoms.First, systematic literature reviews were conducted on the associations between FI and both HIV viral load and CD4 count among people living with HIV to fully understand the impact of FI among this vulnerable population subgroup. Meta-analyzed results indicated that HIV-positive people experiencing FI were more likely to have a detectable HIV viral load and a lower CD4 count compared to people who were food secure.Second, the association between FI, and both HIV viral load and CD4 count among HIV-HCV co-infected people was assessed using data from the Food Security &amp; HIV-HCV Sub-Study of the Canadian Co-Infection Cohort. An Inverse probability weighted marginal structural model was fitted to account for potential time-varying confounders. The results demonstrated that FI was associated with both detectable HIV viral load and lower CD4 count among co-infected people.Third, we evaluated if the presence of depressive symptoms mediates the effect of FI on HIV viral load and CD4 count through two sub-steps: (1) assessing the association between FI and depressive symptoms, (2) assessing the associations between depressive symptoms, and both HIV viral load and CD4 count. In both analyses, marginal structural models were fitted to account for time-varying confounders. Findings demonstrated that the presence of depressive symptoms mediates the effect of FI on HIV viral load.  Lastly, a stochastic mediation analysis was conducted to assess the mediating role of depressive symptoms in the association between FI, and both HIV viral load and CD4 count. For comparison purposes, the mediating role of cART adherence was also assessed for the same associations. Results showed that both depressive symptoms and cART adherence partially mediate the effect of FI on HIV related health outcomes, indicating the existence of pathways other than depressive symptoms and cART adherence. Therefore, intervention on depressive symptoms and cART adherence was not sufficient to eliminate the harmful effect of FI on HIV viral load and CD4 count.Through this work, we identified an important risk factor for having detectable HIV viral load and lower CD4 count among people co-infected with HIV-HCV. These patients tend to have higher mortality due to high rates of liver related death. Since unsuppressed HIV viral load and low CD4 count represent independent risk factors for liver related morbidities, addressing FI could improve both HIV related and HCV related health outcomes. Lastly, mediation analyses showed that intervention on mediators was not sufficient to block the detrimental effect of FI on HIV related health outcomes. Given the significant amount of direct effect, intervention on FI must be accompanied to improve HIV related treatment outcomes among this population subgroup.</description><creator>Aibibula, Wusiman</creator><contributor>Paul Brassard (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Joseph Cox (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Food insecurity and HIV related health outcomes in HIV-Hepatitis C virus (HCV) co-infected individuals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612r06v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k7618</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hf71q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:43:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Imaging allows the visualization of biological processes at the anatomical, cellular and molecular level inside a living organism. Using a variety of imaging techniques, it is possible to diagnose and monitor disease evolution and response to therapy. Radiation-induced lung injury (RILI) occurs in up to 30% of thoracic radiation therapy (RT) for lung or breast cancer and remains a major limiting factor to dose escalation and more efficient treatments. The underlying molecular mechanisms of RILI development remain an area of active research and limited treatment options are available to mitigate this debilitating side effect. Stem cell therapy and in particular mesenchymal stem cells (MSCs) have shown promise for potential RILI treatment. However, the use of stem cell therapy has been hindered by our lack of understanding regarding their behavior once administered in the body. In this thesis, we proposed, developed and validated a pre-clinical imaging platform to image and quantify the evolution of RILI and study MSCs behavior in a rat model of RILI using in vivo fluorescence endomicroscopy (FE) imaging and computed tomography (CT). We first demonstrated the feasibility of tracking fluorescently labeled-MSCs in the lung with FE imaging in a rat model of RILI.Next, following successful MSCs tracking, we used longitudinal CT imaging to monitor the evolution of RILI and assess MSCs' potential in mitigating it. Finally, since CT imaging is restricted to anatomical macroscopic imaging, we developed a fibrosis targeted fluorescent probe coupled with FE imaging to detect RILI at the molecular level in vivo. In order to relate microscopic FE images to their location in the lung, we used x-ray fluoroscopy guidance to detect the position of the endoscope at the time of imaging and map it back to its corresponding location on the CT image.The imaging tools developed here provide valuable information into disease state and progression as well as the assessment of new therapies such as MSCs-based stem cell therapy for RILI. The applications of those tools can be expanded to other diseases, cell types or biological processes of interest, paving the way to clinical implementation for improved patient care.  </description><description>L'imagerie permet la visualisation de processus biologiques au niveau anatomique, cellulaire et moléculaire à l'intérieur d'un organisme vivant. En utilisant différentes techniques d'imagerie, il est possible de diagnostiquer et suivre l'évolution d'une maladie et la réponse au traitement.Les blessures pulmonaires radio-induites (BPRI) se manifestent jusqu'à 30% des radiothérapies (RT) thoraciques pour le cancer du poumon ou du sein et demeurent une limitation majeure à l'escalade de la dose ou d'autres traitements plus efficaces. Les méchanismes moléculaires sous-jacents du développement des BPRI demeurent un domaine de recherche actif et les options de traitements pour atténuer ces effets secondaires débilitants sont limitées.La thérapie par cellules souches et en particulier, les cellules souches mésenchymateuse (CSMs) se sont démontrée prometteuse pour le traitement potentiel des BPRI. Toutefois, l'utilisation de la thérapie par cellules souches a été entravée par notre manque de compréhension en ce qui concerne leur comportement une fois administé dans le corps.Dans cette thèse, nous avons proposé, développé et validé une plate-forme d'imagerie pré-clinique pour imager et quantifier l'évolution des BPRI et étudier le comportement des CSMs dans un modèle de rat des BPRI in vivo en utilisant l'endomicroscopie à fluorescence (EF) et l'imagerie par tomodensitométrie (TD). Nous avons premièrement démontré la faisabilité du suivi des CSMs marquées par fluorescence dans le poumon avec l'imagerie EF dans un modèle de rat des BPRI. Suite au succès du suivi des CSMs, nous avons utilisé l'imagerie par TD longitudinale pour surveiller l'évolution des BPRI et évaluer le potentiel des CSMs à les atténuer.Enfin, comme l'imagerie par TD est restreinte à l'imagerie macroscopique anatomique, nous avons développé une sonde fluorescent ciblée pour la fibrose couplée à l'imagerie EF pour détecter la FPRI au niveau moléculaire in vivo. Afin d'établir un rapport entre les images EF microscopiques et leurs emplacements dans le poumon, nous avons utilisé le guidage par fluoroscopie à rayons-x pour détecter la position de l'endoscope au moment de l'imagerie et de retracer l'emplacement correspondant sur l'image de TD.Les outils d'imagerie développer ici fournissent des informations de valeurs sur l'état d'une maladie, sa progression ainsi que l'évaluation de nouvelles thérapie comme la thérapie par cellules souches avec CSMs pour traiter les BPRI. Les applications pour ces outils peuvent s'étendre à d'autres maladies, types de cellules ou processus biologiques d'intérêts, ouvrant la voie à une mise en oeuvre clinique pour améliorer les soins aux patients.</description><creator>Perez, Jessica Rika</creator><contributor>Jay Nadeau (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Issam El Naqa (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Molecular imaging of radiation-induced lung injury</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059c982x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hf71q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wj506</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:43:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L’enzyme UDP-glucose:glycoprotéine glucosyltransférase (UGGT) est un contributeur clé pour le repliement des glycoprotéines et pour le bon fonctionnement du système immunitaire. La fonction de UGGT la mieux étudiée est celle de détecteur de protéines mal-repliées dans le réticulum endoplasmique (ER), où cet enzyme ajoute une étiquette de manière sélective aux glycoprotéines dénaturées et en les dirigeant vers des cycles supplémentaires de repliement avec des chaperonnes. Avant cette étude, la structure de UGGT était inconnue et il n’existait pas de mécanisme de sélection pour les protéines mal-repliées par UGGT. En premier, j’ai produit et caractérisé UGGT de différentes espèces, en obtenant des échantillons de protéine active et de pureté adéquate pour mener des analyses structurales. Deuxièmement, j’ai obtenu des modèles de faible résolution de UGGT en utilisant deux différentes techniques: modélisation ab initio à partir de données de réfraction de rayons x à faible angle (SAXS) et par microscopie électronique (EM) à coloration négative. Troisièmement, j’ai défini la position des domaines de UGGT en utilisant des échantillons de UGGT étiquetés avec streptavidine et en faisant une analyse par EM à coloration négative, identifiant le domaine catalytique et le domaine senseur. Quatrièmement, j’ai déterminé une structure à résolution moyenne de UGGT par cryo-EM et j’ai positionné des modèles de homologie des domaines individuels de UGGT dans la structure.  Cinquièmement, en collaboration avec Dr. Naoto Soya, on a déterminé le site d’interaction entre Sep15 et UGGT en utilisant des expériences d’échange d’hydrogène/deutérium couplé à la spectrométrie de masse. En considérant toutes les données acquises, on propose un mécanisme de sélection où le site catalytique de UGGT est localisé dans une profonde cavité hydrophobique, dans laquelle ont accès uniquement les chaînes glycosidiques portées sur ou proches de boucles hydrophobes flexibles de la protéine mal repliée.</description><description>The enzyme UDP-glucose:glycoprotein glucosyltransferase (UGGT) is a key contributor to glycoprotein folding and to proper immune system function. The most characterized function of UGGT is that of a misfolded protein sensor in the endoplasmic reticulum (ER), where it selectively labels unfolded glycoproteins and sends them for chaperone-assisted folding. Prior to my work, the structure of UGGT and the mechanism for selection of misfolded proteins were unknown. First, I produced and characterized UGGT from various species, yielding pure and active protein adequate for structural analysis. Second, I obtained low-resolution models of UGGT through two different techniques: small angle x-ray scattering (SAXS) ab initio modeling and negative-stain electron microscopy (EM). Third, I defined the domain positions within UGGT by making streptavidin-labeled UGGT samples and carrying out negative-stain EM studies, identifying the catalytic and sensor domains. Fourth, I determined a medium-resolution cryo-EM structure of UGGT and fit homology models of UGGT individual domains within the structure. Lastly, in collaboration with Dr. Naoto Soya, we determined the binding site of Sep15 on UGGT using hydrogen/deuterium exchange and mass spectrometry experiments. Taking all the data into consideration, we propose a selection mechanism where the catalytic site of UGGT is located deep in a cavity lined by hydrophobic patches, which can only be reached by the glycan on or near flexible hydrophobic loops of the misfolded protein.</description><creator>Calles Garcia, Daniel Ernesto</creator><contributor>Kalle Burgess Gehring (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Mapping the structure of UDP-glucose: glycoprotein glucosyltransferase</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bf21v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wj506</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d246r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:43:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La puissance des phénomènes de variation aléatoire et sélection naturelle dans les mécanismes d’adaptions d’organismes à leur milieu a maintenant été largement documentée à plusieurs niveaux phénotypiques distincts. Le long cou des girafes, la morphogenèse des vaisseaux sanguins, la compartimentation des cellules, ou même le repliement des protéines thermophiles comptent parmi les exemples les plus fréquents. De telles propriétés phénotypiques peuvent être classées comme des optimisations du support matériel.Dans cette thèse, nous nous intéressons sur les phénomènes d’adaptations `logicielles'. Les réseaux d’interaction moléculaire peuvent être représentés par des graphes dont les nœuds et les arêtes représentent respectivement des gènes et leurs interactions. Indépendamment de l’organisme ou du contexte physiologique, pratiquement tous les réseaux biologiques ont une topologie commune. En effet, une majorité écrasante (80%) des gènes foliaires interagissent avec 1 à 4 gènes au plus, tandis qu’une petite minorité (6%) de gènes centraux interagissent avec 10 ou plus de gènes. À ce jour, on ne sait pas quel mécanisme de sélection naturelle est à l’origine de cette topologie caractérisée par une majorité de feuilles et minorité de `hubs'. Nos travaux montrent que cette topologie résulte d’un mécanisme d’adaptation visant à contourner une difficulté calculatoire.À un certain moment de l’évolution, certains gènes (nœuds) ou interactions (arêtes) peuvent devenir essentiels ou préjudiciables aux capacités de survie de l’organisme.Nous modélisons la pression évolutive et le travail nécessaire pour la surmonter par un problème d’optimisation combinatoire que nous prouvons la complexité calculatoire (i.e. NP-difficile). Toutefois, la topologie majorité de feuilles et minorité de hubs facilite la résolution des instances de ce problème. Nous simulons donc l’évolution de ces réseaux grâce à un algorithme évolutif sélectionnant les réseaux associés aux instances les plus simples à résoudre. Par le biais de cet algorithme, les réseaux synthétiques adoptent rapidement une topologie indiscernable de celle des réseaux biologiques de taille comparable.Pour conclure cette thèse, nous étudions aussi les applications de ces concepts de complexité calculatoire dans des systèmes in-vitro. Tout d’abord, nous introduisons un algorithme moléculaire qui encode et résout une instance du problème de l’existence d’un chemin Hamiltonien NP-complet en utilisant un processus qui imite le fonctionnement de la cellule : le code source est codé dans les brins d’ADN, qui sont ensuite transcrits (compilés et exécutés) en les brins d’ARN, et les résultats sont imprimés sous forme de protéines dont la séquence d’acides aminés code un chemin Hamiltonien. Ensuite, nous présentons un algorithme moléculaire transformant l’auto-assemblage de l’ADN synthétique en une tâche de programmation. Par analogie à une `fonction’ dans les langages de programmation modernes pour lequel l’algorithme est écrit une fois, mais qui en fonction des données à l’entrée produit des résultats différents après chaque invocation. Notre algorithme est la réaction en chaîne de la polymérase et l’entrée est un ensemble d’amorces qui détermine la structure du réseau d’ADN à la sortie. En fonction de l’ensemble d’amorces, la polymérase fabrique, par exemple, un carré de 100x100 nanomètres avec une entrée d’amorces ou un rectangle de 100x20 nanomètres avec une autre entrée d’amorces. Nous concluons la thèse avec une discussion sur les applications et les extensions futures de ces idées.</description><description>    Evidence for the power of random variation and non-random selection to produce organisms that are well-adapted to their environments has been extensively documented at various phenotypic levels. Classic examples include long necks in giraffes,  optimal width and sturdy material of blood vessels, compartmentalization of sub-cellular components, and stably-folded proteins at extreme temperatures. Such phenotypic properties can be classified as `hardware' adaptations. In this thesis we study whether there are `software' adaptations as well.     Molecular interaction networks are graphs whose nodes and edges represent genes and interactions, respectively. Irrespective of organism or physiological context, virtually all biological networks have a common topology: an overwhelming majority (~80%) of leaf genes interacting with at most 1-3 other genes, and a small elite minority (~6%) of hub genes interacting with at least 10 other genes. It is unknown whether natural selection is behind this majority-leaves minority-hubs topology, and if so, for what purpose. Our results suggest that this topology is an adaptation to circumvent computational intractability.    At some point in evolutionary time, some genes (nodes) or interactions (edges) can become essential or detrimental to the overall fitness of the organism.We model evolutionary pressure, and the effort needed to overcome it, as combinatorial optimization problem which we show to be NP-hard. However, the majority-leaves minority-hubs topology in biological networks renders instances of this problem easy to satisfy. We further simulate network evolution using an evolutionary algorithm whose fitness function measures instance difficulty of this problem and selects for networks that produce the easiest instances. Evolved synthetic networks quickly morph into a topology indistinguishable from biological networks of equal size.    In this thesis we also bring ideas from computational complexity into wet laboratory contexts. First, we introduce a molecular algorithm that encodes and solves an instance of the NP-complete Hamiltonian path problem using a process that mimics the functioning of the cell: the source code is encoded in DNA strands, which are then transcribed (compiled and executed) into RNA strands, and the result is printed as a protein whose amino acid sequence encodes for the correct Hamiltonian path. Second, we present a molecular algorithm that turns the self-assembly of synthetic DNA into a programming task. Analogous to a `function' in modern programming languages whose logic is written once but ---depending on the input--- produces different results in each invocation, the algorithm logic is polymerase chain reactions and the input is a set of primers that determines what the fabricated DNA lattice looks like. Depending on the input set of primers, the polymerase fabricates, say, a 100x100 nano-meter square given one input of primers or 100x20 nanometer rectangle given another. We conclude the thesis with a discussion about the applications and future extensions of these ideas.</description><creator>Atiia, Ali A.</creator><contributor>Jérôme Waldispuhl (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>The computational weight of biological processes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655j98x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d246r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x166h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:44:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Abstract IntroductionL’encéphalopathie ischémique hypoxique est la cause la plus fréquente d’encéphalopathie néonatale, et entraîne une morbidité ainsi qu’une mortalité significative. D’un point de vue éthique et clinique, le pronostic neurologique est fondamental dans les soins apportés aux nouveau-nés atteints d’une encéphalopathie ischémique hypoxique. Toutefois, la prédiction précise des conséquences neurodéveloppementales de l’encéphalopathie ischémique hypoxique est particulièrement difficile, et remplie de défis. Présentement, la recherche dans ce domaine ciblé est limitée. ObjectifsCette thèse vise à présenter une revue de la littérature actuelle sur le pronostic et la pratique du pronostic de l’encéphalopathie ischémique hypoxique néonatale, en se concentrant sur les défis globaux posés par ce groupe vulnérable de nouveau-nés. De plus, cette thèse incorpore une étude qualitative originale qui explore la perspective des physiciens à propos de la pratique du pronostic dans l’encéphalopathie ischémique hypoxique néonatale. L’objectif principal de cette thèse est d’avancer la compréhension actuelle de la pratique du pronostic dans le contexte de l’encéphalopathie ischémique hypoxique néonatale, en espérant ouvrir le dialogue et encourager les modifications dans la pratique clinique pour améliorer les soins aux patients. MéthodeLa section de l’introduction et de la problématique de cette thèse présente une revue de la littérature sur le pronostic, la pratique du pronostic et sur l’encéphalopathie ischémique hypoxique néonatale. L’accent est mis sur des articles précis en vue d’introduire le lecteur à l’importance de ce sujet. La publication de recherche incluse dans cette thèse repose sur une étude qualitative canadienne de néonatologistes et de neurologues pédiatriques, qui met l’accent sur l’exploration de la perspective des médecins sur le pronostic et la pratique du pronostic dans l’encéphalopathie ischémique hypoxique néonatale. Aux fins de cette thèse, seulement les données se rapportant à la pratique du pronostic seront présentées, bien qu’il y avait d’autres thèmes explorés dans la recherche plus globale incluant l’incertitude, la communication et la prise de décisions partagée. RésultatsIl y a deux chapitres présentant les résultats dans cette thèse. Le premier consiste en un manuscrit publié qui rapporte les données se rapportant à la perspective des médecins à l’égard de la pratique du pronostic dans le contexte de l’encéphalopathie ischémique hypoxique néonatale. Le second présente des données non publiées qui explorent les défis de la pratique du pronostic dans le contexte de l’encéphalopathie ischémique hypoxique néonatale. Conclusions (Conclusion)Même si cette thèse recommande des changements pratiques pour l’amélioration des soins cliniques dans l’encéphalopathie ischémique hypoxique néonatale, sa plus grande contribution est de servir de tremplin pour de plus amples recherches. Des recherches ciblées sont requises pour explorer à la fois la perspective parentale et prospectivement, l’impact de différentes approches et de styles cliniques dans la pratique du pronostic de l’encéphalopathie ischémique hypoxique néonatale.</description><description>AbstractBackgroundHypoxic ischemic encephalopathy is the most frequent cause of neonatal encephalopathy, and results in significant morbidity and mortality.  From an ethical and clinical standpoint, neurological prognosis is fundamental in the care of neonates with hypoxic ischemic encephalopathy.  However, accurately predicting neurodevelopmental outcomes for neonatal hypoxic ischemic encephalopathy is particular difficult, and fraught with challenges. At present, focused research in this area is limited.  ObjectivesThis thesis aims to present a review of the current literature on prognosis and the practice of prognostication in neonatal hypoxic ischemic encephalopathy, focusing on the integral challenges posed by this vulnerable group of neonates.   Furthermore, this thesis incorporates an original qualitative study that explores physician perspectives about prognostication in neonatal hypoxic ischemic encephalopathy.  The main objective of this thesis is to advance the current understanding of the practice of prognostication in neonatal hypoxic ischemic encephalopathy, in hopes of opening up dialogue and encouraging modifications in clinical practice to improve patient care.  MethodsThe introduction and background section of this thesis presents a review of the literature on prognosis, prognostication, and neonatal hypoxic ischemic encephalopathy.  Focus is placed on selected articles in an attempt to introduce the reader to the subject mater. The research publication included in this thesis is based on a Canadian qualitative study of neonatologists and pediatric neurologists, which focuses on exploring physician perspectives on prognosis and prognostication in neonatal hypoxic ischemic encephalopathy. For the purpose of this thesis, only data pertaining to the practice of prognostication will be presented, though there were other themes explored in the larger research study including uncertainty, communication, and shared-decision-making. ResultsThere are two chapters presenting the results in this thesis. The first consists of a published manuscript that reports on data regarding physician perspectives on prognostication in neonatal hypoxic ischemic encephalopathy, and the second presents unpublished data exploring the challenges of prognostication in neonatal hypoxic ischemic encephalopathy. ConclusionsAlthough this thesis offers some practical changes for the improvement of clinical care in neonatal HIE, its true contribution is to serve as a launching point for further research. Focused research is needed to explore both the parental perspective and, prospectively, the impact of different clinical approaches and styles to prognostication for neonatal hypoxic ischemic encephalopathy. </description><creator>Rasmussen, Lisa Anne</creator><contributor>Eric Racine (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Prognostication in neonatal hypoxic ischemic encephalopathy; A qualitative research study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t877w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x166h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rw93m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:44:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Contexte : Les indications et les résultats de la chirurgie bariatrique chez les personnes âgées souffrant d'obésité morbide demeurent controversés. Nous visions à évaluer la sécurité et les résultats à moyen et à long terme des procédures bariatriques dans cette population de patients. Lieu : Hôpital universitaire, Canada. Méthodes : Il s'agit d'une étude rétrospective monocentrique d'une base de données prospectivement collectée. Nous avons inclus des patients âgés de ≥ 60 ans qui ont subi une gastrectomie verticale (SG), une dérivation gastrique en anse en-Y (RYGB) ou une dérivation biliopancréatique avec un switch duodénal (BPD/DS) entre janvier 2006 et décembre 2014 et qui avaient ai minimum 2 ans de suivi. Résultats : 104 patients ont subi 115 chirurgies bariatriques (11 patients ont eu deux procédures). Soixante-six patients étaient super-obèses (IMC&gt; 50 kg / m2). Soixante-quatorze pour cent avaient SG, 16% RYGB, et 8% ont subi BPD/DS. L'âge moyen et l'IMC étaient respectivement de 63,3 ± 2,6 ans et de 51,7 ± 8,1 kg / m2. Le temps moyen de suivi était de 42 ± 19 mois. Au départ, 78% souffraient d'hypertension (HTN), 60% de diabète sucré de type 2 (DT2) et 30% d'apnée obstructive du sommeil (AOS). Il n'y avait pas de mortalité de 30 jours. Le taux de complication était de 14% (n = 16): 2 fuites post-RYGB, 1 fuite post-BPD/DS, 1 obstruction post-SG, 1 saignement nécessitant une transfusion, 1 blessure hépatique avec fuite de bile, 2 hernies, 1 infarctus du myocarde, 2 sténoses gastro-jéjunales, 1 infection de la plaie, 1 infection des voies urinaires et 3 exacerbations du reflux gastrique. Le pourcentage moyen de perte de poids excédentaire à 2 ans était de 52,2 ± 23,8. Les taux de rémission de HTN, DT2 et AOS étaient de 26%, 44% et 38%, respectivement.5Conclusion : La chirurgie bariatrique est sûre et efficace pour améliorer les comorbidités liées à l'obésité chez les patients âgés souffrant d'obésité morbide. L'âge seul ne devrait pas empêcher les patients plus âgés d'obtenir la meilleure procédure bariatrique pour l'obésité et ses comorbidités.</description><description>Background: Indications and outcomes of bariatric surgery in older adults suffering from morbid obesity remain controversial. We aimed to evaluate safety and medium to long-term outcomes of bariatric procedures in this patient population.Setting: University Hospital, Canada.Methods: This is a single-center retrospective study of a prospectively-collected database. We included patients aged ≥60years who underwent sleeve gastrectomy (SG), Roux-en-Y gastric bypass (RYGB) or biliopancreatic diversion with duodenal switch (BPD/DS) between January 2006-December 2014 and had at least 2 years of follow-up.Results: 104 patients underwent 115 bariatric surgeries (11 patients had two procedures). Sixty-six patients were super-obese (BMI&gt;50kg/m2). Seventy-four percent had SG, 16% RYGB, and 8% underwent BPD/DS. Mean age and BMI were 63.3±2.6years and 51.7±8.1kg/m2, respectively. Average follow-up time was 42±19months. At baseline, 78% had hypertension (HTN), 60% had type-2 diabetes mellitus (T2D), and 30% had obstructive sleep apnea (OSA). There was no 30-day mortality. Complication rate was 14%(n=16): 2 leaks post-RYGB, 1 leak post-BPD/DS, 1 obstruction post-SG, 1 bleeding requiring transfusion, 1 liver injury with bile leak, 2 port-site hernias, 1 myocardial infarction, 2 gastro-jejunal strictures, 1 wound infection, 1 urinary tract infection, and 3 gastric reflux exacerbations. Mean percent excess weight loss (%EWL) at 2 years was 52.2±23.8. Remission rates of HTN, T2D and OSA were 26%, 44% and 38%, respectively.Conclusion: Bariatric surgery is safe and effective in improving obesity-related comorbidities in older patients suffering from morbid obesity. Age alone should not preclude older patients from getting the best bariatric procedure for obesity and related comorbidities.</description><creator>Elbahrawy, Aly</creator><contributor>Olivier Court (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Medium to long-term outcomes of bariatric surgery in older adults with super obesity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dc350.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rw93m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zw12z771c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:44:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le cerveau humain est un organe incroyablement complexe qui peut être décrit et mesuré de nombreuses façons. Peu importe le moyen choisi, aucun cerveau n’est identique. L’objectif général de cette thèse sera de comprendre les causes de cette variabilité interindividuelle, comment différents aspects du cerveau en sont affectés, comment ces effets peuvent varier spatialement et à travers le temps, et comment ceci pourra ultimement améliorer notre compréhension des processus cognitifs, comportementaux et des maladies neurologiques.Le premier chapitre fournit une introduction plus détaillée de ces concepts et de la structure de cette thèse. Le second chapitre offre d’abord un survol de la neuroanatomie structurelle et fonctionnelle du cerveau, ce qui introduit les traits qui seront utilisées pour mesurer le cerveau dans les chapitres suivants. Ces sections sont suivies d’un court résumé des différences inter-espèces qui sont observées, au niveau macroscopique, entre le cerveau humain et celui des primates. Ceci met l’emphase sur l’importance de l’étude des traits quantitatifs au niveau interindividuel et sur le fait que des variations génétiques sont nécessairement une cause importante de cette variation interindividuelle. La seconde section de ce chapitre offre donc un survol de l’organisation structurelle et fonctionnelle du génome, ainsi que des types de variations génétiques qui peuvent y être trouvées. Vu l’importance des traits quantitatifs, une description détaillées des mécanismes par lesquels la variance des traits quantitatifs peut être héritée est fournie, suivie d’une description des méthodes statistiques qui permettent d’estimer cet effet et des paramètres d’intérêt qui en découlent.Ensuite, the troisième chapitre jette un premier regard sur la génétique quantitative de la structure du cortex cérébral, spécifiquement du point de vue des interactions entre l’âge et les influences génétiques sur l’épaisseur corticale. Le quatrième chapitre s’attarde aux influences génétiques au niveau fonctionnel, spécifiquement du point de vue de la connectivité fonctionnelle au repos. Ceci inclut la cartographie complète de l’héritabilité, de ses interactions avec l’âge et des corrélations génétiques à travers le connectome fonctionnel en entier. Les résultats sont ensuite analysés et interprétés en rapport à l’histoire évolutive des systèmes fonctionnels du cerveau. Finalement, le cinquième chapitre dépasse l’analyse seule des aspects structurels et fonctionnels pour démontrer comment les résultats des chapitres précédents peuvent être utilisés dans l’étude d’autres traits liés aux aptitudes cognitives, au comportement et aux maladies. Le focus est placé sur la génétique de l’intelligence et sur l’identification de régions du cerveau où les mesures corticales sont sous l’influences des mêmes facteurs génétiques.Dans l’ensemble, ces résultats démontrent que la variation génétique est une cause importante de variation interindividuelle dans les mesures structurelles et fonctionnelles du cerveau. Ils démontrent aussi que l’étude détaillée et la juste interprétation de ces influences pourrait nous fournir d’importantes informations sur la génétique des traits cognitifs, comportementaux, des maladies neurodégénératives et peut-être même sur l’évolution du cerveau humain.</description><description>The human brain is an incredibly complex organ that can be described and measured in many different ways. Whichever way we choose, no two brains are exactly the same. The general focus of this thesis will be to understand the causes of this inter-individual variability, how different aspects of the brain are affected, how these effects vary over time and space, and how this can ultimately further our understanding of cognition, behavior and neurological disorders.In Chapter 1, a more detailed introduction to these concepts and to the structure of the thesis is provided. Chapter 2 first provides an overview of the anatomy of the brain from the perspective of structure and function, which introduces the measures that will be used to describe the brain in the following chapters. This is followed by a short account of the inter-species differences found, at the macroscopic level, between human and primate brains. This emphasizes that inter-individual variation in quantitative traits is most relevant and that genetic variation is necessarily an important cause of this inter-individual variability. The second section of Chapter 2 then provides an overview of the structure and function of the human genome along with the types of genetic variation that can be found within. Given the importance of quantitative variation, a complete account of how discrete genetic factors can account for the inheritance of quantitative traits is then provided, followed by a description of the methods used to estimate this effect and the definition of the specific parameters of interest for this thesis.Chapter 3 then takes a first look at the quantitative genetics of brain structure, specifically from the perspective of age-related changes in the genetic influences over cortical thickness. Chapter 4 then looks at the quantitative genetics of brain function from the perspective of resting-state functional connectivity. This includes the complete mapping of heritability, age-related interactions and genetic correlations across the entire functional connectome. The results are then further analyzed and interpreted in view of the evolutionary history of the brain's functional systems. Finally, Chapter 5 moves beyond the analysis of structure and function to show how the results from the previous two chapters could be used to inform other traits related to cognition, behavior and disease. The focus is placed on the genetics of intelligence and the identification specific brain areas where measures of cortical structure are influenced by these same genetic factors.Taken together, these results demonstrate that genetic variation is an important cause of inter-individual variation in measures of brain structure and function in the population. They also show that the detailed investigation and proper interpretation of these influences could offer valuable insight into the genetics of cognition, behavior, and neurological disorders, and perhaps even into the evolution of the human brain.</description><creator>Chouinard-Decorte, Francois</creator><contributor>Pierre Bellec (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Alan C Evans (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Quantitative genetics of human brain structure and function</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zg895.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z771c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97ks891</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:44:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse examine les discours et pratiques d’organisations caritatives musulmanes en Inde. À la suite de seize mois de recherches ethnographiques menées en Uttar Pradesh, j’analyse comment les organisations caritatives musulmanes répondent aux enjeux liés à la marginalisation sociale et économique des Musulmans, une situation qui a récemment été soulevée par différents rapports gouvernementaux, dont le Sachar Committee Report (2006). Mes résultats de recherche mettent en lien les pratiques quotidiennes d’organisations musulmanes sunnites dans des quartiers défavorisés de Lucknow ainsi que leurs interventions humanitaires à Muzaffarnagar, faisant suite à des émeutes contre les musulmans qui ont forcé le déplacement de plus de 50 000 villageois. Ces deux terrains de recherche démontrent comment des formes « ordinaires » de violence structurelle, mais aussi des formes « extraordinaires » de violence ciblée façonnent les discours et pratiques de développement économique que ces organisations mettent de l’avant. Je soutiens que les bénévoles et les travailleurs dans ces organisations caritatives encouragent une forme de développement privatisé et orienté vers le marché comme un nouveau modèle pragmatique de mobilisation sociale et politique. Cependant, leurs approches ne renforcent pas nécessairement les processus d'individualisation ou de réduction des responsabilités de l’État, que les analystes associent généralement aux modèles de développement économique néolibéral. Les efforts des travailleurs et des volontaires musulmans pour « optimiser » la charité musulmane et mobiliser les communautés par le biais de discours sur le développement de soi et l’intégration économique restent fermement ancrés dans une éthique religieuse du don, du devoir familial et du bien-être collectif. Ce nouvel accent mis sur la figure du « pauvre musulman » et le développement personnel oblige néanmoins les musulmans à se « réformer » eux-mêmes et, paradoxalement, peut détourner l'attention portée aux formes de marginalisation persistantes auxquelles les musulmans sont confrontés dans le contexte indien postcolonial. Ma recherche met donc en évidence les variations locales, les complexités et les paradoxes que suscitent les projets de progrès social et économique imaginés par ces organisations. </description><description>This dissertation examines the politics of Islamic charitable action in India. Based on sixteen months of ethnographic research conducted in Uttar Pradesh, it focuses on how Muslim charitable organizations address Muslims’ social and economic marginalization, an issue recently evidenced by national commission reports (Sachar Report 2006). The research findings bring together the everyday practices of Sunni Muslim charitable organizations in the poor urban neighbourhoods of Lucknow as well as the organizations’ humanitarian aid in Muzaffarnagar, following anti-Muslim riots that led to more than 50,000 Muslim villagers’ displacement. These two locations capture ordinary forms of structural violence, but also how extraordinary forms of targeted violence shape Muslim charitable organizations’ discourses and practices of economic development.  I argue that Muslim NGO volunteers and workers promote privatized, market-oriented development as a new, pragmatic form of social and political mobilization. However, their approaches do not necessarily increase the processes of individualization or sidelining of the state—as critics of neoliberal economic development would expect. Instead, Muslim workers and volunteers’ attempts to “optimize” Islamic charity and mobilize communities through discourses of self-responsibility and economic integration remain firmly grounded in religious ethics of giving, familial duty and collective well-being. This new focus on the figure of the “poor Muslim” and self-development nonetheless puts the responsibility on Muslims to “reform” themselves, and paradoxically, might deflect attention from forms of enduring marginalization faced by certain Muslim communities in the postcolonial Indian context. My research thus highlights the local variations, complexities and paradoxes characterizing the projects of social and economic improvement imagined by these organizations. </description><creator>Larouche, Catherine</creator><contributor>Katherine Lemons (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Spiritual and material development the politics of Islamic charitable action in North India</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77ss28t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97ks891</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xp68kj76m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:44:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L’homéostasie et le maintien des tissus adultes dépend d’une régulation dynamique des cellules souches et des progéniteurs qui existent dans ces tissus. L'équilibre entre la prolifération et la différenciation, ainsi que les mécanismes par lesquels ces processus sont contrôlés dans les cellules souches sont encore mal compris. La prostate contient plusieurs populations de cellules souches et les progéniteurs ce qui lui donne un potentiel de régénération et de croissance important. Ces cellules sont également étroitement impliquées dans la formation de tumeurs et peuvent représenter autant les cellules d'origine du cancer et/ou la source de la résistance aux thérapies anti-cancéreuse. Afin d’avoir une meilleure compréhension des cellules souches et des progéniteurs de la prostate, nous avons utilisé une combinaison d’approche in vitro et in vivo i.e. des modèles génétiques de souris, de l’analyse bioinformatique, de la microscopie, ainsi que des essais de culture en 3D et de transplantation des cellules souches. Dans les chapitres 1 et 3, nous avons identifié un rôle essentiel pour le facteur de transcription GATA3 dans les cellules souches basales et progéniteurs à la fois pendant le développement, l'homéostasie chez l’adulte et la progression du cancer de la prostate. GATA3 joue des rôles distincts au cours de ces différentes étapes: la régulation de l'orientation de la division cellulaire pendant l'organogenèse post-natale et la régulation du potentiel d'auto-renouvellement des cellules souches et des progéniteurs de la prostate chez l'adulte. L'analyse transcriptomique et bioinformatique des cellules souches basales de prostates GATA3 knockout et des tumeurs prostatiques humaines a permis d’identifier plusieurs voies de signalisation sous le contrôle de GATA3. Pendant le développement, GATA3 contrôle la localisation cellulaire de la protéine kinase PRKCZ. La perte de GATA3 ou la mauvaise localisation de PRKCZ provoque une orientation aléatoire du fuseau mitotique et des défauts de spécification de lignée, ce qui entraîne une accumulation de progéniteurs intermédiaires dans le tissu. Dans le chapitre 2, nous avons étudié le rôle de l'orientation du fuseau mitotique dans la spécification des lignées cellulaires en examinant la fonction d'INSC, LGN et SAPCD2 pendant le développement. Ces études ont permis d’identifier des mécanismes d'orientation du fuseau mitotique distincts durant le développement et l'homéostasie chez l’adulte, qui nécessitent LGN et SAPCD2, mais pas INSC. Ensemble, ces résultats mettent en évidence la complexité de l'activité des cellules souches et progénitrices au niveau de la prostate. Une meilleure compréhension de la régulation de ces mécanismes homéostatiques dans divers contextes, y compris au niveau du cancer, sera fondamentale pour l’émergence d’une nouvelle génération d’interventions thérapeutiques.</description><description>The homeostasis and maintenance of adult tissues relies on the dynamic regulation of tissue resident stem and progenitor cells. The balance between proliferation and differentiation, and the mechanisms by which these processes are controlled in stem cells is poorly understood. The mammalian prostate contains multiple populations of stem and progenitor cells, and displays extensive growth and regenerative potential. Prostate stem and progenitor cells are also intricately linked to prostate tumourigenesis and may act as cells-of-origin and or sources of therapeutic resistance. To gain insight into prostate specific stem and progenitor cells, we utilized genetic mouse models, in combination with bioinformatic, in vitro and in vivo stem cell techniques, and microscopic imaging. In Chapters 1 and 3, we identified an essential role for the transcription factor GATA3 in basal stem and progenitor cells during prostate development, adult homeostasis, and prostate cancer progression. GATA3 has distinct roles during these stages: regulating the orientation of cell division during post-natal organogenesis, and regulating the self-renewing potential of prostate basal stem and progenitor cells in the adult. Transcriptomic and bioinformatic analysis of adult GATA3-null prostate basal stem cells and prostate tumours identified multiple signalling pathways under the control of GATA3. However, during development, GATA3 controls the localization of the kinase PRKCZ. Loss of GATA3 or mis-localization of PRKCZ during this stage induces spindle randomization and lineage specification defects, leading to intermediate progenitor cell accumulation. In Chapter 2 we followed up on the role of spindle orientation in lineage specification by examining the function of INSC, LGN, and SAPCD2 during this stage. These studies identified distinct spindle orientation mechanisms occurring during development and in adult homeostasis that required LGN and SAPCD2, but not INSC. Together these results highlight the complexity of stem and progenitor cell activity in the mammalian prostate. Understanding how these homeostatic mechanisms are regulated in diverse contexts, including cancer, will be fundamental for the generation of new therapeutic interventions.</description><creator>Shafer, Maxwell</creator><contributor>Maxime Bouchard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Regulation of the prostate progenitor cell fate</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945t37q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kj76m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zd61m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:44:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, I attempt to quantify the effect of density on toad dispersal in a series of steps that coincide with the amphibian’s notable life stages, which are outlined by the five chapters of my thesis. Chapter 2 examines the direct effect of density on tadpole survival, growth and size at metamorphosis using a unique technique of density manipulation. I discuss potential downfalls of the traditional method of tadpole density-manipulations whereby raising them in crowded conditions might confound results as tadpoles are known to respond differently to chemical cues left in the water by conspecifics. My method of manipulating density by volume resulted in a strong negative relationship with tadpole survival, growth and size at metamorphosis, as predicted, while the traditional method showed similar but less striking trends. Chapter 3 addresses whether carry-over effects are present in the new metamorphs (i.e. toadlets) that emerge from a range of density treatments, by monitoring changes in behaviour between the tadpole and toadlet life stages. I discovered a significant change in activity levels in those grown under high densities as tadpoles, where their small post-metamorph body size coincided with a notable decrease in activity. My results support the concept of density-dependent carry-over effects being present in these amphibians, and that their post-metamorphic mobility may be impacted by their early-life growth conditions. Chapter 4 examines the behavioural plasticity of tadpoles under these effects using a controlled factorial experiment. My results showed that larger sized tadpoles had high activity levels under all temperature regimes only when they came from high density treatments. This suggests that the size of the animal is important, as it becomes relevant under more stressful conditions and that the behavioural plasticity of tadpoles is governed by an interaction among individual body size, water temperature and density. Chapter 5 follows the size-dependent movement capabilities of individual toadlets from density-treatments in a controlled performance test, and their subsequent free-ranging movement behaviour in the field. I discovered that the body size of toadlets predicted dispersal in a quadratic relationship, where intermediate sized toads, regardless of their tadpole density, move greater distances and had the highest probability for dispersal. Interestingly, these intermediate-sized toads became the largest in their cohort as adults, resulting in a positive logistic relationship between adult size and dispersal probability.  Chapter 6 uses the information gathered for size-dependent dispersal probabilities, and calculates the populations density-dependent dispersal rates using historical data, to inform model simulations to predict the extinction risk of this Fowler’s toad population. I discovered that this population has a quadratic relationship between dispersal probability and population density, where very low and very high densities coincided with the highest dispersal rates. Additionally, I was able to predict a low extinction risk for the population if carrying capacity was kept at a minimum of 16 toads, however if continuous habitat management, which translates into continuous habitat disturbances, were to be employed on a short 7-year cycle, extinction risk could be as high as 78%.Human activities, including fragmentation and restoration, continue to impact the animals living in the surrounding environment. As dispersal is a key process that can save many populations from local extinctions it is important to understand how movement is restricted on a species-specific level. My thesis provides a detailed examination of density-dependence and movement capabilities across multiple life stages in a pond breeding amphibian and advances our understanding of how density itself can impact dispersal under different mechanisms.</description><description>Dans cette thèse, je tente de quantifier l'effet de la densité sur la dispersion des crapauds dans une série d'étapes qui coïncident avec les stages de vie remarquables des amphibiens. Le chapitre 2 examine l'effet direct de la densité sur la survie, la croissance et la taille des têtards à leur métamorphose en utilisant une technique unique de manipulation des densités. Ici, je discute des problèmes potentiels des méthodes traditionnelles des manipulations de densité des têtards. Ma méthode de manipulation de la densité en utilisant des volumes différents a entraîné une relation négative forte avec la survie, la croissance et la taille du têtard à la métamorphose, comme prévu, alors que la méthode traditionnelle présentait des tendances similaires mais moins frappantes. Le chapitre 3 adresse si les effets de report sont présents dans les nouveaux métamorphes qui émergent d'une gamme des traitements de densité, en surveillant les changements de comportement entre le têtard et les stades de vie des allaches. J'ai découvert un changement important dans les niveaux d'activité des metamorphes cultivés sous les densités élevées des têtards, où leur petite taille de corps post-métamorphisme coïncidait avec une diminution notable d’activité. Mes résultats appuient la notion que les effets de report dépendants de la densité sont présent dans ces amphibiens et que leur mobilité post-métamorphique peut être significativement affectée par des conditions de croissance précoces. Le chapitre 4 examine la plasticité comportementale des têtards sous ces effets en utilisant une expérience factorielle contrôlée. Cependant, mes résultats ont montré que les plus grands têtards avaient des niveaux d'activité élevés dans tous les régimes de température seulement lorsqu'ils provenaient de traitements de haute densité. Cela suggère que la taille de l'animal est importante, car elle devient pertinente dans des conditions plus stressantes. Le chapitre 5 suit les capacités de mouvement dépendantes de la taille des juvéniles individuels des traitements de densité dans un test contrôlé de performance et leur comportement de mouvement détaillé sur le terrain. J'ai découvert que la taille du corps des juvéniles prévoyait leur dispersion selon une relation quadratique, où les juvéniles de taille intermédiaire, quelle qu’étaient la densité des têtards pendant leur croissance, se déplacent sur de plus grandes distances et ont une probabilité plus forte de dispersion. Le chapitre 6 utilise les informations recueillies des probabilités de dispersion dépendantes de la taille et calcule le taux de dispersion dépendant de la densité de la population en utilisant des données historiques, afin de préciser les prédictions des simulations de risque d'extinction des populations des crapauds Fowler. J'ai découvert que cette population avait une relation quadratique entre la probabilité de dispersion et la densité de la population, où des densités très faibles et très élevées coïncidaient avec les taux de dispersion les plus élevés. En outre, j'ai pu prédire un risque d'extinction faible pour la population si la capacité de charge était maintenue à au moins 16 crapauds, mais le risque d'extinction pourrait atteindre 78%. Les activités humaines continuent d'avoir un impact sur les animaux vivant dans les alentours. Vu que la dispersion est un processus important qui peut sauver des nombreuses populations de l’extinction locale, il est important de comprendre comment le mouvement est restreint d’une façon spécifique à l'espèce. Ma thèse fournit un examen détaillé de l’impact de la densité sur les capacités de mouvement d’un amphibien des étangs à travers plusieurs étapes de sa vie et avance notre compréhension de diffèrent mécanismes sous lesquelles la densité elle-même peut avoir un impact sur la dispersion.</description><creator>Yagi, Katharine</creator><contributor>David M Green (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Density-dependence and dispersal mechanisms in a pond breeding amphibian</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33rz99d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zd61m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50gz64w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:44:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A knowledge of sea-ice dynamics is key to achieving proper Arctic climate simulations. The goal of this thesis is to lay the foundation for a three-dimensional ice dynamics model that considers both thermal and dynamic stresses. This thesis presents in-situ observations from buoys deployed in the Canadian Arctic Archipelago (CAA). In the CAA, the sea ice is landfast for approximately six months in winter. In a first step, we have analyzed in-situ data from a sea-ice stress buoy deployed in the Viscount Melville Sound. Results demonstrate that thermal stress is the dominant source of internal stress in the CAA with few short-lived important dynamic stress events caused by ice floe collisions in the free drift season prior to the landfast season. This is in contrast with similar internal sea-ice stress measurements made in the Arctic Ocean, in which both dynamic and thermal stresses are of similar magnitude. Prior to landfast ice onset, the thermal stresses are isotropic, as hypothesized in prior analyses of ice internal stress data measured in the Arctic Ocean. After landfast ice onset, however, the ther- mal stresses become anisotropic. Results from the buoy data, together with results from a 1.5D thermal stress model (forced with simulated internal sea-ice temperatures), demonstrate that the anisotropy in thermal stress arises from land confinement induced by the coastline in the direction of the short-axis of the channel. Results from the model are in good agreement with the observed stress in the direction of both principal stresses. They suggest that anisotropy in thermal stress could impact the mode of failure of sea ice in the CAA. The results also suggest that viscous creep stress relaxation is important and acts on time scale of several days, which is longer than the time scale (several hours) suggested from the previous measurements. In a second step, we derive estimates of the sea-ice compressive strength parameter (P∗) based on a simple force balance and known external forcing (surface air-ice and ice-ocean stresses) and whether sea ice drifts under the action of these external loads or not. Results from a proof of concept experiment using internally consistent data from a fully coupled ice-ocean model (the Regional Ice Operation Prediction System, RIOPS) demonstrate that it is indeed possible to estimate P∗, which is a known quantity in the model, from the simple force balance presented. When the same method is applied to in-situ observations and reanalysis data, the method only produces meaningful bounds of P∗ ( = 94.4 ± 4.4 kN/m2) when the pack ice is mostly composed of first-year ice with little multi-year ice present. This P∗ estimate is approximately three times the value currently used in the modelling community. This highlights the fact that the ice drift measured at a point may not be representative of the ice behaviour on average in a region. For instance, results suggest that larger tidal ocean currents in the region are enough to prevent a landfast ice cover to develop locally while the pack ice is mostly landfast on larger scales. The failures of the method when it is applied to some buoy data also suggest that there may be error in the surface forcing from the CGRF (Cana- dian Meteorological Center’s Global Deterministic Prediction System Reforecast). The analysis of these errors is left for future work. Results discussed in this thesis highlight the importance of thermal stresses in sea-ice models. The only forcing required by a thermal stress model is the internal temperature profile. Therefore, a thermal stress model could be implemented in current sea-ice thermodynamic models with a little effort. It would then be coupled with the dynamical part of the model by developing yield criteria for ice failure that are a function of the total (dynamical and thermal) stresses at a point rather than the depth average internal stress as currently done in the community.</description><description>Cette thèse présente l’analyse d’observations enregistrées par des bouées déployées dans l’Archipel Arctique Canadien (AAC), où la glace de mer consiste en un couvert de glace de rive pendant approximativement six mois par année. En premier lieu, les contraintes internes enregistrées sur place par une bouée déployée dans le détroit du Vicomte de Melville sont analysées. Cette étude démontre que les contraintes thermiques dominent les forces internes de la banquise dans l’AAC, et ce malgré la présence de quelques évènements où de fortes contraintes dynamiques de courte durée ont été enregistrées. Ces résultats diffèrent des observations obtenues par des bouées similaires déployées dans l’océan Arctique, qui indiquent plutôt une équivalence en magnitude entre les contraintes de source thermique et de source dynamique. Pendant la période de dérive, les contraintes thermiques mesurées dans l’AAC présentent une isotropie qui concorde avec les analyses pour l’océan Arctique. Les contraintes thermiques deviennent cependant anisotropes après la transition vers le régime de glace de rive. En combinant ces résultats avec des simulations provenant d’un modèle de glace à 1.5 dimensions, il est démontré que cette anisotropie découle du confinement de la glace de rive par les berges du chenal. Les contraintes simulées par le modèle, dans chacun des axes principaux, concordent bien avec celles observées par les bouées. Les résultats de cette étude suggèrent que le mode de fracture de la glace de rive dans l’AAC peut être affecté par l’anisotropie des contraintes thermiques. De plus, il est observé que la relaxation visqueuse des contraintes due au fluage de la glace ne devient importante que sur une échelle temporelle de l’ordre de plusieurs jours, ce qui est plus long que l’ordre suggéré par les mesures en laboratoire. En second lieu, nous avons obtenu des valeurs approximatives pour le paramètre de résistance à la compression de la glace de mer (P*) à partir de l’équilibre des forces, en se basant sur l’état observé de la dérive de la glace (dérive ou glace de rive) et en utilisant un forçage connu. Afin de démontrer qu’il est possible de déterminer P* à partir du simple équilibre des forces, la méthode proposée est appliquée sur les données d’un modèle de glace entièrement couplé à l’océan (RIOPS), dans lequel P* est une variable connue. En appliquant cette méthode sur les données d’observations et de réanalyses, des limites physiques sont établies pour restreinte la plage de valeur de P* (= 94.4 ± 4.4 kN/m2) lorsque la glace est composée principalement de glace annuelle. Cette plage de valeur correspond approximativement au triple de la valeur couramment utilisée dans la communauté de modélisation. Les résultats cette étude suggèrent que les mesures de dérive à un point précis peuvent ne pas correspondre au comportement moyen de la glace dans une région. Par exemple, il est montré que dans une région principalement recouverte de glace de rive, la présence de courants de marée plus forts peut être suffisante pour prévenir le développement de la glace de rive localement. Dans le cas de certaines bouées, l’échec de la méthode proposée suggère la présence d’erreurs dans les forçage de surface du CGRF, et l’analyse de ces erreurs est laissé comme projet futur. Les résultats discutés dans cette thèse soulignent l’importance des contraintes thermiques pour la modélisation de la glace de mer. Le profil de température interne de la glace étant le seul forçage nécessaire dans un modèle de contraintes thermiques, il serait possible de l’implémenter dans un modèle thermodynamique de glace de mer. Ce modèle thermodynamique pourrait ensuite être couplé à une composante dynamique par le développement de limites de contraintes en fonctions des contraintes totales (dynamiques + thermiques) en un point, plutôt qu’en fonction des contraintes internes moyennées sur l’épaisseur, comme il est couramment utilisé dans la communauté.</description><creator>Hata, Yukie</creator><contributor>Bruno Tremblay (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Sea-ice strength and internal stresses from in-situ measurements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x630b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gz64w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150m47x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:44:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Building on research in musicology, disability studies, Deaf studies, and sound studies, this dissertation analyzes the creative endeavours of contemporary disabled musicians and listeners in relation to three idealized pillars of musical experience: listening, looking, and performing. In Chapter 2, I approach listening through the musical experiences of deaf people, revealing multi-sensory ways of listening beyond hearing while detailing the precarious social, physical, and musical contours of “normal” hearing. Chapter 3 examines performances by musicians with “visible” disabilities to interrogate the presumed visual dynamics of stigma in existing disability theory: I argue that genre, sound, and identity politics shape the spectator’s perception of the performer’s disability. Finally, in Chapter 4, I show how amputee musicians intervene in prevailing conceptions of musical ability through their use of prosthetic technologies, unsettling the customary physical terms of musical expression. Ultimately the dissertation pushes beyond naturalized conceptions of music, handed-down sensory hierarchies, and conventional understandings of musical expertise to offer a plural understanding of music and disability alike.</description><description>S'appuyant sur la recherche en musicologie, en études sur les personnes ayant des incapacités, en études sur la surdité, ainsi qu’en études du son, cette thèse analyse les déploiements créatifs chez les musiciens et les auditeurs contemporains ayant des incapacités en fonction de trois piliers idéalisés de l'expérience musicale: l'écoute, l'observation, et l'exécution. Dans le deuxième chapitre, j'aborde l’écoute musicale à partir de l’expérience des personnes sourdes, révélant ainsi des modes d'écoute multi-sensoriels allant au-delà de l’ouïe, en plus de détailler la précarité des contours sociaux, physiques, et musicaux de l'audition dite « normale ». Le troisième chapitre examine les œuvres de musiciens ayant des incapacités « visibles » afin de remettre en question les hypothèses avancées dans la littérature existante sur la dynamique visuelle de la stigmatisation chez les personnes ayant des incapacités. Je suggère que la perception du spectateur du déficit de l’interprète est façonnée conjointement par le genre, le son, et le champ identitaire. Finalement, dans le quatrième chapitre, je démontre comment les musiciens amputés interviennent dans les conceptions dominantes de la capacité musicale grâce à leur utilisation de technologies prothétiques, perturbant ainsi les conditions physiques habituelles de l'expression musicale. En ce sens, cette thèse propose d’aller au-delà des conceptions naturalisées de la musique, des hiérarchies sensorielles transmises, ainsi que des compréhensions normatives de l'expertise musicale pour offrir une approche plurielle à la musique et à l’incapacité.</description><creator>Holmes, Jessica</creator><contributor>Lloyd Whitesell (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Music, disability, and embodiment in contemporary performance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nn97c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150m47x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pj80f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:44:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nos sens travaillent de paire avec nos fonctions motrices afin de nous permettre d’interagir avec notre environnent. Cette interaction est communément appelée intégration sensorimotrice. La recherche en intégration sensorimotrice investigue les réponses motrices aux stimulis visuels et auditifs. Plus particulièrement, dans les études d’intégration audio-motrice, les participants chez qui le développement est typique (TD) ont tapé suivant des battements de vitesse et de complexité métrique variable afin d’évaluer une forme spécifique d’intégration aussi appelée synchronisation. Chez les patients diagnostiqués de trouble du spectre de l’autisme (TSA), l’intégration sensorimotrice montre des déficits dans les tâches visuo-motrices et audio-motrices. Malgré que de plus en plus de recherche est complétée dans le domaine des TSA en utilisant des tâches visuo-motrices et audio-motrices complexes (tel que l’analyse de la parole), plusieurs lacunes demeurent dans notre compréhension comportementale et cérébrale de l’intégration sensorimotrice de base (tel taper à un certain rythme). La dissertation suivante est composée de trois articles qui visent à investiguer l’intégration sensorimotrice chez les TSA et les individus TD. Une tâche de synchronisation rythmique, pour laquelle les rythmes variaient en complexité métrique avait déjà été testée chez les individus TD afin d’investiguer leur synchronisation audio-motrice (Chen et al., 2008b). Cette tâche a été modifiée pour les articles 1 et 2 afin d’être adaptée aux enfants et utilisée chez les enfants TSA ainsi que TD. Dans l’article 1, la performance de synchronisation rythmique audio-motrice a été examinée chez les enfant TSA et TD avec l’accent mis sur les effets développementaux. Les résultats ont démontré que la performance des enfants TSA était comparable aux enfants TD dans les tâches de synchronisation rythmique et que les deux groupes s’amélioraient avec l’âge. Afin de caractériser la synchronisation audio-motrice plus profondément chez les enfants TSA et TD, l’article 2 a examiné les corrélations structurelles de la synchronisation audio-motrice au niveau cérébral en utilisant la même tâche que dans l’article 1. Les résultats n’ont pas démontré de relation entre les structures cérébrales et la performance dans les tâches de synchronisation audio-motrice pour tous les sujets, ni au niveau individuel, ni au niveau des sous-groupes. L’article 3 a évalué les corrélations cérébrales fonctionnelles de l’intégration audio-motrice dans le contexte de la perception de la parole chez les individus TSA et TD en utilisant la méthodologie méta-analytique « activation likelihood estimation » (ALE). Les résultats d’études antérieurs de neuroimagerie fonctionnelle qui ont investigué la perception de la parole chez les individus TSA et TD ont été compilés et les contrastes ALE ont été utilisés afin de déterminer une convergence d’activation à travers toutes les études. Ces résultats ont démontré des modèles d’activation communs dans chaque groupe dans les régions principales liées à la parole, sans évidence de différences entre les groupes. Par contre, lors d’une comparaison qualitative des modèles d’activation, des résultats divergents sont démontrés. Plus spécifiquement, le groupe TD activait des régions cérébrales associées avec un traitement de la parole plus complexe. Les trouvailles des trois articles permettent d’approfondir les connaissances dans la caractérisation de l’intégration audio-motrice chez les individus TSA et TD. Elles démontrant de nouvelles preuves d’une synchronisation audio-motrice intacte chez les individus TSA, ainsi que des modèles d’activation neurale communs et divergents dans la perception de la parole chez les individus TSA et TD. Cette dissertation encourage de futures études comportementales et cérébro-comportementales et aide à guider les interventions audio-motrices chez les enfants TSA. </description><description>Our senses work in conjunction with our motor functions to be able to properly interact with the environment. This interaction is referred to as sensorimotor integration. Research in sensorimotor integration has investigated motor responses to both visual and auditory cues. Specifically in auditory-motor integration studies, typically-developing (TD) participants have tapped along to beats of varying speed and metrical complexity in order to evaluate a specific form of integration known as synchronization. In autism spectrum disorder (ASD), sensorimotor integration has shown general impairments for both visuomotor and auditory-motor tasks. Although more research has been completed in ASD using visuomotor and complex auditory-motor tasks such as speech processing, less is known about the behavioral and brain correlates of basic auditory-motor integration (i.e. tapping to a beat).This dissertation is comprised of three articles that aim to investigate auditory-motor integration in ASD and TD individuals. A rhythm synchronization task, where rhythms varied in metrical complexity, had been previously tested in TD adults investigating auditory-motor synchronization (Chen et al., 2008b). This task was modified to be child-friendly for the purposes of Article 1 and 2 to be used with ASD and TD children. In Article 1, auditory-motor rhythm synchronization performance was examined in ASD and TD children with a focus on developmental effects. The results showed that children with ASD performed similarly to TD children on the rhythm synchronization task, and that both groups performed better with age. To further characterize auditory-motor synchronization in ASD and TD children, Article 2 examined the brain structural correlates of auditory-motor synchronization using the same task previously described in Article 1. The results did not find a relationship between brain structure and auditory-motor synchronization performance across all subjects. There were also no group differences when correlating brain structure to auditory-motor synchronization performance. Article 3 evaluated brain function correlates of auditory-motor integration in the context of speech perception in ASD and TD individuals using activation likelihood estimation (ALE) meta-analysis methodology. Results from previous functional neuroimaging studies that investigated speech perception in ASD and TD individuals were compiled and ALE contrasts were performed to determine convergence of activation across all studies. The results showed common activation patterns within ASD and TD groups in core speech-related regions. The results also found no group differences. However, qualitatively comparing the within group results showed divergent activation patterns. Specifically, the TD group activated regions associated with more complex speech processing.The findings from these three articles extend the characterization of auditory-motor integration in ASD and TD individuals. These findings produced new evidence of intact basic auditory-motor synchronization in children with ASD as well as common and divergent patterns of neural activation for speech perception in ASD and TD individuals. This dissertation encourages future research in both behavioral and brain-behavioral studies, and gives guidance for auditory-motor interventions in ASD.</description><creator>Tryfon, Ana</creator><contributor>Krista Hyde (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Auditory-motor integration in typical development and autism spectrum disorder: behavioral and brain correlates</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505285m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pj80f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pr76f609q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:44:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The gastrointestinal tract imposes a chemical and physical barrier to the oral delivery of bio-therapeutics such as insulin. As a consequence, bio-therapeutics need to be injected subcutaneously. Swallowable capsules, capable of injecting a drug directly into the intestine wall, would enable painless and convenient oral delivery of these drugs. This thesis focuses on the development of needle deployment and retraction mechanisms to be implemented into Drug Injecting Swallowable Capsules (DISCs). The design space for the mechanisms is defined, and eleven novel designs, inspired by biological systems and macro-scale mechanisms, are proposed. One particular design, inspired by the defense mechanism of the Spanish newt, is further developed, prototyped, and tested. The Spanish newt design consists of two concentric cylinders with needles attached to the inner cylinder. The motion of the inner cylinder, the core, is powered by two preloaded springs. This motion causes the needles to rotate with respect to their hinge point on the core, thus enabling needle deployment and retraction. The force required to achieve deployment and injection is characterized via mechanical tests, and the test results are used to select the springs from commercially-available off-the-shelf models. The final prototype is tested in vitro using a capsule measuring 15.9 mm in diameter and 31.5 mm in length, with a deployed needle length of 1.9 +/- 0.5 mm. The mechanism successfully performs needle deployment, drug injection in 1.3 s, and needle retraction.</description><description>Le système digestif représente une barrière chimique et physique à l'administration orale de bio-thérapeutiques tels que l'insuline. Par conséquent, ces médicaments doivent être injectés par voie sous-cutanée et non orale. Une capsule administrée oralement, capable d'injecter un médicament à travers la paroi intestinale, permettrait une administration commode et indolore de bio-thérapeutiques.Le présent mémoire traite de la conception de mécanismes de déploiement et de rétractation d'aiguilles pour les DISCs (\textit{Drug Injecting Swallowable Capsules}), i.e. les capsules administrées oralement, capables d'injecter un médicament à travers la paroi intestinale. L'espace de conception de ces mécanismes est établi, et douze concepts sont proposés, inspirés par des êtres vivants ou des mécanismes communs existants. Un de ces concepts, inspiré par le mécanisme de défense du triton espagnol, donne lieu au développement, à la fabrication et à l'essai d'un prototype.Le concept du triton espagnol est composé de deux cylindres concentriques, le cylindre interne comprenant quatre courtes aiguilles. Le déplacement du cylindre interne par rapport au cylindre externe est effectué par deux ressorts précontraints. Ce mouvement provoque le basculement des aiguilles, et permet ainsi le déploiement et la rétractation de celles-ci. La force nécessaire pour réaliser le déploiement et l'injection est caractérisée par un essai mécanique. Les résultats de cet essai sont exploités afin de choisir des ressorts disponibles sur étagère. Le prototype final, mesurant 15.9 mm de diamètre et 31.5 mm de long, avec une longueur d'aiguilles déployée de 1.9 +/- 0.5 mm, est testé in vitro. Le prototype de capsule remplit le cahier des charges, et permet de réaliser le déploiement des aiguilles, l'injection du médicament en 1.3 s, et la rétraction des aiguilles.</description><creator>Omerovic Beccalli, Nina</creator><contributor>Srikar Vengallatore (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Needle deployment and retraction mechanism for drug injecting swallowable capsules</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290d03f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f609q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9g54xm17w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:44:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le virus adéno-associé (AAV) est présentement le vecteur viral le plus étudié pour la thérapie génique. Il a le potentiel de traiter, sinon de guérir, des milliers de maladies monogéniques et complexes. Cependant, un des obstacles majeurs limitant son utilization au niveau clinique est le dosage élevé de particules virales requises pour produire un effet thérapeutique. Les meilleures techniques actuelles de production atteignent des rendements acceptables pour les maladies orphelines ou les régimes à faible dose. Cependant, ces rendements seraient inacceptables si la thérapie génique induite par l'AAV devenait une option de traitement utilisable pour de larges populations. L'objectif de cette thèse est d'optimiser le processus de production en établissant une lignée cellulaire stable pour la production d'AAV recombinant (rAAV). L'hypothèse est centrée sur le fait que les AAV de type sauvage génèrent, pendant l'infection, un nombre de virions beaucoup plus élevé par cellule que le rAAV. Il est donc clair que, pour obtenir des rendements plus élevés de rAAV, il faut essayer d'imiter le processus d'infection naturel le mieux possible. Un domaine où cela est réalisable, en lien avec les lignées cellulaires stables, est l'emplacement génomique de l’intégration des transgènes et des fonctions auxiliaires. Il s'avère que l'AAV a développé son propre emplacement optimal pour l'intégration génomique appelé AAVS1, qui a été ciblé comme région pour une intégration spécifique dans ce site. Cela a été accompli grâce à l'utilisation de CRISPR-Cas9. En utilisant le système CRISPR pour effectuer une coupe précise dans la région AAVS1 et ensuite fournir les séquences d'insertion requises, une tentative a été faite pour intégrer le génome du vecteur rAAV dans cette région. Trois clones cellulaires ont été isolés et identifiés comme étant capables de produire du rAAV. Ils ont produit des titres allant de 8,9x108 -1,7x109 VG/mL et 7,74x107-1,24x108 IVP/mL. Ceci a été comparé avec la triple transfection contrôlée, qui a produit des titres de 3,2x109 VG/mL et 1,05x108 IVP/mL. Alors qu’il n’était pas confirmé que l’intégration se soit produite dans la région AAVS1, ces lignées de cellules stables générées se sont révélées être une méthode viable et rentable pour la production de rAAV à grande échelle.</description><description>Adeno-Associated Virus (AAV) is currently the most researched viral vector for use in gene therapy. It has the potential to treat, if not cure, thousands of monogenic and even complex disorders. However, a current major obstacle limiting its translation to the clinic is the high dosage of viral particles required to achieve a therapeutic effect. The current best production techniques attain yields acceptable for orphan diseases or low dose regimens. However, these yields are unacceptable if AAV-mediated gene therapy is to become a viable treatment option for the general public. The goal of this thesis is to optimize the production process by establishing a stable cell-line for recombinant AAV (rAAV) production. The hypothesis is centered on the fact that wild-type AAV generates significantly higher virions per cell upon infection than does rAAV. It is, therefore, clear that in order to achieve higher yields of rAAV, one must try to imitate the natural infection process as best as possible. One area where this is possible in relation to stable cell-lines is the genomic location of transgene and helper-function integration. It so happens that AAV has evolved its own optimal location for genomic integration termed AAVS1, which was used as the region for site-specific integration. This was accomplished through the use of CRISPR-Cas9. By using the CRISPR system to make a precise cut in the AAVS1 region and then supplying the desired insertion sequences, an attempt was made to integrate the rAAV vector genome into that region. Three cell clones were isolated and identified as being capable of producing rAAV. They produced titers ranging from 8.9x108 -1.7x109 VG/mL and 7.74x107-1.24x108 IVP/mL. This was contrasted to the triple transfection control, which produced titers of 3.2x109 VG/mL and 1.05x108 IVP/mL. While it was not confirmed that the integration occurred in AAVS1, stable cell-lines were nonetheless shown to be a viable and cost-effective method or producing rAAV on a large-scale. </description><creator>Kligman, Ryan</creator><contributor>Amine Kamen (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Renald Gilbert (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Establishing a stable cell-line for producing Adeno- Associated Virus using CRISPR-Cas9</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xf154.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xm17w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Bioengineering and Biomedical Engineering Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149s15v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:44:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Healthy aging is known to affect the structure and function of the hippocampus In order to stimulate this region in healthy older adults, we developed an automated computerized spatial memory intervention program called NeuroNautilus because spatial memory is a function critical to the hippocampus. NeuroNautilus is designed to promote the use of spatial strategies, taking particular attention to avoid the use of stimulus-response strategies that are dependent on the caudate nucleus, a region of the brain which competes against the hippocampus. In this study, we aimed to characterize the effects of the NeuroNautilus training program on the functional topology of the default-mode network (DMN), the first intrinsic functional network to show degradations during aging. We also investigated the resting differences in the topology of the DMN between individuals who employ hippocampus-based spatial strategies and individuals who employ caudate nucleus based stimulus-response strategies. Healthy older adults were assigned to take part in the NeuroNautilus training or an active placebo control condition. Consistent with our hypotheses, we found that the NeuroNautilus training program significantly increased within network connectivity in the precuneus, a structure involved in higher order executive processes highly vulnerable to aging. Furthermore, we found that the placebo control group showed greater increase in connectivity within the dorsal medial prefrontal cortex, a finding consistent with other aging literature. No significant differences were found in the topology of the DMN between spatial and stimulus-response strategy users, although trends highlight the importance of larger samples in such studies. These results highlight the potential for spatial memory training in restoring activity to the brain’s intrinsic functional networks.</description><description>Au cours de la sénescence, de multiples changements structurels et fonctionnels surviennent à travers le cerveau. Certains réseaux d’activité fonctionnelle intrinsèque tels que le réseau dit « de mode par défaut » (RMD) sont particulièrement affectés. Afin de stimuler le RMD chez des personnes âgées en santé, nous avons développé un programme d’entraînement de la mémoire spatiale nommé NeuroNautilus. En effet, la mémoire spatiale est une fonction clé de l’hippocampe, une structure centrale du RMD. NeuroNautilus a été conçu pour promouvoir l’utilisation de stratégies spatiales, cherchant particulièrement à éviter l’utilisation de stratégies stimulus-réponse, qui dépendent des noyaux caudés une structure qui fait compétition à l’hippocampe. La présente étude cherchait à caractériser les effets de NeuroNautilus sur la topologie fonctionnelle du RMD. Nous avons aussi cherché à identifier les différences de topologie fonctionnelle dans le RMD d’utilisateurs de stratégies spatiales et stimulus-réponse, au repos. Des personnes âgées en bon état de santé furent recrutées puis assignées soit au groupe d’entraînement NeuroNautilus, soit au groupe de contrôle placebo. Conformément à notre hypothèse, les participants qui ont complété NeuroNautilus ont démontré une augmentation moyenne significative de l'amplitude du signal dans le précunéus, une zone centrale du sous-système postérieur du RMD. De plus, nous avons observé une plus grande augmentation de l’amplitude du signal dans le cortex préfrontal chez le groupe placebo que dans le groupe d’entraînement, un effet déjà observé dans d’autres études d’imagerie fonctionnelle sur le vieillissement. Aucune différence significative de topologie fonctionnelle du RMD n’a été observée entre les utilisateurs de stratégies spatiales et les utilisateurs de stratégies stimulus, malgré la présence de plusieurs effets approchant le seuil. Ces résultats démontrent l’importance de grands échantillons pour de telles analyses. Finalement, les résultats présentés ci-dessous soulignent le potentiel de l’entraînement de la mémoire spatiale pour restaurer l’activité dans les réseaux intrinsèques du cerveau.</description><creator>Ducharme, Daniel</creator><contributor>Veronique Bohbot (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>UMIC code is not required - UMIC code is not required</subject><title>Virtual spatial memory improvement program: impact on resting state functional connectivity in the default-mode network</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv9355378.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149s15v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):5425</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>