<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T04:02:04Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):44150" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311p847</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new, general method for the asymmetric synthesis of quaternary  carbons is described. This technique involves stereocontrolled generation of  alpha,alpha-disubstituted amide enolates via reduction of bicyclic  alpha,alpha-disubstituted alpha-thioglycolate lactams using one-electron transfer  reagents. A model of the geometric constraints necessary to reductively prepare  alpha,alpha-disubstituted amide enolates with control of enolate E/Z stereochemistry  is described and several chiral auxiliaries were prepared to test this  design. Successful preparation, trapping, isolation and characterization  of alpha,alpha-disubstituted amide enolates is described. This reductive enolization  method allows, for the first time, the stereoselective preparation of both E- and  Z-acyclic alpha,alpha-disubstituted amide enolates. Reactivity and selectivity of alpha,alpha-disubstituted amide  enolates in alkylation with alkyl halides is explored. Dichotomous reactivity is  observed for both E- and Z-alpha,alpha-disubstituted amide enolates.  Z-alpha,alpha-Disubstituted amide enolates are shown to alkylate with high levels of  stereoselectivity; E-alpha,alpha-disubstituted amide enolates alkylate with poor  stereoselectivity. Methods for isolation of the quaternary carbon-containing  adducts are described. Conditions for the determination of the enantiomeric excess  of chiral, non-racemic neopentyl alcohols were developed and are also  described. Development of a facile, environmentally friendly, modular  synthesis of a model second-generation chiral auxiliary using simple, inexpensive  starting materials is described.</description><creator>Manthorpe, Jeffrey Michael</creator><contributor>Gleason, James L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>A general method for the asymmetric synthesis of quaternary carbons : reductive formation and alkylation of [alpha],[alpha]-disubstituted enolates</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343s72z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311p847</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150j734</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study of resilient children has overturned many deficit  focused models about the ontogenesis of children raised in adversity. Resilience  research has flourished over the last three decades, and emphasis on the development  of resilience skills are increasingly being incorporated into prevention programs.  This study explores whether youth identified as resilient are as likely as those  identified as vulnerable to engage in excessive gambling behaviour, and to examine  the impact of several risk and protective factors on gambling severity among  adolescents. The sample consisted of 1,273 students aged 12-19. The results suggest  that vulnerable youth, low in resilience, are more likely to meet diagnostic  criteria for problem gambling. There were no significant differences between  resilient and low risk-exposure groups suggesting that the individual protective  factors examined in this study may prevent maladaptive outcomes. These findings were  interpreted with respect to their implications for resilience and prevention  research.</description><creator>Lussier, Isabelle D.</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Teenage gamblers.</subject><subject>Gamblers.</subject><subject>Resilience (Personality trait)</subject><title>Youth gambling behaviours : an examination of the role of resilience</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k780w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150j734</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mv70r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigated whether English second language learners  learn the senses of polysemous vocabulary items in an order from a core sense to  more extended senses. Polysemous words have one form but many interrelated meanings.  It was hypothesised that such an order could be explained by way of the theory of  prototypicality. 48 ESL learners from three language groups, French, Japanese and  Chinese, took part in the study. The participants translated into their first  language 29 English sentences using different senses of the word over. Translations  were coded for correct translations of the sense of over and for variation in the  correct translations. A MANOVA analysis showed that core senses were translated  significantly more correctly than extended senses. A negative correlation was shown  between variation in translation and correctness of translation. Following  Krzeszowski, T. (1990), the study confirms that the theory of prototypicality offers  an effective way of explaining language transfer.</description><creator>Maby, Mark</creator><date>2005</date><subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Foreign speakers</subject><subject>Polysemy</subject><subject>Language acquisition</subject><title>How non-native speakers learn polysemous words : a study of the equivalence of prototypicality across languages</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zn92z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mv70r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Second Language Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930bx70h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, I examine how, during the twentieth century, the  Lacandons, an ethnic subgroup of the Mayas came to be considered the " purest  " of the indigenous groups living in Chiapas, the southeasternmost state of  Mexico. As the development of ethnic tourism continues to intensify, a conception of  culture that emphasizes timeless traditions and continuity with the past is  concurrently increasing. I intend to demonstrate that this essentialization of the  lacandon culture imposes constraints within which individuals must operate. However,  while the ways in which they define and represent themselves for tourists,  anthropologists, and other visiting foreigners reveals the pervasiveness of this  essentialization, it is also argued that through these encounters, the Lacandons  negotiate a space in which they articulate their subjectivities as they meet  visitors' expectations.</description><creator>Lévesque, Manon</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Tourism -- Mexico -- Chiapas.</subject><subject>Lacandon Indians -- Mexico -- Chiapas.</subject><title>Entre privilège et marginalisation : politiques de la culture et développement du tourisme ethnique chez les Mayas Lacandóns de Nahá, Chiapas, Mexique</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79407x83t.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930bx70h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f1881m409</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les cellules dendritiques plasmacytoïdes (pDCs) sont très efficaces pour initier une réponse immunitaire contre les virus parce qu'elles sont des productrices efficaces d'interféron (IFN) de type I. Cette habileté à contrôler les infections virales est accompagnée par une expression sélective des récepteurs Toll-like (TLR)-7 et TLR-9 qui reconnaissent, en ordre, l'ARN viral à simple brin et l'ADN à double brin contenant des séquences cytosine-phosphate-guanosine (CpG) non-méthylées. Par la sécrétion d'IFN de type I, les pDCs peuvent moduler la cytotoxicité des cellules natural killer (NK), l'activation des DC myéloïdes (mDCs), la maturation des lymphocytes B et l'activation des lymphocytes T. Les pDCs murines expriment le récepteur Ly49Q, une lectine de type C contenant une séquence de type immunoreceptor tyrosine-based inhibitory motif (ITIM) qui reconnaît une molécule classique du complexe majeur d'histocompatibilité (CMH de classe Ia), H-2K(b). Avant nos études, le ligand et la fonction de Ly49Q chez les pDCs étaient inconnus. Nous avons utilisé un test de cellules ayant un gène rapporteur pour démontrer qu'un ligand pour Ly49Q est présent sur des cellules tumorales et des cellules isolées ex vivo d'origine H-2(b), mais pas d'origine H-2(d), H-2(k), H-2(q), ou H-2(a). Le ligand dépend de la présence de peptides et est une molécule CMH de type Ia puisque le ligand est absent de cellules déficientes pour l'expression de TAP-1, beta-2m, ou d'H-2K(b)/D(b). De plus, Ly49Q est spécifique pour H-2K(b), puisque le récepteur se lie à H-2K(b) couplé à un peptide et non à un complexe de peptide et d'H-2D(b) et la reconnaissance par Ly49Q peut être bloquée par un anticorps pour H-2K(b) mais pas pour H-2D(b). Ces résultats démontrent que Ly49Q se lie efficacement à H-2K(b) et suggèrent que la fonction des pDCs est contrôlée par des molécules classiques CMH de type Ia. Afin de caractériser les implications de l'interaction entre Ly49Q et H-2K(b), nous avons utilisé la souris déficiente pour Ly49Q précédemment générée par notre laboratoire.  Des pDCs isolés ex vivo stimulées avec CpG produisent des quantités élevées d'IFN-alpha et d'IL-12.  La production de cytokines peut être bloquée à l'aide d'anticorps pour Ly49Q ou H-2K(b) tandis que la ligation de Ly49Q à l'aide d'un anticorps ou d'H-2K(b) recombinant augmente la production de cytokines. Du sérum isolé de souris déficientes en Ly49Q injectées avec du CpG et du milieu de culture de pDCs déficients en Ly49Q stimulés avec du CpG démontrent une production diminuée de cytokines. Pour résumer, nous concluons que la reconnaissance d'H-2K(b) par Ly49Q est cruciale pour la production de cytokines par les pDCs. Une meilleure compréhension de la réponse immunitaire des pDCs humains contre les cellules transformées et infectées par des pathogènes peut être obtenue par l'étude du récepteur Ly49Q et de son ligand dans le modèle murin.</description><description>Plasmacytoid dendritic cells (pDCs) are especially suited for initiating immune responses against viruses because they are the most potent producers of type I interferon (IFN). This property of controlling viral infections is accomplished by their selective expression of toll-like receptor (TLR)-7 and TLR-9, which recognize viral single-stranded RNA (ssRNA) and unmethylated cytosine-phosphate-guanine (CpG)-containing double-stranded DNA (dsDNA), respectively. Through the secretion of Type I IFN, pDCs can modulate natural killer (NK) cell cytotoxicity, myeloid DC (mDC) activation, B cell maturation and T cell priming. Mouse pDCs express Ly49Q, a C-type lectin-like immunoreceptor tyrosine-based inhibitory motif (ITIM) -containing receptor that binds to the classical major histocompatibility complex class I molecule (MHC-Ia), H-2K(b).  Prior to our studies, both the ligand and function of Ly49Q on pDCs was unknown. We used reporter cell analysis to demonstrate that a high-affinity ligand for Ly49Q is present on H-2(b), but not H-2(d), H-2(k), H-2(q), or H-2(a)-derived tumour cells and normal cells ex vivo. The ligand is peptide-dependent and MHC-Ia-like, as revealed by its functional absence on cells deficient in TAP-1, beta-2m, or H-2K(b)/D(b) expression. Furthermore, Ly49Q is specific for H-2K(b), as the receptor binds peptide-loaded H-2K(b) but not H-2D(b) complexes, and Ly49Q recognition can be blocked using anti-K(b) but not anti-D(b) mAb. These results demonstrate that Ly49Q efficiently binds H-2K(b) and suggest that pDC function is regulated by classical MHC-Ia molecules. To characterize the implications of Ly49Q: H-2K(b) interaction, we utilized the Ly49Q-deficient mice previously generated in our lab.  Ex vivo pDCs stimulated with CpG resulted in enhanced IFN-alpha and IL-12 production. Blocking with soluble Ly49Q or H-2K(b) mAb abrogated cytokine production, while receptor cross-linking with platebound anti-Ly49Q and recombinant H-2K(b) increased cytokine production. Sera obtained from CpG injected Ly49Q-deficient mice and supernatant obtained from CpG stimulated Ly49Q-deficient pDCs displayed reduced cytokine production. Taken together, we conclude that Ly49Q recognition of H-2K(b) is crucial for pDC cytokine production. Insight into human pDC immune response against transformed and pathogen infected cells can be acquired from characterizing the Ly49Q ligand and receptor in the mouse model.</description><creator>Tai, Lee-Hwa</creator><contributor>Andrew Makrigiannis (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Benoit Cousineau (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Microbiology</subject><title>Elucidation of ligand and function for the mouse plasmacytoid dendritic cell receptor Ly49Q</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qs33z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881m409</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43nx38q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Experiences that resemble delusions of psychiatric patients can be observed in the general healthy population. These experiences, named hereafter delusional-like ideations, are not the only fact in line with the idea that there is a continuum between clinical delusions and normality. Previous research suggests that at least two types of cognitive bias could be common to patients and healthy subjects: first, a tendency to jump to conclusions, which can play a role in the formation of delusional ideation and second, abnormal semantic processes, which could lead to the maintenance of these ideations. The present thesis was aimed at further investigating these two biases in the general population to see whether further support can be obtained for the continuum view. In addition, the impact of current paranoid feelings on these cognitive biases was assessed in these healthy participants. The tendency to jump to conclusion was evaluated with a reasoning task. Healthy people with delusional-like ideation needed less information to reach a conclusion than people without or with few delusional-like ideations, replicating findings obtained in deluded patients. Furthermore, paranoid feelings strengthened the relationship between delusional-like ideation and this jump to conclusion style of thinking. Results also show that people with delusional-like ideation jump to new conclusions when they experienced paranoid feelings, a finding that only tended to be significant when no paranoid feelings were induced. These results provide further support to the continuum idea and to the hypothesis that the jump to conclusion bias may be involved in delusion formation. On the other hand, semantic processes of healthy participants were investigated by recording the N400 event-related brain potential in a semantic categorization task. When paranoid feelings were induced, delusional-like ideation scores were associated with smaller raw N400 amplitudes, as was found in schizophrenia patients with delusions. The analysis of the independent components of the N400 potential showed that delusional-like ideation had an influence on the N400 even when no paranoid feelings were induced. These results suggest that semantic processing of people with delusional-like ideation can be modulated by their current mental state. The implications for delusion formation and maintenance are explored. In conclusion, both the results of the jump to conclusion and those of the semantic processes studies lend further support to the idea of a continuum between clinical delusions and delusional-like ideation.</description><description>Des expériences qui ressemblent aux idées délirantes psychiatriques peuvent être observées dans la population générale saine. Ces expériences, ci-nommées idées de type délirantes, ne sont pas les seuls faits en accord avec l'idée qu'il existe un continuum entre les idées délirantes et la normalité. Des études précédentes suggèrent qu'au moins deux types de biais cognitif sont communs aux patients et aux personnes saines: 1/la tendance à tirer des conclusions hâtives qui pourrait jouer un rôle dans la formation des idées délirantes et 2/les processus sémantiques anormaux qui pourraient conduire à la persistance de ces idées. La présente thèse a pour objectif d'explorer ces deux biais et d'évaluer s'ils soutiennent l'idée de continuum. De plus, l'influence de sentiments paranoïdes sur ces biais cognitifs est évaluée chez ces participants sains. La tendance à tirer des conclusions hâtives a été testée avec une tache de raisonnement. Les personnes saines ayant des idées de type délirantes nécessitaient moins d'information pour arriver à une conclusion que ceux sans idées de type délirantes, ce qui réplique les résultats trouvés chez les patients délirants. De plus, les sentiments paranoïdes renforçaient le lien entre les idées de type délirantes et le saut aux conclusions des participants. Les résultats montrent aussi que les participants avec des idées de type délirantes tirent de nouvelles conclusions hâtives, ce qui n'était pas significatif lorsque les sentiments paranoïdes n'étaient pas induits. Ces résultats  soutiennent l'idée du continuum ainsi que l'hypothèse proposant que tirer des conclusions hâtives pourrait participer à la formation des idées délirantes. D'autre part, les processus sémantiques des participants sains ont été évalués en enregistrant le potentiel cérébral évoqué qu'est la N400, dans une tache de catégorisation sémantique. Quand des sentiments paranoïdes étaient induits, les scores d'idées de type délirantes étaient associés à de plus petites amplitudes brutes de N400, rappelant les résultats observés chez les patients. L'analyse des composantes indépendantes du potentiel N400 montre que les idées de type délirantes avaient une influence sur la N400, même lorsque les sentiments paranoïdes n'étaient pas induits chez les participants. Ces résultats suggèrent que les processus sémantiques des personnes avec des idées de type délirantes pourraient donc être modulés par leur état mental. Les implications pour la formation et la maintenance des idées délirantes sont explorées. En conclusion, les résultats des études sur le fait de tirer des conclusions hâtives et ceux des études sur les processus sémantiques soutiennent l'idée de continuum entre les idées délirantes pathologiques et les idées de type délirantes.</description><creator>Prévost, Marie</creator><contributor>Jacques Bruno Debruille (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Psychology - Clinical</subject><title>Information processing in healthy people with delusional- like ideation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515n808.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43nx38q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sk005</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Antécédent: les patients transplantés rénaux hautement sensibilisés sont sur la liste de transplantation en raison d'anticorps anti-HLA. Les protocoles actuels de désensibilisation sont non fiables. Interleukin-21 est une cytokine de type I qui signale par intermédiaire d'un récepteur commun entre les facteurs de croissance des cellules T (TCGFs). Sécrétée par les cellules T, l'IL-21 agit comme un régulateur de la production  d'anticorps anti cellule B, de la différenciation des plasmocytes, ainsi de la commutation de classe d'immunoglobuline. Il co-stimule la prolifération et la réponse de la mémoire dans les cellules T. Nous avons évoqué l'hypothèse que l'IL-21 pourrait être un facteur contributif important pour l'induction de la sensibilisation et pour la production d'anticorps par les lymphocytes B. Nous avons évalué l'effet de l'IL-21 sur la capacité de production d'anticorps par les cellules B et avons comparé l'expression des récepteurs IL-21 (IL-21R) sur les cellules B périphériques chez les patients hautement sensibilisés et nonsensibilisés étant sous dialyse. Méthodes: Les patients sélectionnés dans la liste d'attente de transplantation et sont enrôlé en deux groupes: les non sensibilisés avec (PRA &lt;5%), sensibilisés (PRA&gt; 50%). Après l'obtention du consentement, du sang périphérique a été utilisée pour l'évaluation de l'IL-21R expression sur PBMNCs par la Cytométrie de Flux. Résultats: (1) La co-stimulation in vitro des cellules B avec l'IL-21 et anti-CD40 résulte à la production d'anticorps plus élevée comparativement à la production liée à la stimulation isolée d'anticorps anti-CD40 ou à celle d'IL-21. (2) La stimulation in vitro des cellules B humaines par des anticorps anti-CD40 augmente l'expression de l'IL-21R. (3) L'expression de l'IL-21R est significativement plus élevée dans les cellules B périphériques chez les patients hautement sensibilisés par rapport aux patients non sensibilisés. (4) Il existe une corrélation significative entre les niveaux de PRA et le pourcentage de cellules périphériques exprimant IL21R. Conclusion: L'IL-21 et l'IL-21R peuvent être une cytokine d'interaction importante entre les cellules B et la production d'anticorps chez les receveurs de greffe rénale hautement sensibilisés. Il se peut que ceci offre une nouvelle cible pour les protocoles de désensibilisation.</description><description>Background: Renal transplant patients who are highly sensitized linger on the transplant list due to HLA specific antibodies. Current desensitization protocols are unreliable. Interleukin-21 is a type I cytokine that signals through a receptor shared by the all T-cell growth factors (TCGFs). Secreted by T-cells, IL-21 acts as a regulator of B-cell anti-body production and differentiation into plasma cells as well as immunoglobulin class switching. It co-stimulates proliferation and memory response in T-cells. We hypothesized that IL-21 could be a significant contributing factor in induction of sensitization and antibody production by B-lymphocytes. We evaluated the effect of IL-21 on the anti-body production capacity of B-cells and compared the expression IL-21 Receptor (IL-21R) on the peripheral B-cells in highly sensitized and non-sensitized patients on dialysis. Methods: In-vitro studies: B-cells isolated from peripheral blood of healthy individuals, were stimulated with mouse anti-Human CD40 monoclonal antibody (R&amp;D), recombinant IL-21 or combination of both. Produced IgG and IgM levels were measured by classic Eliza method. Ex-vivo studies: Patients selected from the transplant waiting list and assigned into two groups: non-sensitized with (PRA&lt;5%), sensitized (PRA&gt;50%). After obtaining consent, peripheral blood was used for evaluation of IL-21R Expression on PBMNCs by Flowcytometry. Results: (1) In-vitro Co-stimulation of B-cells with IL-21 and anti-CD40 results in higher antibody production compared with isolated anti-CD-40 or IL-21 stimulation. (2) In-vitro stimulation of human B-cells with anti-CD40 Antibody increases expression of IL-21R. (3) The expression of IL-21R is significantly higher on the peripheral B-cells in highly sensitized patients compared to non-sensitized patients. (4) A significant correlation exists between PRA levels and the percentage of peripheral cells expressing IL21R. Conclusion: IL-21 and IL-21R may be an important cytokine interaction in B-cells and antibody production in highly sensitized renal transplant recipients. This may offer a novel target for desensitization protocols.</description><creator>Tavana, Reza</creator><contributor>Jean I Tchervenkov (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery</subject><title>The expression of interleukin 21 receptor (IL-21R) on the peripheral B-Lymphocytes in highly sensitized and non- sensitized transplant patients</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kg71t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sk005</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20ss90r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le réchauffement planétaire lié à l'émission croissante des gaz à effet de serre menace la production alimentaire mondiale. Une augmentation des températures ainsi qu'une modification des régimes de précipitations augmentent les risques de mauvaises récoltes à long terme. Toutefois, certaines pratiques agricoles, comme le choix du type de semence, les dates de semis, et l'irrigation permettent aux agriculteurs de s'adapter au mieux aux variations climatiques. Afin d'évaluer le rôle combiné du climat et des pratiques agricoles sur le rendement des cultures, un nouveau modèle agricole, PEGASUS 1.0 (Predicting Ecosystem Goods And Services Using Scenarios), a été développé. PEGASUS simule le rendement du maïs, du soja, et du blé de printemps à l'échelle mondiale. Cette thèse présente les méthodes utilisées pour développer le modèle, ainsi que son évaluation sur les données agricoles actuelles. Par ailleurs, la sensibilité du modèle à un réchauffement global de 2°C a été estimée. De manière générale, les résultats des simulations correspondant aux conditions climatiques actuelles sont satisfaisants. Ainsi, les dates de semence et de récolte simulées coïncident avec l'éventail des dates observées pour plus de 62% des surfaces cultivées, pour chacune des trois cultures. De plus, l'évaluation du rendement agricole calculé indique un coefficient de détermination, pondéré par la surface récoltée, égale à 0.81 pour le maïs, 0.63 pour le so ja, et 0.45 pour le blé de printemps. Les résultats des simulations correspondant à un réchauffement de la température montrent une réduction générale des rendements agricoles. Cependant, lorsque les dates de plantation et le choix du cultivar sont adaptés à la nouvelle température, les pertes sont réduites de 60 à 78%. Les variations de rendement agricoles ont été comparées par revenus économiques, démontrant que les pays les plus riches pourraient bénéficier$</description><description>Global warming resulting from increasing greenhouse gas emissions is a threat to global food production. A rise in temperatures along with a shift in precipitation regimes is expected to decrease production in the future. However, farm management, such as the choice of crop cultivar, planting decisions, and irrigation can help farmers to alleviate some of the potential crop yield losses from climate change. In order to estimate the role of climate and agricultural management practices on yield, a new global crop model, PEGASUS 1.0 (Predicting Ecosystem Goods And Services Using Scenarios) has been developed for maize, soybean, and spring wheat. This thesis presents the methods used to develop the model, and its evaluation against present-day data, along with a model sensitivity experiment to a global warming of 2°C. Overall, results for present-day simulations are reasonable. Simulated planting and harvesting dates occur within the range of observations for more than 62% of total crop harvested areas, for each of the three crops. A comparison between simulated and observed crop yields indicates a weighted coefficient of determination, with the weighting based on crop harvested area, of 0.81 for maize, 0.63 for soybean, and 0.45 for spring wheat. The model simulates that an increase in temperature will result in a global decrease in crop yields. Nevertheless, adapting planting dates and cultivar choices to changes in temperature can avoid 60–78% of yield losses globally. Overall, the model results suggest that agricultural production in the richest countries, mostly located in the northern high latitudes, could benefit from increase in temperature, while the agriculture in the poorest countries in the tropics are likely to suffer the most.</description><creator>Deryng, Delphine</creator><contributor>Navin Ramankutty (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Physical Geography</subject><title>Simulating the effects of climate and land management practices on global crop yield</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v829j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20ss90r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60cw81c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Three adult ESL students in a private setting participated in  this case study, which investigated the effects of teaching students through  strategy instruction, to adopt learning strategies that matched their individual  learning style. I designed the training to draw attention to 16 learning strategies,  that learners could chose from, according to their VARK (visual, aural, read and  write, kinesthetic) profile. Instruction was provided in the context of an  intermediate level 1 class, for a weekly three hour class. The focus of the study  was to gain knowledge of cognition, metacognition and apply that knowledge to the  use of personalised learning strategies. The goal was to then apply these strategies  to facilitate learning a new verb tense, the present perfect. The training provided  opportunities for practice, in both the learning strategies and the linguistic  content. This study is a descriptive case study and not an experimental study.  Therefore, in order to describe the contributions of strategy instruction, as  revealed by the data, I employed a number of procedures. Pretest and postest results  were analysed and showed a significant increase in the ability of students exposed  to the training to correctly use the present perfect in context. Interview and  questionnaire data were used to complement the test score data. It appears that  strategy instruction is a factor that contributed to the score improvement and,  because strategy instruction entails a number of elements, it is the combination of  these elements such as the selection and use of appropriate strategies, cognitive  and metacognitive awareness, knowledge of self, and practice in context that  contributed to the score gains.</description><creator>Bourgeois, Sophie</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Learning strategies</subject><subject>English language -- Tense</subject><subject>English language -- Study and teaching (Continuing education) -- Foreign speakers</subject><title>The effects of matching learning strategies to learning modalities in the acquisition of the present perfect with adult ESL learners /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xm39n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cw81c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Second Language Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cb381</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main objective of this thesis is to defend an account of the  control that agents possess over their actions from the perspective of the causal  theory of action, that is, a theory that sees actions as events caused by internal  states of their agents. The explanatory strategy that is employed for this purpose  consists in addressing three interdependent and fundamental problems concerning the  possibility of this type of control. The first problem arises from the possibility  of controlling an action that is itself transitively caused by previous events. The  answer given to this problem is grounded on a careful description of basic actions  and on an identification of the internal states that function as the sources of  control. The second problem emerges from a variety of causal deviance, namely, a  conceptually possible scenario that satisfies the requirements for a bodily movement  to be under the control of its agent without this movement being intuitively under  the control of its agent. The answer given to this problem comes from the  examination of the sources of the intuitions associated with causal deviance and  from the recognition of the causal contribution of epistemic features present in the  antecedents of an action. The third problem results from the possibility of  producing an action that can only be partially controlled. This is problematic if  one accepts that producing an action entails controlling it, as is suggested in this  thesis. The reply given to this problem adapts an intention-based account of action  guidance to the needs of an account of degrees of control, while remaining  compatible with the proposal that producing an action is sufficient to control  it.</description><creator>Aguilar, Jesús H.</creator><contributor>Pietroski, Paul (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Davies, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Agent (Philosophy)</subject><subject>Action theory.</subject><subject>Causation</subject><title>Agency and control</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45q949w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cb381</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514nk901</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le sodium (Na) ainsi que le potassium (K) sont des nutriments essentiels. Nous avons examiné le contenu de Na et de K d'aliments collectés pour l'Étude Canadienne sur l'alimentation totale de Vancouver conduite en 2007. Notre base de données sur le contenu nutritionnel des aliments a démontré que les aliments traités et les soupes ont un haut niveau de Na alors que le lait, les viandes non-traitées ainsi que plusieurs fruits et légumes détiennent un niveau élevé de K. Basés sur ces données, de nouvelles prises ont été générées en utilisant l'Enquête sur la santé dans les collectivités canadiennes (ESCC 2.2), cycle 2.2, Nutrition. En général, les résultats ont démontré un niveau d'ingestion de Na moins que CCHS mais plus élevé que l'apport maximum tolérable (AMT). Les ingestions de K étaient similaires aux données contenues dans l'ESCC 2.2, démontrant une ingestion inférieure à l'apport suffisant (AS).</description><description>Sodium (Na) and potassium (K) are essential nutrients.  We investigated Na and K content of foods collected from the 2007 Vancouver Total Diet Study (TDS). Our food nutrient content data showed that processed foods and soups had a high Na content while fluid milk, unprocessed meats and several fruits and vegetables had a high K content. The Na/K ratio indicated, with few exceptions, a segregation of the foods high in Na from ones high in K. Based on this data, new Na and K intakes were generated using Canadian Community Health Survey (CCHS2.2), cycle 2.2 Nutrition dietary recall. In general, the results showed a lower Na intake than indicated by CCHS2.2, but still higher than the Tolerable Upper Level of Intake (UL). K intakes were similar to CCHS2.2 data showing an intake lower than the AI.</description><creator>Tanase, Corina</creator><contributor>Kristine G Koski (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Kevin Cockell (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Nutrition</subject><title>Sodium and Potassium in the Canadian total diet study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn106z52f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nk901</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085k641</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Research has shown that children attending immersion programs  reach a native-like level in comprehension and in reading by the end of elementary  level. However, in writing and speaking, they rarely achieve target-like  proficiency. Some conditions seem to favor the production of output. This study  presents an investigation of children's ability to notice errors in their French  second language in immersion program in Montreal. The study was conducted with  forty-three (43) children aged 8-9, and aimed to gather information related to the  following research questions: Can we train 8 year-old second language learners to: (a) notice  their errors; (b) self-correct (given certain prompts); (c) use metalinguistic  terminology to identify forms; and (d) negotiate form using language as a conscious  tool to improve their L2 oral production? Children were required to participate in two (2) stages: first,  video recording of communicative activities whit ungrammatical episodes with  provision of corrective feedback were selected; and second, audio recording of  children's attempts to negotiate form. The database was collected from these  stimulated recall sessions of collaborative discussion. Results show how young  learners may benefit from the provision of metalinguistic information, thus  facilitating their second language learning development.</description><creator>Bouffard, Laura Annie</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Language awareness</subject><subject>French language -- Study and teaching (Elementary) -- Foreign speakers</subject><subject>French language -- Study and teaching -- Immersion method</subject><title>Maturing metalinguistically : negotiation of form and the refinement of repair</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397883n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085k641</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Second Language Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xd07gt09k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In recent years, dependent type systems have gathered interest because they make it possible to express stronger properties about programs. However, they are also very verbose. In this thesis, we show how to eliminate some of this verbosity (for the user) by doing reconstruction over dependent types. More precisely, we present the work done in the implementation of the Beluga programming language. Our goal is to present the key issues arising in reconstruction and give a formal and accessible description of ideas that have been around for some time but never given the spotlight. We also prove the soundness of our reconstruction algorithm.</description><description>Au cours des dernières années, les types dépendants ont reçu un intérêt particulier parce qu'ils permettent d'exprimer des propriétés plus précises sur les programmes. Cependant, ces systèmes de typage sont aussi très redondants. Dans cette thèse, nous allons expliquer comment éliminer une partie de cette redondance en reconstruisant ces types dépendants. Plus précisément, nous présenterons le travail fait sur l'implémentation du langage Beluga. Notre but est de présenter les problématiques importantes liées à la reconstruction de types dépendants et de présenter de façon formelle et accessible certaines idées qui, malgré le fait qu'elle ne sont pas toutes récentes, sont toujours restées dans l'ombre jusqu'à maintenant. Une preuve de correction de notre algorithme de reconstruction est aussi donnée.</description><creator>Germain, Renaud</creator><contributor>Brigitte Pientka (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>Implementation of a dependently typed functional programming language</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nt98v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gt09k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s286m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette étude a testé l'utilisation de différentes techniques dans l'évaluation  des caractéristiques microstructurales de friture profonde de pépites de poulet panées tout en considérant l'effet des conditions de friture et la formulation de la pâte. Un porosimètre d'intrusion de mercure a été utilisé pour mesurer la porosité, la distribution de la taille des pores et la forme des pores dans des pépites de poulet panées lyophilisées. La porosité a varié de 40 à 69 %. Le temps et la température de la friture ont affecté significativement (P &lt; 0.05) la porosité. La porosité a montré une haute corrélation positive et négative avec le contenu en humidité et en graisse. Les coefficients de corrélation étaient entre 0.88 – 0.96 et 0.78 – 0.8, respectivement. Le phénomène d'hystérèse a montré que les pores n'ont pas tous une structure cylindrique. La porosité de pépites de poulet panées frites préformées et formulées au laboratoire a été mesurée en utilisant un pycnométreen hélium. L'effet de la température de friture et la composition de la pate sur la porosité était significatif (P&lt;0.05). La porosité à une température de friture de 170 °C a été significativement différente de celles à des températures de 180 et 190°C, alors que la porosité de la pâte avec 100 % de farine de blé a été significativement  inférieure aux autres pâtes formulées. La porosité a augmenté avec le temps et la température de friture. Elle varie de 2.2 à 48 % et de 10 à 55 % pour la pâte préformée et la pâte formulée, respectivement. fr Des images en 3D du revêtement et du noyau des pépites de poulet panées frites ont été obtenues par  X-ray micro computed tomography (CT). La porosité du revêtement et du noyau des pépites a varié de  7 à 14.1 % et de 4.5 à 7.7 %, respectivement. Le temps de friture a influencé significativement (P&lt;0.05) la porosité, le degré de l'interconnectivité et la dimension des pores. La  porosité et la dimension des pores a augmenté avec le temps de friture alors que l'interconnectivité des pores a diminué. fr Des Rayons MicroCT X ont été utilisés pour tester l'effet de la formulation de la pâte sur les caractéristiques des pores. La formulation de la pâte a influencé significativement (P &lt; 0.05) la porosité, l'index de fragmentation et le nombre des pores. La forme des pores de toutes les formulations est restée la même avec unestructure modèle index forme cylindrique. La porosité a varié entre 18.2 et 32.1 %. L'ajout de carboxymethyl cellulose (CMC) a causé une diminution de porosité d'environ 25 %. L'ajout de la farine du riz dans la formulation de la pâte a augmenté significativement la porosité comparée à la pâte formée de 100 % de la farine de blé sans CMC. Des corrélations ont été observées entre les propriétés physico-chimiques de la pâte et la porosité. Les images fluorescentes et réflectives de la friture profonde des revêtements de pépites de poulet ont été obtenues en 2 dimensions à l'aide de la  microscopie confocale laser à balayage (MCLB). Une diminution de l'intensité de la graisse de la surface vers le noyau de l'échantillon a été observée. La porosité et la distribution de la graisse ont été influencées significativement par le temps et la température de la friture. La porosité était entre 5  et 33 %, tandis que la taille des pores  était entre 1.2 et 523 µm. Une forte corrélation (r = 0.8) a été observée entre la distribution de la matière grasse obtenue à partir de l'imagerie MCLB et le contenu en matière grasse obtenu par la méthode conventionnelle  à 180 et 190°C, indiquant une capacité raisonnable pour prédire l'une de l'autre. Toutes les techniques utilisées ont évalué efficacement les propriétés microstructureles des aliments frits étudiés au sein de leur limite de mesure. Il est donc suggéré que plusieurs techniques soient combinées afin d'obtenir des données complètes des caractéristiques des pores des aliments frits.</description><description>This study investigated the use of different techniques in evaluating the microstructural characteristics of deep-fat fried chicken nuggets, and considered the effect of frying conditions and batter formulation. Mercury intrusion porosimetry was used to obtain porosity, pore size distribution and pore shape for freeze dried deep-fat fried chicken nuggets batter coating. Porosity was found to range between 40 - 69%. Frying time and temperature significantly (P &lt; 0.05) influenced porosity. Porosity showed a high positive and  negative correlation with moisture and fat contents, and the correlation coefficients was between 0.88 – 0.96 and 0.78 - 0.8, respectively. Hysteresis phenomenon showed that pore shapes other than cylindrical structure were present within the samples. Porosity of preformed and lab formulated deep-fat fried chicken nuggets batter coatings were investigated using helium pycnometry. There was significant (P &lt;0.05) effect of frying temperature and batter formulation on porosity. Porosity at 170°C was significantly different from those at 180 and 190°C, while porosity of batter with 100% wheat flour was significantly lower than the other formulated batters. However, porosity increased with frying time and temperature, and it ranged from 2.15 – 47.9% and 9.96 – 54.8% for the preformed and the formulated batter, respectively. Images (3-D) of deep-fat fried chicken nuggets batter coating and core were obtained by X-ray micro computed tomography (CT). Porosity for the batter coating and the chicken core varied from 7 – 14.1% and 4.4 – 7.7%, respectively. Frying time significantly (P &lt; 0.05) influenced porosity, fragmentation index (degree of interconnectivity) and pore count. Porosity and pore count increased with frying time while pore interconnectivity decreased. Pore size distribution showed that micropores (&lt; 100 µm) increased in volume and number with frying time. X-ray microCT was also used to investigate the effect of batter formulation on pore characteristics. There was significant (P &lt; 0.05) effect of batter formulation on porosity, fragmentation index and pore count. Pore shape of all the formulations remained relatively the same with structure model index from 2 – 3, indicating cylindrical shape. Porosity ranged between 18.2 – 32.1%. The addition of carboxymethyl cellulose (CMC) caused about 25% decrease in porosity, though not significantly. The addition of rice flour into the batter formulation resulted in significant increase in porosity when compared to batter with 100% wheat flour without CMC inclusion. The addition of CMC resulted in decreased interconnectivity between the pores while rice flour addition caused increase pore connectivity. Some correlations were shown between the physico-chemical properties of the batter system and porosity. Fluorescence and reflective images of the deep fat-fried chicken nuggets batter coating were obtained in 2-D using confocal laser scanning microscopy (CLSM). There was a decrease in fat intensity from the surface towards the core of the sample. Porosity and fat distribution were significantly influenced by frying temperature and time. Porosity ranged between 5– 33%, while pore size varied from 1.20 – 523 µm. There was formation of smaller (pores ≤ 42 µm) and bigger (pores ≥ 270 µm) pores, while medium size (191 – 270 µm) pores diminished with frying time. There was a strong correlation (r = 0.79) between fat distribution obtained from CLSM imaging and fat content obtained by the conventional method at 180 and 190°C, indicating a reasonable capacity to predict one from the other. All the techniques used effectively evaluated the microstructural properties of fried foods studied within their limit of measurement. None could provide full microstructural properties of the fried foods. It is suggested that various techniques be combined in order to obtain a complete data of the pore characteristics of fried foods.</description><creator>Adedeji, Akinbode</creator><contributor>Michael O Ngadi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Agriculture - Food Science and Technology</subject><title>Evaluation of different techniques for microstructural characterization of deep-fat fried foods</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q189b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s286m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5h73pw45h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Energy is one of the biggest concerns of today's society, because of the rapid depletion of the world's fossil fuel reserves. Efficient energy technologies and renewable energy sources must therefore be developed and implemented. With a 5% share of the total energy consumption, agriculture can benefit from such developments. To preheat cold and fresh ventilation air for livestock barns, solar collectors are one of the promising renewable energy sources to reduce fossil fuel used in heating. Besides identifying energy saving strategies, the objective of the present project was to evaluate the performance of a specific type of solar air pre-heaters consisting of unprotected black corrugated metal sheeting with 1% perforation, installed over the barn fresh air inlets facing south. In this experiment, the two identically built commercial broilers barns were located in St-Jean-Baptiste, 40 km east of Montreal, Canada at 45.5 ° latitude. Each barn offered three floors with a capacity of 6500 broilers/floor, and 73.65 m2 of solar air pre-heaters for a total of 221 m2/barn. From November 2007 to March 2009 the project monitored inlet, inside and outside air conditions, ventilation rate and solar energy recovery and, from this data, conducted energy balance analyses. Measured efficiencies in recovering solar radiation varied from 65% to 20% depending on wind velocity and produced an annual return on investment of 4.7%. Air temperature stratification inside each room was responsible for the loss of 25 and 15% in heater energy and recovered solar energy, respectively. Although reducing heating load, the solar air pre-heaters had no impact on livestock performance because of limited effect on ventilation rate. The monitoring of ambient air temperature and relative humidity was complicated by air temperature stratification. Furthermore, the proper monitoring of ventilation rates requires the installation of electromagnetic sensors on all exhaust fans. The pyranometers used i</description><description>L'énergie est l'une des plus grandes préoccupations de la société d'aujourd'hui en raison de l'épuisement rapide des réserves de combustibles fossiles dans le monde. Des technologies nouvelles et plus efficaces ainsi que des sources d'énergies renouvelables doivent par conséquent être développées et implantées. Avec une part de 5% de la consommation mondiale d'énergie, l'agriculture peut bénéficier de ces développements. Pour préchauffer l'air frais entrant par la ventilation des bâtiments d'animaux d'élevage, les capteurs solaires sont une des sources d'énergies renouvelables prometteuses afin de réduire la consommation d'énergie en chauffage. Outre l'identification des stratégies d'économie d'énergie, l'objectif de ce projet était d'évaluer la performance d'un type spécifique de capteurs solaires pour le préchauffage de l'air constitué d'un revêtement métallique noir, ondulé et non protégé du vent ayant 1% de sa surface en perforation. Ce revêtement était installé aux prises d'air d'un bâtiment dans la direction la plus méridionale possible. Les deux poulaillers étudiés au cours de cette expérience étaient identiques et exploités de façon commerciale. Ils étaient situés à St-Jean-Baptiste, à 40 km à l'est de Montréal, au Canada à une latitude de 45.5o. Chaque bâtiment comprenait trois étages ayant un capacité 6500 poulets par étage et un système de capteur solaire de 73.65 m2 chacun pour une aire totale de 211 m2 par poulailler. De novembre 2007 à mars 2009, les caractéristiques de l'air dans les entrées d'air, à l'intérieur et à l'extérieur ainsi que le taux de ventilation et la radiation solaire ont été mesurés et analysés pour faire un bilan énergétique. Les efficacités de la récupération de chaleur provenant du rayonnement solaire ont varié de 65% à 20% dépendamment de la vélocité du vent, en plus les capteurs ont produit un retour sur l'investissement annuel de 4.7%. La stratifi</description><creator>Cordeau, Sébastien</creator><contributor>Suzelle Barrington (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</subject><title>The performance of a solar air pre-heater system for the ventilation of two commercial poultry barns</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935336k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73pw45h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074v526</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La fausse teigne de la cire, Galleria mellonella, est utilisée extensivement comme modèle pour etudier le système immunitaire inné. Le processus multicellulaire de nodulation isole de grandes quantités de microbes de petite taille (bacteries et levures) dans l'appareil circulatoire (hémocèle) de l'insecte et est controlé par les deux cellules sanguines immunitaires (hémocytes) principales: les cellules granulaires et les plasmatocytes. Les protéines G et leurs produits de réactions sont impliqués dans les réponses immunitaires precoces (l'adhésion hémocytes-microbes) et tardives (humorale), cependant, leur participation dans les intéractions hémocytes-hémocytes conduisant à la formation des nodules demeure inconnue. Ci-dessous, j'ai traité les hémocytes avec la protéine AB5, la toxine cholérique (CTX), reconnue pour sa stimulation des Gαs, une sous-unité des protéines G hétérotrimériques et est responsable de l'activation de l'adénylate cyclase et de l'augmentation de l'AMP cyclique intracellulaire dans les neutrophiles mammifère. La CTX a causé une augmentation bimodale du nombre d'hémocytes par micro-agrégats in vitro et de la fréquence des nodules in vivo. L'augmentation des concentrations élevées a induit une augmentation de ces paramètres, tandis que de faibles concentrations induit des taux d'hémocytes par micro-agrégats in vitro et de la fréquence de nodules in vivo semblables à ceux obtenus avec la concentration la plus élevée de CTX, bien que les hémocytes aient démontré une réduction d'adhérence au substrat. Le retrait CTX-dépendantes des bacteries (Bacillus subtilis) injecter dans l' hémocèle de l'insecte était inversement corrélé avec la fréquence des nodules. La sous-unité B de la CTX était responsable des effets obtenus aux concentrations plus élevées, alors que la sous-unité A de la CTX n'a eu aucune effet sur les hémocytes. La formation des micro-agrégats in vitro par la CTX était inh</description><description>The greater wax moth, Galleria mellonella, is used extensively as a model to study innate immunity. The multicellular process of nodulation acts to isolate large numbers of small microbes (bacteria and yeasts) in the open circulatory system (hemocoel) of the insect and is directed by the main immune blood cell (hemocyte) types, the granular cells and the plasmatocytes. G proteins and their downstream products have been implicated in both early (hemocyte-microbe adhesion) and late (humoral) immune responses, however, their involvement in hemocyte-hemocyte interactions leading to nodule formation is not known. Herein, I treated hemocytes with an AB5 protein, whole cholera toxin (CTX), known to stimulate the Gαs subunit of heterotrimeric G proteins and is responsible for activating adenylate cyclase and elevating intracellular cAMP in mammalian neutrophils. CTX caused a bimodal increase in hemocytes per in vitro microaggregate and nodule frequency in vivo, wherein increasing high cholera toxin concentrations induced these effects, while low concentrations induced levels of hemocytes per in vitro microaggregate and nodule frequency similar to the highest concentration of CTX, but the hemocytes showed reduced substratum-related adhesion. CTX-dependent bacterial (Bacillus subtilis) removal from the insect hemocoel was inversely correlated with nodule frequency. The cholera toxin B-subunit was responsible for the effects of CTX at higher concentrations, while isolated cholera toxin A-subunit had no effect on the hemocytes. In vitro CTX-induced, hemocyte microaggregate formation was inhibited by RGD peptides, suggesting the involvement of integrins. Human integrin antibodies to αv, β3, α5, and β1 bound integrin-like molecules from unseparated, whole hemocyte lysates and labeled both the granular cells and plasmatocytes adhering to coverslips. The anti-α5 integrin labeled the junction between interacting granular cells and plasmatocytes, the frequency of this labeli</description><creator>Lapointe, Jason</creator><contributor>Gary Brian Dunphy (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Craig A. Mandato (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Cell</subject><title>The involvement of G(alpha)s proteins and integrins in the cellular immune responses of a lepidopteran insect, «Galleria mellonella»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d0142.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074v526</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x437v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Lors de la conception d'un nouveau principe actif, les chimistes médicinaux disposent d'un grand nombre d'outils leur permettant de générer rapidement une série de composés ayant une action spécifique. L'optimisation du procédé chimique requiert l'utilisation et le développement de méthodes toujours plus simples, rapides et peu couteuses. Ainsi, nous avons souhaité concevoir et utiliser quelques outils chimiques permettant de résoudre certains de ces problèmes. Cette thèse présente des outils spécifiques à la chimie médicinale et la chimie des procédés. Dans un premier temps, nous nous sommes intéressés à une enzyme : la prolyl oligopeptidase. Nous avons tout d'abord répertorié un grand nombre de données, quant à son implication dans certains troubles neurologiques (ex. : maladie d'Alzheimer), ainsi que de nombreux programmes de recherche visant le développement de nouveaux inhibiteurs conçus à partir de la structure du substrat naturel. Dans l'optique de mieux comprendre l'environnement chimique du site de liaison de l'enzyme et concevoir notre propre inhibiteur sélectif, nous avons synthétisé et testé une série de composés pseudo-peptidiques et peptidomimétiques. Lors de cette étude, nous avons identifié deux inhibiteurs covalents, actifs et sélectifs : l'un pseudo-peptidique (IC50 = 3-7 nM), l'autre peptidomimétique (IC50 = 20-700 nM). Dans la deuxième partie de cette thèse, nous avons rapporté les méthodes déjà existantes permettant une fonctionnalisation régioselective des différents groupements alcools des hexopyranosidases afin de rendre plus accessible l'utilisation des sucres en chimie médicinale. La compilation de cette recherche bibliographique dans une table permettra aux chimistes de facilement sélectionner la méthode la plus adéquate. Afin de réduire le nombre d'étapes (protections et déprotections) associées à la chimie des sucres, nous avons appliqué le groupement protecteur-directeur dév</description><description>In the field of drug design and development, medicinal chemists use a variety of tools to quickly generate a series of hit compounds controlling a specific biological target and culminating in a lead compound. Process chemists seek efficient methods to synthesize the lead compounds provided by the medicinal chemists and using readily available and inexpensive starting materials, shortcuts and simpler routes. With this in mind, we aimed to design, develop and apply chemical tools to generate hit compounds, but also developing new simpler methods to make pharmaceutically relevant compounds. In this context, this thesis has two goals. In the first part, we focused on the enzyme prolyl oligopeptidase, reviewing its involvement in neurological disorders, such as Alzheimer's disease, and the efforts of several researchers to synthesize potent, selective inhibitors resembling the natural substrates of this enzyme. We proposed another method, using small pseudopeptidic and peptidomimetic inhibitors as chemical tools to better understand the shape, size and electronics of inhibitors and generate a more potent, selective prolyl oligopeptidase inhibitor. From our series of compounds, we discovered a few potent and highly selective, covalent inhibitors, one of them pseudo-peptidic (IC50 = 3-7 nM) and the other peptidomimetic (IC50 = 20-700 nM). In the second part of this thesis, with the goal of being able to exploit sugars in medicinal chemistry, we first reviewed the methods that exist to regioselectively functionalize the various hydroxyls of hexopyranosides. We compiled these methods into a table which chemists could consult when they are seeking to perform a specific reaction on a specific sugar. We then proposed to use a hydrogen bond accepting protecting group which can direct subsequent reactions to specific sites on sugars in an effort to reduce the number of protection and deprotection steps. We applied this protecting-directing group and developed methods to regio</description><creator>Lawandi, Janice</creator><contributor>Nicolas Moitessier (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Chemistry - Organic</subject><title>Development and application of chemical tools for the design and synthesis of bioactive molecules</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920fx270.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x437v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rd89t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La glycosylation des protéines joue un rôle important dans leur repliement, leur sécrétion, dans la signalization cellulaire, et pourrait même participer à l'adhérence entre les cellules. Chez les eucaryotes, la biosynthèse de N-glycanes débute avec le transfert de Glc3Man9GlcNAc2 à l'amide d'une asparagine située dans la séquence Asn-X-Thr (Ser). L'élimination de trois glucoses et d`un mannose a ensuite lieu dans le réticulum endoplasmique. Dans le cas de la levure, les protéines qui nécessitent encore plus de maturation, par exemple celles destinées à entrer dans la voie de sécrétion, sont envoyées au cis-Golgi. Ensuite, la glycane Man8GlcNAc2, est ornée de mannoses additionels et de mannose-1-phosphate. L'enzyme responsable du transfert du mannose-1-phosphate dans Saccharomyces cerevisiae est Ktr6p. Il est caractérisé comme étant un membre de la famille des mannosyltransferases liés à la protéine Kre2p (KTR). Ktr6p conserve une identité de séquence de 38% avec Kre2p, suggérant une structure homologue. Toutefois, plus de 50% des résidus présents dans le site actif présumé de Ktr6p diffèrent de Kre2p, suggérant que Ktr6p a une fonction différente. Pour ces raisons, des études cristallographiques sur cette mannosyltransferase présumé sont poursuivies. Ici, nous présentons les méthodes employées pour obtenir la structure finale de Ktr6p à une résolution de 3.11 Å en utilisant la technique de remplacement moléculaire. Une discussion détaillée analysant les résultats obtenus suivra.</description><description>The post-translational addition of sugar moieties onto proteins plays an important role in protein folding, secretion, signaling, and is even thought to partake in cell-cell adhesion. In eukaryotes, the biosynthesis of N-glycans begins with the transfer of Glc3Man9GlcNAc2 to the amide group of an asparagine situated in the tripeptide Asn-X-Thr(Ser), of a protein. Subsequent removal of three glucoses and one mannose occurs in the Endoplasmic Reticulum. In yeast, those proteins that require further maturation, e.g. those destined to enter the secretory pathway, are sent to the cis-Golgi. The core, Man8GlcNAc2, is then decorated with additional mannoses and mannose-1-phosphates. The enzyme responsible for the transfer of mannose-1-phosphate in Saccharomyces cerevisiae is Ktr6p. It is a member of the Kre Two Related family of mannosyltransferases: Kre2p. Ktr6p shares 38% sequence identity with Kre2p, suggesting a similar three-dimensional structure. However, greater than 50% of the residues in the Ktr6p putative active site differ from Kre2p, signifying that Ktr6p may have a modified mannosyltransferase function. For these aforementioned reasons, crystallographic studies on this putative mannosylphosphate transferase are pursued. Here, we present the methods employed to obtain the final Ktr6p crystal structure that has been solved, via molecular replacement, to a resolution of 3.11 Å. A detailed discussion analyzing the results obtained ensues.</description><creator>Marks, Daniella</creator><contributor>Albert Berghuis (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Chemistry - Biochemistry</subject><title>Structural analyses of the putative mannosylphosphate transferase, Ktr6p from «Saccharomyces cerevisiae»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hc612.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rd89t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:js956g184</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le glycérol qui est un sous-produit de la production de biodiesel est devenu une source abondante du carbone. La conversion du glycérol en produits de valeur supérieure est nécessaire pour augmenter la viabilité du processus de la production du biodiesel de point de vue économique. Une conception factorielle complète a été utilisée pour tester les effets de la concentration du glycérol et les conditions de l'espace libre sur la croissance cellulaire et la production de l'éthanol et de l'hydrogène. Les résultats ont montré que l'augmentation de la concentration du glycérol a accéléré la fermentation  ainsi que la production de l'hydrogène a affecté négativement la croissance cellulaire. La production maximale de l'éthanol a eu une valeur de 0.38 g/g de glycérol. Cette valeur a été obtenue avec une concentration de glycérol de 10 g/L avec une membrane comme condition de l'espace libre. L'optimisation statistique a montré que les conditions optimales pour la production d'hydrogène ont été obtenues avec une concentration initiale de  glycérol de 20 g/L avec barbotage initiale de l'espace libre du réacteur et pour l'éthanol avec une concentration initiale de  glycérol de 10 g/L avec une membrane. L'étude a également enquêté la production de l'hydrogène et de l'éthanol par la fermentation du glucose, du glycérol et du glycérol brut en utilisant l'Escherichia coli. Les conditions optimales de la fermentation du glycérol et du glycérol brut n'ont pas été les mêmes concernant la concentration initiale du glycérol, la supplémentation et la vitesse de mélange. La production maximale de l'éthanol en utilisant le glycérol brut a eu une valeur de 0.42 g/g. Cette valeur correspond à 85% de la production maximale de l'éthanol obtenues dans les conditions optimales de la fermentation du glycérol pur.</description><description>As a by-product of biodiesel production, glycerol has now become an abundant and cheap source of carbon.  Conversion of this glycerol to higher value products will increase the economic viability of the biodiesel production process. A full factorial experimental design was used to test the effects of glycerol concentration and headspace conditions on the cell growth, ethanol and hydrogen production were investigated. The results demonstrate that increase of glycerol concentration accelerates fermentation and that hydrogen production negatively affects cell growth. Maximum ethanol yield was obtained with a glycerol concentration of 10 g/L and was 0.38 g/g glycerol under membrane condition headspace.  Statistical optimization showed that optimal conditions are 20 g/L initial glycerol with initial sparging of the reactor headspace for hydrogen production and 10 g/L initial glycerol with a membrane for ethanol. The study also investigated hydrogen and ethanol production from glucose, glycerol and crude glycerol via fermentation using Escherichia coli. The optimal conditions for fermentation of crude glycerol differ from that of pure with respect to initial glycerol concentration, supplementation and mixing speed.   The maximum ethanol yield for crude glycerol was 85% of the maximum yield of ethanol of 0.42 g/g obtained at the optimum conditions of pure glycerol fermentation.</description><creator>Chaudhary, Nida</creator><contributor>Michael O Ngadi (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Benjamin K Simpson (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Engineering - Agricultural</subject><title>Anaerobic fermentation of glycerol by «Escherichia coli K12» for the production of ethanol</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qc57q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956g184</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603qx87v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Planning under uncertainty is an increasingly important research field, and it is clear that the design of robust and scalable algorithms which consider uncertainty is key to the development of effective autonomous and semi-autonomous systems. Partially Observable Markov Decision Processes (POMDPs) offer a powerful mathematical framework for making optimal action choices in noisy and/or uncertain environments. However, integration of the POMDP model with real world applications has been slow due to the high computation cost of exact approaches to POMDP planning. In recent years, point-based POMDP solvers have emerged as efficient methods for providing approximate solutions by planning over a small subset of the belief space. This thesis first provides a survey on many of the proposed point-based POMDP solvers. We then conduct an empirical analysis on the key components of point-based methods, the belief collection and belief updating processes. This is an important contribution, as previous publications on point-based methods have only compared full algorithms, without comparing the underlying processes. As well, we verify the effect of a variety of parameters and optimizations that could be used within a point-based solver. Experiments are conducted on a variety of POMDP environments.</description><description>L'importance grandissante de la recherche dans le domaine de la planification sous incertitude est signe que l'élaboration d'algorithmes robustes et extensibles qui gèrent l'incertitude est un élément clé dans le développement de systèmes autonomes et semi-autonomes efficaces. Les processus de décision markoviens partiellement observables (POMDP) constituent une puissante fondation mathématique pour le choix d'actions optimales dans un environnement incertain. Il a cependant été difficile d'incorporer les POMDPs à des applications réelles, à cause de leur coût de calcul élevé lorsqu'une solution exacte est requise. Récemment, les approches de résolution de POMDPs dites par points, qui planifient sur un petit sous-ensemble de l'état des croyance, se sont révélées être efficaces pour obtenir des solutions approximatives. Le présent m´emoire propose tout d'abord une revue de plusieurs approches par points. Par la suite, une analyse empirique des composantes primordiales des approches par points, de la collecte d'observations, ainsi que du processus de mise à jour de l'état des croyance, est proposée. De plus, les effets de différents paramètres et optimisations liés aux approches par points sont vérifiés. Des expériences sont conduites avec une variété d'environnements de type POMDP.</description><creator>Kaplow, Robert</creator><contributor>Joelle Pineau (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Artificial Intelligence</subject><title>Point-based POMDP solvers: Survey and comparative analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354f63m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603qx87v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128nf171</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cet ouvrage examine les motifs inhérents à la compréhension de la nature du fruit défendu en tentant de démontrer des parallèles entre le raisonnement des interprètes bibliques d'un côté, et celui des artistes de l'autre. Alors que le texte biblique de la Genèse 2:16-17 offre une représentation abstraite en employant vaguement le mot «fruit», les représentations visuelles, elles, présentent inévitablement une image plus concrète et moins générique en illustrant un fruit spécifique. Ma recherche présente ce phénomène d'abstraction et de concrétisation à travers cinq chapitres qui manifestent la juxtaposition entre le texte biblique et son illustration: en premier, la représentation du Jardin d'Éden; en second, l'image des deux arbres, l'Arbre de la Connaissance et l'Arbre de la Vie; en troisième, la présence du Fruit de l'Arbre de la Connaissance dans ces représentations visuelles; en quatrième, son absence; et en cinquième, les références typologiques du Fruit Défendu à travers des scènes du Nouveau Testament.</description><description>This work examines the patterns inherent to the understanding of the nature of the forbidden fruit in an attempt to demonstrate parallels between the reasoning of biblical interpreters, on one hand, and of artists, on the other. While the biblical text, in Gen. 2:16-17, offers an abstract portrayal by vaguely employing the word "fruit," visual representations inevitably present a more concrete and less generic image by illustrating a specific fruit. My research presents this phenomenon of abstraction and concretization through five chapters that exhibit the juxtaposition of the biblical text to its illustration: first, the representation of the Garden of Eden; second, the portrayal of the two trees, the Tree of Knowledge and the Tree of Life; third, the presence of the Fruit of the Tree of Knowledge in those visual depictions; fourth, its absence; and fifth, typological references to the Forbidden Fruit within New Testament scenes.</description><creator>Ovadis, Alyssa</creator><contributor>B Barry Levy (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Religion, Biblical Studies</subject><title>Abstraction and concretization of the Fruit of the Tree of Knowledge of Good and Evil as seen through biblical interpretation and art</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rk72v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nf171</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Jewish Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67jr62t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La programmation orientée aspect a atteint son objectif, la séparation des considérations. Une fois séparées, par contre, ces considérations ne se remboîtent pas toujours parfaitement; certaines, tout simplement incompatibles, se comportent de manière surprenante lorsqu'elles sont utilisées ensemble. Afin de prévenir ces conflits, une approche conservatrice consiste à définir des ensembles d'aspects pour lesquels nous avons la preuve qu'ils sont compatibles les uns avec les autres. Pour obtenir cette preuve, étonnament, il suffit de s'assurer que ces aspects produisent les mêmes effets, qu'ils soient tissés dans un ordre ou dans l'autre. Ce principe est à la base d'une série de preuves permettant de construire, d'étendre et de transformer des ensembles d'aspects à la fois utiles et compatibles.</description><description>Aspect-oriented programming is very good at separating concerns, but a little less at combining them back together; some aspects are simply incompatible, causing unexpected behaviours when used together. To prevent such conflicts, a conservative approach is to construct sets of aspects which are provably guaranteed to be compatible with one another. Surprisingly, to establish that two aspects are compatible, it is enough to show that they yield the same result regardless of the order in which they are woven. This principle can be used to construct, extend and transform sets of useful and compatible aspects.</description><creator>Gélineau, Samuel</creator><contributor>Brigitte Pientka (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Jorg Andreas Kienzle (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>Commutative composition - a conservative approach to aspect weaving</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924c17b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jr62t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440s86j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La modulation de phase est considérée comme l'une des technologies clés pour la prochaine génération des systèmes de communication optiques à haut débit et longue portée, en raison des avantages suivants: (1) A l'aide d'une modulation en phase suivi d'un détecteur balancé, nous obtenus une meilleure sensibilité du récepteur comparé aux formation de modulation en intensité conventionnels, par exemple, une amélioration de la sensibilité de ~3 dB en utilisant une modulation en modulation déplacement phase différentielle (DPSK) et une amélioration de la sensibilité de ~1.3 dB en utilisant une modulation en modulation déplacement phase en quadrature (DQPSK); (2) une tolérance accrue aux effets non-linéaires de la fibre; (3) une efficacité spectrale élevée, si l'on considère les formats de modulation de phase à plusieurs niveaux, comme par exemple la modulation en DQPSK. Puisque l'information est encodée par des changements de phase, ces formats de modulation sont sensibles aux dégradations liées à la phase du signal et aux détériorations provoquées par le processus de conversion phase-intensité. L'objectif de cette thèse est d'identifier les principaux défis associés à leur mise en oeuvre, et de proposer des moyens de mitigation. Le premier défi concerne la pénalité de transmission engendrée par la modulation de phase croisée (XPM), affectant les canaux modulés en phase qui sont adjacents aux canaux à modulation d'intensité. Dans ce cas, la dégradation de performance est provoquée par le fait que les fluctuations d'intensité des canaux voisins modulés en intensité, sont converties en bruit de phase pour les canaux utilisant la modulation de phase. Nous proposons un modèle théorique pour analyser l'effet du phénomène de walk-off et son influence sur  les pénalités provoquées par la XPM. À partir de ce modèle, nous suggérons que l'utilisation de fibres optiques avec une dispersion locale importante ou l'ajout d'une certaine quantité de dispersion résiduelle à chaque section permettrait d'atténuer la pénalité XPM. fr Le deuxième défi est associé au décalage de fréquence dépendant de la polarisation (PDf), qui survient lors de la conversion phase-intensité. La modulation en DPSK repose sur l'utilisation au récepteur d'un interféromètre à délai (DI) Mach-Zehnder dont la sensibilité à la polarisation provoque du PDf, ce qui en retour cause un décalage entre la fréquence d'émission du laser et la sensibilité maximale du DI, dégradant ainsi la qualité du signal DPSK démodulé. Nous avons trouvé que le ratio PDf, définit comme étant PDf/FSR, joue un rôle primordial dans la détermination des performances du démodulateur. Nous étudions également l'influence de l'effet de filtrage optique induit par le PDf pour un démodulateur 40-GHz DPSK sur un signal 40-Gb/s RZ-DPSK. Une dégradation de performance est observée lorsque l'effet de filtrage induit par le PDf est présent. fr Le troisième défi pour les formats de modulation de phase est l'interférence entre symboles provoquées par la dispersion de la fibre. Traditionnellement, la dispersion est compensée en utilisant des modules de compensation de dispersion (DCF). Des techniques plus récentes font appel à des systèmes de compensation de dispersion électroniques (EDC). Ceux-ci, en plus d'éviter l'atténuation induite par les DCF, peuvent simultanément compenser la dispersion chromatique (CD) et la dispersion de polarisation (PMD). Nous étudions les performances de systèmes EDC appliqués à la compensation de la CD et de la PMD, pour un signal NRZ-DPSK en détection directe. Les résultats de simulations indiquent qu'environ 300-ps/nm de CD et 10-ps de DGD peuvent être compensées par l'utilisation de systèmes EDC. Par contre, l'efficacité des EDC est moindre pour les systèmes de modulation par phase que pour les systèmes OOK. Un signal RZ-DPSK est également considéré et l'étude présentée met en relief que l'égaliseur de décision rétroactif (DFE) est plus performant avec ce type de modulation.</description><description>Phase modulation formats are believed to be one of the key enabling techniques for next generation high speed long haul fiber-optic communication systems due to the following main advantages: (1) with a balanced detection, a better receiver sensitivity over conventional intensity modulation formats, e.g., a ~3 dB sensitivity improvement using differential phase shift keying (DPSK) and a ~1.3 dB sensitivity improvement using differential quadrature phase shift keying (DQPSK); (2) excellent robustness against fiber nonlinearities; (3) high spectrum efficiency when using multilevel phase modulation formats, such as DQPSK. As the information is encoded in the phase of the optical field, the phase modulation formats are sensitive to the phase-related impairments and the deterioration induced in the phase-intensity conversion. This consequently creates new challenging issues. The research objective of this thesis is to depict some of the challenging issues and provide possible solutions. The first challenge is the cross-phase modulation (XPM) penalty for the phase modulated channels co-propagating with the intensity modulated channels. The penalty comes from the pattern dependent intensity fluctuations of the neighboring intensity modulated channels being converted into phase noise in the phase modulation channels. We propose a model to theoretically analyze the XPM penalty dependence on the walk off effect. From this model, we suggest that using fibers with large local dispersion or intentionally introducing some residual dispersion per span would help mitigate the XPM penalty. The second challenge is the polarization dependent frequency shift (PDf) induced penalty during the phase-intensity conversion. The direct detection DPSK is usually demodulated in a Mach-Zehnder delay interferometer (DI). The polarization dependence of DI introduces a PDf causing a frequency offset between the laser's frequency and the transmissivity peak of DI, degrading the demodulated DPSK signal. We found that PDf ratio, defined as PDf/FSR, plays a predominant role in determining the performance of the demodulator. We further investigate on the PDf induced penalty for a 40 GHz DPSK demodulator on a 40-Gb/s return-to-zero (RZ)-DPSK signal to study PDf incurred optical filtering effect and spectrum distortion. Degradation for the RZ signal has been found in the presence the PDf. The third challenge is fiber dispersion induced inter-symbol interference for the phase modulated signals. Traditionally the dispersion is compensated using dispersion compensation fibers (DCF). Recently emerged electronic dispersion compensation (EDC) not only avoids the attenuation that would be introduced by DCF, but also is capable of simultaneously compensating the chromatic dispersion (CD) and polarization mode dispersion (PMD). We investigate on EDC's CD and PMD compensation capabilities for the direct detection return-to-zero (NRZ) DPSK signal. The simulation results show that around 300 ps/nm CD and 10 ps differential group delay (DGD) can be compensated by employing EDC. However, compared with the on-off keying (OOK) signal, the EDC is actually less effective with the DPSK signal. The investigation is extended to the RZ-DPSK signal and found out the decision feedback equalizer (DFE) exhibits better performance with the RZ-DPSK signal.</description><creator>Xu, Xian</creator><contributor>David V Plant (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Odile Liboiron-Ladouceur (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Enabling technologies for direct detection optical phase modulation formats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053g47v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440s86j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278t466</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les personnes âgées forment la tranche de la population mondiale dont la croissance est la plus rapide. De plus, l'augmentation de l'espérance de vie grâce aux avancées technologiques en médecine va affecter de façon considérable le système de santé. En effet, le vieillissement de la population implique une diminution des fonctions physiques. Ces diminutions influence la marche et la capacité de se déplacer de façon fonctionnelle et sécuritaire. Une intervention, destinée à améliorer la marche pourrait améliorer la santé et la qualité de vie des personnes âgées fragiles. En premier lieu, une revue structurée de la littérature a été effectuée (Manuscrit 1) afin d'évaluer l'efficacité des programmes couramment utilisés afin d'améliorer la marche chez les personnes âgées. Les banques de données MEDLINE, Embase, CINAHL et Cochrane Library ont permis de trouver des articles anglais ou portugais publiés dans des journaux révisés par les pairs. La taille d'effet de ces programmes de marche ont étés estimés puis illustrés dans un graphique en arbre. Aucun programme de marche n'améliorait significativement l'endurance ou la vitesse de marche. Dans ces études, les programmes avec une taille d'effet importante avaient une puissance statistique faible et les autres programmes avaient une taille d'effet réduite. Afin d'identifier et d'estimer l'efficacité d'interventions destinées à améliorer la marche chez les personnes âgées, d'autres études sont nécessaires. Le second manuscrit a évalué l'efficacité de deux interventions destinées à améliorer la capacité fonctionnelle de marche chez les personnes âgées fragiles. Un projet pilote de type essai clinique randomisé a comparé la marche nordique au programme « overground walking ». Trente participants en provenance de deux centres de réadaptation de la région de Montréal ont été aléatoirement placés dans la marche nordique (n=14) et dans le « overground walking » (n= 16). Pour la marche nordique, la taille d'effet pour le 6MWT était modérée (ES=0.5), celle de vitesse de marche était importante (ES=0.9), et celle pour la peur de chuter était petite (ES=0.4). Pour le « overground walking », la taille d'effet pour le 6MWT était modéré (ES= 0.5). La taille d'effet pour la vitesse de marche était petite (E.S. = 0.4) tout comme celle pour la peur de chuter (E.S = 0.3). Les ratios d'efficacité pour les deux interventions ont démontré qu'en comparaison avec le « overground walking » la marche nordique est 125% plus efficace pour améliorer la vitesse de marche chez les personnes âgées fragiles. D'autres études avec de plus large échantillons sont nécessaires pour corroborer ces résultats.</description><description>The elderly are the fastest growing proportion of the world population. Additional increase in longevity, brought about by improved medical technology, will impact significantly on the health care system as, with advancing age comes a variety of acute and chronic health conditions. No matter how fit, advancing age leads to reduction in mobility and physical function, and these changes, affect quality of gait and the capacity for functional and safe ambulation. With the frail elderly, gait impairments are often severe and impact on health and quality of life. Given that improving walking capacity among the elderly is a desired goal, a structured review was conducted - Manuscript 1 - to derive a global estimate for elderly people of the effectiveness of walking training in improving walking related outcomes. The review included publications on MEDLINE, Embase, CINAHL and the Cochrane Library published in English or Portuguese in peer-reviewed journals. Effect sizes of walking programs in these articles were estimated and forest plotted; there was no overall significant effect of walking training on walking distance or gait speed. Some individual studies showed large effect sizes but were underpowered; others showed small effect sizes. Heterogeneity in population and the nature, frequency and intensity of training indicates that this important question is not yet answered and further research is needed. The second manuscript presents the results of a pilot study designed to provide supporting data for a future trial testing a novel walking training strategy - Nordic style pole walking. The purpose of the pilot study was to estimate, for frail elderly persons undergoing physical rehabilitation, the relative efficacy in improving functional walking capacity of two gait training interventions: Nordic Walking and Overground Walking. A randomized controlled trial of 30 participants from two rehabilitations centers of the Greater Montreal Area was carried out: 14 randomized to Nordic Walking and 16 randomized to Overground Walking. Effect sizes for Nordic Walking were moderate for 6MWT (ES = 0.5), large for gait speed (ES = 0.9), and small for fear of falling (E.S = 0.4). Overground Walking showed moderate effects sizes for 6MWT (ES = 0.5) and small ones for gait speed (E.S = 0.4) and fear of falling (E.S = 0.3). After calculating the effectiveness ratio of both interventions, Nordic Walking was 125% more effective in improving gait speed than regular Overground Walking among a frail elderly population. Future trials with large sample sizes are needed to corroborate these results.</description><creator>Figueiredo, Sabrina</creator><contributor>Nancy Mayo (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - General</subject><title>Nordic Walking: a new training for frail elderly</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21tf86s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278t466</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xd07gt12w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:27:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Possédant un taux de croissance important, la filière éolienne est supposée remplacer des centrales électriques polluantes.  La réduction du nombre de machines synchrones entraîne une diminution du nombre de stabilisateurs de réseau conventionnels menant à une dégradation de l'amortissement des oscillations angulaires critiques d'un réseau ce qui pourra limiter la capacité de transfert de puissance des lignes de transports. Plusieurs rapports indiquent que des oscillations angulaires excessives, causées par un manque d'amortissement, ont contribué ou même étaient à l'origine des pertes de charges, déconnection des alternateurs et des blackouts. La génératrice éolienne, équipée par un contrôleur d'entraînement à vitesse variable, est capable de réguler précisément et rapidement sa puissance active et réactive d'une façon découplée. L'amortissement des oscillations angulaires peut être amélioré en modulant une fraction de la puissance active et/ou réactive des génératrices éoliennes. Des boucles de commandes supplémentaires sont introduites dans la structure de control des éoliennes.  Des limites de modulation de puissance active sont ajoutées pour  respecter les contraintes opérationnelles de vitesse rotationnelle des turbines. Une méthode analytique est développée pour évaluer le potentiel d'amortissement des oscillations de puissances à travers les interconnections, étant donné  le placement d'une ferme éolienne dans un réseau électrique ainsi que le type de modulation. Des indices d'observabilité sont utilisés pour sélectionner les signaux d'entrée du stabilisateur. La fonction de transfert du stabilisateur est dérivée via une optimisation H∞. Le contrôleur est testé dans un réseau  qui consiste de 4 alternateurs séparés en deux zones. Le réseau possède un mode oscillatoire critique qui varie entre 0.4-0.6 Hz.  Les scenarios comprennent des tests pour différents placements du parc éolien, niveaux de puissance du parc, et opérations du réseau. Les résultats démontrent l'efficacité des stabilisateurs des éoliennes à amortir les oscillations angulaires et à contribuer à la stabilisation du réseau.</description><description>Wind energy, increasing its share in the generation mix, is intended to replace fossil fuel plants in order to reduce green house gas emissions. However, the replacement of conventional synchronous units by wind generators reduces the number of online Power Systems Stabilizers (PSS) and may therefore deteriorate the damping of critical swing modes, leading to a reduction of the power transfer capacity in transmission corridors. Several reports indicate that angular instability, due to insufficient damping and inadequate tuning or disabling of power system stabilizers, is one of the major events that lead and/or contributed to wide area blackouts. Variable speed wind turbine generators are capable of fast decoupled real and reactive power control. A damping torque can be generated by modulating a fraction of the real and reactive power output of the wind farm. Supplementary active and reactive power control loops are designed and integrated in the wind turbine controls. Operating limits are added to restrict the kinetic energy exchange of the supplementary control loop within a specified turbine speed. An analytical method is developed in order to assess the effectiveness of real and reactive power modulation in damping inter-area oscillations and to justify the use and commissioning of wind based PSS.  A wide area measurement based power system stabilizer suitable for wind farms is designed and integrated in the global and local controls of wind turbines. Feedback signals are selected based on an observability index of the selected mode(s). The proposed stabilizer transfer function is derived via a constrained H∞ optimization. The controller is tested in time domain simulations using a two area four generators benchmark suffering from interarea oscillatory mode within the range of 0.4-0.6Hz. Testing scenarios show the resiliency and effectiveness of the wind based PSS in damping angular oscillations and stabilizing the power system. The damping contribution of the wind stabilizer is found to be comparable to two conventional PSS.</description><creator>Martinez, Carlos</creator><contributor>Geza Joos (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Energy</subject><title>Design and implementation of power system stabilizers in wind farms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35t898c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gt12w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):44175</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>