<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:14:18Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):6175" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gk010</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:56:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The geomorphic evolution of the northern Rupununi, Guyana, is described and explained. The region, located on the Amazon-Essequibo divide, forms a tectonic depression in the heart of the Guiana Shield; it is characterised by a distinctive geologic individuality and by a unique drainage history. The major physical aspects, including geology, tectonics, climate, geomorphic processes, drainage and relief conditions, are analysed in detail and expressed cartographically wherever possible. The surficial deposits of the region are identified, mapped and their origin and morphology is described and explained. Particular attention is given to the laterites of the region and to the evolution of landform in laterites. It is postulated that dissection of the laterite plateau and lowering of local base level in early- and middle- Pleistocene led to a change in vegetation from former forest to the present savanna. Significance of terrace and dune sands, cobbles and boulders of various rocks, climatic and vegetation change s of the Pleistocene, together with erosion surfaces, are evaluated prior to a summary presentation of the evolution of the northern Rupununi landscape. [* Now Guyana]</description><creator>Sinha, Nawal K. P.</creator><contributor>Bird, J. B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1967</date><subject>Geography</subject><title>Geomorphic Evolution of Northern Rupununi British Guiana</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322h06h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gk010</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fk579</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:56:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This report describes a finite element, structural analysis of a 34' diameter rotary grinding mill. The purpose of this study 1stwo fold. In the framework of computational analysis, the boundary conditions were found to beill posed and, hence, it was necessary to contrive a novel means of adequately representing these conditions. Secondly, it was required to employ the prescribed model for an analysis of the mill under maxlinum loading conditions. Two approaches to the modeling of the boundary conditions are formulated in this report. The results of these analyses are presented 1n the form of stress contour plots for the principal stresses. It is found that both analyses yield realistic over-all stress distributions, with one yielding more accurate stress magnitudes. These magnitudes are substantially lower than the yield strengths of the materials used. </description><creator>Lockhart, Edith A.</creator><contributor>Provan, James W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1985</date><subject>Finite element method</subject><title>The use of the finite element method in the structural analysis of a rotary grinding mill</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43p071b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fk579</identifier><degree><name>Bachelor of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440w270</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:56:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Après une brève introduction dans laquelle nous abordons la critique anglaise et américaine jusqu'en 1967, nous passons en revue tout au long de cette étude, de nombreux écrits se référant a la réception du théâtre de Pirandello de 1968 à 1977 en Grande Bretagne et aux Etats-Unis. La raison du choix de cette date (1968) s'explique par le fait que pour la période précédente nous nous referons a 1 'article d'Antonio Illiano intitule "pirandello in England and the United stated: A Chronological List of Criticism, tt publie en 1967 dans The Bulletin of the New York Public Library, et a celui d 'Auqusto Guidi, ttPirandello in Inghilterra e negli stati Uniti," publie en 1967 dans la revue Lettere Italiane. Enfin, pour rendre la lecture plus aisée, nous avons ajoute un index des noms d'auteurs dont les critiques forment l'objet de la présente étude.</description><description>After a brief introduction in which I discuss the reception of Luigi pirandello's theatre in Great Britain and the united states up to 1967, I examine in detail the contribution of each critic covering a period of ten years from 1968 to 1977. I have chosen 1968 as the starting point because for the preceding period one may consult "Pirandello in England and the united states: A Chronological List of criticsm," written by Antonio Illiano and published in The Bulletin of the New York Public Library in 1967 and "Pirandello in Inghilterra e negli stati uniti," written by Augusto Guidi and published in Lettere Italiane in 1967. To facilitate the reader's task, I have added at the end an index of the names of the authors whose critical contributions form the object of this study.</description><creator>Di Mambro, Evelina.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Teatro di Parandello</subject><title>Il teatro di Pirandello in Gran Bretagna e negli Stati Uniti dal 1968 al 1977 : bibliografia critica</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77ss41c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440w270</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Italian</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dx93z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:56:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Using sport adaptations as a method to facilitate successful inclusion of students with disabilities in physical education has been recommended frequently. A plethora of guidelines, and criteria have also been suggested for adapting sport activities and physical education curriculum to accommodate children of varying abilities. Nevertheless, no study has examined if sport adaptations can meet criteria for successful adaptations; and thus benefit both students with and without disabilities while in the same physical education class. [...] No differences were found concerning the interest/enjoyment variable. However, interviewing the participants suggested that sport adaptations may have had a relatively negative effect on the interest/enjoyment variables of some students that was not captured by thequestionnaire. Age and repetition of the activity were found to have an impact on the effectiveness ofthe adaptations.</description><description>Trouver des adaptations au sport pour faciliter l’intégration d'étudiants handicapes a I ‘éducation physique, a souvent été propose. 8eaucoup d'instructions et de critères ont été suggérées afin d'adapter les activités sportives et les cours d'éducation physique pour accueillir les enfants possédant des capacités différentes. Pourtant, aucune étude n'a examiné ces adaptations en pratique dans les centres sportifs, étant donc impossible pour eux de mesurer le vrai degré de succès que ces adaptations ont eu entre tous les élevés d'une même classe, handicapes ou non.[…] Aucune différence n'a été trouvé concernant intérêt et enthousiasme des enfants entre les deux types de jeux. Cependant, les entrevues ont révèle que certains enfants réagissaient d'une manière relativement négative a ces adaptations, mais cette nuance n'était pas retranscrite par le questionnaire. Et un effet, rage et la répétition de ce jeu ont eu un impact sur l’efficacité de ces adaptations.</description><creator>Kalyvas, Vassilis</creator><contributor>Reid, Greg (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Physical Education</subject><title>Effects of sport adaptations on particpation and interest-enjoyment of students with and without disabilities</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430723f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dx93z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vk335</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:56:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'infection de cellules hôtes par les virus mène à l'activation de plusieurs facteurs de transcription impliques dans la réponse de l‘hôte à l’infection. Parmi ces facteurs se trouve le facteur de transcription interferon regulatory factor 3 (IRF-3) qui est modifié de façon post traductionnelle suite à l'infection virale; la phosphorylation de l'IRF·3 cytoplasmique et inactif lui permet de dimeriser, de migrer du cytoplasme vers le noyau Oll il s'associe au coactivateur CBP/p300, se lie à l'ADN et stimule la transcription de gènes cibles. Sa phosphorylation mène éventuellement à sa dégradation par le proteasome. […]Donc, l'activation d'IRF-3 permettrait une réponse immédiate à I ‘infection virale qui passe par l'établissement d'un état antiviral dans les cellules voisines, l'attraction du système immunitaire au site d'infection et l'élimination des cellules infectées par apoptose. La génération de souris déficientes pour le gène IRF-3 et I ‘identification des voies de signalisation impliquées dans son activation par l'infection virale procureront de nouveaux indices quant au rôle que joue IRF-3 lors de l'infection par le virus.</description><description>Infection of host cells by viruses leads to the activation of multiple transcription factors that are involved in the host response to the infection. Among these factors is the interferon regulatory factor 3 (IRF-3) transcription factor which is post translationally modified as a result of virus infection; phosphorylation of latent cytoplasmic IRF-3 leads to its dimerization, cytoplasmic to nuclear translocation, association with the p300/CBP coactivator and stimulation of DNA binding and transcriptional activities. IRF-3 phosphorylation ultimately results in its degradation via the ubiquitin-proteasome pathway.[...] Activation of IRF-3 would therefore allow an immediate early response to virus infection that involves the stimulation of the antiviral response in neighboringcells, attraction of the immune system to the site of infection and the elimination of virally infected cells by apoptosis. In the future, generation of IRF-3 deficient mice and identification of the signal transduction pathway involved in virus induced IRF-3 activation will provide new insights into the functions of lRF-3.</description><creator>Heylbroeck, Christophe</creator><contributor>Hiscott, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology</subject><title>Regulation of cytokines gene activation in virus infected cells by interferon regulatory factor 3</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42nb39z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vk335</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:12579v85p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:56:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La présente étude se veut une réflexion critique sur l'approche dite «scientifique» de la planification urbaine dans des pays en développement, prenant comme exemple le Brésil. Nous examinons d'abord l'utilité d'une telle approche dans le contexte urbain particulier de ces pays, afin d'évaluer dans queue mesure elle contribue en fait à la dégradation urbaine évidente. Nous considérons ensuite les reforme structurelles possibles pour répondre à la situation chaotique existante, notamment la question de la participation publique dans le processus de planification. A notre avis, une telle mesure est importante pour contrer l'une des causes principales de la ségrégation socio-spatiale dans des villes du sud, à savoir: l'aliénation du publique dans le processus de planification. Nous examinons de près deux exemples de participation publique: celle prévue par la Lo; sur l'aménagement du territoire de l'Ontario, Canada, et celle de la planification budgétaire participative de Porto Alegre, Brésil Nous terminons avec quelques observations sur les tendances actuelles en droit urbain face au phénomène de la globalisation. </description><description>This study is a critical reflection about the 'scientific' approach to urban planning in the context of developing countries, and Brazil in particular. It first examines the usefulness of such an approach to the Third World reality, and tries to assess the extent to which it in fact contributes to the degradation that one sees. The study then considers what sort of structural refonns might be undertaken to change this chaotic situation, with particular emphasis on public participation in the planning process. In our view, this is an important measure to respond to one ofthe leading causes ofsocio-spatial exclusion in southern cities: that is, alienation of the public from the planning process. Two concrete examples of public participation are examined as case studies: the procedure provided under the Planning Act of Ontario, Canada, and the participatory budget planning process practised in Porto Alegre, Brazil. We conclude with some observations about trends in planning law in the face ofthe phenomenon ofglobalization.</description><creator>Filho, Carlos Alberto Amin</creator><contributor>Matthews Glenn, Jane (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Law</subject><title>Planning law and developing needs, an artificial paradox : a study on traditional and participatory planning in the south</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w720q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579v85p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74ct07h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:56:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Drosophila melanogaster gene, Polar granule component (Pgc) encodes an RNA that localizes to the polar granules and subsequently to the pole cells ofearlY4r embryos. Pgc has an essential role in pole cell migration; however, its exact mode of function is not known. The major transcript is 0.7 Idlobases (kb) and contains five putative ORFs. Ofthese five only one ORF is in a good context for translation initiation. This putative ORF encodes a 46 amino acid polypeptide, but has poor Drosophila codon usage suggesting that Pgc may encode for a non-translatable RNA. [...] Moreover, all the potential polypeptides show poor codon usage. Both these factors give further evidence that the Pgc transcript is not translated. In addition, I present the initial identification oftwo proteins (120 kDa and 50 kDa, respectively) that interact specifically with the Pgc RNA.</description><description>Chez la mouche Drosophila melanogaster, le gène Polar granules component (Pgc) code pour un ARN qui se trouve localise dans les granules polaires et qui, par la suite, se trouve localise dans les cellules polarisées chez les jeunes einbryons. Pgc"p)ue un rôle essentiel dans la migration des cellules polarisées. Cependant, son mode d'action précis demeure inconnu. Le transcrit le plus abondant est d'une longueur de 0.7 kilobases (kb) et contient cinq cadres de lecture ouverts. Parmi ceux-ci, un seul cadre de lecture ouvert se trouve dans un contexte propice à I'initiation de la traduction. Ce cadre de lecture ouvert putatif code pour un polypeptide de 46 acides aminés, mais utilise des codons qui ne sont pas typiques de la Drosophile, ce qui suggère que Pgc pourrait coder pour un ARN non traduisible. […]De plus, tous les polypeptides potentiels utilisent des codons non-typiques de la Drosophile. Ces deux aspects apportent de l'évidence supplémentaire à l'hypothèse que le transcrit de Pgc n'est pas traduit. Je présente aussi l'identification initiale de deux protéines (50 kDa et 120 kDa) qui interagissent spécifiquement avec l'ARN de Pgc.</description><creator>Chikarmane, Rashmi</creator><contributor>Lasko, Paul (Supervisor) </contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology</subject><title>Interspecific analysis of the D. melanogaster gene Polar granule component</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gn57r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74ct07h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j6731658x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:56:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis we use a modular form constructed by Zagier[Z] together with the Lindelof hypothesis to find first an estimate of the order of magnitude of the Fourier coefficent of a cusp form of weight k for the full modular group, when k = 12,16, 18,20,22 and 26. Then we will explore other applications of this cusp form to the L-function attached to the symmetric square of the modular form.</description><description>Dans cette thèse, nous utilisons une forme modulaire construite par Zagier avec l'hypothèse de Lindelof pour trouver une borne pour les coefficients de Fourier d'une forme parabolique de poids k pour la groupe modulaire, quand k = 12, 16, 18,20,22, et 26. Aussi, nous donnons d'autres applications de cette forme parapolique de Zagier. En particulier, nous considérons la fonction L attachée avec le carre symétrique d'une forme modulaire.</description><creator>Hashim, Ashwaq</creator><contributor>Murty, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Lindelöf hypothesis</subject><title>Application of Lindelöf hypothesis to Cusp forms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j148f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j6731658x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mq045</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:56:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Several computational methods were applied with the aim of studying their performance in calculating the highly unsteady two-dimensional flow and heat transfer past a circular cylinder. The present numerical investigation is concerned with the flow and heat transfer both near to and for from the cylinder over a wide range of Reynolds numbers (Re 200, 1000,2400,5000, 8290, and 15550). The computations were carried out using a stream function-vorticity and thermal energy formulation. The well established finite-volume method furnished the discretisation equations for both vorticity and heat transport. A grid in polar coordinates is selected such that the resolution of its smallest cell is based on the boundary layer thickness at the cylinder's front stagnation point.[...] At the same time, the simulations of the complex behaviour of a fully developed wake far from the cylinder greatly depend on the numerical methodology and strategy. The detailed comparison of these numerical results obtained from the different methodologies and strategies with the available experimental data are presented in this thesis.</description><description>Plusieurs méthodes numériques ont été appliquées afin d’étudier leur performance pour le calcul de l'écoulement transitoire et le transfert de chaleur sur un cylindre circulaire à deux dimensions. Cette étude porte à la fois sur l'écoulement et les transferts de chaleur à Proxima et loin du cylindre pour un ensemble de nombres de Reynolds (Re = 200, 1000, 2400, 5000, 8290 and 15550). La tache de calcul a été accomplie à l'aide d'une fonction de courant et une formulation adéquate pour la température. La méthode des volumes finis a permis de discrétiser les équations de transport des tourbillons et de températures. Une grille en coordonnées polaires a été choisie de telle sorte que la résolution de la plus petite cellule soit basée sur l'épaisseur de la couche limite au niveau du point de stagnation en amont du cylindre. [...] Par ailleurs, les simulations du comportement complexe d'un écoulement établi loin en amont du cylindre ont montré qu’elles étaient très dépendantes de la méthode numérique de résolution et de la stratégie employées. La comparaison détaillée des données expérimentales disponibles avec les résultats numériques, obtenus à l'aide de différentes méthodes et stratégies, est présentée dans cette thèse.</description><creator>Bouharie, Salem</creator><contributor>Chu, Vincent H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2005</date><subject>Applied Mechanics</subject><title>Computational methods for calculating heat transfer from a circular cylinder in a cross flow</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xf23t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mq045</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q678j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:57:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Heat pipes have been investigated, developed and applied in many industrial fields since their inception in 1964. However, the area of heat pipe technology is still a new topic in the metallurgical industry. This study focused on applying heat pipes as cooling devices to protect injection lances in pyrometallurgical operations. [...] Steelmaking, copper converting, and silver refining experiments featuring the heat pipe cooled injection lance in vertical and several inclined positions have been carried out. When compared with water-cooled lances for oxygen injection, this kind of lance has many advantages such as reduced operating cost, enhanced energy efficiency, greater control and flexibility, and it is safer to operate. Finally, a mathematical model for this new generation of heat pipe cooled injection lance was formulated and tested.</description><description>Les caloducs ont été étudies, développés et utilises dans de nombreux domaines industriels depuis leur invention en 1964. Cependant, ils restent toujours peu employés dans le domaine de la métallurgie. Il s'agit ici d'étudier la possibilité d'utiliser les caloducs comme moyen de refroidissement pour protéger les lances d'injection dans les opérations pyrometallurgiques.[…] Par comparaison avec des lances a oxygène refroidies par eau, ce type de lance présente de nombreux avantages; réduction des couts d'opération, augmentation du rendement énergétique, meilleur contrôle, plus grande flexibilité et augmentation la sécurité de travail.  Enfin, un modèle mathématique pour cette nouvelle génération de caloducs a été proposé et teste.</description><creator>Jin, Ning </creator><contributor>Mucciardi, Frank (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Mining</subject><title>Heat pipe cooled injection lances : experimenal investigation and mathematical modeling</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462792r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q678j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278w95j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:57:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>To investigate the mechanisms regulating axonemal motility, a panel of monoclonal antibodies (MoAb) against axonemal proteins from Chlamydomonas reinhardtii has been prepared. MoAb L2 and L3 each recognized a 110 kDa protein and were shown to cause a marked decrease in the percentage of motile demembranatedreactivated Chlamydomonas. In contrast, MoAb L6 recognized a 34 kDa protein and decreased flagellar beat frequency. Studies on Chlamydomonas mutants showed that the L2 and L3 antigens were located on the stem and head of the radial spokes, respectively, while the L6 antigen was localized directly on microtubules. Screening a cDNA expression library using MoAb L6 allowed the detection of a cDNA encoding for the L6 antigen. Our results suggest that each of antigens recognized by these three MoAbs is involved in axonemal motility.</description><description>Pour étudier les mécanismes régulateurs de la mobilité axonemale, une série d'anticorps monoc1onaux (AcMo) a été produite contre les protéines axonemales de Chlamydomonas reinhardtii. Les AcMo L2 et L3 ont tous deux reconnu une protéine de 110 kDa et ont fortement diminue le pourcentage de mobilité de Chlamydomonas de membranes-reactives. Par contre, I' AcMo L6 a reconnu une protéine de 34 kDa et a diminué la fréquence de battement flagellaire. Les études sur les mutants de chlamydomonas ont démontré que les antigènes L2 et L3 sont situés sur la tige et la tête des ponts radiaires, respectivement, tandis que l'antigène L6 est situé directement sur les microtubules. En utiIisant I'AcMo L6, le criblage d'une banque de cDNA a pennis la détection d'un insert de cDNA codant pour l'antigène L6. Nos résultats démontrent que les antigènes reconnues par ces trois AcMos sont impliques dans la mobilité axonemale.</description><creator>Aghigh, Soroush</creator><contributor>Gagnon, Claude (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology</subject><title>eCharacterization of novel axonemal proteins that modulate the motility of Chlamydomonas reinhardtii flagella</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hf80p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278w95j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227ms42r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:57:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Purpose: Posterior capsule opacification (PCO) is the most common complication after cataract surgery, affecting up to 50% of patients 2-5 years post-operatively. Epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition (EMT) is the main pathophysiology underlying PCO. Metformin, a drug with an excellent safety profile used primarily for diabetes, has been shown to suppress EMT. The objective of this study was to test the effectiveness of metformin in inhibiting EMT in an in vitro model of PCO. Methods: The human lens epithelial cell (LEC) line HLE-B3 was exposed to transforming growth factor-beta (TGF-β) and fibroblast growth factor (FGF) to induce EMT. Subsequently, the effect of metformin on the following cellular parameters were determined: (1) survival, using a viability assay and drug concentrations ranging from 0-100 mM; (2) expression of epithelial (Pax6, E-cadherin) and mesenchymal (α-smooth muscle actin or α-SMA, fibronectin) markers via Western blot; (3) morphology, via microscopy and image analysis; (4) and migration, using the wound assay. The presence of the metformin uptake receptor SLC22A1 in the cell line and the ratio of active to inactive protein kinase B (pAkt/Akt) were assessed via Western blot. SLC22A1 expression was confirmed with immunohistochemistry on donor eyes. Statistical analysis of variance (ANOVA) with Tukey post-hoc test was done for analysis of cytotoxicity, morphology and migration data. Results: Metformin is lethal to half (LC50) and all cells at 30 and 80 mM, respectively. A decrease in viability (P&lt;0.05) was noted at 5 mM. Compared to untreated cells, EMT-induced LECs treated with 1 mM metformin showed increased Pax6 and E-cadherin and decreased α-SMA and fibronectin expression. LECs treated with metformin also maintained the roundness and circularity consistent with an epithelial phenotype. In addition, migration was significantly inhibited with 0.5 mM metformin (P&lt;0.05). The HLE-B3 cell line and lens ocular epithelium in donor eyes were found to express SLC22A1, and treated HLE-B3 cells showed a decreased pAkt/Akt ratio. Conclusion: Metformin inhibits EMT in LECs, decreasing survival and migration and maintaining the epithelial phenotype. These findings suggest that metformin entry into the cell is through the SLC22A1 receptor, and its action mediated via decreased Akt activation. Metformin thus has potential as an adjunct to treatment. Toxicity to proximal eye tissues and effectiveness in vivo must be tested to determine dose, route and timing of administration.</description><description>Objectif: L'Opacification de la capsule postérieure (OCP) est la complication la plus courante suite à la chirurgie d'une cataracte et affecte environ la moitié des patients dans les 2-5 années suivant l'opération. Un phénomène appelé transition épithéliale-à-mésenchymale (TEM) est le principal mécanisme sous-jacent l'OCP. La metformin, un médicament principalement utilisé chez les diabétiques et ayant un excellent profil thérapeutique, est reconnue pour sa capacité d'inhibition de la TEM. L'objectif de cette étude est de vérifier et prouver l'efficacité de la metformin à inhiber la TEM dans un modèle in vitro d'OCP. Méthodologie: Une lignée de cellules épithéliales du cristallin humain, HLE-B3, fut exposée à des facteurs de croissance bêta (TGF-β) ainsi que des facteurs de croissance de fibroblastes (FGF) afin d'induire la transition épithéliale-à-mésenchymale. Par la suite, les effets de la metformin ont été déterminés selon les paramètres suivants : (1) la survie, utilisant un test de viabilité et des concentrations de metformin allant de 0-100mM ; (2) l'expression de marqueurs épithéliaux (Pax6, E-cadhérine) et mésenchymaux (α-SMA, fibronectine) mesurée par Western-Blot ; (3) la morphologie, par microscopie et analyse d'image; (4) et la migration cellulaire, par le test de migration. La présence du récepteur de metformin SLC22A1 ainsi que le ratio de protéine kinase B active (pAkt/Akt) fut vérifiée dans la lignée cellulaire par Western-blot. L'expression de SLC22A1 fut aussi confirmée par immunohistochimie sur des yeux de donneurs post-mortem. Le test statistique d'analyse de la variance (ANOVA) ainsi que le test Tukey post-hoc ont été effectués sur les données d'analyse de cytotoxicité, de morphologie et de migration cellulaire. Résultats: La metformin est létale pour la moitié (LC50) et la totalité des cellules à 30 et 80mM, respectivement. Un déclin de la viabilité (p&lt;0.05) fut noté à 5mM. En comparaison aux cellules non-traitées, les cellules épithéliales de cristallin pour lesquelles la TEM a été induite et ensuite traitées avec 0.5mM de metformin, montrent une augmentation de l'expression de Pax-6 et E-cadhérine ainsi qu'une diminution de l'expression de α-SMA et fibronectine. Les cellules traitées avec la metformin maintiennent aussi leur rondeur et leur circularité, ce qui est consistant avec un phénotype de cellules épithéliales. De plus, la migration des cellules fut inhibée de façon significative avec 0.5mM de metformin (p&lt;0.05). La lignée cellulaire HLE-B3 montre un déclin du ratio pAkt/Akt lorsque traités avec la metformin. Enfin, l'expression du récepteur à metformin SLC22A1 a été confirmée dans le modèle cellulaire in vitro ainsi que in situ avec des yeux de donneurs post-mortem. Conclusion: La metformin a la capacité d'inhiber la TEM dans une lignée de cellules épithéliales de cristallin ; causant un déclin de la survie et de la migration de celles-ci, tout en maintenant leur phénotype original. En somme, ces résultats suggèrent que la metformin entre dans les cellules via le récepteur SLC22A1 et que son action est médiée par une baisse de l'activation de Akt. Ainsi, la metformin pourrait potentiellement être administrée en tant qu'adjuvant lors de chirurgies des cataractes. La toxicité au niveau oculaire et péri-oculaire ainsi que l'efficacité de la metformin restent à déterminer afin d'établir quelles doses, voies et fréquences d'administration seront à recommander.</description><creator>Lasiste, Jade Marie Edenvirg</creator><contributor>Miguel Noel Burnier (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Pathology</subject><title>Metformin inhibits epithelial-to-mesenchymal transition in lens epithelial cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150m575.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227ms42r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514np05v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:57:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Extrusion is a high shear, high temperature processing technique that involves a short time treatment to transform raw materials to intermediate or finished products to enhance sensory and other quality attributes. Most extruded snacks prepared using starch based blends are usually high in carbohydrates but low in other vital nutrients. Snack food consumption is ever increasing and has resulted in demand for producing healthy snack foods by replacing the starch with protein, fiber and other nutrients. The overall objective of this research was to prepare nutritious extruded snack foods by partially replacing rice flour with green lentil and chickpea flours and tomato powder.         Using the D-optimal mixture design different feed mixtures formulations were obtained and prepared using rice flour (33-60%), green lentil flour (20-45%), chickpea flour (10-30%), tomato powder (0-7%) and added moisture. These were subjected to extrusion processing at a preset screw speed of 125 rpm and barrel temperature profile progressively increasing from 80⁰C at the entrance to 140⁰C at the exit. The semi-moist extrudates were air dried at 55⁰C at 0.1 m/s air flow rate to reduce their water activity to &lt; 0.75 for stability. From the drying data, moisture diffusion coefficients and drying times were computed. The physicochemical properties of dried extrudates were evaluated. Lentil and chickpea flours added to the feed mix enhanced the protein content of the product while lentil and tomato powders contributed to improving the antioxidant activity. Added lentil flour also decreased the diffusion coefficient and hence increased the drying time. The extrusion processing led to the reduction of anti-nutrients present in pulse flours by more than 80%.          In the second phase of study, sensorial and physico-chemical properties of the extrudates were enhanced using conventional deep frying or dry roasting using microwave. Deep frying was done at 200±1 ⁰C for 70 s while microwave roasting was carried out in a domestic MW oven (1000 W) carried at 75% power level for 50 s. The frying and roasting processes significantly influenced the product properties. Addition of chickpea flour significantly decreased the expansion ratio while increasing the b* value of the products. Lentil flour and tomato powder increased breaking stress value. Sensory properties of the products were enhanced with both frying and MW roasting. Expansion ratio and L* value had strong positive correlation with overall product acceptability. Microwave roasting resulted in better retention of antioxidants than the frying process.        Overall, the research contributed to better understanding of the extrusion process involving rice flour blends enriched with lentil flour, chickpea flour and tomato powder. A high protein snack with good sensory properties was prepared with help of extrusion followed by drying and frying or microwave roasting. The results obtained demonstrated that microwave roasting in combination with extrusion processing produced more nutritious and healthier snack as compared to frying.</description><description>L'extrusion est un procédé de cisaillement à haute température qui implique un traitement de courte durée dans le but transformer les matières premières en produits intermédiaires ,en produits finis, ou dans le but d'améliorer les propriétés sensorielles et autres qualités des produits finis. La plupart des collations extrudées, préparées à l'aide de mélanges à base d'amidon, sont souvent riches en glucides mais faibles en nutriments essentiels. L'accroissement de la consommation de ces collations aboutie a une augmentation de la demande pour des produits plus sains, dans lesquels l'amidon serait remplacé par des protéines, des fibres et d'autres nutriments. Le but de cette recherche était de préparer des collations extrudées nutritives en remplaçant partiellement la farine de riz par des farines de lentilles vertes et de de pois chiche et par de la poudre de tomate.En utilisant le system de conception de mélange D-optimal, différents mélanges d'aliments ont été préparés avec notamment de la farine de riz (33-60%), de la farine de lentilles vertes (20-45%), de la farine de pois chiche (10-30%), de la poudre de tomate (0-7%) et de l'humidité ajoutée. Ces mélanges ont été soumis à un traitement par extrusion à une vitesse de rotation de la vis de 125 tr/min et à un profil de température du fût augmentant progressivement de 80°C à l'entrée à 140°C à la sortie. Les extrudés semi-humides ont été séchés à l'air à 55°C avec un débit d'air de 0.1 m/s pour réduire leur activité d'eau à 0.75 afin de les stabiliser. À partir des données de séchage, les coefficients de diffusion de l'humidité et les temps de séchage ont été calculés. Les propriétés physico-chimiques des extrudés séchés ont été évaluées. Les farines de lentilles et de pois chiches ajoutées au mélange ont augmenté la teneur en protéines du produit tandis que les poudres de lentilles et de tomates ont amélioré l'activité antioxydante de celui-ci. L'ajout de la farine de lentilles a également diminué le coefficient de diffusion et, par conséquent, a augmenté le temps de séchage. Le traitement par extrusion a conduit à la diminution des antinutriments présents dans les farines de plus de 80%.    Dans une seconde phase de la recherche, les propriétés sensorielles et physico-chimiques des extrudats ont été améliorées en utilisant la friture traditionnelle ou la torréfaction sèche au micro-ondes. La friture a été effectuée à une temperature de 200 ± 1°C pendant 70 s, tandis que la cuisson au micro-ondes a été effectuée dans un four a micro-ondes domestique (puissance nominale W 1000) portée à un niveau de puissance de 75% pendant 50 s. Les processus de friture et de torréfaction ont influencé de façon significative les propriétés du produit. L'ajout de farine de pois chiche a considérablement diminué le taux d'expansion tout en augmentant la valeur b* des produits. La farine de lentilles et la poudre de tomate ont augmenté la valeur de résistance à la rupture. Les propriétés sensorielles des produits ont été améliorées avec la friture et la torréfaction au micro-ondes. Le rapport d'expansion et la valeur L * présentaient une corrélation positive forte avec l'acceptabilité globale du produit. La cuisson au four à micro-ondes a conduit à  une meilleure rétention des antioxydants que le processus de friture.      Dans son ensemble, la recherche a contribué à une meilleure compréhension du procédé d'extrusion impliquant des mélanges de farine de riz enrichis avec de la farine de lentilles, de la farine de pois chiche et de la poudre de tomate. Une collation riche en protéines et ayant de bonnes propriétés sensorielles a été préparée grâce a une extrusion suivie d'un séchage et d'une friture ou bien d'une cuisson au four à micro-ondes. Les résultats obtenus durant cette étude ont démontré que le traitement par extrusion utilisé avec la cuisson au four à micro-onde produisait un produit plus nutritif et plus sain qu'un traitement  alliant le procédé d'extrusion a la friture.</description><creator>Singh, Prabhjot</creator><contributor>Hosahalli Ramaswamy (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</subject><title>Functional extruded products from rice flour, pulse flour and tomato powder blends</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322h07s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514np05v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rb68xf243</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:57:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le système immunitaire inné est très important pour défendre l'hôte contre l'infection virale. Les protéines induites par l'interféron avec des répétitions de tetratricopepetide (IFIT) sont le point culminant d'une cascade de signalisation qui se trouve à restreindre l'infection virale. Les IFIT ont nombreux membres dans différentes espèces, et je travaille avec les protéines Ifit1 et Ifit1b chez la souris et le lapin. Les protéines IFIT reconnaissent l'ARN viral avec simple brin et l'ARN auto de différentes manières, et IFIT1b le fait sur la base de la 5'-modification des ARN. IFIT1b peut seulement se lier qu'à l'ARN viral qui porte un triphosphate ou qui a une méthylation N-7 mais sans méthylation 2'-O du premier nucléotide. Cette liaison peut entrer en compétition avec la liaison de eIF4E avec l'ARNm, ce qui est crucial pour la traduction d'ARNm et, par conséquent, éliminer l'infection virale.L'IFIT1 humain a été étudié depuis longtemps, mais IFIT1b, qui était d'abord pensé être étroitement lié à IFIT1, sa structure n'a pas été résolue. Dans cette étude, je cherche à cristalliser la protéine Ifit1b et sa liaison avec l'ARN chez la souris et le lapin, afin d'étudier le noyau de liaison de Ifit1b et ses préférences nucléotidiques. Puisque chez humain, les structures 3D de l'IFIT5, IFIT2, IFIT1 N-terminal et IFIT5 se liant avec l'ARN triphosphate ont été résolues, et les structures de la liaison IFIT1 humaine avec l'ARN coiffé et différentes modifications 5 'seront publiées prochainement, ces structures ont m'a fourni des renseignements directeurs sur mes recherches.</description><description>The innate immune system is very important to defend the host from viral infection. Interferon-Induced proteins with Tetratricopeptide repeats (IFITs) are the culmination of a signaling cascade that is found to restrict the viral infection. IFITs have many members in different species, and I'm working with the Ifit1b proteins from mice and rabbits. IFIT proteins recognize viral single-stranded RNA from self RNA in different ways, and IFIT1b does this on the basis of RNAs' 5'-modifications. That is, IFIT1b can only bind to the viral RNA that bears a triphosphate or that has an N-7 methylation but without 2'-O methylation of the first nucleotide. This binding can compete with eIF4E binding with mRNA, which is crucial for mRNA translation, and as a result eliminate viral infection. Human IFIT1 has been studied for a long time, but IFIT1b, which was first thought to be closely related to IFIT1, has not been structurally solved. In this study, I aim to crystallize Ifit1b protein and its complex with ppp-RNA in mice and rabbits, in order to study the binding core of Ifit1b and its nucleotide preferences. Since the 3D structures of human IFIT5, IFIT2, N-terminal IFIT1, and IFIT5 binding with triphosphate RNA have been solved, and the structures of human IFIT1 binding with capped-RNA and different 5'-modifications will be published soon, these structures have provided me with directive information on my research.</description><creator>Wang, Hongyu</creator><contributor>Bhushan Nagar (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Biochemistry</subject><title>Structural studies of the IFIT proteins and the IFIT-RNA complex</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g988r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xf243</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gh93h209b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:57:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le cancer de la prostate (CaP), comme de nombreux cancers, évolue par l'incursion de nombreuses mutations somatiques et subit de multiples processus de sélection, aboutissant à une hétérogénéité génétique étendue résultant à une résistance aux médicaments. L'intervention thérapeutique biologique, le plus souvent par des médicaments ciblant des androgènes, peut conduire à la sélection de tumeurs plus agressives qui peuvent à terme se transformer en cancer résistant aux médicaments. De plus, les traitements chirurgicaux et/ou radiologiques peuvent également aggraver la situation par d'autres effets secondaires. Nous avons par conséquent développé une nouvelle approche thérapeutique en utilisant des nanoparticules ciblées qui agissent en photo-ablation physique qui contournerait et surmonterait les limites présentées par les options de traitements actuels. Récemment, des nanoparticules composées de différents matériaux ont été largement appliquées dans le développement de nouvelles thérapies contre le cancer. Parmi les nanoparticules disponibles, les nanotubes de carbone à parois multiples (MWCNTs) offrent des propriétés uniques telles qu'une stabilité chimique, une grande disponibilité en surface, ainsi qu'une absorption et une conductivité efficaces de l'énergie thermique et électrique. Lorsque ces nanoparticules sont combinées avec un fragment de ciblage, tel qu'un anticorps ou des molécules similaires, elles peuvent être utilisées pour distribuer une «énergie» hautement localisée à proximité immédiate des cellules et peuvent causer des dommages cellulaires importants. C'est pour ces différentes raisons que nous avons utilisé les MWCNTs en conjugaison avec un anticorps contre l'antigène de membrane spécifique de la prostate (PSMA), un marqueur de surface cellulaire pour CaP progressif, pour le ciblage photo-ablatif actif. Dans nos études in vitro, en utilisant les cellules du cancer de la prostate LNCaP positives pour PSMA, nous avons pu obtenir plus de 80% d'ablation tumorale avec une exposition de 30 secondes en utilisant un laser à longueur d'onde de 532 nm de 2.7 W/cm2. En outre, la spécificité et la sélectivité du ciblage de PSMA ont été confirmées en évaluant sous les mêmes conditions la lignée cellulaire PC3 qui n'expriment pas de PSMA. Ces résultats confirment également notre capacité à surmonter certaines limites présentées par la photo-thermothérapie traditionnelle. Le développement de cette nouvelle technique apportera sans aucun doute un véritable changement dans l'approche des modalités thérapeutiques actuelles et ouvrira une nouvelle ère de traitement efficace contre le cancer, en s'attaquant directement à l'hétérogénéité tumorale. Finalement, une revue de la littérature a été réalisée pour générer une liste des nanoparticules actuellement disponibles en nanomédecine, à la fois comme agent photothermique et comme vecteur de distribution du médicament. De ce fait, l'évaluation des différents nanomatériaux se fera en même temps que l'analyse du rôle émergent des nanoparticules dans l'environnement clinique potentiel.</description><description>Prostate cancer (CaP), like many cancers, evolves through the incursion of numerous somatic mutations and undergoes multiple selection processes, resulting in extensive genetic heterogeneity, ultimately leading to drug resistance. Many times, biological therapies lead to the selection of more aggressive cancers. Moreover, surgical or radiological treatments are also compounded by other physical side-effects. Therefore, a new generation of therapeutic approaches that would circumvent or overcome such limitations presented by current treatment options is essential. Recently, many types of nanoparticles have been applied broadly in the development of novel cancer therapies. Of the available nanoparticles, multi-walled carbon nanotubes (MWCNTs) offer unique properties such as chemical stability, efficient thermal and electrical energy absorption and conductivity, and extensive surface area availability. When combined together with a targeting moiety, MWCNTs may be used to deliver highly-localized "energy" (via a laser) in the immediate proximity to the cells and can cause significant cellular damage, thus making them an ideal physical therapeutic platform. Therefore, functionalizing the MWCNTs by conjugating antibody against prostate specific membrane antigen (PSMA), a marker for progressive CaP, on their surface would be an effective approach for active targeting. In the in vitro studies using PSMA positive LNCaP prostate cancer cells, over 80% cell ablation was achieved within a 30 second exposure to low 2.7 W/cm2 532nm wavelength laser. Furthermore, the specificity and selectivity of PSMA targeting was confirmed by assessing PSMA-null PC3 cell lines under the same conditions (&lt;10% cell ablation), thereby overcoming some of limitations in the conventional photothermal therapy. Developing this new platform will undoubtedly bring a real change vs. current therapeutic modalities and will usher in a new age of effective cancer treatment, by squarely addressing tumoral heterogeneity. </description><creator>Lee, Seung Soo</creator><contributor>Miltiadis Paliouras (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Targeted nanotherapy for prostate cancer: applications for cancer therapeutics and imaging</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t889p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h209b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j67316596</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:57:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An interpretive phenomenological research approach was chosen to explore the meaning of living with chronic orofacial pain. Individual interviews were conducted with 6 participants experiencing chronic pain and undergoing treatment at a pain clinic. The interviews were transcribed verbatim and interpreted phenomenologically. Interpretive phenomenology is a qualitative research approach that attempts to investigate people's experiences to reveal what lies 'hidden' in them. This approach was used because of the empirical nature of the present topic. Three essential findings were identified: 1) Suffering from loss, 2) Disbelief, and 3) Dissatisfaction with health care. The first finding highlights the effect of chronic pain on the lives of participants. This includes loss of relationships, employment, the ability to enjoy eating, engaging in social activities, and culminating in a loss of self-identity and isolation. The second finding highlights disbelief among the families and the medical community of pain participants in this study. This is possibly due to the invisibility of their chronic pain in their surroundings. The last finding suggests participants felt dissatisfaction with their journey through the health care system.Previous studies have focused on chronic pain mainly through quantitative methods based on measurements, such as questionnaires. The biomedical aspects of pain are important, but the emphasis on this can result in lack of attention to the experiences of living with chronic pain. In qualitative studies, patients are considered on a patient level, not on a group level, and allowed to discuss their personal experiences with pain. Thus, qualitative methodologies are important in order to achieve a more profound understanding of the unique, individual patient. It is hoped that the findings of this study will benefit other sufferers learning to live with chronic pain and also guide healthcare providers to approach these patients with more compassion and empathy.</description><description>Une approche de recherche phénoménologique interprétative a été choisie pour explorer le sens de vivre avec la douleur orofaciale chronique. Des entrevues individuelles ont été menées avec 6 participants souffrant de douleur chronique et ayant suivi un traitement dans une clinique de la douleur. Les entretiens ont été transcrits textuellement et interprétés de manière phénoménologique. La phénoménologie interprétative est une approche de recherche qualitative qui tente d'enquêter sur les expériences des gens pour révéler ce qui est «caché» en eux. Cette approche a été utilisée en raison de la nature empirique du présent sujet. Trois constatations essentielles ont été identifiées: 1) souffrir de perte, 2) incrédulité et 3) insatisfaction à l'égard des soins de santé. Le premier constat met en évidence l'effet de la douleur chronique sur la vie des participants. Cela comprend la perte de relations, l'emploi, la capacité de manger, de s'engager dans des activités sociales et de culminer dans une perte d'identité et d'isolement. Le deuxième constat met en évidence l'incrédulité parmi les familles et la communauté médicale de la douleur participants à cette étude. Cela est probablement dû à l'invisibilité de leur douleur chronique dans leur environnement. Le dernier constat suggère que les participants se sentent mécontents de leur voyage dans le système de santé.Des études antérieures ont porté sur la douleur chronique principalement par des méthodes quantitatives basées sur des mesures, comme des questionnaires. Les aspects biomédicaux de la douleur sont importants, mais l'accent mis sur cela peut entraîner un manque d'attention aux expériences de vivre avec la douleur chronique. Dans les études qualitatives, les patients sont considérés au niveau du patient, et non au niveau du groupe, et sont autorisés à discuter de leurs expériences personnelles avec la douleur. Ainsi, les méthodologies qualitatives sont importantes afin de parvenir à une compréhension plus profonde du patient unique et individuel. Il est à espérer que les résultats de cette étude seront bénéfiques pour les autres personnes souffrant de souffrir de douleur chronique et guider les fournisseurs de soins de santé à aborder ces patients avec plus de compassion et d'empathie.</description><creator>Hosseinkhani Hazaveh, Mahta</creator><contributor>Richard Hovey (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Dentistry</subject><title>What does it mean to live with orofacial pain? an interpretive phenomenological exploration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf2687839.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j67316596</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn9999210</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:57:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les fascinations que développe Julia Kristeva pour l'instabilité de l'identité, la fragilité des frontières, et le processus de la signification s'infiltrent autant dans les aspects politiques de son œuvre que dans sa pensée sémiotique et psychanalytique. L'intérêt qu'elle porte aux structures inconscientes et aux pulsions refoulées constitutives de chaque individu fournit la base d'une éthique sur la désintégration psychique tout en offrant également un moyen de concevoir une politique qui reconnaît, qui respecte et qui exige la différence. L'analyse de Kristeva sur 'l'étranger' sera utilisée pour évaluer comment l'étrangeté se manifeste parmi les femmes détenues au Royaume-Uni, dont les statuts liminaux et les revendications complexes contestent fortement les définitions de la légitimité et de l'identité sur lesquelles s'est basé le régime d'immigration du Royaume-Uni. À travers son engagement avec les travaux de Hannah Arendt, cette thèse examinera comment Kristeva met l'étrangeté au cœur de sa pensée éthico-politique afin d'examiner les limites de l'identité nationale et de contester la validité des concepts associés. </description><description>Julia Kristeva's fascination with the instability of identity, the fragility of borders, and the process of meaning-making, permeates the political aspects of her work as much as it does her semiotic and psychoanalytic thought. Her emphasis on the unconscious structures and repressed drives constituting each individual provides the basis for an ethics that can embrace our internal disintegration, while also offering a way to conceive of a politics that recognises, respects, and demands difference. Kristeva's analysis of the 'stranger' will be used to evaluate how strangeness is manifested in women detainees in the UK, whose liminal status and complex claims profoundly challenge the categories of legitimacy and identity upon which the UK immigration system is premised. Via her engagement with Hannah Arendt, this thesis will examine how Kristeva places strangeness at the heart of her ethico-political thinking, to scrutinise the limits and trouble the meaning of any fixed concept of national identity. </description><creator>Robathan, Lucie</creator><contributor>Patricia Kirkpatrick (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Daniel M Cere (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Religious Studies</subject><title>Re-imagining strangeness and welcoming difference: Julia Kristeva, the "stranger", and the UK detention estate</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s7438.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn9999210</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445cg93n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:57:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction: Actuellement, la chirurgie reconstructrice est limitée par le manque de greffons vascularisé disponibles. Dans cette étude, nous avons tenté de stimuler une néo-formation vasculaire au sein d'un bio-matériaux imprimé en 3D avec un model composé d'une arteriovenous loop (AV loop) et un model vasculaire simplifié. Nous avons ensuite comparé ces deux models et espérions obtenir des réseaux vasculaires néoformés transplantables et équivalents sur le plan fonctionnel. Matériel et méthodes: Induction de formation de néo-vaisseaux: Les scaffolds, de 12mm de long et 4 mm de diamètre avec un trou axial central de 1 mm pour loger les vaisseaux, ont été imprimés en 3D à partir de monetite, biomatériau décrit dans un précédent article. Les scaffolds se présentent en deux pièces identiques et assemblées ensemble autour des vaisseaux fémoraux après suture. Trois conditions ont été examinées chez le rats Wistar après une implantation de 4 semaines: le groupe contrôle négatif (implantation du scaffold sous-cutanée sans vaisseau en son centre), le groupe veine (adaptation du scaffold autour de la veine fémorale) et le groupe contrôle positif, le groupe de la boucle artério-veineuse, AV loop (adaptation du scaffold autour d'une anastomose artério-veineuse crée par microchirurgie). Résultats: L'analyse par micro-CT n'a pas montré de différence significative entre le groupe Veine et le groupe de la boucle AV. Le groupe témoin a affiché la plus faible densité vasculaire. A un seuil de 5% de risque d'erreur, le groupe veineux et le groupe artério-veineux ont montré une densité nettement plus élevée de vaisseaux comparativement au groupe témoin (3,5 ± 2,5 [groupe boucle AV] et 3,7 ± 2,6 [groupe veine] vs. 0,5 ± 0,54 [groupe témoin], p-valeur &lt;0,05). Conclusion: Cette étude a démontré pour la première fois que la veine et la boucle AV placées axialement dans un biomatériau imprimé en 3D peuvent induire une ramification vasculaire égale. Cela peut avoir des implications importantes en chirurgie reconstructrice. En effet, si la microchirurgie vasculaire nécessaire à la confection de la boucle AV pouvait être évitée et substituée par l'usage d'une simple veine, elle permettrait de simplifier grandement le protocole nécessaire à la pré-vascularisation des scaffolds. </description><description>Introduction: The inability to induce transplantable new blood vessels in biomaterials is a major obstacle in reconstructive surgery for critical bone defects. In this study, we attempted to induce neovascularization within a 3D printed construct using both an arteriovenous loop (AV loop) model and a simpler vascular model. We compared these two models. Materials and methods: Induction of vascularised synthetic free-flaps: Scaffolds, with a 1 mm central axial channel designed to accommodate blood vessels, were 3D printed utilizing monetite as described previously. Scaffolds were implanted in the femoral region of a Wistar rat and allowed to mature for 4 weeks.  Three experimental models were studied utilizing either a/an: arteriovenous loop, femoral vein or negative control (subcutaneous implantation) within the central channel of the scaffold. Analysis: Prior to sacrifice, the vasculature was perfused with a CT contrast agent (Microfil®) and the specimens were explanted and investigated by means of micro-CT followed by a 3D analysis, which was which was supplemented by immunohistochemistry. Results:  The micro-CT analysis clearly indicated no significant differences between the venous group and the AV loop group and the control group displayed statistically the lowest vascular density (3,5 ± 2,5 [AV loop group] and 3,7 ± 2,6 [Vein group] vs. 0,5 ± 0,54 [control group], p-value &lt; 0,05). Conclusion: This study demonstrated for the first time that vascularization can be equally induced utilizing a vein or AV loop that is placed axially in a scaffold. This implies that time consuming AV loop microsurgery may not necessary to promote neovascularization in a large size biomaterial. </description><creator>Maillard, Sophie</creator><contributor>Nicholas Maroun Makhoul (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Jake Barralet (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Dentistry</subject><title>Pre-vascularization of implanted 3D-printed constructs «In vivo»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43p072m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cg93n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:76537372n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:57:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La raison d'être de cette étude est de comparer les profils cinématiques d'hommes et femmes joueurs de hockey de niveau élite lors de patinage à vitesse maximale sur une patinoire. Un système de capture de mouvement en trois dimensions utilisant dix-huit caméras a été installé sur la patinoire pour enregistrer la trajectoire du centre de masse du patineur depuis un départ arrêté jusqu'à vitesse maximale. Les cinématiques de patinage furent enregistrées durant l'accélération initiale et les foulées maximales sur un corridor de 34m. De manière générale, les résultats ont révélé que les hommes et femmes démontrent des mouvements du corps similaires depuis le départ jusqu'à vitesse maximale; cependant, des différences entre hommes et femmes étaient visibles au niveau de la progression de la vitesse du centre de masse ainsi que pour les angles des hanches et des genoux. Les hommes ont démontré une plus grande accélération durant les premières foulées, ainsi qu'une plus grande abduction de la hanche et flexion du genoux durant le contact entre patin et glace. Hommes et femmes ont démontré un phénomène similaire de « plateau d'extension du genoux », durant lequel un arrêt temporaire d'extension du genou est observé lors du contact avec la glace; cependant, le phénomène était plus visible chez les femmes. Ces informations peuvent être associées à l'étiologie des blessures au bas du corps, et peuvent justifier la création de protocoles d'entraînement, d'équipement (ex. patins), ou de techniques de réhabilitations spécifiques au sexe de l'athlète en démontrant que les techniques de patinages diffèrent d'un sexe à l'autre, même à un niveau élite.</description><description>The purpose of this study was to compare kinematic profiles of elite male and female ice hockey players skating at maximal speed on the ice surface. An eighteen-camera 3D motion capture system was placed on the ice surface to record the trajectory of the body's centre of mass (COM) from a standing start to maximal speed. Skating kinematics were recorded during the initial acceleration and maximal skating strides over a 34 m corridor. In general, the results showed that males and females exhibit similar whole-body movement patterns from start to maximum speed; however, sex-specific differences in terms of velocity progression, as well as hip and knee joint angles were evident. In particular, males demonstrated greater net positive acceleration during the initial accelerative steps, and greater hip abduction and knee flexion from ice contact to push off. Both males and females exhibited a similar "knee extension plateau" phenomenon, in which a temporary cessation of knee extension occurs at ice contact, but females exhibited this phenomenon to a greater extent. This information may have some relation to lower body injuries' etiology, and may justify the creation of sex-specific training protocols, equipment (e.g. skate) designs, or rehabilitation techniques by showing that skating mechanics differ between the sexes, even at an elite level.</description><creator>Budarick, Aleksandra</creator><contributor>Shawn Robbins (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>David J Pearsall (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Kinesiology and Physical Education</subject><title>Ice hockey skating mechanics: Transition from start to maximum speed for elite male and female athletes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g264t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537372n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429c86q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:57:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dans le monde occidental, la Seconde Guerre Mondiale est connue surtout pour les victoires mythiques des Alliés ou pour la destruction de l'Europe causé par les Nazis. Dans les premières années de la guerre, cependant, la victoire ne pouvait pas être pris pour acquis. En Grande-Bretagne et en France—divisé entre zone occupée, zone "libre" de Vichy, et le gouvernement en exile des Forces Françaises Libres—les citoyens ordinaires se concentraient sur la préservation de la famille nucléaire. Cet effort était lié à l'espoir d'une victoire. Cette thèse porte sur le traitement littéraire de la famille, de la sexualité et du genre dans quatre romans britanniques et français écrits entre 1940 et 1943, la période entre la bataille de France et sa libération. Le silence de la mer de Vercors (1943) et Suite française d'Irène Némirovsky (2004) ont été écrits sous des conditions très différentes de celles sous lesquelles Pied Piper (1942) de Nevil Shute et Cloudless May (1943) de Storm Jameson ont été écrits. Vercors et Némirovsky écrivirent clandestinement après que la France ait capitulé; Shute et Jameson écrivirent pendant le Blitz, craignant des circonstances similaires. Aucun des auteurs ne cherche une solution pratique à la guerre dans leurs romans. Pour eux, le maintien des valeurs familiales traditionnelles assurera la survie de la nation.</description><description>In the West, the Second World War is remembered for the mythic victories of the Allies or the destruction of Europe at the hands of the Nazis. In the first years of the war, however, victory was never certain. In both Britain and France—divided between German-Occupied Northern France, Vichy in the South, and the Free French Forces abroad—much of the attention of ordinary citizens and government officials was focussed on preserving the integrity of the nuclear family. This endeavor was closely tied to the prospect of victory. This thesis attends to the treatment of family, sexuality, and gender in four British and French novels written between 1940 and 1943, the period between the Fall and Liberation of France. Vercors' Le Silence de la Mer (1943) and Irène Némirovsky's Suite Française (2004) were written in very different conditions than Nevil Shute's Pied Piper (1942) and Storm Jameson's Cloudless May (1943). Vercors and Némirovsky wrote clandestinely after their nation had submitted to Hitler; Shute and Jameson, fearing a similar fate, wrote during the Blitz. None of the authors seek a practical solution to the war in their novels. For them, the maintenance of traditional family values will ensure the endurance of the nation.</description><creator>Fauteux, Travis</creator><contributor>William Allan Hepburn (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>English</subject><title>Family values in British and French occupation novels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w492x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429c86q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gf06g5247</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:57:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dans cette thèse, je vais analyser les relations qui existent entre les mécanismes de la justice transitionnelle et les crimes sexistes. Je vais baser mon travail sur une étude de deux études de cas. La première concerne l'Afrique du Sud, qui, après l'Apartheid, a préféré une justice dite « réparatrice » centrée sur la victime et sur la réparation; Et dont la principale initiative était la Commission de Vérité et Réconciliation. La deuxième étude de cas concerne le Cambodge qui a mis en place, avec l'aide de l'Organisation des Nations Unies, un tribunal hybride, les Chambres Extraordinaires au sein des Tribunaux Cambodgiens (CETC), composées de juges nationaux et internationaux. Le Cambodge a donc priviligié une justice dite punitive. Je vais analyser comment ces deux mécanismes de justice transitionnelle ont fourni séparément une réponse atténuée aux besoins des victimes femmes. La Commission de Vérité et Réconciliation n'a pas réussi à modifier la culture du viol et les attitudes entourant la question de la violence sexuelle en Afrique du Sud. Elle n'a pas intégré une approche sexospécifique dans le cadre de son mandat et au cours des audiences, et si elle l'a fait, il était bien souvent trop tard. De nombreuses victimes ont alors développé le sentiment que leurs bourreaux pouvait agir impunément. Les CETC, pour leur part, n'ont pas donné une réponse satisfaisante aux besoins des victimes en matière de reconnaissance de leur souffrances et n'ont ainsi pas contribué pleinement au processus de guérison. Dans la dernière partie, je ferai des recommandations visant à promouvoir une justice transitionelle holistique. Par justice transitionnelle holistique, je veux parler de justice qui tient compte de tous les mécanismes de la justice transitionnelle en les faisant coopérer ensemble pour atteindre les objectifs poursuivis par les sociétés sortant d'un conflit: poursuites pénales, rétablissement de la vérité, réforme institutionnelle, réparations, et réconciliation.</description><description>In this thesis I will analyze the relationships between mechanisms of transitional justice and gender-specific crimes. I will base my work on a study of two case studies. The first is South Africa, which, after Apartheid, favoured restorative justice; and whose leading initiative was the Truth and Reconciliation Commission (TRC). The second case study concerns Cambodia which has set up, with the help of the UN, a hybrid tribunal. This is the Extraordinary Chambers in the Court of Cambodia (ECCC), composed of both national and international judges. I will analyze how these two mechanisms of transitional justice have separately provided a mitigated response to the needs of female victims. The TRC alone has failed to change the culture of rape and the attitudes surrounding the issue of sexual violence in South Africa. It did not incorporate a gender-specific approach within its mandate and throughout the hearings, and if it did so, it was too late. Many female victims have developed the sense that their perpetrators can act with impunity. The ECCC, for its part, failed to give a satisfactory answer to the victims' needs of recognition in their healing process. In the final part, I will then consider recommendations for improved holistic transitional justice. By holistic transitional justice, I mean justice that takes into account all the mechanisms of transitional justice by making them cooperate together to achieve the goals pursued by post-conflict societies: prosecution, truth recovery, institutional reform, reparations, and reconciliation.</description><creator>George, Lucie</creator><contributor>Nandini Ramanujam (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Law</subject><title>Gender and transitional justice: a comparative study of Cambodia and South Africa</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214r73w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g5247</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b8515r02h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:57:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new formulation is developed for the analysis of waveguide problems. Maxwell's equations for the modes are reduced to coupled equations for the transverse components of both the electric and magnetic field. A finite element method using edge elements is derived to solve the equations. Both homogeneous and inhomogeneous waveguides are analysed with the method. Reliable solutions without spurious modes are obtained.</description><description>Une nouvelle formulation est développé pour l'analyse de problèmes de guides d'ondes. Les équations de Maxwell pour les modes sont réduit à des équations couplées pour les composantes transversales du champ électrique et magnétique. Une méthode des éléments finis utilisant des éléments de bord est dérivée pour résoudre les équations. Les guides d'ondes homogénes et non homogénes sont analysés avec la méthode. Des solutions fiables sans modes parasites sont obtenues.</description><creator>Zhang, Zihuan</creator><contributor>Jonathan P Webb (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</subject><title>A finite element method for waveguide modes using transverse electric and magnetic fields</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v5390.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515r02h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7m01bp18x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:57:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'usage et la compréhension du langage figuré est d'importance cruciale pour communiquer avec succès. Les expressions idiomatiques, par exemple, sont des expressions dont le sens ne peut être identifié par l'analyse de leurs mots composants (par exemple, « casser sa pipe », qui signifie « mourir » en français); elles constituent une catégorie du langage figuré fréquemment utilisée. Même s'il y a eu beaucoup de recherches portant sur l'acquisition et le traitement des expressions idiomatiques, la variabilité entre les expressions idiomatiques ainsi que la familiarité des gens avec celles-ci rendent difficile la tâche d'isoler les facteurs linguistiques spécifiques qui favorisent leur compréhension. Pour essayer de contourner ces limitations, la présente thèse emploie un paradigme d'expressions idiomatiques inventées permettant d'exercer un contrôle précis sur ces facteurs. Spécifiquement, 29 participants ont appris une série de 24 expressions idiomatiques factices lors d'une phase de formation sémantique à choix forcé. Pendant cette phase de formation, la manière dont les expressions idiomatiques factices étaient apprises variait à deux égards : la répétition (le nombre des fois que chaque participant a vu une expression donnée) et le sens dominant (la présentation de l'expression idiomatique de manière à privilégier son sens figuré ou son sens littéral). Au cours d'une phase subséquente, les mouvements des yeux des participants étaient enregistrés alors qu'ils lisaient des phrases renfermant les expressions idiomatiques nouvellement apprises dans de contextes différents. Les mesures de la compréhension selon les mouvements des yeux des participants étaient : la durée du regard de premier passage, pour les régions de l'expression idiomatique et de la désambiguïsation, dans les phrases individuelles; et le temps de lecture total pour la région de l'expression idiomatique. Les résultats ont montré que la répétition aussi bien que le sens dominant avaient un impact sur le temps de lecture des participants, lequel était modulé par le caractère décomposable plus ou moins évident des expressions idiomatiques (c'est-à-dire le degré auquel leur sens figuré était lié à leur sens littéral / non-idiomatique). Ces résultats sont discutés dans le contexte des hypothèses existantes à propos du traitement des expressions idiomatiques. </description><description>Fluently using and understanding figurative language is crucial for successful communication. For example, idioms are phrases whose meanings are not identifiable through analysis of their constituent words (e.g., kick the bucket, which means to die suddenly in English), and are a very common class of figurative language. While a great deal of research has investigated how adults process idioms, variability across idioms as well as people's experiences with idioms make it difficult to isolate the specific linguistic factors that promote their comprehension. In attempt to circumvent this limitation, this thesis makes use of an invented idiom paradigm where such factors can be precisely controlled. Specifically, 29 participants learned a series of 24 novel idioms in a semantic, forced-choice training phrase. During this training phase, the way the invented idioms were learned varied in two respects: repetition (the number of times each participant was exposed to a given idiom) and meaning dominance (whether they were exposed to an idiom more in its figurative sense or its literal sense). During a subsequent test phase, participants' eye movements were recorded as they read test sentences containing the newly learned idioms in different contexts. Eye movement comprehension measures consisted of participants' first pass gaze duration for the idiom and disambiguating regions of individual test sentences, and total reading time for the idiom region. The results showed that both training repetition and dominance impacted comprehension participants' reading times in a manner that was modulated by the idioms' varying levels of decomposability (i.e., the extent to which their figurative meanings relate to their non-idiomatic literal meaning). These results are discussed in the context of the existing hypotheses about idiom processing.</description><creator>Riley, Shannon</creator><contributor>Debra Ann Titone (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Signy Sheldon (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Psychology</subject><title>Eye movement measures of "invented idiom" processing reflect frequency, meaning dominance, and compositionality during training</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892d55c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bp18x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f3903</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:57:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Une série de simulations numériques est réalisée pour étudier l'impact des ondes de tempête sur les infrastructures, ainsi que leur rôle dans le déplacement des minéraux au sein des torrents de montagne. Les forces irrégulières provoquées par les ondes de tempête sont calculées pour trois problèmes. Le premier consiste à déterminer l'impact de la force des vagues sur des infrastructures données. Dans la simulation, l'infrastructure est un bloc carré. Le calcul montre que les forces agissant sur le bloc, sont proportionnelles à la taille de l'onde correspondante. Un coefficient de frottement de l'onde est donc défini. Celui-çi est directement corrélé au nombre de Froude de l'onde. Le second et le troisième problème sont des simulations réalisées pour étudier les processus de transport dans les cours d'eau montagneuses. Ainsi, les simulations sont formées de telle manière que les vagues submergent un bloc carré puis un obstacle hémisphérique submergé. La pression et le point de basculement sont calculés, grâce à la simulation d'une grande variété de nombres d'ondes de tempêtes. Le but est de trouver le point critique de pression causant le déplacement des graviers, roches et rochers dans les courants d'eaux montagneux. La simulation pour la profondeur de l'eau, la vélocité autour de l'infrastructure et sur les roches et graviers, est ainsi obtenue sous la forme de solutions numériques à l'aide de l'équation de Barré de Saint-Venan. L'approximation du volume fini, produite par l'équation de Saint-Venan, est appliquée sur une grille décalée. Le schéma d'ajustement des flux MINMOD est utilisé pour supprimer les excès ou manques causés par de nettes discontinuités, telles que le ressaut hydraulique lorsque le flux passe d'un état supercritique à subcritique. La méthode de Runge-Kutta, du quatrième ordre, permet d'estimer le progrès de la computation en temps défini.</description><description>A series of numerical simulations are conducted to study the flood wave impact on infrastructure and its role on the transport processes in mountain streams. Unsteady forces by the flood waves are calculated for three typical problems. The first is to find the wave forces on a critical infrastructure. In the simulations, the infrastructure is a square block. The calculation shows the forces on the square block are in proportional to the height of the reflected surge wave. A wave-force coefficient is defined to quantify the magnitude of the force. It is found uniquely correlated with the surge-wave Froude number. Thesecond and the third series of simulations are conducted to find the mobility of the submerged obstacles to study transport processes in mountain streams. For the purpose, the simulations for the flows over a submerged square blockand a submerged hemispherical obstacle are conducted. The forces and the tipping moments are calculated from the simulations for a wide range of surgewave discharge coefficient. The goal is to find the critical discharge for the mobility of the gravels, rocks and boulders in the mountain streams. Thesimulation for the water depth and the velocity around the infrastructureand over the rocks and gravels are obtained by numerical solutions of the shallow water equations. The finite-volume approximation of the shallow water equations is implemented on a staggered grid. The shock-capture scheme MINMOD is used to suppress the overshot and undershot across the depth and velocity discontinuity such as the hydraulic jump as the flow changes from supercritical to subcritical state. A fourth-order Runge-Kutta method estimates the advancement of the computation step in time.</description><creator>Xie, Peiwei</creator><contributor>Vincent H Chu (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</subject><title>Flood waves on infrastructure and on transport processes in mountain streams</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vd98j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f3903</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795b268</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:57:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La naissance prématurée (PTB; accouchement avant 37 semaines de gestation), laquelle représente approximativement 8% des naissances, est une problématique de santé en hausse dans le monde. La raison pour laquelle le nombre de PTB augmente constamment est que les causes demeurent inconnues. La seule cause de PTB qui a été confirmée est la présence d'une infection et donc, de l'inflammation qui s'ensuit. Les molécules d'importance majeure liées à la fois à l'inflammation et à la PTB sont l'interleukine (IL)-6, l'IL-1 et le facteur de nécrose tumoral alpha (TNFα). Des études récentes ont montré que les concentrations d'IL-6 augmentent significativement dans le liquide amniotique, en présence d'infection, ce qui conduira à la PTB. Par conséquent, il est important d'étudier la possibilité de cibler IL-6 dans le but de prévenir la PTB et ses comorbidités. IL-6 agit en se liant au récepteur de l'IL-6 (IL-6R), ce qui forme un complexe qui se lie par la suite à la protéine accessoire gp130, générant une réponse intracellulaire. L'action d'IL-6 se traduit par l'activation de trois principales voies de signalisation, lesquelles débutent par la phosphorylation des protéines STAT3, Erk1/2 et Akt. Notre groupe a développé un petit peptide, nommé 633, en analysant les motifs flexibles de la portion extracellulaire du IL-6R. Des études ont montré que la génération d'antagonistes à partir de ces motifs flexibles tend à produire des molécules possédant des caractéristiques allostériques. Dans ce projet, nous avons caractérisé l'effet du 633 sur la signalisation et les fonctions proinflammatoires de l'IL-6. Nous avons également étudié la possibilité que 633 possède des propriétés allostériques. Ensuite, nous avons testé le potentiel du 633 dans un modèle murin de travail préterme induit par IL-6, dans le but de valider que l'IL-6 constitue une cible valable et pour étudier la possibilité que 633 constitue un agent thérapeutique potentiel pour prévenir la PTB. Finalement, nous avons confirmé l'efficacité du 633 dans un modèle murin de travail préterme induit par l'administration de lipopolysaccharide (LPS). Les résultats ont montré la présence d'une première caractéristique allostérique du 633, soit l'agonisme biaisé, via la modulation différentielle de la signalisation de l'IL-6. Le 633 engendre une réduction significative de la voie de signalisation de STAT3 sans inhiber les voies de Akt ou Erk1/2. Nous avons démontré, in vitro, que le 633 modulait l'induction des cytokines pro-inflammatoires (IL-6, IL-1β et TNFα) en réponse à IL-6 de façon dosedépendante. Nous avons prouvé que le 633 possédait une seconde caractéristique allostérique en montrant que le 633 modulait de manière différentielle l'efficacité et l'affinité de l'IL-6. Ce résultat montre la capacité du 633 à réduire l'efficacité de l'IL6 et, aux doses les plus élevées, à augmenter l'affinité de l'IL-6 pour son récepteur. Nous avons validé que l'IL-6 constitue une cible importante dans la prévention de la PTB en montrant que IL-6 seule est capable de déclencher une PTB. Nous avons aussi prouvé que 633 était capable de prévenir la prématurité due à l'IL-6 en modulant sélectivement l'augmentation de l'expression des gènes de cytokines proinflammatoires et de protéines activatrices de l'utérus dans les tissus maternels et gestationnels. Finalement, nous avons confirmé que 633 était efficace en prouvant que cette molécule pouvait prévenir la naissance prématurée induite par le LPS via la modulation sélective de l'augmentation de l'expression des gènes et des protéines pro-inflammatoires dans les tissus et fluides maternels et gestationnels. Nous avons aussi démontré la capacité du 633 à rétablir la survie néonatale et le poids. À la lumière des résultats obtenus, nous pouvons conclure que le 633 est une molécule thérapeutique à fort potentiel dans le traitement des PTB et que ce projet établit la base d'un développement clinique ultérieur favorisant l'usage du 633 chez l'humain.</description><description>Preterm birth (PTB; delivery before 37 weeks of gestation), representing approximately 8% of the births, is an increasing health concern worldwide. The reason why PTB numbers are in a constant increase is because even 50% of the cases present unknown causes. The only confirmed causal link is the existence of an infection and thus its related inflammation. The most important molecules related to both, inflammation and PTB are interleukin- (IL-) 6, IL-1β and tumor necrosis factor alpha (TNFα). Current reports show how the levels of IL-6 significantly increase in amniotic fluid in the presence of an infection that will later become PTB. Therefore, it will be important to study the possibility of targeting IL-6 in order to prevent PTB and its co-morbidities. IL-6 acts by binding to the IL-6R and this complex will later bind to the intracellular receptor gp130 generating an intracellular response. The action of IL-6 will translate into the activation of three main signaling pathways whose start-up point is characterized by the phosphorylation of the proteins STAT3, Erk1/2 and Akt. Our group has developed a small peptide, called 633, by analyzing the extracellular flexible motifs of the IL-6R. Some reports indicate that the generation of antagonists based on this flexible motifs tends to produce molecules with allosteric characteristics. In this work, we characterized the effect of 633 in the IL-6 signaling and in its pro-inflammatory function. We analyzed the possibility of 633 of presenting allosteric features. Then, we tested the potential of 633 in an IL-6-induced PTB mice model, in order to validate IL-6 as a valuable target and to study 633 as a potential therapeutic agent to prevent PTB. Lastly, we confirmed 633 efficacy in a lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-induced PTB mice model. The results showed the presence of the first allosteric characteristic of 633, biased agonism, by the differential modulation of IL-6 signaling. The effect of 633 produced a significant reduction of the STAT3 pathway without inhibiting the Akt or Erk1/2 pathway. We demonstrate a dose-response behavior of 633 against the IL-6-driven induction of pro-inflammatory cytokines (IL-6, IL-1β and TNFα) in vitro. We displayed the second allosteric characteristic by showing a differential 633 modulation of IL-6 efficacy and affinity. This result demonstrates the ability of 633 to reduce IL-6 efficacy and in the highest 633 doses, to even increase IL-6 affinity for its receptor. We validate IL-6 as an important target in the prevention of PTB by showing that the sole action of IL-6 is sufficient to generate the onset of PTB. We also prove how 633 was able to prevent the IL-6 prematurity by selectively modulating gene upregulation of proinflammatory cytokines and uterine activation proteins in maternal and gestational tissues. Lastly, we confirmed 633 efficacy by presenting evidence how 633 can prevent LPS-induced PTB by selectively modulating pro-inflammatory gene and protein upregulation in maternal and gestational tissues and fluids. We also demonstrate the ability of 633 to rescue the neonate survival and weight. For all the aforementioned, we conclude that 633 is a valuable therapeutic molecule for the treatment of PTB and that this work set the basis for the potential clinical development and later use of 633 in humans.</description><creator>Marin Sierra, Estefania</creator><contributor>Barbara F Hales (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Sylvain Chemtob (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2017</date><subject>Pharmacology and Therapeutics</subject><title>Characterization of the mechanism of action of an anti-IL-6R small peptide in an infection-and inflammation-induced preterm labor model</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150m58f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795b268</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):6200</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>