<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:58:20Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43400" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rh42z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present thesis aimed to identify trends and individual differences in prosocial behaviour frequencies throughout childhood and adolescence, in addition to examining longitudinal patterns of association between prosocial behaviours and externalizing and internalizing problems. Neurochemical bases of prosocial behaviours, specifically serotonergic functioning, were also investigated.  Three studies are presented. Study 1 longitudinally described prosocial behaviour development from childhood to adolescence, using multiple informants within Canadian and Italian samples. Participants were boys from low SES areas of Montreal, Canada, as well as boys and girls in Genzano, Italy.  Developmental trajectories were estimated based on yearly ratings by mothers and teachers (Montreal, ages 10 to 15) and children and teachers (Genzano, ages 10 to 14). Results revealed that the majority of children, across cultures and informants, followed trajectories characterized by stable or declining levels of prosocial behaviours over time. Low to moderate agreement was observed between informants. Prosocial behaviour development must however be viewed within the broader context of children's behavioural and affective functioning.  Study 2 therefore focused on longitudinal associations between prosocial behaviour development and the development of externalizing and internalizing problems. Potential predictors of joint development were also investigated.  Using a large, representative sample of Canadian children, prosocial behaviour, physical aggression, anxiety, and depression developmental trajectories spanning ages 2 to 11 were modeled based ratings by the person most knowledgeable about the child.  A negative association tended to operate between prosocial behaviour levels and levels of physical aggression and depression, while a more complex relationship emerged with anxiety. Child, mother, and family characteristics significantly contributed to the prediction of joint development, with evidence of maternal depression and low family income increasing the likelihood of displaying high levels of prosocial behaviours with high levels of externalizing and internalizing difficulties. Study 3 focused on the neurochemical underpinnings of prosocial behaviours, specifically investigating the impact of acute tryptophan supplementation, and by extension increased serotonergic functioning, on children's laboratory aggressive and prosocial behaviours.  Boys with a history of relatively high levels of physical aggression were randomly assigned to a tryptophan supplementation or control condition following a double-blind procedure. Results revealed that boys in the tryptophan condition were more likely to sustain competition with a fictitious opponent during a computerized reaction time game.  Boys in the tryptophan condition also showed greater perspective taking, as well as greater instrumental help. Taken together, results of the present thesis provide evidence of both stability and change in prosocial behaviour frequencies during childhood and adolescence. Results also highlight the complex relationship of prosocial behaviours with adjustment, as well as potential contributions of the serotonergic system to the regulation of prosocial responding in children.  The present thesis sets the stage for future studies investigating the interplay of psychosocial and biological forces in determining individual differences in prosocial behaviour and related aspects of functioning.</description><description>L'objectif de la présente thèse était d'identifier les patrons et les différences individuelles dans le développement des comportements prosociaux au cours de l'enfance et de l'adolescence, ainsi que d'examiner les associations longitudinales entre les comportements prosociaux et les problèmes extériorisés et intériorisés.  Les bases neurochimiques des comportements prosociaux, spécifiquement le fonctionnement sérotonergique, ont également été examinées.  Trois études sont présentées. La première étude décrit de façon longitudinale les comportements prosociaux au cours de l'enfance et l'adolescence, à l'aide de multiples informateurs et d'échantillons canadiens et italiens.  Les participants étaient des garçons provenant de quartiers défavorisés de Montréal, Canada, et des garçons et des filles de la ville de Genzano, Italie. Des trajectoires développementales ont été estimées basé sur des évaluations annuelles faites par les mères et les enseignantes (Montréal, 10 à 15 ans) et par les enfants et les enseignantes (Genzano, 10 à 14 ans). Les résultats ont démontré que la majorité des enfants, au sein des deux cultures et pour tous les informateurs, suivait des trajectoires de comportements prosociaux aux niveaux stables ou déclinants au cours du temps. Un niveau faible à modéré d'accord était présent entres les différents informateurs. Le développement des comportements prosociaux doit toutefois être observé dans le contexte général du fonctionnement comportemental et affectif des enfants. La deuxième étude a donc examiné les associations longitudinales entre le développement des comportements prosociaux et des problèmes extériorisés et intériorisés. Les predicteurs potentiels du développement conjoint ont également été étudiés.  Les trajectoires développementales (2 à 11 ans) de comportements prosociaux, agressivité physique, anxiété, et dépression ont été estimées à l'aide d'évaluations chez un large échantillon représentatif d'enfants canadiens.  Une association négative tendait à être présente entre les niveaux de comportements prosociaux et les niveaux d'agressivité physique et dépression, tandis que des associations plus complexes étaient observées pour l'anxiété. Les caractéristiques de l'enfant, de la mère, et de la famille contribuaient significativement à la prédiction du développement conjoint, la dépression maternelle et un faible revenu famillial augmentant la probabilité de démontrer conjointement un haut niveau de comportements prosociaux et de hauts niveaux de problèmes extériorisés et intériorisés. La troisième étude a examiné les bases neurochimiques des comportements prosoicaux,  évaluant spécifiquement l'effet de la supplémentation ponctuelle de tryptophan, ainsi donc de l'augmentation de la sérotonine, sur les comportements agressifs et prosoicaux des enfants en laboratoire.  Des garçons présentant un historique relativement élevé d'agressivité physique ont été assignés au hasard à la supplémentation de tryptophan ou à la condition controle, suivant un devis double aveugle.  Les résultats ont démontré que les garçons du groupe tryptophan étaient plus enclins à soutenir la compétition avec un adversaire fictic lors d'un jeu compétitif de temps de réaction sur l'ordinateur. Les garçons du groupe tryptophan ont également démontré une plus grande prise de perspective ainsi que plus de comportements d'aide. Globalement, les résultats démontrent la présence de stabilité et changements dans la fréquence des comportements prosociaux durant l'enfance et l'adolescence.  Les résultats soulignent également la relation complexe entre les comportements sociaux et l'adaptation, ainsi que la contribution du système sérotonergique à la régulation de la prosocialité.  La présente thèse invite les études futures portant sur l'interaction de facteurs psychosociaux et biologiques pouvant déterminer les différences individuellles en prosocialité et autres aspects du fonctionnement associés.</description><creator>Nantel-Vivier, Amelie</creator><contributor>Robert O Pihl (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Psychology - Developmental</subject><title>Patterns and correlates of prosocial behaviour development</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806014s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rh42z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj430515b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>S'appuyant sur une analyse comparative de deux des plus grands romans du XIXe siècle français, cette thèse tente de s'approcher au plus près des relations dialogiques qui s'établissent entre la culture et la politique dans les régimes politiques transitoires par lesquels la France est passée de la monarchie à la république. fr Concrètement, cette thèse se divise en quatre parties. La première est historique et offre un panorama historique qui va de la Révolution de 1789 à l'établissement de la IIIe République dans le dernier tiers du XIXe siècle. Dans cette partie, une attention particulière est portée aux conditions qui ont permis à la France de passer d'un régime monarchique à des régimes plus démocratiques, en mettant en évidence l'avènement de l'espace public. La seconde partie est théorique. Dans un premier temps, une analyse à la fois plus historiographique et plus politique est faite de la Restauration et de la monarchie de Juillet, dans le but de mettre au jour les conditions par lesquelles la France s'est peu à peu convertie à l'idéologie et à la pratique républicaines. Dans un deuxième temps, en s'appuyant sur des théoriciens des discours, il est démontré que la culture occupe une place essentielle dans l'espace public. Les troisième et quatrième parties sont consacrées à des analyses littéraires plus classiques. La troisième partie porte sur Les Mystères de Paris d'Eugène Sue, publiés en feuilleton en 1842, et qui furent l'un des plus grands succès littéraires du siècle. Dans cette analyse l'attention est portée sur le dialogue qui s'est mis en place entre l'auteur et les lecteurs, durant la publication du feuilleton. C'est par ce dialogue que le roman d'aventure d'abord offert aux lecteurs, s'est transformé en roman social. Cette modification générique procura aux Mystères de Paris une efficacité politique jusque-là inédite. Le dernier chapitre de cette partie contient une analyse de la manière dont Eugène Sue allie, avec beaucoup d'habileté, un récit romanesque classique, qui raconte les péripéties de ses personnages et des commentaires explicitement politiques qui s'appuient sur les mésaventures de ses personnages dont il fait des exemples. La quatrième partie est consacrée aux Misérables de Victor Hugo, publiés vingt ans plus tard. Dans cette analyse, il est montré comment Victor Hugo s’approprie et modifie le roman de Sue, pour lui donner une visée républicaine. Il est mis en évidence qu’Hugo travaille à la fois sur deux aspects de l’œuvre de Sue, soit l’aspect proprement littéraire et l’aspect rhétorique. Sur le plan littéraire, Hugo reprend certains des personnages de Sue, mais en s’assurant que leurs quêtes réussissent. Sur le plan rhétorique, Hugo remplace le dialogue qu’avait entamé Eugène Sue avec ses lecteurs par des commentaires beaucoup plus autoritaires et paternalistes, tout à fait à l’image de l’idéologie de la bourgeoisie de la IIIe République. La conclusion permet de voir quels constats on peut tirer d’une comparaison entre les modifications thématiques et rhétoriques des œuvres littéraires et la succession des différents régimes politiques par laquelle la France a réussi à atteindre la stabilité politique à la fin du XIXe siècle.</description><description>Based on a comparative analysis of two of the greatest novels of 19th century France, this thesis seeks to closely examine the dialogical relations that were established between culture and politics in the transitional political regimes through which France passed from the monarchy to the republic. Concretely, this thesis is divided into four sections. The first is historical and provides an historical panorama ranging from the 1789 Revolution to the establishment of the Third Republic in the last third of the 19th century. Through a highlighting of the advent of public space, this section pays particular attention to the conditions that enabled France to pass from a monarchic regime to increasingly democratic regimes. The second section is theoretical. Firstly, a both more historiographical and political analysis of the Restoration and July Monarchy will be undertaken with the aim of bringing to light the conditions whereby France progressively converted to the republican ideology and practice. Secondly, by drawing on discourse theorists, it will be demonstrated that public space is essentially driven by discourse. The third and fourth sections are dedicated to more classical literary analyses. The third section focuses on The Mysteries of Paris by Eugène Sue, serially published in 1842, and which was one of the greatest literary successes of the century. In this analysis attention will be given to the dialogue that emerged between the author and the readership during the serial's publication. It is through this dialogue that the initial adventure novel was transformed into a popular novel. This generic modification provided The Mysteries Paris with an unprecedented political efficacy. The last chapter of this section includes an analysis of the manner in which Eugène Sue very skillfully allied a classical novelistic narrative that recounts the characters' episodes with explicitly political commentaries based on the misadventures of his characters, who he makes examples of. The fourth section is dedicated to Victor Hugo's Les Misérables, published twenty years later. This analysis shows how Victor Hugo appropriated and modified Sue's novel in order to give it a republican aim. It is made clear that Hugo worked jointly on two aspects of Sue's work, i.e. the properly literary aspect and the rhetorical aspect. On the literary level Hugo takes up some of Sue’s characters again, but in such a way that their quests end in success. On the rhetorical level Hugo replaces the dialogue, initiated by Sue with the readers, through far more paternalistic and authoritarian commentaries that are altogether in the image of the Third Republic bourgeois ideology. The conclusion allows one to see what assertions can be drawn from a comparison of the thematic and rhetorical modifications of literary works and the succession of various political regimes through which France succeeded in attaining political stability at the end of the 19th century. </description><creator>Choiniere, Paul</creator><contributor>Marcel Marc Angenot (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Literature - Modern</subject><title>Des mystères aux misères : le romantisme social et la question de la misère</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397869t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430515b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8623hz17v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les matériaux fonctionnels à base de carbone ou composés d'une matrice de carbone, incluant les matériaux dopés par des métaux de transition, sont largement utilisés dans le domaine de la catalyse par l'hydrogène et sont présentement développés pour des applications dans l'emmagasinage d'hydrogène. Le but premier de ce travail de thèse est d'acquérir des connaissances fondamentales et des détails quantitatifs sur : (i) la chimie de leur mode de synthèse, (ii) leur microstructure et leur composition chimique et (iii) leur fonctionnalité, en utilisant des modélisations à différentes échelles ainsi que des méthodologies de simulation. Le palladium et le palladium (II) acétyl acétonate sont respectivement le métal de transition et son précurseur d'intérêt. Une approche de modelage ab initio consistant en une implantation d'une onde planaire pseudo-potentielle dans la théorie de densité fonctionnelle de Kohn-Sham, combinée à une dynamique moléculaire de Car-Parrinello, a été mise en application afin de modéliser l'étape de dopage par le palladium dans la synthèse de matériaux à base de carbone ou composés d'une matrice de carbone et ses interactions avec les atomes d'hydrogène. La structure électronique est analysée à l'aide de la fonction de localization par électron et, lorsque nécessaire, les interactions dynamiques de l'hydrogène ont été accélérées et le bilan énergétique des interactions a été calculé en utilisant des techniques méta-dynamiques. Les pseudo-potentiels de palladium sont testés et validés quant à leur utilisation dans un environnement d'hydrocarbures par des simulations corroborant la stucture crystalline du palladium (II) acétyl acétonate observée expérimentalement. Des hypothèses expérimentales de longue date sur le dopage par le palladium ont été confirmés et de nouvelles considérations fondamentales en lien avec leur chimie moléculaire ont été révélées. La cinétique, les mécanismes et les barrières et empreintes énergétiques de l'adsorption de l'hydrogène ainsi que sa migration et sa désorption du complexe de palladium et de matériel à base de carbone ou composé d'une matrice de carbone ont été mis de l'avant pour une première fois. Les effets du dopage par le palladium et de la procédure de synthèse sur la structure poreuse de fibres de carbones activées par le dopage par le palladium sont quantifiés par une application d'une nouvelle méthode mécanique statistique sur les isothermes de physisorption expérimentales. Les inconvénients des méthodes conventionnelles d'analyse de structures poreuses basées sur l'adsorption sont démontrées. Puisque les fonctionnalités des matériaux à base de carbone dépendent fortement de leur microstructure, un modèle basé sur la thermo-poro-mécanique, servant à expliquer et prédire l'adsorption induite par les déformations au niveau de la microstructure, est développé et validé. Une explication au niveau moléculaires des tendances observées expérimentalement quant à la déformation est également proposée. En résumé, ce travail de thèse propose une étude scientifique compréhensible des matériaux fonctionnels à base de carbone ou composés d'une matrice de carbone en intégrant : (i) un modelage ab initio du dopage par le palladium et de l'interaction avec les atomes d'hydrogène, (ii) un calcul de la structure des pores basé sur les données issues des études expérimentales sur la physisorption, et (iii) un modelage statistique au niveau du continuum mécanique de l'adsorption induite par la déformation.</description><description>Functional carbon‒based/supported materials, including those doped with transition metal, are widely applied in hydrogen mediated catalysis and are currently being designed for hydrogen storage applications. This thesis focuses on acquiring a fundamental understanding and quantitative characterization of: (i) the chemistry of their synthesis procedure, (ii) their microstructure and chemical composition and (iii) their functionality, using multiscale modeling and simulation methodologies.  Palladium and palladium(II) acetylacetonate are the transition metal and its precursor of interest, respectively. A first‒principles modeling approach consisting of the planewave‒pseudopotential implementation of the Kohn—Sham density functional theory, combined with the Car—Parrinello molecular dynamics, is implemented to model the palladium doping step in the synthesis of carbon‒based/supported material and its interaction with hydrogen. The electronic structure is analyzed using the electron localization function and, when required, the hydrogen interaction dynamics are accelerated and the energetics are computed using the metadynamics technique. Palladium pseudopotentials are tested and validated for their use in a hydrocarbon environment by successfully computing the experimentally observed crystal structure of palladium(II) acetylacetonate. Long‒standing hypotheses related to the palladium doping process are confirmed and new fundamental insights about its molecular chemistry are revealed. The dynamics, mechanism and energy landscape and barriers of hydrogen adsorption and migration on and desorption from the carbon‒based/supported palladium clusters are reported for the first time. The effects of palladium doping and of the synthesis procedure on the pore structure of palladium‒doped activated carbon fibers are quantified by applying novel statistical mechanical based methods to the experimental physisorption isotherms. The drawbacks of the conventional adsorption‒based pore structure analysis methods are demonstrated. Since the functionality of carbon materials is strongly dependant on their microstructure, a thermodynamics‒poromechanics based model, to explain and predict the adsorption induced deformations in their microstructure, is developed and validated. A molecular level explanation for the experimentally observed unique trend in the deformation is also provided. In summary, this thesis provides a comprehensive scientific investigation of the functional carbon‒based/supported materials by integrating: (i) the first‒principles modeling of palladium doping and hydrogen interaction, (ii) pore structure calculations extracted from the experimental physisorption data, and (iii) statistical mechanical‒continuum level modeling of adsorption induced deformation.</description><creator>Mushrif, Samir</creator><contributor>Alejandro D Rey (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Engineering - Chemical</subject><title>Multiscale theoretical and computational modeling of the synthesis, structure and performance of functional carbon materials</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f6239.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623hz17v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78tc39j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Androgens are responsible for maintaining epididymal structure and functions. However, little is known about how androgen action is mediated and the identity of mechanisms underlying the restoration of epididymal cell integrity after androgen deprivation. It was therefore the goal of this thesis to determine the initial and sequential role of androgen action in altering cellular architecture and function in an androgen-deprived condition. The first objective was to elucidate the morphological changes in the regressed rat epididymal cell epithelium before and after hormone replacement. Using morphometric analysis and antibodies to cell proliferation markers, we determined changes in epithelial cell height and lumen diameter, as well as in the number of nuclei labeled, respectively, in different regions and at various time points after testosterone replacement in the regressed epididymis. We concluded that testosterone induces an increase in the number of new cells and re-expansion of existing cells in the regressed epididymis. The second objective was to determine the sequence of gene activation or suppression that occurs in an androgen deprived tissue upon re-administration of the two active metabolites of testosterone, dihydrotestosterone and estradiol by using Affymetrix Rat Genome Microarray chips. Interestingly, there are few genes that were regulated by estradiol, while many were affected by dihydrotestosterone. Using Pathway Assist software, we identified the early response pathway activated by dihydrotestosterone. Epidermal growth factor (EGF) and insulin-like growth factor (IGF1) appear to play an important role in the pathway due to their function in regulation and expression of many other genes. Lastly, we established the intracellular signaling pathway that may play a central role in mediating androgen action in restoring epithelial cell integrity in the epididymis. Involvement of two potential pathways activated by dihydrotestosterone, MAPK/ERK and AKT, in the proximal caput (PC-1) epididymal cell line was investigated. Using specific inhibitors for each pathway and an androgen receptor antagonist, we assessed the involvement of the androgen receptor in these pathways. IGF1 and EGF receptors were found to be the important mediators of MAPK/ERK pathway activations. Collectively, the results obtained from these studies provide a greater understanding of the mechanisms of androgen action in the epididymis.</description><description>Les androgènes sont responsables du maintien de la structure et des fonctions de l'épididyme. Cependant, nous en savons très peu sur la manière dont les androgènes agissent et l'identité des méchanismes sous-jacents à la restauration de l'intégrité cellulaire épididymale après privation des androgènes. Le but de cette thèse a donc été de déterminer le rôle initial et séquentiel de l'action des androgènes dans l'alteration de la structure architecturale et de la fonction en condition de privation des androgènes. Le premier objectif a été d'élucider les changements morphologiques dans l'épithélium cellulaire épididymal dans le rat régressé avant et après remplacement de l'hormone. En utilisant une analyse morphométrique et des anticorps pour marquer la prolifération cellulaire, nous avons respectivement déterminé les changements dans la hauteur des cellules épithéliales et du diamètre de la lumière ainsi que le nombre de noyaux marqués dans différentes régions et à différents moments après remplacement de la testostérone (T) dans l'épididyme régressé. Nous avons conclu que la T induit une augmentation du nombre de nouvelles cellules et une ré-expansion des cellules existantes dans l'épididyme régressé. Le second objectif a été de determiner la sequence d'activation ou de suppresion des gènes qui arrivaient dans un tissu privé d'androgènes après ré-administration des deux metabolites actifs de la T, dihydrotestostérone (DHT) et l'estradiol (E2) en utilisant des micropuces Affymetrix Rat Genome. Peu de gènes ont été régulés par l'E2, alors que beaucoup ont été affectés par la DHT. En utilisant, le programme Pathway Assist, nous avons identifé le chemin de réponse activé tôt par la DHT. Le facteur EGF (Epidermal growth factor) et le facteur IGF1 (Insulin-like growth factor) semblent jouer un rôle important dans le chemin dû à leur fonction dans la régulation et l'expression de plusieurs gènes. Finalement, nous avons établi le chemin de signalisation intracellulaire qui pourrait jouer un rôle central dans la médiation de l'action des androgènes pour restaurer l'intégrité cellulaire épithéliale dans l'épididyme. L'implication de deux chemins potentiels activés par la DHT, MAPK/ERK et AKT, dans la lignée cellulaire épididymale PC-1 a été exploré. En utilisant des inhibiteurs spécifiques pour chaque chemin et un antagoniste du récepteur à androgènes (AR), nous avons évalué la participatation d'AR dans ces chemins. Les récepteurs IGF1 et EGF ont été identifés comme des médiateurs importants de l'activation du chemin MAPK/ERK. Ensemble, les résultats obtenus de ces etudes apportent une meilleure comprehension des mechanisms d'action des androgens dans l'épididyme.</description><creator>Hamzeh, Mahsa</creator><contributor>Bernard Robaire (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Pharmacology</subject><title>Androgen action in the maintenance of epithelial cell integrity in the rat epididymis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074v54r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tc39j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53ww230</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>For the development of a healthy baby, the regulation of gene expression during development is critical. DNA methylation is an epigenetic mechanism that regulates gene expression, is established during gametogenesis and must be properly maintained throughout development.   DNA methylation also establishes the parent-of-origin expression of imprinted genes, which play key roles in embryo and placenta development, cancer, postnatal behaviour and are implicated in human disease. The primary objective of this work was to determine the effects on the embryo and placenta of perturbing epigenetic events during oocyte or preimplantation development.  The administration of exogenous hormones to increase the numbers of oocytes ovulated (superovulation) was hypothesized to affect the establishment of imprints in the oocyte and was thus employed as a model to perturb this key event in development.  Using this model, we demonstrated an effect on the maintenance of imprints that resulted in aberrant expression of imprinted genes specifically in the placenta and further identified the dysregulation of a key mitogen, Insulin-like growth factor II (IGF2), in the placenta as a potential contributor to the intrauterine growth restriction observed following superovulation.  In order to perturb methylation during the peri-implantation stage, we identified betaine homocysteine methyltransferase (BHMT) as the enzyme likely to be responsible for the provision of one-carbon units during this critical stage of development.  The expression of BHMT was knocked down using morpholino technologies, resulting in a significant increase in postimplantation loss.  Further, the methylation of imprinted genes was not affected following BHMT knockdown, however hypomethylation of non-imprinted regions was observed.  Taken together, the results of this thesis highlight the importance of appropriate DNA methylation for the growth and survival of the embryo, and have important implications for the use of</description><description>Afin d'assurer le sain développement d'un bébé, la régulation de l'expression génique pendant le développement embryonnaire est cruciale. La méthylation de l'ADN est l'un des mécanismes épigénétiques qui contrôlent l'expression génique. Cette modification épigénétique est instaurée pendant la gamétogenèse et doit être correctement maintenue pendant les étapes subséquentes du développement. La méthylation de l'ADN dicte aussi l'origine parentale de l'expression des gènes à empreinte; gènes qui jouent un rôle essentiel dans le développement de l'embryon, du placenta, du cancer, des comportements postnataux et qui sont aussi impliqués dans diverses maladies humaines. L'objectif principal de cette thèse était de déterminer les effets, sur l'embryon et le placenta, qu'ont des événements de perturbation épigénétique pendant le développement de l'ovocyte ou de l'embryon préimplantatoire. Nous avons émis l'hypothèse que l'administration d'hormones exogènes dans le but d'augmenter le nombre d'ovocytes ovulés (superovulation) aura pour effet d'altérer l'établissement des empreintes dans l'ovocyte.  La superovulation fut donc utilisée comme modèle afin de perturber cet événement fondamental du développement. Nous démontrons dans nos travaux que la conservation des empreintes est bel et bien affectée, ce qui résulte en une expression erronée des gènes à empreinte, spécifiquement au niveau du placenta.  De plus, nous avons découvert que la dérégulation d'un gène mitogène clé dans le placenta, le facteur de croissance analogue à l'insuline II (Igf2), pourrait contribuer à une croissance intra-utérine restreinte suite au processus de superovulation. Afin de perturber la méthylation pendant le stade péri-implantatoire, nous avons identifié BHMT (bétaïne-homocystéine méthyltransférase) comme l'enzyme potentiellement responsable de l'accumulation d'unités à un carbone pendant cette période critique du d</description><creator>Fortier, Amanda</creator><contributor>Jacquetta M Trasler (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>Effects on the embryo and placenta of perturbing epigenetic events during oogenesis and preimplantation development</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sg70h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53ww230</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75r831t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of the present research consisted in trying to understand whether we process the meaning of words similarly when they are repeated or presented for the first time in an experiment. A number of studies have shown that repetition can disrupt the processing of meaning, resulting in a reduction or a suppression of semantic effects. I have investigated whether semantic effects such as congruity effects, concreteness or effects of semantic category would be maintained or suppressed for highly repeated words. Behavioral as well as event-related potentials (ERPs) measures were acquired. Results indicate that semantic processing and its neural bases are similar in repeated and non-repeated conditions, as long as participants are explicitly invited to process meaning. This maintenance of semantic processing with multiple repetitions was demonstrated both in prime-target designs and in designs with single-word trials. In contrast, in tasks in which access to the meaning of words is not necessary, such as in lexical decision tasks, repetition resulted in a suppression of semantic effects. Using repeated words in explicit semantic designs could allow avoiding problems of category specificity and physical variance that are present when using large groups of words. Furthermore, it could allow the investigation of the organization of semantic representations at a finer scale than usual, the scale of individual concepts.</description><description>Le but de la recherche présentée était d'essayer de comprendre si l'on traite de manière similaire le sens de mots lorsqu'ils sont répétés ou présentés pour la première fois au cours d'une expérience. Des études ont montré que la répétition pouvait perturber le traitement du sens, résultant en une suppression ou une réduction des effets sémantiques. Je me suis intéressé à savoir si des effets comme la congruité sémantique, la concrétude ou les effets de catégories seraient maintenus ou supprimés pour des mots hautement répétés. Dans les expériences présentées, nous avons mesuré à la fois les temps de réaction et les potentiels évoqués (ERPs). Les résultats indiquent que le traitement sémantique et ses bases neurales sont similaires en conditions répétées et non-répétées, tant que les participants sont explicitement invités à traiter le sens. Ce maintien du traitement sémantique avec des présentations multiples a été démontré à la fois dans des protocoles de type « amorce-mot cible » et des protocoles où un seul mot était présenté à chaque essai. Par contre, dans les tâches ou le traitement du sens n'est pas nécessaire, comme la tâche de décision lexicale, la répétition a résulté en une suppression des effets sémantiques. Utiliser des mots répétés dans des tâches où le traitement du sens est explicite pourrait permettre d'éviter les problèmes de spécificité des catégories ou de variabilité des caractéristiques physiques des stimuli qui sont présents lorsqu'on utilise de nombreux mots. De plus, cela permettrait l'étude de l'organisation des représentations sémantiques à une résolution plus précise qu'habituellement, c'est à dire au niveau de concepts individuels.</description><creator>Renoult, Louis</creator><contributor>Jacques Bruno Debruille (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Psychology - Cognitive</subject><title>Do we still process the meaning of highly repeated words? A behavioral and electrophysiological investigation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w66344057.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75r831t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50gw61n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis asks the following question: "how does race and ethnicity emerge in the daily practice of community organizers who work in low-income, multi-racial, multi-ethnic neighbourhoods?"  Given that the concepts of race and ethnicity are understood to be social constructs, community organizing practice is analysed in this thesis in terms of its' constitutive role.  By examining community organizing practice in one neighbourhood in Québec, Canada, I argue that issues of race and ethnicity are largely constructed in community organizing practice as distinct from relations of power.  I demonstrate this construction of race and ethnicity using data gathered from 16 community organizers through interviews, textual analysis and observations.  I analyse the data from three angles: first, actions regarding issues of race and ethnicity that are normalized (i.e. "possible"); second, actions regarding issues of race and ethnicity that are constrained (i.e. "not possible"); and, lastly, actions that are resistant to normalized and/or constrained practices, and that link race and ethnicity to power relations.  In this way, I delineate Foucault's "field of action" (1982, p. 221) regarding race and ethnicity in neighbourhood community organizing and demonstrate how the structure of power in community organizing functions to render the connection between race and power largely invisible.</description><description>Cette thèse pose la question suivante : «Comment la race et l'ethnicité émergent dans la pratique quotidienne des organisateurs communautaires qui oeuvrent dans des quartiers à faible revenu, multiraciaux et multiethniques ?» Étant donné que les concepts de race et d'appartenance ethnique sont compris pour être des constructs sociaux, la pratique d'organisation des communautés est analysée dans cette thèse en termes de son rôle constitutif.En examinant la pratique d'organisation des communauté dans un quartier de Québec au Canada, je soutiens que les questions de race et d'appartenance ethnique sont en grande partie construites dans la pratique d'organisation de communauté par opposition aux relations de pouvoir. Je démontre cette construction de race et d'appartenance ethnique utilisant des données rassemblées auprès de 16 organisateurs communautaires par des interviews, l'analyse de textes et des observations. J'analyse les données de trois angles : d'abord, les actions quant aux questions de race et d'appartenance ethnique qui sont normalisées (c'est-à-dire «possible»); deuxièmement, des actions quant aux questions de race et d'appartenance ethnique qui sont contraintes (c'est-à-dire «non possible»); et, finalement, les actions qui sont résistantes aux pratiques normalisées et/ou contraintes et qui relie race et appartenance ethnique pour faire fonctionner des relations.  De cette façon, je définis «le champ d'action» de Foucault  (1982, p. 221) quant à la race et l'appartenance ethnique dans les organisations communautaires de quartier et démontrent comment la structure de pouvoir dans la communauté organisant des fonctions pour rendre la connexion entre la race et le pouvoir en grande partie invisible.</description><creator>Lavoie, Carmen</creator><contributor>Julia Krane (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>David A Dillon (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Social Sciences - Social Work</subject><title>Race, power and social action in neighbourhood community organizing: a case study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wd096.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gw61n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54kn508</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis describes a study of shielding design techniques used for radiation therapy facilities that employ megavoltage linear accelerators. Specifically, an evaluation of the shielding design formalism described in NCRP report 151 was undertaken and a feasibility study for open-door 6 MV radiation therapy treatments in existing 6 MV, 18 MV treatment rooms at the Montreal General Hospital (MGH) was conducted. To evaluate the shielding design formalism of NCRP 151, barrier-attenuated equivalent doses were measured for several of the treatment rooms at the MGH and compared with expectations from NCRP 151 calculations. It was found that, while the insight and recommendations of NCRP 151 are very valuable, its dose predictions are not always correct. As such, the NCRP 151 methodology is best used in conjunction with physical measurements. The feasibility study for 6 MV open-door treatments made use of the NCRP 151 formalism, together with physical measurements for realistic 6 MV workloads. The results suggest that, dosimetrically, 6 MV open door treatments are feasible. A conservative estimate for the increased dose at the door arising from such treatments is 0.1 mSv, with a 1/8 occupancy factor, as recommended in NCRP 151, included.</description><description>Ce mémoire décrit une étude des techniques de blindage utilisées dans les installations de radiothérapie pour des accélérateurs linéaires à mégavoltage. Plus précisément, une évaluation du formalisme de calcul de blindage tracée par le rapport NCRP 151 a été entrepris, et une étude de faisabilité a été menée avec le but de laisser la porte ouverte pour les traitements à 6 MV dans des salles de traitement déjà existantes à l'Hˆopital général de Montréal (HGM). Pour évaluer le formalisme de blindage du NCRP 151, des doses équivalentes atténués par barrière ont été mesurés et comparés avec les résultats des calculs du NCRP 151. Cette étude a démontré que, meme si les idées et recommandations du NCRP 151 sont très valables, ses prévisions de doses ne sont pas toujours correctes. En tant que tel, la méthode du NCRP 151 est mieux utilisée en conjonction avec des mesures physiques. L'étude de faisabilité pour des traitements de 6 MV à porte ouverte a utilisé le formalisme du NCRP 151, avec des mesures réalistes pour les charges de travail à 6 MV. Les résultats suggèrent que, dosimetriquement, les traitements de 6 MV à porte ouverte sont réalisables. Une estimation prudente pour la dose plus élevée à la porte découlant de ces traitements est 0.1 mSv, avec un facteur d'occupation de 1/8, comme recommandé dans le rapport du NCRP 151.</description><creator>Kildea, John</creator><contributor>Michael Evans (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Ervin Podgorsak (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery</subject><title>An evaluation of NCRP Report No. 151 - radiation shielding design for radiotherapy facilities, and a feasibility study for 6 MV open-door treatments in an existing high-energy radiation therapy bunker</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35t896t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kn508</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Medical Physics Unit</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72p759d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction: Cisplatin chemotherapy causes ototoxicity manifested as sensorineural hearing loss and/or tinnitus. Ototoxicity is induced via damage to the inner ear by reactive oxygen species. Dexamethasone reduces reactive species and has a well-documented history of transtympanic clinical use for various cochlear disorders. Objectives: Determine the effect of transtympanic dexamethasone on cisplatin ototoxicity in a guinea pig animal model. Material and Methods: Pre- and post-treatment Auditory Brainstem Responses (ABRs) were compared to measure threshold changes in 58 guinea pigs. The optimal ototoxic dose of cisplatin, the safety of dexamethasone and the effect of dexamethasone on cisplatin ototoxicity were examined. Results: Cisplatin at a dose of 12 mg/kg induces significant hearing loss (p &lt; 0.05) with minimal mortality. Transtympanic dexamethasone in cisplatin-treated guinea pigs showed signs of otoprotection particularly in the lower frequencies. Conclusion: Transtympanic dexamethasone presents as a simple, safe and potentially effective treatment modality against cisplatin ototoxicity.</description><description>Introduction: La chimiotherapie au cisplatin cause une perte auditive ototoxique induite par dommages à l'oreille interne par des espèces réactives. La dexaméthasone réduit les espèces réactives et a déjà fait ses preuves dans des traitements trans-tympaniques (TT) de pathologies cochléaires. Objectifs: Déterminer l'effet de la dexaméthasone TT sur l'ototoxicité du cisplatin chez le cobaye. Matériel et méthodes: Les potentiels auditifs évoqués du tronc cérébral (PTE) ont été comparés chez 58 cobayes. La dose ototoxique optimale du cisplatin, la sécurité de la dexaméthasone et l'effet de la dexaméthasone sur l'ototoxicité du cisplatin ont été examinés. Résultats: 12 mg/kg de cisplatin induit une perte auditive significative (p &lt; 0.05) avec une mortalité minime. La dexaméthasone TT a montré des signes d'otoprotection chez les cobayes traités au cisplatin surtout dans les basses fréquences. Conclusion: La dexaméthasone TT se présente comme une modalité de traitement simple, sécuritaire et potentiellement efficace contre l'ototoxicité produite par le cisplatin.</description><creator>Murphy, Denise</creator><contributor>Sam Joseph Daniel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery</subject><title>Transtympanic administration of dexamethasone: an innovative otoprotection against cisplatin chemotherapy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rt73q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p759d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816n02f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse est consacrée aux représentations de la Grande Guerre dans la poésie française écrite entre 1914 et 1918. Plus précisément, elle propose une analyse sociocritique de six oeuvres poétiques écrites tandis que le conflit faisait rage et dans lesquelles la topique guerrière est centrale. Ces textes sont Calligrammes de Guillaume Apollinaire, Discours du Grand Sommeil de Cocteau, Interrogation de Pierre Drieu La Rochelle et les trois recueils suivants de Paul Éluard : Le Devoir, Le Devoir et l'inquiétude et Poèmes pour la paix. La thèse s'ouvre sur un chapitre consacré aux innombrables textes poétiques instrumentalisés qui ont vu le jour entre 1914 et 1918 et qui sont voués à claironner l'honneur des armes ou à proclamer la nécessité de la paix. Suivent trois chapitres permettant de démontrer qu'Apollinaire, Cocteau, Drieu La Rochelle et Éluard déplacent le langage dont on se servait alors communément pour dire la guerre par les moyens du poème. Dans leurs recueils de guerre, le conflit se profile et se déploie selon des modes inattendus. Le deuxième chapitre montre que ces quatre écrivains ont élaboré des figures très ambivalentes de poète-soldat, intriquant autobiographie et fiction d'une façon complexe et troublante, cette imbrication leur permettant de préserver une partie de la subjectivité au milieu du chaos et du drame collectif. Dans le troisième chapitre, la dimension autoréflexive des textes poétiques retenus est étudiée. En ces derniers se profile toujours une réflexion sur la poésie de guerre, sur les rapports qu'elle entretient avec l'événement. Ces poésies de guerre, qui n'oublient jamais l'événement, n'oublient jamais non plus la poésie en tant qu'art et ne cessent de faire retour sur elles-mêmes, se distinguant par là du discours poétique contemporain. Enfin, le dernier chapitre établit que dans les oeuvres analysées, la poésie de guerre ne va jamais toute seule. Elle thématise certes la guerre de façon obvie, mais chacun des poètes retenus parle aussi d'autre chose et interdit qu'on réduise le poème à la seule tragédie militaire. Un motif étranger à ceux que convoque habituellement la topique guerrière se profile toujours d'un bout à l'autre des recueils. Leur développement participe à créer des réseaux de sens parallèles qui permettent non seulement de suggérer des représentations inédites du conflit, mais aussi de faire signifier la poésie dans d'autres registres que le guerrier. Les enjeux poétiques étudiés dans les deuxième, troisième et quatrième chapitres, que sont, respectivement, le statut du sujet poétique, l'autoréflexivité et la visée référentielle de la poésie, mettent en évidence que les oeuvres retenues s'inscrivent toutes de plain-pied dans la modernité poétique. Ces questions étaient au coeur des débats qui agitaient la scène poétique avant-gardiste à l'orée du XXe siècle et les réponses poétiques qui ont été imaginées entre 1914 et 1918 par Apollinaire, Cocteau, Drieu La Rochelle et Éluard préfigurent, en pleine tourmente, le renouveau de la poésie à partir du surréalisme.</description><description>This thesis is dedicated to the representations of the Great War in the French poetry written between 1914 and 1918. More particularly, it proposes a socio-critical analysis of six poetical works created while the conflict was raging and in which the war topic is central. These works are Calligrammes by Guillaume Apollinaire, Discours du Grand Sommeil by Jean Cocteau, Interrogation by Pierre Drieu La Rochelle and the three following collections of poems by Paul Éluard : Le Devoir, Le Devoir et l'inquiétude and Poèmes pour la paix. The thesis opens up with a chapter dedicated to the numerous purposeful poetical texts which were brought to light between 1914 and 1918 and which subject is to trumpet the military honor or to proclaim the need for peace. The next three chapters serve to demonstrate that Apollinaire, Cocteau, Drieu La Rochelle and Éluard used the poem to transform the language then commonly used to describe war. In their war poetry, the conflict is depicted and laid out with unexpected forms. The second chapter shows that the four writers have created thoroughly ambivalent representations of the poet-soldier, mixing autobiography and fiction in a complex and troubling way so as to preserve some of their subjectivity in the midst of the chaos and collective drama. In the third chapter, the self-reflexive dimension of the chosen poems is studied. They always carry a reflection on war poetry and its relations with the event. They never obliterate the war, nor forget about poetry as an art; they always come back to their own source, thereby distinguishing themselves from the contemporary poetic speech. Finally, the last chapter demonstrates that war poetry never stands all by itself. Although the poets being studied thematise war in an obvious way, each of them addresses other subjects, refusing to reduce the poem to its sole representation of the war tragedy. All through those works there lies this motive that is lacking in most war writings. Those subjects are developed so as to create parallel themes not only suggesting new representations of the conflict but also elevating poetry to another level that that of the warrior. The poetic topics analyzed in the second, third and fourth chapters - which respectively treat of the status of the poetic subject, self-reflexivity and the referential aim of poetry - bring to light the fact that the chosen works are definitely part of poetic modernism. All these questions were thoroughly debated on the avant-garde poetic scene at the beginning of the twentieth century and the poetic answers imagined by Apollinaire, Cocteau, Drieu La Rochelle and Éluard amidst the turbulence of the years 1914-1918 foreshadow the renewal of poetry with Surrealism.</description><creator>Parenteau, Olivier</creator><contributor>Michel Biron (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Literature - Modern</subject><title>L'honneur des poètes. Grande guerre et modernité poétique (Apollinaire, Cocteau, Drieu La Rochelle, Éluard)</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j6097.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816n02f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j6100</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>While Milton's ambivalence towards myth has been attributed to pagan-Christian tension or to pressure from a utilitarian culture, I argue that his poetical struggle with Orpheus the enchanting bard is equally political.  His attraction to the divinely gifted singer, evident in his juvenilia, was tempered by the need to take account of the myth's royalist currency as a figure for the ordering power of monarchy.  The court masque epitomized an art of Orphic enchantment designed to spellbind the audience - an art antithetical to Milton's quest for a collaborative readership empowered to choose citizenship over subjection.  Growing dissident under Charles I, he rejected this royalist art of mastery along with the traditional union of bard and king.  Milton used Ovidian irony to reposition Orpheus within a dialogical poetics of engagement that might inspire readers to realize their god-given freedom. I trace the development of Milton's poetics to show that, in search of a mutually beneficial relation between artists and audiences, governors and peoples, his poetry weighs Orphic enchantment against more dialogical models.  I demonstrate how the more secular poems link the pursuit of Orphic art to escapism and question the passivity of the enchanted audience, implying that we open ourselves all too readily to political subjection.  Milton takes on royalist art by gesturing towards a poetics that awakens others to social action.  I further argue that the sacred poems harness the Christian concept of trial to such an anti-authoritarian poetics, delving more deeply into the temptations of Orphic power and the problem at their heart: why do we so often prefer enchantment to engagement, too often deserve subjection for failing to earn citizenship?  While the poems affirm that art can serve engagement, they warn that Orphic temptations such as nostalgia and melancholy may arrest development and encourage disengagement.  Milton builds his epic and his God alike on the levelling model of dialogue.  The freedom fostered by that model is fragile, but engaging in debate gives us a taste for the choosing that it requires, stimulating the desire to exercise our free will further.  The dialogue through which we flourish as reasoners and choosers demands both chutzpah and humility.  The "skilfull and laborious gatherer[s]" expected in Milton's prose become the engaged and collaborative readers for whom his poetry calls by refusing merely to enchant us.</description><description>Tandis que l'ambivalence de Milton envers le mythe a été attribuée ou à la tension entre les traditions païenne et chrétienne ou à la pression d'une culture utilitaire, je soutiens que sa lutte poétique contre Orphée le barde enchanteur est également politique.  Son admiration pour le chanteur divinement doué, évidente dans ses oeuvres de jeunesse, était tempérée par le besoin de tenir compte du crédit dans le milieu royaliste du mythe comme symbole du pouvoir ordinateur de la monarchie.  Le masque de la cour a exemplifié un art d'enchantement orphique destiné à envoûter le public - un art antithétique à la quête de Milton d'un lectorat participant prêt à choisir la citoyenneté plutôt que la subjugation.  En devenant dissident sous Charles Ier, il a rejeté cet art royaliste de la domination ainsi que l'union traditionnelle du poète et du roi.  Milton a employé l'ironie ovidienne pour replacer Orphée dans une poétique dialogique d'engagement qui pourrait inspirer ses lecteurs à réaliser leur liberté, donnée par Dieu. Je suis le développement de la poétique de Milton pour montrer comment, à la recherche d'une relation mutuellement bénéfique entre les artistes et les publics, les gouverneurs et les peuples, sa poésie évalue l'enchantement orphique par rapport à des modèles plus dialogiques.  Je démontre que les poèmes plus séculiers lient la poursuite de l'art orphique à l'évasion et mettent en question la passivité des enchantés, en suggérant que nous nous exposons bien trop volontiers à la subjugation politique.  Milton affronte l'art royaliste en signalant une poétique qui incite les autres à l'action sociale.  Je soutiens en plus que les poèmes sacrés exploitent le concept chrétien de l'épreuve pour cette poétique antiautoritaire, en fouillant plus profondément les tentations du pouvoir orphique et le problème à leur base: pourquoi préférons-nous si souvent l'enchantement à l'engagement, pourquoi méritons-nous trop souvent la subjugation en ne réussissant pas à gagner la citoyenneté?  Alors que les poèmes affirment que l'art peut servir l'engagement, ils avertissent que les tentations orphiques telles que la nostalgie et la mélancolie risquent d'arrêter le développement et de favoriser le désengagement.  Milton construit son épopée et son Dieu d'après le modèle égalisateur du dialogue.  La liberté favorisée par ce modèle est fragile, mais nous lancer dans le débat nous donne le goût de faire les choix que le débat nécessite, en stimulant notre désir d'exercer encore notre libre arbitre.  Le dialogue qui nourrit nos capacités de raisonner et de choisir exige du culot ainsi que de l'humilité.  Les « skilfull and laborious gatherer[s] » attendus dans la prose de Milton deviennent les lecteurs engagés et participants que sa poésie réclame en refusant simplement de nous enchanter.</description><creator>Dawes, Martin</creator><contributor>Margaret A Kilgour (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Literature - English</subject><title>Milton and the politics of orphic enchantment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73pw50c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j6100</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296wz52k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Designers of software components can use finite-state properties to denote behavioral interface specifications which enforce client-side programming rules that state how the components ought to be used. This allows users of these components to check their client code for compliance with these rules, both statically and at runtime. In this dissertation we explain the design and implementation of Clara, a framework for specifying and verifying finite-state properties of large-scale programs. With Clara, programmers specify finite-state properties together with runtime monitors, using a syntactic extension to the aspect-oriented programming language AspectJ. Clara then uses a sequence of three increasingly detailed static analyses to determine if the program satisfies the finite-state properties, i.e., is free of property violations. Clara produces a list of program points at which the program may violate the properties, ranked by a confidence value. If violations are possible, Clara also instruments the program with the supplied runtime monitor, which will capture property violations when the program executes. Due to its static analyses, Clara can omit the instrumentation at program locations which the analyses proved safe, and so optimize the instrumented program. When much instrumentation remains, Clara partitions the instrumentation into subsets, so that one can distribute multiple partially instrumented program versions that each run with a low overhead. We validated the approach by applying Clara to finite-state properties denoted in multiple formalisms over several large-scale Java programs. Clara proved that most of the programs fulfill our example properties. For most other programs, Clara could remove the monitoring overhead to below 10%. We also found multiple property violations by manually inspecting the top entries in Clara's ranked result list.</description><description>Les concepteurs des différentes composantes logicielles peuvent utiliser les propriétés des automates finis pour fixer les spécifications de l'interface comportementale qui contrôleront les règles de programmations définissant l'utilisation des composantes. Ceci permet aux utilisateurs de ces composantes de vérifier le respect de ses règles par leurs codes sources, à la fois lors d'une analyse statique qu'à l'exécution. Dans cette dissertation,  nous montrerons la conception de Clara, une structure qui permet de spécifier et de vérifier les propriétés des automates finis dans des programmes étendus, puis expliquerons son implantation. Le programmeur, à l'aide de Clara, peut définir les propriétés des automates finis en complément aux processus de vérification à l'exécution, en utilisant une extension de la syntaxe d'AspectJ, un langage de programmation orienté aspect. Clara utilise alors, en séquence, trois analyses statiques de précision croissante pour déterminer si le programme respecte les propriétés des automates finis. Clara produit une liste des positions dans le code source où il y a risque de violation de ces «propriétés», en ordre décroissant de  certitude d'une violation. Quand cela  est possible, Clara ajoute au programme  des processus de vérification permettant d'étudier la violation de «propriétés»  lors de son exécution. Grâce à son analyse statique, Clara n'ajoute pas au code  ces processus dans les portions de code qui n'ont pas la possibilité de violer  les propriétés des automates finis, ce qui limite les ralentissements dus aux  processus de vérification. Lorsque ses ajouts restent considérables, Clara  organise les processus de vérification à l'exécution en sous-groupe, de sorte  qu'il soit possible de distribuer différentes versions du programme contenant  seulement une partie de ceux-ci, limitant ainsi l'utilisation des ressources  système à l'exécution. Nous avons validé cette approche en soumettant à Clara les propriétés des automates finis sous différents modèles à appliquer sur différents programmes Java. Clara a permis de prouver que la plupart de ces programmes respectaient déjà les propriétés définies.  Dans les autres cas, Clara a pu réduire le coût des processus de vérification à moins de 10%. De plus, nous avons pu localiser de nombreuses violations de propriété manuellement, en inspectant les entrées en importance dans la liste produite par Clara.</description><creator>Bodden, Eric</creator><contributor>Laurie Hendren (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>Verifying finite-state properties of large-scale programs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r3599.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296wz52k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qp991</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La capacité de l'être humain à adapter ses mouvements à une grande variété de situations témoigne de la grande plasticité du contrôle neuronal du mouvement. Cette plasticité peut s'étudier via l'apprentissage dynamique qui correspond au processus par lequel le système nerveux met en place les signaux neuronaux nécessaires à la production des forces qui génèrent le mouvement. La présente thèse reporte une série d'expériences étudiant l'apprentissage dynamique et sa généralisation. Dans ces expériences, l'apprentissage dynamique est obtenu en amenant le sujet à compenser une perturbation mécanique systématiquement appliquée sur le bras par un robot au cours de l'exécution d'un mouvement d'atteinte de cible. Plus particulièrement, nos études sont centrées sur deux propriétés importantes de l'apprentissage dynamique: (1) le fait que l'apprentissage dynamique impliquerait des instances d'adaptation locales et (2) le fait que la généralisation de cet apprentissage se fonderait sur une interpolation entre ces instances d'adaptation locales. Après une introduction générale dans le Chapitre 1, le Chapitre 2 examine si l'étendue de la généralisation de l'apprentissage dynamique dépend de l'étendue des situations rencontrées lors de la phase d'apprentissage. Le Chapitre 3 est consacré à l'étude de la généralisation de l'apprentissage dynamique à des mouvements de différentes amplitudes. Au Chapitre 4, nous montrons ensuite que la généralisation de l'apprentissage ne relève pas seulement de ces aspects méthodologiques. Comme le rapporte le Chapitre 2, la généralisation dépend aussi de l'étendue de l'apprentissage, elle-même liée aux propriétés biomécaniques des effecteurs. Le Chapitre 5 est consacré à l'évolution de la généralisation de l'apprentissage dynamique au cours du temps. L'ensemble de nos travaux suggère que l'apprentissage dynamique est un processus impliquant une adaptation locale des signaux du contrôle neuronal du mouvement et que l'interpolation de ces instances d'apprentissage local est possible. Ainsi, comme nous le discutons au Chapitre 6, l'apparente facilité de l'être humain à adapter ses mouvements à des situations nouvelles pourrait en réalité être le fruit de l'interpolation entre les instances d'apprentissages antérieurs acquis dans une gamme de situations similaires.</description><description>Humans demonstrate the ability to move with little error in a wide range of situations. To do so requires a high degree of plasticity in the neural control of movement. The study of dynamics learning, the process by which the nervous system learns neural signals that are needed to produce the forces underlying movement, is a well-known method for examining plasticity in motor control. This dissertation reports on a series of experiments on dynamics learning and its generalization. Our studies touch on two important features of the dynamics learning process. The first is that dynamics learning involves instances of local adaptation. The second is that generalization can occur based on interpolation between these instances of learning. Following a General Introduction in Chapter 1, in Chapter 2 we examine whether having learned to move in multiple directions affects the extent of generalization. In Chapter 3, we examine generalization of dynamics learning across changes in movement amplitude. In Chapter 4, we note that generalization of learning does not depend only on the separation between training and test directions, as was shown in Chapter 2. In addition, generalization depends on the extent of learning during training. We examine the effect of impedance - a mechanical property of the arm under neural control - on dynamics learning and generalization. In Chapter 5, we examine generalization of dynamics learning over time. Overall, our findings suggest that dynamics learning is a process involving local adaptation of the neural control signals for movement, and that interpolation between these instances of local learning is possible. These findings suggest that the apparent ease with which humans move in new situations may depend on interpolation between instances of previous learning that were acquired in a range of nearby situations. We elaborate on this idea in a General Discussion in Chapter 6.</description><creator>Mattar, Andrew</creator><contributor>David J Ostry (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Psychology - Experimental</subject><title>Generalization of dynamics learning across direction, distance and time</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35t902r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qp991</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:41687h90d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse examine l'évolution de la réglementation canadienne de la radiodiffusion depuis l'adoption de la Loi sur la radiodiffusion (fédérale) en 1991 en se concentrant plus particulièrement sur la transition à la télévision numérique. Pour le Canada, ce changement de cap est révélateur des grandes modifications que les politiques publiques ont connues dans les deux dernières décennies : une foi dans les mécanismes de marché, une réglementation en pointillé, des approches axées sur la coréglementation et la puissante influence des nouvelles technologies. La question centrale étudiée dans ce mémoire est la suivante : la politique sous-jacente à la transition à la télédiffusion numérique constitue-t-elle un défi en regard des préoccupations traditionnelles afférentes au rôle de la radiodiffusion dans la démocratie canadienne ? Adoptant une approche de économie politique institutionnelle, cette étude se fonde sur l'étude de documents gouvernementaux ou provenant des entreprises privées oeuvrant dans le secteur ainsi que sur des entretiens effectués avec certains acteurs clés de la radiodiffusion canadienne. Cette thèse offre une contribution unique au savoir quant à trois aspects : établir des paramètres clairs permettant de différencier les politiques de la réglementation dans le domaine de la radiodiffusion ; offrir la première étude détaillée sur la transition canadienne à la télévision numérique, et présenter une analyse du développement et de l'impact de l'autoréglementation et de la coréglementation dans les politiques canadiennes relatives à la radiodiffusion. Les conclusions de cette étude mettent en lumière les dynamiques de pouvoir existant entre les divers acteurs engagés dans le processus d'élaboration et d'adoption des politiques canadiennes, l'influence des nouvelles technologies et les grandes orientations politiques ayant prévalu dans le domaine de la radiodiffusion depuis l'adoption d</description><description>This thesis examines the evolution of Canadian broadcasting regulation since the adoption of the 1991 Broadcasting Act with a specific focus on the digital television transition.  For Canada, this technological shift exemplifies many of the greater changes in public policy in the last two decades: a faith in market mechanisms, light-touch regulation, co-regulatory approaches, and the powerful influence of new technologies.  This dissertation will address the following central question: does the policy surrounding the transition to digital television broadcasting pose a challenge to traditional concerns of the role of broadcasting in Canadian democracy?  Utilizing the approach of institutional political economy, this study is informed by primary government and industry documents and interviews conducted with key actors within Canadian broadcasting. This dissertation offers a unique contribution to knowledge in three areas: establishing clear parameters for the differences between policy and regulations in Canadian broadcasting; offering the first comprehensive study of the Canadian digital television transition; and analyzing the growth and impact of self and co-regulation in Canadian broadcasting policy. The results of this study speak to the power dynamics amid the range of actors involved in the Canadian policy process, the influence of new technologies, and the greater prevailing policy directions in broadcasting since the 1991 Broadcasting Act was adopted.</description><creator>Taylor, Gregory</creator><contributor>Raboy, Marc (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Mass Communications</subject><title>Canadian broadcasting regulation and the digital television transition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mm71d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687h90d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s0588</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Now that the genome has successfully been sequenced, the next aim will be to characterize and annotate features. With the development of high resolution tools, such as Chromosome Conformation Capture (3C) technology, the 3-dimensional architecture of large linear spans of DNA can be determined. We have established that the mouse HoxA gene cluster is structured in such a way as to contain four distinct looping regions with a central interacting rosette core in its resting pluripotent state. This central core feature might directly affect the spatiotemporal regulation of the Hox genes during normal development as well as differentiation via retinoic acid administration in the P19 embryonal carcinoma cell line. The DNA looping might be mediated by cis-regulatory elements, which could function in a cooperative manner to regulate HoxA gene expression. Regulatory elements might include the previously identified retinoic acid response elements (RAREs) known to mediate specific developmental cues. Interestingly, Hox genes expressed earlier and more anteriorly are within loops containing higher amounts of identified RAREs as well as other conserved non-coding sequences that also appear to play a potential role in orchestrating the collinear mechanism of action. Loops containing the more 5' located genes have fewer regulatory elements and therefore may respond later to developmental cues.</description><description>Maintenant que le génome été séquencé avec succès, le but suivant sera de caractériser et annoter les caractéristiques regulataire. Avec le développement d'instruments de haute résolution, comme la technologie du Capture de Conformation Chromatin (3C), l'architecture 3- dimensionnelle de grandes durées linéaires d'ADN peut être déterminée. Nous avons établi que le groupe de gène de HoxA dans la souris est structurée d'une telle façon pour contenir quatre régions boucles distinctes avec un centre de rosette réagissant réciproquement central dans son état de reposant pluripotent. On croit que cette caractéristique centrale de base directement affecte le règlement spatiotemporel des gènes Hox pendant le développement normal aussi bien que la différentiation via l'administration acide rétinoïque dans le P19 ligne de cellule de carcinome. Les éléments cis-de-contrôle responsables de définir ces boucles ont l'air de fonctionner dans une manière coopérative dans laquelle le pluripotent HoxA l'état est plein d'assurance de réagir à l'administration acide rétinoïque dans une manière colinéaire contrôlée d'expression de gène.  Auparavant identifié les éléments de réponse acide rétinoïque (ERARs) sont organisés pour tenir compte de la réorganisation dynamique du groupe sur la réception de signaux spécifiques du développement. Les gènes de Hox ont exprimé tôt et sont plus antérieurement dans les boucles qui contiennent de plus hautes quantités de ERARs identifié aussi bien que d'autres ordres de non-codification conservés qui ont aussi l'air de jouer un rôle potentiel dans le fait d'orchestrer le mécanisme colinéaire d'action.</description><creator>Pinchuk, Matthew</creator><contributor>Josee Dostie (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>The 3-Dimensional landscape of the mouse hox A cluster conforms to collinear function</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fc006.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s0588</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354f66f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Industrial applications such as pulp washing and displacement bleaching of pulp are using the flow of reactants and products through a packed bed of fibers, because this is the most efficient contact process in terms of energy requirements. The adsorption phenomenon can be quantified using a packed bed of pulp fibers, and measuring the exit concentration of polymer (breakthrough curve) for various polymer inlet concentrations. The concentration of the polymer at the exit can be monitored on-line by UV-Vis spectroscopy, and by polyelectrolyte titration. The kinetics of polymer adsorption can be evaluated under different solution conditions (pH, concentration). The amounts of adsorbed polyelectrolyte can be calculated from differences between the breakthrough curves of an inert tracer and those of the polymers. The transport and adsorption behaviour of two cationic polyelectrolytes were studied in columns of packed beds of pulp fibers: polyethylenimine (PEI), and poly-trimethyl aminoethyl chloride acrylate (p-TMAEAC). The results show that polyelectrolyte adsorption on fibers in packed beds is similar to that on suspended fibers subjected to flow. The kinetics of adsorption of PEI on pulp fibers is faster at pH 10 than at pH 6, while the adsorbed amount is about 4 times as large. This is ascribed to the porosity of the fibers, the polydispersity of PEI and the pH-dependence of the size of PEI molecules.</description><description>Des applications industrielles telles que le lavage de la pâte à papier et le blanchiment par déplacement de la pâte à papier utilisent le flux de réactifs et de produits au travers d'un lit à garnissage de fibres cellulosiques, parce que ce procédé est le plus efficace au niveau de la consommation d'énergie. Le phénomène d'adsorption peut être quantifié en utilisant un lit à garnissage de fibres cellulosiques et en mesurant la concentration du polymère à la sortie du lit (la courbe de percée) pour des concentrations différentes de polymères. La concentration du polymère à la sortie du lit peut être analysée en continu par spectroscopie UV-Vis, et par titrage de polyélectrolytes. La cinétique de l'adsorption des polymères peut être évaluée dans des conditions variables de la solution (e.g. le pH, la concentration). Les quantités de polyélectrolyte adsorbées peuvent être calculées par les différences entre les courbes de percée d'un traceur inerte et ceux des polymères. Les deux polyélectrolytes cationiques dont le transport et l'adsorption ont été étudiés dans des colonnes remplies de fibres cellulosiques sont le polyéthylénimine (PEI) et le chlorure de poly-triméthyl aminoéthyl acrylate (p-TMAEAC). Les résultats montrent que l'adsorption de polyélectrolytes sur des fibres cellulosiques dans des lits à garnissage est semblable à celle sur des fibres en suspension dans un flux. La cinétique de l'adsorption de PEI sur les fibres cellulosiques est plus rapide à pH 10 qu'à pH 6 et la quantité adsorbée est environ 4 fois plus grande. Ceci est attribué à la porosité des fibres, à la polydispersité du PEI, et à la variation de la taille moléculaire du PEI selon le pH.</description><creator>Ciovica, Laura</creator><contributor>Theodorus G Van de Ven (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Nathalie Tufenkji (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Engineering - Chemical</subject><title>Polyelectrolyte adsorption on packed beds of pulp fibers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977v28v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354f66f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv9353405</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La production de la  banane était  la plus importante activité pour l'économie de Ste. Lucie, avant de  la commercialisation internationale des bananes. Utilisant des données provenant d'une enquête sur les dépenses des ménages et sur l'impôt sur le revenu des particuliers le potentiel que l'état d'inégalité et du bien-être en Ste. Lucie ait a changer été fut déterminé. Une méthode non-paramétrique d'autoamorçage servit à tirer des inférences à partir du coefficient de Gini quant aux changements à l'inégalité à l'échelon national entre 1995 et 2005. .Comme le changement du coefficient de Gini ne fut pas significatif,  cette analyse ne porta aucun d'appui statistique à l'idée que le niveau d'inégalité ait changé après la libéralisation  Choisissant les contribuables comme sous-ensemble de la population, une inférence non-paramétrique appliqué à des courbes de Lorenz indiqua que des améliorations significatives au bien-être des 20% plus pauvres se manifesta durant la période suivant la libéralisation  (1998-2007). Afin d'obtenir des résultats plus robustes à l'avenir, le développement d'un régime de collecte des données à long terme doit être visé.</description><description>Banana production was central to the economy of St. Lucia prior to the liberalization of international banana marketing. The potential for change in inequality and welfare following this liberalization was examined using household expenditure survey and income tax filer data.  The non-parametric bootstrap method was used to conduct statistical inference on the Gini coefficient to assess the change in inequality, at the national level between 1995 and 2005.  It was concluded that the change in the Gini coefficient was not statistically significant so this analysis does not provide statistical support for a change in inequality following the liberalization. Lorenz curves were constructed with the income tax data, and then distribution free statistical inference performed on them, indicating that there were statistically significant improvements in welfare for the poorest 20 percent of these income distributions, after the liberalization (1998-2007). For more robust results in the future, attention should be given to the development of long term data collection.</description><creator>Lewis, Lerona</creator><contributor>John C Henning (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Economics - Agricultural</subject><title>Effect of the change in the EU international banana marketing regime on inequality and welfare in St. Lucia (1995 - 2005)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405s9778.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv9353405</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930bx57z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The genus Trachyphloeomimus is redescribed and the T. championi species group is revised. The T. championi group includes three previously described species: T. championi O'Brien, T. spurcus Champion, T. undulatoides O'Brien; and thirteen new species: T. apionus, T. arcuatibius, T. batmobile, T. bravoensis, T. calcaritibius, T. carinatus, T. discus, T. festivipenis, T. heliconodulus, T. jonesi, T. junctus, T. obrieni, T. popeyeus. Relationships among these species are assessed and discussed and the monophyly of the species group is demonstrated. A key to species in the T. championi group and illustrations of species-group level defining characters are provided. Species in the T. championi group are restricted to Mexico, largely in the state of Oaxaca, but the distribution of the genus now includes Mexico, Guatemala, Costa Rica, Nicaragua, Honduras and El Salvador. Six of the sixteen species in the T. championi group are known only from females.</description><description>Le genre Trachyphloeomimus est redécrit et le groupe d'espèces de T. championi est mis à jour. Le groupe de T. championi inclut trois espèces précédemment décrites: T. championi O'Brien, T. spurcus Champion, T. undulatoides O'Brien; et treize nouvelles espèces: T. apionus, T. arcuatibius, T. batmobile, T. bravoensis, T. calcaritibius, T. carinatus, T. discus, T. festivipenis, T. heliconodulus, T. jonesi, T. junctus, T. obrieni, T. popeyeus. Les liens entre ces espèces sont évalués et discuté et la monophylie du groupe d'espèces est démontrée. Une clé pour les espèces dans le groupe de T. championi et des illustrations des caractères qui définissent le niveau d'espèce-groupe sont fournies. Des espèces dans le groupe de T. championi sont limitées au Mexique, en grande partie dans l'état d'Oaxaca, mais la distribution du genre inclut maintenant le Mexique, le Guatemala, le Costa Rica, le Nicaragua, le Honduras et le Salvador. Six des seize espèces dans le groupe de T. championi sont connus seulement au niveau des femelles.</description><creator>Horsley, Pamela</creator><contributor>Robert Samuel Anderson (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Terry A Wheeler (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Entomology</subject><title>Systematics of the genus «Trachyphloeomimus» Champion (Coleoptera: Curculionidae) with a revision of the «T. championi» species group</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b168d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930bx57z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xp68kg812</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>5-10% of hereditary breast cancer cases are caused by germline mutations in well-defined, dominantly acting susceptibility genes such as BRCA1 and BRCA2. However, more than 50% of the genetic predisposition to hereditary breast cancer remains unexplained. In the following thesis, we present a multifaceted approach aimed at further elucidating hereditary breast cancer associated with BRCA1 and BRCA2 interacting genes; specifically, by analyzing the potential contribution from of two previously unscreened BRCA1-associating genes, RAP80 and Abraxas, assessing the presence and risk associated with CHEK2 susceptibility alleles in the previously uninvestigated French Canadian population and by investigating molecular and cellular mechanisms underlying the increased risk associated with PALB2 susceptibility alleles. A combination of genotyping 96 BRCA1/2 negative, high risk breast cancer patients and segregation analysis was utilized in the determination of whether or not RAP80 and Abraxas are breast cancer susceptibility genes. The contribution of CHEK2 associated breast cancer amongst the French Canadian population was determined through the genotyping 25 BRCA1/2 negative, high risk breast cancer and a cohort of 25 controls. Finally, the biological significance of four PALB2 susceptibility alleles was investigated through the use of the cellular cytotoxicity assay WST-1, telomere specific Q-FISH, centromere specific FISH and spectral karyotyping. The results presented herein suggest that both RAP80 and Abraxas are not high to moderately penetrant breast cancer susceptibility genes. Further, our results suggest that alleles other than the CHEK2 1100delC are unlikely to significantly contribute to the hereditary breast cancer risk in the French Canadian population. Lastly, the results obtained throughout our analysis of PALB2 heterozygous cell lines may be suggestive of a possible chromosomal instability phenotype predisposing carriers to additional tumourgenic mechanisms.</description><description>5-10% des cas de cancer héréditaire du sein sont causés par des mutations germinales dans des gènes des susceptibilité bien caractérisés et à l'effet dominant tel les gènes BRCA1 et BRCA2. Cependant, plus de 50% de la prédisposition génétique au cancer du sein héréditaire demeure inexpliquée. Dans cette thèse, nous présentons une approche à trois volets ayant pour but d'étudier les cas de cancer héréditaire du sein associés avec des gènes interagissant avec BRCA1 et BRCA2. D'abord, nous analysons la contribution potentielle de deux gènes peu caractérisés qui sont partenaires de BRCA1 : RAP80 et Abraxas. Nous étudions ensuite le risque associé avec la présence d'allèles nouveaux ou connus du gène CHEK2 jamais encore caractérisés dans la population canadienne française. Enfin, nous examinons les mécanismes cellulaires et moléculaires responsables de l'augmentation du risque de cancer du sein conférée par des allèles à risque du gène PALB2. Nous avons utilisé une combinaison de génotypage chez 96 patients souffrant du cancer du sein mais étant non porteurs de mutations dans BRCA1/2 et d'analyse de ségrégation des mutations et des phénotypes dans leurs familles afin de déterminer si RAP80 et Abraxas sont ou non des gènes de prédisposition au cancer héréditaire du sein. La contribution au risque de cancer du sein du gène CHEK2 fût déterminée grâce au génotypage de 25 cas à haut risque, non porteurs de mutations chez BRCA1/2, et de 25 contrôles sans cancer. Finalement, nous avons étudié 4 allèles nonsense du gène PALB2 à l'aide du test de toxicité cellulaire WST-1 ainsi qu'en utilisant l'analyse Q-FISH spécifique aux télomères, l'analyse FISH spécifique aux centromères et finalement par caryotype spectral (SKY). Les résultats présentés dans cet ouvrage suggèrent que RAP80 et Abraxas ne sont pas des gènes de susceptibilité au cancer du sein à pénétrance moyenne ou élevée. De plus, il est peu probable que des allèles du gène CHEK2 autres que l'allèle connu 1100delC contribuent de façon significative au risque de cancer du sein héréditaire dans la population canadienne française. Par contre, les résultats de notre analyse du gène PALB2 dans les lignées cellulaires hétérozygotes pour un allèle nonsense suggèrent la possibilité que la présence de ces allèles crée de l'instabilité chromosomique chez les porteurs de mutations qui puissent prédisposer à la progression tumorale.</description><creator>Novak, David</creator><contributor>Marc Derek Tischkowitz (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>William Foulkes (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>A multifaceted approach to elucidating the role of BRCA1- and BRCA2- related genes in hereditary breast cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gd442.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kg812</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354f698</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We reported that transgenic mice constitutively expressing the B7.2 (CD86) T cell costimulatory ligand on microglia spontaneously develop a T cell-mediated demyelinating disease.  We have shown that CD8+ T cells are the primary effector T cell-subset that initiates the pathological process. This demyelinating disease appears to be initiated by the activation antigen-specific CD8+ T cells within the central nervous system (CNS) and shows a complete dependence on IFN-gamma receptor signalling. To further understand the pathological process that occurs in this animal model, we characterized the phenotypic and functional status of the CD8+ T cells that accumulate/expand in the CNS.  Our data indicate that the CNS CD8+ T cells have unusual phenotypic and functional characteristics resembling effector-memory CD8+ T cells in an activated state. The CD8+ T cells in the CNS have a homogenous phenotype that closely resembles effector-memory CD8+ T cells.  They are CD44high, CD62-Llow, CCR7low/neg, CD127high and Ly6Chigh when compared to the spleen of control and Line 31 mice. They also express cell surface markers characteristics of acutely activated cells (CD69, CD25, an isoform of CD43 recognized by the monoclonal antibody 1B11 and NKG2D). However, the CD8+ T cells that accumulate in the CNS of L31 mice differ from typical effector-memory CD8+ T cells by their low level of CD122 expression, the beta chain for the IL-2 and IL-15 receptor. We also show both at the mRNA and protein levels that they are well equipped to kill target cells through various cytotoxic pathways. After short restimulation (4 hours), the majority of the CD8+ T cells produced IFN-gamma and TNF-alpha and some cells produced IL-2. On a per cell basis, the production of TNF-alpha was much higher by the CNS than the splenic CD8+ T cells. CNS CD8+ T cells also produced the cytotoxic molecules perforin and granzyme B after short restimulation and were able to kill target cells in a cytotoxic assay.</description><description>Nous avions rapporté que les souris transgéniques (Line 31) qui expriment constitutivement le ligand de costimulation des lymphocytes T, B7-2 (CD86), dans les microglies, développent spontanément une maladie de démyelination induite par les lymphocytes T. Nous avions montré que les lymphocytes T CD8+ étaient les principales cellules effectrices dans cette pathologie. Cette maladie de démyelination semble être initiée par l'activation des lymphocytes CD8+ spécifiques pour un antigène présent dans le système nerveux central (SNC) et son développement est strictement dépendant de la signalisation par le récepteur d'IFN-gamma. Afin de mieux comprendre le procédé pathologique observé chez ces animaux, nous avons caractérisé le phénotype et le statut fonctionnel des lymphocytes CD8+ qui s'accumulent dans le SNC. Nos résultats indiquent que les lymphocytes CD8+ du SNC ont des caractéristiques phénotypiques et fonctionnelles inhabituelles semblables aux lymphocytes CD8+ effecteurs/mémoires dans un état activé. Les lymphocytes CD8+ du SNC ont un phénotype homogène similaire aux cellules effectrices/mémoires. Ils sont CD44haut, CD62-Lbas, CCR7bas/neg, CD127haut et Ly6Chaut comparés aux lymphocytes CD8+ de la rate des souris contrôles et des souris Line 31. Ils expriment aussi des marqueurs de surface caractéristiques de cellules activées (CD69, CD25, un isoforme of CD43 reconnu par l'anticorps monoclonal 1B11 et NKG2D). Cependant, les lymphocytes  CD8+ du SNC sont différents des cellules effectrices/mémoires typiques par leur basse expression de CD122, la chaîne beta du récepteur de IL-2 et IL-15. Nous avons aussi montré, tant au niveau des protéines que de l'ARN messager, que ces cellules sont bien équipées pour tuer des cellules cibles via plusieurs processus cytotoxiques. Après une courte restimulation, la plupart des lymphocytes CD8+ du SNC produisent de l'IFN-gamma et du TNF-alpha. Certaines cellules sont aussi capables de$</description><creator>Ndiaye, Marie Monique</creator><contributor>Sylvie Fournier (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Immunology</subject><title>Phenotypic and functional characteristics of CNS CD8+ T cells mediating a demyelinating disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hj53k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354f698</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bb98v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>West Nile Virus (WNV) is maintained in bird populations by ornithophilic mosquito vectors. It invades mammalian hosts through the action of bridging vectors, which are either indiscriminant feeders or arise when strict feeding preferences break down. Patterns of seasonal abundance of mosquito species along an East-West transect through urban, suburban and rural habitats from Montréal to Rigaud, Québec, were used in conjunction with temperature and rainfall data to develop models to predict population abundance of three mosquito species, Aedes vexans (Meigen, 1830), Aedes triseriatus (Say, 1823) and Culex pipiens (Linnaeus, 1758). All three species have been implicated as important vectors of WNV. Modelling predicted exponential population growth for Ae. vexans and Ae. triseriatus at high temperatures and precipitation levels in the Rural and Suburban environments. More moderate conditions have additive and/or diminutive effects on population abundance. In the Rural habitat, Ae. vexans may outcompete Cx. pipiens. Culex pipiens was predicted to be more resistant to desiccation and wash-out conditions, most likely due to the availability of artificial breeding habitats, and was the only species predicted to exhibit exponential growth in the Urban environment. Blood meal analysis revealed that 88.56% of mosquitoes fed on humans, and 5.97% on raccoons. The remainder fed on a number of other mammals, but none fed on birds. These findings may explain the low level of WNV in southwestern Québec.</description><description>Le maintien du virus du Nil occidental (VNO) dans les populations aviaires est assuré par les populations de moustiques ornithophiles. Sa propagation aux hôtes mammifères est due aux vecteurs passerelles soit lors de changement d'habitudes alimentaires strictes ou grâce aux espèces qui se nourrissent de façon non discriminatoire. L'échantillonnage des populations saisonnières de moustiques le long d'un transect est-ouest dans les secteurs urbains, de banlieue (suburbains) et ruraux de Montréal à Rigaud, Québec, a été utilisés en combinaison avec les mesures de températures et de précipitations afin de développer un modèle de prédiction des populations espèces : Aedes vexans (Meigen, 1830), Aedes triseriatus (Say, 1823) et Culex pipiens (Linnaeus, 1758). Les trois sont considérées comme des vecteurs importants du VNO. Le modèle prédit une croissance exponentielle de la population pour Ae. vexans et Ae. triseriatus à hauts niveaux de températures et de précipitations dans les environnements ruraux et suburbains. Des niveaux de températures et de précipitations modérées peuvent avoir impact positif ou négatif sur l'abondance des populations. Dans l'habitat rural, Ae. vexans peut surpasser Cx. pipiens. Les résultats ont démontré que Cx. pipiens peut être plus résistant à la sécheresse et au lavage par la pluie, sûrement dû à la présence d'habitats artificiels favorables à la reproduction, et était la seule espèce dont la croissance prédite était exponentielle en milieu urbain. L'analyse des repas sanguins a révélé que 88.56% des moustiques se sont nourris sur les humains, 5.97% sur les ratons laveurs, le reste sur d'autres mammifères, mais aucun sur des oiseaux. Ces résultats peuvent expliquer la faible prévalence du VNO dans le sud-ouest du Québec.</description><creator>Pritchard, Edgar Jonathan</creator><contributor>Manfred Ernst Rau (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>David James Lewis (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Entomology</subject><title>Seasonal abundance and distribution of mosquito species (Culicidae) in southwestern Québec and their potential role as vectors of West Nile Virus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mv61s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bb98v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tm441</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette dissertation cherche l'origine des idées occidentales de proportion à partir du concept de l'articulation dans la Grèce archaïque et classique. De nos jours, l'articulation est perçue comme étant le jointoiement de pièces pour fabriquer un objet, telle la connexion physique entre des pièces de bois, tissu, métal, ou pierre. Toutefois, dans le grec archaïque, les mots utilisés pour décrire ces procédés d'assemblage parlaient aussi, et inextricablement, de la signification pour une personne, une chose, ou le monde, d'être beau, sain et juste. La première section de la dissertation explore, à partir de l'oeuvre d'Homère, les idées archaïques d'expérience corporelle (chapitre un); de métiers d'art (chapitre deux); puis de leurs interrelations (chapitre trois). Ces chapitres mettent l'emphase sur la manière dont le langage et les concepts d'articulation construisirent une perception du monde particulière à la Grèce antique. Ensuite, la deuxième section examine les idées antiques de proportion, dans la vie sociale et politique telle que dépeinte dans Homère (chapitre quatre); dans les idées classiques du corps humain médicalisé et le corps humain civique de la polis (chapitre cinq); puis dans les théories cosmogoniques d'Empédocle et de Platon (chapitre six). Ainsi, cette dissertation vise à démontrer comment les idées d'articulations permirent d'une part et évoluèrent d'autre part en celles de proportions, fusionnant l'ordre du corps, du cosmos, et des métiers d'art, incluant l'architecture.</description><description>This dissertation searches for the origins of western ideas of proportion in the archaic and classical Greek conceptual terrain of articulation. We think of articulation, in the first instance, as having to do with the joining of parts to fabricate an object, such as in the physical connection of pieces of wood, cloth, metal, or stone. However, the early Greek language that described these craft processes also, and inextricably, spoke in a number of ways about what it meant for a person, thing, or the world to be beautiful, healthy, and just. Taking Homer as its primary source, Part One therefore explores archaic ideas of bodily experience (Chapter One); of crafts (Chapter Two); and of the interrelations between the two (Chapter Three). These chapters lay emphasis on how the language and concepts of articulation constructed a worldview particular to early Greece. Part Two then examines early ideas of proportion, in social and political life as depicted by Homer (Chapter Four); in classical ideas about the medicalized human body and the civic body of the polis (Chapter Five); and in the cosmogonic theories of Empedocles and Plato (Chapter Six). In so doing, I aim to demonstrate how ideas of articulation allowed for and expanded into those of proportion, binding together the ordering of bodies, of the kosmos, and of crafts, including architecture.</description><creator>Chang, Lian</creator><contributor>Alberto Perez-Gomez (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Architecture</subject><title>Articulation and the origins of proportion in archaic and classical Greece</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rd992.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tm441</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967413c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background: The question whether certain cognitive domains in schizophrenia qualify as disproportionate/core impairments against a back-drop of generalized deficits remains unresolved. Investigating more homogeneous subgroups of patients may enhance our understanding of the exact nature of disproportionate deficits. Method: One-hundred and twenty-one patients attending an early psychosis program completed a neuropsychological battery comprising of six cognitive domains and IQ. Symptom severity and pre-morbid adjustment were also assessed. Results: Early psychosis patients with high levels of negative symptoms and "stable-poor" pre-morbid functioning have severe generalized cognitive impairment. Patients with low levels of negative symptoms and "stable-good" pre-morbid adjustment present with milder generalized impairments. Conclusion: Contrary to our hypothesis, visual memory appears to be disproportionally impaired against a back-drop of severe generalized cognitive deficits in early psychosis patients. Patients who have a consistently poor (stable-poor) course pre-morbid adjustment and those with high levels of negative symptoms are more impaired.</description><description>Contexte: Les déficits cognitifs sont hétérogènes chez les schizophrènes. La question reliée à la présence de certains déficits cognitifs disproportionnés par rapport à un déficit généralisé reste non-résolue. L`étude de sous-groupes de patients plus homogènes au niveau de la sévérité des symptômes et du fonctionnement prémorbide pourrait éclairer notre compréhension entourant la nature exacte des déficits disproportionnés. Méthode : Cent-vingt et un patients suivis dans un programme de premier épisode psychotique ont complété une batterie neuropsychologique complète évaluant cinq domaines cognitifs et le QI global. La sévérité des symptômes et le fonctionnement prémorbide ont aussi été évalués. Résultats : Dans un échantillon hétérogène de premier épisode de psychose, les patients présentent des déficits cognitifs généralisés sévères. En classifiant les patients en sous-groupes, ceux avec de hauts niveaux de symptômes négatifs et un fonctionnement prémorbide «stable-pauvre » présentent des déficits cognitifs généralisés sévères. Les patients avec peu de symptômes négatifs et un fonctionnement prémorbide « stable-bon » démontrent des déficits généralisés plus modérés. Conclusion: Nos résultats indiquent la présence de sévères déficits cognitifs au niveau de la mémoire visuelle et de la vitesse de traitement de l`information chez les jeunes souffrant d`un premier épisode de psychose. De plus, il semble plus prononcés chez  les patients avec un fonctionnement prémorbide «stable-pauvre ».</description><creator>Bechard-Evans, Laura</creator><contributor>Ashok Malla (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Mental Health</subject><title>Core cognitive impairments and their association with symptomatology and premorbid adjustment in first-episode psychosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xs059.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967413c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712m705z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Aims:  1) to compare pregnant women's energy intake (EI), physical activity (PA) and gestational weight gain (GWG) to current recommendations 2) to explore PA and GWG health professional (HP) advice and 3) to determine behaviors associated with GWG. Methods: Women (n = 81) were recruited from prenatal classes.  Current weight and pre-pregnancy weight were documented.  Pregnancy PA levels and HP advice for PA and GWG were surveyed using questionnaires.  Dietary recalls and pedometer steps were recorded. Results:  Participants included women with normal body mass indices (BMI), average EI (2237 kcal/d) and EE (2328 kcal/d).  Most exceeded GWG recommendations despite receiving HP advice regarding GWG (74%) and PA (73%).  Majority were classified as low active (36%, &lt; 7500 steps/d).  Women who achieved &gt;8.5 MET-hr/wk were most likely to achieve appropriate GWG. Conclusion: Pregnant women need to receive appropriate PA and GWG guidelines.  Development of pregnancy step and MET-hr/wk recommendations are warranted.</description><description>Buts: 1) l'apport énergétique (AE), la pratique de l'activité physique (AP) et le gain de poids gestationnel (GPG) pour établir si les femmes enceintes observent les recommandations, 2) étudier l'impact des conseils reçus des professionnels de la santé sur le GPG et la pratique d'AP,  3) déterminer les comportements associés au GPG recommandé. Méthodes: Les femmes enceinte (n=81) ont été recrutées. Le poids, AP actuels et le conseil de pourvoyeur pour le AP et GWG a été étudié en utilisant des questionnaires. La consommation alimentaire et les pas d'un pédomètre ont été enregistrés. Résultats: Les participantes à l'étude avaient un indice de masse corporelle (IMC) moyen de 23.3 ± 4 kg/m2 avant la grossesse, un AE moyen de 2237 kcal/jour et une dépense énergétique moyenne de 2328 kcal/jour. Par contre, celles-ci ont eu un GPG hebdomadaire supérieur aux recommandations malgré avoir reçu des conseils au sujet de GPG (74%) et de l'AP (73%). La plupart des femmes étaient sédentaires (&lt; 5000 pas / jours) ou légèrement active (36%, &lt; 7500 pas / jours). Les femmes ayant un niveau d'AP supérieur à 8.5 MET-hr/sem avait plus de change d'avoir un GPG approprié. Conclusion: Les femmes enceintes doivent recevoir les conseils relatifs à l'AP et au GPG.   L'élaboration de recommandations pour le nombre de pas quotidien durant la grossesse et le nombre de MET-hr/sem est justifié pour encourager la pratique de l'AP lors de la grossesse.</description><creator>Cohen, Tamara</creator><contributor>Kristine G Koski (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Nutrition</subject><title>Survey of nutrition and physical activity during pregnancy: the SNAP study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jv084.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m705z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cr56n1584</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background: High frequency oscillations (HFOs) are transient electroencephalographic events that may play a role in epileptogenesis.  Initially detected using microcontacts (10-3 mm2), they can be recorded using macrocontacts (1 to 20 mm2).  It has been demonstrated that microcontacts detect HFOs better than macrocontacts.  Given the wide range of clinical contact sizes, it was hypothesized that smaller macrocontacts detect HFOs better than larger macrocontacts. Methods: Rates, characteristics and cross correlation of HFOs, coherence and amount of artefact were compared between the recordings from adjacent contacts of electrodes containing contiguous macrocontacts of different sizes, in 10 patients and 8 experimental animals. Results: Rates and characteristics were not significantly different between the different contact sizes.  Differences in coherence and artefact were not significant. Conclusion: In the range tested, contact size did not affect HFO detection rate.  Further study remains to be done to determine if larger contact sizes than those evaluated here are also equivalent.</description><description>Introduction : Les oscillations de haute fréquence (high frequency oscillations, HFOs) sont de brefs phénomènes électroencéphalographiques qui pourraient jouer un rôle dans l'épileptogénèse.  Initialement décrites à partir d'enregistrements à l'aide de microcontacts (10-3 mm2), les HFOs peuvent aussi être enregistrées par des macrocontacts (1 à 20 mm2), mais ces derniers paraissent moins efficaces à les détecter.  Vu le spectre de tailles des macrocontacts, nous avons supposé que de plus petits macrocontacts détectent mieux les HFOs que de plus grands Méthodes : Les taux de détection, caractéristiques et corrélation croisée des HFOs, ainsi que la cohérence et les artéfacts de l'EEG, ont été comparés entre des enregistrements intracrâniens provenant de contacts contigus mais de taille différente chez 8 rats expérimentaux et 10 patients. Résultats : Aucune différence significative de taux, caractéristiques, cohérence ni artéfact n'a été décelée. Conclusion : A l'intérieur du spectre de tailles étudiées, la taille du contact n'influence pas la détection des HFOs.  Il reste à déterminer si des macrocontacts plus grands demeurent aussi efficaces.</description><creator>Châtillon, Claude-Edouard</creator><contributor>Jean Gotman (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery</subject><title>The effect of contact size on high frequency oscillation in human and rat intracerebral EEG recordings</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xc30t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n1584</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43425</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>