<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:09:57Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):30300" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv935449v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:17:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of this study was to explore applied and mechanistic aspects of the silane dehydropolymerization reaction catalyzed by cationic early transition metallocene compounds. This problem was dealt with by a combination of spectroscopic techniques, kinetic studies, and trapping of reaction intermediates. The results of this integrated approach allow the proposal of a new redox mechanism for the dehydropolymerization reaction which explains and predicts the reactivity and selectivity of cationic early transition metal catalysts. The novel zirconocene complexes $ rm lbrack Cp sp prime sb2 Zr( mu$-H)(SiHR) rbrack$ sb2 sp{2+}$ lbrack BR$ sp prime sb{n}$(C$ sb6$F$ sb5) sb{4-n} rbrack sb2 sp{2-}$(Cp$ sp prime$ = Cp, MeCp, Me$ sb5$Cp; R = Ph or PhCH$ sb2;$ R$ sp prime$=Bu or H) were isolated from silane dehydropolymerization reaction mixtures catalyzed by Cp$ sp prime sb2$ZrCl$ sb2$/2BuLi/B(C$ sb6$F$ sb5) sb3$ or by $ rm lbrack Cp sp prime sb2Zr( mu$-H)H rbrack$ sb2$/2B(C$ rm sb6 F sb5) sb3$ combination catalysts. A total structure analysis of these compounds, performed by multinuclear, multidimensional NMR spectroscopy, shows that each zirconocene fragment bears a positive charge, which is delocalized between the metal center and the hydrosilane ligand. Reactions and intermediates leading to zirconocene complexes $ rm lbrack Cp sp prime sb2Zr( mu$-H)(SiHr) rbrack$ sb2 sp{2+}$ lbrack BR$ sp prime sb{n}$(C$ sb6$F$ sb5) sb{4-n} rbrack sb2 sp{2-}$ (Cp$ sp prime$ = Cp, MeCp, Me$ sb5$Cp; R = Ph or PhCH$ sb2;$ R$ sp prime$ = Bu or H.) were investigated { it in situ}, by NMR and EPR studies, and by trapping unstable intermediates with PMe$ sb3.$ Two novel Zr(III) complexes, $ rm lbrack Cp sb2Zr sp{III} rbrack sp+ lbrack$BBu$ sb{n}$(C$ sb6{ rm F} sb5) sb{4-n} rbrack sp-$ and $ rm lbrack Cp sb2Zr sp{III}(PMe sb3) sb2 rbrack sp+ lbrack$BBu$ sb{n}$(C$ sb6{ rm F} sb5) sb{4-n} rbrack sp-$ were identified by EPR spectroscopy. The unstable, diamagnetic compound $ rm lbrack Cp sb2Zr sp{IV}Bu rbrack sp+ lbrack$BBu$ sb{n}$(C$ sb6{ rm F} sb5) sb{4-n} rbrack sp-$ was identified by $ sp1$H-$ sp1$H COSY and $ sp1$H-$ sp{13}$C HMQC experiments at ${-}20 sp circ$C. Redistribution of the borate butyl and pentafluorophenyl ligands was found to occur by a direct boron to boron migration and not by a metal assisted mechanism. The latter was ruled out by an independent synthesis of expected reaction intermediates for both reaction pathways $ rm( lbrack Ph sb3C rbrack lbrack BBu(C sb6F sb5) sb3 rbrack, lbrack Cp sb2Zr(C sb A key step in the synthesis of the active dehydrocoupling catalyst is the thermal decomposition of $ rm Cp sb2ZrBu sb2,$ which at room temperature affords paramagnetic Cp$ sb2$ZrR (R = Bu, crotyl and H) and other minor paramagnetic compounds. The pathway and the trends of this reductive decomposition were investigated in detail by EPR and multinuclear, multidimensional NMR spectroscopy. A number of intermediates were characterized. Reactions leading to the above compounds are rationalized from mechanistic and thermochemical points of view. Although it has not been possible to identify all of the decomposition products, the very fact that the $ rm Cp sb2ZrCl sb2$/2BuLi reagent contains substantial amounts of Zr(III) explains the origin of the unusual reactivity of the $ rm Cp sb2ZrCl sb2$/2BuLi reagent in dehydropolymerization of silanes and sheds new light on the reaction mechanism. A kinetic study of the photochemical reaction of $ rm lbrack Cp sb2Zr(SiHPh)( mu$-H) rbrack$ sb2 sp{2+} lbrack$BBu$ sb{n}$(C$ sb6$F$ sb5) sb{4-n} rbrack sb2 sp{2-}$ with benzylsilane was carried out with a combination of NMR and EPR spectroscopy. The role of the paramagnetic intermediate, $ rm lbrack Cp sb2Zr sp{III} rbrack sp+ lbrack$BBu$ sb{n}$(C$ sb6$F$ sb5) sb{4-n} rbrack sp-,$ was investigated. The rate law and qualitative observations support a new Zr(IV)/Zr(III) redox mechanism. The use of ``cation-like'' metallocene combination catalysts $ rm(Cp sp prime sb2MCl sb2$ - 2BuLi - $ rm B(C sb6F sb5) sb3; Cp sp prime{=} eta sp5$-cyclopentadienyl, or substituted $ eta sp5$-cyclopentadienyl; M=Ti, Zr, Hf, U) for dehydropolymerization of silane significantly improves the polymer molecular weight. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Dioumaev, Vladimir K.</creator><contributor>Harrod, John F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Chemistry, Inorganic.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Chemistry of some cation-like silyl zirconocene complexes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rv94p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935449v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jd472z00w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:17:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigates the Indonesian experience in managing the privatization of State Controlled Enterprises (SCEs) during the period from 1983 to 1993. The main objective of this study is to assess and explore the following research question: Why has there been little ownership transfer from state to the private sector in Indonesia even though official policy objectives and strategies for proving SCEs have been articulated and firms have been selected for potential privatization? Realizing complex combination of challenges and obstacles faced by Indonesia, attempts to answer the research question are directed at three main issues: (1) the role of SCEs in the overall national economy; (2) factors that led the Indonesian government to undertake privatization policy, and (3) the preferred models of privatization along with the rationale for such preferences. Five types of data were collected during three separate field work stages from July 1991 to October 1995: State policy analysis, direct observation, analysis of the statistical data, analysis of mass media and personal interviews with key individuals. This triangulation method is employed to ensure a greater presentation of the key elements that deserve to be explored. The principal argument developed throughout this study is that despite the apparent needs for privatization due to the fiscal difficulties and inefficiencies of the SCEs operations, the Indonesian state seems to be reluctant to transfer ownership to the private sector. In the case at hand, the pursuit of privatization is largely a political decision. Transferring ownership would require an overhaul of the present development policy, a huge step that Indonesian state is not ready to take. Instead, the priority has been given to reform the state sector by improving the efficiency and productivity of SCEs operations, and by isolating SCEs from the rent seeking behaviours of government bureaucrats. This tendency, as this study demonstrates, is explained by a deepening direct state involvement in the economy. This study shows that the Indonesian state has expanded its roles in the economy to include not only regulator, facilitator and stabilizer, but also that direct participant as a competitor to the private sector. Consequently, being kept under tight state control, has caused Indonesian SCEs to operate in a highly regulated environment. This environment has resulted in SCEs tendency to become instrument of development and, therefore has prevented them from becoming efficient and productive business entities.</description><creator>Djamhari, Choirul.</creator><contributor>Masi, Anthony C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Indonesia -- Economic policy.</subject><subject>Privatization -- Indonesia.</subject><subject>Government business enterprises -- Indonesia.</subject><title>Privatization of state controlled enterprises in Indonesia (1983-1993) : policy and practice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311q90k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd472z00w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67js65v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:17:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this thesis was to characterize the distribution, variability and determinants of exposures to extremely low frequency (ELF) electric and magnetic fields in environments where no information was previously available, and to advance the methodology of exposure estimation. The thesis is divided into three related papers. The first paper reports a study of personal ELF field exposure measurements of 465 randomly selected workers in an electrical utility. By job category, arithmetic mean magnetic field exposures ranged from 0.09 to 2.36 $ mu$T (electric fields: 2.5 to 400 V/m). ELF magnetic field exposures were highest for substation workers, hydroelectric generating station operators and cable splicers; electric fields were highest for forestry workers, equipment electricians and distribution linemen. Most alternative indices of exposure were highly correlated with the arithmetic or the geometric means (r $ ge$ 0.8). Job category explained half of the total variance in logarithms of weekly magnetic and electric field means. The second paper reports a method developed to estimate past ELF field exposures of the electric utility workers. The present intensities and durations of exposures for tasks were measured, then separately extrapolated to the past based on information from interviews with long-service personnel at the utility. From reconstructed time weighted average (TWA) exposures, magnetic fields were estimated to have increased most over time for substation and distribution-line jobs; the increase for electric fields was less than for magnetic. The method is applicable to other exposures where monitoring records allow calculation of the intensity and duration of exposures for tasks and estimates of past intensities and durations of exposures for these tasks can be obtained. In the third paper, the methodology developed in the occupational setting was applied to a study of personal exposures to ELF fields among 365 randomly selected Canadian children. Overall, the arithmetic mean total magnetic field was 0.121 $ mu$T (electric field: 14.4 V/m), with magnetic fields highest in Quebec and lowest in Alberta. Magnetic fields were highest at home during the day. Measurements were at their lowest at night but provided the highest correlation with total magnetic field exposure (r =.91). This study found that children's magnetic fields exposures varied substantially between certain provinces (province accounting for 14.7% of the variation) most likely because of differences in the proportion of residences in multiple dwellings, heated electrically or cooled by air conditioning. These attributes were identified as potentially useful predictors of magnetic fields.</description><creator>Deadman, Jan-Erik.</creator><contributor>Armstrong, Ben (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Occupational Health and Safety.</subject><title>Estimation of exposures to extremely low frequency electric and magnetic fields</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gm44g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67js65v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Occupational Health</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795927b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:17:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation analyzes post-structuralist theses concerning the literary work's potential for political critique and impact. By placing contemporary claims as to the inevitably oppressive or ineffectual character of the literary work next to the texts and reception of novels by John Dos Passos, James T. Farrell and Richard Wright, I examine whether such claims can account for the political achievements of actual literary works. Locating in Dos Passos's U.S.A., Farrell's Studs Lonigan and Wright's Native Son instances of an effective oppositional literature, I argue against the post-structuralist position and for a reconsideration of the Sartrean assertion of the "negative," and thus potentially critical and oppositional, agency of writers and readers, and thus, too, of the literary work. In using a particular case study as a corrective both for recent theory and for the excesses of Sartre's own arguments for "committed" writing, "Crisis and Dissent" contributes both to on-going critiques of post-structuralism and to recent re-evaluations of Sartre's own literary theory.</description><creator>DeCoste, Damon Marcel.</creator><contributor>Hjort, Mette (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Bristol, Michael D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Politics and literature.</subject><subject>Structuralism (Literary analysis)</subject><title>Crisis and dissent : literary agency in philosophy and fiction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322f747.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795927b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558f80m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:17:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The retinoblastoma tumour suppressor family plays an important role in the regulation of cellular growth in the cell cycle, growth arrest, and differentiation. The RB family includes pRB, p107, and p130 which interact primarily with two sets of transcription factor families, E2F and DP, resulting in the inactivation of E2F/DP transcriptional activity. The RB family members are targets for DNA tumour viral oncogene products such adenovirus E1A proteins which interact with all members, and displace E2F/DP heterodimers, resulting in the activation of E2F-dependent transcription. The binding of pRB was found to be absolutely required for EIA-mediated transformation, however, there is no correlation between E2F activation and transforming efficiency because some E1A mutants which failed to interact with pRB induced E2F at high levels presumably due to interaction with p107 and p130. These results suggest that pRB regulates E2F activity differently from p107 and p130. Analysis of mutants in conserved region 2 (CR2) of the E1A protein, including the (D)LXCXE conserved motif showed that the integrity of these conserved residues is important for interactions with both pRB and p130, but no single site mutation diminished binding of p107. Thus interactions with multiple members of the RB family appeared to be required for full activation of E2F and stable cell transformation by E1A proteins. In undifferentiated cells such as C2C12 and P19 mouse cells, E2F is primarily complexed with p107/cyclinA/E/Cdk2. It was show that formation of pRB/E2F complexes is specifically induced during cell differentiation. In addition, p130/E2F complexes are also generated. We identified a novel slowly-migrating p130/E2F complex which is present not only in terminally differentiated cells, but also in growth-arrested cells. This complex is found in high amounts in Go/G1 phases, it disappears near the G1/S transition, and reappears in mitosis. Analysis of the content of these complexes showed that they contain cellular protein(s) which interact with p130 in a fashion similar to the CR2 region of E1A. Characterization of the novel E2F complex by antibody supershift assays revealed the presence of a known RB-binding protein, RBP1 which seems to be part of large family of cellular proteins interacting with p130 and which may be involved in the represssion of basal promoter activity of E2F regulated genes.</description><creator>Corbeil, Hugues B.</creator><contributor>Branton, Philip E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Role of the retinoblastoma tumour suppressor family in transformation, differentiation, and cell cycle</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j263f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558f80m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z237k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:17:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A series of studies were conducted to investigate differences in voluntary and evoked contractile properties of trained, untrained and previously immobilized ankle fracture subjects before and following fatigue. Measurements included twitch contractile properties, maximal voluntary contractions (MVC), electromyography (EMG) and muscle activation (interpolated twitch (IT) ratio and second order polynomials). Although second order polynomials were found to be a more precise measurement of muscle activation ($ sim$6% error) than the IT ratio (superimposed evoked torque/potentiated resting evoked torque), both techniques provided a general estimate of muscle activation before and following fatigue. Prior to fatigue, trained plantarflexor subjects exerted greater force (17.5%) and had significantly less antagonist activity (41.3%) than untrained subjects. Following fatigue, untrained subjects experienced greater deficits in excitation-contraction coupling and increased antagonist activity (58%) contributing to their tendency for increased fatiguability. The lower force output (45.8%) and muscle activation (20.4%) of previously immobilized non-fixated ankle fractures did not result in greater fatiguability than controls. Disuse adaptations such as potentiation of the muscle action potentials and twitch torque helped to maintain the fatiguing contractions. However the more severely fractured ankles of the internally-fixated subjects experienced increased agonist (13%) and antagonist (8.5%) EMG activity and similar changes in muscle activation and evoked contractile properties while performing fewer contractions. This would suggest that injuries of greater severity may result in an intrinsically more fatiguable muscle. To determine whether the findings could be generalized to other muscles and fatigue protocols, various contraction intensities were used to elicit short and long duration fatiguing contractions in the plantarflexors and quadriceps. Muscle activation, and t</description><creator>Behm, David G.</creator><contributor>St-Pierre, Diane M. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><title>Voluntary and evoked contractile properties of trained, untrained and previously immobilized subjects before and following fatigue</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k06988969.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z237k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fn19q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:17:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents the formulation of a general finite element program for the computation of the bone adaptation process after total joint arthroplasty. This program is applied to study this phenomenon in the distal femur resurfaced with a prosthetic component whose fixation is achieved by bone ingrowth. The motivation for this formulation and application stems from the fact that evidence of adverse bone adaptation after total joint arthroplasty is being increasingly reported in the literature. The stability of the bone adaptation model is investigated in terms of the exponents of some of its constitutive equations. These exponents are determined based on previous experimental studies and based on the constraint of the stability criterion. The iterative procedure that models the bone adaptation process is evaluated by comparing the computed results with analytical solutions for the density in a beam. The finite element model of the resurfaced bone takes into account the frictional properties of the contact between bone and the prosthetic component. The general contact formulation is evaluated by comparing the computed results with analytical solutions for the contact pressures in test situations for which these solutions are available. The application of the general program to the resurfaced distal femur clarifies the role of the model variables in terms of their influence on the computed bone adaptation. The computed results compare favourably with the available clinical observations of bone adaptation in the distal femur following total knee arthroplasty. Furthermore, the present application allows the investigation of the possible beneficial effects of some of the prosthesis design parameters.</description><creator>Ben Souda, Karima.</creator><contributor>Ahmed, A. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Finite element formulation of the bone adaptation process following arthroplasty and application to the distal femur</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462702k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fn19q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451k11x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:17:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis we have not entered the names of all the authors who wrote in the Venetian language in the course of the XX century, but only the names of those who distinguished themselves. This thesis does not deal exclusively with poetry, but it includes also prose, theatre and journalism. In fact, analyzing so many and such varied works allowed us to formulate working hypotheses on the origins, evolution and various motivations of their respective authors. It also supplied us with some clues as to why they chose to write in a regional language and, sometimes, in one of its dialects. Our work has taken into account the literary production in other regional languages of Italy, as well as the theoretical writings on this subject. Owing to the synoptic presence of all of these elements, this thesis fills an existing gap and thus offers a positive contribution to contemporary scholarship on regional languages and literatures.</description><creator>Bedon, Elettra.</creator><contributor>Gilardino, Sergio Maria (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Dialect poetry, Italian -- Italy -- Veneto -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Dialect literature, Italian -- Italy -- Veneto -- History and criticism.</subject><title>Il filo di Arianna : letteratura in lingua veneta nel XX secolo</title><language>ita</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bg55n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451k11x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Italian</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gf562</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:17:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The structure of one member of a family of maize mitochondrial RNA replicons (or RNA plasmids), RNA b, has been characterized. It is shown that RNA b shares a 13 nucleotide sequence with the central conserved region of Cadang-Cadang viroid of coconuts which might be involved in substrate recognition by the RNA replicase during replication. RNA b likely was derived from a larger member in that family, RNA a, through co-linear deletions similar to those involved with the generation of the defective interfering (DI) elements associated with both animal and plant viruses. RNA b may represent a "selfish" RNA optimized for replication as it does not have the capacity to encode its own replicase. Mitochondrial RNA plasmids have been found not to be restricted to the S and RU cytoplasms, as previously reported. Related plasmid RNAs have been detected in maize plants with C, N and T cytoplasms as well as 13 Latin American races. They were not found, however, in teosintes, indicating that the ancestral nucleic acid from which these RNAs evolved was acquired soon after the split between teosintes and maize, before the divergence of the maize races. Distribution of the plasmid RNAs, a maize mRNA (atp6), and a mitochondrial rRNA (26S) in different organs and tissues was investigated by in situ hybridization. These results indicated that mitochondrial gene expression is subjected to an unexpected degree of both spatial and developmental regulation, and that individual mitochondrial genes are subjected to different controls. Similar results were obtained in in situ hybridization studies of Brassica floral buds. Both studies suggested that the levels of mitochondrial genes transcripts are not particularly high in the tapetal cells of both maize and Brassica anthers contrary to common belief. High levels of RNA plasmid were detected in the pollen of S maize anthers prior to pollen abortion, suggesting they might be related to the cytoplasmic male sterility (CMS) trait of S maize</description><creator>Zhang, Mingda</creator><contributor>Brown, Gregory G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>RNA</subject><subject>Plant mitochondria</subject><subject>Plant genetic regulation</subject><title>Plant mitochondrial RNA : replicons characterization and developmentally regulated distribution</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591985w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gf562</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zw12z692x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:17:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Flotation of sphalerite with xanthate in the presence of iron ions has been studied as a function of pH. Sphalerite floated readily at pH 8-11 in the presence of ferrous ions, but not in the presence of ferric ions. The Fe$ sp{2+}$ ion concentration, pH and oxygen concentration were shown to be factors in controlling flotation. Electrokinetic measurements indicated that the surface charge increased in the presence of Fe$ sp{2+}$ ions and oxygen, and decreased upon adding xanthate and in the presence of Fe$ sp{2+}$ ions with the absence of oxygen. As a prelude to surface analysis to try to identify the species responsible for the sphalerite flotation, bulk precipitates formed from iron salt and xanthate solutions under various conditions were obtained and analysed. Analysis techniques included ultraviolet spectroscopy, infrared spectroscopy, x-ray diffraction and Mossbauer spectroscopy. It was tentatively concluded that the bulk precipitates contained three ferric components: two hydroxy xanthates, Fe(OH)$ sb2$X and Fe(OH)X$ sb2$ and an iron oxide, FeO$ sb{ rm x}.$ Iron xanthate precipitates prepared over the pH range 6-12 showed a flotation response and electrokinetic behaviour similar to those of Fe$ sp{2+}$/xanthate-treated sphalerite. An ex situ X-ray photoelectron spectroscopic (XPS), ex situ infrared (DRIFTS) and in situ infrared (ATR) investigation of the interaction of sphalerite with ferrous, ferric and xanthate ions at pH 10 was undertaken. The formation of the hydrophobic surface species was found to involve initial adsorption of Fe$ sp{2+},$ followed by oxidation to Fe$ sp{3+}$ and subsequent reaction with xanthate. There was no significant incorporation of Fe$ sp{3+}.$ A three-step reaction mechanism is proposed to account for Fe$ sp{2+}$ ion activation of sphalerite: (i) adsorption of Fe(OH)$ sp+,$ (ii) oxidation to Fe(OH)$ sp{2+}$ on the surface, (iii) reaction with xanthate to form Fe(OH)$ sb2$X or Fe(OH)X$ sb2.$</description><creator>Zhang, Qingsong, 1963-</creator><contributor>Finch, James A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Sphalerite activation in the presence of iron ions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xt23f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z692x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pn89d8187</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:17:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Immunohistochemical studies have shown opioid peptides in sympathetic ganglia and preganglionic neurons. An inhibitory action of opioids has been demonstrated in some central and peripheral synapses. However, a physiological role of endogenous opioids in sympathetic ganglia has not been well characterized. The present study investigated endogenous opioid action in the SCG of the cat. The results obtained show that an endogenous opioid is released from preganglionic axon terminals, in a frequency range that matches the natural activity of sympathetic preganglionic neurons, and inhibits ganglionic transmission by acting on post-synaptic opiate receptors of the $ mu$ and $ delta$ subtypes coupled to PTX-sensitive G protein. The size of the store of the endogenous opioid in the preganglionic axon terminals is small and readily exhaustible. Protein synthesis and axonal transport are required for maintenance of the store. The opioid inhibition is under control of the PKC system. This study provides the first thorough characterization of the properties of an opioid-mediated inhibitory mechanism in a well-defined synapse.</description><creator>Zhang, Chunyi</creator><contributor>Polosa, Canio (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Properties of an opioid-mediated inhibition evoked by preganglionic axons in the superior cervical ganglion of the cat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jz72g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89d8187</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74cr95q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:17:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mammalian striate and circumstriate cortical neurons have long been understood as coding spatially localized retinal luminance variations, providing a basis for computing motion, stereopsis, and contours from the retinal image. However, such perceptual attributes do not always correspond to the retinal luminance variations in natural vision. Recordings from area 17 and 18 neurons revealed a specialized nonlinear processing stream that responded to stimulus attributes having no corresponding luminance variations. This nonlinear stream acts in parallel to the conventional luminance processing of single cortical neurons. The two streams were consistent in their preference for orientation and direction of motion, but distinct in processing spatial variations of the stimulus attributes. The ensemble of these neurons provides a combination of stimulus attributes with and without corresponding luminance variations.</description><creator>Zhou, Yi-Xiong</creator><contributor>Baker, Curtis L., Jr. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Visual pathways -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Cats -- Physiology.</subject><subject>Visual cortex.</subject><title>Responses to envelope patterns in visual cortical neurons</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bn23k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cr95q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f2762</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although motor neurons represent an important and well defined neuronal population, little is known about their unique gene expression. Because of the difficulties of purifying and culturing large numbers of primary motor neurons, we adopted a cloning strategy based on the NSC34 motor neuron-like hybrid cell line. This cell line was developed by fusing dissociated E14 mouse spinal cord cells with N18TG2 neuroblastoma cells and expresses a host of motor neuron markers and traits. We examined a cDNA library of the NSC34 cell line using a subtractive screening strategy in order to isolate cDNA copies of mRNAs preferentially expressed in the hybrid cells with respect to the N18 parents. Of 8 cDNAs isolated, two encode known neural genes, namely chromogranin B (a component of neurosecretory vesicles) and GAP43 (important for growth cone extension) and a third clone corresponds to a sequence which has been proposed to be the glutamate binding subunit of an NMDA receptor. One novel cDNA was isolated which appears to be preferentially expressed in brain and spinal cord (as determined by semi-quantitative PCR), and is clearly detectable in motor neurons by in situ hybridization. The remaining 4 cDNAs encode cytochrome oxidase subunit II, the mouse IAP element, and the mouse b1 element (2 copies). We conclude that this strategy is effective in isolating novel genes from rare cell types, but that large numbers of library phage must be examined and that hybrid cell-specific probes should be generated by subtraction with other hybrid cells (rather than the N18 parent) because of the large number of genes non-specifically activated by cell fusion.</description><creator>Pasternak, Stephen H.</creator><contributor>Cashman, N. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Hastings, K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Subtractive cloning of cDNAs from motor neuron-like hybrid cells : a strategy for cloning cDNAs from rare cell types</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vj27t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f2762</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g1797</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two experiments studied the effectiveness of Imitation and Listener Uncertainty as speech training techniques for profoundly hearing-impaired children. In the first study, a single-subject design was employed with two children who were trained on /$ int$/ and /r/ in words using alternating treatments. Results showed short term benefits for both treatments, but better retention and better generalization to spontaneous speech for the Listener Uncertainty approach. In the second study, 33 children were matched as closely as possible and randomly assigned to the Imitation Group, Listener Uncertainty Group or Control Group. Students in the treatment groups were trained on fricatives in words, phrases and sentences. Plosives were used as control phonemes. Results indicated significant improvement on production of trained and untrained words for both treatments, with higher scores for Listener Uncertainty. However, there was no difference between the treatment groups and control group on ability to generalize target sounds to spontaneous speech. Effects of context and phoneme position were also examined.</description><creator>Perigoe, Christina Barris</creator><contributor>Doehring, Donald G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Health Sciences, Speech Pathology.</subject><title>Effectiveness of two phonologic speech training strategies for hearing-impaired children</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m557t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g1797</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52j9518</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis reviews, analyses and classifies extraction methods and sequences used in steep, tabular orebodies in Ontario hardrock mines and how new bulk mining techniques have affected them. The thesis examines, as a case study, the complexities of sequencing the extraction of the Hemlo orebody through three adjacent mines and details the planning and monitoring of extracting one section of the David Bell orebody. It examines the use of numerical modelling as a tool in extraction sequence planning and demonstrates how, in conjunction with an instrumentation program, the results assist successful completion of the plan. The thesis concludes that bulk mining sequences have increased resource extraction and productivity, lowered costs and improved ground control aspects of extraction planning; but have compromised grade control. This aspect should be improved to maximize the economic benefits. In addition, as automated or continuous mining methods are developed, their benefits should be analyzed in the context of overall sequence planning objectives.</description><creator>Pelley, Charles W.</creator><contributor>Scoble, Malcolm (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>A study of sequencing strategy for steep, tabular, hardrock orebodies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612q175.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j9518</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hr25c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>eIF-4A is a eukaryotic translation initiation factor and DEAD box RNA helicase that is thought to be responsible for the melting of secondary structure in the 5$ sp prime$ untranslated region of messenger RNAs to facilitate ribosome binding. A mutational analysis of eIF-4A revealed that the ATPase A motif (AXXXXGKT) is involved in ATP binding, the ATPase B motif (DEAD) is implicated in ATP hydrolysis, the SAT region is essential for RNA unwinding, and the HRIGRXXR region is required for ATP hydrolysis-dependent RNA binding. Furthermore, defective eIF-4A mutants exhibit a strong dominant negative effect on in vitro translation of several mRNAs, including those translated by a cap-independent internal initiation mechanism. It is demonstrated that eIF-4A functions primarily as a subunit of eIF-4F, and singular eIF-4A is required to recycle through the eIF-4F during translation. Accordingly, eIF-4F appears to be required for cap-dependent and internal initiation of translation.</description><creator>Pause, Arnim</creator><contributor>Sonenberg, N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Mutational analysis of the mammalian translation initiation factor eIF-4A</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n204066d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hr25c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr171z75c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The formulation of a co-located equal-order Control-Volume-based Finite Element Method (CVFEM) for the solution of two-fluid models of two-dimensional, planar or axisymmetric, incompressible, gas-solid particle flows is presented in this thesis. The main focus is on the development of a numerical method that allows computer simulation of gas-solid particle flows over a wide range of solid-phase volume concentration in complex irregular geometries. A general two-fluid mathematical model is presented. This model is essentially borrowed from published works in the area of granular flows. It is established here that this model is applicable to gas-solid flows over a wide range of solid-phase concentration. The governing equations of the fluid phase are obtained by volume averaging the Navier-Stokes equations for an incompressible fluid. The solid-phase macroscopic equations are derived using an approach that has been successfully used earlier for the description of granular materials, and is based on the kinetic theory of dense gases. This approach accounts for particle/particle collisions, and permits the determination of the solid-phase macroscopic properties such as viscosity and pressure. The proposed CVFEM is formulated by borrowing and extending ideas put forward in earlier CVFEMs for single-phase flows. In axisymmetric problems, the calculation domain is discretized into torus-shaped elements and control volumes: in a longitudinal cross-sectional plane, or in planar problems, these elements are three-node triangles, and the control volumes are polygons obtained by joining the centroids of the three-node triangles to the midpoints of the sides. In each element, mass-weighted skew upwind functions are used to interpolate the volume concentrations. An iterative variable adjustment algorithm is used to solve the discretized equations. The chosen mathematical model, along with its specializations to single-phase flows and dilute gas-solid flows, and the proposed CVFEM have been applied to several test problems and some demonstration problems. These test and demonstration problems include single-phase flows, dilute-concentration gas-solid particle flows and dense-concentration gas-solid particle flows. The CVFEM results have been compared with results of independent numerical and experimental investigations whenever possible. These comparisons and the results of the demonstration problems are quite encouraging.</description><creator>Masson, Christian</creator><contributor>Baliga, B. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Numerical prediction of gas-solid particle flows over a wide range of concentration in irregular geometries</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j2668.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr171z75c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s161772p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents the results of a systematic study on the structural relaxation and the glass transition of ternary metal-metal glasses Zr$ sb{67}$(Ni$ sb{1-x}$Cu$ sb{x}) sb{33}$. Differential scanning calorimetry provides macroscopic evidence of structural changes from the compositional and temperature dependence of enthalpy change. Results from high precision x-ray diffraction and Mossbauer spectroscopy, performed mainly on $ rm Zr sb{67}Ni sb{10}Cu sb{23}$ (x = 0.7), complete the picture of structural changes at the atomic level. Irreversible structural relaxation leads to densification and enthalpy release. Shear-like atomic motion enhances local atomic order, highlighting the atomic processes during the irreversible relaxation. Reversible structural relaxation involves two partly overlapping processes initiated at different temperatures, which are characterized by the solid and liquid atomic mobilities, respectively. Interatomic positional exchanges between Cu and Ni atoms change the local structure and are active during the reversible relaxation at low temperatures, which are also partly responsible for the irreversible relaxation. Above 500 K, shear-like atomic movements characterize the reversible relaxation, involving all three atomic species in a length scale of a few near-neighbor atomic shells. The overall density is unchanged during reversible relaxation. The strong compositional dependence of the glass transition in the ternary glasses indicates an intimate association of the glass transition with interatomic bondings among different atomic species. The atomic motion from room temperature up to above the glass transition temperature, measured by the Mossbauer spectroscopy, is macroscopically tracked by the volume expansion and the enthalpy evolution. The glass transition occurs when the length scale of the atomic motion expands so rapidly that the interatomic potential can no longer maintain the on-site atomic vibration. The rapid development of translational atomic motion upon approaching the glass transition is reflected by the dramatic enhancement of the diffusive atomic motion.</description><creator>Mao, Ming</creator><contributor>Altounian, Zaven (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Structural relaxation and the glass transition in metal-metal glasses</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074w75q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161772p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bg257g629</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Thermodynamics of irreversible processes in a radiation field is formulated, based on kinetic theory, by treating nonequilibrium radiation as a nonequilibrium photon gas interacting with matter. The generalized hydrodynamic equations for macroscopic variables necessary for describing temporal and spatial evolution of irreversible processes in the system of matter and radiation are derived from kinetic equations by using the modified moment method. The method rigorously yields the conclusion that entropy differential is not an exact differential when the system is away from equilibrium. Therefore, an extended Gibbs relation for the entropy density does not hold valid. However, an extended Gibbs relation-like equation holds for the compensation differential which has been shown to be an exact differential. The entropy balance equation is cast into an equivalent form in terms of a new function called the Boltzmann function. In the context of the present formalism the light-induced viscous flow is theoretically explained for the entire range of pressure. The modified moment method has been extended to the covariant Boltzmann equation in order to formulate a theory of relativistic irreversible thermodynamics. Furthermore, the kinetic theory foundations for relativistic irreversible thermodynamics for the system of radiation and matter are provided. The statistical mechanical formulas are obtained for various material and radiative transport coefficients. The radiative transport coefficients stand in simple ratios independent of material parameters. The ratios calculated are in agreement with those used in the phenomenological theory using the Rosseland mean.</description><creator>Mao, Kefei</creator><contributor>Eu, B. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Physics, Radiation.</subject><title>Kinetic theory of irreversible processes in a system of radiation and matter</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515p81r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257g629</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bd24g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A study of Kalman filtering in atmospheric data assimilation is presented. Our research aims at an understanding of the physical and statistical mechanisms as well as the principles underlying its application to atmospheric data assimilation. Both the continuous and the discrete formulations of the filter were considered. Using nonlinear advection diffusion dynamics, a number of aspects in data assimilation were addressed, often by exploring the parameter space or by performing Monte Carlo simulations. The filtering properties, the spatial regularity and indirect inference about the model error covariance were examined with a discrete linear Kalman filter. The dynamics of the mean, variance, and correlation of forecast errors for Burgers' equation were studied. The validity of the tangent linear approximation for Burgers' equation was examined. An ensemble of realizations of the extended Kalman filter has permitted a statistical investigation of its performance, errors and limit of validity.</description><creator>Mnard, Richard</creator><contributor>Daley, Roger (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Yau, Peter M. K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>Kalman filtering of Burgers' equation and its application to atmospheric data assimilation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jc87s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bd24g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892c377</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Genetic parameters were estimated using 8086 weaning weight records of Mashona cattle from commercial herds in Zimbabwe, through Derivative-free Restricted Maximum Likelihood (DFREML) procedure fitting an individual animal model. All known additive relationships among animals were incorporated and all sires were assumed to have been bred by unknown parents. A simulation study was carried out to estimate the amount of bias in the estimated genetic parameters caused by the failure to account for the true relationships among the breeding animals. Genetic differences between the weaning weights of Mashona cattle in commercial herds and in small holder herds were estimated using performance records of progeny from 2 reference bulls, 3 bulls from commercial herds, 14 bulls from Makoholi Research Station and 20 bulls from small holder farms. The findings from this study were used as a basis for simulating different strategies of improving the weaning weights of Mashona cattle through the creation of nucleus herds. Estimates ($ pm$s.e) of direct heritability (h$ sb{ rm A} sp2$), maternal heritability (h$ sb{ rm M} sp2$) and the correlation between direct and maternal genetic effects (r$ sb{ rm AM}$) were 0.243 $ pm$ 0.046, 0.392 $ pm$ 0.031 and $-$0.282 $ pm$ 0.081, respectively. When a permanent environmental effect of the dam (c$ sp2$) was fitted, the estimates of h$ sb{ rm A} sp2$, h$ sb{ rm M} sp2$, r$ sb{ rm AM}$ and c$ sp2$ were 0.281 $ pm$ 0.026, 0.113 $ pm$ 0.022, $-$0.269 $ pm$ 0.106 and 0.228 $ pm$ 0.023, respectively. No significant trends were observed in direct breeding values but there was a decline in maternal breeding values. The simulation study indicated that the bias in h$ sb{ rm A} sp2$ and h$ sb{ rm M} sp2$ resulting from the lack of sire pedigrees was trivial if the correlation between direct and maternal genetic effects was high and a large proportion of dams had known pedigrees. The progeny test showed that both the mean breeding values of the reference sires and the bulls from commercial farms were significantly higher than the mean breeding values of small holder bulls for birth weight (by 1.6 and 1.7 kg, respectively) and weaning weight (by 10.4 and 11.0 kg, respectively). The strategies that selected breeding animals on their maternal genetic values resulted in the highest responses for weaning weight. It was concluded that maternal genetic values of Mashona cattle should be improved to allow this breed to compete favourably as a maternal breed in commercial agriculture.</description><creator>Khombe, Carroll Themba</creator><contributor>Hayes, J. F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Beef cattle -- Zimbabwe -- Weight.</subject><subject>Beef cattle -- Zimbabwe -- Feeding and feeds.</subject><subject>Grazing.</subject><subject>Beef cattle -- Zimbabwe -- Genetics.</subject><title>The inheritance of weaning weight in Mashona cattle grazing on free range in Zimbabwe</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913r43j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892c377</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd375x925</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A comparison was made between NIOSH-type, prepacked nutshell charcoal tubes and layers of commercial charcoal cloth in a stainless steel cassette designed for the active sampling/adsorption of different concentrations of a mixture of volatile organic chemicals (VOCs) (benzene, trichloroethylene, toluene, tetrachloroethylene, chlorobenzene and o-xylene). Physicochemical parameters of the charcoal cloth including breakthrough times and volumes and adsorption capacities were determined for toluene and the VOC mixture. The quantitative removal of VOCs from the charcoal cloth by solvent desorption, by supercritical fluid extraction (SFE), and by thermal desorption was studied prior to analysis by gas liquid chromatography with photoionization detection. Optimal conditions were explored both in laboratory and industrial environments. Charcoal cloth was comparable to the NIOSH tube, adsorbed VOCs being quantitatively removed at any time up to 32 days after sampling. Although solvent (pentane, hexane) desorption yielded accurate, reproducible results with a high percent recovery of the VOCs, a major disadvantage was the irreparable damage done to the cloth, preventing its repeated use. Desorption by SFE proved unreliable for these low molecular weight VOCs, both the collecting solvents and the VOCs being lost during extraction. Thermal desorption proved to be efficient, sensitive and reliable, repeated heating having no effect on the adsorptive properties of the cloth. Charcoal cloth would appear to be a useful adsorbing medium for air sampling of both industrial and office building/home environments for either single chemicals or mixtures.</description><creator>Kongtip, Pornpimol</creator><contributor>Ecobichon, D. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Farant, J. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Health Sciences, Occupational Health and Safety.</subject><title>Charcoal cloth as an adsorbant for the analysis of volatile organic compounds in indoor air</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870x464.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375x925</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Occupational Health</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fj65s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study provides an in-depth account of the practices of the Bordeaux parlement for the years 1714-26 as a background and prelude for an understanding of Montesquieu's political theory. The first chapter demonstrates that the discipline of jurisprudence in early eighteenth century France was in a state of transition and was to a large degree unreflective of new political realities. The discipline did not offer the intellectual resources needed to construct a compelling account of contemporary developments in the growth of the state and of its tools. In contrast, it is shown in chapters two and three that the magistrates of the Bordeaux parlement rejected standard principles of Roman law, constitutionalism and patriarchalism and fashioned their own particular form of political argument. This new form of argument, called 'associational discourse' by the author, has significant resonance in the work of Montesquieu. Chapter four shows how this theoretical disposition was developed more fully in Montesquieu's early writings. Chapter five in turn shows how this was articulated in its fullest form in his major work, L'Esprit des lois (1748). Chapters six and seven show how this new form of political thinking was to have an important effect on Montesquieu's comprehensive theory of criminal justice. In conclusion, it is suggested that this early-modern form of associationalist thinking points to an alternative to liberalist and communitarian positions, by the consideration that governments should be concerned for the moral strength of subordinate associations in their communities, while not being fully responsible for the exact content of the beliefs fostered within them.</description><creator>Kingston, Rebecca</creator><contributor>Tully, James (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Montesquieu, Charles de Secondat, baron de, 1689-1755</subject><subject>France. Parlement (Bordeaux)</subject><title>Montesquieu and the parlement of Bordeaux</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042v48q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fj65s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bk128c422</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cyclophosphamide is an alkylating agent which has deleterious effects on reproduction in both males and females. When administered to male rats in chronic low doses (6 mg/kg/day), cyclophosphamide caused a dose-dependent increase in post-implantation death of the offspring. On day 7 of gestation, two days after implantation, the inner cell mass-derived embryonic tissues were retarded or absent while trophectoderm-derived extraembryonic tissues appeared normal. The preimplantation growth of embryos sired by cyclophosphamide-treated males was affected; as early as day 3 there was a significant decrease in cell number and in DNA synthesis. On day 3, there was no ultrastructural evidence of active cell death, and embryos underwent compaction, despite their decreased cell numbers. On day 4, embryos sired by treated males had less than half the cell number of controls: this decrease was not lineage-specific. A minority of embryos sired by treated males did not cavitate and showed signs of autophagic death on day 4 of gestation. The majority of embryos sired by treated males were able to cavitate and differentiate morphologically to form small blastocysts. Thus the target of cyclophosphamide damage may be a paternal gene more important for cell proliferation than for cell differentiation in the preimplantation rat embryo.</description><creator>Kelly, Sara M.</creator><contributor>Hales, Barbara F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Paternal cyclophosphamide exposure exerts deleterious effects on early rat embryo development</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720f343.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128c422</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns0647384</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:18:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis develops improved stochastic models for the description of a large variety of fatigue crack growth phenomena that occur in structural and mechanical components of fundamental importance to the functionality and reliability of complex and modern engineering structures. In essence, the models are based upon the recently available McGill-Markov and the newly developed Closure-Lognormal stochastic processes. These models have not only the capability of predicting the statistical dispersion of the crack growth rate, which is dependent on the inherent crack resistance characteristics of the material being examined, but also, by incorporating the concept of crack closure into the Paris-Erdogan law through the use of the effective stress intensity range factor, have the capability of transferring the stochastic properties of crack growth rates measured under ideal laboratory conditions to situations of industrial significance, such as those occurring under adverse loading and/or environmental conditions. The primary data required in order to be in a position to estimate the pertinent parameters of these stochastic models are obtained, as is fully discussed in this thesis, from a statistically significant number of replicate tests. The application of both the theory and the experimental technique are illustrated using a Ti-6Al-4V alloy of considerable importance to the aerospace industry. The application of these models for the assessment of component reliability is detailed in the latter stages of the investigation reported in this thesis. Important reliability, availability and maintainability concepts are developed and thoroughly illustrated. In this way, fundamental models developed during the course of this investigation will in the future, have the capability of predicting reliability and maintenance parameters of considerable significance to the assessment of component reliability.</description><creator>Farhangdoost, Khalil</creator><contributor>Provan, James (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>On the fatigue reliability assessment of Ti-6Al-4V</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881n529.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns0647384</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):30325</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>