<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:01:19Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):15325" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214s74c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation is about the architecture of the Swahili peoples living along the eastern coast of Africa. Specifically, it explores the links and relationships between oral traditions, rituals and the built environment of the Waswahili (sing. Mswahili) or the 'people of the coast'. The 'ambiguous' and 'anomalous' identity of the Waswahili raises important questions on the definition and the understanding of Swahili architecture. To understand Swahili architecture, one must, first, understand the language and identity of the Waswahili. This dissertation makes use of new sources for the interpretation of the built environment of the Waswahili as depicted in the standing 18th century buildings in Lamu town, the oldest living town on the eastern coast of Kenya. Designated on UNESCO's World Heritage List, Lamu has a unique architecture that has often been misinterpreted and misunderstood, and such studies often lack authenticity. This dissertation is an attempt to bridge the gap between the identity and the built environment of the Waswahili and to portray Swahili architecture through oral discourse.</description><creator>Kamalkhan, Kalandar, 1961-</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Lamu (Kenya) -- Social life and customs.</subject><subject>Architecture -- Kenya -- Lamu.</subject><subject>Swahili-speaking peoples -- Kenya -- Lamu.</subject><title>The Swahili architecture of Lamu, Kenya : oral tradition and space</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xq19s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214s74c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn00b219z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation addresses the profound influence that the shared experience of humans and animals had on the poetics of early modern drama. With reference to a selection of early modern comedies and a range of non-literary texts that includes natural history encyclopedias and animal husbandry manuals, I argue that the vernacular knowledge of animals shaped the early modern imagination generally and the early modern playwright's imagination particularly. I propose an original approach to early modern literature, one which urges integrating a consideration of the real-world referent for animal representation, the collective life lived by humans and animals, and the poetics of early modern drama. In my introduction, I take up the dissertation's general claims about the ethical and historiographical dimension of interpreting early modern animal representation. I continue to work at this theoretical level in Chapter One, where I consider how the animal-focused disciplines of sociobiology and ecology can help and hinder readers interpret early modern drama. In the following chapters, I work closely with a selection of early modern plays, contexts, and literary and theatrical devices. Chapter Two focuses on a web of comic plays that feature instantiations of animals in stage properties and actor's gestures. The web of plays in Chapter Two includes the anonymous Mucedorus; Lording Barry's Ram Alley; John Fletcher's Women Pleased; Thomas Nashe's Summer's Last Will and Testament ; William Rowley, Thomas Dekker, and John Ford's The Witch of Edmonton; Shakespeare's Love's Labor Lost; and Shakespeare and Fletcher's Two Noble Kinsmen. Chapter Three is devoted to the anthropomorphism of the allegorical representations of animals in Ben Jonson's plays Volpone and The Alchemist. In my reading of Shakespeare's A Midsummer Night's Dream in Chapter Four, I move on to consider animals whose representation is removed from reality not merely by anthropomorphism, but also by magic. All of these instances of representation draw animals into a sphere of existence that is commonly understood as the exclusive domain of humans at the same time that they draw humans in the other direction, which is to say into the muck and mire that is the origin of all life.</description><creator>Margalit, Yael.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>English drama -- Early modern and Elizabethan, 1500-1600.</subject><subject>Animals in literature.</subject><title>Creaturely pleasures : the representation of animals in early modern drama</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806359r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b219z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225f61x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Motivation: Various brand equity measures have been proposed in extant literature. Few researches have explored the theoretical similarities, differences and relationship between different brand equity measures. In the thesis, I will explore two types of brand equity measures, namely customer mind-set measures and product-market performance measures. In particular, I will look at: 1) the correlation between the two types of measures; 2) which measure reflects the underlying brand equity construct better; 3) the impacts of marketing mix elements on the two types measures respectively; and 4) the prediction relationship between customer mind-set measure and product-market performance measure. Theoretical Framework: My main theoretical framework will be brand equity literature. I draw upon the Brand Value Chain framework (Keller &amp; Lehmann, 2(03) to explore the conceptual differences between two types of brand equity measurements, namely customer mind-set and product-market performance measurements. Furthermore, I also use Keller's (1993) Customer-Based Brand Equity concept to explore how specific marketing activities impact the brand equity theoretically. Data and Methodology: This thesis measures brand equity by two methods: customer mind-set (Keller, 1993) and revenue premium (Ailawadi, Lehmann, &amp; Neslin, 2(03). I use two types of data in the empirical analyses. Survey data, procured from a consumer-packaged product company 1, is used to measure customer mind-set brand equity. This unique data consists of proprietary equity scan surveys on 11 brands from 2004 -- 2006 in the United States. The measurement model of brand equity is rooted in Keller's customer-based brand equity concept (1993). The measurements include brand awareness, brand performance, brand image, brand judgment, brand feelings and brand resonance (Keller, 2(01). The second data is from commercial sources, including IRI and TNS, for the specific brands and time periods corresponding to the survey data and includes revenue premium, price, sales, distribution, promotion, and advertising information. Various techniques are employed for analyses including descriptive and reliability analyses, correlation analyses, multiple-regression, and cross-validation. Contribution: The contribution ofthis thesis is threefold. Firstly, it sheds light on the underlying theory and relationship between two types of brand equity measurements and provides empirical test of the theory. Secondly, it provides a systematic exploration of the impact of marketing mix elements on brand equity using real market data and two different measurements. Third, it offers very practical guidance for managers on how to choose a specific brand equity measures and how to track the brand equity measures over time for their brands. 1Because a confidential agreement with this company, the company name, brands name as well as product category will be disguised in the thesis.</description><creator>Huang, Rong, 1973-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Brand choice.</subject><subject>Brand name products -- Management.</subject><title>Exploration of brand equity measures : linking customer mind-set measure to product-market performance measure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79408153w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225f61x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Desautels Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20sx39m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study explores the hitherto unexamined phenomenon of queer-care in higher education from the teacher educators' perspectives. While care in education has been the subject of scholarly interest for many years and demonstrating caring for the wellbeing of students is an important component of teaching, the lack of attention to queer-care is a significant oversight in the body of care research and teacher education. Pertinent to this study is the investigation of how well Noddings' enactments of care (modeling, dialogue, practice, and confirmation) address the care needs of queer students. Four teacher educators shared stories of their efforts to care for the emotional wellbeing of their queer students. As the fifth teacher educator in this work, I investigate my journey to becoming a queer-care practitioner, and my own practice of queer-care. The theoretical frameworks of qualitative and phenomenological research and feminist theory undergird this study. Two processes of analysis were employed, the first being the key sensitizing concepts of Noddings' enactments of care as points of entry into an understanding of the teacher educators' narratives of queer-care. The second level of analysis used the insights so gleaned to guide the focus of the self-study undertaken in this work. Analysis of the teacher educators' narratives indicates that the practice of queer-care, while sharing certain similarities, is idiosyncratic, complicated, lonely, and often exhausting work. Alongside these findings are indicators that queer-care as practiced by these teacher educators is welcomed by queer students as being all too rare in their university experience, and of benefit to their sense of wellbeing. Findings also reveal that Noddings' enactments of care neither include nor address the particular care needs of queer students. This led me to identify particular care needs of queer students as being those of unwavering discretion, absolute safety, full social membership, and unstinting succour. This necessary awareness expands Noddings' model of care allowing it to include and be responsive to queer students. This research has implications for teacher educators and any educators concerned with the wellbeing of queer students. It provides suggestions to enrich caring practice in teacher education programs and field experience.</description><creator>Benson, Fiona.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Homophobia in schools.</subject><subject>Homophobia in higher education.</subject><subject>Homosexuality and education.</subject><subject>Teachers -- Training of.</subject><subject>Education -- Social aspects.</subject><title>Teacher educators' practice of queer-care : a necessary expansion of Noddings' model care</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g846m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20sx39m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Curriculum and Instruction</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816r03b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The modern soundscape buzzes with noise. In the 1930s, telephones, radios, and gramophones filled domestic spaces with technological noise, while crowds shouting in the streets created political clamour. During the war in the 1940s, bombs and sirens broke through buildings and burst through consciousness. This dissertation examines the response of three British modernist writers to the cultural shifts brought about by technology and politics, which altered everyday experience and social relations. Elizabeth Bowen, Evelyn Waugh, and George Orwell represent noise in their fiction and nonfiction as a trope of power. Noise, as a palpable emblem of discontent and the acoustic unconsciousness of the period, infiltrates sentences and rearranges syntax, as in the invention of Newspeak in Nineteen Eight-Four. Noise cannot leave listeners in a neutral position. The "culture racket" of the 1930s and 1940s required urgent new ways of listening and listening with ethical intent. Chapter One provides a reading of Elizabeth Bowen's audible terrains in her novels of the 1930s, where silences and sudden noises intrude on human lives. In Bowen's novels, technological noise has both comedic and tragic consequences. Chapter Two examines noise as a political signifier in The Heat of the Day, Bowen's novel of the blitz. Chapter Three takes up the significance of the culture racket to Evelyn Waugh's novels and travel writing of the 1930s; noise assumes a disruptive, if highly comedic, value in his works, an ambiguity that expresses what it means to be modern. Chapter Four examines Waugh's penchant for satirizing the phoneyness of contemporary culture---its political vacillations---especially in Put Out More Flags, set during the Second World War. Chapter Five considers Orwell's engagement with the emerging social and political formations amongst working, racial, and warring classes in the 1930s. Documenting noise in his reportage, Orwell sounds alarms to alert readers to the mounting social and political crises in his realist novels of the decade. Chapter Six argues that Orwell's final two novels of the 1940s, Animal Farm and Nineteen Eighty-Four, represent the politics of noise in as much as they announce the noise of politics in totalitarian futures. Noise demarcates the insidiousness of propaganda as it screeches from telescreens, the keynote in Big Brother's ideological symphony of domination. Noise, throughout Orwell's writing, signifies the struggle for power. In its widest ramifications, noise provides an interpretive paradigm through which to read Bowen's, Waugh's, and Orwell's fiction and non-fiction, as well as modernist texts generally.</description><creator>Feenstra, Robin E. (Robin Edward), 1972-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Bowen, Elizabeth, 1899-1973 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Sound in literature.</subject><subject>Technology in literature.</subject><subject>Waugh, Evelyn, 1903-1966 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Orwell, George, 1903-1950 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Modern noise : Bowen, Waugh, Orwell</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g609b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816r03b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q524js370</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A wealth of recent scholarship has focused on interreligious dialogue as a resource for the transformation of religious conflicts. Such studies often mention the importance of discoveries or 'insights' as key factors in successful dialogue processes. However, few authors have devoted sustained attention to understanding how insights contribute to transforming conflict dynamics during interfaith dialogues. The present study draws on the cognitional theory of Canadian philosopher Bernard Lonergan as a framework for exploring the significance of insights in interreligious dialogue processes. The study begins with an overview of representative perspectives on learning in interfaith dialogue and conflict transformation. Following this, I offer a detailed analysis of Lonergan's work on insight in understanding, judgment, and practical learning, highlighting the important role that insights play in structuring interpretation and communication in dialogue situations. Drawing on Lonergan's theoretical framework, I explore how insights are implicated in shaping communication in dialogues between religious actors, both in the development of conflicts, as well as in their transformation. Using case studies from dialogues involving Christians, Muslims, and Jews, I examine how mistaken insights can contribute to sustaining relationships of threat among parties in religious conflicts. I then examine how dialogue processes can act as catalysts for the emergence of new and more accurate insights that transform parties' understanding of the conflict. By helping parties correct mistaken interpretations and discover alternate ways of communicating, such insights can often play an important role in facilitating shifts from hostile patterns of interaction to more cooperative forms of engagement. Throughout, I explain how Lonergan's work offers significant advances over existing discussions of insight and its role in conflict transformation processes. His approach identifies a range of different types of insights, and thus facilitates an analysis of the different roles insights can play in structuring communication at different phases of dialogue processes. It also permits a more developed exploration of the various cognitional and environmental conditions that facilitate or frustrate the occurrence of insights in dialogue situations. His work thus constitutes an important resource for theorists and practitioners seeking a better understanding of the cognitive dynamics that contribute to the transformation of interreligious dialogue processes.</description><creator>Bianchi Melchin, Derek.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Religions -- Relations.</subject><subject>Religious pluralism.</subject><subject>Lonergan, Bernard J. F.</subject><title>Insight, learning, and dialogue in the transformation of religious conflict : applications from the work of Bernard Lonergan</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v838405j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524js370</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451n12m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The dynamics of airline deregulation have resulted in significant changes in airline competition and network structure. This dissertation examines airline competition and network structures in the presence of low-cost entry in a deregulated environment. The first chapter investigates the effect of low-cost entry on the equilibrium network choice of a monopolistic air carrier. This essay differs from previous analyses in that it incorporates asymmetric city sizes, and distances as a determinant of costs into the model. Numerical exercises illustrate that the threat of entry may result in an entry accommodating, an entry deterring or even an interlining equilibrium, depending on demand and cost conditions and on the level of fixed costs of connecting city pairs. In particular, when the demand in city-pair markets are identical and cities are equal distance apart, the monopolist restructures its network in an attempt to minimize the competitive effect of entry. If demands vary across city pairs and distance is a factor of cost, then the restructuring of the network may be an entry deterring strategy. The incorporation of distance not only influences the number of direct connections between city pairs but may also affect how city pairs are connected within the network. In Essay Two the model is extended to a duopolistic airline market in which network structures are endogenously determined by the competition between two incumbent airlines; numerical exercises are then used to demonstrate how the threat of entry by a low-cost airline affects the network choices of these incumbent carriers. The main result of the essay is that, in many situations, incumbent carriers restructure their networks in order to compete with potential entrants. The results indicate that incumbents' response to the threat of entry depends on the potential entrant's cost advantage and on the fixed costs of connecting city pairs. In particular, if the fixed costs of connecting city pairs are low and the cost advantage of the entrant is significant then entry may not affect the network structure of incumbent carriers. However, at higher fixed costs at least one incumbent will adjust its network in an attempt to soften the competitive effect of entry. Furthermore, the numerical exercises show that the threat of entry not only affects the equilibrium network structure but may also result in one incumbent leaving the industry and the potential entrant actually entering. Essay Three studies network competition and welfare implications in partially and fully liberalized transatlantic markets using the model developed in Essay Two. This essay illustrates some conditions under which the price and welfare effects of an open-skies agreement depend on the equilibrium network choice of the competing airlines. In particular, network choices of airlines may result in higher prices on some transatlantic routes and if pre-liberalized domestic markets are competitive price reductions on domestic routes could be negligible. Another finding is that the opening of transatlantic markets mainly redistribute airlines' market shares and as a result the expected increase in passenger traffic may not be realized.</description><creator>Belford, Carlene.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Airlines -- Deregulation.</subject><subject>Competition.</subject><subject>Airlines -- Cost of operation.</subject><title>Essays on airine competition and network structure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vp51f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451n12m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dz76h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study seeks to analyze the Turkish nation-building process during the early Republican period (1920-1938). In doing this, the substantive focus will be on three main dimensions --language, education, and citizenship -- with particular emphasis on the rhetoric and actions of the political elite. By looking at language, education, and citizenship policies, and their formulations, the present analysis will make three main propositions: First, and in contrast to the existing literature on nations and nation-building, it will be demonstrated that the process of Turkish nation-building was neither a smooth nor an automatic process. Moreover, during the period under analysis, there were competing definitions of nationhood which were taken up, and discussed by the political elite. The final conceptualization of nationhood --which took an assimilationist form with an ethnic understanding attached to it -- was formed over time. At times, the process was wrought with tensions as illustrated by the heated debates among the political elite. Second, the present analysis will seek to bring together two different ways of looking at nation formation. More specifically, the analysis will attempt to bridge the gap between those works which only underline the role of ideas in the formation of nations, and those which emphasize the role of structural forces. By paying attention to the "voices" (and actions) of the political elite, this study will demonstrate that it is not only ideas, nor is it only structural forces that matter. Rather, the crystallization of the contents of Turkish nationhood illustrates the interplay of ideological as well as geopolitical and political forces. Third, a detailed analysis of the trajectory of Turkish nation-building and the formulation of Turkish nationhood reveals the complexity of this process. The existing literature on Turkey tends to treat the Kemalist era as an undifferentiated whole. The present work will remain critical to such an outlook. Instead, and by looking at the shifting conceptualizations of nationhood, it will seek to demonstrate the complexity and contingent nature of the Turkish nation-building process.</description><creator>Bayar, Yesim.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Nationalism -- Turkey -- History -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Turkey -- Ethnic relations -- History -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Education -- Turkey -- History -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Turkey -- History -- 1918-1960.</subject><title>Turkish nation-building process : an analysis of language, education, and citizenship policies during the early Republic (1920-1938)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mn394.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dz76h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65vc09p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis aims at defining the argumentative terms and strategies of the rhetoric of praise in printed collected eulogies of women of the first half of the XVIth Century, both in collections of famous women (which celebrate exceptional feminine figures) and apologies of the female sex (which defend womankind through praise). The inquiry starts with the first French printed translation of Boccaccio's De mulieribus claris, entitled De la louenge et vertu des nobles et cleres dames (1493), and ends with the Fort inexpugnable de l'honneur du sexe foeminin (1555) by Francois de Billon, who provides the first historic panorama of the encomiastic tradition. Its specificity lies in the combination of two types of collective eulogy, which up to now have been separately analyzed but which in fact deserve to be taken up in a single interpretative gesture. Our approach, that of rhetoric, is founded in composition manuals and treatises on ancient eloquence, as well as recent theory on argumentation. Unlike other studies which take the rhetorical approach, this thesis deals with a relatively short time span, about fifty years, which allows a reading of the texts in their historical and literary contexts. Through the vantage points of inventio and dispositio, this thesis shows how a discourse praising women collectively was built, at a time when women formed the crux of contradicting discourses and the centre of a topics that crystallized those tensions. Beyond this uncertain discursive situation, this thesis also claims to bring to light a neglected aspect of eulogy: its function as definition of object praised. It offers, therefore, a reflection on epideictic rhetoric from a perspective of the poetics of literary genre. This is seen as a space that is propitious to the exploration of ethical stakes, such as the valorization of individual feminine figures, the fashioning of the author's persona or the introduction of secondary objectives which bear new values.</description><creator>Breitenstein, Renée-Claude.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>French literature -- 16th century.</subject><subject>French literature -- To 1500.</subject><subject>Laudatory poetry.</subject><subject>Women in literature.</subject><title>La rhétorique encomiastique dans les éloges collectifs de femmes imprimés de la première Renaissance française (1493-1555) /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f472c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65vc09p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vq27zr97z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The socio-economic and political changes effected in Kerala by the British and colonial discourse at the beginning of the twentieth century challenged traditional structures of power. This eventually resulted in social mobility within various communities which, as a result, embraced modernity and began to pursue modern education. However, Mappila Muslims' long-standing tradition of struggle against colonial powers and their hatred of British rule had led them to resist the modernization process and consequently become more socially and educationally backward than other communities in Kerala. It was in this context that Vakkom Muhammad Abdul Khadir Moulavi (1873-1932), who is acknowledged as the "father" of the Muslim socio-religious reform movement in Kerala, undertook to persuade Mappilas to embrace various aspects of modernity, especially modern education. Based mainly on primary sources written in Malayalam, this pioneering study argues that Vakkom Moulavi's thought was largely shaped by the colonial discourse on modernity. It shows how he reinterpreted Islamic principles and Muslim history using the framework of the rational, secular, universal humanism of the European Enlightenment. One result of this was that his reinterpretation precluded the possibility of understanding Islam as discursive tradition, which in turn reified Islam and negated the potential vibrancy of Islamic societies. At the same time his championing of modern education as a means to modernization eventually tore traditional Muslim education from its historical and cultural roots. The study also demonstrates that, because he saw the state is a key agent in the modernization process, he was keen to educate people about their rights and responsibilities. In sum, this analysis of Vakkom Moulavi's career demonstrates that, in order to understand the intellectual framework and activities of modern socio-religious reform movements, these latter need to be studied in the light of colonial discourse on modernity.</description><creator>Abraham, Jose, 1970-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Islamic renewal -- India -- Kerala.</subject><subject>Islam -- India -- Kerala.</subject><subject>Moulavi, Vakkom, 1873-1932.</subject><subject>Moplahs.</subject><title>Modernity, Islamic reform, and the Mappilas of Kerala : the contributions of Vakkom Moulavi (1873-1932)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xz59c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zr97z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225f626</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Africa, as both a place and as an idea, looms large in the construction of Black identity in Brazil and plays an increasingly important role in the identity processes of many Afro-American societies. Consequently, this dissertation seeks to explore how the idea of Africa is used and manipulated in the discourse and formulation of Blackness in the northeastern Brazilian state Bahia. Today, Afro-Brazilian elites and academics---particularly anthropologists---privilege the cultures of the Bight of Benin as crucial markers of a new Black identity in Black Bahia's religious spaces, cultural institutions and social movements. This new form of Black identity seeks to reject the dominant ideology of 'racial democracy' in Brazil and replace it with one that articulates an Africanised approach to Blackness. In this model, Yoruba religious practices are emphasised and placed at the centre of an array of cultural forms including carnaval, Afro-Brazilian religion, language instruction, culinary practice and the remnant maroon communities of the Bahian interior. In analysing these movements, the present work eschews the need to define Afro-Brazilian cultural practices in the historical context of a plantation society that contained so-called 'survivals' of African culture. Rather, this work adopts a perspective that simply attempts to understand how ideas such as 'Africa', 'slave', 'roots', 'orixa', 'Yoruba' and other, similar African concepts are deployed in the creation of Bahian, and more generally, Brazilian Blackness. Further, the construction of Africanised Blackness in Bahia needs to be understood in the context of an ongoing live dialogue between the cultures and peoples of Afro-America and different regions of the African continent. This dissertation explores this dialogue and also investigates the extent to which these redefinitions actually resonate and penetrate the diverse Black populations of Bahia, including those that are not actively involved with Bahia's Black movements, such as evangelical Christians and residents of the impoverished Bahian interior---the sertao. Keywords: Africa, Bahia, Blackness, Brazil, dialogue, elites, ethnography, identity, Yoruba.</description><creator>Dawson, Allan Charles, 1973-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Africa -- Civilization.</subject><subject>Blacks -- Brazil -- Bahia (State) -- Race identity.</subject><title>In light of Africa : globalising blackness in northeast Brazil</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149t127.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225f626</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tx31qn273</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Critical social work theories have taken a prominent place in Canadian social work curriculums and academic social work literature in recent years. The prevalence of critical social work theory is understandable considering that the content of critical theories can help social workers grapple with how to carry out a practice that is centrally concerned with social justice. However, critical social work theories have generally been presented abstractly, with little attention placed upon the particular contexts of social work practice. As a result, not much is known about how critical social work theory is actually applied in practice. This is especially important in the context of child protection, where issues of oppression and power are particularly acute. This thesis is premised on the assumption that an understanding of the context of child protection work is necessary in order to develop a critical social work theory that is applicable to this field. The thesis examines the context of child protection practice by exploring the subjective experiences of 14 front-line child protection workers. Drawing on in-depth interviews that focus on day-to-day practice, this thesis suggests that child protection work involves dealing with a range of fears that influence workers' practice, including their fears about children being harmed and about their own physical and professional vulnerability. As well, child protection workers presented a picture of the ways that their legislative and organizational context shaped their work. These factors of child protection appeared to influence a practice in which relationships and interventions with clients were focused on monitoring parents' completion of a series of tasks and children were constructed as vulnerable, individual, and rights-bearing. Ideas for a critical child protection practice are offered, based on these results. In particular, a critical child protection practice that includes the adoption of more detailed attention to the internal worlds of parents, child-care workers and children is discussed.</description><creator>Collings, Sara, 1971-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Social advocacy.</subject><subject>Social justice.</subject><subject>Child welfare.</subject><title>Experiences from the front-line : implications for a critical child protection practice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02871054d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qn273</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795c35f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Today, education is arguably one of the most important facets used to prepare and train students for the future. Society expects that students will acquire the requisite knowledge and competence in their respective fields to prepare them to successfully navigate the demands of today's competitive markets. This expectation has consequences on teachers at all levels of education across many domains. Teachers have a significant role: to prepare students for the future. Competent teachers spend a great deal of time reflecting on their own practices and beliefs, reviewing their teaching goals and evaluating if students have met these goals effectively. The process of reflection in teaching is vital in the preparation and training of students. The purpose of this dissertation therefore was to investigate how statistics professors reflect on their practice. The research questions were designed to access what statistics teachers thought about before giving their courses and before giving two of their classes (hypothesis testing, t-tests). Post class evaluation interviews were conducted to determine where professors thought they were effective and whether they considered a need for change based on student understanding. More specifically, the questions asked: 1) What are the main themes in teacher reflection? 2) How is the content of reflection similar or different between statistics teachers? 3) How is the content of teacher reflection defined in statistics? The design was based on a grounded theory approach whereby data collection consisted solely of interviews conducted throughout the semester: one pre-course interview and two sets of pre-class and post-class interviews. There were 13 participants in total. Participants were either statistics teachers from Quebec Cegeps or university professors. Participants were from the following departments: anthropology, economics, psychology, sociology, education, math, and biology. The analyses dealt with three data sources: pre class reflection, in class reflection, and post class reflection. Data analysis focused on defining the main themes of teacher reflection that emerged from the data, identifying the content of reflection between and within participants in terms of similarities or differences. The pre course interview revealed five main themes: the course (logistics), the teacher as 'self, teaching approaches (what do they say they do in the classroom?), teaching and learning influences, and evaluation of teaching. The pre and post class interviews addressed class planning. What did the professors foresee as any issues students might have in understanding hypothesis testing and t-tests? What changes would they make the next time they taught these concepts? Results showed that the focus of professor reflection centered around three main categories: the class, the student, and the teacher. For the main category, class, some professors reviewed lecture notes, added examples that emphasized authentic statistical problems, and others did no preparation. Student related themes addressed issues students had with understanding statistical content, learning associated difficulties, and student affect. The last category, the teacher, looked at self evaluation, their in-class strategies, methods of promoting and gauging student understanding, and decisions made in class and for future classes. Recommendations for future research include examining the role of experience in professor's level of reflection as well as defining the process of decision making and its role in reflection.</description><creator>Cumyn, Lucy A.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Statistics -- Study and teaching (Higher)</subject><subject>Effective teaching.</subject><subject>Reflection (Philosophy)</subject><title>Pedagogical reflection in statistics instruction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395wc098.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795c35f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54kr57t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The three essays in the present dissertation build on and expand the notion of generativity in the context of a learning (i.e., knowledge creating) organization, and learning (i.e., knowledge based) economy in sequential progression with increasing levels of analysis. Essay One advances a view of individuals' learning motivated by their desire to grow, and the role of a generative individual in motivating and supporting such a desire in others to enable collective and cumulative learning processes in a learning organization. Essay Two expands upon Essay One by examining 1) the dominant value of generativity, "caring for the growth of others," as a core value of the organizational culture in a knowledge creating company to proliferate the generative interpersonal relationship examined in Essay One for enhancing the company's knowledge creating capability, and 2) the evolutionary progression from ba to basho that the company makes in order to amplify its internal creative processes through a partnership with a network of others, based on mutual growth and benefits to them by extending caring, beyond the company's organizational boundary. Essay Three empirically verifies the theoretical perspective of Essays One and Two through an in-depth case analysis of Qualcomm using a pattern matching analysis. We subsequently conclude the dissertation by reflecting upon our journey in the context of a view that a good society should enable and support individual constituents to live as contributing members achieving their individual and collective aspirations.</description><creator>Chu, Hankyu.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Organizational learning.</subject><subject>Social psychology.</subject><title>Three essays on generativity and caring in constructing partnership orientation in learning organizations and the society</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j883x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kr57t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Desautels Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:np193d44f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aims of this study are two-fold: (a) to describe facilitators' educational beliefs about human rights education (HRE), and (b) to identify which of these are shared and are idiosyncratic. Using research on teachers' educational beliefs as a starting point for this study, the following five dimensions of educational beliefs about HRE were explored: (a) participants and participating, (b) facilitation, (c) HRE, (d) learning to facilitate, and (e) Self and the facilitation role. A sample of facilitators from North and Central America, Eastern Europe, Western and Eastern Africa, and South and South-East Asia who were affiliated with a large-scale HRE training program were invited to participate in this study. Fifteen facilitators were interviewed, three of whom consented to providing additional data through stimulated recall sessions. Research results suggest that facilitators' shared educational beliefs about HRE represent universal principles of facilitation practices in the field, while idiosyncratic beliefs are linked to local needs and issues, respectively. Focusing on facilitators' shared educational beliefs provides the basis for a general model of possible relationships that exist between key components of HRE. Outcomes from this study indicate that the psychological construct of educational beliefs is both a significant factor and viable research focus involved in the professional practices of facilitators working in non-formal contexts. Implications for future research and professional development arising from this study of facilitators' edudtional beliefs in non-formal educational contexts are discussed.</description><creator>Chin, Kevin.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Human rights -- Study and teaching.</subject><subject>Teachers -- Attitudes.</subject><title>Exploring facilitators' beliefs in the field of human rights education</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687m69s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193d44f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g158bm94w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les importants benefices de I' allaitement maternel pour la sante sont tres bien documentes, et on recommande a. l'heure actuelle d'allaiter exclusivement (c.-a.-d. de ne donner que du lait maternel au nourisson) durant les six premiers mois de vie. Guidee par Ie modele interactionnel (Loiselle, 2001), cette etude prospective corelationnelle a examine l'influence predictive et interactive de facteurs potentiellement modifiables personnels (la confiance en l'allaitement, les croyances des meres face a. I'allaitement, la perception de la satisfaction du bebe qui allaite) et contextuels (les croyances des peres face a. l'allaitement, l'information disponible sur l'allaitement, Ie soutien en matiere de post-partum) conditionnant la duree et l'exclusivite de l'allaitement maternel d'un echantillon de convenance de 189 meres primipares allaitantes. Les facteurs personnels, contextuels, et de contr6le ont ete evalues en fonction de questionnaires d'auto-evaluation remplis durant l'hospitalisation, a. 6 semaines et a. 4 mois post-partum.[...]</description><description>The significant health benefits of breastfeeding are extensively documented, and it is now recommended to breastfeed exclusively (Le., feed infants nothing but breastmilk) for the first 6 months of life. Guided by the Interactional Model (Loiselle, 2001), this prospective correlational study explored the predictive and interactive influence of potentially modifiable personal (Le., breastfeeding self-efficacy, maternal infant feeding beliefs, perceived infant satisfaction with breastfeeding) and contextual factors (i.e., paternal infant feeding beliefs, breastfeeding informational support, general postpartum support) on breastfeeding duration and exclusivity among a convenience sample of 189 primiparous breastfeeding mothers. Personal, contextual, and control factors were assessed by self-report questionnaires and/or interviews during postpartum hospitalization, at 6 weeks, and at 4 months postpartum. Breastfeeding outcomes were assessed via telephone interview at 6 weeks, 4 months, and 6 months postpartum. [...]</description><creator>Semenic, Sonia E.</creator><contributor>Loiselle, Carmen (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2005</date><subject>Nursing.</subject><title>The influence of personal and contextual factors on breastfeeding duration and exclusivity among first-time mothers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h303w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bm94w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Nursing</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26z165t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Imperialism, as understood by the British in the year 1850, was sentimental in essence as opposed to later utilitarianism. Lord Beaconsfield and his party assumed ‘’an attitude of superiority towards other civilized nations.” “Trade follows the flag” had not yet become an Imperial slogan. [...]</description><creator>Ritchie, Verna Ford</creator><contributor>Reid, W. Standford (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1959</date><subject>South Africa -- History.</subject><subject>Rhodes, Cecil, 1853-1902.</subject><subject>History, African.</subject><subject>Great Britain -- Colonies -- Africa.</subject><title>Cecil Rhodes’ influence on the British government’s policy in South Africa, 1870-1899.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t284x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z165t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g732dd49j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The soil-solution partitioning of dissolved organic carbon (DOC) withinmineral soil horizons is primarily controlled by processes of adsorption and desorption. These abiotic processes largely occur within a short equilibration time of seconds to minutes, which generally occur faster than microbial processes. To characterise the adsorption of DOC to mineral soils, I used the Langmuir adsorption isotherm, which holds several advantages to the commonly used linear initial mass (IM) isotherm. One advantage to using the Langmuir isotherm is anestimation of the maximum DOC adsorption capacity (Qmax). The Qmax estimates the number of remaining DOC binding sites available on the mineral soil particle surfaces. I modified the traditional Langmuir isotherm in order to estimate the DOC desorption potential of native soil organic matter (SOC).[...]</description><description>Le partitionnement entre les solutions de sols du carbone organiquedissous (COD) dans les horizons des sols minéraux est essentiellement contrôle par les processus d'adsorption et de désorption. Ces processus abiotiques se déroulent normalement dans un bref temps d'équilibration variant de quelques secondes a quelques minutes, ce qui est en général plus rapide que les processus microbiens. Pour caractériser Fadsorption de COD aux sols minéraux, nous avons utilise l'isotherme d'adsorption de Langmuir. Cette isotherme présente plusieurs avantages par rapport a Fisotherme de masses initiales (IM) linéaires couramment utilisée, en particulier F estimation de la capacité d'adsorption maximale du COD (Qmax). Le Qmax estime le nombre de sites de liaison de COD restants a la surface du sol minéral. Nous avons aussi modifie Fisotherme de Langmuir traditionnelle afin d'évaluer le potentiel de désorption de COD de la matière organique du sol indigène (MOS).[...]</description><creator>Kothawala, Dolly N.</creator><contributor>Moore, Tim (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Soils -- Organic compound content -- Canada.</subject><subject>Soils -- Nitrogen content -- Canada.</subject><subject>Forest soils -- Canada.</subject><subject>Soil absorption and adsorption -- Canada.</subject><title>Controls on the soil solution partitioning of dissolved organic carbon and nitrogen in the mineral horizons of forested soils</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pk78m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732dd49j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3484zm27q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A subject that is beginning to be discussed more widely - heretofore, especially in Church circles, is the relationship between Sacremental Confession and Psyohotherapy* The problem centres mound the question of how the priest or minister can make use of either or both of these practices to the furthering of his office in the Church, and to the benefit of those committed to his charge. The question is. asked, are the two mutually exclusive, or is there some area in which they both can be used, or are they both to be used together? [...]</description><creator>Rogers, David Handley</creator><date>1960</date><subject>Confession.</subject><subject>Psychotherapy.</subject><title>The relation of sacramental confession and psychotherapy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pk79w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zm27q</identifier><degree><name>Bachelor of Divinity</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429d93b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In a recent publication* by the Quebec Fertilizer Board for farmers, some emphasis was placed on the fact that the soils of Quebec are "undernourished" and are gradually becoming "impoverished." Figures were also presented which indicated that there was a general decline in fertilizer usage during the 1945-1956 period. It has been the general opinion that the soils of Quebec are not sufficiently fertile to warrant this decline in the use of commercial fertilizers. To study the situation more thoroughly, the establishment of field experiments appeared to be a logical endeavour.</description><creator>Beauchamp, Eric. G.</creator><contributor>Steppler, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Agronomy.</subject><title>The response of oat crops and succeeding hay crops to chemical fertilizers on different soil types in southwestern Quebec.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43p166p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429d93b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agriculture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wk59w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Kierkegaard was utterly convinced that apologetics were a form of treason arising out of stupidity, and that whosoever invented them has been a second Judas within the Christian world. It is true however, that apologetics have been the concern of Christian Theologians throughout the History of the Church. The twentieth century does not constitute an exception to this rule in spite of the passionate warning of the Danish philosopher and its profound repercussions in the theology of K. Barth. The demythologization programme, championed by Rudolph Bultmann in the field of New Testament studies, seems to pursue once again the defence of Christian faith in the modern world.</description><creator>Bertalot, Renzo.</creator><contributor>McLelland, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Divinity.</subject><title>Imago Christi: an investigation of the doctrine of man according to the later writings of Paul Tillich (Systematic Theology II) and Karl Barth (Church Dogmatics III, 2).</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k595x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wk59w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Religion</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j4491</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The first aviation law was promulgated in 1784, just one year after the first successful balloon flight was made by the Montgolfier Brothers in 1783. This was a decree by the Prefect of Police, Paris, forbidding balloon flights without police permits. This indicates the prompt response of law to the new invention. The first regulation for safety in aerial navigation was made by the Prefect of Seine in 1819, which prohibited the flights of the Montgolfiers (named after the pioneer flyers), required all balloons to be equipped with parachutes and forbade ascents until after the harvest time. The first reported case of tort in aviation was decided in 1822, in the United States of America.</description><creator>Ahmad, Mumtaz.</creator><contributor>Pépin, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1957</date><subject>International Air Law.</subject><title>The law of civil aviation in Pakistan.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd376118p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j4491</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jq226</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The patterns of land subdivision form an essential element in the analysis of an urban area. In this essay an attempt is made to evaluate the importance of these patterns for urban growth on the Island of Montréal. The approach is an historical one, since the understanding of past patterns aids in our comprehension of the present. Thus in Part One the historical background to land granting procedures is examined, firstly in the Province of Québec, and then for the Island of Montréal. The cadastral divisions of the Island are discussed in Chapter Three, and a classification of the long lot systems is proposed. Part Two traces in greater detail the subsequent subdivision of the long lots for urban purposes.</description><creator>Khor, Ean. L.</creator><contributor>Spence-Sales, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Architecture.</subject><title>Evolution of patterns of land subdivision with special reference to Montreal.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hn935.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jq226</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h793b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The possibility of extending the range of operation of turbojet engine to hypersonic Mach number and its possible uses have been investigated. It is well known that addition or an afterburner extends the range of turbojet to Mach number of about 3. A further addition or a cooling system between ram intake and compressor can extend this range to Mach number of up to 6, depending upon the specific impulse required. A study of the choice of cooling systems for the precooled turbojet has been made. Liquid methane is used as the fuel and while passing through a heat exchanger it does some cooling. The thermodynamic cycle study and other considerations show that for the remaining part or the cooling load an aerothermopressor is advantageous as compared to a water heat exchanger.</description><creator>Keswani, Chander. A.</creator><contributor>Mordell, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering.</subject><title>An investigation of the precooled turbojet engine.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mt36t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h793b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816r04m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:47:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present hospital mortality rate for myocardial infarction is reported as 47%, and when shock occurs it is said to be above 85% regardless of the type of therapy. Most of these patients die in left heart failure. It is obvious that present treatment of myocardial infarction is inadequate and a new approach is required. The answer appears to lie in some type of support to the heart which could adequately maintain systemic and coronary circulation, while the damaged myocardium recovers from its injury. With such assisted circulation surgical correction could be accomplished in isolated lesions and collateral circulation might develop in diffuse disease.</description><creator>Keon, Wilbert. J.</creator><contributor>Scott, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>The investigation of closed left heart bypass.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zm280.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816r04m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Health Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):15350</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>