<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:32:40Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):23800" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x508m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study records an attempt to apply feminist epistemology to the conduct and communication of social science research, specifically of the Badgley Report. When I began, I wanted to understand why and how mainstream social science research persists in evading feminist analysis of the problem of child sexual abuse, despite agreement on incidence and perpetrators. I also wanted to find ways of producing knowledge that did not either evade nor postpone voicing the truths of women's and children's experiences of child sexual abuse. I have learned that commitment to a feminist framework requires critical consciousness of all aspects of the processes by which knowledge is constructed, including the relationship and interaction between the writer and reader of research. Thus, what I have attempted to do in this thesis is to communicate feminist research processes through both the form and the content of my report.</description><creator>Solari, Pauline</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Sex crimes -- Canada</subject><subject>Committee on Sexual Offences Against Children and Youths (Canada)</subject><subject>Child sexual abuse -- Canada.</subject><subject>Child abuse -- Canada</subject><title>Searching for ways to voice women's truths : a feminist interpretation of the Badgley report</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj2363145.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x508m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p148g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The French personalist movement (1930-1938) finds its origins in French Neo-criticism and Thomism, and German existentialism. The contribution of Russian religious-populist philosophy has not yet been studied. Nikolai Berdyaev (1874-1948) incorporated this tradition in his philosophy. Exiled after the Russian Revolution, he brought his version of Russian "personalism" to France, where his works were seized as a manifesto by the French personalist movements L'Ordre Nouveau and Esprit. Alexandre Marc (1904-), another exile, and Emmanuel Mounier (1905-1950) tried to reconstruct the Russian mir as a French institution. Populism envisioned Russia as a decentralized federation of autonomous mirs; likewise, French personalists advocated a federalized European union in which communal patries would serve as the primary unit of government. Russian populism presented models for and was perpetuated by the French personalists. The influence of Russian ideas on French personalism offers a new dimension to the History of ideas.</description><creator>Baird, Catherine, 1966-</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Populism -- France</subject><subject>Populism -- Soviet Union</subject><title>Russian personalism : the influence of Russian populism on French personalism, 1930-1938</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g130s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p148g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj139303d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The role of ethnic minorities in present day Quebec is clearly one of the important topics which many researchers and social players of diverse political and cultural allegiances have addressed and still continue to address. The study which follows, attempts to show the importance which is given to French by certain non-francophone youths attending French schools and colleges in the regions of Montreal and Hull. The analysis of socio-linguistic attitudes and behaviours of these youths, as well as their vision of the future with respect to the French or English reality is especially needed, as school aged youth are the ones who will soon become important actors in a Quebec which is becoming more and more multicultural. This kind of analysis is also important because it allows for a better understanding of the causal factors underlying these attitudes and behaviours. It is therefore the achievement of these objectives with which the following study is concerned.</description><creator>Corbeil, Jean-Pierre, 1961-</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Minorities -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Sociolinguistics -- Québec (Province)</subject><title>Vision et agir linguistiques chez des jeunes non-francophones du Québec</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25x962z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139303d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150k30j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Experimental and theoretical studies on the extraction of the cation K$ sp+$ and Mg$ sp{++}$ from a bulk aqueous phase to an organic phase using the water/dinonylnaphthalene sulfonic acid (HD)/heptane reverse-micellar system was conducted. The counter ion of the surfactant, H$ sp+$, was exchanged with the alkali metal cations in the aqueous phase. Two different types of experiments were conducted. The first set involved a constant total normality of ions while the second investigated the effect, of varying the normality of ions. Electrolyte solutions with molarities ranging from 0 to 1 were contacted with a reverse-micellar organic containing different concentrations of surfactant with different types of counter ions. The HD reverse-micellar extraction system exhibited behavior similar to that of conventional ion-exchange resin systems. A preferential extraction for Mg$ sp{++}$ over K$ sp+$ was observed. The efficiency of the extraction was high for low salt concentrations and it was independent of surfactant concentration. The amount of water uptake was low, with W$ sb{o}$ ranging between 4 and 10. For a wide range of salt and surfactant concentrations W$ sb{o}$ was independent of surfactant concentration. The HD surfactant showed a low solubility in the aqueous phase. The results of the equilibrium partition experiments were correlated using a thermodynamic model. Interaction parameters determined from binary system experimental data were used to predict the ternary system partition behavior. The ternary system predictions were compared with experimental results and found to be satisfactory.</description><creator>Ashrafizadeh, Seyed Nezameddin</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Cation exchange with reverse-micelles</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dd56n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150k30j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:05741s93j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the role of broadcasting in Canada with regard to developing and maintaining a national identity in the face of United States influence via the media. The subject is examined within the theoretical framework provided by the science of cybernetics and the Laws of Thermodynamics. A historical overview of Canadian broadcasting policy and institutions is provided. The work of the various royal commissions and other investigatory bodies is analyzed. The most important contemporary institutions, the CRTC, the CBC and the federal Department of Communications, are situated within the context. The effects of the most recent technologies, cable television, satellites, Pay-TV and VCRs are examined. Canadian broadcasting is also viewed in the context of the 1989 Canada-United States Free Trade Agreement and the New World Information and Communication Order. Our conclusion suggests that the future of Canada's identity depends primarily on the quality of domestic broadcasting. Finally, we suggest that Canadians and Europeans, who are facing some comparable problems in a united Europe, can learn from each others's experiences.</description><creator>Rapp-Jaletzke, Sybille M.</creator><contributor>Thomson, Dale C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1991</date><subject>Nationalism -- Canada</subject><subject>Television broadcasting -- Social aspects -- Canada</subject><title>The Canadian experience : broadcasting in Canada and its influence on the Canadian identity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n224h.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741s93j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v692t746p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The temperature of the polymer melt plays an important role in injection molding, directly affecting the quality of the molded part. A new barrel, nozzle, and crew tip were constructed for an injection molding machine to allow the installation a Vanzetti infrared optical fiber temperature sensor and several exposed junction thermocouples. These sensors were compared for the measurement of polymer melt temperature. Open loop pseudo-random binary sequence experiments were performed to obtain dynamic temperature models for nozzle melt temperature when the band heater power was varied. The open loop response of the nozzle melt temperature was found to be second order overdamped with a dead time. Process control simulations were done with the PID, Dahlin, a second order modified Dahlin, and Smith predictor control algorithms in order to determine the optimum parameters for the controllers and to compare their responses. Experiments using the PID and the Dahlin controller were performed, with step changes in set points and disturbances introduced into the system.</description><creator>Ruscitti, Gino</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>The measurement and control of nozzle melt temperature in injection molding /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354g43b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t746p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rp768</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is the intention of this memoire to study the behaviour of the principal characters in the Chroniques du plateau Mont-Royal by Michel Tremblay. This will be done through an analysis of the relationship between them and certain archetypes suggested by the reading of relevant works by C. G. Jung and his followers, in particular those concerning the archetype of the mother. The absence of the father exerts a considerable influence on this behaviour, which, as a result, becomes non-conformist, abhorrent or neurotic. Homosexuality, transvestitism, alcoholism, sexual obsession and obesity are manifestations of the difficulty experienced by a people which has been separated from its traditional rural roots, and forced to adapt to a sterile city of concrete. It is only in the realisation of the nature of its malaise, that this part of the urban population can begin to settle in its new environment.</description><creator>Pitt, Peter V.</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Tremblay, Michel, 1942- Chroniques du Plateau Mont-Royal</subject><title>Le comportement marginal dans les Chroniques du Plateau Mont-Royal /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj139304p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rp768</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dt24h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Food frequency questionnaire and 24-hour recall methods were used to assess the general consumption of leafy vegetables and fruits within the Luo of northern Tanzania. The frequency questionnaire focused specifically on the consumption of Crotalaria brevidens, a leafy vegetable in a genus characterised by toxic pyrrolizidine alkaloids. Leafy vegetables were the most frequently consumed food group, contributing 23% of the total frequency scores. Crotalaria brevidens contributed 1.7% of the total frequency scores although some individuals consume significantly more. High consumption frequency of Crotalaria sp. is negatively associated with the consumption of fruits, fats and oils, vitamin A animal sources and consumption of animal products. Edible portions of Crotalaria sp. contain toxic pyrrolizidine alkaloids detected by thin layer chromatography. HPLC analysis showed that the plant contains high amounts of $ beta$-carotene. Quantification of the toxic alkaloids was not possible due to the low sensitivity of the methods used and low quantities present in the edible portions. Based on reported detection limits for the methods used a low and high estimated intake of toxic alkaloids was calculated and risk/benefit is assessed in relation to its nutrient content.</description><creator>Uiso, Febronia Christian</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Pyrrolizidines.</subject><subject>Crotalaria brevidens</subject><subject>Nutrition surveys -- Tanzania -- Mara Region.</subject><title>Determination of toxicological and nutritional factors of Crotalaria species used as indigenous vegetables</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k618s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dt24h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cn69m526t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>For over forty years, at the turn of this century, the white settlers of Southern Rhodesia devoted considerable energy to the discussion and the regulation of inter-racial sexual relations. The settlers' worries about maintaining their position in power were expressed, in part, in the periodic outbreaks of 'black peril' hysteria, a term which well-captures white fears about the threat that African men were thought to represent to white women. Although voluntary sexual encounters between white women and black men were prohibited from 1903 onwards, no such prohibition existed for white men in their relations with black women. The white women made several attempts to have legislation passed prohibiting such liasons, and failed largely because in doing so they were perceived to be challenging the authority of the white men. The regulation of interracial sexual intercourse thus served to reinforce the white male domination of Rhodesian society.</description><creator>Gombay, Katherine</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Interracial marriage -- Law and legislation -- Zimbabwe</subject><subject>Zimbabwe -- Social life and customs</subject><subject>Miscegenation -- Zimbabwe</subject><title>The black peril and miscegenation : the regulation of inter-racial sexual relations in southern Rhodesia, 1890-1933</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p149r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m526t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k3569557v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Home-ownership is a source of security, sense of belonging and saving accumulation. In the City of Montreal only a quarter of the population own their homes. Despite the fact that the majority of renters wish to become owners, only a small fraction can afford new products of the home-building industry. In this thesis the author proposes to the industry a strategy for cost reduction: uncompleted condominiums, that are the least finished dwelling units legally allowed for living. The proposed design is analyzed from the legal, social, technical and economic points of view. The research is founded on a review of the literature, a market survey and three simulations. It was found that the proposed product might be 26-29% less expensive, than investigated examples, and could be appreciated by childless households.</description><creator>Kowalska, Danuta</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Condominiums -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><subject>Housing -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><title>Uncompleted condominiums : a strategy for cost reduction in Montreal housing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vs00r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569557v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nc580n73g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In order to understand the implications of Frege's Grundlagen der Arithmetik, we must bear in mind that Frege saw logic as an overarching discipline, necessary for all scientific enquiry. This consideration allows us to make sense of his logicism, the idea that arithmetic is embedded in logic, and his platonism, the commitment to the mind-independent nature of arithmetic objects, such as numbers. In 1902, Russell generated a paradox from Basic Law (V), found in the first volume of Grundgesetze, which suggested that Frege's entire logical system was inconsistent. Recent work by Boolos and Wright, have fenced off the damage and shown that the bulk of Frege's work is consistent. I shall argue, however, that their proposed solutions prove unsatisfactory with respect to Frege's view of logic and especially his logicism.</description><creator>Friend, Michèle</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Frege, Gottlob, 1848-1925 -- Contributions in logic</subject><subject>Logic, Modern -- 20th century</subject><subject>Logic, Modern -- 18th century</subject><title>The possibility of Frege's logicism /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sw989.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580n73g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zs25x9637</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An experiment was conducted to investigate the effects of N formulation, application rate, and application time on corn yield and quality under Eastern Canadian conditions, to evaluate the hypothesis that application of N will increase corn grain yield and protein concentration without decreasing the total energy content. Three N formulations, each with the rates of 90, or 180 kg ha$ sp{-1}$ were applied at different times. The results indicated that the grain yield increased with increasing N fertilizer rate and with increasing numbers of N application times. N application significantly increased grain protein concentration, on both a per kernel and a dry matter basis, and protein yield. Such as, N application increased the averaged protein concentration, on a dry matter basis, of corn grain by about 8.40% as compared to the control. The protein concentration was not affected by the number of N application times before the plants were 90 cm high. Neither lipid nor non-structural carbohydrate concentration, on both a per kernel and a dry matter basis, were significantly affected by N application in most of the location-years. In addition Near infrared reflectance (NIR) was used to determine the lipid concentration in the aerial corn tissue at different growth stages. The correlation coefficients between the standard analytical method and the NIR method of lipid concentration were all above 0.95, and were significant at 0.01 level.</description><creator>Zhang, Feng, 1962-</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Corn -- Yields.</subject><subject>Corn -- Canada, Eastern.</subject><subject>Corn -- Fertilizers.</subject><subject>Nitrogen fertilizers.</subject><title>Effects of N formulation, application rate, and application time on corn yield and quality in eastern Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35t964r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25x9637</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h302c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Septoria blight of celery (Apium graveolens var. dulce), induced by Septoria apiicola Speg., is a destructive disease that requires fungicide applications for its management. A reliable method of inoculum production was established. Best sporulation was obtained on celery agar (CA) at a predicted optimum temperature of 22.4$ sp circ$C. A moderate inoculum density within a range of 17-35 conidia/cm$ sp2$ of leaf surface provided non-coalescing lesions necessary for rapid enumeration. Initial blight incidence thresholds of about 0.6 and 0.5% to time the first fungicide application were established based on the proportion of maximum plant weight equivalent to the cost of one fungicide application calculated plant weight and petiole number per plant, respectively, in the summers of 1990 and 1991. The IBI levels of 0 and 2% to time the first fungicide application provided non-significant results in terms of the final amount of blight and yield. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Mudita, I. Wayan</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Conidia.</subject><subject>Septoria apiicola</subject><subject>Celery -- Diseases and pests -- Control.</subject><title>Production of Conidia, selection of inoculum density, and timing the first fungicide application to manage Septoria blight of celery</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sd80w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h302c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289k24d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigates the characteristics and use of spawning sites by the bluehead wrasse Thalassoma bifasciatum in Barbados, and movements of wrasses from source reefs to proximate and isolate recipient reefs. Pair spawning rate increased with increasing projection height; group spawning rate increased with increasing proximity to the downcurrent reef edge. Daily group spawning rates, but not pair-spawning rates, were higher when daily current speeds were lower, suggesting that fertilisation rates in group spawns may be more sensitive to current speed than fertilisation rates in pair spawns. Migration rate to isolated reefs was 16% that to proximate reefs. Immigration rate to recipient reefs decreased with increasing distance from the source reef and increased with increasing population density on the source reef. Immigration rates to proximate reefs were phase, sex, and size-specific, and were strongly influenced by phase, sex, and size-specific differences in home range size of wrasses. Immigration to isolated reefs was also phase and sex-specific. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Southey, Katherine</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Thalassoma bifasciatum -- Barbados</subject><subject>Coral reef animals -- Barbados.</subject><subject>Wrasses -- Barbados -- Reproduction.</subject><title>Spawning and spatial movement in the bluehead wrasse (Thalassoma bifasciatum) at Barbados, West Indies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67js28q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289k24d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Renewable Resources</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gp49z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis attempts to put into practice certain precepts culled from leading semioticians in its focus on La camisa (1960), a work by the contemporary Spanish dramatist, Lauro Olmo (1922-). Semiotics has, thus, provided the theoretical framework from which to question the usual critical interpretations of this work: by concentrating on the theme of heroism the intention here is, therefore, to offer an alternative critical reading of the play's protagonists. The work of Patrice Pavis, Anne Ubersfeld and Keir Elam is examined in the first chapter and particular attention is paid to the interface between signs, communication and characterization on stage. This is the theoretical basis for the consideration in the next chapter of the heroism of the masculine protagonist, widely acknowledged in previous criticism. In the third chapter an innovative interpretation is offered, using the same theoretical base, of the heroism of the female protagonist, which posits a code of behaviour rarely commented upon before.</description><creator>Lauzière, Carole</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Olmo, Lauro -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>Estudio semiológico del personaje "heroico" : La Camisa de Lauro Olmo</title><language>spa</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d771j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gp49z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Hispanic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wh246t13r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Al-Si-Mg alloys containing 7% silicon are the most widely used aluminum foundry alloys owing to their good mechanical properties and excellent castability. Nevertheless, design engineers traditionally apply a design casting factor when designing cast components to ensure that proper strength will be obtained in spite of the recent emergence of techniques of control of the molten alloy quality on which depend, afterwards, the mechanical properties of the castings. In this study, the feasibility of using electrical conductivity to non-destructively predict secondary dendrite arm spacing was investigated on both as-cast and heat treated alloys. In the as-cast condition, conductivity decreases linearly with increasing DAS from 30 $ mu$m, while, below 30 $ mu$m, conductivity readings are influenced by alloying elements retained in solid solution due to the fast solid state cooling rates. Conductivity changes with DAS are more important when the silicon morphology is finer i.e. the alloy modified. After heat treatment, the DAS-conductivity relationships become linear as a result of the homogenisation of the aluminum matrix, but the slopes of the lines are small and the accuracy of DAS determination does not extend below 15 $ mu$m. Conductivity is also greatly influenced by the degree of precipitation achieved during artificial aging so that the determination of DAS by conductivity measurement is best used after quenching (T4 condition).</description><creator>Charbonnier, A. (Alain)</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Secondary dendrite ARM spacing determination in Al-Si casting alloys by conductivity measurements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526d580.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246t13r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26xz436</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis describes a compile-time loop scheduling scheme and a supplementary storage reduction scheme to generate code for computer architectures which exploit fine-grain parallelism, such as superscalar, VLIW, and superpipeline machines. In the first part we propose a new loop scheduling technique based upon the notion of dataflow software pipelining. We use Petri-net theory as the modeling framework, both for describing program behavior and for proving the feasibility of our approach. The time complexity of computing a schedule for an ideal machine model is examined under various program structures; a polynomial bound is established for the scheduling approach. We then integrate resource limitations into the model and construct a unified Petri-net model for schedule generation. Simulation results are conducted on a number of Livermore loops to verify the feasibility of the approach. In the second part we discuss the application of a program restructuring scheme, known as limited balancing, for storage reduction (GHW90a, GHW90b). With this technique, storage is systematically reduced across a loop body according to a balancing ratio. A guideline is derived to determine an appropriate ratio for maintaining a given pipeline utilization.</description><creator>Wong, Yue-Bong</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>A petri-net model for loop scheduling /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87pr447.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26xz436</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795887k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We tested the existence of an intracellular nucleoside transporter pool in sheep reticulocytes. The number of cell surface NBMPR binding sites in sheep reticulocytes is 5.1 $ pm$ 0.5 (S.D.) fmol/10$ sp{6}$ cells (n = 9), compared to 6.9 $ pm$ 0.4 (S.D.) fmol/10$ sp{6}$ cells (n = 9) for total binding. Resealed ghosts made from sheep reticulocytes show no fewer NBMPR binding sites than cell surface, but somewhat fewer than total binding sites. Furthermore, the number of NBMPR binding sites is the same in ghosts $ pm$ saponin, suggesting that after cell lysis and resealing, NBMPR is accessible in the intracellular matrix. The resealed ghosts also show increased permeability to pCMBS (an inhibitor of -SH groups on the cytoplasmic side of the nucleoside transporter in sheep reticulocytes). NBMPR binding sites exhibit a preferential loss compared to those on the cell surface during in vitro maturation of sheep reticulocytes. Species differences in NBMPR binding on cell surface and total were also examined.</description><creator>Liang, Lu</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Nucleoside transport in sheep reticulocytes : evidence for an intracellular transporter pool</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gt83v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795887k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892b95x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The miscibility of poly(vinyl pyrrolidone) PVP with copolymers of vinyl butyral and vinyl alcohol, containing 11% and 19% by weight of vinyl alcohol, has been investigated. To examine how the state of miscibility of these blends varies with the vinyl alcohol content of the copolymers, differential scanning calorimetry(DSC) and solid-state NMR methods were employed. PVP was found to form miscible blends with poly(vinyl butyral) PVB, containing 11wt% of vinyl alcohol, up to a weight ratio of 40/60(PVP/PVB11). At higher PVP loading, phase separated blends were obtained. In contrast, poly(vinyl butyral) containing 19wt% vinyl alcohol units was found to be miscible with PVP, over the entire composition range, with an estimated domain size of 2.5nm. Taken together, the results indicate the importance of the number of hydroxyl groups in achieving miscibility.</description><creator>Yusuf, Said Abdi</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>Miscibility study of poly(vinyl pyrrolidone)poly(vinyl butyral) blends</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wr382.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892b95x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ff3656181</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is about the design and implementation of a program transformation technique for parallelizing loops. The technique is based upon unimodular transformations that was originally proposed to parallelize imperative language loops. Such loops, in which arrays are the dominant data structure, often contain ample parallelism. Baherjee in (Ban90) proposed algorithms to parallelize double loops in imperative languages. His technique subsumes other results in the area of parallelizing double loops. We have implemented those algorithms in a program called U-Transformer. In recursively defined Monolithic Array Constructors in functional languages, which we refer to as MACs, a major problem that arises in their efficient parallel implementation is the overhead of scheduling and synchronizing the array operations. In a MAC, explicit evaluation order of the array elements is specified. If a compiler does not identify the data dependences and use this information to determine a safe order, then a conservative implementation has to rely on inefficient or expensive run-time support to ensure that an array element is defined before it is used. By extending the parallelizing algorithms in (Ban90), we developed algorithms that for a given two-dimensional MAC, explicitly introduce a safe parallel evaluation order. This provides a solution to the problem above. We also implemented these algorithms in a program called AC-Transformer. In both implementations, a one-step unimodular transformation is applied to produce an equivalent double loop in which the outer loop or the inner loop can run in parallel.</description><creator>Shiri-Varnaamkhaasti, Nematollaah</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>A design and implementation of unimodular transformations of loops /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r674g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff3656181</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6q182m326</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The treaty of Rome signed in 1957 creating the European Community establishes a common market and this market has to be done by 1993 upon the European Single Act of 1986. Airlines must be governed by the dispositions of the treaty. For a long time, this had not been affirmed, but the European Court of Justice said in 1974 that the general rules of the treaty apply to the air transport sector and precised this decision in the "Nouvelles Frontieres" case of 1986. Those decisions were a first step towards liberalization and the Council and the Commission of the Community followed the court and adopted measures to liberalize the sector in the first air transport package in December 1987. These decisions and measures are problematic because there are quiet about the external relations of EEC member states with third countries. The "Saeed" case of 1989 brings a solution, but the second air transport package of July 1990 still stays too quiet about it whereas it liberalises the air transport further. This should be resolved in the third package in 1993.</description><creator>Sonntag, Isabelle</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Transportation.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>La concurrence et le transport aerien en Europe /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613mz658.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182m326</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r4188</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA) is a highly glycosylated cell surface glycoprotein which has recently been demonstrated to behave as a Ca$ sp{++}$-independent intracellular adhesion molecule. In order to study the effects of carbohydrates on the intercellular adhesion function of CEA, we have transfected the functional cDNA of CEA into wild type and glycosylation mutant cells Lec1, Lec2, and Lec8. Aggregation assays of cells in suspension were performed with stable CEA transfectants of these cell lines and showed that all of the aberrant CEA glycoforms could still mediate adhesion, and that the specificity of adhesion of these glycoforms was not altered. Lec1 transfectants did, however, show an increased speed and final extent of aggregation, which suggests that, although carbohydrates can modulate the strength of adhesion, they do not determine the adhesion property; this property must therefore reside in the CEA protein backbone itself.</description><creator>Charbonneau, Julie</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>The role of carbohydrates in the intercellular adhesion mediated by carcinoembryonic antigen using Cho mutant cell lines /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526d598.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r4188</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sk625</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The enhancement of portal images using digital image processing techniques is discussed. The previously developed techniques of adaptive histogram equalization, interpolated adaptive histogram equalization, Gordon's algorithm, and modified Gordon's algorithm, are applied to digitized double-exposure portal films and the resulting images analysed. These techniques were found to be limited in their ability to provide good local contrast enhancement without excess noise amplification or long processing times. Two new techniques are proposed. The first, selective histogram equalization, produces excellent local contrast enhancement and an increase in intensity of details within the field region while minimizing noise amplification and processing time. An accompanying automatic segmentation algorithm is also discussed. The second, histogram shifting, enhances the edge detail in the image and can display the contours of objects in both the field region and surrounding region with the same intensity. Enhanced portal images display fine details better, simplifying the task of beam verification.</description><creator>Crooks, Ian</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>PC-based contrast enhancement of portal films</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q750j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sk625</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42n914w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Determining optimum building orientation for naturally ventilated buildings is an important concept. Obtaining the optimum orientation will determine the success of the performance of a naturally ventilated building. This project deals with obtaining the preferred building orientation for 10 regional weather stations across the province of Ontario. Different methods were utilized to obtain the preferred building orientation: the average ventilation rate method, the percentage of ventilation rates above and below the minimum summer ventilation rates, and the consecutive hours method, ie. the number of weather events that are below the minimum summer design ventilation rate for a specific building configuration. The analysis involves six building orientations (0$ sp circ$, 30$ sp circ$, 60$ sp circ$, 90$ sp circ$, 120$ sp circ$, and 150$ sp circ$) with respect to North, and exterior temperatures greater than or equal to 20$ sp circ$C, 25$ sp circ$C, or 30$ sp circ$C. Optimizing building orientation, to minimize the number of weather events where the ventilation rates are below the summer design ventilation rate is the general goal of this research work. A statistical analysis was carried out based on the results obtained from the data for the frequency of ventilation rates versus the ventilation rates below the summer design ventilation rate, for all 10 Ontario weather stations, for temperatures greater than or equal to 20$ sp circ$C, and all six building orientations. The output of the statistical analysis showed that for the above mentioned temperature range, that there is a relationship between the ventilation rates below the design summer ventilation rate and building orientation.</description><creator>Zemanchik, Normand Joseph</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Ventilation</subject><subject>Architecture and climate.</subject><title>Preferred building orientation for naturally ventilated buildings</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78td25d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42n914w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hg673</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:05:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this work, the carbothermal reduction of Al$ sb2$O$ sb3$ to AlN was studied. Several kinds of aluminum oxides including $ alpha$-Al$ sb2$O$ sb3$, $ gamma$-Al$ sb2$O$ sb3$, $ theta$-Al$ sb2$O$ sb3$ and boehmite (AlOOH) were examined in order to observe the differences in reaction behaviour and powder characteristics obtained from each type of precursor. Cane sugar (sucrose) and carbon black were used as carbon sources. Reaction conditions studied were carbon to alumina ratio, temperature and reaction time. Sucrose resulted in a close-to-stoichiometric ratio of Al$ sb2$O$ sb3$:C (1:3.2) achieving full conversion to AlN and produced a regular powder morphology, whilst carbon black required higher ratio ($&gt;$1:4) to reach full conversion with agglomeration of the AlN powder. The optimal reaction temperature was 1600$ sp circ$C with the reaction time being dependent on the Al$ sb2$O$ sb3$ source. The results of the thermodynamic study for the Al-N-O-C system suggest a solid-state reaction process which is consistent with the experimental observations. Moreover, flowing N$ sb2$ gas flushes out the product CO gas and thus forces the equilibrium in favour of AlN formation. Reaction mechanisms are proposed for the two forms of carbon precursor.</description><creator>Baik, Youngmin</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Carbothermal synthesis of aluminum nitride using sucrose</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d535k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hg673</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):23825</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>