<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:59:58Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2600" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:736666846</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD) is emerging as an integral part of engineering design and analysis. Traditionally, idealizations have been made to categorize flows as being either incompressible or compressible, with their respective numerical treatments being completely different. Incompressible flow solvers are completely incapable of capturing compressible flow phenomena, while compressible flow solvers are very inefficient in the limit of low compressibility. For situations in which there are regions of incompressible and compressible flows, or when there is no a priori knowledge of the level of compressibility, a general numerical treatment is no longer obvious. The method proposed in this thesis has been formulated for efficient computation of mixed incompressible/compressible flows and is based on the SIMPLE algorithm of S. V. Patankar. It is capable of correctly modeling the elliptic/hyperbolic nature of the pressure perturbations and is well suited for calculating a wide range of engineering applications such as turbomachinery, aerodynamics, etc. This thesis will describe the details of the compressible extension of the SIMPLE algorithm and provide numerical examples which demonstrate the ability of the solver to efficiently resolve mixed incompressible/compressible flows.</description><creator>Kho, Cedric.</creator><contributor>Hedberg, Peter (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><title>A unified formulation for mixed incompressible/compressible flows /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k0271.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/736666846</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3484zj87r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effect of pulp potential on the recovery of copper, lead, zinc and iron from the ore of Kidd Creek Mines (Timmins, Ontario) was examined. Air and nitrogen as flotation gases were compared for their effect on the metallurgical response (recovery and the separation efficiency of Cu/Zn and Cu/Fe). The extraction of metal cations from the mineral surface in-situ by EDTA at varying pulp potentials and with various reagent schemes was performed, and the differences in extraction from concentrates and tailings was examined. The effect of aeration on the extraction of cations Cu, Pb, Zn and Fe was analysed as well as its effect on dissolved oxygen (Dynamic Dissolved Oxygen). Plant surveys of pulp potential, pH and extraction by EDTA are compared to laboratory values. The optimum pulp potential for the recovery of copper with no collector addition was -50 mV (vs Ag/AgCl). Collector increased the range of pulp potential where maximum copper recovery could be achieved. The maximum separation efficiency between copper/zinc and copper/iron was approximately -230mV and -50mV, respectively. Copper was not extracted by EDTA, possibly due to its incorporation in the lattice of pyrite and sphalerite. The extraction of iron, zinc, and lead from the feed decreased with increased aeration, and was not strongly affected by the addition of SO2, lime or collector. The factors Em and Es (mg metal per gram of solid and mg of metal per gram of metal, respectively) were developed to analyse the data obtained. The differences in the extraction of iron between tails and concentrates was strongly related to the separation efficiency. Extractions at specific pulp potentials were found to be similar between the plant and laboratory.</description><creator>Kant, Claudia.</creator><contributor>Finch, J. A. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>The effect of pulp potential and surface products on copper mineral flotation /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05ff03f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zj87r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb397b41j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Self-cycling fermentation (SCF) is a technique in which sequential batch fermentations are performed using a computerized feedback control scheme. In this method, half of the reactor volume is periodically removed and replaced by fresh medium. This results in very stable and repeatable growth cycles and synchronized cell cultures. In this work, two segregated microbial population balance models are developed and used to simulate SCF. Cell age and cell mass distribution models are both used to study the behavior of microorganisms in various systems. One example is the study of autonomous oscillations and partial synchronization in cultures of Saccharomyces cerevisiae. However, when the cell age and cell mass models are compared for the modeling of cell synchrony in SCF, two contrasting population profiles arise from the simulations. The SCF technique with its existing data can be used as a powerful tool to test and validate models of microbial systems. When used to simulate SCF, the cell age model was able to predict cell synchrony, however, the cell number profile obtained was remarkably different than that observed in experiments. The cell mass model, as proposed by Eakman et al. was able to capture the dissolved oxygen concentration, the limiting substrate concentration, and the biomass concentration, but was not able to describe the cell number profile or the feature of cell synchrony. By introducing a feedback mechanism between the critical division mass and the limiting substrate, cell synchrony was achieved and the experimental cell profile was captured.</description><creator>Godin, François.</creator><contributor>Cooper, D. G. (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Rey, A. D. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Theory and simulation of self-cycling fermentation : a population balance approach</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nk356.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397b41j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr172040n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Using a perceptual approach to image analysis, the process encompassing image capture to perceptual feature extraction is modeled as a digital communications system. Within this novel approach, image features become information carrying symbols which are transmitted by the scene to the observer through a band-limited channel. The principal effect of the band-limited channel is to cause severe inter-symbol interference in image regions where feature density cannot be resolved by the modeled sensor. The output of the band-limited channel is then fed into an image analyzer whose purpose is naturally to reliably recover as much of the originally transmitted information as possible. Using this qualitative model as a guiding framework, a novel sparse perceptual coding method is developed based on Spatial Frequency Analysis using Wavelet Packets. The goal is to extract the recoverable subset of symbols or image features originally transmitted from the scene. Each visual symbol or feature is quantitatively modeled using simple complex polynomials. In turn these elementary polynomials can be decomposed into both shape and positional terms. The parameters of the elementary polynomials are estimated using Harmonic Wavelets Packets. This Spatial Frequency analysis technique borrows equally from both the Fourier and Wavelet domains. The obtained parameters can the be used to select a representative feature set which sparsely describes image data.</description><creator>Gauthier, François, 1955-</creator><contributor>Morgera, Salvadore (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Sparse image coding using wavelet packets</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698966s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr172040n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795984z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The growing complexity and inherent risks associated with the operation of power transmission and distribution systems have caused personnel training to become a priority for a growing number of electrical utilities. Training simulators offer an interesting means for helping the personnel of those enterprises to learn their work. Simulation-based training has the advantage of being safe for both personnel and equipment, while ensuring service continuity. It also offers the trainee, the opportunity to be exposed to various scenarios and to exceptional conditions, which either happen rarely or are hazardous to reproduce. This thesis presents a review of virtual reality (VR) technologies and applications and describes the design and implementation of a VR based operator training simulator prototype developed for a local power utility. The architecture of this client-server system is explained in addition to the interaction metaphors the prototype offers. The training simulator is built as a distributed network system comprised of heterogeneous computer platforms and integrates various virtual reality technologies. A visual simulation host renders the three-dimensional world and manages interactions between the user and the VR application. The system also supports generation and super-imposition of sounds typically found in the substation environment such as ambient background noise, sound events related to user actions and also vocal message output used for didactic purposes. The system is augmented with speech-recognition capabilities that free the user from cumbersome manipulations and make its use more natural. ESOPE-VR automatically generates a representation of a typical power utility substation from the single-line diagram representing it. The virtual environment in which the user navigates and can simulate his daily work, is comprised of a yard with equipment such as transformers, disconnect switches and circuit breakers. A control room with a mock-up of a real control panel activating the equipment is also implemented.</description><creator>Garant, Etienne.</creator><contributor>Malowant, Alfred (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>A virtual reality training system for substation operators /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f5753.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795984z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mp52m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis proposes a morphological complexity index for use in classifying orebodies. Formulated and tailored for application on underground steep clipping narrow base metal orebodies from Inco Limited's Manitoba Division, the complexity index was proved transferable to the base metal deposits of Inco Limited's Ontario Division. Thus it appears that the index could be applied to various styles of mineralization and orebody morphology. The complexity classification was designed to aid in geologic control and subsequently improve mining method performance. Motivated by an industry wide move from selective mining to bulk mining, to increase productivity and improve safety. It is intended that development and application of an orebody complexity index will increase the understanding of geology and prevent the sacrifice of selectivity, minimizing dilution and ore loss. With the advent of automation, simplification in mining is necessary and thus more intelligent design and control vital. This thesis offers one means by which MDPPC (Mine Design, Planning and Production Control) could be further integrated with geological understanding to achieve such an end. The thesis provides explanation of how such a complexity index can be used to understand mining method performance and be used for more successful mine design.</description><creator>Francis, Helen.</creator><contributor>Scoble, Malcolm J. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Orebody complexity in geological control over selective mining</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qc00v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mp52m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52jb14b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>High quality aluminum castings must contain a minimum of defects. Currently, melt treatments, including degassing and liquid metal filtering, are used to this end. Reducing hydrogen pick-up and the formation of inclusions is a more efficient way of dealing with defect control, however, the configuration of most current casting processes make prevention difficult. This thesis proposes a new process which involves submerging a mold in the molten metal. Process improvements include the elimination of liquid metal pouring and transferring, the reduction of melt temperatures and the availability of hot liquid to feed shrinkage. A prototype device was constructed using high temperature heat pipes to provide cooling. Excellent mold filling was attainable after optimizing the preheat temperature, the melt temperature and the submerging velocity of the mold. The process also provided directional solidification with a flat solid/liquid interface. After considering the characteristics of the prototype, an improved device is proposed.</description><creator>Ledermann, Thomas H.</creator><contributor>Mucciardi, Frank (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Gruzleski, J. E. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Submerged mold casting using heat pipes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h397x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52jb14b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6395w958s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:23:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The reversed cyclic loading test of an "as-built" bridge column with details typical of those designed and built (Griezic, 1996) in the Montreal area in the 1960's is reviewed. This test emphasized the inadequate design and detailing used at that time and showed how poorly lap-spliced dowels perform under reversed cyclic loading. A retrofitting technique (Griezic, 1996) that employs an added footing block, which moves the location of expected plastic hinging to the top of the lap splice and adds confinement to the lower portion of the lap splice region, and adds an infilled steel shell to confine the column, is also reviewed. An alternative retrofit technique suitable for corrosive environments is developed and tested under reversed cyclic loading. This retrofit uses an added footing block and a fibre-reinforced, high performance concrete sleeve containing steel hoops in order to confine the column. Predictions are made on the responses of each retrofit technique, and these are compared to the experimental results. The response of the alternative retrofit technique is analysed and its performance compared to the "as-built" specimen and the column that was retrofitted with an infilled steel jacket. The alternative retrofit specimen increased the strength of the "as-built" column by 53%, compared to an increase of 74% provided by the infilled steel shell retrofit. The alternative retrofit specimen increased the displacement ductility of the "as-built" column from 3.3 to 10.0, compared to 8.3 achieved by the infilled steel shell retrofit. This retrofit technique dissipated almost as much energy as the specimen with the infilled steel jacket retroprofit, and both retroprofit techniques substantially increased the stiffness of the "as-built" column.</description><creator>Dunwoodie, David.</creator><contributor>Mitchell, Denis (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><subject>Applied Mechanics.</subject><title>Seismic retrofit of bridge columns using fibre-reinforced concrete</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w457b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w958s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816p65x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In order to deal with the negative impacts associated with disposal of used oils by thermal remediation, a study of the material under combustion-like conditions was undertaken. Two used motor oils were subjected to slow heating using a Thermogravimetric Analyzer coupled with a Fourier Transform Infrared Spectrometer. Based on the results obtained, mechanisms of the general transformation process the oil undergoes and the evolution of the solid particles were proposed. The presence of Polycyclic Aromatic Hydrocarbons (PAHs), considered hazardous, was observed and individual PAHs were identified. The results show that initial oxygen content in the oil plays a significant role in the thermal remediation process, primarily leading to smaller, more compact final residues. This may have significant implications In terms of leachability of toxic metals. The insight gained here can be utilized in further studies to understand and then possibly control, the process in practical combustion systems.</description><creator>Di Lalla, Sergio.</creator><contributor>Kozinski, J. A. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Low temperature oxidation of used lubricating oil</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zz77m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816p65x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z7090031</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the processing of steels, various types of alloy compositions and heat treatments have been used to improve strength and ductility. Unfortunately, these methods are usually accompanied by a decrease in formability. It has been well recognized that the presence of retained austenite, in microstructures which include ferrite and bainite, can significantly strengthen the steel and improve ductility by transforming to martensite under an applied stress or strain. This is the basic principal behind the TRIP (transformation-induced plasticity) effect. In this work, the effects of thermomechanical processing (TMP) and chemical composition on the structure and properties of C-Si-Mn TRIP steels were investigated. It was found that the addition of Nb to these steels not only increases the volume fraction of retained austenite, but also improves the total elongation and tensile properties. It was also revealed that the combination of strength and ductility is further optimised by varying the C content in the steel. For C-Si-Mn Nb-bearing TRIP steels, the bainite transformation conditions are the critical parameters in dictating the final mechanical properties. The effects of retained austenite characteristics on the mechanical properties were examined. Although the retained austenite volume fraction is indeed a key factor in controlling the final properties, there are other parameters that must be considered, such as the morphology, particle size, solute enrichment and the mechanical stability of the retained austentite. In this work, the approach involved a systematic investigation of the effects of TMP parameters on the state of the retained austenite characteristics and finally, an evaluation of the final mechanical properties. It was revealed that, for a given ferrite/bainite structure, the tensile strength and total elongation are controlled by the volume fraction and the mechanical stability of the retained austenite. Increasing the mechanical stability of retained austenite leads to transformation at higher strains. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Di Chiro, Andrew.</creator><contributor>Yue, Steve (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Processing and properties of C-Si-Mn trip steels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s1618379.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z7090031</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:73666685g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Oral administration of encapsulated proteins for the treatment of metabolic enzyme disorders has received recut attention. In this study alginate was used a the immobilization matrix because of its ease of use and mild formulation conditions. In the treatment of enzyme disorders, proteins encapsulated in alginate gels may be deactivated by proteolytic enzymes such as chymotrypsin, which are present in gastric fluids. To reduce the permeability to chymotrypsin (MW 21,600), the alginate beads were coated with polycationic membranes. Chitosan, poly-L-lysine, and Poly(methylene co-guanidine) membranes were evaluated for their capacity to exclude alpha-chymotrypsin and other proteases from alginate beads. When alginate beads were exposed to 0.5% chymotrypsin for 10 min, 98% activity of the encapsulated urease was lost due to deactivation. Polymer coating of the alginate beads resulted in higher chymotrypsin exclusion. Chitosan provided approximately 50% activity retention after chymotrypsin exposure. A combination of low and high molecular weight chitosans offered 30% activity retention, while urease within poly-L-lysine membranes only had 12% residual activity. Poly(methylene co-guanidine) membranes did not provide any protection from chymotrypsin. Lyophilization causes the beads to shrink and results in a more compact structure and a reduced pore size. After rehydration the beads do not swell to their original diameter, effectively reducing the pore size. After exposure to chymotrypsin, the activity retention of the encapsulated urease for uncoated beads was 71%, and 89% for chitosan coated beads. Gastric fluids contain many proteases that can affect the activity of encapsulated proteins. The effects of two other proteases trypsin and proteinase K in addition to chymotrypsin, were evaluated. Chitosan coated alginate beads were exposed to trypsin and the remits were similar to those obtained from chymotrypsin. The exposure of chitosan, coated beads to the slightly larger molecular weight proteinase K resulted in a higher level of retained activity. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>DeGroot, Andreas R.</creator><contributor>Neufeld, Ronald J. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Encapsulation of urease in alginate beads and protection from alpha-chymotrypsin with chitosan membrane</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w6634587x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666685g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827d781</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Electrokinetic remediation is an in-situ technique in which a direct current is applied across a water-saturated contaminated soil. As a result, metal ions are transported through the soil from the anode toward the cathode by electromigration, electroosmosis and diffusion. Electrokinetic remediation experiments were performed with Bentonite clay contaminated with Pb and/or Zn under a constant current. The clay bed was cylindrical with a diameter of 5 cm and a length of 15 cm. The electroosmotic flowrate decreased with time due to a significant increase in the concentration of H+ ions in the bed. Without cathode rinsing the clay bed cracked and the voltage increased. Rinsing the cathode prevented cracking and decreased the voltage applied across the bed. The acid front generated at the anode advanced across the clay bed at a speed of approximately 1.4 mm/hr. When there was no rinsing, most of the metals precipitated in the cathode region. With rinsing, the metals which reached the cathode compartment were removed by the effluent at constant rates over four days. For clay contaminated with Zn, the rate of removal was 15 mg/hr; for clay contaminated with Pb, the rate of removal was 54 mg/hr. For clays with single contaminants and cathode rinsing, the energy consumption was approximately 1.3 x 106 kJ/m3 of clean soil for zinc removal and 1.8 x 106 kJ/m3 for lead removal. For clays contaminated with both metals, the rates of removal were 11 mg/hr for Zn and 26 mg/hr for Pb. After four days, 23% of Pb and 67% of Zn was removed. The efficiency of current utilization was 32% for removal of Zn alone and 40% for removal of Pb alone. For removal of mixed contaminants the efficiency was 40%. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Chen, Huan, 1971 Mar. 8-</creator><contributor>Weber, M. E. (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Mujumdar, A. S. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Environmental.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Electrokinetic removal of zinc and lead from saturated clay</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752j96m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827d781</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65v9896</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis reports work not only on the numerics behind, but also the implementation of real-time redundancy-resolution schemes on a real robot. Furthermore, the robot that was chosen as the experimental platform is, isotropic. Redundant robots have more degrees of freedom than needed to perform a class of tasks. A new performance index is proposed in the thesis, that is quadratic in the joint variables and its weighting function has units of frequency. It is shown how this performance index can produce cyclic trajectories in a simple manner, thereby eliminating the undesired drift of the joint angles upon tracking a closed Cartesian trajectory. Isotropic robots can be postured in such a way that the condition number of their Jacobian matrices can attain a minimum value of unity. It is shown in the thesis that this feature is closely related to the performance of the robot. It appears that trajectories that are close to the set of isotropic postures are performed with smaller errors than trajectories lying far from that set. The experiments reported here were conducted on the McGill-IRIS C3 Arm, an isotropic, four-revolute redundant manipulator, used to position the operation point of its end link. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Arenson, Noga.</creator><contributor>Angeles, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Real-time redundancy-resolution schemes for robotic manipulators</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418q32s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65v9896</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:th83m1703</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In stereoscopic images, the behavior of a curve in space is related to the appearance of the curve in the left and right image planes. Formally, this relationship is governed by the projective geometry induced by the stereo camera configuration and by the differential structure of the curve in the scene. In this thesis, I propose that the correspondence problem---matching corresponding points in the image planes---can be solved by relating the differential structure in the left and right image planes to the geometry of curves in space. Specifically, the compatibility between two pairs of corresponding points and tangents at those points is related to the local approximation of a space curve using an osculating helix. To guarantee robustness against small changes in the camera parameters, I introduce the principle of differential invariance and show how this principle resolves a natural ambiguity in selecting the osculating helix. A relaxation labeling network demonstrates that the compatibilities can be used to infer the appropriate correspondences in a scene. Finally, parallels between the proposed solution and binocular processes in primate vision are discussed.</description><creator>Alibhai, Shamez.</creator><contributor>Zucker, Steven W. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Curves, compatibility and correspondence : a differential-geometric approach to the stereo correspondence problem</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731618z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m1703</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zw68h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents a new method for the prioritization of maintenance and repair (M&amp;R) activities related to engineering facilities. Only M&amp;R that can be programmed into a two to three years budgeting cycle are considered in the ranking procedure. Tasks that are of an emergency nature and that must be accomplished immediately are beyond the scope of this thesis. The methodology is intended to assist in a rational allocation of M&amp;R funds by generating a priority list of tasks based on component importances and conditions. The premise is that the most important component in the worst condition is given the highest priority. The methodology is then applied to embankment dams, where M&amp;R activities are performed to prevent (1) the failure of the dam (prevention system) and (2) to maintain the ability to detect the presence or absence of undesirable condition (detection system). Both systems are treated separately, and two independent lists of prioritized activities result from the ranking procedure. The reliability of the monitoring system in detecting undesirable conditions is used to reassess the relative importance of the components of the prevention system. Finally, the proposed methodology is applied to two embankment dams, the first one (TA-24) is operated by Hydro-Quebec, and the second one (Lewisville) by the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers.</description><creator>Abdo, Fady.</creator><contributor>Chouinard, Luc E. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><subject>Engineering, Industrial.</subject><title>Decision analysis for the prioritization of maintenance and repair activities on engineering facilities</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xk75k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zw68h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d56zz78w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Statistics corroborate the substantial and deleterious impact of substance abuse to both client and client systems. Social workers are regularly exposed to clients who are directly or indirectly affected by substance abuse. A random survey of social workers working with Anglophone and Allophone populations on the island of Montreal was conducted to evaluate the workers perceived ability to recognize and respond to the needs of this client group. Links were drawn to the various ways in which social workers developed their knowledge about addiction and to the worker's formal social work education. The study demonstrates the inadequacy of the formal social work program to address the problem of substance abuse. The implications for schools of social work and the need to develop core curriculum as well as specializations in substance abuse are presented.</description><creator>Lannaman, Christine F.</creator><contributor>Rowe, B. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Social work with alcoholics -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Social work with drug addicts -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Social work education -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Social workers -- Québec (Province) -- Attitudes.</subject><title>The link between social work education and the social worker's reported ability to respond to the needs of anglophone and allophone clients directly or indirectly affected by substance abuse /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429c46r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zz78w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gn13p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Throughout history the concept of a "mall" has manifested itself in various forms. Malls provided once and continue to provide an opportunity for ostentation and observation in a constructed environment. Ranelagh Gardens is an example of such an environment. It is an Eighteenth Century London pleasure garden devoted exclusively to the acts of exhibiting one's self and beholding others, a sort of celebratory act of mutual affirmation. These gardens were frequented by various elements of London society, from royalty to the middle class. All sorts of boundaries were further blurred through the ritual of the masquerade, which flourished at Ranelagh. After examining the various devices employed to that end, I will look into the parallels of such interaction in our increasingly virtual society.</description><creator>Yurchuk, Dorian.</creator><contributor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Masquerades -- England -- London.</subject><subject>Ranelagh Gardens (London, England)</subject><title>Ranelagh gardens and the recombinatory Utopia of Masquerade</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vj94p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gn13p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn301354g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Canada's first Parliament Buildings, built in 1859--65 and destroyed by fire in 1916, were the nation's most prominent symbol of national identity and its most celebrated public space. Built into its fabric was an exclusively masculine definition of public persons, one which, at the end of the nineteenth century, women challenged in both subtle and overt ways. This research examines the design of the Parliament Buildings as a multi-faceted building type, a complex mix of domestic, office and legislative design where both public and "private" spaces intersected. It overlays official documentation of the buildings with a rich variety of sources---archival photographs, newspaper articles and women's columns, letters, journals---to show how women transgressed the architectural prescription which placed them on the political periphery in the Ladies' Gallery, as observers and objects of observation. These sources show that, in fact, women altered and created spaces and initiated influential networks of their own both in and outside of the Parliament Buildings. By illuminating the primacy of the "political hostess," this research argues that women were not relegated to the sidelines, but appropriated---and practiced politics from within---the most privileged of spaces. This methodology, by examining the interior organization and actual use of the Parliament Buildings, opens new possibilities for the study of legislative buildings and public buildings in general as dynamic systems of relationships rather than uni-dimensional building types. By showing how women challenged the spatial demarcations of gender and power and transformed the meanings associated with parliamentary and public spaces not initially intended for their use, we can draw a picture of the larger role women in Canada played as "public architects."</description><creator>Reid, Vanessa.</creator><contributor>Adams, Annmarie (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Women in public life -- Canada -- History -- 19th century.</subject><subject>Architecture and women -- Canada -- History -- 19th century.</subject><subject>Parliament Buildings (Ottawa, Ont.) -- History.</subject><title>Ladies in the House : gender, space and the parlours of Parliament in late-nineteenth-century Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn301355r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301354g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cw275</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The informal sector plays a very important role in developing countries. It acts as a stabilizer, and within this the urban poor find the necessary strategies for their survival. Home based commercial activities are a part of these strategies. They provide households with an additional income and open opportunities for those who can not qualify for jobs within the "formal" workforce. The extraordinary abundance and variety of home based commercial activities are recorded in the case study. The study registers all the home based commercial activities existing in an informal settlement within the city of Guadalajara, Mexico. Emphasis is placed on the precise location of the businesses, and an analysis of its physical attributes. The different forms of adapting parts of the dwellings to serve as businesses are also observed. Home based enterprises promote a rich mixture of activities in poor communities. The findings suggest that this mixed use of the land creates a better environment in informal settlements, as opposed to the division of activities implemented in official housing projects. Researchers and developers should therefore consider home based commercial activities as tools of development.</description><creator>Medina, Jose Antonio.</creator><contributor>Bhatt, Vikram (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Home-based businesses -- Mexico -- Guadalahara.</subject><title>Home based commerce in informal settlements : a case study in Guadalajara</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dc12p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cw275</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z903206r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Comedy and tragedy originated in Greece, from singing and dancing. By definition, dramatic art is an imitation of action. This artistic form was born during the passage from the archaic world to the democratic and classical Greece, and it is the ancestor and first form of philosophy. This birth was also shown in aesthetic ways by the historic and astonishing encounter of Apollo, the visionary god, the ultimate achiever in painting, sculpture and poetry, and Dionysos, the god of ecstasy, music and delirious action. The whole architecture of the ancient theatre, from antiquity to Renaissance, affords all the necessary support for the "action" and "voice" of the players themselves. The theatre was built as a musical instrument, on an acoustical geometry and the plan of heavens. This lasted until the advent of the "scenographic theatre", during the Renaissance, built on the optic geometry of scientific perspective. This led to the triumph of visual illusion and of Deus ex machina in the baroque theatre, to the disadvantage, of actors and poets. Through this musical dimension of drama that will be carried, the study of the "theatrical space" of architecture. Mainly, it is from the drama of Dionysos, which in terms of aesthetics shows us the musical origin of the Greek Theatre, and from the drama of Prospero, which shows us the place of music in Shakespearian Theatrum Mundi , that will be showed, finally, the architecture of the Globe Theatre which as the last representative of this classical idea and conception of the theatre, founded on the action of characters and the musicality of poetic language. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Lévesque, Pierre, 1967-</creator><contributor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Theaters.</subject><title>Le théâtre de l'architecte et la mesure festive des lieux /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547t653.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903206r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5999n546w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is a radical reinterpretation of the Hannover Merzbau ( Cathedral of Erotic Misery) by Kurt Schwitters. It proposes and demonstrates that two of Schwitters' own photographs of the work should not be viewed as being descriptions of a "constructed" Merzbau, but rather understood as complex constructions that generate a critical questioning of the modern site of perception. Through an exploration of language (as understood within Giambattista Vico's New Science) the photographs come to deconstruct themselves within a context of simultaneous readings; allowing both the "secret" space of the modern Merzbau, and the sacred place of the Cathedral to exist simultaneously.</description><creator>Labossière, Donald F.</creator><contributor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Schwitters, Kurt, 1887-1948. Merzbau.</subject><title>Between worlds : a search for secrets within the Cathedral of erotic misery</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956j089.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n546w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s4594</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis attempts a Buddhist interpretation, commentary and reflection on a lecture by Louis I. Kahn (1901--1974) at Pratt Institute, entitled "1973: Brooklyn, New York." This lecture provides the framework and point of departure for a discussion of Kahn's philosophy. With the aid of Buddhist thought, this investigation argues that the ethical function of architecture begins with the effort of the architect to know his or her self. The juxtaposition of Buddhist philosophy and Kahn's lecture on architecture also seeks to present a way in which Buddhist thought might engage and illuminate the issues of ethical action in architecture. In doing so, the possible contributions of Buddhist thought to contemporary architectural discourse may present themselves.</description><creator>Ho, Jeffrey Kiat.</creator><contributor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Architecture -- Philosophy.</subject><subject>Kahn, Louis I., 1901-1974.</subject><title>The philosophy of Louis I. Kahn and the ethical function of architecture /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bh27p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s4594</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10ws53c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>No substantial studies, at least to my knowledge, have yet been dedicated either to Milton's or to Shelley's extensive poetic use of the grotesque. This omission surprises me, especially given the voluminous critical attention both authors receive. Neither Milton nor Shelley's grotesquerie can be viewed as the basis of artistic method or artistic achievement as we might with, say, Rabelais, or Poe, or even Kafka. And neither Milton nor Shelley is self-consciously an artist of "the grotesque." In fact, Milton, from his seventeenth century perspective, would scarcely have regarded the term as being applicable to literary criticism at all. And as a late Romantic, Shelley defined himself rather as a poet of the imagination. Nonetheless I will show that both artists avail themselves of a grotesque aesthetic to achieve some of their most powerful and provocative poetry: we may here consider, for instance, Milton's memorable descriptions of the incongruities of Hell and the deformities of its fallen denizens in Paradise Lost, or Shelley's Gothic touches and his perplexing distortion of conventional linguistic and dramatic form in Prometheus Unbound. Aside from general considerations of the grotesque in these texts, I will especially focus on how Milton's and Shelley's uses of the grotesque mode provide us with unique, and often fascinating vantage points from which to appreciate their respective political concerns and revolutionary interests. While I expect this critical approach will elucidate Milton and Shelley in their own separate artistic and political spheres, I am especially interested to compare and contrast the poets, to show how the quite different uses made of the grotesque in Prometheus Unbound and Paradise Lost reflect the various ways in which Shelley responds to Milton in his role as a revolutionary forefather.</description><creator>White, Michael, 1971-</creator><contributor>Burris, Kenneth (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Prometheus unbound.</subject><subject>Grotesque in literature.</subject><subject>Milton, John, 1608-1674. Paradise lost.</subject><title>The relationship between the grotesque and revolutionary thought in Milton's Paradise lost and Shelley's Prometheus unbound /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365740r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10ws53c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k06989672</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The influence technology has on human subjectivity has been the occupation of philosophy for some time. Recent technological advance has re-motivated the speculation on subjectivity where a bodily dimension of subjectivity becomes necessary to understand the complexities of subjectivity as it is formulated in contemporary society. In this thesis subjectivity has been schematized according to its states relative to the body to demonstrate how technology and its mythologies influences and define individual subjectivity and the larger constructive factors that shape that subjectivity. Various examples are used to show the contemporary postmodern response to technological subjective imposition as subjectivity both negotiates and responds to the four orders of subjectivity: dormant, active, material, and terminal. As shall be demonstrated, each subjective form is constituted by a series of technologies and mythologies that form a reciprocal and continuous pattern illustrated by individual, cultural, bodily, and communicative models.</description><creator>Wauters, Brennan Murray.</creator><contributor>Finlay, Marike (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Body, Human (Philosophy)</subject><subject>Subjectivity.</subject><subject>Technology -- Social aspects.</subject><title>Four orders of human subjectivity as determined by body technique, technology, and objectification</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870z142.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k06989672</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967589x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:24:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In four pieces selected from the late Baroque repertoire, the "Allemanda" from Corelli's Sonata for Violin and Continuo, Opus 5, No. 8, the "Allemande" from Bach's Clavierubung, Partita, No. 1, the chorus, "Thy Right Hand, Oh Lord" from Handel's Israel in Egypt, and the aria duetto, "Mein Freund ist Mein" from Cantata No. 140, Wachet Auf, by Bach, harmonic, melodic and motivic parameters are analysed and graphed so that their integration in each work is readily observable. Then, in an attempt to establish more general formal models similar to those developed by Arnold Schoenberg, Erwin Ratz, and William E. Caplin for the classical style, recurring patterns of integration are noted. Of special significance is the prominence of acceleration processes in each piece and their diversity, both in the parameters involved, as well as in the structural levels on which these processes operate.</description><creator>Von Holtzendorff, Peter.</creator><contributor>Alphonce, Bo (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Music -- 18th century -- Analysis, appreciation.</subject><title>A parametric integration model for the analysis of late Baroque music : a tentative approach</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311r54x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967589x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2625</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>