<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:58:18Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2025" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zs25xb693</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the last decades, several numerical methods have been developed for the study of steady and unsteady flows past fixed or oscillating wings. Several studies were also conducted to analyze the structural oscillations of wings subjected to aerodynamic loading and to explore the possibilities of suppressing the aeroelastic oscillations of the wings, for example by using piezoelectric strips. However, it was difficult to use efficiently these numerical methods for the analysis of wing oscillations including the effect of the vibration-suppressing elements. This work presents an analytical method for the analysis of steady and unsteady flows past fixed or oscillating wings, which may be efficiently used for complex problems involving the structural dynamics analysis of the wing. The method is first validated for steady flows past fixed wings. Then results are presented for unsteady flows past oscillating wings in comparison with previous results.</description><creator>Grigore, Daniel.</creator><contributor>Mateescu, Dan (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Analysis of steady and unsteady flows past fixed or oscillating wings</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t8432.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xb693</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62fb50f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Given the great discord concerning the mechanisms that govern shear failure, the shear behaviour of concrete beam elements with no transverse reinforcement is investigated. The variables introduced in the experimental program are member depth, amount of longitudinal steel reinforcement and concrete strength. The effects of these variables on the shear stress at failure of the concrete are investigated. Two geometrically similar series of beams of different concrete strengths are compared. Beam heights in each of the series range from 90 mm to 960 mm and all the beams have a constant a/d ratio of 2.5. Results show a strong "size-effect" in the behaviour of concrete beam or one-way slab elements subjected to shear, where deeper members have smaller shear stresses at failure than shallower ones. Increasing the amount of flexural reinforcement increases the shear stress at failure while increasing the concrete compressive strength has little or no effect on the diagonal shear resistance of concrete. The ACI Code equations for shear are found to be unconservative for large elements while the CSA Standard simplified shear design method yields conservative predictions within the range of beams tested. For the beams tested, with an a/d ratio of 2.5, the combination of the modified compression field theory and a strut-and-tie analysis provides more accurate predictions.</description><creator>Ghannoum, Wassim M.</creator><contributor>Mitchell, D. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Size effect on shear strength of reinforced concrete beams</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/76537320w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fb50f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns064795r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The behaviour of interior slab-column connections in flat plates is investigated. The first part of this thesis discusses six two-way slab-column specimens which were designed such that they would fail in punching shear. The parameters investigated were the use of high-strength concrete and the concentration of the slab flexural reinforcement in the immediate column region. The effects of these parameters on the punching shear capacity, negative moment cracking, and stiffness of the two-way slab specimens are investigated. The second part of this thesis is a comparison of the test results obtained from this experimental program with the punching shear predictions of the Canadian CSA A23 3-94 Standard and the American ACI 318-95 Code. Some comparisons of the punching shear strength provisions of the British BS 8110-85 Standard and the European CEB-FIP 1990 Model Code are also carried out. Furthermore, the CSA Standard and the ACI Code predictions are compared to the experimental results obtained from some slab-column connections tested in this experimental program and tested by various investigators. The beneficial effects of the use of high-strength concrete and of the concentration of flexural reinforcement in the immediate column vicinity are demonstrated. It is also concluded that the punching shear strength of slab-column connections is a function of the flexural reinforcement ratio and that the shear design of slabs according to the current Canadian and American codes can be unconservative under certain conditions. It is recommended that the punching shear expressions of the CSA Standard and the ACI Code be modified to include the effect that the flexural reinforcement ratio has on the shear capacity of slab structures.</description><creator>Ghannoum, Carla M.</creator><contributor>Mitchell, D. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Effect of high-strength concrete on the performance of slab-column specimens</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79408028b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064795r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p686p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Epoxy-based flexible polymer concrete overlays have been used in the past 15 years in North America to protect the bridge deck from deterioration, to extend the service life, and to improve skid resistant of the riding surface. While 15 years of field applications have demonstrated the effectiveness of the protection offered by the technique, cracking and delamination failures have also been observed. The purpose of the research reported herein is to understand the mechanism of durability failure of the epoxy polymer concrete overlay system. The tests conducted were water permeability, chloride ion penetration, water absorption, strength loss, temperature cycling, and water vapour pressure. Methods of application of polymer concrete overlay play a key role in the success of the overlay. In addition to the two commonly used methods, the multiple layer and the slurry methods, five new application methods were proposed and evaluated. It was found that the addition of a primer in the overlay system helps reduce water permeability, and that the thin polymer concrete overlay was much less permeable than the thick asphalt overlay. The temperature cycling tests revealed that no significant delamination occurred after 103 cycles from -50°C to 40°C at an accelerated rate. The rapid chloride ion penetration test confirmed that polymer concrete overlays did provide sufficient protection to stop the chloride ion intrusion. Nevertheless, the epoxy polymer concrete overlays were found to absorb 2--3% of water, which caused a significant strength loss. This strength loss could lead to cracking inside the overlay and accelerate delamination thereafter. The water vapour pressure generated from the saturated concrete substrates was not large enough to promote delamination. Overall, the newly proposed overlay applications methods have proven effective in constructing a thin, durable, less expensive and fast overlay for aged bridge deck protection.</description><creator>Gama, Nuno, 1974-</creator><contributor>Shao, Y. (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><title>Durability of epoxy polymer concrete overlays for bridge decks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w37639133.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p686p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tx28d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The system under study is that of a two-dimensional, two-degree-of-freedom airfoil (NACA 0012) in a steady subsonic airstream with external forcing. This airfoil is flexibly mounted in both degrees-of-freedom, and thus, describes an aeroelastic system. Non-linearities arising from the aerodynamics are responsible for the phenomenon of dynamic stall when the airfoil oscillates past the static-stall angle of attack. These non-linearities also cause the system to produce non-linear classes of motion, the most important of which is chaotic motion. Aeroelastic instabilities are also present in the system. This thesis explores the instabilities present in this system as well as its non-linear behaviour. A semi-empirical numerical model revolving around the concept of an indicial response is used to model the non-linear aerodynamics in both degrees-of-freedom. The structural components of the system are modeled using simple linear elements, such as translational and torsional springs. Structural damping is ignored. Simple force and moment balancing equations allow for the derivation of the pertinent aeroelastic equations, which are then solved using numerical techniques. Self-excited oscillations, examples of aeroelastic instability, were found in the one-degree-of-freedom system for oscillations about the static-stall angle. Binary flutter, another form of aeroelastic instability, was found in the two-degree-of-freedom system. Every class of non-linear motion (equilibrium, periodic, quasi-periodic and chaotic) was discovered in the non-linear analysis, and several routes to chaos were discovered. These routes included the quasi-periodic route, period-doubling route and intermittency route. Some of the routes discovered compared well with classical examples.</description><creator>Fragiskatos, Gerasimos.</creator><contributor>Price, Stuart J. (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Non-linear response and instabilities of a two-degree-of-freedom airfoil oscillating in dynamic stall</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75df68n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tx28d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60cz74c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Many concrete structures built in the 1960s and 1970s are now showing significant signs of deterioration. The Dickson Bridge, constructed in 1959, was decommissioned by the City of Montreal in 1994 due to extensive deterioration of the bridge deck. A collaborative research investigation was carried out in 1997--8 on the bridge to: (a) assess the corrosion induced damage in the concrete deck, (b) identify the causes of the observed deterioration, and (c) investigate suitable test techniques for predicting corrosion. The results of this collaborative research program between McGill University and The Queen's University of Belfast, Northern Ireland, and some industrial partners, are presented in this thesis. A range of test methods related to the mechanisms causing corrosion, or to the concrete properties indicative of the probability of corrosion was used. Both methods (measuring damage, and measuring material properties and exposure parameters) were used to predict the corrosion rate of the reinforcing steel. Overall, the measurement of the corrosion potential was of important significance, however, to improve the assessment of the likelihood of corrosion, it was advantageous in combining this technique with a survey of the delamination, concrete cover thickness and chloride profiles. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Fazio, Rossella.</creator><contributor>Mirza, M. S. (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>The assessment and prediction of reinforcing steel corrosion on the Dickson Bridge /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh73f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz74c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xs55md98p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In recent years the disposal and the treatment of mine waste has been increasingly causing concern to the mining industry. One of the biggest challenges today is acid mine drainage (AMD), which is associated in particular with sulfide bearing tailings. As a consequence of AMD, heavy metals and sulfates are released into the environment. This project has studied the effect of lime-based treatments in the stabilization of two sulfide tailings, one waste predominately containing pyrite minerals and the second containing pyrrhotite minerals. Different proportions of pozzolans (fly ash and slag) were also added to the lime-tailings mixtures. The physical properties of the mixtures have been evaluated, using several tests such as strength (unconfined compressive strength), permeability and durability. The mineralogical changes in the treated wastes were also examined. The stabilization process and the treatment validity would not be complete without a chemical analysis of the treated waste; therefore a quantitative analysis was performed, including leaching and extraction tests for some elements (Zn, Mg, Ca, and Fe), and also sulfate measurement. The samples were tested after 1 and 28 days of curing time. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Elbadri, Hatim A.</creator><contributor>Hassani, Feeri P. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Environmental.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>The effect of pozzolans in the stabilization of sulfide tailings /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257h065.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55md98p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30pv82q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A study on the web-buckling behavior of castellated beams is described in this thesis. Both elastic and plastic methods of analysis are utilized to predict the failure modes of these beams. Interaction diagrams predicting formation of plastic mechanisms, yielding of the horizontal weld length and elastic buckling analysis using the finite element method are correlated with a number of experimental test results from previous studies given in the literature. Test-to-predicted ratios for a total of 42 test beams ranging from 45° to 60° openings are computed with the plastic and elastic methods of analysis, and a mean of 1.086 and coefficient of variation of 0.195 are obtained. A parameter study covering a wide range of 60° castellated beam geometries is performed to derive elastic buckling coefficients under pure shear and bending forces. An elastic buckling interaction diagram is then defined, which along with the diagrams utilized in the plastic analysis, can be used to predict the elastic buckling and plastic failure loads under any given moment-to-shear ratio. To incorporate the effect of plasticity associated with buckling, expressions are derived to improve the previous theoretical models used, by combining both elastic and plastic results. This results in an improvement in the coefficient of variation of the test-to-predicted ratios or the 60° beams considered from 0.170 to 0.137.</description><creator>Demirdjian, Sevak.</creator><contributor>McClure, G. (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Redwood, R. G. (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Stability of castellated beam webs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bd813.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pv82q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c2749</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>IF 409 stainless steel is a common industrial steel grade used in automotive exhaust systems. It combines a high formability with the corrosion resistance associated with stainless steels. Two particular grades of IF 409 were used in these experiments: a titanium stabilized and a titanium-niobium stabilized. The current work explores the mechanical behavior Of this grade with emphasis on the occurrence of dynamic recrystallization. Hot torsion tests were performed over a range of temperatures and strains to determine the behavior. The tests were analyzed using the flow curves, optical microscopy and texture measurements. The optical micrographs indicated that dynamic recrystallization was occurring. The texture results confirmed that the titanium stabilized steel dynamically recrystallized around 1000°C and the titanium-niobium grade recrystallized around 1200°C. In addition, the effects of strain and temperature were quantified. The results allow the feasibility of dynamic recrystallization in industrial applications to be determined.</description><creator>DeArdo, Ian A.</creator><contributor>Yue, S. (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Jonas, J. J. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Mechanical behavior of IF 409 ferritic stainless steel</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mp47r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c2749</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967584j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The mineral processing group of McGill University developed a novel gas holdup probe that consists of two conductivity flow cells: an open cell used to estimate dispersion (slurry + air) conductivity and a syphon cell used to estimate slurry conductivity. These two values are entered into Maxwell's model to calculate gas holdup. In this work some design criteria for conductivity flow cells and the syphon cell are given. Effect of geometrical cell constant and electrode width on cell behaviour are analyzed. New dimensions for open and syphon cells are proposed. Conditions to prevent bubbles from being entrained into the syphon cell are established. The new design of the gas holdup probe was tested successfully over a prolonged period at the INCO Matte Separation Plant (Copper Cliff, Ontario). Tests carried out in waste paper de-inking at BOWATER (Gatineau, Quebec) showed the gas holdup values given by the probe agreed with the values obtained from pressure. The noise associated with the gas holdup signal obtained by the probe could be used to diagnose sparger operation. Gas holdup showed some degree of correlation with flotation efficiency of waste paper de-inking and flotation rate constant. Chemistry and rheology of the feed are other factors to be considered. Estimation of bubble surface area flux should consider rheology properties (liquid viscosity and density).</description><creator>Cortés-López, Franklin.</creator><contributor>Finch, James A. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Design of a gas holdup sensor for flotation diagnosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mp481.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967584j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930c041n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Crossed anode wire position sensitive photomultiplier tubes (PS-PMTs) detect the location of a light source and provide the X and Y coordinates of the events. These coordinates are typically generated using Anger logic, where a resistor chain divides the current flow into two signals for each coordinate (X+, X-, &amp; Y +, Y-). In the standard readout, identical resistor values are used across the entire resistor chain. While this arrangement provides a linear readout in the central portion of the photomultiplier face, the readout is non-linear and sometimes even double valued near the edges of the PS-PMT due to the truncation of the charge beyond the last anode wire. To counter this effect, we have increased the value of the resistance near the ends of each resistor chain in order to compensate for the charge lost beyond the anode wires. Measurements were made using a Hamamatsu R-3941 PS-PMT coupled to a pixellated BGO matrix of cut crystals with a 2 mm. pitch in each direction. After changing the end resistors, the usable field-of-view increased by 39%. This simple modification should enhance the operation of PS-PMTs in application such as positron emission mammography, and small animal PET imaging.</description><creator>Clancy, Raymond Lecours.</creator><contributor>Thompson, C. J. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>A simple technique to improve the linearity and field-of-view of crossed anode wire position sensitive photomultiplier tubes /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z754q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c041n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78tf186</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During planetary hot rolling of 304 austenitic stainless steel, cracks are formed along the plate edges. In order to explain the mechanism of edge cracking, the metallographical quantitative analysis of microstructural inhomogeneity of steel plates containing edge cracks of different intensities is performed. The austenitic matrix of the steel contained small amounts of delta ferrite inhomogeneously distributed across the width and the thickness of the plate. A correlation was found between ferrite content and edge cracking: the higher the ferrite content the longer the edge cracks. Among the chemical elements present in the steel, the most critical effect on delta ferrite content was exerted by carbon and nitrogen are a powerful gamma phase stabilizers at high temperature. To understand the effects of reheating parameters on the morphology and content of delta ferrite, the specimens selected from different locations of as-cast 304 stainless steel slab, were reheated according to the temperature profiles, which simulated the industrial reheating process before hot rolling. In general, reheating reduced the delta ferrite content, increased the size of the individual ferrite island and changed its shape to a more spherical. An increase of reheating time to 92 minutes caused drastic reduction in delta ferrite content and its further spherodization. Moreover, the size of the individual ferrite islands decreased. A possible, contribution of steel chemistry and reheating parameters to changes in the steel microstructure and the possibility of edge cracking, is discussed.</description><creator>Cho, Jae-Young, 1970-</creator><contributor>Szpunar, J. A. (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Effect of [delta] ferrite on edge-crack formation during hot rolling of austenitic stainless steel</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gn08t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tf186</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns0647961</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In plastics manufacturing, the morphology and crystallinity are important in the determination of the properties of the final product. They are influenced by several parameters, in particular the pressure and the temperature history during solidification. Therefore, the study of the influence of pressure and temperature on crystallization kinetics is important. In this study, the crystallization kinetics and the PVT behavior of various grades of polyethylene resins were evaluated and compared using a high-pressure dilatometer under both isothermal and isobaric conditions. Also, the PVT behavior was compared to the predictions of the Tait equation of state. It was found that polyethylene chain structure, as determined by branching and branching uniformity; influences nucleation, crystallization kinetics, and the effect of pressure an these processes. In addition, the results confirm the decrease of the surface free energy of the crystal nucleus with increasing pressure.</description><creator>Capt, Ludovic.</creator><date>1999</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><subject>Plastics Technology.</subject><title>The pressure-volume-temperature behavior and the effect of pressure on crystallization kinetics of polyethylene resins /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj1394101.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns0647961</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892d080</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Much water pollution is due to the disposal of liquid waste from industrial and municipal outfalls. The disposed effluent from the outfalls, located on the banks of streams and rivers, affects the pollutant concentration levels along the coast. The effluent in the form of a jet mixes with the crossflow on the upstream side and forms a recirculation region immediately downstream of the discharge. The objective of this thesis, therefore, is to study the behaviour of such polluting effluents with emphasis on its impact along the coast. The study consisted of experiments conducted in a laboratory whereby a dye was introduced at the source of the discharge to act as a tracer; the dyed effluent was discharged from a side channel into an open channel crossflow. The entrapment and the mixing process of the pollutant in the recirculation region were then examined. A video imaging technique was employed to detail the characteristics of the recirculation eddy in terms of the jet and eddy geometry, the steady-state concentration, and the retention time of the dye concentration in the recirculation region. From the video information, a simplified control volume model was developed from which were derived unified relations between the concentration in the recirculation region and the momentum flux ratio of the jet and the crossflow. The resulting data obtained by the video imaging technique are consistent with and complimentary to a number of data sets from previous experimental investigations.</description><creator>Bouhairie, Salem.</creator><contributor>Chu, V. H. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>A study of the entrapment process in a recirculation flow by video imaging method /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tt79j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892d080</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nk313</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis describes the design and implementation of a content-based image retrieval system that improves on classical appearance-based methods of retrieval. The motivation is to build a system capable of retrieving complex scenes in unconstrained environments. In this work, we use principal components analysis as a parameterization of the images. The analysis, however, is not performed on the level of the intensity values of image pixels as in traditional approaches, but on the level of two intermediate representations. We use the magnitude of the Fourier Transform as a relevant and stable comparison feature to retrieve complex scenes, and zero crossings across various scales for well-framed images. We show through experimental results that the inclusion of suitable intermediate representations in the system renders more reliable responses, and allows relaxing the constraints about the nature of the images used. This work also extends beyond normal content-based image retrieval systems. Given an unknown image query, our system does not merely return the closest images to the query, but further enhances the response by classifying the image as belonging to one of several classes comprising the database. Two methods of classification are used: the k nearest neighbors method, and a Bayesian classification method. In the latter case, we re-map the basis calculated by principal components analysis into another basis whose vectors are optimal for class discrimination. These vectors are called the most discriminating features. Experimental results are presented showing how the resulting system can be used to return a confidence measure in the decisions it takes, allowing for subsequent refining of the search.</description><creator>Beyrouti, Fadi.</creator><contributor>Ferrie, Frank (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>An improved appearance-based approach to image retrieval and classification /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn00b103v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nk313</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xs55md99z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mobile robots are taking an important role in society. They are being used in many industries from entertainment to space exploration. McGill University's Ambulatory Robotics Laboratory recently introduced a new class of quadruped robot---the SCOUT series. These robots feature only one actuated degree of freedom per leg. By keeping the degrees of freedom to a minimum, this class of robots is simpler, less expensive and more reliable than most legged robots built to date. The design and development of the second of these robots, SCOUT II, is the topic of this thesis. Unlike its predecessor SCOUT I, SCOUT II has unactuated prismatic knee joints in addition to the revolute joints, which allow compliant walking, stair-climbing and running gaits to be explored. SCOUT II is a self-contained, autonomous mobile robot whose primary purpose is to serve as the testbed for the various gaits that are being developed. This thesis describes the robot's mechanical design, electrical design, sensors and construction. A preliminary stair-climbing algorithm is developed and simulated. An attempt, though partially unsuccessful, is made to implement this algorithm on SCOUT II. The reasons for the discrepancies between the simulations and the actual system are outlined. This will provide useful insight on modelling parameters, actuator limits and robot dynamics for future stair-climbing, walking and running algorithms that are developed for SCOUT II.</description><creator>Battaglia, Robert F.</creator><contributor>Buehler, Martin (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Design of the SCOUT II quadruped with preliminary stair-climbing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c4825.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55md99z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jd472z52n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It has been well established that the development of discipline in the gymnasium and the classroom is affected by factors related to proper management and instruction (Siedentop, 1991; Doyle, 1986). However, little research has been done to investigate discipline in relation to the overall teaching context by investigating the instructional and managerial systems together. This study provided an in-depth investigation of one secondary physical education teacher's learning environment. The first two instructional units of the school year for each of two grade levels (25 and 22 lessons, respectively) were observed. The Rules, Routines and Expectations (RRE) instrument was used to investigate preventative management strategies, and teacher and student behaviours were analyzed with a modified Task Structure Observational System (TSS). Teacher interviews focused on her perceptions of discipline within the overall learning environment. The results indicated that five rules, seven routines and three expectations were communicated to the students at the beginning of the school year. Engagement with the content dominated lesson episodes and applying tasks dominated the task types observed. Students' responses to instruction showed high percentages of congruence with the assigned tasks and high success rates. Very few instances of student misbehaviour were recorded except in one unit. Content selection, learners' skill level, management strategies and class dynamics were possible explanations for the students' misbehaviour. Interviews indicated that the teacher felt that student discipline affected her program to some extent as she sometimes had to modify her expectations and objectives and devote time to management tasks. The interaction of the instructional and managerial systems was apparent.</description><creator>Yip, Gary.</creator><contributor>Downey, Peggy (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Physical education and training -- Study and teaching (Secondary) -- Québec (Province) -- Case studies.</subject><subject>School discipline -- Québec (Province) -- Case studies.</subject><title>Discipline in physical education : a case study of one secondary physical education teacher</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161832x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd472z52n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720g07d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis provides an historical description and analysis of Labyrinth, the National Film Board of Canada's pavilion at Montreal's Expo 67. The thesis discusses Labyrinth in the context of traditions of multiscreen cinema and immersive artworks; further it relates the pavilion's structure, film content, and role in Expo within the context of Canadian art traditions and the 1967 centennial celebrations. Analysis of the pavilion is grounded in Bruce Elder's treatise on Canadian cinema entitled "The Cinema We Need". The thesis also explains the technological and formal, connections between Labyrinth and the invention of IMAX cinema.</description><creator>Whitney, Allison.</creator><contributor>Straw, Will (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Experimental films -- Canada -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>National Film Board of Canada.</subject><title>Labyrinth : cinema, myth and nation at Expo 67</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bh211.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720g07d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hr78d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This Master's thesis analyses the connection between the Illuminati ideology and the sociopolitical ideals contained in pre-classical works---contemporary to the existence of the order---of Johann Wolfgang Goethe and Friedrich Schiller. The first chapter examines the creation, the development and the eventual collapse of the Illuminati Secret Society (Geheimbund der Illuminaten) founded in 1776 by Adam Weishaupt in the context of the Enlightenment. The second chapter explores the ideological similarities between the young Goethe and this secret society through the analysis of his works Gotz von Berlichingen (1771--1773), Egmont (1775--1784) and Der Gross Cophta (1791). The third chapter expounds Schiller's ideological opinion of the Illuminati through Don Carlos (1787), and discusses their republican visions of freedom and human rights. The conclusion integrates the findings made in each chapter and demonstrates, through both authors' discussed works, the similar ideals of both authors and Illuminism.</description><creator>Wellige, Rainer.</creator><contributor>Hsia, Adrian (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1749-1832 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Illuminati.</subject><subject>Schiller, Friedrich, 1759-1805 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Elemente der illuminatischen Ideologie in einigen vorklassischen Werken von Goethe und Schiller</title><language>ger</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v059q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hr78d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of German Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rg587</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The notion, which has persisted over many years, of Mary Shelley as the conservative daughter of a radical, proto-feminist mother can be traced to the views of Edward Trelawney, a contemporary and fair-weather friend of Shelley. This study, by exploring female identity, largely in terms of modern feminist psychoanalytic theory, in several of Shelley's lesser-known novels, attempts to contribute to the efforts of those who have challenged such notions and who have strived to render a more accurate portrait of Mary Shelley. Anne Mellor's discussion of female identity in Shelley's sentimental novels, Mathilda, Lodore and Falkner, (in her book Mary Shelley: Her Life, Her Fiction, Her Monsters) does much to dispel the notion of Shelley's apathy with regard to gender politics. Mellor convincingly argues that these novels celebrate what she terms the "relational" identity of their heroines, and thus "support a feminist position which argues that female culture is morally superior to male culture." She further maintains, however, that these novels simultaneously reveal the damage that such an identity can do to a woman's personal development. My paper challenges Mellor's assertion that Lodore and Falkner Shelley's last novels, portray relational identity with ambivalence. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Walker, Tara.</creator><contributor>Kilgour, Maggie (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Shelley, Mary Wollstonecraft, 1797-1851 -- Characters -- Women.</subject><subject>Identity (Philosophical concept) in literature.</subject><subject>Women in literature.</subject><subject>Interpersonal relations in literature.</subject><title>"Each half a nothing, so disjoined" : Mary Shelley's vindication of relational identity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042w08z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rg587</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q631n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>After a series of reversals in its wars with European powers during the eighteenth century, the Ottoman Empire was forced to reevaluate its military technology and training. The realization that the West had outstripped the Muslim East in scientific and technological advancement led Ottoman reformers to introduce changes to the traditional educational system, especially to the curriculum. However, what the reformers soon realized was that the military superiority of Europe was only a symptom, and not the cause of, the West's advancement; this led to the introduction of more Western-style institutions in an effort to achieve its military goals. It was through these new institutions that Western ideas of equality, rationalism and liberalism were introduced into the Ottoman Empire. These imported ideas were bitterly resisted by the ulema, who continued to operate a traditional school system parallel to that developed by the reformers. In spite of their objections, however, the traditional Muslim educational system was forced to undergo a significant metamorphosis both prior to and during the Tanzimat period.</description><creator>VanDuinkerken, Wyoma.</creator><contributor>Turgay, U. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Turkey -- History -- Tanzimat, 1839-1876.</subject><subject>Educational change -- Turkey -- History -- 19th century.</subject><title>Educational reform in the Tanzimat era (1839-1876) : secular reforms in Tanzimat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386m57d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q631n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1831cn057</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An abnormal chronotropic response to exercise is a common finding following surgical repair of tetralogy of Fallot (TOF) which has generally been attributed to a putative sympathetic dysfunction. There exists little information on sympathetic function in patients operated for a congenital heart defect to support such a claim. This study used spectral analysis of heart rate (HRV) and blood pressure (BPV) variability to examine sympathovagal influences on the sinus node in 9 adolescents operated for TOF 13.0 +/- 1.12 years previously and in 8 healthy age and sex-matched control (CTRL) subjects. Continuous ECG and BP recordings were obtained under supine or seated resting positions, with or without controlled respiration at 0.20 Hz (CR); after passive 85° head-up tilt (HUT); during cycling at steady-state heart rates of 100 and 120 bpm (Ex 100, Ex 120), and after 10 and 20 minutes of passive seated recovery. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Tzovanis, Maria.</creator><contributor>Perrault, Helene (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Tetralogy of Fallot.</subject><subject>Heart function tests.</subject><subject>Heart -- Abnormalities -- Surgery.</subject><subject>Exercise tests.</subject><title>Power spectral components of heart rate variability at rest and exercise after surgical repair of tetralogy of fallot</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f4627575.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cn057</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vd64q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the development of an anorexic discourse in Goethe's Die Wahlverwandtschaften. Chapter 1 investigates anorexia as a cultural signifier and its relationship to non-clinical and non-medical disciplines. I then submit that female self-starvation serves a structural and a thematic function in WV. In Chapter 2, I argue that Ottilie's arrested female development illustrates the central, concept (elective affinities) of the novel. Chapter 3 examines food as a non-verbal system of communication in the narrative. Here, I demonstrate that Ottilie's eating disorder denies her subjectivity while it signifies and affirms the dominant social institutions depicted in the novel. Chapter 4 examines Ottilie's oscillation between corporeality and bodilessness. Her physicality is always associated with instability. The disappearance of her flesh allows for the passive reflection of masculine identity. In Chapter 5, I analyze the representation of Otttilie's death and demonstrate that her corpse allegorizes the construction of subjectivity in the narrative. In closing, I argue that Ottilie is an empty signifier in the novel, onto which the plot is imposed. Her anorexia functions as a sign for the process of narration and is a condition of the novel itself.</description><creator>Trépanier, Michèle.</creator><contributor>Sia, Adrian H. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Anorexia nervosa in literature.</subject><subject>Goethe, Johann Wolfgang von, 1749-1832. Wahlverwandtschaften.</subject><title>Food, flesh and death : anorexic discourse in Goethe's Die Wahlverwandtschaften</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tf19g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vd64q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of German Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c275k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The "end of the century" nourishes a questioning movement on national identity and on the concept of modernity that is encouraged by the Quebec essayists. We propose an organization of the elements of the sovereign narrative which would be able to conduct and constitute a generative grammar of its argumentation. Our project consists in creating a matrix of the nationalistic discourse during the 1995 Quebec referendum period on sovereignty. This schematic figure will bring to its most simple expression the narrative of the Quebec nationalistic discourse selecting examples from ten texts of our primary bibliography. Our matrix will incorporate ideas, dogmas, theories, facts and myths stemming from the ideological discourses. We will see how these elements do interact, to be able afterwards to gather them in a framework on which national identity and legitimity of the national accession to sovereignty should be based. The study of this narrative of the past, as well as the analysis of the public characters will be leaded by the sociocritical approach of discourse analysis. The francophone cultural nation living on the territory of the Province of Quebec demonstrates itself through the values of tenacity, solidarity, labour and openness of mind towards "Others". The nation increases the standing of a society project based on a democratic basis, condemning the traitors of the Quebec nation. This history concerns the francophone majority even though it is linked to the other "oppressed peoples" of the World History. This "french-quebecer" history is enhanced with a collective memory, projected towards the future in making the project of sovereignty the purpose of its teleological progression.</description><creator>Trépanier, Anne.</creator><contributor>Angenot, Marc (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Referendum -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Nationalism -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Québec (Province) -- History -- Autonomy and independence movements.</subject><title>La grammaire générative de l'argumentaire souverainiste en 1995 /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967585t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c275k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b8515q62r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is an examination of the various ways in which marijuana, its use, and its users have historically been signified, within both hegemonic and subcultural discourses, from marijuana's origins in antiquity through its North American prohibition in the earlier part of the twentieth century. Attention is given to how this history, and prohibition in particular, has informed contemporary North American significations of the drug, its use and its users.</description><creator>Thomson, Ian, 1965-</creator><contributor>Kaite, Berkeley (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Marijuana -- Government policy -- United States.</subject><subject>Marijuana -- Social aspects.</subject><title>Inhaling : the changing significations of marijuana in hegemonic and subcultural discourses, from antiquity through its prohibition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sz05q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515q62r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2050</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>