<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:30:30Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):10650" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gk56k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:31:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A tRNA N2 guanine dimethylase was partially purified from mouse Ehrlich ascites tumour cells, and some of its properties studied. The enzyme was purified from 105,000g supernatant by precipitation at pH 5.1 followed by chromatography on hydroxyapatite at pH 6.8. Activity was assayed by measuring the rate of methylation of either E. coli B or yeast tRNA with (14C or 3H)-Me-S-adenosyl-, methionine at pH 8.2. Although substantial amount of other methylated guanine derivatives and methylated pyrimidines were detected in tRNA incubated with the "supernatant enzymes" fraction or with the "pH 5 enzymes" fraction, 86% of the methylation of tRNA with one of the fractions from hydroxyapatite was of guanine to form N2 -dimethyl guanine. No methylation of adenine by any of the enzyme fractions was detected.</description><creator>Chan, Tak-Chor</creator><contributor>Fraser, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Mammalian tumour tRNA methylases</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m7178.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gk56k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150n075</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:31:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A study has been made of the regulation in normal and neoplastic rat liver of the induction of ornithine decarboxylase, a key enzyme in polyamine synthesis in eukaryotes. The radioassay for this enzyme was significantly improved by the addition of EDTA and the substitution of Tris buffer for phosphate buffer. In contrast to DNA synthesis the profile of the ornithine decarboxylase induction in response to partial hepatectomy does not vary dramatically with the age of the rat. The induction of ornithine decarboxylase is inhibited by 8-azaguanine and 5-azacytidine, inhibitors of protein synthesis. The induction is however reinitiated after a delay of approximately 4-6 hours, a time at which the drug is almost completely metabolized. This supports a theory of transcriptional control for ornithine decarboxylase induction. Although ornithine decarboxylase is induced in response to stress and corticosteroids, the induction after partial hepatectomy or thioacetamide administration was shown to be independent of stress. The two slow growing hepatomas examined showed a relationship between ornithine decarboxylase and spermidine levels but none with spermine levels. On the basis of these results, it is proposed that the levels of spermidine and spermine may be controlled separately in the cell.</description><creator>Cavia, Emile</creator><contributor>Webb, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Control of polyamine synthesis in normal and neoplastic rat liver</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892f07x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150n075</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:000003182</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:31:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fine structure of normal and activated rat parathyroids was studied using routine and glycoprotein staining. The chief cells of the gland contained organelles concerned with the formation of secretory material, that is rER and Golgi apparatus. In routine staining, the Golgi apparatus consisted primarily of flattened saccules and connecting profiles. The prosecretory and secretory granules associated with the connecting profiles contained a dense central core surrounded by a clear halo. With glycoprotein staining the Golgi saccules showed a gradual transition from the unstained forming face to the moderately stained mature face. In this region the connecting profiles outlined a network of hexagon-like structures. The prosecretory and secretory granules were outlined by positive material, however, their internal content was delicately stained.</description><creator>Bodak-Gyovai, Levente</creator><contributor>Warshawsky, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Anatomy.</subject><title>Electron microscopic study of the secretory activity of the normal and hyperactive parathyroid gland of the rat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827f76p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000003182</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv935602c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:31:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Approximately one-half of one percent of the total population suffers from epilepsy, a neurological disorder characterized by the paroxysmal occurrence of seizures. "An epileptic seizure is a state produced by an abnormal excessive neuronal discharge within the central nervous system." (Penfield and Jasper, 1954) Two drugs very widely used for the medical management of "the epilepsies" are phenobarbital and diphenylhydantoin (5, 5-diphenylhydantoin, phenytoin). These pharmaceutical agents are the prime concern of this thesis.</description><creator>Bock, George W.</creator><contributor>Sherwin, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Neurology and Neurosurgery.</subject><title>Measurement of the levels of diphenylhydration and phenobarbital in patients with epilepsy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04ds67c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935602c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kd827</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:31:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Billick, Robin C.</creator><contributor>Nadler, N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Anatomy.</subject><title>The classification of cells of the transplantable thyroid tumor of the rat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77st09t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kd827</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5999n6463</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:31:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A theoretical investigation into the launching of dipolar surface waves on a dielectric tube is presented. The source under consideration is a transversely oriented point electric dipole situated on the axis of the tube. It is found to excite only the dominant HE11 mode. Phase and group characteristics as well as some field distributions are given for the source -free case; however, these are independent of the choice of the source, and are dependent only on the particular mode being excited. Surface-wave as well as radiated powers are obtained in terms of the current in the source dipole, and the launching efficiency of the surface waves is determined as a function of the tube radius, wall-thickness and permittivity of the material. Finally, comparisons are made between the dielectric tube and the solid rod which was investigated previously [27] as possible surface-wave transmission lines, and also the launching efficiencies for these two cases.</description><creator>Auyeung, Tatyan</creator><contributor>Yip, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Electrical Engineering.</subject><title>Launching efficiency of the HE11 surface wave mode on a dielectric tube</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977z06f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n6463</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bf819</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:31:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objectives of these studies were to investigate the effect of inositol on 45Ca absorption by bone of rats in comparison with 89Sr; and whether there has been evidence that it could play a part in reversing the loss of calcium-proteinate in osteoporotic bones of rats previously given corticosteroids, as a model of the human disorder, both idiopathic or following drug treatment. The relationship of inositol was the prime concern, as a primary objective, but was enlarged to study the interrelationships between several hormones and inositol in terms of bone calcium content.</description><creator>Angeloff, Luben</creator><contributor>Skoryna, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1972</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Radiocalcium and radiostrontium update in bones of rats with relation to effect of vitamin D action and inositol synergism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913s904.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bf819</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j851n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:31:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La préoccupation avec les basses classes, qui est le trait saillant du roman noir Américain des années 1920, a son origine dans le désir de certains intellectuels de promouvoir une solution culturelle au problème racial. Servant d’introduction à la présente étude de cette solution est une revue générale de l’époque. Elle vise à recréer l’atmosphère essoufflée et d’euphorie qui a marqué la vie contemporaine et qui a vu l’éclosion sans précédent du talent artistic noir. D’abord, on étudie l’aspect positif de la solution. [...]</description><description>The lower-class theme that predominates in the Harlem novel stems from the desire of the black novelist of the Twenties to give aesthetic and social sanction to folk-life as a solution to the American race problem. The thesis begins with a broad survey that attempts to recreate the cultural mood and artistic effervescence of an era that unleashed an unprecedented outpouring of black talent. Part One is concerned with the affirmative aspects of the ideal of folk-life. The originality of this study resides partly in its analysis of black folk values and in their description as a kind of racial or group soul. Part Two, which focuses on the critical aspects of the above ideal, explores the historical origins and the fictional expression of the resistance to white American culture. And Part Three examines reservations toward the ideal by dissenting Harlem novelists through a new interpretation of the “passing” theme.</description><creator>Casimir, Stephen P., 1936-</creator><contributor>Dorsinville, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Bristol, Michael D. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Elliott, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1981</date><subject>American fiction -- 20th century -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Harlem Renaissance.</subject><subject>African American authors -- Political and social views.</subject><subject>Literature, English.</subject><subject>American fiction -- African American authors -- History and criticism.</subject><title>Folk-life in the Harlem renaissance novel</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053k38h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j851n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d570076v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:31:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Considerable recent research has been devoted to the treatment of L2 learners’ errors within the framework of a communicative methodology. This research has so far not led to any systematized guidelines for error treatment in the L2 classroom. Communicatively- oriented language teachers must respond to errors without any empirical proof of the efficacy of one response over another. Teachers of adult L2 learners find that these students often have traditional expectations about grammar instruction and error correction which are at odds with a communicative approach. [...]</description><creator>Brown, Nancy</creator><contributor>Spada, Nina (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1990</date><subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Foreign speakers.</subject><subject>Adult education.</subject><subject>Second language acquisition.</subject><subject>English language -- Errors of usage.</subject><subject>Language and languages -- Study and teaching -- Error analysis.</subject><subject>Education, Adult and Continuing.</subject><title>Error correction in the adult communicative ESL classroom : teachers’ perceptions and realities</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462846v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d570076v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Education</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Teaching of English as a Second Language</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074z15p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:31:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The first carotenoid to be isolated was carotenefrom the root of the cultivated carrot (Daucus carota),this was done by Wackenroder in 1831 and named by himcarotin (59).</description><creator>Goss, George Charles Louis.</creator><contributor>McFarlane, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>The conversion of carotene to vitamin A in vitro.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nx72b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074z15p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418r38n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:31:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis nresents preliminary work on the study of the structure a,nd mechanism of rain showers emploving radar as a research tool. The first chapter is compiled from published literature, and is intended to bring the reader up to date on both the previous and present work in the field. It includes a section on the basic theory involved when radar is used to investigate atmospheric pheno1nena. Section 1 of this chapter has been written in collaboration with Mr. W.M. Palmar.Chapter II is an assessment of the scattering functions presented by RYDE( 4 ), a pioneer in the theoretical treatment of scattering of electromagnetic ra11at1on by raindrops.The author has gone more fully into the applicability of these functions under variouP cond1tions than has been done elsewhere, and has considered their applicability in the lightof recent findings of the Canadian Army Onerational research Group. Chapter III presents the analyses of rain showers as seen on the radar displays. Numerous illustrations are included,which provide a comprehensive picture of the internal structure of showers, as well as certain features of their motion and\ development.</description><creator>Gunn, Kenrick Lewis Stuart.</creator><contributor>Marshall, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>Radar echoes from rain showers.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d968n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418r38n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50h031q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:31:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The method ot separating substances by centrifuging is so ancient that its origin is unrecorded. In recent years, its use has become more widespread until, today, centrifuges are employed in many industries and in most laboratories. However, the development of the technique ot employing very high centrifugal fields tor the measurement ot particle sizes has taken place since 1923.</description><creator>Gunton, Robert Carl.</creator><contributor>Foster, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>Some applications of a Svedberg rotor in ultracentrifuge measurements.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nf224.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50h031q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80hz68k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:31:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Iserhoff river area lies in Abitibi East county at some 80 miles north of Senneterre, a town on the Canadian National Railway. It is bounded by longitudes 76°45’ and 77°00’ west and by latitude 49°45’ north and by a line about 4 miles south of latitude 49°30’ north [...]</description><creator>Imbault, P. E.</creator><contributor>Osborne, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>The acidic plutonic rocks of the Iserhoff river area.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bm44p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hz68k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rf55zb88w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:31:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>[...] The data outlined in the foregoing paragraphs clearly show that the functional characteristics of the potentials recorded from the intracranial portion of the auditory nerve differ in several significant aspects from those of the potentials obtained from the cochlea. Nevertheless, a few observations contradictory to the hypothesis that the Wever and Bray phenomenon involves a non-neural component must now be considered and explained. [...]</description><creator>Kellaway, Peter E.</creator><contributor>Hoff, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>The bioelectric phenomena of the auditory apparatus.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289n10g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55zb88w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526g396</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:31:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The carrot (Daucus carota, Linn.) is a native of Europe, Asia and Northern Africa and possibly North and South America. Authors seem to disagree as to the place where the horticultural improvement of the species began. Bailey (1944) attributes it to Holland while Coulter (1941) says that the transition of the wild carrot to the garden form took place in France. Though there are some rather hazy indications that a form of carrot may have been known to man in remote antiquity, for practical purposes the garden type is to be regarded as one of the comparatively later developed species dating from approximately the second century B.C. It is difficult to be precise about the carrot of that time, or even much later, since the ancient writings are so brief and vague in their references to it and to plants of similar type. Thus it is not always possible to ascribe with accuracy to individual species the various names which are in use. One Greek word usually translated as carrot, is “staphulinos” meaning “clustered”, evidently with reference to the umbel. Dioscorides, a physician of the first century in our era, whose work was the standard authority for 1,500 years, says the umbel or inflorescence had a little purple in the midst of the tuft, so it seems evident to regard it as the wild carrot. [...]</description><creator>Laliberté, Jacques.</creator><contributor>Murray, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Horticulture-Botany.</subject><title>A study of mineral nutritional effects on carrots.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dw345.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526g396</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Horticulture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sk39n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:31:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Numerous investigators have described morphologic changes attributed to experimentally induced hypersensitivity. Different observers have stressed different lesions, and the recent recognition or sulfonamide hypersensitivity has resulted in further additions to an already long list of tissue alterations. In the experiments forming the basis or this thesis, 77 rabbits were given large doses of horse serum intravenously, and their tissues searched for lesions. An acute arteritis, quite similar to the vascular lesions or periarteritis nodosa was found in 47 cases. Diffuse and focal inflammatory lesions were found in smooth, cardiac and skeletal muscle. The latter changes bore a striking resemblance to the muscle lesions of dermatomyositis, and less closely simulated the muscle changes associated with rheumatoid arthritis. Inflammatory cardiac lesions somewhat reminiscent or the cardiac changes in acute rheumatic fever were also found, but their occurrance in small numbers in control animals vitiated the significance of this experimental result. The joints of 6 animals showed subacute inflammatory changes considerably in excess of any changes seen in control rabbits.</description><creator>McLean, Chester R.</creator><contributor>Duff, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Pathology.</subject><title>Experimental studies in the pathology of allergy.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rr95w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sk39n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf268835v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:31:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The vasopressin level was measured by the antidiuretic assay after an extraction procedure based on adsorption of the hormone on an ion exchange resin. Modifications and problems related to these procedures have been discussed. The method was applied for: (a) Measurement of plasma ADH in dogs with surgically induced congestive heart failure and in patients with congestive heart failure. There was no definite correlation between the level of plasma vasopressin and the occurrence of cardiac edema. (b) Studying the effect of chlorpropamide administration on the level of urinary ADH in a patient with diabetes insipidus in order to have some information on the mechanism of the antidiuretic action of this drug. (c) The study of patients with the syndrome of inappropriate secretion of ADH.</description><creator>Nawar, Tewfik</creator><contributor>Genest, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Studies on the determination of antidiuretic hormone and some of its applications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd376082h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268835v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3197xp812</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:31:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A sensitive microwave spectrometer which operates over the range V = 0.715 cm^-1 to V =  0.870 cm^-1 has been constructed and used to study molecular absorption spectra of numerous gases. The spectral lines in this region of NH3, H2O, HDO, OCS, and CH3OH, which had been reported in the literature, have been confirmed with this instrument. In the spectrum of CH3OH a new line has been found, having a frequency of 24,926 megacycles. Thirty-four other compounds which showed theoretical possibilities of possessing spectral lines in this region have been studied, but no new lines have been found. A modification of the spectrometer has been effected to allow the Stark effect on the strongest NH3 spectral line to be observed and measured. The effect is a simple frequency shift proportional to the square of the applied electric field as is predicted by elementary theory.</description><creator>Millar, Charles H., 1920-</creator><contributor>Foster, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>Molecular absorption spectra in the 1.25 centimeter region.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365829z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xp812</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mm99c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:31:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The cardio-respiratory effects of a thoracic epidural anaesthetic as is given for pain relief following upper abdominal surgery were examined in thirteen surgical patients studied in the immediate pre-operative period, following an overnight fast and without premedication. The focus of interest was on its effects on FRC and on gas exchange (measured as A-aDO2 and QS/QT%), which have not been previously reported. All subjects were given 10 ml/Kg glucose in saline I.V. during the pre-epidural period. Lidocaine 1.5% was used in all cases, plain lidocaine for the first eight and lidocaine with epinephrine 1/200,000 in the other five subjects. This agent was given to achieve a sensory block to both pin-prick and ice up to T4. Neither FRC nor gas exchange showed any consistent changes following the epidural anaesthetic. These findings are in keeping with what was anticipated from a consideration of the basic physiology and pharmacology concerned and with a review of the pertinent literature.</description><creator>Meleika-Wahba, W.</creator><contributor>Becklake, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Cardio-respiratory effects of thoracic epidural anaesthesia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021j23s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mm99c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xw05x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ch. I: Nutritional needs of ill patients have resulted in elemental diets consisting of amino acids, essential fats, simple sugars, minerals, and vitamins. Elemental diet therapy in certain conditions is established whereas the full scope of their usefulness has not yet been determined. Ch. II: Medical advances account for an increase in stress ulcer; its cause is unknown. Subnuclear swelling, cell membrane rupture, and lifting of the cell is the common response of the epithelial cell to microcirculatory changes, and may he explained by epithelial cell polarity. Ch. III A: The porcine stomach resembles that of man and lends itself well to the study of stress ulcer. Ch. III B: Prefeeding elemental diet protects pigs against stress ulcer formation. Pyloric ligation has no effect. Ch. IV: Elemental diet has been used in 20 patients to treat trauma, fistulae, enteritides, short gut, pancreatitis, burns, and bowel preparation.</description><creator>Voitk, Andrus J.</creator><contributor>Wlodek, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Studies in the use of an element diet: with special reference to the prevention of stress ulcers in the pig; and its clinical value in patients</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cf07n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xw05x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214s32v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is an introduction to the ideas and attitudes of some of the women who participated in the Canadian campaign for woman's suffrage. The first chapter outlines briefly the activities of the suffragists and examines the reaction to the suffrage question of two representative women's organizations. Chapter II contains the arguments for and against woman's suffrage together with an ideological study of these arguments. The third chapter examines the suffragists' attitude toward the woman's role in society. Chapters IV and V deal with the suffragists’ tactics, the attitudes of their political allies, and the suffragists' reaction to World War 1. Al though the woman's cause in Canada attracted no widespread following, the suffragists' ideas represent an important segment of the intellectual history of the period (1890-1920).</description><creator>Bacchi-Ferraro, Carol L.</creator><contributor>Miller, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>History.</subject><title>The ideas of the Canadian suffragists, 1890-1920</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pg97q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214s32v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v8723</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Biotin deficiency has been shown to cause morphological aberrations in A. globiformis 425. Single compounds, such as oleic acid, linoleic acid, linolenic acid, Tween 80, aspartame, and oxalacetate, showed varying degrees of biotin-replacing activity, but none was able to restore the cell to normal growth. Comparative analysis of fatty acid composition indicated that biotin deficiency causes a shift in synthesis from anteiso to normal straight chain fatty acids. RNA, DNA, and protein accumulation were followed throughout the growth cycle. The RNA content per cell was reduced by the vitamin deficiency, however, the DNA per C.F.U. was maintained at a level comparable to that of the normal cell. Protein reached a final level 35% greater than the normal cell protein. It is probable that much of this material is comprised of structural proteins which would account for the morphological abnormalities which accompany biotin-depletion in this organism. Hydrolysates of cell wall material were analysed for amine sugar and amino acid contents. The abnormal cell was found to contain 13.4 times more ninhydrin-reacting material and 19.4 times more hexosamine per mg dry weight over the biotin-sufficient cell.</description><creator>Zyk, Brenda</creator><contributor>Chan, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Microbiology and Immunology.</subject><title>Some biochemical aspects of biotin deficiency in arthrobacter globiformis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xw066.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v8723</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hc90t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The toxic reaction which can occur when patients taking monoamine oxidase (MAO) inhibitors are given meperidine has never been satisfactorily explained. It is well known that MAO inhibitors elevate brain amines, and compounds such as morphine and meperidine have also been shown to affect these agents. It therefore appeared reasonable that the interaction between phenelzine and meperidine might be linked to their combined effect on one or more of these amines. Male Sprague-Dawley rats were treated with phenelzine or meperidine, killed by immersion in liquid nitrogen, and the frozen brains were removed and analysed for 5-hydroxytryptamine, noradrenaline and dopamine. Phenelzine (10 to 50 mg/kg) elevated all three amines, with a maximum change at six hours following administration. The effects of meperidine (15 to 50 mg/kg) were less striking. It had no significant effect on brain levels of noradrenaline, and tended to slightly increase levels of dopamine and lower those of 5-hydroxytryptamine. When a low dose of meperidine (15 mg/kg) was given to rats pretreated with phenelzine (25 mg/kg), brain levels of all three amines were significantly different from those in rats receiving phenelzine alone. Both catecholamines were further elevated, with the most marked change in dopamine, while 5-hydroxytryptarnine levels decreased. The results of these experiments support the involvement of all three brain amines in the phenelzinemeperidine interaction.</description><creator>Zorychta, Edith A.</creator><contributor>Eade, N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Pharmacology.</subject><title>The interaction between monoamine oxidase inhibitors and meperidine</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z3977.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hc90t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cr56n413d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>(1) Dietary manipulation of thyroid function was shown to be associated with changes in the activity of adenyl cyclase and cyclic AMP phosphodiesterase that signify a rapid turn-over of cyclic AMP in the chronically stimulated gland and the reverse in the suppressed gland. Measurement of a fairly constant concentration of cyclic AMP in these circumstances further emphasized the physiological importance of turn-over rate rather than concentration of the nucleotide. (2) Acute enhancement of the concentration of cyclic AMP (after in vitro incubation with theophylline) in the mouse thyroid by intravenous injection of LATS or thyrotropin offers firm support for cyclic AMP's role as mediator of the action of both thyroid stimulators. (3) The subcellular distribution of adenyl cyclase in the homogenate of thyroids of the rat and other species was shown to differ but the inference to be drawn regarding cyto-structural variability is not known. (4) Various attempts in vitro and in vivo ta stimulate acutely rat thyroid adenyl cyclase were not met with striking success, further underlining the insensitivity of the rat thyroid to exogenous thyrotropin.</description><creator>Zakarija, Margita</creator><contributor>McKenzie, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Studies on the adenyl cyclase-cyclic AMP system in the thyroid glands of rats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hz69v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n413d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g158bm45z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The metabolism of free fatty acids in hemorrhagic and endotoxin shock was studied in a group of 93 mongrol dogs. The changes produced by norepinephrine and isoproterenol infusions in the shock state were evaluated. The concentration of FFA in the plasma of dogs anesthetized after a 12-16 hour fast was 450 µEq/l. (range 150-1040 µEq/l). Norepinephrine and isoproterenol increase the plasma FFA concentration by mobilizing FFA from adipose tissue. A moderate hemorrhage increases the plasma FFA concentration, but a several hemorrhage produces no such increase. Catecholamine infusion during shock produces a hemodynamic response, but no metabolic response. Endotoxin injection produces a fall in B.P. and C.O., and a gradual elevation in plasma FFA. Norepinephrine has a minimal effect after endotoxin injection. The half life of palmitic acid-1-C14 in the plasma before and after endotoxin injection was 2.00 and 2.75 minutes respectively. Other studies evaluated changes in FFA concentration across the heart, liver, and adipose tissue.</description><creator>Young, Jerrold Y.</creator><contributor>Sheiner, N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>The metabolism of free fatty acids by the hemorrhagic and endotoxic shock in dogs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354j37m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bm45z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):10675</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>