<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:37:46Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):38725" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21th289</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le facteur onconécrosant de tumeur (TNF) est une cytokine                inflammatoire qui joue un rôle important pour combattre diverses infections. La                dérégulation de TNF peut cependant entraîner une inflammation non-contrôlée qui est à                l'origine de diverses conditions pathologiques. L'expression de TNF est donc                fortement régulé aux niveaux transcriptionnels et post-transcriptionnels. Les AREs                (éléments riches en adénine\uridine) qui sont présents dans la région 3' non-traduite                de l'ARNm de TNF sont reconnus pour leur capacité à stimuler rapidement la                dégradation de ces ARNm. Plusieurs protéines se liant aux AREs ont la capacité de                médier ce processus. Nous avons identifié une nouvelle protéine, FXR1P (Fragile                X-related protein 1) capable de se lier à l'ARE de l'ARNm de TNF. L'utilisation d'une                lignée cellulaire de type macrophage provenant de souris où le gène Fxr1 est inactivé                a résulté en une expression plus élevée de la protéine TNF sans affecter les niveaux                d'ARNm ni la stabilité de ceux-ci. L'analyse de polyribosomes a démontré que l'ARNm                de TNF est associé de façon préférentielle avec les fractions lourdes des                polyribosomes dans les macrophages FXR1-KO. Ceci indique un rôle de répression de la                traduction de l'ARNm de TNF pour FXR1P. Nous avons par la suite définie le rôle de                FXR1P lors de l'induction de TNF par les ligands de TLR (récepteur ressemblant à                Toll) autres que LPS. Les effets de S28463 (TLR7-L) et de CpG (TLR9-L) ont été testé                parce qu'ils possèdent des propriétés thérapeutiques potentielles. La stimulation                avec S28463 n'a pas entrainé de différence d'expression de TNF entre les macrophages                FXR1-KO et FXR1-WT.</description><description>Tumor necrosis factor (TNF) is a key inflammatory cytokine that plays a                major role in combating infections. Its dysregulation, however, can lead to                uncontrolled inflammation which may cause deleterious conditions such as septic                shock. Therefore, the expression of TNF is tightly regulated at both the                transcriptional and post-transcriptional level. AU-rich elements, present in the                3'-untranslated region of TNF mRNA, are primarily known for their ability to                stimulate rapid mRNA decay. ARE-binding proteins such as TTP and AUF-1 mediate this                process. We have identified a new protein, Fragile X-related protein 1 (FXR1P), which                binds to the ARE of TNF mRNA. The generation of a macrophage cell line, in which the                Fxr1 gene is ablated, resulted in higher expression of TNF protein without affecting                TNF mRNA steady state level or stability. Analysis of polysomes showed that TNF mRNA                was associated preferentially with heavy polysome fractions in macrophages cell lines                derived from FXR1P knockout mice, indicating a translational repressor role for                FXR1P. We next defined the role of FXR1P in TNF induction by Toll-like receptor (TLR)                ligands other than LPS (a TLR4 ligand). The effects of S28463, a synthetic TLR7                ligand, and CpG, a TLR9 ligand, were tested as they have potential clinical                therapeutic properties. FXR1P ablation in macrophages did not alter TNF expression                compared with wildtype macrophages stimulated with S28463. However, FXR1P-deficient                macrophages stimulated with CpG had significantly higher TNF secretion than wildtype                cells. Although CpG-stimulated FXR1P-KO cells had higher TNF mRNA steady state                levels, no difference in TNF mRNA stability was observed compared with wil</description><creator>Lachance, Claude</creator><contributor>Danuta Radzioch (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Role of Fragile X-related protein 1 in controlling the expression of TNF and other pro-inflammatory cytokines and chemokines</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fj91d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21th289</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1c18dh59v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis offers evidence that phases (Chomsky 1995) induce                word-internal cycles of morphological and phonological interpretation. Phases                proposed in the syntactic literature are shown to have effects word-internally,                therefore supporting a representational theory of morpho-phonology (e.g. Distributed                Morphology (Halle &amp; Marantz 1994)). It is argued that phases exist at the nP,                aP, vP, vP, DP, and CP syntactic levels. These phases are shown to have differing                behaviour with regards to the domain which is sent to PF upon merger of the phase                head. DP, CP, and vP are argued to be complement spellout phases following Nissenbaum                (2000). nP, aP, and vP, however, offer evidence that the head of a phase is                interpreted at PF with its complement. A possible motivation for this difference in                interpretation domain is discussed. It is in derivations where syntactic material                spans one (or more) of these boundaries that cyclic domains may be found within words                at PF. Phonological and morpho-syntactic patterns induced by wordinternal phases are                investigated. Main stress patterns in Cupeño, Turkish, and Ojibwa are analysed.                Turkish and Cupeño seemingly irregular main stress patterns are argued to be regular                at the phase level. Main stress is assigned in these languages at the interpretation                of the first phase. In other words, main stress is cyclic and immovable in these                languages. Ojibwa main stress assignment is then shown to be insensitive to                word-internal phase boundaries. Word internal phases are present in Ojibwa, as                demonstrated by hiatus resolution strategies and footing patterns in the language                (Piggott &amp; Newell 2007). Main stress is assigned to the word, regardless of</description><description>Cette thèse présente des données qui montrent que les                phases (Chomsky 1995) provoquent des cycles d'interprétation morphologique et                phonologique internes au mot. Les phases proposées dans la littérature syntaxique ont                des effets internes aux mots, représentant ainsi une théorie morpho-phonologique                (c.à.d. une morphologie distribuée (Halle &amp; Marantz 1994)). On propose que                les syntagmes existent aux niveaux syntaxiques nP, aP, vP, DP, et CP. Il est démontré                que ces syntagmes se comportent différemment selon le domaine envoyé à PF au cours de                la fusion du syntagme de tête. On montre que DP, CP, et vP sont des syntagmes                compléments spellout d'après Nissenbaum (2000). Cependant, nP, aP, et vP montrent que                la tête d'un syntagme est interprétée avec son complément à PF. Une raison possible                de cette différence dans le domaine d'interprétation est proposée. C'est dans les                dérivations où le matériel syntaxique s'étend sur une (ou plusieurs) de ces                frontières que l'on peut trouver des domaines cycliques internes aux mots à PF. Les                structures phonologiques et morpho-syntactiques provoquées par les syntagmes internes                aux mots sont explorées. Les structures relatives au stress majeur en cupeño, turc,                et ojibwa sont analysées. Il est proposé que les structures de stress majeur                apparemment irrégulières en turc et en cupeño sont régulières au niveau du syntagme.                Dans ces langues, le stress majeur est assigné au niveau de l'interprétation du                premier syntagme. Autrement dit, dans ces langues le stress majeur est cyclique et                fixe. On montre ensuite que l'assignement du stress majeur en ojibwa est insensible                aux frontières des syntagmes internes</description><creator>Newell, Heather</creator><contributor>Glyne L Piggott (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Language - Linguistics</subject><title>Aspects of the morphology and phonology of phases</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xt59t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dh59v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720f70z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Syndromic surveillance has emerged as a novel, automated approach to                monitoring diseases using pre-diagnostic but often non-specific data sources.                However, there is little consensus about the best data sources. Using physician                billing data from community-based care settings and emergency departments in Quebec,                Canada during 1998-2003, we evaluated the lead-lag relationship between ambulatory                medical visits for influenza-like illnesses (ILI) and pneumonia and influenza                (P&amp; I) hospitalizations by age-group, visit setting, and influenza season. To                do so, we applied ARIMA modeling methodology and computed the cross-correlation                function (CCF) using the residuals. ILI visits in community settings by children aged                5-17 years tended to provide the greatest lead times (at least 2 but up to 3 weeks)                over P&amp;I hospitalizations. Lead times varied each season, possibly due to the                circulation of different strains each season. These findings have important                implications for syndromic surveillance of influenza, as well as epidemic control                strategies such as vaccination and school closure policies.</description><description>La surveillance syndromique a émergé comme une nouvelle                approche automatisée pour le contrôle des maladies avec des sources de données                pré-diagnostic, mais qui sont souvent non-spécifiques. Pourtant, il y a peu de                consensus concernant les meilleures sources de données. En utilisant des factures                médicales émises entre 1998 et 2003, et provenant de centres communautaire et de                services d'urgence au Québec, Canada, nous avons évalué par tranche d'âge, le cadre                des visites, et la saison de la grippe la relation d'avance-décalage entre les                visites médicales ambulatoires pour le syndrome d'allure grippale (SAG) et les                hospitalisations pour la pneumonie et la grippe. Pour ce faire, nous avons appliqué                la méthodologie des modèles d'ARIMA et calculé la fonction de contre-corrélation                (CCF) avec les résidus. Les visites communautaires reliée au SAG par des enfants âgés                de 5-17 ans ont eu tendance à pourvoir les plus grandes avances (au moins 2 semaines,                mais quelques fois jusqu'à 3 semaines) contre des hospitalisations pour la pneumonie                et la grippe. Les avances ont varié chaque année, peut-être à cause de la circulation                des souches différentes chaque saison. Ces résultats ont des implications importantes                pour la surveillance syndromique de la grippe, ainsi que pour des stratégies de lutte                contre l'épidémie, comme la vaccination et la fermeture d'écoles.</description><creator>Chan, Emily</creator><contributor>David Buckeridge (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Robyn Tamblyn (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</subject><title>Evaluating the use of physician billing data for age and setting specific influenza surveillance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53wx65q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720f70z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2r36v0397</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'objectif de ce projet est de développer une procédure                d'évaluation dosimétrique intra-opératoire en implantation prostatique de grains                d'iode 125. Pour y arriver, la position 3D des grains doit être reconstruite et                recalée avec les contours de la prostate imagée en échographie endorectale. La                reconstruction des grains est basée sur une technique de tomosynthèse requérant 7                projections acquises entre -30o et 30o. Le recalage entre la position 3D des grains                et les contours utilise comme cible la position planifiée des grains. Notre technique                de reconstruction dosimétrique a été testée sur un mannequin et dans une étude                clinique incluant 25 patients. Notre méthode permet de reconstruire la position 3D                des grains avec une précision de 0.4 ± 0.4 mm. De plus, l'étude clinique a démontré                un taux de détection de 96.7% des grains et incluant moins de 2.6% de faux-positifs.                La méthode de recalage n'a pas permis d'atteindre une précision acceptable pour une                application clinique. La technique développée permet de repérer la présence de                sous-dosage considérable et ouvre la porte vers la réimplantation de grains                additionnels afin d'améliorer la couverture dosimétrique de la prostate.</description><description>The aim of this study is to develop an intraoperative dose assessment                procedure that can be performed after an I-125 prostate seed implantation, while the                patient is still under anaesthesia. To accomplish this, we reconstruct the 3D                position of each seed and co-register it with the prostate contour acquired with a                transrectal ultrasound (TRUS) probe. Our seed detection method involves a                tomosynthesis-based filtered reconstruction of the volume of interest requiring 7                projections acquired over an angle of 60o with an isocentric imaging system. The                co-registration between the tomosynthesis-based seed positions and the TRUS-based                prostate contour is based on the planned position. A phantom and a clinical study (25                patients) were carried out to validate the technique. In the patient study, the                automatic tomosynthesis-based reconstruction yields a seed detection rate of 96.7%                and less than 2.6% false-positive. The seed localization error obtained with a                phantom study is 0.4 ± 0.4 mm. The co-registration method based on planned seed                position has proved to be not accurate enough for dosimetric purposes. We believe                that this technique may be used to discover considerable underdosage and to improve                the dosimetric coverage by potentially reimplanting additional seeds.</description><creator>Brunet-Benkhoucha, Malik</creator><contributor>Frans Verhaegen (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Jean-François Carrier (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Physics - Radiation</subject><title>Tomosynthesis-based intraoperative dosimetry for low dose rate prostate brachytherapy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j3334229.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36v0397</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Medical Physics Unit</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150k92j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Eradication of invasive species is an eminent concept in conservation                biology. After prevention is no longer an option, many ecologists argue that                eradication is the most effective way to mitigate the risk of impacts from invasive                species, given the elevated costs and often prolonged environmental effects of                long-term control strategies. In the majority of systems, eradication is most likely                to succeed early in the invasion process, when an invader is localized. However,                rarely is early eradication considered in practice. This paradox may result from the                many uncertainties regarding the future spread and impacts of novel invaders and                managers lacking practical guidance to make logical decisions to manage them. In this                thesis, I use a case study of an introduced mud crab, Rhithropanopeus harrisii, to                propose guidelines for rapidly assessing and communicating the feasibility and the                benefits of early eradication. First, I document the recent discovery of an                established population of R. harrisii in the Panama Canal, highlighting how maritime                traffic in this hub of international shipping may further increase the spread of this                invader worldwide. Second, I evaluate the distribution, abundance, and demographics                of R. harrisii across the Panama Canal with a standardized quantitative survey; I                also assess the crab's potential for spread beyond its distribution in the Canal with                two laboratory experiments. Third, I develop an analytical framework for evaluating                the feasibility of a rapid response to eradicate R. harrisii and for communicating                the potential benefits of this management strategy to decision-makers. My results                indicate that R. harrisii currently occupies a limited</description><description>L'éradication d'espèces introduites invasives est un                concept populaire dans le domaine de la biologie de la conservation. Lorsque la                prévention d'une invasion échoue, de nombreux écologistes soutiennent que                l'éradication est la méthode la plus efficace afin d'éviter que les espèces                introduites ne causent de dommages, considérant les coûts élevés et les effets                parfois prolongés du contrôle à long-terme. Notamment, dans la majorité des systèmes,                le succès d'un programme d'éradication est supérieur s'il est entrepris tôt lors du                processus d'envahissement, lorsqu'une espèce est peu dispersée. Cependant, cette                stratégie qui consiste à éradiquer les espèces introduites de façon hâtive est                rarement mise en pratique. Ce paradoxe peut résulter d'un haut niveau d'incertitude                concernant le potentiel qu'ont les espèces nouvellement introduites à se propager et                à causer des impacts, et par le fait que les administrateurs responsables de leur                gestion manquent souvent de conseils pratiques afin de réagir promptement suite à                leur découverte. Pour remédier à cette lacune, cette thèse se base sur une importante                étude de cas et suggère un modèle théorique servant à analyser de façon rapide la                possibilité d'implémenter un programme d'éradication hâtif et d'en évaluer les                bénéfices. Premièrement, je documente la découverte récente du crabe Rhithropanopeus                harrisii dans le Canal de Panama. Le Canal de Panama est une plaque tournante du                trafic maritime international et pourrait jouer un rôle important dans                l'accroissement de la propagation de R. harrisii au niveau mondial. Deuxièmement, au                moyen d'un échantillonnage quantitatif stand</description><creator>Roche, Dominique</creator><contributor>Brian Leung (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Mark Torchin (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Ecology</subject><title>Discovery, distribution, and eradication potential of the introduced mud crab, «Rhithropanopeus harrisii», in the Panama Canal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79408004r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150k92j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892c687</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The tent caterpillar, Malacosoma disstria, a major pest insect of North                American arboreal forests, has not been extensively studied in terms of the innate                blood cell (hemocyte) responses to bacterial antigens. Herein, physico-chemical                factors and signaling enzymes affecting the adhesion of fifth instar larval M.                disstria hemocytes to slides were determined. Maximum adhesion of the hemocyte types,                the granular cells and plasmatocytes, occurred at pH 6.0-7.0 and 6.0, respectively,                in phosphate-buffered saline (PBS). Activated protein kinases A and C inhibited                hemocyte adhesion. Dead, Gram-negative, entomopathogenic Xenorhabdus nematophila and                non-pathogenic Gram- positive Bacillus subtilis exhibited differential binding to                different hemocyte types altering patterns in phenoloxidase and lysozyme activities.                The plasma protein, apolipophorin-III, limited hemocyte responses. However, initial                binding of the protein to X. nematophila and B. subtilis increased granular cell                levels and lowered plasmatocytes levels with bacteria. Injections of the protein                spontaneously activated phenoloxidase. The protein delayed bacterial removal from                (blood) hemolymph in vivo. Surface antigens of X. nematophila and B. subtilis                participated in hemocyte reactions. X.nematophila endotoxin and its lipid A moiety                elevated damaged hemocyte levels limiting X. nematophila removal from the hemolymph.                Endotoxin and lipid A inhibited phenoloxidase activation but enhanced enzyme                activity. B. subtilis lipoteichoic acid elicited nodulation and enhanced                phenoloxidase activation and/or activity. Apolipophorin-III neutralized the effects                of the three surface antigens on hemocytes and prophenoloxidase until the</description><description>La livrée des forêts, Malacosoma disstria, un insecte qui                est une peste majeure des forêts de l'Amérique du Nord, n'a pas été examinée de façon                approfondie dans les réponses de ses cellules du sang (hémocytes) face aux antigènes                bactériens. Dans cette étude, les facteurs physico-chimiques et la signalisation                enzymatique affectant l'adhésion sur lamelle des hémocytes de la larve du cinquième                stade M. disstria ont été étudiés. L' adhésion maximale des cellules sanguines, (plus                précisément) des cellules granulaires et des plasmocytes a lieu respectivement à un                pH 6.0-7.0 et 6.0 dans une solution phosphate saline (PBS). L'activation des                protéines kinases A et C entraîne une inhibition de l'adhésion des cellules                sanguines. L'utilisation de l' inactif entomopathogène Xenorhabdus nematophila                bactérie Gram-négative et du Bacillus subtilis, une bactérie Gram-positive                non-pathogène montre une liaison distincte aux différentes cellules sanguines à                laquelle on observe une modification du patron des activités de la phénoloxydase et                de la lysozyme. La protéine plasmatique, apolipoprotéine-III, restrinct la réponse                immunitaire des hémocytes. Cependant, la liaison initiale de la protéine aux                X.nematophila et B. subtilis augmente les niveaux des cellules granulaires et diminue                les niveaux des plasmocytes en présence des bactéries. In vivo, la protéine suspend                le déplacement bactérien de l'hémolymphe. Les antigènes de surface de X. nematophila                et B. subtilis participent aux réactions des hémocytes. L'endotoxine X.nematophila et                sa fraction lipide A altèrent les niveaux des hémocytes limitant le déplacement de X.                nematophila de l'hémo</description><creator>Giannoulis, Paschalis</creator><contributor>Donald F Niven (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Gary Brian Dunphy (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Entomology</subject><title>Interactions between larval «Malacosoma disstria» (Lepidoptera: Lasiocampidae) hemolymph and selected antigens</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n204098p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892c687</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj139385w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the development of a multicellular organism, the cell cycle must                be tightly regulated in order to ensure that cell division and growth are coordinated                with the ongoing cell fate specification and morphogenetic programs. Although the                molecular mechanisms that drive cell division are well understood, many of the                signaling pathways regulating their functions during development remain to be                discovered. The nematode Caenorhabditis elegans represents a unique model system to                investigate developmental regulation of the cell cycle since the division pattern of                its multiple lineages are invariant, allowing for easy detection of lineage defects                following modification of gene activity by means such as mutagenesis or RNAi. We                isolated mutations that affect the different cell cycles occurring in the intestinal                lineage in order to identify the developmental pathways that control their                stage-specific execution or transition. Our initial work focused on the                characterization of a stabilizing gain-of-function mutation in the cdc-25.1                phosphatase that triggers intestinal hyperplasia during embryogenesis. We found that                CDC-25.1 is targeted for degradation during a short developmental period by an SCF E3                ubiquitin ligase containing the F-box protein LIN-23/β-TrCP. To find regulators of                CDC-25.1 levels and/or function during embryogenesis, we performed a genetic modifier                screen of the cdc-25.1(gf)-dependent hyperplasia. Analysis of an intragenic                suppressor that destabilizes CDC-25.1 revealed that multiple cues control its                stability and turnover, so as to ensure timely coordination of intestinal cell                division with organogenesis. In addition, we found that one of the extragenic</description><description>Durant le développement d'un organisme multicellulaire, il                est primordial que le cycle cellulaire soit régulé de façon à ce que la division et                la croissance des cellules soient coordonnées avec les programmes de spécifications                cellulaires et de morphogenèse en cours. Bien que les mécanismes moléculaires                sous-jacents à la division cellulaire soient bien compris, il reste encore à                découvrir l'identité des voies de signalisation qui les régulent durant le                développement. Le nématode Caenorhabditis elegans représente un organisme modèle                idéal pour l'analyse de la régulation du cycle cellulaire durant le développement, dû                en majeure partie au mode de division invariable de ces multiples lignées                cellulaires. Cette caractéristique permet de détecter facilement des défauts de                divisions suite à la modification de l'activité génique par mutagenèse ou par                interférence d'ARN (RNAi). Nous avons isolé des mutations affectant les différents                types de cycles cellulaires présents dans la lignée intestinale de C. elegans, afin                d'identifier les voies de signalisation agissant durant les différentes périodes du                développement pour en contrôler l'exécution ou la transition. Notre recherche                initiale portait sur la caractérisation d'une mutation dominante stabilisant la                phosphatase CDC25.1 et donnant lieu à une hyperplasie intestinale durant                l'embryogenèse. Nous avons découvert que CDC-25.1 est dégradée durant une courte                période du développement par une ligase d'ubiquitine E3 de type SCF contenant la                protéine F-box LIN-23/β-TrCP. Afin de trouver des gènes régulant les niveaux et/ou la                fonction de CDC-25.1 durant l'embryogenèse, nous avons ef</description><creator>Hebeisen, Michaël</creator><contributor>Richard D W Roy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>From cells to organs: the developmental challenge of multicellular organisms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fj92p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139385w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hh63sx713</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nous étudions les contraintes qui peuvent être appliquées                sur deux paramètres cosmologiques en utilisant les observations du rayonnement de                fond cosmologique (CMB). Premièrement, nous développons une technique de contrainte                de la tension des cordes cosmiques, $G\mu$, en utilisant l'algorithme de détection                des contours Canny afin de détecter la signature de l'effet Kaiser-Stebbins dans les                cartes de température du CMB. Nous testons le potentiel de cette méthode avec des                cartes de la température du CMB simulées à haute résolution . En imitant les futures                données du projet South Pole Telescope, nous trouvons qu'une limite de                $G\mu&lt;5.5\times10^{-8}$ pourrait être imposée. Deuxièmement, dans le cadre du                modèle cosmologique d'un gaz de cordes, nous examinons la limite imposée par le CMB                sur un spectre des ondes gravitationnelles incliné vers le bleu. Nous trouvons que le                CMB ne peut fournir de contrainte plus stricte que celles provenant d'autres                observations, nommément la nucléosynthèse, qui impose déjà une limite de                $n_{T}\lesssim0.15$.</description><description>We investigate the constraints which can by applied on two different                cosmological parameters using observations of the cosmic microwave background (CMB).                First, we develop a method of constraining the cosmic string tension, $G\mu$, which                uses the Canny edge detection algorithm as a means of searching CMB temperature maps                for the signature of the Kaiser-Stebbins effect. We test the potential of this method                using high resolution, simulated CMB temperature maps. By imitating the future output                from the South Pole Telescope project, we find that a bound                $G\mu&lt;5.5\times10^{-8}$ could potentially be imposed. Second, motivated by the                string gas cosmological model, we examine the constraint levied by the CMB on a blue                tilted gravitational wave spectrum. We find that the CMB cannot provide a tighter                bound than those coming from other observations, the most stringent of which is                $n_{T}\lesssim0.15$ from nucleosynthesis.</description><creator>Stewart, Andrew</creator><contributor>Robert Brandenberger (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Physics - Astronomy and Astrophysics</subject><title>Constraining cosmological parameters with the cosmic microwave background</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj4306572.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sx713</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v735r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le droit, et a fortiori les juristes, ont horreur du vide                et du multiple. Le débat contemporain sur la « fragmentation » du droit international                en offre une illustration saillante. Cerné par les incertitudes, les paradoxes et les                contradictions de son droit, l'internationaliste fait montre d'un attachement quelque                peu artificiel et quasiment compulsif à l'idée d'unité de l'ordre juridique                international. Acceptée partout, ou presque, comme une évidence, cette idée-là mérite                pourtant un examen critique et réclame une élaboration théorique. Que signifie en                effet, pour le droit international, le fait d'être « Un » ? N'y a-t-il qu'une seule                façon de concevoir l'unité de l'ordre juridique international ? L'unité du droit                international est-elle simplement une affaire de normes, ou bien se joue-t-elle                également du côté des formes et des valeurs juridiques ? Cette unité est-elle                monocausale ou repose-t-elle sur un entrelacs complexe de dynamiques variées –                dynamiques déontiques, herméneutiques, éthiques ou culturelles ? A l'heure où la                fragmentation est en train de se constituer en question canonique de la discipline du                droit international, cette étude appelle à suspendre un temps le discours doctrinal                conventionnel et à tenir en suspicion le postulat d'unité. Tenir en suspicion ne veut                pas dire le récuser définitivement, mais simplement secouer la quiétude avec laquelle                on l'accepte, l'arracher à sa quasi-évidence, montrer qu'il ne va pas de soi et qu'il                n'est pas nécessairement ce qu'on croyait au premier regard. L'argument s'articule                autour d'une proposition centrale : le concept d'unité du droit, masqué par une                simplicité trompeu</description><description>Law and a fortiori lawyers despise emptiness and multiplicity, as                evidenced by the present-day debate on the so-called « fragmentation » of                international law. Surrounded by uncertainty, paradox and contradiction,                international law scholars show a somewhat artificial and quasi-compulsive attachment                to the unity of their law. Although it seems to be accepted all round as evident,                however, the idea of unity calls for a critical examination and a theoretical                elaboration. What does it mean for international law to be « One » ? Is there only                one way to conceive of international law's unity ? Is unity only about norms, or does                it also involve juridical forms and values ? Is unity monocausational or does it rest                on a complex nexus of different dynamics – whether deontic, hermeneutic, ethical or                cultural ? While fragmentation is becoming something of a canonical question in the                international law discipline, the present study is an invitation to suspend the                mainstream discourse on fragmentation and to put the postulate of unity on hold. To                put unity on hold does not mean to rebut or refute it indefinitely. Rather, it means                questioning the way in which it is accepted as an undisputed assumption, disquieting                the usage of this taken-for-granted concept, showing that it is not self-explanatory                and that unity might not necessarily be what we thought in the first place. The                argument revolves around one central claim about the unity of international law :                behind a seemingly simple and elementary concept lies a complex and multidimensional                problematic. The modern « technicians of unity » cut unity down to the binary laws of                conflicts of norms and jurisprudence. Against this, the</description><creator>Prost, Mario</creator><contributor>Rene Provost (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>Unitas multiplex - les unités du droit international et la politique de la fragmentation</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fq74z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v735r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53jz99w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS; aka Lou Gehrig Disease) is an                adult-onset, rapidly progressing motor neuron disease for which there is currently                very little treatment. Glutamate excitoxicity, formation of proteinaceous inclusions,                proteasome impairment, and mitochondrial dysfunction have been associated with both                sporadic and familial ALS, but there are many questions about how these events fit                together to cause motor neuron dysfunction and death. In culture models of familial                ALS due to mutations in the enzyme Cu/Zn-superoxide dismutase (SOD1), treatments that                reduce intracellular Ca2+ prolong viability and prevent formation of mutant SOD1                inclusions. Motor neurons are vulnerable to Ca2+ overload due to poor Ca2+ buffering                and high glutamatergic input. Thus, disruption of calcium homeostasis may play an                early and key role in ALS. The goal of this thesis was to investigate how levels of                Ca2+ in cytosol and calcium-buffering organelles (mitochondria and endoplasmic                reticulum) change in motor neurons in an experimental model of ALS and how these                changes relate to other hallmarks of ALS pathogenesis (impaired mitochondrial and                proteasome function). To achieve this goal, ALS-causing G93A-SOD1 was expressed in                motor neurons of dissociated murine spinal cord-dorsal root ganglia cultures. Using                microfluorometric techniques, increases in mitochondrial Ca2+ ([Ca2+]m) and                endoplasmic reticular Ca2+ ([Ca2+]ER) were observed prior to an increase in cytosolic                Ca2+ ([Ca2+]c). Decrease in mitochondrial membrane potential and rounding of their                shape was observed concomitant with the early increase in [Ca2+]m. A further increase                in [Ca2+]c was observed in motor neurons with mutant</description><description>La sclérose latérale amyotrophique (SLA, alias la maladie                de Lou Gehrig) est une maladie neuromusculaire à évolution rapide qui commence à                l'âge adulte, et pour laquelle il existe présentement très peu de traitements.                L'excitotoxicité du glutamate, la formation d'inclusions protéiques, la déficience du                protéasome et le dysfonctionnement mitochondrial ont tous été associés à la SLA                sporadique et héréditaire, mais on se questionne toujours sur ce qui rassemble ces                éléments qui, ensemble, mènent au dysfonctionnement neuromusculaire et au décès. Dans                les modèles de culture de SLA héréditaire causée par des mutations de l'enzyme                Cu/Zn-superoxyde dismutase (SOD1), les traitements réduisant le Ca2+ intra-cellulaire                prolongent la viabilité et empêchent la formation d'inclusions mutantes de la SOD1.                Les motoneurones sont vulnérables aux surcharges de Ca2+ causées par une régulation                du Ca2+ inadéquate et par un grand apport glutamatergique. Ainsi, la perturbation de                l'homéostasie du calcium joue peut-être un rôle précoce important dans la SLA. Le but                de cette thèse était d'enquêter sur la façon dont les niveaux de Ca2+ à l'intérieur                des organites assurant la régulation du cytosol et du calcium (mitochondrie et                réticulum endoplasmique) changent dans les motoneurones d'un modèle expérimental de                la SLA, ainsi que sur la façon dont ces changements sont liés à d'autres marques de                pathogénie de la SLA (détérioration du fonctionnement mitochondrial et du                protéasome). Afin d'atteindre cet objectif, la G93A-SOD1 causant la SLA a été                introduite dans les cultures de motoneurones provenant de neurones ganglions de la                racine dorsale mu</description><creator>Tradewell, Miranda Lee</creator><contributor>Heather D Durham (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience</subject><title>The central role of calcium dysregulation in a primary cell culture model of amyotrophic lateral sclerosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967550q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53jz99w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:736666383</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>ABSTRACT The present project provides information on the nutritional                health of James Bay Cree children and youth who have been deeply affected by                nutrition transition and are now at risk for overweight and poor diet quality. The                current thesis found that 63.2% of the Cree youth aged 9 to 18 years old were at risk                of overweight while 47.2% were overweight. Almost all of the participants reported                consuming high-sugar and high-fat foods which accounted for 12.8% and 40% of their                total energy intake respectively. Furthermore, all youth had notably lower fruit and                vegetable and milk and milk product consumption than recommended. Traditional food                consumption was low. However, youth who consumed traditional food at least once a                week had a significantly lower BMI percentile and a higher fruit and vegetable intake                than those who consumed traditional food less frequently. The findings highlight the                urgent need for dietary interventions among Cree youth. It is hoped the project will                build awareness and capacity to effectively deal with the obesity epidemic in Cree                communities and also be of value to other communities affected by this global obesity                epidemic-recently referred to as "globesity" by the WHO.</description><description>RÉSUMÉ Cette étude vise principalement à souligner les                problèmes nutritionnels auxquels font face les Cree de la Baie James qui souffrent                aujourd'hui d'un taux élevé de surpoids et qui ont été profondément affecté par les                changements qu'ont subis les conditions de vie, notamment en matière d'alimentation                et l'accès aux biens de consommation. Les résultats du projet suivant montrent que                63.2% des Jeunes Cree âgés entre 9 et 18 ans se sont avérés en risque de surpoids                tandis que 47.2% souffrent de surpoids. Environ tous les participants ont affirmé                avoir consommé des aliments riche en sucre et en gras, qui représentent                respectivement 12.8% et 40% de leur énergie totale. D'ailleurs tous les jeunes ont                généralement une consommation de fruits et légumes et lait et produits laitiers plus                faible que celle recommandée. La consommation d'aliments traditionnels est en                générale faible. Néanmoins, les jeunes qui ont consommé au moins 1 aliment                traditionnel par semaine ont en moyenne un BMI percentile plus bas et ont démontré                une consommation plus élevée de fruits et légumes. Ces conduites appellent au besoin                urgent d'interventions nutritionnelles a l'égard des Jeunes Cree. Il est espéré que                ce projet va alerter les gens au sujet de surpoids et mieux guider les interventions                pour combattre l'obésité dans les communautés Cree ainsi que dans les autres                communautés affectées par l'épidémie d'obésité.</description><creator>Bou Khalil, Cynthia</creator><contributor>Grace Egeland Hovda (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health Sciences - Nutrition</subject><title>Emerging obesity and dietary habits among James Bay Cree youth: 3 communities</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569627b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/736666383</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558g040</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research is based on the hypothesis that by permanently                immobilizing Fibronectin (FN) on a metal substrate surface, it will be possible to                enhance endothelial cells (EC)/surface interactions. FN was covalently bound onto                self assembled monolayers (SAMs) modified gold surfaces with COOH terminal groups.                SAMs composed of various surface ratios of X/COOH (X=CH3, OH, NH2) were formed in                order to control the surface conformation of FN by modulating the surface charge                (potential) and wettability. Human umbilical vein endothelial cell (HUVEC) attachment                and proliferation onto such surfaces was investigated. Results have shown that SAM                and SAM-protein surfaces are stable with time. An increased HUVEC attachment and                proliferation was obtained on FN-free SAMs compared to a bare Au surface. However,                the presence of covalently bound FN on the SAM surface further significantly enhanced                EC attachment and proliferation rate. The optimum surface for the HUVEC attachment                and proliferation was found to be the NH2/COOH surface, which is positively charged                and hydrophilic.</description><description>Cette recherche est basée sur l'hypothèse qu'en                immobilisant la protéine Fibronectin (FN) sur une surface métallique, il serait                possible d'améliorer les interactions entre les cellules endothéliales et la surface.                Un lien covalent a été fait entre FN et le group terminal de COOH apparentant à une                couche unitaire de molécules assemblées (CUMA) sur une surface en or. Les CUMAs                étaient composés de plusieurs fraction des groupes terminales X/COOH (X=CH3, OH, NH2)                dans le but de modifier la charge et l'hydrophobicité sur la surface afin de                contrôler la conformation de FN. L'attachement et la prolifération des cellules                provenant d'une veine ombilicale humaine (CVOH) furent investigué sur ces surfaces.                Les résultats démontrent que les surfaces constitués de CUMA et CUMA-protéine sont                stables avec le temps. Les surfaces CUMA-FN ont éprouvé plus d'activités cellulaires                comparées aux surfaces de CUMA. Ces derniers étés plus avantageux que les surfaces                d'or. Les surfaces composées des groups NH2/COOH, qui étés de nature chargée et                hydrophilique ont obtenu le plus haut niveau d'activités cellulaires.</description><creator>Afara, Nadia</creator><contributor>Sasha Omanovic (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Biomedical</subject><title>Modification of a gold surface with mixed alkanethiol self-assembled monolayers and fibronectin: design of surfaces for controlled cell/surface interactions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s2008.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558g040</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nj988</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The genus Mycobacterium is best recognized for its pathogens M.                tuberculosis and M. leprae, the etiologic agents of Tuberculosis and Leprosy.                Sequencing of their genomes has revealed an evolutionary process of reductive                genomics. Another common species, the M. avium complex (MAC), consists of both                environmental isolates that can cause opportunistic infection in humans as well as                pathogenic isolates that cause disease primarily in birds and livestock. The basis of                this variation in disease phenotypes is unknown. Two genome sequences representing a                pathogen of cattle, M. avium subsp. paratuberculosis (MAP) and an opportunistic                isolate from a human (M. avium subsp. hominissuis) have served as the foundation for                the comparative genomics of MAC. This is complicated by a level of genetic                variability one log greater than found within the M. tuberculosis complex (MTBC), and                by the existence of other MAC subsets beyond the two sequenced strains. In this                thesis, I set out to define the phylogenetic relationships of the various members of                MAC and explore the evolutionary processes that led to the emergence of the                pathogenic species MAP. An identification scheme was developed to unambiguously brand                subsets of MAC, a tool lacking in the past thus hampering data interpretation.                Expansion to a multilocus sequence analysis (MLSA) system revealed that the MAC                consists of a highly variable group with most of the genotypes belonging to what is                considered to be the environmental subset. However, both the avian and MAP pathogens                manifested as two separate clones that have independently evolved from their larger                subset. The distribution and directionality (insertion or deletion) of large se</description><description>Le genre Mycobacterium est mieux reconnu pour ses espèces                pathogènes M. tuberculosis et M. leprae, les agents étiologiques de la tuberculose et                de la lèpre. Le séquençage de leur génome a indiqué un processus évolutionnaire de                réduction génomique. Des autres espèces communes, le complexe M. avium (MAC) est                composé de souches environnementales qui peuvent causer des infections opportunistes                chez l'homme aussi bien que de souches pathogènes qui causent la maladie                principalement chez les oiseaux et le bétail. La base de cette variation phénotypique                est inconnue. Deux séquences génomiques représentant le pathogène de bétail M. avium                subsp. paratuberculosis (MAP) et un isolat opportuniste d'humain (M. avium subsp.                hominissuis) ont servi de base pour la génomique comparative du MAC. Ceci est                compliqué par un niveau de variabilité génétique d'un ordre logarithmique plus grand                que celui qui se trouve dans le complexe de M. tuberculosis (MTBC), et par                l'existence d'autres sous-ensembles de MAC au-delà des deux souches séquençées. Dans                cette thèse, je cherche à définir les rapports phylogénétiques des divers membres du                MAC et à explorer les processus évolutionnaires qui ont mené à l'apparition de                l'espèce pathogène MAP. Une technique d'identification a été développée pour                déterminer clairement les sous-ensembles de MAC, un outil dont l'absence par le passé                limitait l'analyse des données. La possibilité d'utiliser un système d'analyse par                séquençage multi-locus (MLSA) a révélé que le MAC est composé d'un groupe hautement                variable avec la plus grande partie des génotypes appartenant à ce que l'on considère                comme étant le$</description><creator>Turenne, Christine</creator><contributor>Marcel A Behr (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Microbiology</subject><title>The evolution of the pathogen «Mycobacterium avium» subsp «paratuberculosis»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945s68h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nj988</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602269g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le taux d'obésité et des maladies liées à celle-ci                augmentent à une vitesse inquiétante. Aussi, la connaissance du mécanisme de                régulation de certaines hormones anaboliques et de leurs récepteurs dans le tissu                adipeux constitue une étape importante dans la compréhension du métabolisme                lipidique. Cette thèse a pour but (i) d'étudier l'impact du traitement hormonal                associé à la résistance à l'insuline et au métabolisme sur la régulation directe, in                vitro, de la visfatine et du C5L2 en utilisant des modèles de 3T3-L1 préadipocytes et                des adipocytes, et (ii) d'explorer, en utilisant des techniques de micro puces à ARN,                la régulation de plusieurs gènes impliqués dans la résistance à l'insuline et dans la                fonction de l'ASP, ex vivo, dans des tissus adipeux humains provenant de dépôts                sous-cutanés (SC) versus omental (OM) extraits de sujets minces et de sujets atteints                d'obésité morbide. Nos travaux ont démontré que le traitement à l'insuline, le TNFa,                la progestérone, l'oléate, le palmitate et le traitement au TZD rosiglitizone                régulent directement l'expression des ARNm de la visfatine dans les 3T3-L1                préadipocytes et/ou adipocytes. De plus, dans les tissus adipeux humains ex vivo,                nous avons noté une régulation préférentielle des gènes impliqués dans la                signalisation par l'insuline, surtout dans le tissu adipeu omental de sujets atteints                d'obésité morbide et ayant des taux d'insuline et de glucose relativement plus                élevés. Par contre, les changements touchant la signalisation ASP-C5L2 se trouvent                dans le tissu adipeux sous-cutané. Cette étude nous a permis de déterminer la                présence du C5L2 dans les tissus adipeux humains</description><description>Obesity and obesity related diseases are increasing at an alarming rate.                Elucidating the regulation of three anabolic hormones and their receptors in adipose                tissue is an important step to understanding adipose tissue metabolism. The aims of                this thesis are to (1) investigate the direct regulation of visfatin and C5L2 in                vitro using a 3T3-L1 preadipocyte and adipocyte model with hormone treatments related                to insulin resistance and metabolism and (2) investigate the regulation of multiple                genes related to insulin resistance and ASP function in ex vivo human adipose tissue                from SC vs OM depots in lean and morbidly obese subjects using a microarray                technique. We observe a direct regulation of visfatin mRNA in 3T3-L1 preadipocyte and                / or adipocytes by insulin, TNFa, progesterone, testosterone, oleate, palmitate, and                the TZD treatment rosiglitizone. Further, in human ex vivo adipose tissue we observe                a preferential regulation of insulin signaling genes in OM adipose tissue of morbidly                obese subjects with relativly higher insulin and glucose (IRO). In contrast, changes                in adipose tissue related to ASP-C5L2 metabolism are primarily in SC adipose tissue.                From the studies presented in this thesis we have determined that C5L2 is present in                human SC and OM adipose tissue, preadipocytes and adipocytes, and in all mouse                adipose depots. In the absence of C5L2, ASP does not stimulate TGS. Endogenous C5L2                is downregulated by TNFa and upregulated by a TZD treatment in vitro, and C5L2 is                upregulated ex vivo in a population of morbidly obese subjects with high ASP and high                TG. Further, in this same morbidly obese population a general trend for the                upregulation of anti-inflammatory genes</description><creator>MacLaren, Robin</creator><contributor>Katherine Cianflone (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Metabolic hormones and their receptors in obesity: Insulin, Visfatin, and ASP</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sm26h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602269g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:08612q485</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A series of fluorinated copolymers were prepared and used to fabricate                optical waveguides by photolithography. Reproducible syntheses were established for a                buffer material,                4-fluoro-styrene-co-pentafluoro-styrene-co-[4-styren-4'-yl-2,3,5,6-tetrafluorophenylether]                (bufTxx), and guiding material,                Styrene-co-penta-fluorostyrene-co-[4-styren-4'-yl-2,3,5,6-tetrafluorophenyl-ether]                (terTxx), as well as their precursors. The polymers were characterized by attenuated                total reflection Fourrier transform infrared spectroscopy (ATR FT-IR), gel permeation                chromatography (GPC), proton nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy (1H NMR), and                thermal analyses. Freestanding waveguide structures and multilayer buried waveguide                devices were prepared on silicon substrates. The guiding polymer behaved as a                negative resist, facilitating photoinitiated lithographic printing. These structures                were investigated by optical microscopy, field-emission gun scanning electron                microscopy (FEG SEM) and prism coupling analysis. A 632 nm HeNe laser was                successfully end-coupled to printed waveguide structures from an optical fiber.</description><description>Une série de copolymères fluorés a été préparée et                employée pour fabriquer des guides d'ondes optiques par photolithographie. Des                synthèses reproductibles ont été établies pour un matériel tampon, le                4-fluorostyrène-co-pentafluorostyrène-co-[4-(styrèn-4'-yl)-2,3,5,6-tétrafluorophényléther]                (bufTxx), pour le matériel de guidage, du                styrène-co-pentafluorostyrène-co-4-(styrèn-4'-yl)-2,3,5,6-tétra-fluoro-phényléther]                (terTxx), ainsi que leurs précurseurs. Les polymères ont été caractérisés par                spectroscopie infrarouge par transformé de Fourier de type réflexion totale atténué                (ATR FT-IR), par chromatographie sur gel perméable (GPC), par spectroscopie de                résonance magnétique nucléaire de proton (1H RMN), ainsi que par des analyses                thermiques. Des motifs de guides d'ondes indépendants et des dispositifs de guide                d'ondes à plusieurs couches ont été préparés sur des substrats de silicium. Le                polymère agissant comme guide d'ondes a des propriétés de résistances négatives,                facilitant une impression lithographique photoinitiée. Ces motifs ont été étudiés par                microscopie optique, par microscopie électronique de balayage utilisant un canon à                émission de champ (FEG SEM) et par analyse de couplage par prisme. Un laser de 632                nanomètres (HeNe) a été couplé avec succès aux motifs de guide d'ondes imprimées                d'une fibre optique.</description><creator>Maron, Elizabeth Sara</creator><contributor>Mark P Andrews (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Chemistry - General</subject><title>Fluorinated styrene polymers for optical waveguides</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544br271.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612q485</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj236395c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>B cells are becoming increasingly recognized as important immune                regulatory cells. Depending on their context of activation, the balance of B cell                production of proinflammatory and anti-inflammatory cytokines is affected. Recent                work has shown that Toll-like receptor (TLR) ligation is an important signal                affecting B cell activation. We sought to determine the effect that the combination                of antigen recognition, T cell help and TLR ligation would have on B cell response                profiles of both control donors and Multiple Sclerosis (MS) patients. We found that                TLR8 ligation resulted in enhanced B cell proliferation and survival combined with a                marked suppression of B cell effector cytokines. TLR9 ligation resulted in similar                enhancement in B cell proliferation that was combined with significantly increased                effector cytokine production. These findings highlight the importance of TLR ligation                on B cell activation and underscore the importance of understanding the effects of                TLR activation on B cell biology.</description><description>Les cellules B deviennent de plus en plus reconnues comme                étant des cellules immunorégulatrices importantes. Selon leur contexte d'activation,                l'équilibre entre les cytokines pro-inflammatoires et anti-inflammatoires produites                par les cellules B est affecté. Les travaux récents ont prouvé que l'activation des                récepteurs "Toll-like" (communément appelés Toll-like receptors ou TLR) est un signal                important affectant l'activation des cellules B. Nous avons cherché à determiner si                l'activation des TLR combinée à l'identification d'antigène et l'aide des cellules T                pouvait influencer les profils « effecteurs » des cellules B provenant de donneurs                contrôles et de patients atteints de la sclérose en plaques (SP). Nous avons constaté                que l'activation de TLR8 induit une augmentation de la prolifération et de la survie                des cellules B, associée à une suppression marquée des cytokines effectrices                sécrétées par les cellules B. L'activation de TLR9 a également induit une                augmentation de la prolifération des cellules B, associée à une production                sensiblement accrue de cytokines effectrices. Ces résultats accentuent l'important de                l'activation des TLR sur l'activation des cellules B et soulignet l'importance de                comprendre les effets de l'activation de TLR sur la biologies des cellules B.</description><creator>Rieger, Aja</creator><contributor>Amit Bar-Or (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health Sciences - Immunology</subject><title>Toll-like receptor modulation of disease relevant B cell responses</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q3370.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236395c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04dr411</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description> The eukaryotic Rho family of GTPases acts as central regulators of                numerous processes, including the polarization of cell morphology, membrane                transport, transcription, and MAPK pathway signaling. As GTPases, Rho proteins act as                molecular switches which, in the GTP-bound form, transduce upstream signals to a                variety of downstream effectors, thereby generating appropriate cellular responses.                As central nodes of signaling, they are subject to strict regulation, and the                regulation of the GTP-GDP cycle of Rho members has been well characterized. Rho                GTPases participate in a variety of pathways, though in many cases the mechanisms are                still poorly understood. This study examines the roles and regulation of two Rho                GTPases in Saccharomyces cerevisiae, Rho5p and Cdc42p. First, we describe the                regulation of Rho5p signaling by phosphorylation and ubiquitination, the first                instance of post-translational regulation of a yeast Rho-type GTPase. This regulation                is mediated by a module involving the Npr1p kinase and its inhibitor Msi1p. We also                identify Rgd2p as the RhoGAP for Rho5p in vivo, and demonstrate a genetic interaction                between RHO5 and STE50: a STE50 deletion combined with expression of an activated                RHO5 allele results in osmotic sensitivity. Next, we describe a role for Rho5p in the                activation of the cAMP-PKA pathway. Expression of an activated allele of RHO5                generates a number of phenotypes associated with activated cAMP-PKA pathway                signaling, and also suppresses the lethality of a strain deleted for two other                cAMP-PKA activators, Δras1 Δras2. A mechanism by which Rho5p may activate the pathway                is suggested by the observed two-hybrid interaction between Rho5p and adeny</description><description> La famille eucaryote des GTPases Rho agit à titre de                régulateur principal de nombreux processus biologiques, incluant la polarisation de                la morphologie cellulaire, le transport membranaire, la transcription et la voie de                signalisation MAPK. En tant que GTPases, les protéines Rho jouent un rôle de                controlleurs moleculaires qui, sous la forme liée au GTP, transmettent les signaux en                amont à une variété d'effecteurs en aval, générant ainsi les réponses cellulaires                appropriées. Étant des acteurs principaux de la signalisation, les protéines Rho sont                sujettes à une régulation précise. La régulation du cycle GTP-GDP par les membres de                la famille Rho a été largement caractérisée. Cependant, les GTPases Rho participent à                une variété de mécanismes qui, dans plusieurs cas, sont encore aujourd'hui                sous-étudiés. Cette étude examine plus particulièrement les rôles et la régulation de                deux GTPases Rho chez la levure Saccharomyces cerevisiae, Rho5p and Cdc42p. Dans un                premier temps, nous décrivons la régulation de la signalisation de Rho5p par la                phosphorylation et l'ubiquitination, ceci étant le premier exemple de régulation                post-traductionnelle d'une GTPase de type Rho chez la levure. Cette régulation est                arbitrée par un module impliquant la kinase Npr1p et son inhibiteur MSi1p. Nous                démontrons également une interaction génétique entre RHO5 et STE50. En effet, une                délétion au niveau de STE50 combinée à l'expression d'un allèle activé de RHO5                résulte en une sensibilité osmotique. De plus, nous identifions Rgd2p comme étant le                RhoGAP pour Rho5p in vivo. Dans un deuxième temps, nous décrivons un rôle pour Rho5p                dans l'activation d</description><creator>Annan, Robert Bruce</creator><contributor>David Thomas (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Cell</subject><title>Roles and regulation of «Saccharomyces cerevisiae» Rho-type GTPases Rho5p and Cdc42p</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78td928.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dr411</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773x55v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis reports on the design, analysis and optimization of an                accelerometer. This accelerometer is designed as a monolithic structure along the                concept of compliant mechanisms. An elastodynamic analysis is performed on the                compliant mechanism to asses the performance of the inertial sensor. This thesis                proposes an innovative compliant hinge intended to stiffen the struc- ture of                compliant mechanisms. In addition, a procedure for the optimum design of this new                hinge is discussed. The structural optimization problem is approached by coupling a                finite element model to an optimization algorithm. A procedure is devel- oped to                generate the mesh at each optimization step according to the values of the design                parameters provided by the optimization algorithm. The objective function to minimize                is the stress concentration in a hinge loaded under bending. The last chapter focuses                on the multi-objective optimization of the compliant- mechanism accelerometer. The                Pareto method is used to optimally design the ac- celerometer. The purpose is to                maximize the sensitivity of the accelerometer in its sensing direction, while                minimizing its sensitivity in all other directions. The a poste- riori                multi-objective optimization is formulated. By using the normalized normal                constrained method (NNCM), an even distribution of the Pareto frontier is found. The                work also provides several optimum solutions of the Pareto plot as well as the CAD                model of the selected solution.</description><description>Une large gamme d'accéléromètres est offerte sur le                marché. Cependant, la plupart des architectures de capteurs inertiels offerts par                l'industrie sont constituées d'une masse suspendue par une poutre encastrée. Avec les                années, les chercheurs ont mis au point des architectures parallèles offrant une bien                meilleure rigidité qu'une simple poutre encastrée. Les accéléromètres à architecture                parallèle offrent également de bien meilleures rigidités. Cette thèse porte sur la                conception, l'analyse et l'optimisation d'un accéléromètre à architecture parallèle.                Tout d'abord, l'accéléromètre est réalisé comme structure monolithique dans le cadre                des mécanismes flexibles. Par la suite, une analyse elasto-dynamique est effectuée                sur le mécanisme flexible afin de d'´evaluer les performances du capteur inertiel.                Cette thèse propose également une nouvelle articulation flexible visant à améliorer                la structure des mécanismes flexibles. Une procédure optimisant le profil de cette                nouvelle articulation flexible est également proposée. Le problème d'optimisation                structurelle est abordé en établissant une boucle entre un modèle par éléments finis                et un algorithme d'optimisation. Une procédure a été développée afin de générer le                maillage à chaque étape d'optimisation en fonction des valeurs des paramètres de                conception fournis par l'algorithme d'optimisation. La fonction cible à minimiser est                définie comme la concentration de contrainte générée dans l'articulation flexible                sollicitée en flexion. Le dernier chapitre de la thèse met l'accent sur                l'optimisation multi-objectif du mécanisme flexible de l'accéléromètre. La méthode</description><creator>Desrochers, Simon</creator><contributor>Damiano Pasini (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Jorge Angeles (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical</subject><title>Optimum design of simplicial uniaxial accelerometers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515q232.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773x55v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vm81r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description> L'objectif de cette thèse est d'obtenir le peak scatter                factor (PSF) de faisceaux de photons de 6 et 18 MV. Les champs utilisés étaient de                10x10 cm^2 et les mesures furent effectuées à l'aide d'un fantôme de Solid Water tm                couplé à des capuchons d'accumulation fait de Lucite tm, d'aluminium, de laiton et de                cuivre. Le PSF du champ de 10x10cm2 a été déterminé en extrapolant le peak scatter                factor normalisé (NPSF) d'un champ de 0x0cm2. Le NPSF extrapolé correspond à la                réciproque du PSF(10,hv). Le PSF(10, hv) fut ensuite comparé à celui déterminé à                l'aide de méthodes Monte Carlo. Les méthodes Monte Carlo furent utilisées pour                étudier la dépendance entre le signal mesuré et le matériel du capuchon                d'accumulation. Ceci fut accompli en décomposant le signal provenant de la cavité de                la chambre d'ionisation en dose primaire et diffusée. Un facteur liant le PSF et les                mesures fut calculé à l'aide d'études Monte Carlo.</description><description> The purpose of this thesis is to measure the peak scatter factors                (PSFs) for a 10X10 cm2 field size in 6 MV and 18 MV photon beams using a Solid                WaterTM phantom and build-up caps made of LuciteTM, aluminum, brass, and copper. The                PSF for the 10X10 cm2 ﬁeld size was ﬁrst determined by extrapolating the measured                normalized peak scatter factor (NPSF) to 0X0 cm2 ﬁeld size. The extrapolated NPSF was                the reciprocal of the PSF(10, hv). The measured PSF(10, hv) was then compared to the                PSF determined with Monte Carlo methods. We used Monte Carlo methods to investigate                the dependence of the measured signal on the build-up cap material. This was carried                out by calculating the primary and scatter dose contributions to the measured signal                in the air cavity of the ionization chamber. Based on Monte Carlo studies, a factor                was calculated to obtain the PSF from the measurements.</description><creator>Chung, Eunah</creator><contributor>Wamied Tarig Abdel-Rahman (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Ervin Podgorsak (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Physics - Radiation</subject><title>Comparison of measured and Monte Carlo-calculated peak scatter factors for 10X10 cm2 field size in 6 MV and 18 MV photon beams</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qk64t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vm81r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Medical Physics Unit</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sf472</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explains and implements the Finite Difference Method to                simulate for the propagating modes in integrated waveguides. The equidistant and                non-equidsitant methods are explained and implemented. A shape recognition engine is                implemented to recognize rectangular waveguide structures provided by the user in the                form of images. A geometric meshing algorithm is developed to improve accuracy.</description><description>Cette thèse explique et met en oeuvre la méthode des                diffrences finis pour simuler la propagation de modes de guides d'ondes intgré. La                méthode équidistante et non-équidistante est expliquée et mise en oeuvre. Un moteur                de reconnaissance de formes est mise en oeuvre pour reconnaître la structure des                guides d'ondes rectangulaire prévues par l'utilisateur sous forme d'images. Un                algorithme géomtrique de maillage est développé pour améliorer l'exactitude.</description><creator>Siam, Mohamed</creator><contributor>David V Plant (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>The finite difference method in photonics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g683b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sf472</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j333424v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Plusieurs organismes peuvent entrer en dormance, ou                diapause, pour survivre à des conditions environnementales précaires pour une durée                prolongée. Lorsque des larves de Caenorhabditis elegans entrent en diapause dauer,                elles cessent complètement de se développer ainsi que de se nourrir, cependant elles                demeurent actives et mobiles, tout en acquérant une résistance au stress et une                longévité extrême. L'entrée en stade dauer est accompagnée d'une réduction de                signalisation par l'insuline, de l'établissement d'un arrêt généralisé du cycle                cellulaire, de l'accumulation de ressources nutritives et d'un changement global au                niveau du métabolisme. Les processus physiologiques et moléculaires précis qui                induisent la quiescence cellulaire et permettent la survie prolongée en l'absence de                tout apport calorique, demeurent toutefois essentiellement inconnus. Je montre ici                que les orthologues de PTEN, STRAD, LKB1 et de AMPK (sous-unités α1, α2, β1, β2) chez                C. elegans coopèrent dans l'optique d'établir la quiescence cellulaire dans la                population de cellules germinales souches durant le développement de la larve dauer.                Il est intéressant de préciser que chez l'humain, une mutation de LKB1 dans la lignée                germinale provoque une prédisposition au cancer, tandis qu'une mutation dans une                sous-unité de STRAD ou d'AMPK ne semble pas causer de cancer. Chez C. elegans, LKB1                régule aussi la polarité embryonnaire, tandis que STRAD et AMPK sont dispensables                pour ce processus. Donc, mes données suggèrent que LKB1/STRAD régulent la croissance                et la prolifération des cellules à travers AMPK, tandis que LKB1 fonctionne aussi                indépendamment pour contrôler</description><description>Many organisms can execute a dormant state or diapause to survive harsh                environmental conditions for extended durations. When Caenorhabditis elegans larvae                enter the dauer diapause, they completely arrest development and feeding, but remain                active and motile, yet become stress-resistant and extremely long-lived. Entry into                dauer is associated with a reduction in insulin-like signalling, the establishment of                a generalized cell cycle arrest, the accumulation of nutritive resources and a                concomitant global change in metabolism. The precise molecular and physiological                processes that induce cell cycle quiescence and enable long-term survival in the                absence of caloric intake however remain largely unknown. I show here that the C.                elegans orthologs of PTEN, STRAD, LKB1 and AMPK (α1, α2, β1, β2 subunits) cooperate                to establish quiescence in the germline stem cell population during dauer                development. Interestingly, germline mutations in LKB1 cause predisposition to cancer                in humans, while mutations in STRAD or AMPK subunits do not seem to cause cancer. In                C. elegans, LKB1 also regulates embryonic polarity, while STRAD and AMPK are                dispensable for this process. Thus, my data suggest that LKB1/STRAD regulate cell                growth/proliferation through AMPK, while LKB1 also acts independently to regulate                polarity, and that this function may be critical for tumor suppression in human. In                addition, I show that C. elegans larvae that lack LKB1/AMPK signalling rapidly                consume their stored energy and prematurely expire following vital organ failure.                This signalling pathway acts in adipose-like tissues to downregulate triglyceride                hydrolysis so that these fat reserves are rationed to last the</description><creator>Narbonne, Patrick</creator><contributor>Richard D W Roy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>Roles of LKB1/AMPK signalling in the «C.elegans» dauer larva</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085n16s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j333424v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x575g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>En argumentant à partir des derniers écrits de Luce                Irigaray et d'écrits choisis de S. Kierkeggard, nous développons une éthique                kierkegaardienne de la différence sexuelle – une prise en compte de                l'intersubjectivité entre l'homme et la femme, redevable de la pensée de chacun                d'eux. Dans la troisième phase de ses écrits, Irigaray développe sa vision de la                relation éthique entre l'homme et la femme. Elle définit la différence sexuelle en                termes d'irréductibilité propre de l'homme et de la femme et elle définit une éthique                de la différence sexuelle en termes d'une reconnaisance du mystère et de la                différence de l'autre sexué. Cette reconnaissance s'exprime par l'admiration, la                caresse, et le respect du souffle de l'autre. Ceux-ci rendent possible le fait que                l'intervalle de la différence puisse devenir le seuil de la rencontre. Tandis que les                écrits de Kierkegaard sont façonnés par des convictions patriarcales – la femme est                définie à partir de l'homme et est élidée en tant que sujet à part entière – nous                décelons dans ses écrits (spécifiquement dans les lettres au juge William de 'Ou                Bien…ou bien', seconde partie) – une théorie du devenir humain du ressort de la                pensée d'Irigaray du caractère duel de l'humain. Nous argumentons que le juge William                et Irigaray partagent la même vue du soi en tant que tension vécue et imaginative                entre le réel et l'idéal. En associant la façon dont Irigaray rend compte de la                dualité de l'humain à la théorie du devenir humain dans le Juge William, nous sommes                à même d'affirmer la possibilité d'une théorie kierkegaardienne de la différence                sexuelle. Celle-ci nous fournit la base d'</description><description>Through engagement with the later writings of Luce Irigaray, and with                select writings of Søren Kierkegaard, we develop a Kierkegaardian ethics of sexual                difference – an account of intersubjectivity between man and woman that is indebted                to the thought of each. In the third phase of her writings, Irigaray develops her                vision of an ethical relationship between man and woman. She defines sexual                difference in terms of the irreducibility of man and woman to each other and defines                the ethics of sexual difference in terms of an acknowledgment of the mystery and                difference of the sexuate other. This acknowledgment is expressed through wonder,                through the caress, and through respect for the other's breath. These make it                possible that the interval of difference might become a threshold of encounter. While                Kierkegaard's writings are shaped by patriarchal convictions – woman is defined in                terms of man and is elided as subject in her own right – we discern in these writings                (specifically, in the letters of Judge William from 'Either/Or', Part II) a theory of                human becoming that is amenable to Irigaray's account of the human as two. We argue                that Judge William and Irigaray share an account of the self as a lived and                imaginative tension between actual and ideal. Embracing Irigaray's account of the                human as two within the Judge's framework of human becoming enables us to affirm the                possibility of a Kierkegaardian theory of sexual difference. This provides the basis                for a Kierkegaardian ethics of sexual difference. In 'Works of Love' Kierkegaard                develops an account of love centred on God as the middle term – God as one who                creates each person ex nihilo, who relates to each per</description><creator>De Vries, Roland James</creator><contributor>Douglas B Farrow (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Theology</subject><title>Toward a theological ethics of sexual difference: Luce Irigaray and Søren Kierkegaard on mediation and intersubjectivity between man and woman</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bk01p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x575g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806171m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study is, primarily, a presentation of a "re-exploration" of the physiography and vegetation of a large portion of Northern Ontario. At the same time, it serves as an illustration of a method of multiple survey through the use of aerial photographs.</description><creator>Dean, William G.</creator><date>1959</date><subject>Albany River (Ont.)</subject><subject>Ontario -- Aerial photographs</subject><title>Physiography and vegetation of the Albany River map area, northern Ontario : an aerial photography reconnaissance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811km536.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806171m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977w84d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Stover, Dale A.</creator><date>1967</date><subject>Owen, John, 1616-1683</subject><subject>Holy Spirit</subject><title>The pneumatology of John Owen : a study of the role of the Holy Spirit in relation to the shape of a theology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w423h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977w84d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Divinity</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:76537290c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:52:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this study was to compute economic values of traits for dairy cattle improvement using an empirical approach. Field recorded data were obtained from the Programme d'Analyse des Troupeaux Laitiers du Quebec (PATLQ) and genetic evaluation data were obtained from the Canadian Dairy Network (CDN). After the editing procedure, the data set consisted of 195,001 lifetime records of Holstein, Ayrshire, Jersey, Brown Swiss and Canadienne cows which calved for the first time between January 1980 and December 1994. Different profitability measurements were computed and used as the dependent variables in covariance model to compute different sets of economic values. Since the majority of cows produced 5 lactations or less, results obtained by using lifetime profits and profits until the end of the fifth lactation are similar. A kilogram genetic increase in fat production had higher economic values than the same increase in milk production in all breeds. A unit genetic increase in conformation had the highest positive impact on profit while a same increase in capacity had a negative impact on profit. Results obtained by using lifetime profit adjusted for the opportunity cost of postponed replacement showed that this adjustement reduced the influence of type traits on profit. Finally, profits of first lactations were used to study consequences of changes in pricing systems occurred in Quebec in August 1992. Economic values attached to protein production changed drastically. A kilogram genetic increase in protein production had negative economic values in the 80's and positive economic values after August 1992.</description><creator>St-Onge, Annie.</creator><contributor>Cue, Roger I. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Dairy cattle -- Canada -- Breeding -- Selection indexes.</subject><subject>Dairy cattle -- Canada -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Dairy farming -- Economic aspects -- Canada.</subject><title>Economic values of traits for dairy cattle improvement estimated using field recorded data</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m1215.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537290c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):38750</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>