<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:46:15Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):24125" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f1881m84c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>New stratigraphic evidence strongly suggests that the areally extensive "Lower Schist" and "Keno Hill Quartzite" (informal names), formerly included in the Precambrian Yukon Group, are Jurassic and Lower Cretaceous respectively. [...]</description><creator>Tempelman-Kluit, Dirk Jacob.</creator><contributor>Mountjoy, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1966</date><subject>Geological Sciences. </subject><title>The stratigraphy and structure of the"Keno hill quartzite" in Tombstone area, Central Yukon.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c3659.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881m84c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848r525</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Dupont, Antonin, 1932-</creator><date>1971</date><subject>Church and state -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Québec (Province) -- Politics and government -- 1897-1936.</subject><subject>Taschereau, Louis-Alexandre, 1867-1952</subject><title>Les relations entre l'Eglise et l'Etat sous Louis-Alexandre Taschereau, 1920-1936.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623d52k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848r525</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3f462635x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Lorriman, G. T. (Gabrielle T.)</creator><date>1971</date><subject>Time in literature</subject><subject>Goncharov, Ivan Aleksandrovich, 1812-1891 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>Goncharov, Ivan Aleksandrovich, 1812-1891. Oblomov</subject><title>Time in Gončarov's Oblomov</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k347v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f462635x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Russian</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj236297q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A two-level diagnostic baroclinic model is constructed for the purpose of examining the role of latent heat release in the production of vertical motion and rainfall. Incorporated in the model are terrain and frictional inflow effects and a variable level of non-divergence. The computations are carried out on a 300 point standard rectangular grid covering the North American continent. [...]</description><creator>Daley, Roger Willis</creator><contributor>Boville, B. W. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>O'Reilly, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1966</date><subject>Evaporation, Latent heat of.</subject><subject>Rain and rainfall.</subject><subject>Meteorology.</subject><subject>Numerical weather forecasting.</subject><title>Experimental large-scale numerical rainfall prediction.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613mz373.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236297q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hm50ts51n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The proteins of hen's egg yolk have long attracted the attention and interest of numerous scientists, and especially since the recognition of its nutritional values. The early chemical study of hen's egg yolk resulted in the discovery and isolation of 'vitellin'. This material was obtained by means of dilution precipitation and was considered for a time to be a major protein component of yolk. [...]</description><creator>Hui, Stella Shun Fong.</creator><contributor>Common, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1966</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry. </subject><subject>Proteins</subject><title>Studies on the livetin fraction of the egg yolk of the domestic fowl.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612p518.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50ts51n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jd472x362</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The influence of irrigation on timothy, alfalfa, ladino, bromegrass, and birdsfoot trefoil was investigated. Equal amounts of water were applied at four rates. Irrigation effected greater root and forage yields. The most efficient rate of irrigation was 0.1 inch followed by 0.4 inch and 1.0 inch per hour. [...]</description><creator>Dadson, Robert Benjamin.</creator><contributor>Steppler, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1966</date><subject>Pastures -- Irrigation</subject><subject>Agronomy. </subject><subject>Forage plants</subject><title>Response of certain species in pure and mixed seedings to irrigation.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g845r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd472x362</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agronomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1j92g844g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mean evaporation patterns are presented for cyclones and for anticyclones. From these patterns it is deduced that the rate of evaporation is higher under cyclonic circulation than under anticyclonic circulation. The seasonal variation in the rate of evaporation is analyzed. [...]</description><creator>Chisholm, William Joseph</creator><contributor>Vowinckel, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1966</date><subject>Meteorology.</subject><subject>Atmosphere.</subject><subject>Evaporation (Meteorology)</subject><title>Factors contributing to evaporation over the North Atlantic.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q241c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g844g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:js956g87j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Lower Cretaceous Mannville Group in East-Central Alberta is one of the main    targets for hydrocarbon exploration in Western Canada, typically associated with stratigraphic    controls. The depositional environment is diverse, ranging from fluvio-continental to shallow    marine. Mannville Group strata overlie a major unconformity that separates them from    predominantly carbonate rocks of the Paleozoic (Devonian). This study sought to integrate well    and 3-D seismic data to create a stratigraphic architecture for the zone of interest. Seismic    inversion was applied to the data and proved to be an excellent tool for mapping the    unconformity, clearly distinguishing between the clastic rocks above, and the units below. The    inversion result was included as part of a seismic attribute study applied to the dataset.    Stepwise regression and validation testing indicated that a combination of six attributes was    found to provide the best set able to predict log-derived physical properties related to    lithology (gamma-ray) using the seismic data. This result was used to train a neural network, and    finally, a pseudo-lithology volume able to estimate the distribution of lithology within the    Mannville Group over the whole 3-D survey was generated. New stratigraphic features that were    non-apparent in the original amplitude seismic version were discovered using the inversion and    the pseudo-lithology volumes. The results of this study show how comparing the three different    3-D seismic versions can be useful for understanding the stratigraphic complexity of the    Mannville. The extensive methodology approach presented herein can be used for analog purposes in    Western Canada as well as in any other geological setting.</description><description>La Formation Mannville (Crétacé Inférieur) du Centre Est de    l'Alberta est l'un des principaux objectifs concernant l'exploration    des hydrocarbures, typiquement associés à un contrôle stratigraphique. Les environnements de    dépôts sont variés, allant du domaine fluvio-continental au domaine marin. Les dépôts de la    Formation Mannville reposent sur une discordance stratigraphique majeure qui les sépare des    dépôts carbonatés du Paléozoïque (Devonien). Nous avons cherché à intégrer des données de puits    pour reconstituer l'architecture stratigraphique dans la zone d'étude.    L'inversion sismique à été appliquée aux données existantes, et s'est trouvée    être un excellent outil pour cartographier les discordances, faisant clairement la distinction    entre les dépôts silico-clastiques des dépôts carbonatés en dessous. Les résultats de    l'inversion ont ensuite été utilisés comme faisant partie des attributs sismiques    appliqués au jeu de données dans le but de rechercher si la distribution des sédiments    silici-clastiques dans la zone d'étude peut être distinguée d'un point de vu    sismique. A travers une analyse de régression point par point, une combinaison de six attributs à    fourni le meilleur jeu capable de prédire l'information lithologique dans les données    sismiques dérivées des données de puits (Gamma-Ray). Ce résultat a été transféré dans un réseau    de neurones, qui utilise cette relation pour s'entraîner à prédire la réponse du    Gamma-Ray au delà des points de contrôle dans le volume sismique. Cela conduit à la génération    d'un volume informé en pseudo-lithologie capable d'estimer la distribution de    la lithologie à l'intérieur de le Formation Mannville sur l'ensemble de    l'étude 3-D. Ce nouveau volume est capable de mettre en évidence les caractéristiques    stratigraphiques invisibles avec l'amplitude sismique et dans les volumes    d'inversion. Ce</description><creator>Smaili, Melik</creator><contributor>Bruce Samuel Hart (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Geophysics</subject><title>3-D seismic-based lithology prediction using impedance inversion and neural networks application: case-study from the Mannville Group in East-Central Alberta, Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623hz68b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956g87j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f669x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Probiotics and prebiotics have been used in many areas of animal husbandry for    their beneficial effects on health and productivity. The aim of the study was to determine the    impact of a yeast probiotic and prebiotic on health, growth performance and fecal microflora of    veal calves. Sixty-eight Holstein calves were fed for 8 weeks a control diet or diets in which a    probiotic (Levucell SB®; 0.5g/d) or a prebiotic (AgriMOS®, a manno-oligosaccharide; 3g/d) was    added to the milk replacer (MR). The only significant effect of the additives on calf performance    was on MR intake; calves fed Levucell SB® (SB) consumed more (P&lt;0.05) MR than those fed    AgriMOS®. To assess the effect on the gut flora, fecal samples were collected on d0, 7, 13, 28,    41 and 57. On days7 and 28 the fecal population of lactic acid bacteria (LAB) was greater    (P&lt;0.05) with SB than with AgriMOS; however the average effect of the additives on fecal    LAB was no different (P&gt;0.05) in comparison with control. Animals fed the additives showed    a reduction in E. coli over time, whereas E. coli counts in the control group remained static.    Clostridial numbers were also reduced in the SB group. Results of PCR-TTGE on DNA extracted from    feces revealed that fecal microbial population associated with SB was significant different from    that associated with AgriMOS or control groups. Despite housing, environmental and management    conditions which comprised calf health, neither a probiotic nor a prebiotic proved beneficial in    veal production.</description><description>Les probiotiques et les prébiotiques sont utilisés dans l'élevage    d'une variété de cheptels pour leurs effets bénéfiques sur la santé et la productivité des    animaux. Le but de cette recherche était d'évaluer l'impact d'une levure probiotique et d'un    prébiotique sur le taux de croissance, la santé et la microflore fécale de veaux de boucherie.    Soixante-huit veaux Holstein ont été nourris, lors d'une étude menée sur une période de 8    semaines, de succédané de lait (SL) constitué soit d'un régime témoin (ne contenant aucun    additif), soit d'un régime contenant le probiotique (Levucell SB®, 0.5g/j) ou d'un régime    contenant le prébiotique (AgriMOS, un manno-oligosaccharides 3g/j). Le seul effet significatif    des additifs sur la performance des veaux a été retrouvé sur la consommation du SL; les veaux    nourris avec le Levucell SB® (SB) ayant consommé plus (p&lt;0.05) de SL que ceux nourris avec    AgriMOS®. Pour évaluer les effets des additifs sur la flore intestinale, des échantillons fécaux    ont été recueillis aux jours 0, 7, 13, 28, 41 et 57. Aux jours 7 et 28, la population fécale de    bactéries lactiques (BL) était supérieure (p&lt;0.05) avec SB qu'avec AgriMOS; cependant    l'eff et moyen des additifs sur les BL fécales n'était pas significatif (p&gt;0.05) lorsque    comparé avec le groupe témoin. Une réduction de la population de E.coli été notée pour la durée    de l'étude chez les animaux nourris des additifs alors que sa population est restée stationnaire    dans le groupe témoin. La numération de Clostridium a aussi été retrouvée diminuée dans le groupe    nourris avec le SB. Les résultats obtenus à l'aide de la technique PCR-TTGE sur l'ADN extrait    d'échantillons fécaux ont montré un effet significatif de l'additif SB sur la flore microbienne    lorsque comparé aux groupes témoins et nourris avec AgriMOS (p&lt;0.05). Lorsque de saines    pra </description><creator>Chong, Katherine</creator><contributor>Leroy E Phillip (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Agriculture - Animal Culture and Nutrition</subject><title>Evaluation of a probiotic (Levucell SB®) and a prebiotic (AgriMOS®) on performance, health and fecal microflora of veal calves</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q242n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f669x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892b73w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Généralement rejetées, les coquilles et membranes d'œuf    représentent une importante réserve de composés bioactifs ayant une grande valeur économique et    pécuniare, cette étude se concentre donc sur le problème de trower une méthode appropriée pour    séparer la coquille de la membrane. Premièrement, notre étude évalua l'effet    d'un traitement aux micro-ondes sur l'aise de séparation de la membrane de la    coquille. Comme la réaction d'un matériel aux rayonnements électromagnétiques dépend de    ses propriétés diélectriques, les propriétés diélectriques de coquilles et membranes furent donc    indépendamment évaluées dans une gamme de frequencies de 200 MHz à 20GHz, en combinaison avec des    températures variant de 25°C à 100°C. De plus, la possibilité d'utiliser cette technique    pour détecter la dénaturation des protéines membranaires fut évaluée. En second lieu,    l'efficacité du traitement aux micro-ondes à faciliter la séparation de la membrane de    la coquille fut éprouvée en fonction de la réduction en énergie necessaire à cette séparation,    soit l'énergie de liaison. Pour l'ensemble des traitements aux micro-ondes,    trois facteurs à trois niveaux chacun furent évalués. Le traitement aux micro-ondes réduisit de    façon significative l'énergie de liaison entre la membrane et la coquille. Un modèle fut    développé permettant le calcul de l'énergie de liaison entre membrane et coquille, sous    les divers traitements aux micro-ondes et selon les différents facteurs.</description><description>Eggshell and membranes which are largely disposed of as waste are a reserve of    many bioactive compounds with high economic and monetary value which can be extracted by the    efficient separation of eggshell and membrane. Hence, this study concentrates on finding a    suitable method for separating the eggshell from membrane. First, the effect of microwave    treatment on separation of eggshell and membrane was investigated. The response of a material to    electromagnetic radiation depends upon its dielectric properties; therefore, the study of the    dielectric properties of eggshell and membrane was carried out in the range of 200 MHz to 20 GHz    and in the temperature range of 25 0C to 100 0C. Also, the possibility of using this technique    for detection of protein denaturation in egg membrane and shell was investigated. In the second    part of the study, the effectiveness of microwave treatment on separation of eggshell and    membrane was analyzed in terms of reduction in total energy required to separate the eggshell and    membrane and was termed as bond energy. For all microwave treatments, three factors with three    levels each were considered. Microwave treatment of eggs significantly reduced the bond energy    between eggshell and membrane. A Model for calculating the bond energy between the eggshell and    membrane for all microwave treatments was established.</description><creator>Hussain, Abid</creator><contributor>G S Vijaya Raghavan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Agriculture - Food Science and Technology</subject><title>Dielectric properties and microwave assisted separation of eggshell and membrane</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w081t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892b73w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kb680</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La théorie de la multiplication complexe nous donnent des outils    puissants pour étudier des aspects divers des formes modulaires classiques, ainsi que leurs    généralisations. Les travaux récents de Borcherds donne une nouvelle motivation pour étudier les    formes modulaires sur des groupes orthogonaux de signature (2,n), ainsi que les espaces sur    lesquels elles agissent. Dans cette thèse, nous étudierons les points spéciaux (ou points-CM) qui    existent dans ces espaces. Nous développerons des classifications cohomologiques concernant les    points spéciaux, les corps-CM associés et les espaces dans lesquels ces points peuvent être    trouvées.</description><description>The theory of complex multiplication has been a powerful tool for studying    various aspects of classical modular forms along with their generalizations. With the recent work    of Borcherds there has been an increase in the interest in studying modular forms on orthogonal    groups of signature (2,n) as well as the spaces on which they live. In this thesis, we study the    special points (or CM-points) that exist on these spaces. We develop cohomological    classifications relating the special points, their associated CM-fields and the spaces in which    these points can be found.</description><creator>Fiori, Andrew</creator><contributor>Eyal Z Goren (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics</subject><title>Special points on orthogonal symmetric spaces</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73pw935.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kb680</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945r72w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Currently, out-of-autoclave (OOA) technology is being used to design and    manufacture composite structural components at lower costs. OOA technology enables composites to    be produced using only vacuum pressure, eliminating the cost of purchasing and operating an    autoclave. The key to OOA prepreg is that they are specially designed to remove air that is    entrapped during the lay-up process. The in-plane and through thickness permeability of the    prepreg were characterized to determine which bagging configuration would produce the best    honeycomb sandwich structure. The bagging configuration that produced the lowest skin porosity    was determined to be one ply of non-perforated release film with edge breathing around the    perimeter of the panel. The resin content of the prepreg is such that any resin loss from the    skin will create dry spots, pinholes, and porosity. The edge breathing allows the air inside the    prepreg and core to be removed by the vacuum, and t he non-perforated release film presents resin    starvation and subsequently reduces porosity. Caution should be used when debulking    out-of-autoclave sandwich panels, since removing all the air from the core reduces the amount of    skin compaction available during cure. The skin compaction is needed to suppress void growth, and    the optimal internal core pressure was experimentally determined to be between 35-55 kPa. The    resin was fully characterized such that when the internal core pressure has reached the optimal    range, the resin can flow and close off the air passages. Five representative panels were    manufactured using two low temperature cure film adhesives. The optimal curing temperature to    minimize porosity of the composite skin was determined to be 100°C. Climbing drum peel tests were    used to evaluate the mechanical performance of the panels.</description><description>Présentement, la technologie hors autoclave (OOA) est utilisée    pour la conception et la fabrication à moindre coût des composants structuraux en composite. La    technologie OOA permet de produire des composites en utilisant uniquement la pression générés    lors des procédés d'ensachage sous vide, en éliminant par le fait même les coûts relatifs à    l'achat et à l'exploitation d'un autoclave. L'avantage des matériaux    pré-imprégnés destinés à des cuissons hors autoclave est qu'ils sont spécialement conçus    pour éliminer les bulles d'air emprisonnées au cours de la préparation. Afin de    déterminer la configuration d'ensachage optimale pour la production de structure en    sandwich avec noyau en nid d'abeille, l'épaisseur du matériel pré-imprégné    ainsi que la perméabilité à travers le plan ont été caractérisées. Les conditions d'ensachage    ayant menées à la plus faible porosité correspondent à l'utilisation combinée d'une couche non    perforée de pellicule antiadhésive et d'une bordure permettant l'extraction des produits gazeux.    La pellicule antiadhésive non perforée permet de prévenir les pertes de résine, tandis que la    bordure permettant l'extraction des produits gazeux permet d'évacuer l'air contenu dans le noyau    et les couches pré-imprégnés. L'utilisation d'une pellicule non perforée s'est avérée nécessaire    puisque la teneur en résine du matériel pré-imprégné est telle que toute perte de résine crée des    régions dites sèches (non imprégnée), produit des trous ou défauts à la surface du laminé et    augmente la porosité. Il convient d'être prudent lors du dégazage des panneaux en    sandwich hors autoclave puisque la suppression de tout l'air contenue dans le noyau    réduit le niveau de compaction disponible durant la cuisson. L'application d'une force de    compaction adéquate doit être effectuée lors de la cuisson afin de réduire la formation de vide</description><creator>Kratz, James</creator><contributor>Pascal Hubert (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical</subject><title>Processing composite sandwich structures using out-of-autoclave technology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xs58b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945r72w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hq611</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La question à savoir si les autochtones devraient avoir des droits    éducationels spéciaux mijote depuis quatre décénnies tout en ayant parfois atteint un point    d'ébullition. Cette controverse demeure irrésolue principalement en raison des tensions perçues    entre les valeurs libérales et les droits des minorités. Will Kymlicka tente de résoudre ce    conflit en affirmant que le concept libéral de l'autonomie peut constituer un point de départ    pour les droits des minorités. Cependant, plusieurs questions demeurent sans réponse dans sa    théorie. Par exemple, est-ce que l'autonomie est véritablement importante? Quelle est la    signfication d'une culture particulière? Est-ce qu'une société libérale devrait soutenir des    cultures non libérales? En répondant à ces questions, je vais démontrer que le concept libéral de    l'autonomie nécessite que des cultures adéquatement restreinte soit protégées. Ensuite, il est    possible de développer une théorie cohérente des droits des minorités qui peut être utilisée pour    défendre le contrôle autochtone de l'éducation formelle.</description><description>Whether Aboriginal people should have special educational rights is a question    that has simmered and occasionally boiled over during the past four decades. This dispute remains    largely unresolved due to perceived tensions that exist between liberal values and minority    rights. Will Kymlicka attempts to resolve this conflict by claiming that the liberal concept of    autonomy can be used as a starting point for minority rights. However, there are several    questions that are inadequately answered in his theory. Namely, why is autonomy so important?    What is the significance of a particular culture? Should a liberal society support cultures that    are illiberal? In response to these questions I will demonstrate that the liberal concept of    autonomy requires that adequately restrictive cultures be protected. From this it is possible to    develop a cohesive theory of minority rights that can be used to defend Aboriginal control of    formal education.</description><creator>Nikkel, Donald</creator><contributor>Kevin Michael McDonough (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Education - Philosophy of</subject><title>Rethinking restrictions: a liberal approach to minority rights and aboriginal education</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429b16t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hq611</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gp197</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les propriétés optiques et électriques du crystal bi-dimensionel    graphene qui a été récemment isolésont explorées en détail de façon théorique et expérimentale.    La théorie physique pour le comportement des électrons est également présentée. La théorie    électromagnétique est révisée de façon générale et utilisée comme cadre aﬁn de comprendre les    mesures optiques prises sur des échantillons de graphene. Une mesure du nombre de couches sur des    substrats transparents est présentée de façon originale. Un plan pour un instrument de mesure    optique pouvant prendre des mesures dans l'espace libre est présenté en détail. De plus, des    mesures prises avec le système sont également présentées. Finalement, des expériences futures à    faire sur l'instrument présenté sont suggérées.</description><description>The optical and electrical properties of the recently isolated two dimensional    crystal graphene are explored in detail, both theoretically and experimentally. The physical    theory for the behavior of electrons in graphene is introduced. Electromagnetic theory is applied    to the understanding of optical measurements on graphene samples. Original work on the    measurement of layers on bulk transparent substrates is presented. A design for a free space    optical instrument intended to make optical measurements on graphene is shown in detail, and    measurements made with the system are presented. Finally, suggestions are made for future    experiments that could be performed with the designed instrument.</description><creator>Gaskell, Peter</creator><contributor>Thomas Szkopek (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Optical measurements of graphene and thin graphite films on low index substrates</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831ck91w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gp197</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w032393g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette étude de cas d'un projet collaboratif de    développement d'un dossier de santé électronique (DSE) pan-canadien démontre que le    déroulement de ce projet a donné lieu à une convergence d'enjeux politiques et    techniques. La juxtaposition de différents domaines, procédures, bases de connaissances, et    entités impliqués dans l'établissement d'un DSE pancanadien a ainsi abouti à    l'élaboration d'une nouvelle forme hybride de collaboration.</description><description>The convergence of political and technical challenges is demonstrated in a case    study on a collaborative initiative to develop a pan-Canadian Electronic Health Record (EHR)    system. It is argued that the juxtaposition of different domains, procedures, knowledge bases,    and entities involved in establishing a pan-Canadian EHR has resulted in the development of a    new, hybrid form of collaboration.</description><creator>Mardis, Nicole</creator><contributor>Alberto Cambrosio (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Sociology - Organizational</subject><title>The state of health information technology standards: the conflation of the technical and the political in the development of a pan-Canadian electronic health record system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n2084.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032393g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f6727</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Regeneration of HCl from process solutions is an important unit operation in    chloride hydrometallurgy. Currently, it is accomplished by the highly capital and energy    intensive technology of pyrohydrolysis. The research described in this thesis, has focused on an    alternative HCl regeneration system from iron(II, III) chloride solutions that has been coined    "Hydrolytic Distillation". This system relates to the earlier developed (in the 1970s) PORI    Process. Basically this system involves two steps: (1) the oxidation of ferrous chloride solution    by oxygen sparging under reflux conditions (atmospheric pressure) at 150ºC; and (2) the    hydrolytic decomposition under atmospheric pressure of ferric chloride solution by continuous    controlled water addition at 180ºC. As a result of the latter step iron is recovered as hematite    and chloride units as superazeotropic (8-9 M) hydrochloric acid in the vapor phase condensate.    The study on oxidation determined that 2/3 of FeCl2 is converted to FeCl3 and 1/3 to Fe2O3 at a    rate that is controlled by oxygen mass transfer. The hematite product from the oxidation step    proved to be crystalline but nanostructured consisting of 1-2 μm porous aggregated particles    possessing 12-28 m2/g specific surface area and to be essentially pure α-Fe2O3 (70% Fe,    &lt;0.1% Cl-). With reference to the hydrolytic precipitation/distillation step it was    determined that at 180ºC, the temperature at which superazeotropic HCl (8-9 M) was consistently    produced, the composition of the liquid phase is "FeCl32H2O". Controlled continuous addition of    H2O (or feed solution) was found to be critical in maintaining pseudo-steady state and driving    the reaction to ~95% conversion efficiency. The hematite consisted of coarse spherical compact    aggregated particles (~40 μm) that exhibited excellent filtration and washing properties. Its %Fe    content was 68.5% and it contained ~4% H2O and ~3% Cl- that could be re</description><description>Le recyclage d'acide chlorhydrique à partir de solutions    industrielles chlorées constitue une étape importante des procédés hydrométallurgiques. A l'heure    actuelle cette opération est effectuée par pyrohydrolyse, une technique très couteuse d'un point    de vue économique ou énergétique. La recherche présentée dans ce manuscrit se concentre sur un    système de recyclage d'acide chlorhydrique à partir de solutions de chlorure de fer (II, III),    baptisé "Distillation Hydrolytique". Ce système est issu du procédé PORI,    préalablement développé (dans les années 1970). Le système inclus principalement deux étapes :    (1) l'oxidation d'une solution de chlorure de fer (II) (FeCl2) par barbotage d'oxygène et    utilisation d'une colonne à reflux (sous pression atmosphérique), à une température de 150°C ;    (2) la décomposition hydrolytique sous pression atmosphérique d'une solution de chlorure de fer    (III) (FeCl3) à 180 °C par ajout d'eau contrôlé et continu. A la fin de cette dernière étape, le    fer est récupéré sous forme d'hématite et les dérivés chlorés sous forme d'acide chlorhydrique    super-azéotropique (8-9 M) dans le condensat provenant de la phase gazeuse. L'étude sur    l'oxidation a permis de déterminer que 2/3 du FeCl2 était converti sous forme de FeCl3 et le    reste sous forme d'hématite Fe2O3, la vitesse de réaction étant contrôlée par le transfert de    masse de l'oxygène. L'hématite produite lors de l'étape d'oxidation s'est avérée de nature    cristalline, nano-structurée, constituée d'agrégats de particules poreuses, d'une taille moyenne    de 1-2 μm avec une aire de surface de 12-28 m2/g et de composition chimique α-Fe2O3 quasi pure    (70% Fe, &lt; 0.1% Cl-). Quant à l'étape de précipitation/distillation hydrolytique, il a été    déterminé qu'à 180°C, température à laquelle l'acide chlorhydrique super-azéotropique était    continuellement produit, la compo</description><creator>Hock, Sebastian</creator><contributor>George Demopoulos (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Metallurgy</subject><title>Precipitation of hematite and recovery of hydrochloric acid from aqueous iron(II, III) chloride solutions by hydrothermal processing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731485d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f6727</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t287f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Horticultural producers are in need of efficient and timely techniques for    determining crop water requirements. The question of when and how much to irrigate, termed    irrigation scheduling, is particularly important for high-value crops such as strawberries    (Fragaria ananassa). During the growing season, irrigation scheduling decisions are influenced by    climatic variables such as rainfall, temperature and humidity, which directly impact soil    moisture levels. A field study was therefore conducted to evaluate two soil moisture sensors for    irrigation scheduling of commercial strawberries on a farm in Simcoe, Southern Ontario.    Strawberries were grown on raised beds with plastic mulch under two management practices – open    field and plastic high tunnels. For each practice, two soil moisture sensors based on time domain    reflectometry (TDR) were evaluated. The sensors, Campbell Scientific's water content    reflectometer (WCR) and ESI's Gro-point (GP) monitored soil moisture continuously over the    growing season (May to October 2007). Soil samples were collected to obtain volumetric water    content as a unit of reference for the purpose of comparison and evaluation of the two sensors.    Equivalent water depths (EWD) were calculated for an effective strawberry rooting depth of 0.3 m.    The calculated EWDs were compared with the grower's irrigation scheduling practices. The study    found that the WCR and GP reliably recorded continuous trends in soil moisture throughout the    growing season. For the WCR sensor, gravimetric analyses of soil samples showed excellent    correlation, resulting in R2 of 0.94 and 0.97 for the open field and plastic high tunnel,    respectively. The R2 for the GP sensor was good at 0.88 for the open field but poor for the    plastic high tunnels, due to a malfunctioning sensor. The EWDs for the two plots were calculated    to be 699 mm for the open field and 711 mm for the plastic high tunnels. A significant fin</description><description>Les horticulteurs ont besoin de déterminer avec précision les    besoins en eau d'irrigation des cultures. En effet, la bonne gestion de la production et    l'obtention d'un meilleur rendement des fraises (Fragaria ananassa) nécessitent la planification    de la quantité d'eau à apporter et le jour de l'irrigation. Le climat, la pluviométrie et la    variation de la température durant le stade de croissance des plantes sont des variables    importantes qui compliquent la tâche de la planification de l'irrigation. La problématique de    cette étude s'inscrit dans l'optique d'évaluer l'apport de deux capteurs d'humidité du    sol de type TDR (Time Domain Reflectometry) à la planification de l'irrigation des fraises à    Simcoe, au sud d'Ontario. Il convient de noter que les fraises ont été cultivées avec la    technique du paillis de plastique, en plein champ, ainsi qu'avec la technique du tunnel en    plastique. Pour atteindre les objectifs assignés à cette étude, l'utilisation de deux capteurs de    type WRC (Campbell Scientific water content reflectometer) et GP (ESI's Gro-point) a permis de    suivre d'une manière continue l'humidité du sol pendant le stade de croissance (mai à    octobre 2007). Aussi, des échantillons du sol ont été collectés afin d'obtenir la teneur    volumique en eau. Cette dernière a été utilisée comme référence et a permis ainsi de comparer et    d'évaluer les résultats obtenus à l'aide des différents capteurs. Également, nous avons    calculé l'équivalent d'eau en profondeur (EEP) pour une zone racinaire des fraises de 30 cm. Ce    procédé nous a permis de comparer l'EEP calculé pour les différentes pratiques d'irrigation    adoptées par les producteurs. Les résultats obtenus ont démontré que le WCR et GP représentent la    variabilité de l'humidité du sol pendant le stade de la croissance. Pour le capteur WCR,    nous avons pu établir une corrélation très intéressante avec l'analyse</description><creator>Ali, Sajjad</creator><contributor>Chandra A Madramootoo (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Agricultural</subject><title>Evaluation of the soil moisture sensors for irrigation scheduling of strawberries</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623hz70c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t287f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nc580n49d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les glies sont connues comme pouvant intégrer et propager    l'information via une augmentation de leur concentration de calcium interne dépendante de    l'activité neuronale. Des études in vitro ont également démontré que les glies ont des filopodia    motiles. Nous avons effectué une étude sur une population de glies radiales provenant du tectum    optique de têtard de Xenopus laevis qui comme les astrocytes montrent une activité calcique qui    est dépendante de l'activité neuronale. Aussi, nous avons fait de l'imagerie en temps réel de ces    cellules exprimant du EGFP-F in vivo. Nous avons observé que ces cellules ont des filopodia très    motiles et que leur motilité est influencée par des variations de l'activité neuronale. Ces    filopodia se retrouvent dans le neuropile tectal et sont associés aux synapses rétinotectaux.    Enfin, nous avons démontré qu'un stimulus lumineux induit une activité calcique et des    changements dans la motilité des filopodia de ces glies radiales.</description><description>Glia have been reported to integrate and propagate signals via a neuronal    activity-dependent intracellular increase of calcium. In vitro studies have also reported that    glia exhibit rapid structural motility. We have performed in vivo two-photon analysis of a    morphologically identifiable population of radial glia in the optic tectum of Xenopus laevis    tadpoles that spontaneous and neuronal activity-responsive calcium transients much like    astrocytes in the mammalian brain. Using live imaging of EGFP-F-expressing individual glial cells    in intact Xenopus tadpoles, we found that these radial glia rapidly extend and retract long, fine    filopodia within the tectal neuropil. These filopodia interact with retinotectal synapses and    their motility is modulated by neuronal NMDAR activation and NO signaling. Finally, we observed    that natural visual experience drove both an increase in the rate of calcium transients and a    change in filopodial dynamics in these radial glia.</description><creator>Tremblay, Marc</creator><contributor>Edward Ruthazer (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience</subject><title>The role of neuronal activity on radial glia behaviour in «Xenopus laevis» tectum</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526d31k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580n49d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vc30p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description> Space business is subject to many of the same realities as commercial    enterprises in other locations and other market sectors. In addition, the space treaties impose a    separate set of obligations on conduct in space. Predictability is necessary to continue    development of this profound resource. The present state of the space marketplace is examined,    noting current trends. The legal framework regulating these activities is described.    Uncertainties in commercial space projects are identified and solutions proposed. A case study of    a failed space transaction is analyzed and resolutions considered. The thesis ends with    recommendations and an understanding of the role that private space law plays.</description><description> Les affaires de l'espace sont sujettes à des plusieurs    des mêmes réalités que des entreprises commerciales dans d'autres endroits et    d'autres secteurs du marché. En outre, les traités de l'espace imposent un    ensemble séparé d'engagements à la conduite dans l'espace. La prévisibilité est    nécessaire pour continuer le développement de cette ressource profonde. L'état actuel du    marché de l'espace est examiné, notant des tendances courantes. Le cadre juridique    réglementant ces activités est décrit. Des incertitudes dans des projets d'espace    commerciaux sont identifiées et des solutions sont proposées. Une étude de cas d'une    transaction échouée de l'espace est analysée et des solutions est considérées. La thèse    finit avec des recommandations et un arrangement du rôle les jeux privés de cette loi de    l'espace.</description><creator>Howard, Diane</creator><contributor>Rosalie Jukier (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>Making do with what we have: creating certainty in private space law</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45q988k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vc30p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773w64m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Deux raisons principales commandent à l´ajout de la mousse dans le    processusde flottation, à savoir, la réduction de la bulle et la production d´une moussestable.    Léffet de la mousse sur le comportement de la bulle en zone pulpairenést pas pris en compte. Un    travail antérieur a démontré que pour la mêmefraction d´air transporté par les bulles, le type de    mousse a de l´influence sur lataille des bulles. Cela implique que la vélocité de la bulle dépend    de la nature dusurfactant (type de mousse). Une étude basée sur l´usage de plusieurs bullessemble    s´accorder avec l´hypothèse relative au type de mousse, néanmoins lesinteractions des bulles    rendent le problème complexe.La présente étude a résolu cette question en mesurant la vélocité    d´une bulledont les dimensions sont presque égales à 1 ou 2 mm, suivant le type demousse. Il en    est résulté que dans l´intervalle des concentrations d´importanceen flottation, le pentanol peine    à influencer la vélocité, alors que léau toute seuleen serait capable. En revanche, le F150 (un    polyglycol) réduit la vélocité de 50%.Pour les concentrations élevées de pentanol (&gt;100    ppm), la vélocité décroit etdevient comparable à celle engendrée par la présence du F150. Il va    de soi quel´observation antérieure est confirmée dans l´intervalle pratique desconcentrations.En    guise d´investigations, des expériences au cours desquelles les alcoolsaliphatiques allant du    butanol (C4) à l´octanol (C8), ont été réalisées. Il a étédémontré que léffet du type de mousse    sur la vélocité dépend de laconcentration. Il existe une concentration minimale de la mousse en    dessous delaquelle, la bulle monte comme dans le modèle de léau contaminée de Clift etal. La    concentration minimale critique dépend de la dimension de la bulle et dudéplacement mesuré à    partir du point terminal du tube capillaire. L´on rapporteque les bulles les</description><description>The addition of frother in flotation has two main functions, to help reduce    bubble size and help produce a stable froth. A role of frother on bubble behavior in pulp zone is    usually not considered. A previous study showed that as frother type was changed the same gas    holdup was given by different size bubbles. This implies that bubble rise velocity depends on the    nature of the surfactant (frother type). A study using bubble swarms appears to support the    frother type effect but bubble interactions are a possible confounding factor. This study    resolved the question by measuring terminal rise velocity profile of single bubbles (ca. 1 to 2    mm) as a function of frother type. It is shown that at the concentrations of interest in    flotation, 1-pentanol hardly alters the velocity compared to water alone while F150 (a    polyglycol) reduces the velocity by up to 50%. The results become in 1-pentanol bubble did not    reach terminal velocity. For high concentration of 1-pentanol (&gt;130ppm) the rise velocity    is reduced comparable to F150. To investigate, experiments were performed using aliphatic    alcohols from 1- butanol (C4) to 1-octanol (C8). It was found there is a minimum concentration    for the frother to give terminal velocity close to the Clift et al. contaminated eater result.    The concentration decreases as molecular weight (chain length) of alcohol increases. Larger    bubbles (1.8 vs. 1.5mm) require higher minimum concentration. To study the influence of molecular    structure, three 6-C alcohols, 1-hexanol, MIBC and 2-hexanol, were used. The results show that    molecular structure influences rise velocity through the position of OH group, and whether the    alcohol is straight chained or branched. The observation can make a useful link frother to    chemistry for understanding frother influence on bubble rise and possibly its function in    flotation. The influence of three industrial frother, MIBC, F150 and DF250, was studied and</description><creator>Rafiei Mehrabadi, Amir Arash</creator><contributor>James A Finch (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Metallurgy</subject><title>Effects of frother type on single bubble rise velocity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/000000948.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773w64m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x494g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le mouvement de la prostate est un problème critique dans le    traitement conforme du cancer de la prostate, le plus commun cancer parmi les hommes au Canada.    La radiothérapie guidée par l'image (IGRT) utilisant les images ultrasons (US)    quotidiennes est une technique largement utilisée pour régler ce problème. Une nouvelle technique    de localisation ultrasons en trois dimensions, basée sur une méthode de vérification intra    modalités, a été testée à l'Hôpital General de Montreal en 2005. L'objectif principal de cette    thèse a été de mieux quantifier l'amplitude du mouvement de la prostate à travers une analyse    rétrospective de 32 patients et d'évaluer son impacte dans la dosimétrie des traitements de la    prostate avec et sans localisation US. L'analyse rétrospective a montré que la moyenne     écart-type des mouvements de la prostate dans les directions AP, SI et DG est de -3.3  7.9 mm,    -1.1  6.4 mm et -0.2  5.6 mm, respectivement. La plus grande rotation survient autour de l'axe    latérale, avec une moyenne  écart-type de -0.9  4.6, s'échelonnant entre -6.7 et 8.0. Pour    estimer l'impacte dosimétrique du mouvement rigide de la prostate, la dose a été calculée en    utilisant la méthode XVMC, qui prend en considération la géométrie du patient, les hétérogénéités    et les corrections pour le mouvement. Une déviation moyenne de la D95% de jusqu'à -11.9%    a été observe pour le PTV, -5.1% pour le CTV et -4.2% pour le GTV. Le V95% du PTV a été réduit    par un facteur de -22.2% lorsque la translation quotidienne de la prostate était présente mais    aucune correction n'a été appliquée. La dégradation de la dose à la cible a pu être corrige    presque complètement en appliquant une correction du mouvement de translation, cependant lorsque    la rotation a été prise en compte, le recouvrement de la dose a été moins adéquat. L'effet des    prothèses m</description><description>This thesis retrospectively analyzes prostate's daily motion provided by    three-dimensional US localization and investigates its dosimetric impacts based on XVMC    calculation which takes into account patient geometry, heterogeneity and prostate motion    correction. The retrospective analysis on 32 prostate patients shows that the mean  SD    displacements of prostate in the AP, SI, and RL directions are -3.3  7.9 mm, -1.1  6.4 mm, -0.2    5.6 mm, respectively. The largest rotation occurs about lateral axis with mean  SD of -0.9     4.6, ranging between -6.7 and 8.0 from a preliminary study including three patients. To assess    the dosimetric impacts of prostate motion, five motion scenarios including with and without    prostate translation and correction, with translation and rotation but no correction or only    having translation correction are simulated. Analysis based on dose-volume histograms and isodose    curves shows that prostate motion (translation and rotation) will deteriorate the dose delivered    to patient target and OARs. With translation correction method, the degraded patient dose could    be recovered nearly completely. For the scenarios with both translation and rotation, translation    correction method could dramatically improve the degraded patient dose, but could not completely    eliminate the dosimetric impact of prostate motion. Besides, the dosimetric impact of metal    prosthesis in three patients has been analysed as well. Up to 5% discrepancies in their D90%,    D95%, V90%, and D95% for PTV have been observed.</description><creator>Chen, Yong</creator><contributor>Frans Verhaegen (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>William A Parker (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health Sciences - Radiology</subject><title>Daily three-dimensional ultrasound imaging for Monte Carlo based adaptive radiotherapy of prostate cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dn283.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x494g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Medical Physics Unit</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r193g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Low-mass X-ray binaries (LMXBs) are now routinely used for neutron star (NS)    radius measurements. Observations of these systems in their quiescent stage (qLMXB) is one method    leading to precise measurements. However, the dominant source of uncertainty on the NS radii    remains the distance to the binary systems. Globular clusters (GCs) are therefore the places to    look for more qLMXBs, due to their known or measurable distances and their abundance of binary    systems. This thesis reports the discovery of seven candidate qLMXBs in six GCs, using    observations from the XMM-Newton satellite, based on X-ray spectral consistency with NS hydrogen    atmosphere models. The goal of this program of observations is to increase the population of    known GC qLMXBs, for which longer follow-up exposures will permit high precision radius    measurements. Nine candidates were initially identified based on their X-ray spectra with    signal-to-noise ratio S/N &gt; 3. Two candidates in NGC 6304 were tentatively confirmed, with    consistent best-fit parameters, in a follow-up Chandra X-ray observatory observation. One low-S/N    candidate in NGC 6540 (S/N = 7) was subsequently excluded by a deeper, higher S/N (S/N = 17)    observation. One other candidate was also excluded on the basis of the spatial velocity of the    associated companion star, precluding cluster membership. Thus, the present work has added seven    new qLMXB candidates to the eleven previously known.</description><description>Les systèmes binaires X à faible masse (LMXB) sont de plus en plus    utilisés pour mesurer le rayon des étoiles à neutrons. L'observation de ces systèmes au    repos (en quiescence, qLMXB) est l'une des méthodes utilisées pour obtenir des mesures    précises du rayon. Cependant, l'incertitude dominante reste la distance du système    binaire. Les amas globulaires (AGs) sont donc les emplacements pour chercher des qLMXBs, grâce à    leur distance connues ou facilement mesurables et leur abondance de qLMXBs. Cette thèse présente    la découverte de sept qLMXBs candidates dans six AGs à partir d'observations du    satellite XMM-Newton, basée sur leurs compatibilité avec des modèles d'atmosphère    d'hydrogène d'étoiles à neutrons. Le but de ce programme    d'observations est d'augmenter la population des qLMXBs connues, pour    lesquelles de plus longues observations permettront des mesures de rayons plus précises. Neuf    candidates ont été l'objet de découvertes basées sur leur spectre X avec un rapport    signal-sur-bruit S/B &gt; 3. Deux d'entre elles, dans l'amas NGC 6304, ont    été confirmées, avec des paramètres compatibles, grâce à des observations du satellite Chandra.    Une candidate dans NGC 6540, ayant un faible S/B (S/B = 7), a été exclu après l'analyse    de données avec un S/B = 17. Une autre a également été révoqué à cause du mouvement propre de sa    compagne optique, excluant toute appartenance à l'AG. Par conséquent, le travail    présenté ici a ajouté sept candidates qLMXB aux onze déjà connues.</description><creator>Guillot, Sebastien</creator><contributor>Robert Rutledge (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Physics - Astronomy and Astrophysics</subject><title>An «XMM» search for quiescient low -mass x-ray binaries in globular cluster using x-ray spectral identification</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000095j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r193g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074w03g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Vous pouvez exprimer une histoire différente par l'art.    Que se passe-t-il quand on utilise l'enquête art-basée pour explorer la connaissance    environnementale? Comment les connaissances alternatives artistiques peuvent valoriser et créer    des connaissances alternatives qui auraient autrement été oubliées ou négligées? Les tendances    holistiques et justice-orientées dans l'éducation environnementale plaident pour    l'intégration de l'identité sociale dans les issues écologiques. Ce projet    'Photo-Voice' à caractère communautaire participatoire tient place dans les communautés rurales    autour de 'Tiwai Island' au Sierra Leone. Le projet examine les biens environnementaux,    communautaires et culturels afin d'être protégés pour les générations à venir. Les poèmes    démontrent les nuances, les particularités et le contexte dynamique des aspets d'un endroit    important à conserver pour ces communautés. L'étude appelle l'attention sur le    processus continu de la reconstruction d'après-guerre au sein des communautés autour de    'Tiwai Island.' Elle soulève également des questions autour du rôle des structures physiques dans    l'établissement, la négociation, la construction et le déconstruction de    l'identité.</description><description>You can express a different story through art. What happens when you use    arts-based inquiry to explore environmental knowledge? How can artistic expression value and    construct alternative knowledges that might otherwise be overlooked or silenced? Holistic and    justice-oriented trends in environmental education argue for the integration of social identity    within ecological issues. This participatory community-based Photo-Voice project takes place in    the rural communities around Tiwai Island in Sierra Leone. The project investigates    environmental, community and cultural assets to be protected for future generations. The    performance pieces that emerge elaborate, nuance, and particularize important features of place    for these communities. The study draws attention to the ongoing process of post-war    reconstruction within the communities around Tiwai Island. It also raises questions around the    role of physical structures in the enactment, negotiation, construction and deconstruction of    identity.</description><creator>Thompson, Jennifer</creator><contributor>Claudia A Mitchell (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Education - Social Sciences</subject><title>How we see this place: an intergenerational dialogue about conservation using Photo-Voice around Tiwai Island, Sierra Leone</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b5919270.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074w03g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988k872</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pour avoir une meilleure performance, la plupart des langages    de programmation sont compilés, soit avant leur exécution et statiquement, ou dynamiquement,    pendant leur utilisation, à l'aide d'un compilateur "Just-in-Time" (JIT).    Cependant, les compilateurs avec desfonctionnalités d'optimisation sont complexes, et    plusieurs langages, tel que Ruby, Python, PHP, profitent mieux d'une solution flexible    et portable tel qu'une machine virtuelle (MV) interprétée. Cette solution offre un échange    acceptable entre la performance d'exécution et les coûts de développement. La performance    de la MV est typiquement maximisée par l'utilisation de la technique    d'interprétation "direct threading", qui, malheureusement, interagit mal avec les    prédicteurs de branches moderne. Des techniques plus avancées, tel que "code-copying" ont été    proposées [RS96,PR98,EG03c,Gag02], mais ne sont pas applicable en pratique à cause de    préoccupation de sécurité. C'est sur les bases suivantes que nous avons développé deux    solutions coût-efficace qui offrent une bonne performance. Premièrement, nous avons développé une    extension au langage C qui permet aux programmeurs d'exprimer le besoin pour des    garanties spéciales pour la technique de "code-copying". Notre technique, qui requiert très peu de    maintenance, est développée comme une extension à un compilateur qui a non seulement des    fonctionnalités d'optimisation très élaborées mais qui est aussi un standard    d'industrie, le "GNU C Compiler" (GCC). Nous pouvons alors appliquer cette technique sur    les interpréteur Java, OCaml et Ruby. Nous avons évalué la performance de ces MV sur    plusieurs architectures, en collectionnant de l'information pour analyser la performance    logiciel et matériel. La marge d'amélioration possible est très grande, une accélération    d'ordre 2.81 pour OCaml et 1.44 pour Java sur l'architecture Intel 32-bit. Il    est importan</description><description>To achieve the best performance, most computer languages are compiled, either    ahead of time and statically, or dynamically during runtime by means of a Just-in-Time (JIT)    compiler. Optimizing compilers are complex, however, and for many languages such as Ruby, Python,    PHP, etc., an interpreter-based Virtual Machine (VM) offers a more flexible and portable    implementation method, and moreover represents an acceptable trade-off between runtime    performance and development costs. VM performance is typically maximized by use of the basic    direct threading interpretation technique which, unfortunately, interacts poorly with modern    branch predictors. More advanced techniques, like code-copying have been proposed    [RS96,PR98,EG03c,Gag02] but have remained practically infeasible due to important safety    concerns. On this basis we developed two cost-efficient, well-performing solutions. First, we    designed a C/C++ language extension that allows programmers to express the need for the special    safety guarantees of code-copying. Our low-maintenance approach is designed as an extension to a    highly-optimizing, industry-standard GNU C Compiler (GCC), and we apply it to Java, OCaml, and    Ruby interpreters. We tested the performance of these VMs on several architectures, gathering    extensive analysis data for both software and hardware performance. Significant improvement is    possible, 2.81 times average speedup for OCaml and 1.44 for Java on Intel 32-bit, but varies by    VM and platform. We provide detailed analysis and design guidelines for helping developers    predict and evaluate the benefit provided by safe code-copying. In our second approach we focused    on alleviating the limited scope of optimizations in code-copying with an ahead-of-time-based    (AOT) approach. A source-based approach to grouping bytecode instructions together allows for    more extensive cross-bytecode optimizations, and so we develop a caching compilation server</description><creator>Prokopski, Grzegorz</creator><contributor>Clark Verbrugge (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>Optimizing software-hardware interplay in efficient virtual machines</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88ch44m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988k872</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xd07gt58h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:07:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La ceinture de roches vertes de Nuvvuagittuq est une succession    Éoarchéenne/Hadéenne préservée le long the la côte Est de la Baie d'Hudson dans la Province du    Supérieur, Québec, Canada. Elle est essentiellement composée de trois unités lithologique    majeures : 1) une amphibolite à cummingtonite appelée « faux-amphibolite » étant la lithologie    dominante de la ceinture, 2) des filons-couches mafiques et ultramafiques en intrusion dans la    faux-amphibolite, et 3) des roches sédimentaires chimiques comprenant une formation de fer    rubanée (BIF) and une formation de silice. La faux-amphibolite est basaltique à andésitique en    composition. Elle est constituée de différentes proportions de cummingtonite + biotite + quartz,    ± plagioclase ± grenat ± anthophyllite ± cordiérite variant d'amphibolite à cummingtonite à    schiste à biotite-grenat. Certaines roches de la ceinture de roches vertes de Nuvvuagittuq    présentes des rapports 142Nd/144Nd inférieurs aux standards terrestres (epsilon142Nd = -0.07 to    -0.15). Les rapports 142Nd/144Nd de la faux-amphibolite corrèle positivement avec leurs rapports    Sm/Nd produisant une isochrone 146Sm-142Nd avec un âge de 4280 +53 –81 millions d'années. Des    filons-couches de gabbro hautement déformés en intrusion dans la faux-amphibolite âgée de 4.28    Ga, produisent une isochrone 147Sm-143Nd avec une pente correspondant à un âge de 4023 ± 110 Ma.    La ceinture de roches vertes de Nuvvuagittuq compte également des bandes felsiques de 3.8 Ga et    est entourée par une tonalite datée à 3.66 Ga interprétée comme étant produite par la fusion des    amphibolites mafiques plus âgées. La ceinture de roches vertes de Nuvvuagittuq représente donc    une section crustal Éoarchéenne/Hadéenne comprenant les roches les plus vieilles préservées sur    la Terre. La faux-amphibolite est divisée en un groupe riche en Ti et un groupe pauvre en Ti avec    des filons-c</description><description>The Nuvvuagittuq greenstone belt is an Eoarchean/Hadean succession preserved    along the eastern coast of Hudson Bay in the Northeastern Superior Province, Quebec, Canada. It    is essentially composed of three major lithological units: 1) mafic cummingtonite-amphibolite,    known as the "faux-amphibolite", which is the dominant lithology of the belt, 2) ultramafic and    mafic sills that intrude the faux-amphibolite, and 3) chemical sedimentary rocks comprising a    banded iron formation (BIF) and a silica-formation. The faux-amphibolite has a basaltic to    andesitic composition. It is composed of variable proportions of cummingtonite + biotite +    quartz, ± plagioclase ± garnet ± anthophyllite ± cordierite and ranges from cummingtonite    amphibolite to garnet-biotite schist. Some rocks from the Nuvvuagittuq greenstone belt have lower    142Nd /144Nd ratios than the terrestrial standard (epsilon142Nd = -0.07 to -0.15). The    142Nd/144Nd ratios for the faux-amphibolite correlate positively with their Sm/Nd ratios and    produce a 146Sm-142Nd isochron with an age of 4280 +53 –81 million years. The 4.28 Ga    faux-amphibolite is intruded by highly deformed gabbro sills yielding a 147Sm-143Nd isochron with    a slope corresponding to an age of 4023 ± 110 Ma. The Nuvvuagittuq greenstone belt also comprises    3.8 Ga felsic bands and is surrounded by 3.66 Ga tonalite interpreted to have been produced by    the melting of the older mafic faux-amphibolite. The Nuvvuagittuq greenstone belt thus represents    an Eoarchean/Hadean crustal section comprising the oldest rocks preserved on Earth. The 4.28 Ga    faux-amphibolite is divided into a high-Ti group and a low-Ti group with co-genetic ultramafic    sills and separated by a BIF/silica-formation. At the base of the sequence, the high-Ti    faux-amphibolite is basaltic in composition and has "tholeitic" affinities. The low-Ti    faux-amphibolite above the BIF exhibits a wider range of composition from basalti</description><creator>O'Neil, Jonathan</creator><contributor>Donald M Francis (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Geology</subject><title>The geology of Nuvvuagittuq greenstone belt and its implications for the early earth's evolution</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sh20h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gt58h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):24150</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>