<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:33:12Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):37700" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xx143</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les prédicateurs du changement de poids durant la première année postpartum ont été examinés en utilisant des données de 314 femmes Ghanéennes VIH-positives (VIH-P) et VIH-négatives (VIH-N). L'effet achevé après un an postpartum, en moyenne, était une perte de poids par les femmes qui sont VIH-P et un gain de poids par les femmes qui sont VIH-N. Après avoir contrôler d'autres facteurs, le changement de poids se retrouve négativement corrélé avec VIH-P et le fait d'avoir plus de jours d'allaitement et des maladies, par contre positivement associe avec être un trader. De plus, pour compléter l'analyse quantitative, des informations qualitatives sur les services d'éducation nutritifs fournis aux femmes qui sont VIH-p à Ghana ont été recueillis grâce à des discussions de groupe avec 38 femmes VIH-p, et aussi a travers des entrevues semi-structurées avec 12 inspecteurs de santé, 5 non gouvernementales et gouvernementales personnels et un dirigeant de la communauté. Les obstacles à une éducation nutritionnelle figuraient notamment le manque d'auditoire de matériels appropriés et de la formation continue. L'insécurité financière, le faible soutien des services de santé, et la stigmatisation limite la capacité des femmes à suivre les recommandations reçues. Les femmes VIH-P auraient éventuellement besoin de conseils de nutrition individuels pour les aider à maintenir un poids normal au cours de la période postpartum. </description><description>Predictors of weight change throughout the first year postpartum were examined using data from 314 Ghanaian HIV-positive (HIV-P) and HIV-negative (HIV-N) women. The overall effect over one year postpartum was a loss in average weight in HIV-P women and a gain in average weight in HIV-N women. After controlling for confounders, weight change was negatively associated with being HIV-P and having a higher number of days of breastfeeding and illness, and positively associated with being a trader. To complement the quantitative analysis, qualitative data on nutrition education services provided to HIV-P women in Ghana were collected through focus group discussions with 38 HIV-P women, and semi-structured interviews with 12 health workers, 5 non-governmental and governmental personnel and a community leader. Financial insecurity, low support from health services, and stigma limited the women's ability to follow recommendations received. Barriers to providing more nutrition education included lack of audience-appropriate materials and in-service training. HIV-P women may need individualized nutrition counselling to help them maintain a normal weight during the postpartum period. </description><creator>Chehayber, Hoda</creator><contributor>Grace Marquis (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Health Sciences - Nutrition</subject><title>Postpartum nutrition education services for HIV-positive Ghanaian women are scarce despite their increased risk of weight loss?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547w540.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xx143</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zc77sv10s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The dynamics of cross-linked polymers under stress, such as those thatmake up rubber, are still not well understood. A combination of coherent xrayhomodyne and heterodyne techniques is used in order to measure fluctuations of the system when stretched. The combination of both techniques allows for the measurement of flow patterns, as well as the random nature of the system. After data analysis, the results show that the measurements successfully captured this flow information. The flow velocity was discovered to have a time-dependent nature similar to that of the stress-strain curve. After the flow velocity was extracted, the random nature of the system was analysed. This random motion was discovered not to be dominated by conventional diffusion, but some slower random process.</description><description> La dynamique de polymères réticulés de stress, telles que celle qui compose le caoutchouc, n'est pas encore bien comprise. Une combinaison de techniques homodynes et hétérodynes de rayons x coherentes est utilisé pour mesurer les fluctuations du système, une fois étiré. La combinaison des deux techniques permet la mesure des régimes d'écoulement, ainsi que le caractère aléatoire du système. Après l'analyse des données, les résultats montrent que les mesures ont réussi à capturer cet information. La vitesse d'écoulement a été découverte de contenir une nature en fonction du temps semblable à celle de la courbe contrainte-déformation. Après la vitesse d'écoulement a été extraite, la nature aléatoire du système a été analysé. Cette motion a été découverte au hasard de ne pas être dominé par la diffusion classique, mais de certains processus aléatoires plus lents.</description><creator>Lhermitte, Julien</creator><contributor>Mark Sutton (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Physics - Solid State</subject><title>Using coherent small angle xray scattering to measure velocity fields and random motion</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t330t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77sv10s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n009w638j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Over 260 major rivers flow across international borders, yet many of these vital water resources are stressed by growth in population, consumption, and a changing climate. Only some of these transboundary river basins are effectively managed by the countries that share basin resources, and where management is partial or absent collective action problems are likely to emerge with international consequences. In this thesis I argue that catchment-scale management can promote equitable development, protect riparian ecosystems, and preserve regional security by engaging all users of a basin. I propose a new approach to evaluating and designing basin management based on Elinor Ostrom's common-pool resource (CPR) design principles and focusing on the Ganges River Basin (GRB) as a case study. With modifications for the scale and unique characteristics of transboundary basins, I introduce a new framework for assessing Transboundary Common-pool Resources (TCPR) institutions closely based on the insights and lessons of Ostrom's design. The TCPR framework's descriptive accuracy is methodically derived and validated as an evaluative and prescriptive tool. I apply it in the Ganges Basin, an important example of where equitable access among constituent countries is widely discussed, occasionally pursued, yet little implemented, with severe consequences for downstream communities. This thesis portrays the history and trajectory of transboundary management in the GRB with a focus on India, the most influential basin member, through an analysis of standing treaties and interviews with water resource managers and experts. Joining the details of this case with the TCPR framework provides an assessment of the relevance and durability of present collective agreement in the GRB, as well as specific recommendations for strengthening basin institutions and insuring equitable resource use.</description><description>Plus de 260 grandes rivières traverses des frontières internationales; toutefois, l'augmentation de la population, de la consomation et les changements climates font pression sur une grande partie de ces ressources essentielles d'eau douce. De plus, ce ne sont pas tous les  bassins fluviaux transfrontaliers qui soient gérés efficacement par les pays qui en partagent les ressources. Dans cette thèse, je soutiens que la gestion au niveau du bassin versant affecte tous les utilisateurs du système hydrologique et peut promouvoir le développement équitable, la protection des écosystèmes riverains et la sécurité régionale. Je propose une nouvelle approche pour l'évaluation et la conception de la gestion des bassins versants basée sur une étude de cas du bassin du Gange, et fondée sur des principes d'Elinor Ostrom de ressources commune (ou CPRs : « common-pool resources »). Par le biais de quelques modifications d'échelle et les caractéristiques uniques des bassins transfrontaliers, j'introduis une nouvelle structure pour l'évaluation des institutions des Ressources transfrontières communes (ou TCPR), fondée sur les idées et les leçons de la conception d'Ostrom. La précision descriptive de la structure de TCPR est dérivé méthodiquement et validé comme un outil d'évaluation et de prescription. Je l'applique dans le bassin du Gange qui est un exemple important d'un endroit où l'accès équitable entre les pays qui le composent est largement discuté, parfois poursuivi, mais peu mis en œuvre, avec des conséquences graves pour les communautés en aval. Cette thèse présente l'histoire et la trajectoire de la gestion transfrontalière dans le bassin du Gange en mettant l'accent sur l'Inde, le membre le plus influent du bassin, à travers une analyse de traités existants et des entrevues avec des experts et des gestionnaires de ressources d'eau. L'étude des détails de ce cas avec la structure de TCPR fournit une évaluation de la pertinence et la durabilité du régime actuel dans le bassin du Gange, ainsi que des recommandations spécifiques pour renforcer les institutions de bassin versants et garantir une utilisation équitable des ressources.</description><creator>Adams, Peter</creator><contributor>Peter Gilbert Brown (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Social Sciences - Geography </subject><title>Employing modified common-pool resource design principles in the development of transboundary institutions in the Ganges river basin</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q569p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w638j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hq37vs718</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:45:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Étude de cas d'une classe d'éducation spécialisée : De quelle façon l'esthétisme influence-t-elle l'apprentissage et le développement personnel?Ce mémoire présente une étude de cas sur la façon dont l'esthétisme influence l'apprentissage et le développement personnel dans une classe d'éducation spécialisée. L'objectif est de mieux comprendre l'environnement évolutif de la classe et de son influence sur les élèves et sur moi-même, l'enseignante de la classe témoin. Le cadre de cette étude était une classe d'éducation spécialisée (B-111), située dans une école secondaire de premier cycle. Onze élèves, une préposée et une enseignante ont pris part à cette étude. Les données ont été recueillies et analysées à partir de méthodes issues des récentes recherches en éducation de l'art et plus précisément, sur l'enseignement à partir de l'art. La littérature sur l'esthétisme, sur la négociation de sens et sur l'apprentissage a servi les besoins de cette étude et les commentaires, les opinions ainsi que les  travaux artistiques des participants y sont reliés. La question à savoir si l'esthétisme de la salle de classe crée un sentiment d'appartenance, agissant comme source de motivation sur l'assiduité en classe et sur le respect de l'établissement scolaire a été soulevée. Cette étude de cas démontre l'importance de la création de liens avec les élèves. La connaissance de la nature spécifique de la classe s'avère être un facteur crucial dans la création d'un environnement d'apprentissage sain et équilibré. Cette étude inspirera peut-être les directeurs d'école et les commissions scolaires, les décorateurs d'intérieur et les architectes, lorsque viendra le temps de concevoir les plans architecturaux, la décoration, la construction et l'organisation d'une école ou d'une salle de classe.</description><description>A qualitative study of a special-needs class: how attention to aesthetic considerations informs learning and individual growth. This thesis describes a qualitative study of how attention to aesthetic considerations informs learning and individual growth in a special-needs class. The study is intended to provide an understanding of the evolving classroom environment and its influences on the individual students and myself as the teacher. The research context was a junior high school special-needs class (B111) of eleven students, one teacher and an attendant.  Art-based educational research methods were used to conduct and analyze the data. Literature on aesthetics, meaning making and learning are discussed and connected to the documented comments, opinions and art works of the participants.  The question whether or not a sense of belonging, if fostered through attention to aesthetic considerations, could motivate students to come to class and respect school grounds and property is addressed in the research. This qualitative study illustrates that getting to know the student population and the nature of the class and school is a crucial factor amongst others that contribute towards a healthy learning environment. This can be inspiring to administrators, educators, interior designers and architects when considering the factors involved in designing, building or organizing a school or classroom.  </description><creator>Moubarak, Elizabeth</creator><contributor>Boyd Eric White (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Education - Art </subject><title>A case study of a special needs class: how attention to aesthetic considerations informs learning and individual growth</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881r19w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vs718</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827h04v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis places two important Muslim intellectual leaders of reform in Bukhara in the late 19th and early 20th centuries in a historical and religious context. Jadidism in Central Asia, an Islamic reform movement during this period, is still an understudied topic both in the context of Islamic reform movements and the wider study of Islamic history. The concentration of this project is on efforts towards social reforms in Bukhara by focusing on two major actors in the Jadid movement, ‗Abdalrauf Fitrat and Sadriddin Aini. Through an analytical review of original works written by ‗Abdalrauf Fitrat and Sadriddin Aini, as well as the information provided by secondary sources supporting the historical circumstances and later perceptions of these two intellectuals' influences, this thesis will provide a useful contribution to the growing body of western literature in the field of Central Asian Islam. By using a comparative approach, the thesis examines instances of agreement and disagreement between the two reformers using a variety of sources. Many reports concerning the Jadids at this time have either lumped many reformers together as a singular body or championed the type of reforms proposed by one figure over those or another. It is hoped that this thesis has elucidated the perspectives of reform for Aini and Fitrat and highlighted the multiplicity of ideas present among the Jadids. It is also hoped this work will set a positive foundation on which to set future works concerning the Jadids of Central Asia.</description><description>Ce mémoire situe deux importants leaders réformistes intellectuels musulmans de Bukhara de la fin du 19ème siècle et du début du 20ème siècle dans un contexte historique et religieux. Le jadidisme, mouvement réformiste islamique de l'Asie centrale durant cette période, est très peu étudié, aussi bien dans le cadre des travaux qui portent sur les mouvements réformistes islamiques que dans le cadre de l'histoire islamique en général. Aussi, cette étude examine les efforts qui visent les réformes sociales à Bukhara de 'Abdalrauf Fitrat et Sadriddin Aini, deux acteurs majeurs du jadidisme. Pour ce faire, elle s'appuie sur la revue analytique des écrits originaux de 'Abdalrauf Fitrat et ceux de Sadriddin Aini, ainsi que sur les conclusions des sources secondaires concernant les circonstances historiques et les perceptions ultérieures des influences de ces deux intellectuels. En appliquant une approche comparative à un ensemble de sources, ce mémoire étudie les points de convergence et de divergence entre les deux réformistes. En fait, les travaux existants qui portent sur le jadidisme tendent soit à mettre les réformistes de ce mouvement dans un seul bloc, soit à favoriser un type de réformes proposé par l'un d'eux au détriment des autres. Aussi, ce mémoire se propose de souligner les différentes perspectives réformistes de Aini et de Fitrat, et donc de relever la pluralité des idées qui est véhiculée par le jadidisme. De même, ce mémoire se propose d'établir les fondements pour les études futures qui portent sur le jadidisme de l'Asie centrale. Ce mémoire constitue donc une contribution au corpus de la littérature occidentale dans le domaine de l'Islam de l'Asie centrale.</description><creator>Mixon, Candace</creator><contributor>Turgay, A. Uner (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Religion - History of </subject><title>The Jadids in Bukhara: the juxtaposition of the reforms of Aini and Fitrat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73q117b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827h04v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z709182w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mesh adaptation is modification of an existing mesh as to accurately capture physical phenomena without increasing computational cost excessively. Among many challenges remained in this field, "unsteady mesh adaptation" and "functional-output mesh adaptation" are the two topics addressed in this work. "Transient-Fixed-point" method is a new approach for unsteady mesh adaptation as an implicit coupling between the mesh and the solution. What differentiates transient-fixed-point from steady adaptation methods is the metric intersection through time. In this work a new scheme for transient metric intersection is proposed for orthogonal data preserving. Another challenge in mesh adaptation is to control mesh modifications according to an integral function, known as functional-output, (e.g. lift, drag, moments, etc.) rather than the directly computed variables (e.g. velocity, pressure, Mach, etc.). Such control comes from a suitable edge-based error evaluation to be defined according to the chosen functional. One such definition is proposed in this work that drives surface mesh adaptation based on the chosen functional-output function. </description><description>L'adaptation de maillage est la modification d'un maillage existant afin de saisir avec précision les phénomènes physiques sans augmentation excessive du coût de calcul. Parmi les nombreux défis qui demeurent dans ce domaine, l'adaptation de maillage de manière instable et l'adaptation de maillage selon un « functional-output »  sont les deux thèmes abordés dans ce travail. La méthode « Transient-Fixed-point » est une nouvelle approche pour l'adaptation de maillage de manière instable. Cette méthode consiste à formée un lien entre le maillage et la solution. Ce qui différencie la méthode « Transient-Fixed-point » de méthodes d'adaptation constante est l'intersection des métriques à travers le temps. Dans cet ouvrage, un nouveau régime pour l'intersection de métriques transitoire est proposé afin de préserver l'orthogonalité des données.Un autre défi de l'adaptation de maillage est de contrôler les modifications apporté à la maille selon une fonction intégrale, connu sous le nom de « functional-output » (par exemple, la portance, la trainée, des moments, etc.) plutôt que de calculées directement les variables (par exemple vitesse, pression, Mach, etc.). Un tel contrôle provient d'une d'évaluation approprié de l'erreur des lisières à être définies en fonction des choix de « functional ». Une telle définition est proposée dans ce travail qui entraine l'adaptation de maillage de surface en fonction du« functional-output » choisi.</description><creator>Najafiyazdi, Mostafa</creator><contributor>Wagdi George Habashi (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical </subject><title>Anisotropic mesh adaptation for transient problems and functional-output variables</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d5701630.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z709182w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60d1714</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Contexte: Le cortex cingulaire antérieur (CCA), le cortex orbito-frontal (COF) et les noyaux gris centraux ont été identifiés dans les recherches sur la neurobiologie de l'agressivité pathologique. Ces structures seraient impliquées dans la régulation 'top-down' des impulsions produites dans le système limbique. Le but de cette étude était d'identifier les corrélations neuroanatomiques de l'agressivité impulsive chez les enfants en santé ayant un développement normal. Méthodologie:  Les données de 193 sujets de 6 à 18 ans ont été obtenues de l'étude NIH MRI Study of Normal Brain Development après un contrôle visuel de qualité des données (1). L'épaisseur corticale et les volumes sous-corticaux ont été obtenus avec des programmes automatisés. Le niveau d'agressivité a été mesuré avec l'échelle de comportements agressifs (AGG) obtenue du questionnaire Child Behavior Checklist. Les scores de AGG ont été analysés en régression linéaire avec l'épaisseur corticale et le volume des noyaux gris centraux en utilisant des modèles de premier et de deuxième ordre, et en contrôlant pour les effets de l'âge, du sexe, du numéro de scanner et du volume cérébral total. L'interaction 'AGG X sexe' a aussi été analysée. Une correction statistique de type random field theory pour comparaisons multiples a été appliquée aux résultats.Résultats: Une association positive a été trouvée entre les scores de AGG et le volume du striatum bilatéralement  (droite: r=0.238, p=0.001; gauche: r=0.188, p=0.01).  Une association significative était aussi présente entre AGG et l'épaisseur corticale du CCA droit et du CCA sous-géniculé droit dans un modèle linéaire de deuxième ordre (p &lt; 0.05, corrigé). Les scores AGG élevés étaient associés à un CCA droit relativement mince. Une tendance d'association entre l'épaisseur corticale et l'interaction 'AGG X sexe' a aussi été trouvée dans le COF et le CCA bilatéralement. Conclusion: Cette étude démontre l'existence d'une relation entre l'agressivité impulsive chez les enfants en santé et la structure anatomique du striatum, ainsi que du CCA droit. Elle suggère également l'existence de patterns d'associations spécifiques au sexe dans la matière grise du COF et du CCA. Ces résultats pourraient guider la recherche clinique sur le trouble oppositionnel avec provocation et le trouble des conduites. MOTS CLÉS: Agressivité,  Épaisseur corticale, Cortex cingulaire antérieur,  Cortex orbito-frontal, Striatum,  Imagerie par résonance magnétique (IRM) </description><description>Background: The anterior cingulate cortex (ACC), orbito-frontal cortex (OFC) and basal ganglia have been implicated in the neurobiology of pathological aggression. They are thought to be the structures involved in top-down regulation of impulses from the limbic system. This study aimed at identifying neuroanatomical correlates of impulsive aggression in healthy children. Methods:  Data from 193 representative 6-18 year-old healthy children were obtained from the NIH MRI Study of Normal Brain Development after a blinded quality control (1). Cortical thickness and subcortical volumes were obtained with automated software. Aggression levels were measured with the Aggressive Behavior scale (AGG) of the Child Behavior Checklist (CBCL). AGG scores were regressed against cortical thickness and basal ganglia volumes using first and second-order linear models while controlling for age, gender, scanner site and total brain volume. 'Gender by AGG' interactions were analyzed. Whole brain random field theory corrections for multiple comparisons were implemented.Results:  There were positive associations between bilateral striatal volumes and AGG scores (right: r=0.238, p=0.001; left: r=0.188, p=0.01).  A significant association was found with right ACC and subgenual ACC cortical thickness in a second-order linear model (p &lt; 0.05, corrected). High AGG scores were associated with a relatively thin right ACC cortex. An 'AGG by gender' interaction trend was found in bilateral OFC and ACC associations with AGG scores. Conclusion:  This study shows the existence of relationships between impulsive aggression in healthy children and the structure of the striatum and right ACC.  It also suggests the existence of gender specific patterns of association in OFC/ACC grey matter.  These results may guide research on oppositional-defiant and conduct disorders.KEYWORDS: Aggression, Cortical Thickness, Anterior Cingulate Cortex, Orbito-Frontal Cortex, Striatum, Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI)</description><creator>Ducharme, Simon</creator><contributor>Alan C Evans (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Sherif Karama (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Health Sciences - Mental Health</subject><title>Neuroanatomical correlates of Child Behavior Checklist Aggressive Behavior scores in typically developing children</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354k37t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60d1714</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386p647</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fondés sur la réécriture d'ouvrages latins et médio-latins à forte teneur historique, les romans de Thèbes, d'Éneas, de Brut et de Troie (ca. 1150-1165) signent la « naissance du roman » en empruntant leur sujet à l'histoire. Pourtant, peu d'études ont été consacrées aux liens qui se tissent entre ces romans d'antiquité et la tradition historiographique en tant que genre littéraire (« estoire » et « historia »). La critique tend en effet à approcher les rapports entre l'historiographie et le genre romanesque naissant d'un point de vue strictement thématique de sorte qu'elle néglige souvent d'interroger leurs interactions génériques. Il s'agira donc de démontrer que les premières œuvres romanesques peuvent se définir par leur rapport conscient – et subversif – au genre historiographique médiéval. En conjuguant l'approche jaussienne de la théorie des genres aux méthodes de la « nouvelle philologie », il faudra d'abord établir que la réception médiévale du corpus se laisse infléchir par une double lecture historiographique et romanesque. Cette confusion typologique, diversement relayée par le témoignage des codices, pourra ensuite s'expliquer par une contexture poétique qui se joue des distinctions génériques. Il apparaîtra ainsi que les premiers romanciers convoquent délibérément les conventions de l'historiographie pour poser un geste fondateur dans l'histoire du genre romanesque : ils érigent une frontière – poreuse – entre roman et histoire.</description><description>Recognized as the first medieval instances of the romance genre, the Roman de Thebes, Roman d'Enéas, Roman de Brut and Roman de Troie (ca. 1150-1165) are based on the rewriting of Latin texts deeply rooted in history. Yet few studies have explored the relationship between these romans d'antiquité and medieval historiography, as a literary genre (estoire and historia). There has indeed been a tendency amongst critics to focus on a thematic analysis of the links between the "first romances" and history, at the expense of a more generic approach. Our task, therefore, is to show that this corpus can be defined by its conscious – and subversive – relationship with medieval historiography. By combining the Jaussian approach of the theory of genres with the methods of "New Philology", we shall first establish that the medieval readers interpreted romans d'antiquité not only as romance, but also as works of historiography. This double interpretation, confirmed on various accounts by the manuscripts, will then be explained by a poetic structure that playfully blurs the line between generic distinctions. Hence it will appear that the "first novelist" deliberately use the conventions of historiography in order to lay the foundation of a genre that will maintain a close, yet complicated, relationship with history.</description><creator>Bottex-Ferragne, Ariane</creator><contributor>Isabelle Arseneau (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Literature - Medieval</subject><title>Réécrire l'histoire: genre romanesque et tradition historiographique dans les romans d'antiquité</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rq41p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386p647</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f1881r20n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La perte de tissus musculaire et adipeux associée à la cachexie du cancer pourrait être reliée à des taux accrus de néoglucogénèse (GNG) et de turnover des protéines corporelles.  Cette étude a mesuré la contribution fractionnelle (%) du glycogène, du glycérol et du phosphoénolpyruvate (PEP) à la production endogène de glucose (EGP), à l'aide du 2H2O oral chez des patients avec cancer du poumon (NSCLC) et des sujets témoins appariés.  De plus, les cinétiques de protéines et de glucose ont été quantifiées à l'aide des traceurs 13C-leucine et 3H3-glucose, à jeun et durant un clamp hyperinsulinique, euglycémique. Les taux d'EGP et les contributions fractionnelles des substrats n'étaient pas différents entres les groupes NSCLC et témoins suite à un jeûne de 17 heures.  Le PEP et le glycogène ont contribué également et majoritairement au EGP; le glycérol contribuant pour &lt; 10%. Les patients avec NSCLC étaient résistants à l'insuline. Leur taux inférieurs de captation du glucose n'étaient pas corrélés avec le flux néoglucogénique, mais celui-ci était positivement relié aux taux d'oxydation des protéines, indiquant une moindre rétention.  </description><description>The loss of muscle mass and adipose tissue in cancer cachexia may be linked to increased rates of gluconeogenesis (GNG) and altered whole-body protein metabolism.  This study measured the fractional contributions (%) of glycogen, glycerol and phophoenolpyruvate (PEP) to endogenous glucose production (EGP) using oral 2H2O in non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC) patients and matched healthy control subjects.  Additionally, 13C-leucine and 3H3-glucose tracers were used to measure whole-body protein turnover and glucose kinetics respectively during the fasting state and during a hyperinsulinemic euglycemic clamp.  The rate of EGP and the fractional substrate contributions were not different between the NSCLC and control groups following a 17-hour fast.  The majority of EGP came from equal contributions of PEP and glycogen, whereas glycerol contributed &lt; 10%.  NSCLC patients were insulin resistant; their lesser clamp glucose uptake was not correlated to GNG flux, but rates of protein oxidation were, indicating less protein retention.</description><creator>MacAdams, Jacqueline</creator><contributor>Stephanie Chevalier (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Health Sciences - Nutrition</subject><title>Substrate contribution to endogenous glucose production, insulin resistance and protein metabolism in non-small cell lung cancer cachexia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580r71j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881r20n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hk701</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse examine la compréhension courante des droits d'autonomie de l'enfant tel que transmise par la Convention relative aux droits de l'enfant de l'ONU. Nous examinons si cette conception est efficace dans l'accomplissement des droits d'autonomie de l'enfant ainsi que dans le contournement des obstacles à la réalisation de ces droits qui existent dans certaines juridictions. Cette analyse propose un regard critique sur le processus de négociation et de rédaction de la Convention relative aux droits de l'enfant dans le but de développer une meilleure appréciation des notions sous-jacentes à la compréhension courante et, par conséquent, des défis pour sa mise en oeuvre. Cette analyse propose  qu'il y aurait un besoin de revoir et de reformuler les droits d'autonomie des enfants en intégrant la notion des devoirs. En utilisant l'exemple de la Charte Africaine des droits et du bien-être de l'enfant, ce texte examine les avantages d'une telle approche.</description><description>This thesis reviews the current understanding of autonomy rights of the child as communicated by the UN Convention on the Rights of the Child. It examines whether this conception is effective in achieving the fulfilment of the autonomy rights of the child, as well as in responding to the key challenges in the realisation of these rights within some jurisdictions. It proposes a critical look at the negotiations and drafting process of the Convention on the Rights of the Child in order to develop and foster a better appreciation of the basis of the current understanding and, therefore, the existing challenges in implementation.  It suggests that there is a need to re-conceive the autonomy rights for children by integrating the notion of duties. Using the example of the Africa Charter on the Rights and Welfare of the Child (ACRWC), it explores the advantages of such an approach.</description><creator>Nnadozie, Ugochi</creator><contributor>Angela Campbell (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>Integrating rights and duties: achieving children's autonomy in a culturally diverse world</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mr54k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hk701</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:028711166</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'objectif global de cette recherche est d'évaluer les mécanismes importants de déposition des particules NZVI modifiées en surface dans les milieux granulaires subsurfaciques pendant le transport. Bien que les particules NZVI modifiées en surface aient montré un transport plus facile que les particules NZVI nues, il y a un manque de connaissance sur la façon dont des simples paramètres, tel que la concentration des particules NZVI, leur taille, la vitesse d'écoulement de la phase aqueuse et la taille des particules de sable, influencent le transport des nanoparticules. Dans la première étude, on a étudié les modèles des particules CMC- et PAA-ZVI élues des colonnes remplies de sable dans une gamme de vitesses de l'eau des pores, et des concentrations influentes de particules NZVI. . Les concentrations effluentes relatives des deux types de particules NZVI ont diminué avec la diminution des vitesses d'écoulement et avec l'augmentation des concentrations des particules. Les particules PAA-NZVI présentaient une élution plus lente que les particules CMC-NZVI dans des conditions expérimentales identiques, ceci étant attribué à une cinétique d'agrégation plus rapide pour les particules PAA-NZVI. La réduction de la stabilité colloïdale due à l'agrégation des particules CMC- et PAA-NZVI a été vérifiée en utilisant les tests de sédimentation et on a trouvé que les particules PAA-NZVI ont été moins stables que les particules CMC-NZVI. La deuxième étude portait sur l'évaluation quantitative de la cinétique d'agrégation et les effets d'agrégation possibles sur la déposition des particules NZVI. L'agrégation des particules CMC-NZVI a entraîné un changement dans la distribution de la taille des particules (PSD) avec le temps, et les changements dans la taille des particules étaient évalués par l'analyse de suivi des nanoparticules (NTA).  Les effets de la concentration des particules dans la gamme sur le transport dans les milieux poreux ont été évalués en comparant les profils de temps d'élution des particules CMC-NZVI dans les colonnes remplies de sable. Les profils d'élution des particules NZVI ont eu un bon ajustement avec les équations cinétiques d'agrégation couplées aux équations de transport colloïdal, qui tiennent compte de la déposition des particules et de détachement. La troisième étude portait sur l'évaluation de l'importance de la filtration des particules CMC-NZVI pendant le transport dans les milieux poreux subsurfaciques modèles. Des expériences de laboratoire ont été effectuées pour évaluer le transport des particules CMC-NZVI dans les colonnes  et trois concentrations différentes. Les courbes percées (BTC) et les profils de rétention des particules CMC-NZVI le long de la colonne ont été analysés afin de caractériser le transport. Les courbes BTC suggèrent que les concentrations effluentes diminuent avec la diminution du diamètre moyen du sable. Une très élevée rétention des particules CMC-NZVI a été observée, particulièrement pour les sables plus fins. Ces observations sont en accord avec la rétention des particules dans les milieux poreux due à la filtration et au calage. Deux modèles de transport colloïdal qui considèrent 1) la déposition des particules uniquement par attachement, et 2) la rétention des particules par filtration et déposition par attachement, ont été ajustés aux données expérimentales. La comparaison des données expérimentales avec les calculs du modèle suggèrent qu'en plus de la déposition sur la surface du collecteur, les particules CMC-NZVI sont retirées de la solution par filtration dans les lits remplis de sable, avec des coefficients de filtration qui diminuent avec le diamètre du sable.  </description><description>AbstractThe overall objective of this research is to evaluate significant mechanisms for deposition of surface-modified NZVI in granular subsurface media during transport. Although surface-modified NZVI have been shown to transport more easily than bare NZVI, there is a lack of knowledge of how different parameters such NZVI particle concentration, NZVI size, aqueous-phase flow velocity, and sand particle size influence nanoparticle transport. To investigate the effects of these parameters on transport, a number of laboratory experiments were conducted with NZVI synthesized from ferrous sulfate in the presence of polymers that were effective in colloidal stabilization of the particles. The bare and surface modified-NZVI was characterized for size and surface chemistry by a wide array of analytical instruments. The polymer-stabilized NZVI were employed in three different studies to identify parameters that influence deposition of NZVI in model, granular, subsurface media. In the first study, the breakthrough patterns of carboxymethyl cellulose (CMC)- and polyacrylic acid (PAA)- stabilized NZVI eluted from packed sand columns under a range of pore water velocities and NZVI influent concentrations  were investigated.  The NZVI effluent relative concentrations of both types of particles decreased with decreasing flow velocities and increasing particle concentrations. PAA-NZVI exhibited slower elution from the columns than CMC-NZVI under identical experimental conditions, and this is attributed to more rapid aggregation kinetics of PAA-NZVI. The second study focused on the quantitative evaluation of aggregation kinetics and the possible effects of aggregation on NZVI deposition. Aggregation of CMC-NZVI particles resulted in a change in particle size distribution (PSD) with time, and the changes in particle size were evaluated by nanoparticle tracking analyzer (NTA).  The effects of particle concentrations on the transport in porous media were evaluated by comparing the time profiles of elution of CMC-NZVI from packed sand columns. Changes in PSD over time were responsible for a gradual increase in effluent concentration between 1 and 4 pore volumes, and beyond 4 pore volumes particle detachment contributed to non-steady state effluent concentrations. The NZVI elution profiles had a good fit with aggregation kinetics equations coupled to colloid transport equations that account for particle deposition and detachment. The third study focused on assessing the significance of straining of CMC-NZVI particles during transport in model subsurface porous media. Laboratory experiment were conducted to assess the transport of CMC-NZVI in columns packed with four different sized sands  and with three different concentrations. . Breakthrough curves (BTC) and retention profiles of CMC-NZVI along the column length were analyzed to characterize CMC-NZVI transport. The breakthrough curves suggest that with decrease in mean sand diameter, the effluent concentrations decrease. Very high CMC-NZVI particle retention towards the inlet, particularly for the finer sands  was observed. These observations are consistent with particle retention in porous media due to straining and/or wedging. Two colloid transport models considering 1) particle deposition by attachment only, and 2) particle retention by straining along with particle deposition by attachment were fitted to the experimental data. Comparison of experimental data and the model calculations suggest that in addition to deposition on collector surface, CMC-NZVI particles are removed from the solution by straining in packed sand beds, with straining rate coefficients that decrease with increase in sand diameter. </description><creator>Raychoudhury, Trishikhi</creator><contributor>Nathalie Tufenkji (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Subhasis Ghoshal (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Civil</subject><title>Transport of surface-modified iron nanoparticles through model subsurface porous media</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f5370.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/028711166</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns064987g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A number of innovative techniques were developed to carry genetic material into cells, making gene therapy one of the most active fields in biotechnology. Interest in this domain is due to two factors: the therapeutic potential of the approach and lack of delivery systems which fulfil all requirements for clinical implementation. The advent of new nanotechnologies, combined with a better understanding of biological processes, enables the development of more sophisticated tools for delivery of genetic material to cells. This thesis reports on these novel nanocarriers with promising features for gene delivery. The first part of this thesis describes the state of the art of gene delivery approaches relevant to the research conducted throughout this PhD project. Major gene delivery systems are described to give insight into current advancements, limitations and challenges in the field. This section is followed by a review of therapeutic agent delivery using chitosan-based nanocarriers. In this review, we provide a summary of the most important progress concerning the use of chitosan to produce nanocarriers for several forms of delivery; this includes small molecules, proteins and genetic material. New trends in the area of gene delivery such as the development of stimuli-sensitive devices are described in a separate chapter in order to illustrate the new trends in the field of therapeutic delivery. Together, these three chapters provide a background to better understand the motivation behind the development of the nanocarriers. The second part of the thesis focuses on design and assembly of novel non-viral nanocarriers for gene delivery applications. The characterization and optimization of a delivery system formulated with chitosan and hyaluronic acid are presented, providing an original and viable option to transfer genetic material into cells. The functionalization of the chitosan-based nanocarriers, to obtain an ultraviolet light stimuli-sensitive gene delivery system, is also accomplished, allowing a better control of the spatiotemporal release of genetic material. Validation of the assembly, combined with a proof of concept of nanocarrier functionality, is demonstrated.The research conducted during this PhD thesis represents a significant step towards the development of a new generation of smart carriers, with safer and more efficient delivery of therapeutics. It provides the foundation for further development of a low-cost and easy to produce delivery system, with readily available, biocompatible and biodegradable materials with tunable properties. </description><description>Une multitude de techniques innovatrices ont été établies, pour transporter ou effectuer la correction de gènes à l'intérieur des cellules; rendant la thérapie génique un des secteurs les plus actifs de la recherche biomédicale. L'intérêt pour ce champ d'expertise est principalement attribuable à deux principaux facteurs : les gigantesques attentes médicales associées à ce type de traitement, ainsi que l'absence de système présentant les caractéristiques nécessaires pour l'implémentation de cette technologie, dans le milieu clinique. L'avènement de procédés novateurs, combiné à une compréhension plus approfondie des processus biologiques, rend possible l'élaboration d'outils plus sophistiqués pour la vectorisation de matériel génétique. En l'occurrence, cette thèse expose une de ces nouvelles innovations, par la présentation d'un nanotransporteur comportant des particularités avantageuses, pour de futures applications dans le domaine de la thérapie génique.La première partie de cet ouvrage offre une vue d'ensemble des derniers développements technologique, en relation avec le projet de recherche de ces études de PhD. Un survol des principaux progrès technologies, pour exécuter l'insertion d'information génétique à l'intérieur des organismes, est décrit. Cela permet de connaître les limitations, les avancées et les défis actuels qui restent à surmonter pour permettre, à ce type de traitement, d'être utilisé cliniquement. Cette section est suivie de deux revues concises de la littérature. L'une présente l'utilisation de nanotransporteurs, constitués de chitosan, pour le largage d'agents médicinaux. L'autre décrit les principes fondamentaux, reliés aux systèmes répondants et sensibles aux stimuli spécifiques afin de libérer des composées thérapeutiques. La compilation de ces données scientifiques constitue un élément essentiel dans la conception des transporteurs réalisés au cours de ce doctorat. La seconde partie consiste en la conceptualisation, la réalisation et la validation du concept des nanoparticules à base de chitosan et d'acide hyaluronique comme véhicule de matériel génétique. L'optimisation et la caractérisation de ces nanovecteurs, ont été effectuées avec succès ; fournissant ainsi une avenue prometteuse pour le transfert de gènes à l'intérieur des cellules. Un composé chimique photosensible a été synthétisé et incorporé aux nanoparticules décrites ci-haut, pour leur conférer une fonction particulière : le largage d'ADN en réponse à des stimuli lumineux. L'ensemble du travail accompli durant cette thèse a permis de développer un vecteur du matériel génétique, peu coûteux et facile à produire, avec des matériaux biocompatibles et biodégradables. Elle constitue une contribution considérable dans l'élaboration de véhicules non viraux, pour sa mise en application dans le domaine de la thérapie génique.</description><creator>Duceppe, Nicolas</creator><contributor>Maryam Tabrizian (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Design and development of novel chitosan/hyaluronic acid-based nanocarriers for gene delivery</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj139623h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064987g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h702qb49d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La matière organique du sol (MOS) assure la qualité et la productivité du sol et représente le plus grand réservoir de C de la biosphère terrestre. Comprendre les mécanismes de rétention du carbone organique du sol (COS) s'avère essentiel pour évaluer le potentiel des sols à agir comme puits de C et pour assurer leur qualité et leur productivité futures. La présente recherche visait à évaluer, en conditions contrôlées, la stabilisation du C et de l'N provenant de résidus de culture nouvellement incorporés dans les horizons superficiel et profond d'un sol argileux des Basses-Terres du St-Laurent. Des échantillons de sol des horizons superficiel (0-20 cm, 31.3 g COS kg-1 sol) et profond (30-70 cm, 4.5 g COS kg-1 sol) ont été incubés (25ºC, -38 kPa, C/N=10) pendant 51 jours avec des doses croissantes (0 à 40 g C kg-1 sol) de résidus de maïs enrichis en 13C et 15N. La minéralisation du C était plus importante dans l'horizon superficiel que dans l'horizon profond, alors que la quantité de nouveau C retenue dans le sol entier était similaire dans les deux horizons, suggérant ainsi qu'une minéralisation du COS autochtone est survenue. Le C et l'N des résidus ont été retenus préférentiellement dans les grands macroagrégats (&gt;1000 µm) dans l'horizon profond, mais dans les petits macroagrégats (250-1000 µm) dans l'horizon superficiel. L'enrichissement des macroagrégats en C et N nouveaux s'est produit par adsorption à petite échelle (&lt; 50 µm) et par occlusion à grande échelle (&gt;250 µm) simultanément dans le sol. Le fractionnement densimétrique couplé à l'analyse minéralogique du sol a révélé qu'une proportion plus grande du C et de l'N autochtones et provenant des résidus était associée aux phases minérales dans l'horizon profond que dans l'horizon superficiel. Les complexes organo-minéraux de l'horizon profond étaient enrichis en N autochtone et provenant des résidus, ce qui indique une adsorption préférentielle des composés azotés sur les surfaces minérales non saturées lors des premières étapes de formation des complexes organo-minéraux. Ainsi, les horizons superficiel et profond étudiés peuvent tous deux accumuler davantage de C et d'N provenant des résidus, mais le potentiel de séquestration du C et de l'N par association organo-minérale stable s'avère plus important dans l'horizon profond que dans l'horizon superficiel.</description><description>Soil organic matter (SOM) is a key element in soil quality and productivity, and represents the biggest C pool of the terrestrial biosphere. Understanding soil organic carbon (SOC) retention mechanisms is necessary to address their role as potential C sink, and ensure their quality and productivity for future generations. The objective of this research was to examine, under controlled conditions, the stabilization of newly added C and N coming from crop residues in topsoil and subsoil horizons of a heavy clay soil from the St-Lawrence Lowlands. Topsoil (0-20 cm depth, 31.3 g SOC kg-1 soil) and subsoil (30-70 cm depth, 4.5 g SOC kg-1 soil) were incubated (25ºC, -38 kPa, C/N = 10) for 51 d with increasing amounts (from 0 to 40 g C kg-1 soil) of 13C-15N-labelled corn residues. Carbon mineralization was greater in topsoil than subsoil, but comparable amounts of residue-C were retained in both soils, on a whole soil basis. This suggests that the extra C lost from the topsoil came from the mineralization of autochthonous SOC. Preferential retention of residue-derived C and N occurred in large macroaggregates (&gt;1000 µm) in the subsoil, and in small macroaggregates (250-1000 µm) in the topsoil. Macroaggregate enrichment in residue-derived C and N occurred simultaneously through small-scale adsorption (&lt; 50 µm) and large-scale occlusion (&gt;250 µm). Sequential density fractionation of soil coupled with X-ray diffraction mineralogical analysis revealed a greater proportion of autochthonous and residue-derived C and N associated with soil minerals in subsoil than topsoil. Subsoil organo-mineral complexes were enriched in residue-derived N, indicating preferential adsorption of nitrogenous compounds onto unsaturated mineral surfaces in the early stages of organo-mineral complexes formation. In conclusion, topsoil and subsoil horizons of a heavy clay soil from Eastern Canada can accumulate substantial amounts of residue-derived C and N, with greater potential for C and N sequestration in stable organo-mineral complexes in subsoil than topsoil.</description><creator>Poirier, Vincent</creator><contributor>Joann Karen Whalen (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Denis Angers (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Agriculture - Soil Science</subject><title>Investigating the mechanisms of soil organic matter stabilization in a clayey soil of the St-Lawrence lowlands, Québec, Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741w871.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702qb49d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dx56d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of the present thesis was to investigate the role of specific cognitive representations in some of people's important life outcomes. Episodic memories were chosen as one type of specific cognitive representation and psychological need satisfaction was identified as a core affective and procedural representation of these memories. In Article 1, need satisfaction was found to be an essential psychological component of episodic memories and to be associated with well-being. This relationship also remained after controlling for other memory components that have been used in past research and for various measures of self-knowledge such as traits. Article 2 expanded the investigation of the association between need satisfaction in episodic memories and well-being by examining their prospective relationship as well as the potential causal mechanism implicated in this relationship. Article 3 examined the role of need satisfaction in episodic memories related to a context, namely romantic relationships, and showed the context-dependent value of episodic memories, as well as their behavioral and long-term consequences. Overall, these three articles suggest that episodic memories are particularly at play in people's lives and that they reflect an important measurement level to take into account. The General Discussion of the present thesis outlines the advantages of examining specific cognitive representations in the fields of social and personality psychology.</description><description>Le but de la présente thèse était d'investiguer le rôle des représentations cognitives spécifiques sur certains aspects importants de la vie des gens. Les souvenirs épisodiques ont été choisis comme un type de représentation cognitive spécifique et la satisfaction des besoins psychologiques a été identifiée comme une composante affective et procédurale centrale à ces souvenirs. Dans l'Article 1, la satisfaction des besoins s'est révélée être une composante psychologique essentielle des souvenirs épisodiques associée au bien-être psychologique. Cette association est également demeurée significative après avoir contrôlé pour l'effet de d'autres composantes des souvenirs qui ont été utilisées dans des recherches passées et pour l'effet de plusieurs mesures de connaissances de soi conceptuelles comme les traits. L'Article 2 a approfondi l'examen de l'association entre la satisfaction des besoins dans les souvenirs et le bien-être en testant leur relation prospective de même que le mécanisme causal potentiel impliqué dans cette relation. L'Article 3 a examiné le rôle de la satisfaction des besoins dans les souvenirs reliée à un contexte, soit celui des relations de couple, de même que leurs conséquences à long termes et comportementales. En somme, ces trois articles suggèrent que les souvenirs épisodiques sont particulièrement en jeu dans la vie des gens et qu'ils reflètent un niveau de mesure important à prendre en considération. La Discussion Générale de la présente thèse illustre les avantages d'examiner des représentations cognitives spécifiques dans les champs de la psychologie sociale et de la personnalité.</description><creator>Philippe, Frederick</creator><contributor>Richard Koestner (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Psychology - Social</subject><title>Exploring the role of episodic memories in people's lives</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x793t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dx56d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1544bt47x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Objectifs: Déterminer s'il existe un lien entre le surpoids et l'échec d'un traitement antibiotique (ÉTA) et si le fait de ne pas régler la dose en fonction du poids peut en être la cause.  Méthodes: À partir d'une étude historique de cohorte, nous avons utilisé un échantillon aléatoire de 18 014 patients consentants tiré des enquêtes de Santé Québec entre 1992 et 1998 (taux de réponse de 85%).  Parmi les patients sélectionnés, on retrouvait des groupes de personnes de poids normal, faisant de l'embonpoint et souffrant d'obésité avec un écart d'âge variant de 20 à 79 ans et ayant reçu au moins un traitement antibiotique entre le début de l'enquête et décembre 2005.  Pour mesurer l'ÉTA, nous avons noté les répétitions de prescriptions d'antibiotiques ou les hospitalisations supplémentaires à cause d'infections au cours du mois suivant le traitement initial de chaque participant.  Les ratios de la dose quotidienne (DQ) d'antibiotiques et de la dose quotidienne par rapport à l'indice de masse corporelle (DQ:IMC) ont été calculés pour les personnes avec une prescription d'antibiotiques oraux.  La régression logistique à été utilisée pour déterminer si le surpoids et/ou l'obésité ainsi que d'autres facteurs de dose (ex. le ratio DQ:IMC) constituaient des variables prédictives pour l'ÉTA. Par ailleurs, l'ANOVA avec l'ajustement pour comparaisons multiples de Tukey-Kramer ont été utilisés pour déterminer si les ratios DQ:IMC variaient de façon significative d'un groupe à l'autre, ce qui signalerait l'absence de dosage en fonction du poids.  Résultats : Parmi les 6 179 patients sélectionnés, 828 (13.4%) avaient subi un ÉTA durant la période d'évaluation.  Les résultats ont révélé que l'obésité constituait un facteur significatif de l'ÉTA avec un rapport de cote (RC) de 1.26 (95% IC 1.03-1.52), ceci après avoir ajusté les données en fonction des variables de contrôles possibles comme les variables sociodémographiques ou les facteurs reliés aux antibiotiques (ex. le SARM et les antécédents d'utilisation d'antibiotiques).  Les moyennes du ratio DQ:ICM variaient de façon significative d'un groupe à l'autre, alors que les moyennes diminuaient quand l'ICM augmentait.  Lorsqu'on l'inclut dans le modèle prédictif de l'ÉTA avec d'autres variables précédents, la variation du ratio DQ:ICM était significative (valeur p de 0.03) avec un RC ajusté de 1.004 (95% IC 1.000-1.007).Conclusions : L'obésité constitue un facteur prédictif significatif de l'ÉTA.  Cette association est probablement reliée au fait que les doses sont administrées uniformément parmi les différents groupes de poids.  Ces découvertes devraient encourager d'autres recherches dans le domaine de la pharmacocinétique et de la médecine familiale, afin de pouvoir établir des normes de dosage des antibiotiques axées sur le poids et d'intégrer dans la pratique médicale courante l'administration de doses en fonction du poids.  </description><description>Objectives: To determine whether excess weight is associated with antibiotic treatment failure (ATF) and if this may be due to a lack of weight-based dosing.Methods:  Using a historical cohort study design, data linked to Quebec administrative databases were available for 18 014 consenting patients randomly sampled from the 1992 and 1998 Santé Québec Health surveys (response rate 85%). Selected patients were within the normal weight, overweight and obese weight classes aged 20–79 years, receiving at least one episode of antibiotic therapy from the health survey date to December 2005. ATF was measured via secondary antibiotic prescriptions or additional hospitalizations for infections within the month following initial therapy for each participant. The antibiotic daily dose (DD) and daily dose to body mass index (DD:BMI) ratios were computed for those receiving an oral antibiotic prescription. Logistic regression was performed to determine whether overweight and/or obesity as well as dosing factors (e.g. DD:BMI) were significant predictors of ATF, while one-way ANOVA with Tukey-Kramer adjustment for multiple comparisons was used to determine if DD:BMI ratios differed significantly across weight groups, reflecting a lack of weight-based dosing. Results: Of the 6 179 patients selected, 828 (13.4%) had an ATF event during the outcome assessment period. Obesity was found to be a significant predictor of ATF with an OR of 1.26 (95% CI 1.03-1.52), after adjusting for other potential confounders including sociodemographic, and antibiotic-related factors (e.g. MRSA and history of antibiotic use). The antibiotic DD:BMI ratio means differed significantly between weight groups, where means decreased with increasing BMI. When included in the ATF predictive model along with other previous confounding factors, the DD:BMI variable was significant (p-value of 0.03) with a modest adjusted OR of 1.004 (95% CI 1.000-1.007). Conclusions: Obesity is a significant predictor of ATF and this association is likely due to the current “one size fits all” dosing strategy. Findings may encourage further research in the field of pharmacokinetics and family medicine to find a means of standardizing current antibiotic dosing guidelines for weight as well as implementing weight-based dosing in family practice. </description><creator>Longo, Cristina</creator><contributor>Gillian Bartlett-Esquilant (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</subject><title>The role of excess weight in antibiotic treatment failure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k218g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bt47x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644w80v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Comparées à de jeunes adultes, les personnes âgées ont de la difficulté à se rappeler des détails spatiaux et temporels d'événements passés. Durant le rappel, certaines régions du cerveau augmentent leur niveau d'activité (réseau positif, RP), alors que d'autres diminuent leur niveau d'activité (réseau négatif, RN). Des études ont démontré que les personnes âgées n'activent pas les régions du RP, et ne désactivent pas les régions du RN autant que les jeunes adultes, indiquant que des changements dans les deux réseaux pourraient expliquer les troubles mnémoniques des personnes âgées. Cependant, très peu est connu sur les changements de connectivité se produisant dans différentes tâches de mémoire, dans les deux groupes d'âge. Le but de cette thèse était d'examiner les changements de connectivité dans le RP, le RN, et entre les deux réseaux, lors de tâche de mémoire d'item, de contexte spatial et de contexte temporel, en utilisant la modélisation par équation structurelle (MES). Les personnes âgées ont performé aussi bien que les jeunes de la tâche de mémoire d'item, mais moins bien dans les tâches de mémoire de contexte spatial et temporel. Les résultats de MES démontre que dans le RN, il n'y avait pas de changements de connectivité dus à la tâche, mais il y en avait qui était dû à l'âge : les personnes âgées avaient moins de connectivité entre le cortex préfrontal (CP) et le cortex fusiforme, indiquant un trouble avec la sélection d'information durant le rappel. Par contre, les personnes âgées avaient plus de connectivité entre le CP gauche et le CP droit, et entre le CP gauche et le cortex prémoteur, ce qui pourrait être un moyen de compensation. Les deux groupes ont démontré des changements de connectivité dus à la tâche dans le RN, en entre le RN et le RP. Alors que les jeunes adultes ont démontré moins de connectivité dans le RN en entre le RN et le RP durant les tâches de mémoire contextuelle comparées à la tâche de mémoire d'item, les personnes âgées ont démontré des changements opposés : ils avaient plus de connectivité dans le RN et entre le RN et le RP dans les tâches de mémoire contextuelle. En conclusion, alors que les jeunes adultes se rappellent de mémoires plus détaillées en atténuant les mécanismes cognitifs du RP, les personnes âgées semblent s'en servir davantage pour se rappeler de mémoires plus détaillées.</description><description>Compared to young adults, older adults exhibit impairments in remembering the spatial and temporal contextual details associated with an event. During episodic memory (EM) retrieval, certain regions of the brain exhibit increases in activation (task-positive network, TPN), while others exhibit decreases in activation (task-negative network, TNN), compared to baseline. Studies have revealed that older adults exhibit impairments activating regions of the TPN, and deactivating regions of TNN compared to young adults, indicating that both of these age-related changes may contribute to deficits in context retrieval with age. Yet little is known about the relative changes in connectivity within and between regions of these two networks across different context retrieval tasks, in either age group, and how these changes may relate to memory performance. The goal of this thesis was to assess age-related effective connectivity changes in a simple item recognition task and in harder spatial context and temporal context tasks within and between the TPN and TNN, using structural equation modeling. Older adults performed as well as young in item recognition, but worse on both spatial and temporal context. The connectivity results revealed that there were no within-group task differences in the TPN, although there were between-group differences in this network: older adults displayed less connectivity between right lateral PFC and posterior visual areas, which may reflect less efficient selection of goal-relevant information from posterior visual areas. However, older adults exhibited greater connectivity of left lateral PFC with both right lateral PFC and medial premotor cortex, perhaps reflecting compensatory processes. Both groups exhibited within-group task differences effective connectivity in the TNN and between the TNN and TPN. While young adults exhibited decreased connectivity within the TNN and more negative connectivity the TNN and TPN in context versus item recognition, older adults displayed the opposite pattern: more positive connectivity within TNN and between regions of TNN and TPN in context tasks. Finally, older adults exhibited markedly reduced connectivity in TNN in the item recognition task, compared to young adults; however this difference was attenuated in the temporal context task, and eliminated in the spatial context task. Thus while young adults respond to increasing retrieval load by down-regulating subjective recollection processes in the TNN, older adults may rely on them to a greater extent as retrieval demands increase.   </description><creator>Maillet, David</creator><contributor>Maria Rajah (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Age-related changes in effective connectivity within and between the task-positive and task-negative networks during spatial and temporal context retrieval</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gm572.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644w80v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c4661</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Controlled free radical polymerization is attractive as it produces polymers with well defined microstructures typically associated with “living” polymerization methods, using a wide range of monomers required for applications such as nanoporous membranes and barrier materials. Poly(trioctylammonium p-styrenesulfonate) homopolymer (poly(SS-TOA)) and poly(SS-TOA-ran-styrene) copolymers were synthesized by nitroxide-mediated polymerization (NMP) using an N-tert-butyl-N-[1-diethylphosphono-(2,2-dimethylpropyl)] nitroxide (SG1) based unimolecular initiator, called BlocBuilder.  Polymerizations were controlled for low theoretical molecular weight at complete conversion (Mn,theoretical = 20 kg·mol-1), resulting in very low polydispersities (Mw/Mn &lt; 1.1) and a linear increase in number average molecular weight, Mn, up to ≈ 35% conversion. SS-TOA was effective as a controlling co-monomer for the gradient polymerization with glycidyl methacrylate, using a N-succinimidyl ester modified BlocBuilder (NHS-BlocBuilder), which resulted in a relatively narrow molecular weight distribution (Mw/Mn = 1.43) and linear increase in Mn versus conversion. Poly(styrene-ran-acrylonitrile) (poly(S/AN)) and poly(tert-butyl methacrylate-ran-acrylonitrile) (poly(t-BMA/AN)) were also synthesized by NMP using BlocBuilder and NHS-BlocBuilder. In both systems, the polymers exhibited narrow, monomodal molecular weight distributions with relatively low polydispersities (Mw/Mn = 1.14-1.50), characteristic of a controlled polymerization. Mn versus conversion (X) plots were all relatively linear (Mn = 14.8-18.1 kg.mol-1, X = 40-70%) suggesting that “pseudo-living” behaviour was approached in the range of conversions studied. </description><description>Cette étude se concentre sur le thème de la polymérisation radicalaire contrôlée qui est attrayante de par sa facilité à produire des polymères avec une microstructure bien définie et demeure semblable à la polymérisation ionique/vivante. Elle présente l'avantage de permettre la génération d'une vaste gamme d'application de monomères allant des membranes nanoporeuses aux matériaux barrières. Le poly(trioctylammonium p-styrènesulfonate) (poly(SS-TOA)) et poly(SS-TOA-ran-styrène) ont été préparés par la polymérisation contrôlée par des nitroxydes, à base de la nitroxyde N-tert-butyl-N-[1-diéthylphosphono-(2,2-diméthylpropyl)] (SG1), aussi appelé BlocBuilder. La polymérisation a été le mieux contrôlée pour un faible poids moléculaire théorique (20 kg·mol-1 versus 45 kg·mol-1), avec de très basses polydispersités (Mw/Mn &lt; 1.1) et une croissance linéaire du poids moléculaire moyen en nombre jusqu'à une conversion de ≈ 35%. Le SS-TOA à également prouvé son efficacité comme contrôleur comonomèrique pour la polymérisation de type gradient avec le méthacrylate glycidyl, accompagné d'une forme protégée de BlocBuilder (achevés de N-succinimidyl, appelé  NHS-BlocBuilder). Le Poly(styrène-ran-acrylonitrile) (poly(S/AN)) et poly(tert-butyl méthacrylate-ran-acrylonitrile) (poly(t-BMA/AN)) ont également été copolymérisés par polymérisation contrôlée en employant des nitroxydes avec les initiateurs BlocBuilder et NHS-BlocBuilder. Les deux systèmes ont démontré un bon degré de contrôle : une distribution de poids moléculaire étroite avec des polydispersités relativement faibles (Mw/Mn = 1.14-1.50) combinée à une croissance linéaire du poids moléculaire moyen en nombre avec une conversion (X) relativement élevée (Mn = 14.8-18.1 kg.mol-1, X = 40-70%). Ces résultats confirment bien la notion de "copolymérisation pseudo-vivante".</description><creator>Consolante, Valerie</creator><contributor>Milan Maric (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Chemistry - Polymer</subject><title>Nitroxide mediated synthesis of protected styrenesulfonate and acrylonitrile copolymers for membrane and barrier materials</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848v507.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c4661</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj236642z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fast optical transients (microsecond timescale) are a largely unexplored field of optical astronomy mainly due to the fact that large optical telescopes are oversubscribed. Furthermore, most optical observations use instruments with integration times on the order of seconds and are thus unable to resolve fast transients. Current-generation atmospheric Cherenkov gamma-ray telescopes such as VERITAS (the Very Energetic Radiation Imaging Telescope Array System), however, have huge collecting areas, larger than any existing optical telescopes, albeit at the cost of spatial resolution. Time is typically available for studies without interfering with gamma-ray observations. The following outlines the benefits of using a Cherenkov telescope to detect optical transients and the implementation of VERy TRenDy (the VERITAS Transient Detector), a dedicated multi-channel rate meter based on field-programmable gate arrays. Data are presented demonstrating the ability of TRenDy to detect transient events such as a star passing through its field of view and the optical light curve of a pulsar. Future scientific goals such as looking for microsecond-timescale optical flares are described as are the possible sources.</description><description>Les phénomènes optiques transitoires rapides (sur une échelle de microsecondes) sont un domaine d'astronomie optique encore très peu exploré, du au fait que les demandes de temps d'utilisation des grands télescopes optiques sont trop nombreuses. De plus, la plupart des observations optiques utilisent des instruments avec des temps d'intégration de l'ordre de secondes, et sont donc incapables de résoudre les phénomènes transitoires. Les télescopes atmosphériques Cherenkov pour rayons gamma de la génération actuelle, comme VERITAS (Very Energetic Radiation Imaging Telescope Array System), ont quant à eux d'énormes surfaces collectrices, plus larges que n'importe quel autre télescope optique existant, malgré une perte de résolution spatiale. Il est habituellement possible de consacrer du temps pour faire des études sans interférer avec les observations de rayons gamma. Ce qui suit résume les bénéfices de l'utilisation de télescopes Cherenkov pour détecter les phénoménes optiques transitoires et de l'utilisation de VERy TRenDy (VERITAS Transient Detector), un compteur à multiples canaux basé sur les réseaux de portes programmables in-situ. Les données présentées dans ce mémoire démontrent la capacité de TRenDy a détecter les phénomènes transitoires tels qu'une étoile passant dans le champ de vision et la courbe de lumière d'un pulsar. Les objectifs scientifiques futurs tels que l'observation des éruptions optiques sur une échelle de microsecondes sont décrits, ainsi que les sources potentielles.</description><creator>Griffin, Sean</creator><contributor>David Hanna (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Physics - Astronomy and Astrophysics  </subject><title>VERy TRenDy: the VERITAS transient detector</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hd944.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236642z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65vc804</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Lactococcus lactis est une bactérie lactique Gram-positive couramment utilisée dans l'industrie laitière. Elle a été jugée sans danger pour la consommation humaine par la "United States Food and Drug Administration" et elle détient le statut "GRAS" (Generally Recognised As Safe). L. lactis est non pathogène, non-colonisatrice et non-invasive. L'utilité de cette bactérie comme une cellule «usine» capable de synthétiser des protéines hétérologues est maintenant bien établie. Des travaux antérieurs dans notre laboratoire ont également montré que L. lactis a la capacité de stimuler le système immunitaire inné. Toutes ces propriétés font de L. lactis un vecteur approprié pour l'administration biologique d'antigènes afin de stimuler une réponse immunitaire. La leishmaniose viscérale est une infection protozoaire diffuse, causée par les espèces du complexe Leishmania donovani, qui affecte le foie, la rate et la moelle osseuse. Chaque année, 500,000 nouveaux cas de leishmaniose viscérale sont déclarés et 90% des cas cliniques sont mortels s'ils ne sont pas traités. En plus des inconvénients de coût élevé et les effets secondaires de la chimiothérapie, un autre problème majeur est l'émergence de parasites résistants aux médicaments anti-Leishmania. C'est pourquoi le développement d'un vaccin contre la leishmaniose viscérale est une priorité. Nous avons modifié L. lactis (souches NZ9000 et PH3960) afin qu'elle exprime l'antigène protecteur de Leishmania, stérol 24-C-méthyltransférase (SMT), de façon hétérologue dans le cytoplasme. Dans des études distinctes, ces souches de L. lactis ont été évaluées pour leur capacité de protection comme vaccins vivants contre L. donovani chez la souris BALB/c, individuellement, mais aussi en présence de L. lactis sécrétant de l'IL-12 en tant qu'adjuvant. Les réponses immunitaires à ces vaccinations sous-cutanées ont été suivies en mesurant les titres d'anticorps sériques dirigés contre SMT et la production de cytokines provenant de splénocytes stimulués par les antigènes solubles de Leishmania au point final de l'infection. Les souris immunisées avec les clones de L. lactis NZ9000 exprimant SMT montrent des taux sériques élevés d'IgG1 et d'IgG2a, ainsi qu'un profil de cytokines splénique démontrant une réponse mixte Th1/Th2. La co-administration de clones de L. lactis exprimant SMT et de l'IL-12 murin a permis de réduire la charge parasitaire dans le foie de manière significative dans le cas de L. lactis NZ9000. Dans l'ensemble, nous avons démontré que L. lactis est un vecteur approprié pour l'administration d'antigènes vaccins et la génération de réponses immunitaires protectrices contre la leishmaniose viscérale.</description><description>Lactococcus lactis is a Gram-positive lactic acid bacterium commonly used in the dairy industry. It has been deemed safe for human consumption by the United States Food and Drug Administration and holds Generally Recognised As Safe (GRAS) status. L. lactis is non-pathogenic, non-colonizing and non-invasive. The utility of this bacterium as a cell "factory" able to synthesis heterologous proteins is now well established. Previous work in our lab has also shown that L. lactis has the ability to stimulate the innate immune system. All these properties make L. lactis a suitable vector for biological delivery of antigens to stimulate an immune response.Visceral leishmaniasis is a disseminated protozoan infection, caused by the species of the Leishmania donovani complex, which affects the liver, spleen and bone marrow. There are 500,000 new cases of visceral leishmaniasis every year and 90% of clinical cases are fatal if left untreated. In addition to the disadvantages of high cost and side effects of chemotherapy, there is also emerging resistance of parasites to anti-leishmanial drugs. In light of these facts, the development of a vaccine against visceral leishmaniasis is a priority. We have engineered L. lactis (strains NZ9000 and PH3960) to heterologously express the protective Leishmania antigen, sterol 24-c-methyltransferase (SMT), in the cytoplasm. In separate studies, these strains of L. lactis were assessed for their protective capability as live vaccines against L. donovani in BALB/c mice, both individually and adjuvanted with IL-12-secreting L. lactis. Immune responses to subcutaneous immunizations were monitored by measuring serum antibody titers against SMT and cytokine production from splenocytes upon stimulation by soluble Leishmania antigen at the end point of infection. Mice immunised with SMT-expressing clones of L. lactis NZ9000 had high titers of both serum IgG1 and IgG2a as well as splenocyte cytokine response profiles which demonstrated a mixed Th1/Th2 response. The co-administration of SMT- and murine IL-12-producing L. lactis clones was able to reduce parasite load in the liver significantly in the case of L. lactis NZ9000. Overall, we demonstrated that L. lactis is a suitable vehicle for the delivery of vaccine antigens and generation of protective immune responses against visceral leishmaniasis.</description><creator>Mahbuba, Raya</creator><contributor>Benoit Cousineau (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Microbiology</subject><title>Generation and evaluation of SMT-expressing «Lactococcus lactis» live vaccines against visceral leishmaniasis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p884j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65vc804</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924g828</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One central question in ecology is why some areas have many species and others have few. Many explanations have been proposed and often the forces that drive species richness are context-dependent. These forces are divided into two general categories: biotic drivers and abiotic drivers. Biotic drivers are most commonly described in terms as top-down and bottom-up effects while abiotic drivers are commonly described in terms of climate and habitat disturbance. The objective of this thesis is to determine how these drivers affect species richness in terrestrial ecosystems. To test this I examine an insect herbivore assemblage in a disturbed forest fragment landscape in southern Canada. I use geographic information systems techniques to determine the impact of a natural episodic disturbance (i.e. an abiotic natural driver) and a chronic human disturbance (i.e. an abiotic human driver) on forest habitat quality (Chapter 1) and on a forest-dwelling caterpillar assemblage (Chapter 2). I show that ice storms result in a heterogeneous pattern of spatial damage across a forest landscape, differing depending on the type of coarse woody debris examined. These different types of coarse woody debris provide habitat for a diversity of taxa. In contrast with natural disturbance, I found that human-based disturbance do not have a positive impact on caterpillar assemblages. Pursuant to this, I explore the concept of habitat quality from the perspective of host plant identity (Chapter 3) and host plant quality (Chapter 4). I found that caterpillar assemblages have strong host plant preferences and that these preferences may depend on quadrat-scale foliar qualities (i.e. a biotic bottom-up driver) and parasitoid densities (i.e. a biotic top-down driver) at different times in the growing season. This thesis adds to a growing body of literature aimed to better understand the drivers of insect species richness across disturbed landscapes. In addition, this thesis develops several management-specific tools for measuring forest disturbance and provides valuable insight into how the selection of different tree species for planting initiatives can have important impacts on forest communities.</description><description>Les communautés forestières qui habitent les parcelles de forêts qui subsistent aujourd'hui sont affectées par les perturbations ainsi que par la qualité de l'habitat que leur procure les plantes-hôtes. Ces deux phénomènes ont un impact particulièrement important dans les paysages modifiés par l'activité humaine. Développer une meilleure compréhension de ces phénomènes va faciliter la prise de décision et les efforts de conservations visant à préserver et protéger la biodiversité des forêts. L'objectif global de cette thèse est d'étudier les divers aspects reliés à la qualité de l'habitat dans les parcelles forestières des collines montérégiennes du sud-est du Québec, Canada. J'utilise des techniques en système d'information géographique pour déterminer l'impact d'une perturbation naturelle épisodique (tempête de verglas) ainsi qu'une perturbation anthropogénique chronique (sentiers récréationnels) sur la qualité des habitats forestiers (Chapitre 1) et un assemblage de chenilles vivant en forêt (Chapitre 2). J'ai démontré que les dégâts engendrés par les tempêtes de verglas sont distribués de façon hétérogène à travers le paysage forestier, différant selon le type de débris ligneux grossiers examiné. Ces différents types de débris ligneux grossiers servent d'habitat à divers groupes taxonomiques. J'ai découvert que les perturbations anthropogéniques, au contraire des perturbations naturelles, n'ont pas eu d'impacts positifs sur les assemblages de chenilles vivants en forêt. J'ai également exploré le concept de qualité d'habitat en considérant l'identité de la plante hôte (Chapitre 3) et la qualité foliaire à l'échelle du quadrat (Chapitre 4). J'ai découvert que l'assemblage de chenille démontre des préférences marquées pour certaines plantes hôtes et que ces préférences peuvent dépendre de différentes qualités foliaires à l'échelle du quadrat à différentes périodes durant la saison de croissance. Cette thèse contribue à la documentation croissante sur les facteurs qui affectent la richesse spécifique des communautés d'insectes vivant dans les forêts des paysages perturbés. De plus, cette thèse propose plusieurs outils spécifiques à la gestion pour évaluer les perturbations en milieu forestier et donne un aperçu de l'impact que peut avoir la sélection de différentes espèces d'arbres sur les communautés forestières lors de l'élaboration d'initiatives de plantation d'arbres. </description><creator>White, Peter</creator><contributor>Martin J Lechowicz (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Brian McGill (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Ecology</subject><title>The effects of biotic and abiotic forces on species richness</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vw10m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924g828</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720h982</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The deviation of the frequency of a power system from its nominal value is a reflection of the mismatch between generation and load. Such deviations are serious and must be monitored and controlled very closely. One major impact of operating outside a narrow range around the nominal frequency is that generators can be damaged. To avoid this, manufacturers set time interval limits for under-frequency operation and when such limits are exceeded, the generator trips. However, unless generator tripping is coordinated with some accompanying load shedding, the system inability to supply its load can be exacerbated resulting in an even worse frequency deviation. Under-frequency load shedding (UFLS) is designed to protect the power system from events leading to a sudden drop in system frequency, when the primary frequency regulation built into the generation system is not enough to bring the frequency back to nominal. Under-frequency load shedding disconnects blocks of load when the frequency drops below given thresholds. However, the conventional design of UFLS schemes is primarily based on experience about the behavior of the system. Basically, trial relay settings are proposed, tested, and revised until a successful UFLS scheme is obtained. This process is tedious, not very systematic, and usually leads to shedding conservative amounts of load. This thesis presents a mixed-integer linear programming formulation of the UFLS relay setting problem. The goal is to render the design of UFLS more systematic, less dependent on trial and error, and less conservative in terms of the amount of load shed. </description><description>Dans un réseau électrique, l'écart de la fréquence du réseau par rapport à sa valeur nominale est le reflet d'un manque d'équilibre entre la production et la consommation. Ces écarts peuvent avoir des conséquences graves et ils doivent être contrôlés et surveillés de très près. Un impact majeur dans l'opération d'un réseau électrique avec une tolérance large autour de la fréquence nominale est le risque d'endommager les alternateurs. Pour éviter cette situation, les fabricants établissent des délais pour opérer en sous-fréquence et lorsque ces délais sont dépassés, les alternateurs sont automatiquement déconnectés du réseau, ce qui entraîne une plus grande déviation de la fréquence.Le délestage sur le seuil de sous- fréquence est conçu pour protéger le réseau électrique d'événements conduisant à une baisse soudaine de la fréquence du réseau lorsque les réglages intégrés dans le système de production sont  insuffisants pour ramener la fréquence  à la valeur nominale. Le délestage sur le seuil de sous- fréquence consiste à déconnecter des regroupements de consommateurs lorsque la fréquence descend en dessous d'une certaine limite. Cependant, les manœuvres de délestage sont principalement conçues à partir de l'expérience du comportement du réseau électrique. Les réglages des relais de protection de premières instances sont proposés, testés et modifiés jusqu'à ce qu'une manœuvre de délestage approprié soit obtenue. Ce processus est laborieux, non-systématique, et conduit généralement à un délestage conservateur de la demande. Cette thèse présente une formulation utilisant des techniques de programmation linéaire mixte pour déterminer les réglages des relais de protection de sous-fréquence. L'objectif est de rendre la conception des manœuvres de délestage plus systématique, moins dépendante des méthodes empiriques, et moins conservatrice au point de vue du délestage.</description><creator>Ceja Gómez, Frida</creator><contributor>Francisco D Galiana (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Setting under-frequency relays in power systems via integer programming</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kx99j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720h982</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j5208</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le cancer de la prostate (CaP) figure parmi les plus meurtriers cancers du monde occidental. La mort des patients est attribuée aux cellules tumorales réfractaires aux androgènes, survivant à la chimiothérapie. Les mécanismes moléculaires sous-jacents sont incompris. Le laboratoire d'accueil a rapporté que la tyrosine kinase Fer joue un rôle dans la survie et croissance des cellules prostatiques cancéreuses. Fer est sur-exprimée et localisée dans le noyau des tumeurs prostatiques plus agressives en comparaison des tissus normaux. La recherche de partenaires de Fer parmi les protéines phosphorylées (p) sur tyrosine (Y) a révélé l'actine. Fait intéressant, la pY-actine joue un rôle dans la survie des amibes soumises au stress.  Fer et la pY-actine pourraient ainsi faire partie d'un mécanisme activé de façon à  résister au stress. Cette hypothèse a été testée en exposant les cellules de CaP au Docetaxel, un agent chimio-thérapeutique utilisé en clinique. Nous démontrons que les niveaux de complexes Fer/actine et de leur phosphorylation sur Y augmentent à doses de Docetaxel stressant les cellules. Fer phosphoryle l'actine directement in vitro et lie la pY-actine via son domaine SH2. De plus, le Docetaxel induit la translocation nucléaire de Fer.  L'inhibition de l'expression de  Fer via un siRNA augmente la capacité du Docetaxel à tuer les cellules, supportant ainsi l'implication de Fer dans la survie de cellules. Nos résultats préliminaires montrent que des résidus Y spécifiques de l'actine sont phosphorylés en réponse à la drogue. D'autres agents chimiothérapeutiques induisent la phosphorylation sur Y de Fer et de l'actine.  Ainsi l'activation de ce nouveau mécanisme de  survie en réponse à divers agents cytotoxiques pourrait expliquer la progression du CaP.</description><description>Prostate cancer (PCa) is among leading causes of cancer related mortalities in the western world.  Patient's death is attributed to androgen-refractory tumor cells that survive chemotherapy.  Underlying molecular mechanisms are poorly understood. The host laboratory reported on the role of the Fer tyrosine kinase in the survival and growth of PCa cells.  Fer is over-expressed and localized in the cell nucleus of more aggressive prostate tumors in comparison to normal tissues. The search for Fer's partners among tyrosine (Y) phosphorylated (p) proteins revealed actin. Interestingly, pY-actin plays a role in amoeba cell survival submitted to stress.  Fer and pY-actin could thus be part of a mechanism activated in order to withstand stress. This hypothesis was tested by exposing PCa cells to Docetaxel, a chemotherapeutic agent used in the clinic. We demonstrate that levels of Fer/actin complexes and their Y-phosphorylation increased at stressful doses of Docetaxel. Fer directly phosphorylates actin in vitro and binds pY-actin through its SH2 domain. Moreover, Docetaxel induced Fer nuclear translocation.  Fer knock-down through siRNA enhanced Docetaxel induced cell death, thereby supporting the Fer implication in Pca cell survival. Preliminary results point to specific Y residues in actin being phosphorylated in response to Docetaxel.  Other chemotherapeutic drugs induced the Y-phosphorylation of Fer and actin.  Thus the activation of this novel survival mechanism involving Fer and pY-actin, may explain, at least in part, PCa progression. </description><creator>El Jurdi, Katia</creator><contributor>Simone Chevalier (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Health Sciences - General</subject><title>Consequences of molecular Fer complexes with actin in prostate cancer progression</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053m43k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j5208</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:00000415f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La dégénérescence maculaire liée à l'âge (DMLA) est la principale cause de cécité chez les personnes âgées dans les pays développés. Une recherche dynamique est en cours pour élucider des cibles moléculaires potentiels pour le traitement de la dégénérescence à la fois pour la forme atrophique et la forme néovasculaire de cette maladie.  L'actuelle pharmacothérapie est efficace chez certains patients mais pas suffisante pour arrêter la progression de la maladie ou la réparation des dommages qui ont déjà eu lieu. La decouverte de nouveaux medicaments  et le remplacement de cellules rétiniennes représentent les deux avenues les plus prometteuses de traitements possibles. Le but de cette thèse est d'étudier le rôle d'un régulateur récemment identifié du développement neuronal, SIRT1, dans le developpement de la retine et de rechercher si l'inhibition pharmacologique de cette protéine représente une option de traitement possible dans la DMLA. Via l'immunohistochimie et l'immunocytochimie, nous avons évalué l'expression et la localisation subcellulaire de SIRT1 et de son inhibiteur inné, DBC1, chez la souris et les humains dans les retines fœtales et adultes. Nous avons également étudié SIRT1 dans les  cellules souches de la rétine chez la souris et l'homme. Nous avons trouvé SIRT1  largement exprimé dans la rétine en développement et des adultes et à un régulateur de gènes clés du développement de la rétine, à savoir PAX6, Nestin et CRX. En outre, nous avons constaté que les cellules précurseurs des photorécepteurs ont été parmi les plus petites cellules dans la population hétérogène de cellules progénitrices. Collectivement, ces résultats fournissent la base pour la manipulation de l'expression SIRT1 dans les petits progéniteurs rétiniens comme un moyen d'augmenter le rendement des photorécepteurs à la transplantation dans les modèles de dégénérescence rétinienne. Nous avons en outre constaté que SIRT1 est fortement exprimé dans les membranes néovasculaires humaines et avons cherché  à inhiber son activité pharmacologique par le nicotinamide.  Nous avons trouvé que Nicotinamide est un puissant régulateur de l'hypoxie et de l'angiogenèse au niveau de la protéine et de l'ARN.  Ces résultats indiquent que l'inhibiteur de SIRT1, Nicotinamide est un agent possible pour le traitement de la DMLA néovasculaire. D'autres études de la nicotinamide devraient être poursuivit dans des modèles animaux de la DMLA. Au meilleur de notre connaissance, c'est la première fois qu'une analyse détaillée de SIRT1 l'identifie comme un régulateur du développement tant de la rétine et  de la néovascularisation choroïdienne.</description><description>Age-related macular degeneration (AMD) is the leading cause of blindness in the elderly in developed countries. Aggressive research is underway to elucidate putative molecular targets for therapy for both the atrophic and neovascular forms of this disease. Current pharmacotherapy is effective in some patients but not sufficient to halt disease progression or repair damage that has already occurred. Drug intervention and retinal cell replacement represent the two most promising potential treatment avenues. The purpose of this thesis was to investigate the role of a recently identified regulator of neural development, SIRT1, in retinogenesis and to further investigate whether pharmacological inhibition of this protein represents a possible treatment option in neovascular AMD. Via immunohistochemistry and immunocytochemistry we evaluated the expression and subcellular localization of SIRT1 and its innate inhibitor, DBC1, in mouse and human fetal and adult retinas. We further studied SIRT1 in mouse- and human-derived retinal progenitor cells, the former being using in small interfering RNA studies. We found SIRT1 to be widely expressed in developing and adult retinas and to be a regulator of key retinal development genes, namely PAX6, Nestin and CRX. Moreover, we found that photoreceptor precursor cells were among the smallest cells in the heterogeneous population of mouse retinal progenitors. Collectively, these results provide the foundation for manipulating SIRT1 expression in small retinal progenitors as a means of increasing the yield of photoreceptors for transplantation in models of retinal degeneration.We further found SIRT1 to be highly expressed in human-derived choroidal neovascular membranes and sought to pharmacologically inhibit its activity via the drug Nicotinamide. We found Nicotinamide to be a potent regulator of angiogenic and hypoxic signaling in a human retinal pigment epithelial cell line at both the protein level using angiogenesis arrays and at the RNA level using whole genome microarrays. These results point to the SIRT1 inhibitor, Nicotinamide, as a possible agent for treatment of neovascular AMD. Further studies of Nicotinamide are warranted in animal models of AMD. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first time that a detailed analysis of SIRT1 as a regulator of both retinal development and choroidal neovascularization has been reported.</description><creator>Maloney, Shawn</creator><contributor>Miguel Noel Burnier (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Health Sciences - Pathology</subject><title>Dual role of SIRT1 as a regulator of retinal development and a therapeutic target in age-related macular degeneration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gq087.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000415f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150p18w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>mTOR (mammalian target of rapamycin), la cible de la rapamycine chez les mammifères, est une kinase de type sérine-thréonine très bien conservée à travers les phyla, qui est responsable de la réponse aux mitogènes anabolisants et aux substrats métaboliques tel que l'insuline, les acides aminés et l'ATP. Une réduction de l'activité de TOR peut également permettre l'initiation de réponses cataboliques. Chez S. cerevisiae, le stress physique et la déficience en éléments nutritifs induisent une réponse transcriptionnelle qui nécessite des phosphatases associées à TOR ainsi que la translocation nucléaire de facteurs de transcriptions dépendant de la réaction aux éléments de stress.  Dans cette thèse, j'explore une nouvelle interaction physique et fonctionnelle entre mTOR, ses phosphatases associées et  le transducteur de signalisation et activateur de transcription-1 (STAT1), un facteur de transcription contrôlant l'induction des gènes de l'apoptose.  J'émets l'hypothèse  que l'inactivation de mTOR promeut l'importation de STAT1 au noyau en adoptant un mécanisme nécessitant l'interaction avec ses phosphatases associées; la phosphatase alpha4 et la phosphatase 2A sous-unité catalytique (PP2Ac), ainsi que  STAT1 kariophérine importine-alpha1 (KPNA1).  Ces résultats démontrent que mTOR, alpha4, PP2Ac, KPNA1 et STAT1 interagissent physiquement et forment un complexe protéique macromoléculaire dynamique.  La rapamycine, l'inhibiteur de mTOR, promeut la translocation nucléaire de STAT1 et l'induction de la transcription des gènes de l'apoptose STAT1-dépendant selon un mécanisme nécessitant alpha4, PP2Ac et KPNA1.  De plus je démontre que STAT1 est nécessaire pour renforcer l'effet de la rapamycine sur l'apoptose sur des cellules en culture exposées à des agonistes de STAT1 à caractère pro-inflammatoire (c.-à-d lipopolysaccharide bactérien et interféron-beta). Enfin, je démontre que la rapamycine augmente le niveau de STAT1 actif, l'expression des gènes de l'apoptose STAT1-dépendant, l'apoptose cellulaire et les lésions tissulaires dans les poumons de souris auxquelles du lipopolysaccharide a été administré par voie intratrachéale.  Ainsi, dans les cellules mammifères, la réduction de l'activité de mTOR résulte en une augmentation de  l'apoptose cellulaire et des lésions tissulaires par l'intermédiaire d'un mécanisme impliquant une interaction physique et fonctionnelle avec STAT1.  Les mécanismes moléculaires contrôlant la régulation de STAT1 par mTOR sont des cibles importantes pour la modulation de l'apoptose et des lésions tissulaires chez les mammifères. </description><description>Mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR) is a highly-conserved serine/threonine kinase that permits anabolic responses to mitogens and metabolic substrates (e.g., insulin, amino acids, ATP). When its activity is reduced, TOR can also initiate catabolic responses. In S. cerevisiae, nutrient or physical stress initiates a transcriptional stress response that requires the TOR-associated phosphatases and the nuclear translocation of stress transcription factors. In this thesis, I explore a novel physical and functional relationship between mammalian TOR, its associated phosphatases, and 'signal transducer and activator of transcription -1' (STAT1), a key transcription factor that controls the induction of apoptosis genes. I hypothesized that inactivation of mTOR favours the nuclear import of STAT1 in a mechanism that requires its associated phosphatases alpha4 and ‘protein phosphatase 2A catalytic subunit' (PP2Ac), as well as the STAT1 importin karyopherin alpha-1 (KPNA1). Here, I show that mTOR, alpha4, PP2Ac, KPNA1, and STAT1 are physically associated in a dynamic macromolecular protein complex. The mTOR inhibitor rapamycin promotes STAT1 nuclear import and the induction of STAT1-dependent apoptosis genes in a mechanism that requires alpha4, PP2Ac, and KPNA1. I further show that STAT1 is required for the enhancing effect of rapamycin on apoptosis per se in cultured cells exposed to pro-inflammatory STAT1 agonists (i.e., bacterial lipopolysaccharide, interferon-beta). Finally, I demonstrate that rapamycin enhances the levels of activated STAT1, STAT1-dependent apoptosis genes, cellular apoptosis, and tissue injury in the lungs of mice exposed to intratracheal lipopolysaccharide.  Thus, in mammalian cells, reduction of mTOR activity favours cellular apoptosis and organ injury via a mechanism that involves a physical and functional interaction with STAT1. The molecular mechanisms that mediate the regulation of STAT1 by mTOR are targets for the modulation of mammalian apoptosis and tissue injury.</description><creator>Fielhaber, Jill</creator><contributor>Arnold Scott Kristof (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Health Sciences - Immunology</subject><title>Regulation of signal tranducer and activator of transcription-1 and cell death by mammalian target of Rapamycin</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859k74v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150p18w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930c2366</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:46:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Un inconvénient majeur de l'ingénierie tissulaire du cartilage est dû aux niveaux de collagène de type X élevés exprimés dans les cellules souches mésenchymateuses (CSM) des patients arthritiques. Le collagène de type X est un marqueur de l'hypertrophie avancée des chondrocytes, qui est lié à l'ossification endochondrale. Il a été démontré que l'expression du collagène de type X par les CSM différenciées peut être inhibée en présence des polymères plasma enrichies d'azote (PPE:N, nitrogen-rich plasma-polymerized ethylene). Le but de cette étude était de déterminer si la diminution de l'expression du collagène de type X, induite par PPE:N serait maintenue lorsque les CSM sont transférée dans des cultures culots. Les dernières sont un arrangement de cellules mimant la condensation embryonique des CSM résultant ainsi en des chrondrocytes prehypertrophiques. Les CSM ont été obtenus à partir de la moelle osseuse des donneurs subissant une arthroplastie totale de la hanche. Les CSM ont été cultivées sur des boîtes de polystyrène, ainsi que sur deux surfaces de PPE:N différents; à haute (H) et à faible (L) pression de dépôt pendant 7 jours. Les cellules ont été transférées pour 7 jours supplémentaires dans des milieux sans sérum dans la culture culot. L'ARN a été extrait selon un protocole standard TRIzol. L'ARN a été soumis à la RT-PCR avec des amorces spécifiques pour les collagènes de type I et X. Tel qu'observé dans des études antérieures, la quantité de ARNm de collagène X été supprimée lorsque les CSM était cultivées sur les surfaces HPPE:N et LPPE:N. Le HPPE:N était plus efficace pour diminuer l'expression de collagène de type X que le LPPE:N. De plus, la diminution d'expression du collagène de type X a été maintenue bien que les cellules ont été retirées de la surface PPE:N et transférées à des cultures culots. Cependant, le niveau de ARNm du collagène de type I récupéré dans les patients atteints d'arthrose n'a pas été influencé par les surface PPE:N, ni par la culture culot. Cette étude a établie le potentiel des surfaces PPE:N en supprimant l'expression de collagène de type X par les CSM chez les personnes souffrant d'arthrose. Plus important encore, lorsque ces cellules sont transférées à des cultures culots, la suppression du collagène de type X est maintenue. Ces résultats montrent un avenir prometteur pour l'ingénierie tissulaire en combinaison avec les CSM autologues.</description><description>A major drawback of cartilage tissue engineering is that human mesenchymalstem cells (hMSCs) from osteoarthritic (OA) patients express high levels of typeX collagen. Type X collagen is a marker of late stage chondrocyte hypertrophy, linked with endochondral ossification. It has been shown that a novel plasmapolymer, called nitrogen-rich plasma-polymerized ethylene (PPE:N), is able to inhibit type X collagen expression in committed MSCs. The aim of this study was to determine if the decreased expression of type X collagen, induced by PPE:N, is maintained when MSCs are transferred to pellet cultures, an arrangement of cells which mimics embryonic condensation of mesenchymal stem cells, which results in prehypertrophic chondrocytes. hMSCs were obtained from the bone marrow of donors undergoing total hip replacement for OA. hMSCs were cultured on polystyrene dishes and on two different PPE:N surfaces: high (H) and low (L)pressure deposition for 7 days. Cells were transferred for 7 additional days in serum free media in pellet culture. RNA was extracted using a standard TRIzolprotocol. RNA was subjected to RT-PCR using primers specific for type I and X collagen. As observed in previous studies, type X collagen mRNA level was suppressed when cultured on both H- and L-PPE:N. HPPE:N was more effective in decreasing type X collagen expression than LPPE:N. Results also showed that the decreased type X collagen expression was maintained when cells were removed from the PPE:N surfaces and transferred to pellet cultures. Culturing hMSCs from OA patients on PPE:N surfaces and in pellet culture had however no effect on the level of type I collagen mRNA. The present study confirmed the potential of PPE:N surfaces in suppressing type X collagen expression in hMSCs from OA patients. More importantly, when these cells are transferred to pellet cultures, type X collagen suppression is maintained. These results show a promising future for tissue engineering using autologous hMSCs.</description><creator>Rampersad, Sonia</creator><contributor>John Antoniou (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Fackson Mwale (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Biology - Cell</subject><title>The potential of plasma-generated culture surfaces for stem cell-mediated tissue repair</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fs79r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c2366</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):37725</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>