<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:25:34Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34125" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h415pc08h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the first of three manuscripts, we describe a study in which we measured the electromyographic (EMG) and mechanical responses to brief stretches of the ankle plantarflexors applied at various instants during an imposed movement of the ankle. The results demonstrate that afferent input resulting from movement of the ankle can both modulate and inhibit the reflex EMG activity. They also reveal a dissociation of reflex EMG activity and reflex torque during the movement that cannot be explained on the basis of results obtained under stationary conditions. In the second and third manuscripts, we describe two new techniques to identify time-varying systems from ensemble data. These are meant to serve as building blocks in the development of an algorithm to identify joint mechanics during movement. The first technique applies to linear time-varying systems while the second serves to identify time-varying Hammerstein systems. The techniques can be used when the system varies quickly and require no a priori knowledge of the structure of the linear element and of the form of the time variation. Furthermore, the inputs do not need to be white. Simulation results demonstrate that the new techniques perform well in the presence of significant output noise with a reasonable number of realizations. These techniques are thus capable of yielding good system models under realistic conditions.</description><creator>Lortie, Mireille.</creator><contributor>Kearney, R. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Joint mechanics during movement : experimental and theoretical studies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333394b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pc08h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322f925</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>By combining the tools of social history, poststructural analysis, and cultural studies, this dissertation explores the perceptions and realities of late nineteenth-century retailing within Halifax, Nova Scotia. The study places business within a social, cultural, economic, and political framework, while presenting an uncommon case study in professionalization, emphasizing the heterogeneity of retailers, and redefining petty enterprise as commercial activity worthy of research. Additionally, the dissertation addresses a region and occupational group often neglected by Canadian historians. Specifically, the following study examines the late-Victorian drive for commercial professionalization, middle-class discourse on legitimacy, and recruitment of urban shopkeepers. In an era obsessed with modernity, decades plagued with financial recession, and a region haunted by a conservative reputation, prominent shopkeepers desired an elevated status for themselves, their trade, and their city. Besides the self-representations of leading proprietors, discussions of legitimacy rested upon the views offered by credit-reporting agents, supplying wholesalers, state officials, and social reformers. The external perceptions of retailing 'others'---marginal shopkeepers and itinerant traders---also helped distinguish the 'legitimate' retailer. Contributors to the discourse may have promoted the education of professional business standards, but exclusion remained an essential strategy in designating legitimacy. Although participants in the discourse never applied the criteria consistently, the identity of the 'legitimate' retailer involved the practice of up-to-date business methods and the application of contemporary notions regarding class, gender, race, ethnicity, and religion. Unfortunately for individuals concerned with promoting professionalization, no consensus emerged for the exact definition of legitimacy. Thus, most attempts to create a homogeneous and professional shopkeeping identity failed. Despite this failure, retailers demonstrated a remarkable degree of active agency. Women, minorities, immigrants, and Roman Catholics engaged in business in surprisingly large numbers. Meanwhile, leading shopkeepers were not a population of politically impotent inhabitants who blindly accepted Halifax's reputation for unprogressive enterprise. Finally, whether a retailer confronted modernity willingly or chose to reject the dictates of professionalism, all proprietors actively negotiated a course for success or pursued strategies lessening the burden of financial failure.</description><creator>Gogan, Tanya Lee.</creator><contributor>Morton, Suzanne (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Retail trade -- Nova Scotia -- Halifax -- History -- 19th century.</subject><subject>Halifax (N.S.) -- Social conditions -- 19th century.</subject><title>Accounting for legitimacy : leading retailers, petty shopkeepers, and itinerant vendors in Halifax, Nova Scotia, c.1871 to 1901</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290c169.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322f925</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j333395m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The studies included in this thesis had as aim to elucidate how individual differences in phonetic learning abilities might be related to differences in more general, psychoacoustic learning abilities, and in how they might be related to differences in brain function and brain morphology. We tested and trained English speaking volunteers to perceive the Hindi dental-retroflex phonetic contrast. We found evidence suggesting that the ability to accurately perceive "difficult" non-native contrasts is not permanently lost during development. We also tested and trained subjects to perceive the difference between non-linguistic rapidly changing and steady-state tonal sounds, and found evidence supporting the hypothesis that successful phonetic learning is in part a function of a more general psychoacoustic ability to process rapidly changing sounds. The aim of the second study was to determine how the pattern of brain activity may change as a result of training with non-native speech sounds, and in whether it is possible to differentiate "learners" from "non-learners" on the basis of neural activation patterns. Results of this functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) investigation suggested that successful learning of a non-native contrast results in the recruitment of the same areas that are involved in the processing of native contrasts; but the degree of success in learning is accompanied by more efficient neural processing in classical frontal speech regions, while making greater processing demands in left parieto-temporal speech regions. In the final study, we correlated phonetic learning measures with brain morphology throughout the whole brain volume. We found evidence for overall larger parietal volumes in the left relative to the right hemisphere, and for more white relative to gray matter in the left hemisphere in the learners and not in the nonlearners. This finding is consistent with findings by other investigators suggesting that left-hemispheric dominance for speech may be in part accounted for by hemispheric differences in white matter connectivity, which may allow faster intra- and inter-hemispheric neural transmission. This latter feature may be critical for the processing of consonant speech sounds, which depends on the ability to process sounds that change on the time scale of 30--50 milliseconds.</description><creator>Golestani, Narly A.</creator><contributor>Zatorre, Robert J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Second language acquisition -- Physiological aspects</subject><subject>Speech perception</subject><subject>Neurolinguistics</subject><title>Phonetic learning abilities : behavioral, neural functional, and neural anatomical correlates</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hd839.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j333395m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vq27zq140</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Urban spaces and their meanings are continually reinvented by daily life and representational practices. Public spaces provide an avenue to analyse the construction and contestation of political and social power in the city. The geography of Montreal's gay men's communities underwent profound changes during the 1980s. The traditional gay areas of the downtown core and the "Red Light" districts have disappeared in favour of a new gay quarter, the Village. This transformation raises questions about the exercise of power in space since the heart of the gay neighbourhood and the downtown area were one in the same. The accumulated symbolism of downtown Montreal was contested and subverted by the growing visibility of sexual minorities. This analysis of urban space reflects a transformation in public discourse that evolved from a tight control of morals, to the confinement of private morality to private spaces, and finally to the constitution of a discourse centered on human rights. A variety of qualitative methods including interviews and documentary sources, such as the community press, have been used to show the political dimension of public space and the manipulation of the symbolic economy allowing the establishment of rights to urban space. Dominion Square is the spatial focus around which collective and social phenomena have been analysed. The impacts of these phenomena on our collective imaginations have been reconstructed. The transformation of central urban space by modernist architecture and urban functionalism, reconfigured public spaces in the downtown core, along with its definitions, its representations and its control. A mapping of gay geographic imagination shows the importance of sexuality, language, social class, religion and national identities in the development of a sense of belonging in space. It has been shown that gay geographic imagination is necessarily linked to other aspects of identity and diverse manifestations of power. This imagination questioned the privileged representations of hegemonic social values through the practices of daily life, the subversion of the meaning of space and political protest. Police repression showed itself to be only one of the strategies used by the municipal establishment in its censorship practices.</description><creator>Guindon, Jocelyn M.</creator><date>2001</date><subject>Gay communities -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Gay men -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History.</subject><subject>Sociology, Urban -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>La contestation des espaces gais au centre-ville de Montreal depuis 1950 /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945s55f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zq140</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9880vs585</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of the present study was to investigate the effects of problem-based learning (PBL) with learning-disabled (LD) students. Twenty-four students (12 dyads) classified as LD and attending a school for the learning-disabled participated in the study. Students engaged in either a computer-based environment involving BioWorld, a hospital simulation designed to teach biology students problem-solving skills, or a paper-and-pencil version based on the computer program. A hybrid model of learning was adopted whereby students were provided with direct instruction on the digestive system prior to participating in a problem-solving activity. Students worked in dyads and solved three problems involving the digestive system in either a computerized or a paper-and-pencil condition. The experimenter acted as a coach to assist students throughout the problem-solving process. A follow-up study was conducted, one month later, to measure the long-term learning gains. Quantitative and qualitative methods were used to analyze three types of data: process data, outcome data, and follow-up data. Results from the process data showed that all students engaged in effective collaboration and became more systematic in their problem solving over time. Findings from the outcome and follow-up data showed that students in both treatment conditions, made both learning and motivational gains and that these benefits were still evident one month later. Overall, results demonstrated that the computer facilitated students' problem solving and scientific reasoning skills. Some differences were noted in students' collaboration and the amount of assistance required from the coach in both conditions. Thus, PBL is an effective learning approach with LD students in science, regardless of the type of learning environment. These results have implications for teaching science to LD students, as well as for future designs of educational software for this population.</description><creator>Guerrera, Claudia P.</creator><contributor>Lajoie, Susanne (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology -- Study and teaching.</subject><subject>Learning disabled teenagers.</subject><subject>Problem-based learning.</subject><title>Testing the effectiveness of problem-based learning with learning disabled students in biology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128ng291.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vs585</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h415pc09s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the development and validation of Canadian Land Surface Scheme (CLASS) for various wetland landscapes individually, along with an evaluation of modelled results over a heterogeneous surface with airborne observations. A further statistical analysis of the effects of land surface classification procedures over the study area and their influence on modelled results is performed. CLASS is tested over individual wetland types: bog, fen and marsh in a stand-alone (non-GCM coupled) mode. Atmospheric conditions are provided for the eight site locations from tower measured data, while each surface is parameterized within the model from site specific measurements. Resulting model turbulent and radiative flux output is then statistically evaluated against observed tower data. Findings show that while CLASS models vascular dominated wetland areas (fen and marsh) quite well, non-vascular wetlands (bogs) are poorly represented, even with improved soil descriptions. At times when the water table is close to the surface, evaporation is greatly overestimated, whereas lowered water tables generate a vastly underestimated latent heat flux. Because CLASS does not include a moisture transfer scheme applicable for non-vascular vegetation, the description of this vegetation type as either a vascular plant or bare soil appears inappropriate. CLASS was then tuned for a specific bog location found in the Hudson Bay Lowland (HBL) during the Northern Wetlands Study (NOWES). With bog surfaces better described within the model, testing of CLASS over a highly heterogeneous 169 km2 HBL region is then undertaken. The model is first modified for lake and pond surfaces and then separate runs for bog, fen, lake and tree/shrub categories is undertaken. Using a GIS, the test region under which airborne flux measurements are available is divided into 104 grid cells and proportions of each surface type are calculated within each cell. Findings indicate that although the modelled grid average radiation and flux values are reasonably well reproduced (4% error for net radiation, 10% for latent heat flux and 30% for sensible heat flux), spatial agreement between modelled and observed grid cells is disappointing. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Comer, Neil Thomas.</creator><contributor>Roulet, N. T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Atmospheric circulation -- Hudson Bay Region -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Eddy flux -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Vegetation and climate -- Hudson Bay Region -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Wetlands -- Hudson Bay Region -- Classification.</subject><subject>Atmosphere -- Latent heat release -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Validation and heterogeneity investigation of the Canadian Land Surface Scheme (CLASS) for wetland landscapes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cf968.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pc09s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05fd42x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two kinetically and pharmacologically distinct outward K+ conductances were found to be simultaneously activated at the plasma membrane of TBY-2 suspension culture protoplasts using the whole-cell patch-clamp technique. We used a modified Hodgkin-Huxley model to quantify the activation kinetics of the outward current. Time constants for the two conductances derived from the model differed in magnitude by 5--10 fold over the voltage range from -10 mV to +50 mV, allowing their classification as either fast or slow. Deactivation kinetics were better fit by two exponential terms rather than one, yielding fast and slow deactivation time constants. The voltage dependence of time constants derived from these two independent two-channel models followed a bell-shaped distribution with mid-point potentials for both components at -20 mV with a standard 10-fold K+ gradient (10 K+o/100K+i). Both components were highly K+-selective, however the tail current amplitudes of the slowly activating component at hyperpolarized potentials exhibited non-linear rectification whereas the tail current amplitudes of the fast activating component were linear. The ratio of inward tail current/activated outward current (envelope of tails test) was not constant during the depolarizing step; during the first 50--100 milliseconds the ratio was 6 times higher than at quasi-steady-state (i.e. after 0.3 second). A pharmacological dissection of outward currents revealed that external Ba2+ in the range from 10 muM to 1 mM selectively inhibited a fast, sigmoidally activating, slowly inactivating current as revealed by examining difference currents. The more slowly activating component was inhibited by only 20% with 5 mM Ba2+. Conversely, nitrendipine or bepridil (5--100 muM) selectively inhibited the slower component of outward current. External TEA inhibited both the fast and slow components equally; tail current amplitudes of both components were inhibited by 40% with 2 mM TEA and the activation time courses in the presence of TEA conserved the same kinetic parameters as control currents.</description><creator>Crotty, Christopher M.</creator><contributor>Poole, Ronald J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Protoplasts.</subject><subject>Potassium channels.</subject><title>Two distinct outward K+ conductances are simultaneously activated in TBY-2 suspension culture protoplasts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268677z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fd42x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dt69v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the ecological consequences of sewage disposal in aquatic ecosystems. Sewage simultaneously represents a form of enrichment and a source of stress to a receiving system. Enrichment effects dominate when sewage loading does not exceed the capacity of the system to assimilate waste, as is presently the case in the St. Lawrence River. We developed a method to quantify the assimilation of sewage-derived organic matter by riverine biota, then used this method to examine the pathways by which sewage enhances secondary production in the St. Lawrence. We showed that the relative importance of dissolved nutrients and particulate organic matter to the river food web is to a large degree dictated by the physical and biological characteristics of the local environment. The effects of this enrichment on the receiving water community were also influenced by habitat characteristics. Analysis of body size distributions revealed that only the largest organisms had higher densities at enriched sites, and that the identity of these organisms depended on habitat structure. Densities of smaller organisms were controlled by a combination of habitat characteristics and feeding interactions. This pattern was consistent with food web models of top-down (consumer) control. At each trophic level, relatively invulnerable (large) prey achieved higher densities, whereas densities of more vulnerable (small) prey were controlled by their predators. Finally, we synthesized the ideas outlined above to predict how conditions in the St. Lawrence will change in the future as a result of lower water levels. More extensive macrophyte cover, slower current, and warmer temperatures in a shallower St. Lawrence will all enhance the ability of the system to physically retain and biologically process sewage nutrients, but will also increase the likelihood of negative effects such as anoxia.</description><creator>DeBruyn, Adrian M. H.</creator><contributor>Rasmussen, Joseph B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Saint Lawrence River -- Environmental conditions.</subject><subject>Stream ecology -- Saint Lawrence River.</subject><subject>Sewage -- Environmental aspects -- Saint Lawrence River.</subject><subject>Food chains (Ecology) -- Saint Lawrence River.</subject><title>Sewage and the ecology of the St. Lawrence River</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494b091.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dt69v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87ps01n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>While Pauline studies today are grappling with the question of the core of Paul's thought, the investigation of the apostle's social world is also gaining interest among scholars. The study of Paul's argumentation offers a fundamental contribution to both endeavours. Enthymemes, defined by the rhetorical tradition as the basic building blocks of deductive argumentation, constitute an important part of Paul's argumentation which until now has been relatively unexploited. Study of the manner in which Paul constructs enthymemes gives us insight into his thought world. The premisses that he uses as argumentative proofs can be viewed as a reflection of the common "social knowledge" of the Pauline milieu. The object of this inquiry is to study Paul's use of enthymemes as a rhetorical and argumentative tool and to evaluate what this reveals about his thought, his teaching, and his social world. The study begins with a discussion of the problem of enthymeme definition, followed by a clarification of criteria for identifying enthymemes in texts. A method of analysis is proposed. The entire corpus of Paul's seven undisputed letters is then "combed" for enthymemes, one epistle at a time. Enthymemes are identified and analysed, and their argumentative premisses are catalogued thematically. This exercise permits a serious consideration of Paul's modes of argumentation, rhetorical aims and social world in the context of each epistle. Results from different epistles are compared as a means to consider, in general, Paul's rhetorical habits. This thesis argues that enthymeme analysis is a necessary first step in Pauline exegesis. It is also argued that more attention needs to be given to enthymeme study in the research into Paul's social world. The question of how enthymeme study can inform the study of Paul's theology and core convictions is also discussed.</description><creator>Debanné, Marc J.</creator><contributor>Henderson, I. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Paul, the Apostle, Saint.</subject><subject>Enthymeme (Logic)</subject><title>Enthymemes in the letters of Paul</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000172f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87ps01n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rq43x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Haemophilus influenzae (Hi) is a Gram-negative bacteria that is the causative agent of bacterial meningitis. The outer membrane (OM) of Gram-negative bacteria functions as a selectively permeable barrier. The exchange of small hydrophilic solutes between the external environment and the periplasm is mediated by large water-filled channels, porins. Charged residues of the pore determine the functional properties of the protein, which include: ion conductance, ionic selectivity, and voltage gating. To study the properties of the porin (341 amino acids; Mr 37,782) of Haemophilus influenzae type b (Hib), purified porin was subjected to chemical modification. The covalent modification of lysine residues with succinic anhydride (SA; Mr 100.08) results in charge reversal. The addition of up to 12 succinate groups per porin molecule was identified using electrospray ionization mass spectrometry (MS). Tryptic digestion of the modified Hib porin followed by reverse phase chromatography and matrix assisted laser desorption ionization time-of-flight MS identified the sites of succinylation. The majority of modified lysines were positioned in surface-located loops, numbers 1 and 4 to 7. When the electrophysiological properties of SA-modified porin were analyzed in planar lipid bilayers (PLBs) and compared to Hib porin it was found that the single channel conductance was increased, while the threshold for voltage gating was decreased. The addition of extra negative charges increase the single channel conductance of Hib porin and function as voltage sensors. Selected lysine residues that were found to be modified with SA were substituted with glutamic acid using site-directed mutagenesis. Single point mutations were made in a residue assigned to the barrel lumen and to three residues in each of loops 4 and 6. The mutant Hib porins had increased single channel conductances relative to wild-type Hib porin. Voltage gating of mutant Hib porins was altered by the introduction of negative charges into loops 4 and 6 and in the barrel lumen. Previous experiments had implicated surface-exposed loop 4 in voltage gating. This study ascribes a role for residues in loop 6 and a residue within the barrel lumen in the changes that accompany pore closure. Hi strains causing infection in cystic fibrosis patients are capable of persistent infection despite prolonged antibiotic treatment with beta-lactam antibiotics. During the course of infection porin properties may be altered due to the changes in porin sequences that are attributed to antigenic drift. The electrophysiological properties of four porins from CF patient-derived Hi strains were characterized to examine changes in porin properties arising from persistent infection of the CF lung. The clinical Hi porins displayed altered channel properties that included increased voltage sensitivity and single channel conductances that were either greater or smaller than that of Hib porin. The decreased single channel conductance of one of the porins was associated with an increase in the minimal inhibitory concentration of the antibiotics novobiocin and streptomycin. These results demonstrate a porin-mediated decrease in OM permeability as an antibiotic resistance mechanism for Hi.</description><creator>Arbing, Mark A.</creator><contributor>Coulton, James W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Electrophysiological properties of porin, the major outer membrane protein of Haemophilus influenzae</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128c56d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rq43x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1544br08t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In most food applications, whey proteins are used, rather than the individual proteins and this accounts for the high functional variability among commercially available whey protein products, and limits their applications. The overall objective of this study was to investigate the structural and thermal properties of individual alpha-lactalbumin (alpha-Lac) and beta-lactoglobulin (beta-Lg) fractions isolated from different whey protein sources. A common non-chromatographic process that isolate alpha-Lac and beta-Lg, with relatively high purity and yield from liquid whey (LW), whey protein concentrate (WPC) and whey protein isolate (WPI) using different chelating agents, was developed. The use of sodium citrate (NaC) and sodium hexametaphosphate (SHMP) were more effective than other chelating agents. Yield results indicated that 47 to 69% of beta-Lg originally present in the whey preparations was recovered, with purities ranging from 84 to 95%, and protein contents ranging from 40 to 99%, while the yields of alpha-Lac were 23 to 89%, with purities ranging from 83 to 90%, and protein contents ranging from 65 to 96% depending on the source of whey protein preparations and type of chelating agents. Structural and thermal properties of beta-Lg and alpha-Lac isolated fractions were studied using polyacrylamide electrophoresis (native and SDS), RP-HPLC, differential scanning calorimetry (DSC), Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy (FTIR) and electrospray ionization mass spectrometry (ESI-MS). Results showed that all beta-Lg and alpha-Lac isolated fractions exhibit increased thermal stability and reversibility over standard proteins and difference in thermal properties were dependent on protein source. The relative intensity of the 1692 cm-1 band in the beta-Lg isolated fractions was dependent on the nature of the chelating agent, and disappearance of this band occurred at temperature higher than that of beta-Lg standard, indicating increased thermal stability of beta-Lg isolated fractions. Denaturation of apo-alpha-Lac was related to the gradual decrease in the alpha-helix band and accompanied by the gain in intensity of 1653 and 1641 cm-1 bands, while denaturation of holo-alpha-Lac was associated by breakdown of beta-sheet structure and increase in turns and unordered structures. Changes in charge state distribution (CSD), as measured by ESI-MS of beta-Lg and alpha-Lac in response to pH and storage time, were only qualitative and were of relatively low resolution at basic pH. The hydrogen/deuterium (H/D) exchange results demonstrated that the conformation of holo-alpha-Lac was more stable than that of apo-alpha-Lac and conformation of beta-Lg variant B was more stable than beta-Lg variant A. Kinetics of H/D exchange indicated that alpha-Lac and beta-Lg fractions isolated from different whey protein sources have the same or improved conformational stabilities compared to that of alpha-Lac and beta-Lg standard. The covalent binding of 3 or more hexose residues to alpha-Lac enhanced its conformational stability, but covalent binding of two hexose residues to beta-Lg resulted in less stable conformation.</description><creator>Alomirah, Husam Fahd.</creator><contributor>Alli, I. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Whey products.</subject><title>Separation and structural characterization of alpha-lactalbumin and beta-lactoglobulin from whey products</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n2040786.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544br08t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913r53s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Protein-lipid complexes are known to result from complex molecular interactions which contribute to physiochemical and functional properties of foods. To identify the interactions of food proteins with lipids and the associated changes in properties, the following factors were investigated: incubation temperature, pH, type of lipids (phospholipid, triglyceride and fatty acids) and different proteins (ovalbumin and soybean glycinin). The effects of lipids on physiochemical and functional characteristics of ovalbumin and glycinin were investigated using polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis (PAGE), fluorescence, differential scanning calorimetry (DSC), Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy, and emulsification and gelation properties. The results showed that pH, temperature and the type of lipids affected both ovalbumin-lipid interactions and physiochemical properties of ovalbumin. Changes in the electrophoretic behavior of ovalbumin were related to the presence of lipids, and the relative fluorescence of ovalbumin decreased in the presence of lipids at different pH values. In addition, lipids increased the stability of ovalbumin as revealed by the thermal denaturation (Td) and by the enthalpy transition (DeltaH). FTIR spectra in the amide I absorption region revealed that lipids affected the secondary structure of ovalbumin. Changes in the integrated intensity of the amide II band between (1520--1555) cm -1 in the presence of D2O showed that H-D exchange of ovalbumin decreased in the presence of lipids. Emulsifying properties, gel strength and water holding capacity (WHC) of ovalbumin increased significantly (P &lt; 0.05) in the presence of lipids. Scanning electron microscopy (SEM) showed difference in the microstructure of ovalbumin gel in the presence of different lipids. The more pronounced effect of lipids was observed with lecithin and the lowest was with stearic acid. The order of magnitude for the effects of lipids on physiochemical and functional properties of ovalbumin was: lecithin &gt; cocoa butter &gt; oleic acid &gt; linoleic acid &gt; linolenic acid &gt; stearic acid. It is likely that the degree of polarity of lipids play an important role in protein-lipid interactions and in the enhancement of the functional properties of ovalbumin. The effects of soybean oil (SO), soybean lecithin (SL) and a mixture of both (SOL) on physiochemical and functional properties of soybean glycinin were studied at pH 8.0, with incubation at 40°C. Changes in the electrophoretic behavior were related to the presence of lipids. Relative fluorescence of glycinin decreased in the presence of lipids. Lipids increased the thermal stability (Td) of glycinin from 89.7°C to 92.0°C, 94.3°C and 93.4°C with SO, SL and SOL respectively. FTIR spectra indicated changes in both; the secondary structure and H-D exchange of glycinin in the presence of lipids. Gel strength, WHC and emulsifying properties of glycinin increased significantly (P &lt; 0.05) in the presence of lipids; the order of consequence increase was: SL &gt; SOL &gt; SO. SEM showed difference in the microstructure of glycinin gels with the different lipids used. Overall, the results demonstrate both quantitative and qualitative effects on the physiochemical and functional properties of ovalbumin and glycinin as a result of protein-lipid interactions.</description><creator>Alzagtat, Ahmeda A.</creator><contributor>Alli, I. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Food -- Protein content.</subject><subject>Lipids.</subject><title>Effects of protein-lipid interactions on physiochemical and functional properties of food proteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rm96n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913r53s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cn69m5672</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The research work presented in this thesis deals with flight control problems. Based on robust control techniques such as H infinity control and mu-synthesis, we develop control laws that are efficient in reducing gust loads on flexible aircraft. Uncertainty models for flexible aircraft are proposed and shown to be well adapted for robust control design, while tightly covering unknown but bounded variations of flexible mode parameters. One of the models presented introduces a new complex-rational controller design methodology that takes advantage of the uncertain plant structure and achieves good performance criteria. Other uncertainty models are presented for the first time for the purpose of closed-loop reduction of flexible models. We propose a new model/controller order reduction method for flexible aircraft preserving robust performance in closed loop. Two case studies of complex aircraft are presented with the objective of full flight envelope control. Solutions for scheduled control laws are given to maintain performance objectives along the entire flight envelope. We adapt to our complex aircraft case study known gain scheduling techniques such as observer-form controller scheduling, and we propose new gain scheduling techniques, including a robust performance blending/interpolation design, an optimal multi-switching methodology and a scheduled-partitioned controller.</description><creator>Aouf, Nabil.</creator><contributor>Boulet, Benoit (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Robust control techniques for aerospace vehicles</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322f94q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m5672</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w3763865n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Multiple lines of evidence indicate that neurons within the brainstem pontomesencephalic tegmentum (PMT) are critically involved in the initiation of paradoxical sleep (PS). Evidence suggests that unidentified but "possibly" cholinergic neurons discharge at higher rates during PS than during slow wave sleep or even Waking and would thus play an active role, whereas "presumed" monoaminergic neurons cease firing during PS and would thus play a permissive role in PS generation. Efferent projections from these PMT neurons have been thought to stimulate PS through modulation of (1) adjacent neurons in the oral pontine reticular formation, (2) more caudally distributed neurons of the medullary reticular formation, and (3) more rostrally distributed neurons in the ventral mesencephalic tegmentum, as well as thalamic and extrathalamic relay systems implicated in limbic and cortical activation. In the present study, dual-immunostaining for c-Fos, as a marker of cellular activation, and choline acetyltransferase (ChAT), serotonin (Ser), tyrosine hydroxylase (TH), or glutamic acid decarboxylase (GAD) permitted immunohistochemical identification of active neurons during PS rebound as compared with PS deprivation and PS control conditions. In the PMT, there was an increase in ChAT+/c-Fos+ cells, a decrease in Ser+/c-Fos+ and TH+/c-Fos+ cells, and an increase in GAD+/c-Fos+ cells during PS rebound. These results support the hypothesis that cholinergic neurons are active, whereas monoaminergic neurons are inactive during PS and possibly inhibited by surrounding GABAergic neurons. In the reticular formation, there was an increase in c-Fos+ cells and a decrease in GAD+/c-Fos+ cells during PS rebound in the oral pontine reticular nucleus, suggesting a disinhibition of these reticular neurons. In contrast, in the caudal pontine and medullary reticular nuclei, there was an increase in GAD+/c-Fos+ cells during PS rebound, and covariation with EMG in a manner to suggest an inhibitory role of these GABAergic neurons in muscle atonia. In the midbrain, there was an increase in TH+/c-Fos+ cells in the ventral tegmental area during PS rebound. The results suggest that DA neurons may increase activity during PS and therein, via connections with limbic and cortical structures, contribute to the unique physiological and cognitive aspects of that state, including dreaming.</description><creator>Maloney, Karen J.</creator><contributor>Jones, B. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>The role of cholinergic, monoaminergic, and GABAergic neurons of the brainstem in paradoxical sleep /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p8725.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763865n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr171z832</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The importance of aluminum nitride (AlN) stems from its application in microelectronics as a substrate material due to its high thermal conductivity, high electrical resistance, mechanical strength and hardness, thermal durability and chemical stability. Yttria (Y2O3) is the best additive for AlN sintering, which undergoes densification through a liquid phase mechanism. The surface oxide, Al2O3, reacts with the oxide additive, Y2O3, to form a Y-Al-O-N liquid that promotes particle rearrangement and densification. Construction of the phase relations in this multicomponent system is becoming essential for further development of AlN. Binary diagrams of A2O3-Y2O3, AlN-Al2O3, and AlN-Y2O3 were thermodynamically modeled in this work. The obtained Gibbs free energies of the components, stoichiometric phases and solution parameters were used for the calculation of the isothermal sections and liquidus surface of the AlN-Al2O 3-Y2O3 system. Phase evolutions, melting and solidifications in the Al2O3-Y2O3 phase diagram were investigated using x-ray diffraction and in situ high temperature neutron diffractometry. The phase diagram of AlN-Y2O 3 system was established and verified experimentally. The predicted ternary phase diagram for AlN-Al2O3-Y2O 3 was also verified experimentally using in situ high temperature neutron diffractometry and it has been constructed for the first time in this work. A self-consistent thermodynamic database including all the phases in the AlN-Al2O3-Y2O3 system was developed during the course of this project. This database was used to explain the experimental results of AlN sintering. It has been found that the samples with high densities had lower liquid formation temperatures, and low thermal conductivity was related to the residual Al2O3 and high YAP (Al2O3.Y2O3) content.</description><creator>Medraj, Mamoun.</creator><contributor>Drew, R. A. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><title>Phase equilibria in the AIN-AIO-YO system : utility in AIN processing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930bz89f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr171z832</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f292f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A multicomponent study of Pb and Cu retention was performed using a selective contamination technique. Soil components were selectively extracted from a multicomponent illite clay artificial soil using extractants commonly utilized in sequential extraction studies. Pb and Cu retention by the soil components: carbonates, amorphous oxides, natural organic matter and the clay minerals, were examined. It was found that the clay minerals are the most important contributor to the retention of Pb and Cu, which in this case is predominantly illite. Adsorption and not precipitation is believed to be the controlling mechanism of retention although retention by precipitation increased with increasing pH. Pb and Cu retention from a single metal solution as well as competitive retention of Pb and Cu from a mixed metal solution on each of the untreated and treated artificial soils were examined. Competitive adsorption experiments found that Pb was preferred over Cu for adsorption by the untreated and treated artificial soils and greater quantities of Pb were retained than Pb applied in composite with Cu or Cu applied as a single metal. Pb removed from the artificial soil, using sequential extraction analysis, was compared to Pb retained and mass balance was observed. The artificial soil was found to contain both variable and constant charge surfaces but the artificial soil contaminant interaction was modelled best using only the variable charge surface. The presence of ion exchange adsorption and Ca competition are examined.</description><creator>MacDonald, Elaine.</creator><contributor>Yong, R. N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Lead and copper retention by a shale derived artificial illite clay soil : a multicomponent study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655j244.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f292f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q237ht426</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Let theta be an inner function for the upper half plane. We are interested in the description of positive functions wx defined on R for which fx &amp;les;wx, x&amp;isin;R, for some non-zero f in the model space Ktheta of H2( R ). In the special case theta(x) = e isigmax, sigma &gt; 0, the celebrated multiplier theorem of Beurling and Malliavin gives an almost complete solution. We give a general multiplier theorem applicable to all Ktheta with theta having a smooth argument on the real line. This result applies, in particular, to the spaces KB formed from Blaschke products B for the upper half plane, meromorphic in C . We show that in this case the criterion for a function w to have the above property depends on the distribution of the zeros of B.</description><creator>Mashreghi, Javad.</creator><contributor>Koosis, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Havin, V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Admissible majorants for model subspaces of H</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cc51s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237ht426</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3484zj38t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This PhD. dissertation consists of three essays to fill some gaps in the recent research in international trade and endogenous growth theory. The first essay explores the dynamic effect of interaction of research and development (R&amp;D) activities among countries on endogenous economic growth. It attempts to fill the gap between the current endogenous growth research focused on independent R&amp;D activities and decision-making in the international competition and the interdependent R&amp;D competition in reality. This paper finds that the growth rates, welfare, and investment on R&amp;D in the world do differ between independent R&amp;D activity and interdependent R&amp;D activities among countries. The welfare for each country in the open-loop Nash equilibrium is higher than that of the Markov-perfect Nash equilibrium, and both are lower than that in the cooperative game. The model shows that the ability to commit turns out to make every country better off. The interesting results are that when an increase in the number of countries does increase the growth rate in the open-loop Nash equilibrium, it is very possible to have the negative effect on the growth rate in the Markov-perfect equilibrium. Particularly, the model shows that the tendency of free-ride rises with more countries in the competition. The more general models with durable physical capital, and with the endogenous rate of time preference following Uzawa-Epstein tradition, also prove these conclusions. The second essay turns to the Samuelson-Diamond overlapping generation paradigm, a finite-horizon overlapping generations model with education proposed by Michel (1993). The focus is shifted to the effect of trade on growth. It turns out that when trade affects the formation of human capital, endogenous growth is possible even in the simplest economy with a single sector and constant returns to scale technologies, which is opposite from Boldrin's (1992) and Jones and Manuelli's (1992) results. While the existing theory of trade under oligopolistic competition is mostly static in nature, the third essay fills this gap by modeling international trade under oligopoly in a dynamic setting. This essay adopts the dynamics in the model provided by allowing the demand curve to shift over time as a result of "habit formation". It shows that when the importing country is committing to a policy of voluntary import expansions (VIEs), in the certain condition (i.e. k &gt; 1), VIEs can improve the global welfare, the welfare of the importing country, and the profit of both firms. So, in a sense, voluntary import expansion is truly voluntary.</description><creator>Yin, Xiaopeng, 1963-</creator><contributor>Long, Ngo Van (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>International trade.</subject><subject>Economic development -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Endogenous growth, international trade and dynamics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cs10m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zj38t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52j961h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The key to understanding Islam and civil society is the state. However, this key issue has been decentered due to the prevailing focus in the literature, that is the compatibility/incompatibility between Islam and civil society. The findings of this thesis reveal emergent Islamic sensibilities and capacities that lead to transitions in state-Islam interaction. These findings call for a rethinking of the theories on civil society and Islam. The study is based on an extended empirical research project undertaken in Turkey and Kazakhstan between 1997--1999. It focuses on the leading Islamic community-movement in Turkey, Gulen Community, which is not only national(ist) but also internationally organized in numerous countries. Gulen Community aims to reconcile Islamic ways of lives and faith with the secular institutional milieu. Gulen accomplishes its goal mainly (yet not only) through education, i.e., its numerous high schools and universities in Turkey and all around the world. The main finding of my research contrasts with the juxtaposition of Islam and the state in the literature: Gulen creates the alternative pathways of engagements with the state. The engagements range from domestic symbolic politics and negotiations to international alliances. The thesis examines the engagements in three distinct spheres, i.e., the national education, international undertakings and the gender order. As ethnographic research in Istanbul and Almati revealed, the domestically uneasy interactions between Gulen and the state take the form of overt alliances at the international level. I argue that Gulen's strong identification with the 'nation as the state' facilitates its engagements with the is Republic. Moreover, Gulen's inheritance of the gender strategies of the founding fathers of the nation contributes further to the congruence between Gulen and the state. My argument is that the engagements can largely be explained by the elective affinities between Islam and the nation-state, which are analyzed at three levels: identity, state and the international world order. The thesis reveals that further research has to be done on the following question: Is the Turkish state in the process of creating a nationalist, non-threatening and pro-state Islam?</description><creator>Turam, Berna.</creator><contributor>Hall, John A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Islam and state -- Turkey.</subject><subject>Turkey -- Politics and government -- 1980-</subject><title>Between Islam and the state : politics of engagement : the engagements between Gulen Community and the secular Turkish state</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719n84p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j961h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ms35tb05s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Expatriate social interactions and psychological well-being are two underemphasized areas in expatriate literature. This paper revisits the expatriate adjustment construct and proposes a definition from interactive perspective for expatriate adjustment. Expatriate adjustment is defined, in this study, as a process in which the expatriate interacts with the social aspects of the local environment to obtain psychological well-being. In turn, an expatriate's psychological well-being at one point in time will influence his/her next interactions in the local environment. Based on the proposed definition of expatriate adjustment and supported by literatures of sociology and psychology, a research model and hypotheses are developed. The research model predicts that expatriate network structural characteristics will influence expatriate perceived social support and further influence expatriate psychological well-being and performance. The influence of social support on expatriate psychological well-being and performance is predicted to be moderated by cultural distance, role characteristics and locus of control of expatriates. Spousal support is another immediate factor that will influence expatriate psychological well-being. In order to empirically test this research model, two pilot studies and one main study were conducted. The purpose of Pilot Study 1 was to develop network structural characteristic measurement and social support measurement. Pilot Study 2 was conducted to test the measurement developed in Pilot Study 1 and check the workability of the whole questionnaire. The main survey was conducted in China. Expatriates from North America, Europe, and other countries and regions in Asia were sampled to complete the questionnaire. The data collected were analyzed to test the hypotheses. The results show significant support for the proposed model. Expatriate network structural characteristics have both direct and indirect influence on expatriate psychological well-</description><creator>Wang, Xiaoyun, 1964-</creator><contributor>Kanungo, R. N. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Jaeger, A. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Social networks.</subject><subject>Quality of life.</subject><subject>Alien labor -- Social networks -- China.</subject><subject>Alien labor -- China.</subject><title>Expatriate social support network, psychological well-being, and performance : a theoretical examination and an empirical test</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75df18f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tb05s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43nz795</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation explores the cultural practice of smoking and its connection to social relations from the beginning of cigarette mass production in Montreal in 1888 to the First World War. It uncovers the norms of smoking etiquette and taste, their roots in gender, class and race relations and their use in reproducing these power relationships. It argues that these prescriptions reflected and served to legitimize beliefs about inclusion, exclusion and hierarchy that were at the core of nineteenth century liberalism. Liberal ideals of self-control and rationality structured the ritual of smoking: from the purchase of tobacco; to who was to smoke; to how one was supposed to smoke; to where one smoked. These prescriptions served to normalize the exclusion of women from the definition of the liberal individual and to justify the subordination of the poor and cultural minorities. Furthermore, even while these prescriptions were at their height, an emergent group of beliefs began to recast notions of respectable smoking around new ideals of speed and ungendered universality. This challenge was not only part of the transition from bourgeois to mass consumption, it was the roots of a transformation of the liberal order in the years previous to the First World War.</description><creator>Rudy, Robert Jarrett.</creator><contributor>Young, Brian J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Montréal (Québec) -- Social life and customs -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Tobacco use -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History.</subject><subject>Montréal (Québec) -- Social life and customs -- 19th century.</subject><title>Manly smokes : tobacco consumption and the construction of identities in industrial Montreal, 1888-1914</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x5657.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43nz795</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8623j051j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the United States, the transition from aristocratic agriculturalism to liberal democratic industrialism was distinguished from instances of this transformation in other countries by a threat to the territorial integrity of the Union. In this dissertation, I provide novel insight into this unique challenge and its link to American political development. Drawing on recent works on the process of secession, I have developed an innovative framework for the analysis of secession in which the institutional design of the state plays a central role in facilitating this act of territorial and political withdrawal. This framework specifies five factors that contribute to the development, timing, and success of a movement for secession: grievance, the institutional design of the state, boundaries, leadership, and sequence. My framework is generalizable and can be used to illuminate the desire for secession in other regions of the world. In order to provide a thorough analysis of this case of secession, I examine the historical background of the decision to secede, with an emphasis on the nullification crisis and the first secession crisis. Without the steps and missteps taken in these moments, secession would have been unlikely. In addition, I examine the actions of the other states of the South: the early-seceders of the Deep South, the late-seceders of the Upper South, and the non-seceders of the Border South. I conclude that secession in South Carolina was the result of a number of dynamically interacting factors, beginning with the grievance experienced by the elites and the rest of the white, male population of South Carolina. This grievance was produced by demographic changes in the Union that allowed Republican Abraham Lincoln to be elected president without needing electoral support in the South. The grievance (fear) wrought by these changes animated the desire for secession, but secession was politically feasible because of the institutional design of the American state. Central to my argument is the notion that federal states are both easier to enter, because they facilitate the maintenance of local autonomy, and easier to exit (than other states), because the maintenance of state capacity and a high degree of autonomy at the state level makes withdrawal from the federal state possible with minimal disruption. The very sequence by which secession was accomplished provides essential insight into the dynamics of secession. The South did not secede simultaneously, but sequentially---with South Carolina seceding unilaterally, and forcing the hand of the remaining states. Given the divisions present in the South, this strategy of seeking sequential exit through unilateral secession in South Carolina was the best possible strategy to realize the goal of a Southern Confederacy.</description><creator>Anderson, Lawrence (Lawrence M.)</creator><contributor>Meadwell, Hudson (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Secession -- Southern States</subject><subject>South Carolina -- History -- 1775-1865.</subject><title>Secession, sequence, and the state : South Carolina's decision to lead the secession movement in 1860</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375z051.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j051j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qb98mh272</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two-dimensional free-space optical interconnects (2D-FSOIs) promise to deliver tremendous gains in bandwidth and architectural freedom for applications such as telecommunication switches and massively parallel computing systems. One major obstacle preventing the commercial deployment of 2D-FSOI systems is the problem of optical alignment, which is further exacerbated by the requirements that these systems be field-serviceable and able to sustain the harsh conditions of industrial environments. This thesis proposes a broad range of solutions to alleviate this alignment problem. One important aspect of this work concerns the development of a generic packaging strategy, which consists of partitioning an optical system into separate modules in such a way that the loose tolerances are between the modules while the tight tolerances are between the components inside the modules. To accomplish this, novel alignment techniques are designed and demonstrated, including the use of integrated diffractive features, CMOS position detectors, ultrathick photoresist micro-structures, and semi-kinematic fixtures using dowel pins. In all cases, emphasis is placed on approaches that are amenable to low-cost manufacturing and high-volume production. These techniques were developed in the context of a photonic backplane prototype experiment that demonstrated 1024 free-space interconnections between four optoelectronic-VLSI (OE-VLSI) chips. The design and implementation of a module integrating an OE-VLSI chip, a mini-lens array, a thermoelectric cooler and a heatsink is presented. Optomechanical, electrical and thermal characterization results are reported. The other aspect of this work aims at identifying the types of optical designs that provide more generous misalignment tolerances. This is done by investigating various optical configurations for the design of the chip module. The central objective is to understand the underlying reasons that make one configuration more misalignment-tolerant than another. A significant outcome of this work is to show that the inherent misalignment tolerances of 2D-FSOI systems translates into an aspect-ratio limitation similar to the one found in electrical interconnects.</description><creator>Ayliffe, Michael H.</creator><contributor>Plant, David V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Packaging.</subject><title>Alignment and packaging techniques for two-dimensional free-space optical interconnects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365688q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mh272</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d504rm97x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The efficiency of estimation procedures and the validity of testing procedures in simple and multiple quantitative linear models with autocorrelated errors have been studied in this thesis. The importance of the nature of the explanatory variable(s), fixed and trended versus purely random or following a first-order autoregressive [AR(1)] process, has been emphasized in Monte Carlo studies. The estimation procedures were compared on the basis of different measures of efficiency, relative to OLS or GLS, depending on the context. The estimation procedures studied include the Ordinary Least Squares (OLS), Generalized Least Squares (GLS), estimated GLS, Maximum Likelihood (ML), Restricted Maximum Likelihood (REML), First Differences (FD) and original First-Difference Ratios (FDR). The derived testing procedures were compared on the basis of a condition of strict validity as well as a criterion taking the variability of empirical significance levels into account. In a preliminary step, the conflicting statements made in the literature concerning estimation in quantitative linear models with autocorrelated errors were sorted out. Unlike the efficiency of estimation procedures, the validity of testing procedures had been studied less extensively before. One of the main results of this thesis is that the more efficient of two estimators does not necessarily provide a more valid testing procedure for the parameter of interest. First, FD and FDR are highly inefficient relative to OLS, but they generally provide a valid test for the combinations of sample size and error autocorrelation parameter considered, whatever the nature of the explanatory variable(s) may be. Second, almost all the testing procedures, including the classical t-test and some modified t-tests of the slope, satisfy the criterion of validity in simple linear regression when the explanatory variable is purely random and the errors follow an AR(1) process. An explanation in terms of effective sample size is given. Third, ML and REML are equally efficient for large sample sizes, and at the same time REML provides a test of the slope that is more valid than the ML testing procedures. These features are illustrated in an application to environmental data.</description><creator>Alpargu, Gülhan.</creator><contributor>Dutilleul, Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Statistics.</subject><title>Estimation and testing in quantitative linear models with autocorrelated errors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150k80r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rm97x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xp68kj06x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:43:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The dissertation seeks to contribute to our understanding of the role played by parties in the consolidation of democracy in the context of military tutelage and anti-system challenges. It finds that the conceptualization of parties under internal and external pressures in competitive party systems can be a useful framework to understand the constraints faced by parties in new democracies contemplating legal and constitutional reforms as a way to deepen democracy. The dual party framework focuses on the significance of the institutional (identity and party unity) and rational concerns of parties (electoral success) during democratization, at the same time that it integrates the role of the military in mediating the interplay between the internal and external challenges for parties. On the basis of the insights derived from the political party literature and democratization studies, the thesis identifies the formation of political identity as the major internal challenge for parties as they attempt to institutionalize themselves in the context of revitalized electoral competition. A politically autonomous military constitutes the principle external challenge for parties particularly in the presence of "anti-system" actors. The study then traces the formation and development of political identities by the three major Turkish parties that held power between 1983 and 1995. In particular, it analyzes how these pressures unfolded for party leaders as they confronted a controversial dilemma of reconciling democratization with the maintenance of stability due to the ethnic separatist threat, and to a lesser extent, religious fundamentalism. The study demonstrates that while the Turkish party leaders used democratization agendas as an image building' strategy in the formation of their parties' political identities, their capacity to formulate and implement clear, coherent and consistent democratization reform strategies was hampered by the problems they faced in meeting o</description><creator>Aslan, Canan.</creator><contributor>Oxhorn, Philip (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Political parties -- Turkey.</subject><subject>Democracy -- Turkey.</subject><title>Party-building and democratization : the case of Turkey (1983-1995)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375z04r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kj06x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34150</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>