<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T04:18:21Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):47450" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xh72m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>HIV antiretroviral therapy has evolved since its introduction in 1987 and has improved the lives of patients worldwide.  UNAIDS estimates that 35 million people are HIV infected as of 2014.  In lieu of an effective vaccine or cure regimen, antiretroviral therapy represents the most effective available treatment.  There are 27 approved agents which are classified by target.  Clinical trials designed to gain federal approval for these agents focus on antiviral efficacy and safety.  Comparisons of agents of different classes and their corresponding antiviral mechanisms may not always be able to identify unique virologic phenomena for each class.  With ART requiring a lifelong commitment from the patient, identifying class and drug-specific signatures to inform clinical decisions is important.Previously published data has shown that a greater number of patients taking the CCR5 inhibitor maraviroc exhibited viral loads between 50 and 400 RNA copies/ml when fully suppressed compared to NNRTIs.  In addition, clinical trials with MVC often reported higher frequencies of blips in viral load versus the use of other drug classes.  We hypothesized that the mechanism of action of maraviroc might include changes in viral load measurements despite robust antiviral efficacy.  The data presented in this thesis identify a circulating subset of virions that has been exposed to CCR5 entry inhibitors on the target cell surface and that have rebounded back into extracellular space.  This subpopulation cannot be distinguished from unexposed virions by viral load assays and, as such, may contribute to a perceived antiviral efficacy that is lower when compared to drugs of other classes.  Furthermore, this viral subpopulation seems to be antigenically distinct from the unexposed virion population with regard to susceptibility broadly neutralizing antibodies.  Additionally, these virions exhibited reduced entry efficiency, indicating the likelihood of a modified HIV envelope.  This phenomenon did not extend to another CCR5 inhibitor cenicriviroc.  The data presented in this thesis show that CVC occupies CCR5 differently than MVC and that virions are not rebounded into extracellular space following CVC-mediated inhibition of viral entry into cells.  Taken together, these data indicate that the effect that maraviroc has on cell-free virions can be reflected in viral load measurements.  This effect is not observed with cenicriviroc.  We believe that evaluations of future CCR5 inhibitors should determine whether they are able to repel virus back into extracellular fluids.  </description><description>Le traitement antirétroviral (ART) contre le VIH a évolué depuis son introduction en 1987 et a sauvé la vie de nombreux patients dans le monde. L'ONUSIDA estime que 35 millions de personnes vivaient avec la maladie en 2014. En l’absence d'un vaccin ou d’une thérapie, la prise d’antirétroviraux représente le seul traitement efficace. Il y a 27 agents agréés pour le traitement de l’infection avec le VIH, qui sont classés par cible thérapeutique. Les essais cliniques visant à obtenir l'approbation du gouvernement fédéral Canadien pour ces agents se concentrent sur l'efficacité antivirale et la sécurité. La comparaison des agents de différentes classes et de leur mécanisme antiviral ne permet pas l’identification de phénomènes virologiques propres à chaque classe. Avec un ART nécessitant un engagement à vie, l'identification des signatures spécifiques à une classe ou à un médicament est importante pour aider les décisions cliniques.Des données publiées précédemment ont montré qu'un plus grand nombre de patients prenant du maraviroc (MVC), un inhibiteur de CCR5, possèdent une charge virale entre 50 et 400 copies d’ARN / ml que les patients traités avec des inhibiteurs nucléotidiques de la transcriptase inverse (INTI). De plus, les essais cliniques avec le MVC rapportent des fréquences plus élevées d’augmentation spontanée de la charge virale (blips) que lors de l’utilisation d’INTIs. Nous avons formulé l'hypothèse que le mécanisme d'action du MVC affectait les mesures de la charge virale malgré une efficacité antivirale robuste.Les données présentées dans cette thèse montrent qu’une partie des virions qui ont été exposés au MVC peut rebondir de la surface de la cellule cible vers l'espace extracellulaire. Cette sous-population de virions ne peut pas être distinguée des virions non exposées par simple dosage de la charge virale, et peut ainsi contribuer à une efficacité antivirale qui semble inférieure par rapport à d'autres classes de médicaments. De plus, les virions qui ont rebondi dans l’espace extracellulaire ont une sensibilité différente aux anticorps neutralisants à large spectre que les virions natifs, ce qui indique des changements conformationnels dans ces particules virales. En effet, ces virions exposés au MVC ont également une efficacité réduite à infecter les cellules à cause d’une enveloppe modifiée. Ce phénomène n’est pas observé avec un autre inhibiteur de CCR5, le cénicriviroc (CVC). Les données présentées dans cette thèse montrent que le CVC occupe CCR5 différemment que le MVC et que les virions ne rebondissent pas dans l'espace extracellulaire après avoir été inhibés par le CVC.L’ensemble de ces données indique que l’utilisation de MVC a un effet sur la mesure de la charge virale, ce qui complique potentiellement les décisions cliniques. Cependant, cet effet n'est pas observé avec le CVC, ce qui en fait phénomène unique au MVC. Nous suggérons que l’évaluation de futurs inhibiteurs de CCR5 devrait déterminer si ce phénomène se produit et en tenir compte dans le processus de décision clinique.</description><creator>Kramer, Victor</creator><contributor>Mark Wainberg (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>The identification and characterization of a novel circulating HIV population following exposure to HIV entry inhibitor maraviroc</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343v92v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xh72m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pq82q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background: Patients with an acute myocardial infarction (MI) are at increased risk of recurrent MI or premature death. Beta-blockers (BB) are a mainstay of pharmacologic treatment following MI to prevent such complications. The impact of material deprivation on BB adherence is unclear in the context of a medication insurance plan. Objectives: In the province of Quebec among adults covered by the public medication insurance plan who had a ST elevation MI (STEMI), we determined the impact of material deprivation on adherence to BB at 2 years post-discharge from the hospital. Methods: Retrospective cohort study of patients admitted with a STEMI to 17 Quebec hospitals in 2003. Material deprivation level was based on an established index derived from Canadian census tract data (i.e., Quintile 1 to Quintile 5, most deprived). Adherence to BB at 2 years was calculated by the Mean Refill Adherence rate (MRA) with a cut-off of &gt; 80% considered adherent. Univariate and multivariate logistic regression and survival analysis were performed to study the association between material deprivation and adherence to BB. Results: A total of 553 patients were analyzed, with a mean 608-day (SD 114.9) and median 640-day follow-up. Mean age was 63.5 years (SD 12.7), 33.1% were women, &lt; 10% presented with heart failure, and mean creatinine was 105 umol/l (SD 50.1). Mean left ventricular ejection fraction (LVEF) was 48%, and 23.7% were prescribed bronchodilators for pulmonary disease, a possible contraindication to BB therapy. Point estimates signalled a possibility of higher adherence with higher deprivation levels when quartiles 4-5 were compared to quartiles 1-2-3 (primary analysis: OR 1.17, 95% CI 0.80, 1.59) although confidence intervals were wide. Patients older than 65 years old were more likely to be adherent (OR 1.77, 95% CI 1.21, 2.59). Conclusion: The more deprived did not appear to be less adherent to BB post MI; in fact, there was a signal that they might be more adherent. Patients older than 65 years of age were more adherent than younger patients.</description><description>Contexte: Les sujets ayant subi un infarctus du myocarde (IM) sont à risque de récidive d’IM et de décès précoce. Les béta-bloqueurs (BB) forment la base du traitement pharmacologique de l’IM. L’impact de la défavorisation matérielle sur l’adhérence aux BB n’est pas bien défini. Objectifs : Chez les sujets québécois couverts par un régime public d’assurance médicaments qui ont subi un IM avec sus-décalages des segments ST (STEMI), nous avons évalué l’impact de la défavorisation matérielle sur l’adhérence aux BB deux ans après le congé de l’hôpital. Méthodes: Étude de cohorte rétrospective de sujets admis avec un STEMI dans 17 hôpitaux québécois en 2003. Un niveau de défavorisation matérielle fut assigné à chaque sujet selon un indice établi basé sur le census canadien (i.e. Quintile 1 à Quintile 5, les plus défavorisés). L’adhérence aux BB à 2 ans fut calculée par le Mean Refill Adherence (MRA), avec un seuil de &gt; 80% considéré comme adhérent. Des analyses univariée et multivariée, ainsi qu’une analyse de survie ont été performées pour examiner l’association entre la défavorisation matérielle et l’adhérence aux BB. Résultats: Un total de 553 patients furent recrutés, avec des suivis moyen et médian de 608 (SD 114.9) et 640 jours. L’âge moyen était de 63.5 ans (SD 12.7), 33.1% étaient des femmes, &lt; 10% ont présenté avec de l’insuffisance cardiaque, et la créatinine moyenne était de 105 umol/l (SD 50.1). La fraction d’éjection du ventricule gauche moyenne était de 48% et 23.7% ont été prescrits des bronchodilatateurs pour de la maladie pulmonaire, une contre-indication possible à l’utilisation des BB. Les résultats suggèrent la possibilité d’une meilleure adhérence chez les plus défavorisés lorsque les Quintiles 4-5 furent comparés aux Quintiles 1-2-3 (analyse primaire: OR 1.17, 95% CI 0.80, 1.59) quoique les intervales de confiance soient larges. Les patients âgés de plus de 65 ans avaient tendance à être plus adhérents (OR 1.77, 95% CI 1.21, 2.59. Conclusion: Les plus défavorisés n’étaient pas moins adhérents aux BB après un IM, mais semblaient plutôt être plus adhérents. Les sujets de 65 ans et plus étaient plus adhérents comparativement aux plus jeunes sujets.</description><creator>Nguyen, Viviane Thuy</creator><contributor>Kaberi Dasgupta (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Thao Huynh (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Epidemiology and Biostatistics</subject><title>Is material deprivation a predictor of long-term adherence to beta-blocker therapy post-ST elevation myocardial infarction in Quebec?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pw69c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pq82q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343v934</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ce mémoire considère le développement de la doctrine théosophique moderne et spécifiquement ses effets sur le bouddhisme moderne dans le cadre de la formation de l’état-nation indien. Fondée à New York en 1875 et comptant encore des adeptes dans plus de 100 pays, la Société Théosophique s’est rapidement établie comme un mouvement occulte inspiré par la poésie romantique et la philologie comparative d’une époque colonialiste. La relocalisation, en 1878, de son siège international à Madras en Inde a été à l’origine de plusieurs développements aussi profonds qu’inattendus, qui reflètent diverses tendances vers la modernisation et le cosmopolitisme. L’impact du mouvement spirituel international qu’est la théosophie sur la formation du bouddhisme moderne a déjà été reconnu, comme son implication politique et sociale, par ses connexions avec les élites de l’Asie du Sud, dans les problèmes spécifiques de l’Inde sous gouvernance britannique. Aucune étude n’a cependant entrepris de lier délibérément ces deux éléments. Ce mémoire retrace l’imagerie, la mythologie et la doctrine bouddhistes théosophiques dans l’évolution de la culture populaire indienne. J’examine ce sujet inexploré principalement par une juxtaposition de l’importante théosophiste Annie Besant (1847-1933) et de Mohandas Gandhi (1869-1944).</description><description>This thesis considers the development of modern theosophical doctrine, and in particular, the effects it had on modern Buddhism, within the framework of the formation of the early Indian nation state. Founded in New York in 1875, and still existing in over 100 countries, the Theosophical Society soon established itself as an occult movement that was inspired by the romantic poetry and comparative philology of the colonial period. The relocation of its international headquarters to Madras, India, in 1878 had profound and unpredictable consequences that reflect diverse cosmopolitan and modernizing trends. While it has been acknowledged that this spiritually oriented, international movement had an impact on the shaping of modern Buddhism, and became involved with political and social concerns specific to British-ruled India through its elite South Asian connections, there has been no study that deliberately connects these two elements together. This thesis locates the usage of theosophical Buddhist imagery, mythology, and doctrine in the evolution of popular Indian national culture. I take up this topic primarily through a juxtaposition of the prominent theosophist Annie Besant (1847-1933), and Mohandas Gandhi (1869-1944).</description><creator>Duns, Pamela</creator><contributor>Davesh Soneji (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Religious Studies</subject><title>Nothing higher than the truth: modern theosophy, buddhism, and the making of cultural nationalism in india</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g7896.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343v934</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752k795</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Maple syrup and sugar belong to North America and are produced only in limited areas of this continent, namely Eastern Canada and adjacent States, New England and Middle-West states. The manufacture of maple syrup probably dates back to a period before the advent of the white man because Sy (22) in a review of the writings of early discoverers, notes many allusions to the preparation by the Indians of a kind of sugar and syrup from the sap of the maple tree. There appears to be some difference of opinion as to whether the French settlers taught the Indians the process or the Indians taught the white people, but the latter alternative seems to be the most probable. [...]</description><creator>Findlay, Gordon Hamilton.</creator><contributor>Snell, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1932</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Studies on maple sap and syrup.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010t04j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752k795</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04ds51g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>When one pauses to consider the whole vegetable kingdom; forest, shrubs, grasses, and plants or the higher types, as built up of cellulose crystals, one readily appreciates the importance of a clear conception of the cellulose unit and its properties. Particularly is this true of its behaviour towards water, for upon these latter relations have been builta large part of our modern civilized structure. In view of the above mentioned facts it seems in order to discuss briefly the structure and specific volume of cellulose and wood, together with some particular swelling properties. [...]</description><creator>Filby, Edgar Alan.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1932</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The specific volume of cellulose and wood and the density of adsorbed water vapour.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cd820.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04ds51g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xh73w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The expansion of agriculture into the more northerly latitudes brings growers and breeders face to face with the problem of winter hardiness. The economic importance of the subject has given an impetus to investigation along this line and much recent literature has been devoted to it. The problem is not a new one. Greek philosphers were aware of the difference in cold resistance between plants. They reasoned that plants, like animals, develop heat for protection. This idea remained prevalent for such a long time that practically all our knowledge on the subject is comparatively new. [...]</description><creator>Ferguson, William.</creator><contributor>Scarth, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1932</date><subject>Plant physiology.</subject><subject>Botany.</subject><title>Some studies on the physiology of cold resistance in plants.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w526j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xh73w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Botany</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816q41j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The chief interest of these studies is centred in the recovery process following muscular activity. The changes accompanying the recovery process are associated with an excessoxygen consumption. When this work was chosen by the writer as a research problem, the view was well-established that the excess oxygen consumed during recovery was inseparably united with the removal of lactic acid and resynthesis of glycogen. It was with the realization of the need of further knowledge of the resynthesis of glycogen that the problem was undertaken. [...]</description><creator>Grant, Elizabeth Rhoda.</creator><contributor>Lang, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1932</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Studies in glycogen metabolism.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h2499.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816q41j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wk06v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The victory of Japan over Russia in 1905 was a surprise to the world. The war was fought mostly on Chinese soil, and each of the combatants hoped to dominate Manchuria. China hadnothing to say in the whole matter. She was not consulted at the beginning nor at the end, yet the war was fought on China's account. In 1911 the tottering Manchu dynasty finally fell, and China became a Republic. The object of this thesis is to make a study of the years between 1904 and 1911, and to try to trace the influence of the Russo-Japanese war upon the Chinese revolutionary movement during this period. [...]</description><creator>Copland, Edward Bruce.</creator><contributor>Fryer, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1932</date><subject>Russo-Japanese War, 1904-1905.</subject><subject>History.</subject><title>Traces of the influence of the Russo-Japanese war upon the Chinese revolutionary movement, from 1904-11.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290d492.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wk06v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j38609806</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A complete study of the processes involved in migration would include not only a discussion of the immigrant flow, but also an analysis of the effect on the homeland from which these people were uprooted, and the repercussions in the new land to which they went in search of happiness and economic security. Such a project, while ambitious, is not impossible of accomplishment, and indeed has been attempted by C. H. Young in his study of "The Ukrainian Canadians", and T. C. Blegen in his book, "Norwegian Migration to America 1825-1860." [...]</description><creator>Ramsden, Mary Evelyn.</creator><date>1933</date><subject>Sociology.</subject><subject>Social surveys -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>British Canadians -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>Dependency among British immigrants in Montreal.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xz01z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j38609806</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289m949</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Stability of a power system may be defined as the capacity of the system to remain in equilibrium under steady load oonditions, and its ability to regain a state of equilibrium after a disturbance has taken place. The first part of this definition is referred to as "static stability", and the seoond part as "transient stability." The maintenanoe of stability on the modern power system is obviously of the utmost importance, since a line deficient in stability is inoperative. [...]</description><creator>Crawford, James Merrill.</creator><contributor>Christie, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1932</date><subject>Electrical Engineering.</subject><title>Stability of generation and transmission systems.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33s050b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289m949</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t5049</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The literature dealing with vocational guidance may readily be divided into two categories: (1) Theoretical discussion. (2) Experimental programmes of vocational guidance includinga follow-up of the individuals advised. There is an abundance of literature listed under the first division. In this discussion all such articles and books have been discarded, emphasis being placed entirely upon experimental results. [...]</description><creator>Webster, Edward C.</creator><date>1933</date><subject>Psychology.</subject><title>An experimental approach to vocational guidance.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d289j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t5049</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hq37vr54d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The nature of water adsorption on cellulose has been the subject of considerable controversy. It was hoped that further information regarding the system cellulose - water would be obtained by measuring the heats of wetting and the dielectric constants of cellulose containing varying amounts of adsorbed water. An experimental technic not previously applied to heat of wetting measurements was used. [...]</description><creator>Argue, George Herbert.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1935</date><subject>Cellulose.</subject><subject>Chemistry.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Physical and theoretical.</subject><subject>Adsorption.</subject><title>The nature of adsorption on cellulosic materials from heat of wetting and dielectric constant measurements.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d2909.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vr54d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x920g063f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In 1860 Pasteur discovered and studied the optically active forms of tartaric acids; he regarded optically active molecules as having an asymmetric structure, two (or more)configurations being possible. Van't Hoff imparted a more concrete form to this conception by the discovery that in most optically active compounds at least one carbon atom was linked to four dissimilar atoms or groups, and he termed the carbon atom thus linked an "asymmetric carbon atom". [...]</description><creator>Wilson, Charles V.</creator><contributor>Allen, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1933</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Pt.1. The stereochemistry of certain tertiary amines. Pt.2. Studies on lactols.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sd407.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920g063f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c534fr81k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The subject matter of this thesis is concerned with the question of homogeneous unimolecular gas reactions, a sharply restricted but important field of chemical kinetics.The beginning o£ chemical kinetics lies far back in the history of chemistry, but it is only in the past two or three decades that the subject has been recognized as a definite branch of the science, and has made sound explanations of chemical mechanisms that form a distinct contribution. [...]</description><creator>Calder, Douglas Seymour.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1935</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The thermal decomposition of alkyl nitrites.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nt77m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fr81k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z903274w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mount Johnson is the smallest but one of the best known of the Monteregian Hills; it has become, since it was first described in detail in 1963 by Dr. Frank D. Adams, a classical example of centripetal differentiation in a small body of igneous rock. It shares with the Shonkin Sag laccolith of Montana and the Sudbury lopolith of Ontario the distinction of being cited in many textbooks of geology and in many discussions on differentiation. [...]</description><creator>Wilson, Norman Leslie.</creator><date>1933</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>A petrological study of the rocks of Mount Johnson, Quebec.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qc677.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903274w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mm81x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The correlation of the pressure, voiume and temperature of a gas to give an equation, whioh will be valid under all oonditions, is one of the outstanding problems in the study of the kinetic theory of gases. The failure of the ideal gas law when applied to actual gases is well known. Van der Waals has succeeded partially in accounting for the reasons for this failure by taking into consideration the molecular volume and molecular attraction which exist in any one gas. The classical equation of state derived by Van den Waalsis not, howver, of suoh a general form as to be applicable under all conditions. Numerous attempts have been made to develop a general equation of state, but none can be described as entirely successful. In most cases empirical constants have been introduced into the equations which are without theoretical foundation. [...]</description><creator>Stewart, William Wesley.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1933</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The viscosity of gases and its relationship to the gas laws.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn9999563.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mm81x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50h007n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The realization that the state of all existent matter could be classified under three general heads was a notable advance in the study of science. The further realization that the state of matter was dependent upon the conditions of temperature and pressure in which it found itself was an equally notable step. With the lapse of time, man has drawn up laws and rules based upon comprehensive experimental data which enable him to predict with accuracy the behavior of a system composed of matter in any one of the three states. His generalizations have extended, even to systems of any two or all three of the states. [...]</description><creator>Tapp, James Stewart.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. &amp; Steacie, E. (Supervisors)</contributor><date>1933</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>An investigation of the density of a vapor in equilibrium with a liquid near the critical temperature.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75rb784.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50h007n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gg80b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although our knowledge of protein and carbohydrate metabolism has advanced with great strides in recent years, relatively little interest has been focussed on fat metabolism. A true understanding of the factors that determine the level of the various constituents in the blood is still lacking. Even the intermediary products of metabolism have not yet been isolated. The great obstacle to the advancement of knowledge in this case has been a lack of aocurate methods. A particular attempt has been made in this present work to investigate the reliability of the methods employed and considerable time has been spent in this direction. [...]</description><creator>Venning, Eleanor M.</creator><contributor>Browne, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1933</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Experimental study of blood fats in health and disease.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dj567.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gg80b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gg81m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The 1iterature of the Old Testament Canon is divided into three sections usually designated by the terms: "Law, Prophets, and Writings". The third section embracingthe five "Megilloth" or "Bolls." and known as the "Kethubim" provides the portions of Scripture read on certain Jewish Feast days. Of the five books included in the "Kethubim"three namely, Job, Proverbs, and Ecclesiastes, are generally recognized as belonging to that part ot the Sacred Canon now known by the collective name "Wisdom Literature". [...]</description><creator>Thomas, William.</creator><date>1933</date><subject>Oriental Studies.</subject><title>The philosophy of life of the book Koheleth, in the light of the Hebrew text, and with special reference to English versions.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53wz755.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gg81m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Oriental Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848t46f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Much has been said concerning the value of welded fabrication in structural steel design. In fact, so rapid has been the growth of this method of contruction, that the investigation of its possibilities has been a subject of much research in recent years. Usually when a new method is in its infancy, its limitation and its adaptability are deduced, first, by "trial and error". Tests are carried out to ascertain its properties under certain required conditions, and if the tests prove satisfactory the method is adopted. In due course, by means of mathematical deduction and laboratory research, general laws are formulated to govern, under all practical conditions, the use of the new method. [...]</description><creator>Evans, Delano Ernest.</creator><date>1933</date><subject>Civil Engineering.</subject><title>An investigation of the effects produced by electric arc welding on a steel compression member : with an analysis of the distribution of welding stresses in steel plates.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999958n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848t46f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r609q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A number of separate circuit problems in radio engineering are discussed, the problems being linked by the fact that they all involve non-linear impedance relations in vacuum tubes. There is also a general discussion given on non-linearity, and a critical bibliography. Among the topics discussed are: automatic volume control in radio receivers; some original work leading to a vacuum tube wattmeter; original analysis dealing with a heterodyne detector; a constant impedance circuit primarily intended to meet the problems of coupling a pentode tube to a loudspeaker; and some original work on an amplifier involving de-generation to meet the same problem. A number of measurements are shown to back up the discussion on each topic. [...]</description><creator>Fisher, Charles (Charles Boddy).</creator><date>1933</date><subject>Electrical Engineering.</subject><title>Some non-linear vacuum-tube topics.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wg535.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r609q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21tj34n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ever since the discovery of cyclopropane by Freund (1) numerous substituted derivatives have been prepared and their stability carefully studied. It was early formulatedby Parkin (2) and later by Kotz (3) that the substitutent groups have a marked influence on the stability of the cyclopropane ring. Recently Kohler and his students (4) have prepared a series of ketonic cyclopropanes in which all three carbon atoms are substituted. [...]</description><creator>Cressman, Homer William John.</creator><contributor>Allen, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1933</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The addition reactions of vinyl phenyl ketone, III. malonic ester.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h459q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21tj34n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5999n629f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Observations have shown that in certain years oats in Quebec are subject to serious epiphytotics of blight. Part of this has been found to be due to ha1o-blight, caused by Bacterium coronafaciens Elliott. It was in connection with recent serious outbreaks of this: disease at Macdonald College that the following investigations were undertaken. </description><creator>Hamilton, George Harvey.</creator><date>1933</date><subject>Plant Pathology.</subject><title>Studies of halo-blight of oats caused by bacterium coronafaciens elliott.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n2042010.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n629f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xh76q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although pyrrhotite is a mineral of common occurrence in nature its distribution has never been systematically investigated. This thesis represents the first attack on the problem. The polished surfaces of some 174 rock specimens were examined and the opaque minerals identified. Pyrrhotite was found to occur in basic igneous rocks and in metamorphic rocks. The results indicate that it occurs more commonly in rocks which contain nepheline. Pyrrhotite is most common in rocks of the Monteregian province. As pyrrhotite was found in only 14 of the 174 sections examined it would seem that this mineral does not occur as commonly in igneous and metamorphic rocks as it is usually considered to do. [...]</description><creator>Simard, Lionel Réné.</creator><contributor>Osborne, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1934</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>Pyrrhotite in rocks and mineral deposits. --.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mq49h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xh76q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3f4628317</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:49:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The tirst cytological work on Stooks was carried out by Allen (1924) who found the diploid chromosome number to be 14. In 1919 Frost reported the discovery of an eversporting race,Snowflake, which constantly produces a small percentage of mutant types in its progeny. Upon cytological examination by Frost and Mann (1924) these proved to be simple trisomics (2 n + 1) with an extra chromosome or chromosome fragment. In consequence of their nature these aneuploid mutants do not breed true but 1/4 to 3/4 of their progeny consist of normal Snowflake. [...]</description><creator>Armstrong, John M.</creator><contributor>Huskins, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1933</date><subject>Matthiola incana -- Cytology.</subject><subject>Wheat -- Cytology.</subject><subject>Botany.</subject><title>Cyto-genetic studies in Matthiola and Triticum.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365809g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f4628317</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Botany</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):47475</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>