<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:29:09Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):10200" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526g36c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In Chapter one theoretical indicator dilution curves are calculated using different mathematical models. In Chapter two experimental indicator dilution curves as obtained from working dog hearts were found compatible with a distributed diffusion limited model. The model parameters were obtained by performing least square error curve fits of the model to the experimental data. In Chapter three the above model was extended to include one way cellular uptake. Rubidium dilution curves were found to fit this latter model fairly closely.</description><creator>Ziegler, Wilfred H.</creator><contributor>Goresky, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>Distributed models of transcapillary exchange and their use in the study of the heart.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wq85s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526g36c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qb98mj609</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An in vitro system containing a rabb1t serum medium adapted subline of L5178Y cells and rabbit antiserum was used to study the effects of antibodies, in the absence of complement, on cells in culture. Heat-inactivated antiserum inhibits cell growth and colony formation in soft agar, and kills the cells. These actions occur slowly and metabolic events, in sequence; that is, RNA synthesis is inhibited after 4 hr, but the effects on the rates of protein and DNA syntheses become demonstrable only after 6 to 8, and 8 hr, respectively. Maximal inhibition can he obtained after 24 to 48 hr. These effects together with the apparent involvement of energy generating systems suggest that some indirect mechanism, triggered as a result of primary antigen-antibody reactions on the cells surface, is respons1ble. An indirect mode of action mediated by second messengers, such as cyclic AMP, is proposed.</description><creator>Yang, Tsu-Ju.</creator><contributor>Vas, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Microbiology and Immunology.</subject><title>Studies on modes of action of anticellular antibodies.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354j31z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mj609</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj139507x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The epithelial cells of the distal airway were studied under four different conditions in mice, rabbits and humans. Evidences observed strongly support the theory that osmiophilic bodies are phospholipid components of pulmonary surfactant and type II cells secrete surfactant. Clara cells are merocrine type secretory cells but are immature at the time of birth and not likely to secrete surfactant. Adrenalin is not tropic to either Clara cells or type II alveolar cells. The presence of cytomegalovirus-like particles within Pneumocystis organisms prompted a hypothesis of symbiosis between these two agents. With the scanning electron microscope some fine structures of the lung were demonstrated in stereoscopic and real pictures. These included pores of John, Clara cells and the opening of the bronchial gland. A very minute lesion of squamous metaplasia was found at the opening of the bronchial gland and the squamous metaplasia appeared to be an intracellular process.</description><creator>Wang, Nai-San.</creator><contributor>Thurlbeck, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Pathology.</subject><title>A transmission and scanning electron microscopic study of broncho-pulmonary epithelial structures.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128nh76m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139507x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306t237j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Spleen cells from non-irradiated adult Fl hybrid mice in which graft-versus-host (GVH) reaction had been induced with parental strain lymphoid cells exerted non-specific cytotoxic effects upon target cells whether syngeneic, allogeneic or xenogeneic to the parental strain. The cytotoxic effects were shown in vitro by use of target cells labelled with 5lCr and in vivo by studying the capacity of tumor cells growing in syngeneic hosts. The non-specific cytotoxic effect depended on the intensity of the GVH reactions and was contingent upon direct contact between target cells and metabolically active spleen cells. Lysis could not be induced with the cell-tree supernatant of cultures of these spleen cells. By contrast, spleen cells from. lethally irradiated Fl hybrids similarly treated with parental strain lymphoid cells induced specific lysis of target cells of the second parental strain. The available data suggest that this specific cytotoxic effect was induced by cells of parental origin sensitized to transplantation antigens of the recipients, whereas the non-specific cytotoxic effect induced by spleen cells from non-irradiated Fl hybrids was due to host cells triggered into a cytotoxic state during GVH reaction.</description><creator>Singh, Jagat N.</creator><contributor>Sabbadini, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Sehon, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Microbiology and Immunology.</subject><title>Cell mediated cytotoxicity in graft-versus-host reactions.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j204k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t237j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wm117s04f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cytochrome f was purified from spinach grana membranes with a final yield of 42%. Using disc gel electrophoresis ± non-ionic detergent, it was found that cytochrome f existed as soluble aggregates at pH 8 and could be disaggregated into a single electrophoretic species by 0.1% non-ionic detergent. Disc gel electrophoresis with non-ionic detergent was also instrumental in designing and monitoring the purification procedure and served as a final chromatographic step. Proof of homogeneity of the cytochrome f was established. The cytochrome appeared to contain one c-heme-containing polypeptide chain and one non-heme chain, each of about 31,000, which was consistent with the equivalent weight of 31,600 obtained from amino acid analysis. Cytochrome f was not autoxidizable, did not combine with CO, and contained no non-heme iron. Absorbance spectra at 22º and at -199º are presented. The technology of disc gel electrophoresis ± non-ionic detergent was further tested with purified protein preparations of membranous origin (cytochrome oxidase, cytochrome b-cI complex and dogfish lens a crystallin). All three preparations were found to be aggregated and could be disaggregated with nonionic detergent and chromatographed. The methodology shows promise as an analytical and preparative tool for membranous proteins.</description><creator>Singh, Jasbir.</creator><contributor>Wasserman, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>The use of disc electrophoresis with non-ionic detergents in the purification of cytochrome f from spinach grana membranes. Application of the method to other membranous proteins.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930c138j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117s04f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053k31k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The sulfates of 11-deoxycorticosterone, corticosterone, ll-dehydrocorticosterone, cortisol and cortisone, as well as the respective steroid alcohols were characterized in umbilical cord plasma, maternal plasma and amniotic fluid, by double isotope derivative assays and crystallization. Comparisons of concentrations in maternal and umbilical cord plasma indicated that these conjugates are mainly of fetal origin. The sulfates of ll-deoxycorticosterone (3.4 ± 1.1 microgram%) and corticosterone (2.6 ± 1.1) were predominant in umbilical cord plasma whereas the corresponding steroid alcohols were present in trace amounts. The sulfates of cortisol (3.4 microgram%), cortisone (3.0) and corticosterone (4.3) were the major steroid sulfates measured in amniotic fluid. Tetrahydrocortisone glucuronide and tetrahydro-1l-dehydrocorticosterone glucuronide were present in much greater concentrations in amniotic fluid (12.2 and 2.l microgram%) and umbilical cord plasma (4.1 and 4.8) than maternal plasma (1.6 and 0.1). These results indicate the significance of fetal C-21 steroid sulfate formation and suggest that at term cortisol and cortisone, as well as corticosterone and ll-dehydrocorticosterone are respectively metabolized to tetrahydrocortisone glucuronide and tetrahydro-ll-dehydrocorticosterone glucuronide, by the fetus.</description><creator>Schweitzer, Morris.</creator><contributor>Browne, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Studies on C-21 corticosteroid conjugates during the perinatal period.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k35697382.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053k31k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053k32v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The site of the vasopressor action and the distribution of angiotensin II have been studied in the mouse with physiological techniques and a new morphological method. The site of conversion of angiotensin I to angiotensin II in the isolated lung has been studied with these methods. A comparison of the ratios of l4C angiotensin II and 3H inulin at the time of the pressor effect and the inactivation shows an extracellular location of the peptide. Angiotensin-enzyme complexes of either horseradish peroxidase or cytochrome c made with glutaraldehyde or difluorodinitrodiphenyl sulfone as coupling agents show patterns of behaviour which are similar to angiotensin I and II. The angiotensin-enzyme complexes are localized to the endothelium and not the vascular smooth muscle at the time of the pressor action of angiotensin II. Complexes made with angiotensin I show conversion to angiotensin II; they are in contact only with the pulmonary endothelium at the time of this conversion. The mechanisms whereby the endothelium may transmit a stimulus to the vascular smooth muscle are discussed.</description><description>Le site de l'action vasopressive et la distribution de l'angiotensine ont été étudié chez la souris à l'aide de techniques physiologiques et d'une nouvelle technique morphologique. Le site de la conversion de l'angiotensine I à l'angiotensine II dans le poumon a été étudié avec les mêmes techniques. Les proportions de l'angiotensine-14C et de l'inulin 3H au moment de l'action vasopressive montrent une localisation extracellulaire. Les complexes de l'angiotensine et de la peroxydase du raifort ou de la cytochrome c couplées avec la glutaraldehyde ou diflurodinitrodiphenyl sulfone montrent les mêmes modèles de réponse biologiques que l'angiotensine I et II. Au pic de l'action hypertensive, chez la souris, le produit de la réaction histochimique apparait à la surface ou à l'interieur des vésicules de l'endothelium vasculaire et n'atteint pas le voisinage des cellules musculaires lisses. Les complexes de l'angiotensine I montrent une conversion à l'angiotensine II et sont situés également a la surface de l'endothe1ium. Les mécanismes par lesquels l'endothelium peut transmettre un stimulus au muscle lisse sont discutés par l'auteur.</description><creator>Richardson, John B.</creator><contributor>Beaulnes, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Pharmacology and Therapeutics.</subject><title>The cellular localization of angiotensin.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257h96b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053k32v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977z012</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>1. Methionine exchange diffusion is insensitive to Na+, K+, their gradients and prior depletion of cellular ATP. 2. In the absence of extracellular Na+, methionine uptake can he divided into two components; an initial rapid exchange between methionine and several endogenous amino acids and a slower net uptake inhibitable by alpha-aminoisobutyric acid and L-alanine. 3. After depletion of endogenous ATP and amino acids, carrier mediated methionine uptake from Na+-free medium was barely detectable. This and the evidence in 2 above indicates that the exchange carrier cannot catalyze net methionine uptake. 4. Cellular ATP and extracellular Na+, rather than transmembrane Na+, K+ or Na+ plus K+ gradients, are required for optimal amino acid accumulation. Cellular ATP and extracellular Na+ both decrease the Km values for amine acid influx. 5. Cation gradient-induced amino acid movement in ATP-depleted cells was insufficient to account for accumulation under more physiological conditions. 6. The Na+ gradient hypothesis is not generally applicable to amino acid transport in these cells.</description><creator>Potashner, Steven J.</creator><contributor>Johnstone, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Monovalent cations, transport and exchange diffusion of neutral amino acids in Ehrlich ascites cells.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rp41g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977z012</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g158bm38j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Antibodies, against PGH, PLR and HGH were detected by radioimmunological methods in patients on HGH therapy. The presence of antibodies detectable by 125I PGH was further confirmed by Immunofluorescent method. These antibodies were localized in IgG fraction of serum immunoglobulins. Such antibodies did not neutralize the effect of HGH in the tibia test. Aggregation of HGH and revealed determinants were considered to be responsible for production of such antibodies. Certain commercially available preparations of pitressin were noted to have several contaminating proteins. Antibodies induced by such proteins (eg, PGH, PP) were noted in patients on pitressin therapy and such antibodies were considered to play a possible role in the genesis of hemolytic anemia in a patient. Immunological cross-reactions of pituitary hormones were further studied utilizing antisera of rabbit, guinea-pig and human origin. Heterogenity in such antisera was noted. Antibodies detectable by 125I PLR were noted to partially crossreact with prolactins of other species.</description><creator>Murthy, Gollapudi G.</creator><contributor>McGarry, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Antibodies to pituitary hormones induced by polypeptide hormone therapy.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s332r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bm38j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x2289</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Afferent transmission in the dorsal column - lemniscal sensory pathway of the decerebrate cat was recorded as evoked potentials during acute changes in brain tissue PC02, induced by the inhalation of 2 to 20% CO2. CO2 has a mainly depressant action on overall transmission from a forelimb nerve to the midbrain medial lemniscus, and on the excitability of the presynaptic afferent terminals and postsynaptic relay neurones in the cuneate. From an input/output analysis, correlating trans-synaptic responses at the medial lemniscus and antidromic responses at the nerve, it was concluded that (i) the efficiency of synaptic transmission at individual active synapses was maintained, (ii) the block of afferent transmission was mainly presynaptic. Depression of afferent fibre excitability was greater in the presynaptic terminals than in the dorsal column. Afferent volleys recorded at the dorsal root and dorsal column showed that CO2 blocked the transmission of supra-maximal responses at or after the root entry zone. Depressant effects of CO2 on afferent transmission most probably involve block of conduction at low safety factor regions of branching in axonal pathways, while the transmission of impulses arriving at the synapses is maintained.</description><creator>Morris, Mary E.</creator><contributor>Krnjevic, K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>Carbon dioxide and sensory transmission.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77st060.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x2289</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tz15j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This investigation has been undertaken to study changes in high energy phosphate metabolism of the canine intestine following hemorrhagic shock. The information on energy metabolism in the intestine is scarce, necessitating extensive studies into normal metabolic properties of this tissue. Respiration of intestinal homogenates was not limited by the level of ADP, but it was limited by the level of cytochromes. These results indicated that oxidative phosphorylation in intestinal mucosa is loosely coupled, a fact that was supported further by the lack of effect of DNP on endogenous respiration. In studies with DNP and NaF, the increased turnover of ATP-phosphate in the presence of glucose was found to be due to energy derived from the glycolytic pathway. Hemorrhagic shock had no significant effect on either oxygen uptake or energy production in the intestinal mucosa in vitro. These results led to a proposal that hemorrhagic shock produces a transport barrier between the intestinal epithelial cells and the circulation.</description><creator>Mavrias, Denis A.</creator><contributor>McArdle, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Energy production in the canine ileal mucosa following hemorrhagic shock.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w95053510.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tz15j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nm24w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Patterns of extracellularly-recorded, stationary, background impulse sequences, from individual cervical nerve sympathetic preganglionic units (SPU), have been systematized by time series analysis (interval histogram, IH; autocorrelogram, ACG). Experiments were conducted on anaesthetized (Nembutal, 30 mg/kg) or unanaesthetized (decerebrate) cats - thoracotomized, paralyzed (flaxedil, 8 mg/kg) and artificially ventilated. On the basis of the occurrence and properties of discharge in neuraxially intact and spinal preparations, and the influences of antidromic stimulation, qualitative models are proposed, of SPU spike initiation by a random threshold crossing process (set up by activity in many, independent, converging presynaptic inputs), with firing contiguity limited by postimpulse recovery of excitability. Exponential IH "tails" and ACG "overshoot" are, thus, explained. Bimodal and multimodal IH, revealing cardiac pulse modulation of SPU discharge, are explained in terms of baroreceptor inhibition. Respiratory grouping of SPU spikes is explained as a consequence of respiratory centre activity - phase-locked to the artificial ventilation cycle. The discharge of bursts is triggered by arrivals of excitation from a remote central pacemaker.</description><creator>Mannard, Allan.</creator><contributor>Polosa, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>Patterns of background firing of single sympathetic preganglionic units in the cat spinal cord.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kr16k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nm24w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445ch392</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>At laparotomy, 3H-pregnenolone and 14c-dehydroisoandrosterone were injected into the umbilical vein of the baboon in the 165th day of gestation. Seventeen metabolites were isolated from the placenta and fetal tissues. [...]Biochemistry.</description><creator>Leung, Kiu.</creator><contributor>Solomon, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Metabolism of steroid hormones in the baboon fetus and placenta (papio cynocephalus).</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73q016v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445ch392</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806312v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The analogs 8-azaguanine and 5-azacytidine do not inhibit the initial steroid-mediated induction of tyrosine transaminase; however, the continued induced synthesis of the enzyme, elicited by repeated doses of hydrocortisone, is inhibited in the presence of the analogs after approximately 6 hours. It is inferred from these and other data that the induction cycle involves the activation by hydrocortisone, and subsequent turnover, of a pool of preexisting inactive messenger RNA for tyrosine transaminase. This study provides the first functional test for the existence of such pools. 8-Azaguanine, 5-azacytidine and cycloheximide can maintain the tyrosine transaminase activity at or near the induced level for a prolonged period following induction of the enzyme by hydrocortisone. Immunochemical experiments confirm that this maintenance phenomenon results from an inhibition of tyrosine transaminase degradation. This in turn may be due to the inhibition of the synthesis of a degradative enzyme.</description><creator>Levitan, Irwin B.</creator><contributor>Webb, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Control of protein biosynthesis in eukaryocytes: the induction and inactivation of hepatic tyrosine transaminase.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698b767.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806312v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:73666781k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The role of adenine and adenosine in elevating cellular ATP concentration is investigated. Incubation of erythrocytes with inosine, glucose and adenine; or adenosine in low concentrations, doubles the fresh cell concentration of ATP. The mechanism by which adenine elevates adenine nucleotide concentration is known, however the mechanism by which adenosine acts has not been elucidated. The findings of this study suggest that adenosine is directly incorporated by an erythrocyte adenosine kinase. Evidence for the existence of this enzyme in human erythrocytes along with some of its enzymatic properties are presented. Under optimal conditions the maximum concentration of ATP synthesized was twice that present in fresh cells. It is suggested that ATP itself, controls the rate of adenine nucleotide synthesis as well as the final intracellular ATP concentration. High concentrations of adenosine inhibit glucose and adenine elevation of ATP synthesis. The most likely site of adenosine action is on PRPP synthetase.</description><creator>Lerner, Marvin H.</creator><contributor>Denstedt, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Nucleotide metabolism in erythrocytes.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059cb468.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666781k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c534fr94n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis outlines a method for purifying dopa decarboxylase from 300 g of hog kidney by heat treatment, ammonium sulfate fractionation and chromatography on DEAE-Sephadex, hydroxylapatite and Sephadex G15O. This method yields a product of high purity as shown by gel electrophoresis in three different systems as well as different gel concentrations. The purified material has a specific activity of 21.1 micromoles of SHT produced per mg protein per h. The purified enzyme has 7 times the activity towards L-DOPA as it does towards 5HTP. This ratio does not change during purification. 5HTP and DOPA act as mutual competitive inhibitors with KI's similar to their KM's suggesting that they bind at the same site on the enzyme. Activity towards ortho- and meta-tyrosine and erythro-DOPS was also detected in the purified enzyme. Decarboxylase activity was not detected towards para-tyrosine or threo-DOPS. The molecular weight of the purified enzyme found by gel filtration was 8.5-9.0 x 10^4. Dodecylsulfate polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis gave two bands. The sum of the molecular weights 4 of these bands was 8.8-9.4 x 10^4. As the method used breaks disulfide bonds it is probable that dopa decarboxylase consists of two peptides of unequal length. By direct measurements on the purified enzyme, it was round that 1 PLP is present per mole of enzyme. Additional PLP does not appreciably stimulate activity towards most substrates suggesting that the purified material is holoenzyme.</description><creator>Lancaster, Gerald A.</creator><contributor>Sourkes, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Purification of hog kidney dopa decarboxylase.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pw84g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fr94n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418r338</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A method for measuring the rate of production of C-labelled 14 adenine nucleotides from C-ATP was developed and used to study the relationship of adenyl cyclase to other membrane-bound ATP utilizing enzymes and cyclic 3', 5'-nucleotide phosphodiesterase (PDE) in preparations of rat cerebral cortex and guinea-pig pancreas. It was shown that NaF and Mn++ increased cyclic AMP accumulation in these preparations, in part, by an inhibition of PDE activity. Adrenaline and ouabain stimulated cyclic AMP accumulation by a method not related to inhibition of other membrane-bound ATP utilizing enzymes or to inhibition of PDE activity. Adrenaline stimulation of cyclic AMP accumulation in the synaptic membrane preparation required the presence of Ca++ in the preparation media. Inhibition of a soluble PDE preparation from rat cerebral cortex was maximal in the presence of ATP and ADP and much lower in the presence of methylene analogs of ATP.</description><creator>Katz, Sidney.</creator><contributor>Nickerson, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Pharmacology and Therapeutics.</subject><title>Cyclic AMP metabolism in brain.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q731v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418r338</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547v595</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Deoxythymidine kinase has been purified about 300- fold from calf thymus. Among various nucleosides tested, only dTR and to a much lesser extent, dUR and its 5-halogenated derivatives could serve as phosphate acceptors. All kinds of ribo- and deoxyribonucleoside triphosphates, except for dTTP, were found to be active as phosphate donors, ATP being the most effective. Calf thymus dTR kinase is inhibited specifically by deoxynucleotide derivatives of thymine; the potency of inhibition being in the order of dTTP &gt; dTDP &gt; dTMP. The molecular weight of dTR kinase was found to be approximately 55,000, as determined by gel filtration. Evidence has been obtained which suggests the existence of heat-stable form of the enzyme. Substrates, inhibitors, and products were found to protect the enzyme against heat denaturation. Gel filtration studies suggested that the enzyme undergoes a change in elution volume on Sepharose 6B in the presence of dTTP or ATP, possibly indicating an aggregational or a conformational change in the enzyme. The purified enzyme could be activated by 2-mercaptoethanol or dithiothreitol. The Km values for dTR and ATP were 57 micromolar and 50 micromolar, respectively. The mode of inhibition by dTTP was found to he competitive with respect to dTR. The inhibition was also competitive with respect to ATP at high concentrations of ATP, but noncompetitive with respect to ATP at lower concentrations of ATP. The Ki value for dTTP was 6.7 micromolar, as determined with respect to dTR. Initial velocity studies suggested that dTR kinase reaction proceeds via a sequential mechanism, possibly a "random Bi Bi".</description><creator>Her, Moo O.</creator><contributor>Momparler, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Studies on a mammalian deoxythymidine kinase: purification, properties and kinetics.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h4728.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547v595</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hm50tv598</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Investigations on biogenesis and metabolism of 17-hydroxy and 17-deoxysteroids of the pragn-4-ene C-21 yl sulfate series showed that (a) such conjugates are little if at aIl hydrolyzed by placental sulfatase and are poor substrates with respect to placental 11beta-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase compared to the corresponding steroid alcohols; (b) following injection to adult subjects, cortisol sulfate is in part metabolized to ll-oxo and 11beta-hydroxy etiocholanolone glucuronides, but not to C-2l steroid glucuronides of the pregn-5-ene series; its rate of secretion represents only a fraction of that of cortisol; (c) when H-cortisol and C-cortisol sulfate or H-corticosterone and C-corticosterone sulfate are injected to human newborns, of the total amount of tritium excreted into the urine only small proportions are extractable - from 1.3 - 13% in the glucuronide and from 3 - 18% the sulfate fraction. [...]</description><creator>Hall, Conrad S.</creator><contributor>Browne, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Studies on the metabolism of corticosteroids C-21 yl sulfates with particular reference to cortisol sulfate.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z821c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tv598</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859j66z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two series of recollection micropuncture experiments were performed on the dog kidney to assess renal handling of magnesium. Proximal tubule fluid was obtained before and after isotonic saline infusion and magnesium chloride. Tubule fluid-to-plasma (TF/P) inulin ratio was depressed after infusions of saline and magnesium chloride, whilst the tubule fluid-to-plasma ultrafiltrate TF/UF magnesium ratio approximated to unity. Fractional excretion of sodium and magnesium showed a parallel increase after saline, but after magnesium chloride infusion fractional excretion of magnesium far exceeded that of sodium. Further recollection micropuncture studies were performed during extracellular volume expansion and magnesium sulphate and chloride infusions with or without furosemide. During volume expansion proximal magnesium absorption was isotonic whereas that in the distal was active. Following magnesium sulphate infusion, mean proximal TF/UF magnesium ratio was 1.25 and mean distal TF/UF magnesium ratio was 1.79. After magnesium chloride infusion mean proximal and distal TF/UF magnesium ratio was 1.28 and 1.89 respective1y. There was a marked dissociation in sodium and magnesium transport in the distal nephron. After magnesium sulphate infusion a small net addition of magnesium in the collecting duct was observed, indicating secretion at this site.</description><creator>Evanson, Raphael L.</creator><contributor>Dirks, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>Micropuncture study of magnesium transport in the proximal and distal tubule of the dog kidney with evidence for magnesium secretion.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn1072153.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859j66z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x920g085g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of the experiments reported was to study the reaction of non-necrotic myocardium to a right ventricular infarct produced by right coronary ligation in the rat. Samples were taken from the right ventricle to investigate the reaction in the marginal zone of the infarct, and from the left ventricle to observe the changes in the cardiac muscle remote from the necrosis. Sham operations were performed in order to investigate the effect of the operative trauma. The evolution of findings in the left ventricular myocardium was correlated in time with the known post-operative increase of myocardial resistance, in an effort to find the possible myocardial factors responsible for this increase. Cardiac muscle cells in the marginal zone and some of the subepicardial muscle cells displayed a variety of histochemical and electron microscopic changes suggestive of an impairment of the cellular function and an increased importance of alternative metabolic pathways, in order to preserve the structural integrity of the cells and to meet their energy requirements. The findings in this area were apparently related to the progressive anoxia which resulted from the fibrotic transformation of granulation tissue surrounding the infarct. Biochemical, histochemical and electron microscopic studies of the left ventricular myocardium remote from necrosis suggested that the preparatory procedure resulted in a temporary stimulation of the proteosynthetic activity in the cardiac muscle cells and that this may form the basis for their increased resistance and adaptability. The findings support the hypothesis of a myocardial factor being important in the resistance against various noxious stimuli.</description><creator>Dusek, Jaroslav.</creator><contributor>Rona, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Kahn, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Pathology.</subject><title>Myocardial reaction to experimental ischemic injury in the rat.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580q770.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920g085g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21tj480</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Incorporation of intravenously administered palmitic acid 9,10^3H into beta-lipoprotein steadily increases for the first 20 hours of hepatic regeneration. Thirteen hours after partial hepatectomy the concentration of circulating beta-lipoprotein is at a normal level, but the specific activities of liver and beta-lipoprotein-triglyceride were significantly diminished. During perfusion the 13 hour regenerating liver secretes quantities of beta-lipoprotein-triglyceride which exceed those released by a zero hour liver although there is no difference in liver weight. Equal quantities of protein were released by both livers. Triglyceride specific activity in the liver and perfusate B-lipoprotein was diminished, but the protein was not affected. Prelabelling of the accumulated triglyceride with palmitate-1-14C in vivo showed that the per cent release by the 13 hour regenerating liver was equal to that of the control tissue, while that of a CCl4 treated liver was 1/20 of that level. Liver and perfusate triglyceride specific activities were similar for normal and regenerating livers, indicating one continuous triglyceride pool. The 13 hour regenerating liver was secreting quantities of lipid which were on a par with that of the larger normal liver. This was accomplished by increasing the lipid to protein ratio in the beta-lipoprotein molecule. The results are discussed in relation to the possible controlling mechanisms affecting lipid storage and secretion in the premitotic stage of regeneration.</description><creator>Delahunty, Thomas J.</creator><contributor>Rubinstein, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Lipoprotein synthesis and secretion by rat liver following partial hepatectomy.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w6634677w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21tj480</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f1881q149</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Young rats were injected with 3H-fucose and sacrificed after various times. In electron microscopic radioautographs of duodenal villus columnar cells and hepatocyes, at 2 minutes after injection the label was localized mostly over the Golgi apparatus. By 20 minutes, label appeared at all cell surfaces and in lysosomes. It is interpreted that the fucose label was incorporated by the Golgi apparatus into glycoproteins which migrated to lysosomes and to all cell surfaces to be added to the cell coat. A method developed to stain radioautographs of duodenal cells with phosphotungstic acid revealed glycoprotein in all labelled structures, including cytoplasmic vesicles which may transport the labelled glycoprotein to the cell surfaces. In light microscopic radioautographs of many other cell types, label appeared first over the Golgi region and later over cell secretions or over cell surfaces. Thus cell coat synthesis in all cells may be completed in the Golgi apparatus.</description><creator>Bennett, Gary C.</creator><contributor>Leblond, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Anatomy.</subject><title>Incorporation of 3H-fucose label into glycoprotein in the golgi apparatus of rat cells, and its passage to the cell coat and to lysosomes.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k113w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881q149</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vp03s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A theoretical and experimental study on acoustic, optical and acoustooptic diffraction in anisotropic crystals is presented. It is shown that even though optical activity in quartz introduces only very small changes in the optical wave vector loci, its effects on acoustooptic diffraction geometry are nevertheless easily measurable. A calculation procedure for the diffraction angles incorporating optical activity is described and then experimentally verified. Topez, an optically biaxial crystal, is used to demonstrate the effects on shear-wave acoustooptic diffraction geometry of acoustic propagation along other thon symmetry axes and of interaction in nonsymmetry planes. The diffraction field of a plane aperture or a plane transducer in a highly anisotropic crystal is calculated by means of an angular spectrum of plane waves representation for which the phase velocity surface need only be defined numerically. This theory is experimentally verified by observing optical diffraction from a slit-type aperture in a biaxial crystal and by acoustooptic probe measurements of quasi-longitudinal and quasi-shear ultrasonic beam profiles under conditions of very high elastic anisotropy. Further verification is achieved by using published experimental measurements of ultrasonic surface wave beam profiles on lithium niobate. It is demonstrated that excellent agreement between theory and experiment is possible. Finally, the formalism and associated computational techniques are extended in order to examine various relevant problems in the diffraction and focusing of elastic surface waves.</description><creator>Kharusi, Muhammed S.</creator><contributor>Farnell, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>Diffraction in anisotropic crystals.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892f043.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vp03s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qs92q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:25:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In a strain of Long-Evans rats, central core myofilament dissociation occurred in over 50% of atrial muscle cells (cardiocytes) studied. The major features of this dissociation were: loss of I-bands and Z-lines, loss of sarco-tubules, reduction in size of associated mitochondria, and dissociated aggregates of thick filaments. The thick filaments appeared joined by linear interfilamentary projections which measured about 164 A in length, 40 A in width, and occurred in regular periodic intervals of about 200 A along the filaments. Most often, the dissociated thick filaments were found to be fragmented further, and, together with other factors, was considered part of an irreversible pattern. Plasmocid, an 8-aminoquinoline, known to be myotoxic in selected doses specifically to I-bands and tubules in atrial cardiocytes was administered to cats in or der to produce experimentally the features present in the rats. After I-band loss induced by plasmocid, the linear projections, termed "cross-bars", were found between thick filaments. The cross-bars were considered to contribute to the transversal stability of A-bands. The patterns of reversible structural alterations appeared as: loss of I-band filaments, reduction of amount of Golgi complex, tubular and mitochondrial swelling, and loss of matrical density in mitochondria. Irreversible fine structural alterations appeared as fragmentation or disorganization of sarcoplasmic tubules, amorphous condensation of A-bands, cytoplasmic disintegration with respect to organelles, and chromatin clumping. The irreversible patterns were correlated with severe alterations in ECG P-wave.</description><creator>Berger, Jayson M.</creator><contributor>Rona, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1970</date><subject>Pathology.</subject><title>Fine structure of irreversible alterations in atrial cardiocytes.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440w83b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qs92q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):10225</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>