<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:03:40Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):3550" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rf55z9996</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Après l'imprésentable focuses on the manner in which contemporary artists approach the question of the sublime and the singularity of their reinterpretations vis-à-vis the conceptual history of the sublime. While many recent studies have attempted to theorize a new iteration of the sublime, known as the "contemporary sublime," their interpretations rely too heavily on modern and postmodern interpretations and address art merely as a manifestation of these theories. This thesis challenges such perspectives by examining how individual artworks can be considered as interpretations of the sublime in their own right, specifically addressing three case studies: Shirin Neshat's film series Turbulent (1998), Rapture (1999) and Fervor (2000); Olafur Eliasson's installation The Weather Project (2003–2004); and Ryoji Ikeda's multimedia installations systematics (2012) and datamatics (2012). In doing so, I highlight how these artworks represent anew the relations between humans and nonhumans and defend the hypothesis that the most recent interpretations of the sublime emphasize the power of cultural and technological mediations to render the interconnections between the human and the nonhuman presentable. These new interpretations correspond with the shift from modern conceptions of the sublime, which largely hinged on humanity's superiority over nature, and postmodern reinterpretations that have conceived of the sublime as the effect of an inadequacy between a discourse and the excess or otherness it produces. My research is divided into three parts. The first part examines the conceptual history of the sublime, especially as this concerns modern, postmodern, and contemporary theory. Through this examination, I show how influential modern and postmodern discourses on the sublime have shaped the way we understand the relationship between humans and nonhumans, imposing on these categories a dualistic opposition and reducing their relationship to a discursive or ideological construction. In concluding this first part, I analyze the limitations of reapplying modern and postmodern interpretations before considering a new method for conceptualizing the "contemporary sublime." The second part compares and contrasts two feminist reinterpretations of subjective experiences of the sublime: on the one hand, the postmodern discourse of the feminine, female and feminist sublime; and on the other hand, the symbolic and political forms of resistance enacted by the female protagonists of Neshat's films. I scrutinize these two approaches—the view of the sublime as unrepresentable and its understanding as a presentable experience—to emphasize how the latter provides the most fruitful way to redefine the sublime. The third part focuses on two themes representative of the modern sublime: nature and technology. It probes how modernity produced two emblems of its hierarchical model of the relationship between humanity and nature: the romantic landscape and the steam locomotive. This serves to situate the works of Eliasson and Ikeda not only within the history of the development and re-appropriations of the categories of nature and technology but also in relation to two current cosmological models, the Anthropocene and the Technosphere. Here, I argue that the artworks' contribution to the reconceptualization of the sublime lies in their capacity to mediate between the human and the nonhuman. In the conclusion, I propose a summary of the thesis's major claims and establish how artistic representation of the sublime in the works of Neshat, Eliasson, and Ikeda—understood both as a subjective experience and an attribute of a form or an object—formulates a specifically contemporary interpretation.</description><description>Après l'imprésentable porte sur la manière dont des artistes contemporains réactualisent la question du sublime et sur la singularité de leurs réinterprétations au regard de l'histoire conceptuelle du sublime. Plusieurs études récentes ont tenté de définir un sublime « contemporain » en associant des problématiques actuelles, comme le réchauffement planétaire ou le développement du numérique, à des définitions modernes et postmodernes du sublime que les œuvres d'art sont simplement appelées à illustrer. La thèse innove en partant de la prémisse selon laquelle les œuvres constituent des interprétations du sublime à part entière et en établissant que la spécificité de leur contribution repose sur la façon dont elles rendent justice aux nouveaux modes de relation entre humains et non-humains — entités naturelles, technologiques et fictives qui composent le monde avec lequel nous interagissons — à l'heure des changements climatiques et de l'hyperconnexion technologique. En nous appuyant sur trois études de cas, soit la série de films Turbulent (1998), Rapture (1999) et Fervor (2000) de l'artiste Shirin Neshat, l'installation The weather project (2003-2004) d'Olafur Eliasson et les installations multimédias systematics (2012) et datamatics (2012) de Ryoji Ikeda, nous démontrons l'hypothèse suivante : alors que le sublime moderne fut conçu comme le signe de la supériorité de l'humain sur la nature et le sublime postmoderne, comme l'effet d'une inadéquation entre un discours et l'excès ou l'altérité qu'il produit, le sublime correspond aujourd'hui au pouvoir des médiations culturelles et technologiques d'actualiser l'interconnexion entre l'humain et le non-humain. L'argumentaire est structuré en trois parties. La première partie examine l'histoire conceptuelle du sublime en se penchant spécifiquement sur les périodes moderne, postmoderne et contemporaine. Elle montre de quelles manières les discours modernes et postmodernes sur le sublime ayant le plus influencé la compréhension que nous en avons aujourd'hui ont conçu la relation entre l'humain et le non-humain tantôt en les opposant de façon dualiste, tantôt en réduisant cette relation à une construction discursive ou idéologique. De plus, dans cette partie, nous analysons les limites des tentatives les plus récentes de réactualisation de ces interprétations moderne et postmoderne afin de dégager une nouvelle orientation pour la conceptualisation d'un sublime « contemporain ». La seconde partie compare et contraste deux réinterprétations féministes de l'expérience subjective du sublime : le discours postmoderne du sublime féminin, « femelle » et féministe, et les formes de résistance symboliques et politiques menées par les protagonistes féminins des films de Neshat. Nous opposons le pouvoir que ces approches attribuent respectivement au caractère imprésentable et présentable de l'expérience du sublime en privilégiant la seconde pour réinterpréter le sublime. La troisième partie aborde deux thèmes représentatifs du sublime moderne, la nature et la technologie, et examine la manière dont la modernité a produit les formes et les objets emblématiques d'un rapport hiérarchique entre humanité et nature, soit le paysage romantique et le train à vapeur. En situant les œuvres d'Eliasson et Ikeda dans l'histoire du développement et des réappropriations de ces thèmes, mais aussi par rapport à deux modèles cosmologiques actuels, l'Anthropocène et la technosphère, nous mettons en évidence que leur contribution est liée à la médiatisation des rapports entre l'humain et le non-humain. En conclusion, la thèse présente une synthèse des résultats et établit comment les représentations artistiques du sublime entendu à la fois comme expérience subjective et attribut d'une forme ou d'un objet en formulent une interprétation proprement contemporaine.</description><creator>Ouellet, Maryse</creator><contributor>Ross, Christine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Art History and Communications Studies</subject><title>Après l'imprésentable: contemporanéité du sublime dans les oeuvres de Shirin Neshat, Olafur Eliasson et Ryoji Ikeda</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kj521.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55z9996</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dx662</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Femtosecond (fs) laser micro-machining of metals is useful in imparting surface roughness and wettability characteristics to a material. In fact, extensive research has been done to highlight the relationship between the variety of surface topographies and the resulting wettability characteristics. Recent studies have further explained that wettability can also be linked to surface chemistry, but the nature of this relationship is unclear. Since the surface chemistry of a material is dependent on the machining and storage environment, studies into its impact on surface wettability must be carried out in an environment that effectively isolates the materials from contamination. Hence, this thesis details the design, prototyping and construction of a chamber for fs laser micro-machining in controlled environments.Home-made and commercially available chamber designs were analysed according to a number of criteria. Using materials that were readily available, a prototype chamber was designed, assembled and tested to determine the limitations of such an apparatus. The cost-benefit analysis of the designed options and the data collected from prototype testing were used to inform the final design choice. A standard operating procedure (SOP) was also prepared to guide future operators in the use of the prototype and finalized chamber design.During the prototype testing, it became apparent that nanoparticle accumulation in the chamber could occur under certain conditions. Thus, a short study on a novel nanoparticle collection/removal method was conducted. Experiments showed that an electrically charged metal sheet can attract nanoparticles from a surface during laser micro-machining. While there is no indication of a net surface charge on nanoparticles, the results demonstrate that voltage and choice of material affect the volume of nanoparticles collected.</description><description>Le micro-usinage au laser femtoseconde (fs) est utile pour conférer au matériau des caractéristiques de rugosité de surface et de mouillabilité. En fait, des recherches approfondies ont  été effectuées pour mettre en évidence la relation entre la variété des topographies de surface et les caractéristiques de mouillabilité résultantes. Des études récentes ont en outre expliqué que la mouillabilité peut également être liée à la chimie de surface, mais la nature de cette relation n'est pas claire. Étant donné que la chimie de surface d'un matériau dépend de l'environnement d'usinage et de stockage, les études sur l'impact de celle-ci sur la mouillabilité de la surface doivent être réalisées dans un environnement qui isole efficacement les matériaux de la contamination. Par conséquent, cette thèse détaille la conception, le prototypage et la construction d'une chambre dans le but de réaliser un micro-usinage laser dans des environnements contrôlés.Une combinaison de conceptions de chambre fabriquées à la maison et fabriquées par des professionnels a  été analysée selon un certain nombre de critères. En utilisant des matériaux facilement disponibles, un prototype de chambre a  été conçu, assemblé et testé pour déterminer les limites d'un tel appareil. L'analyse coûts-avantages des options conçues et les données collectées lors des essais de prototypes ont  été utilisées pour éclairer le choix final de la conception. Une procédure standard d'exploitation (SOP) a également  été préparée pour guider les futurs opérateurs dans l'utilisation du prototype et de la conception de la chambre finalisée.Au cours de l'essai du prototype, il est devenu  évident que l'accumulation de nanoparticules dans la chambre pouvait se produire dans certaines conditions. Ainsi, une courte  étude sur une nouvelle méthode de collecte / élimination des nanoparticules a  été menée. Des expériences ont rélévé qu'une tôle métallique chargée  électriquement peut attirer des nanoparticules d'une surface lors du micro-usinage au laser. Bien qu'il n'y ait pas d'indication d'une charge surfacique nette sur les nanoparticules, les résultats démontrent que la tension et le choix du matériau affectent la quantité de nanoparticules collectées.</description><creator>Odusanya, Adeola</creator><contributor>Pierre-Luc Girard-Lauriault (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Anne-Marie Kietzig (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Chemical Engineering</subject><title>Development of a controlled environment apparatus for laser micro-machining experiments</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mm19f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dx662</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8049g731s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Neural network models have seen tremendous success in predictive tasks in machine learning and artificial intelligence, with some attributing their success to implicit use of Bayesian inference. Stan is a state-of-the-art software for Bayesian statistical computing used mainly in the statistical community, however, it is not optimized for use with neural network models. In this thesis, we replicated much of Stan's No U-Turn sampler in PyTorch and explored its use for sampling from Bayesian neural network models. We were able to explore different samplers, model structures and their sampling and predictive performances on a benchmark classification task. We found that Bayesian inference gives more robust predictive performance compared to their frequentist counterparts in general, but care is needed with the choice of prior and the MCMC sampler. </description><description>Neural network models have seen tremendous success in predictive tasks in machine learning and artificial intelligence, with some attributing their success to implicit use of Bayesian inference. Stan is a state-of-the-art software for Bayesian statistical computing used mainly in the statistical community, however, it is not optimized for use with neural network models. In this thesis, we replicated much of Stan's No U-Turn sampler in PyTorch and explored its use for sampling from Bayesian neural network models. We were able to explore different samplers, model structures and their sampling and predictive performances on a benchmark classification task. We found that Bayesian inference gives more robust predictive performance compared to their frequentist counterparts in general, but care is needed with the choice of prior and the MCMC sampler. </description><creator>Lau, Yiu Sing</creator><contributor>David Stephens (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Mathematics and Statistics</subject><title>Exploring dynamic hamiltonian Monte Carlo for bayesian neural networks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mm206.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g731s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9g54xk90p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse examine l'histoire des Indiens démunis en Grande-Bretagne de 1834 à 1914. Elle se concentre spécifiquement sur les marins et les domestiques qui ont travaillé au bord des navires destinés à la Grande-Bretagne dans l'espoir d'y retrouver un salaire décent et un retour à leur terre natale. Dès leur arrivée, plusieurs de ces travailleurs ont été abandonnés par leurs employeurs britanniques et laissés sans nourriture, abri ou ressources. Cette thèse considère les expériences de ces migrants indiens délaissés en analysant leurs interactions avec les Britanniques en métropole. Elle s'intéresse surtout à l'intervention, ou la non-intervention, des institutions sociales et politiques. Elle expose principalement les différences entre le traitement des Indiens démunis par les administrateurs du « Strangers' Home for Asiatics, Africans, and South Sea Islanders » et les officiels travaillant au sein du « India Office ». Alors que le « India Office » a continuellement évité d'assumer la responsabilité pour les démunis, le « Strangers' Home » est devenu un refuge, c'est-à-dire un endroit où la charité était offerte sous forme de nourriture, d'hébergement et de rapatriement. En examinant les relations anglo-indiennes, ainsi que les questions politiques, légales, morales et de responsabilité sociale, la thèse explore le contexte et les méthodes empruntées par les Indiens pour se conformer aux principes de la citoyenneté (« subjecthood ») britannique, malgré la nature contestée et changeante de ceux-ci à cette époque. À la fois intégrés et à l'écart de la Grande Bretagne, les Indiens démunis ont occupé une zone ambiguë de (non)appartenance dans le monde britannique. </description><description>This dissertation examines the history of destitute Indians in Britain from 1834 to 1914. It focuses particularly on sailors and servants who worked on ships bound for Britain in hopes of good wages and promises of return. On arrival, many of these individuals were abandoned by their British employers, and were left without food, shelter, and resources. This dissertation investigates the experiences of these abandoned Indian migrants through a study of their interactions with Britons in the metropole. It looks specifically at the intervention, or lack thereof, of social and political institutions. Chiefly, it studies the contrast between the treatment of destitute Indians by administrators at the Strangers' Home for Asiatics, Africans, and South Sea Islanders, and officials within the India Office. Whereas the India Office persistently evaded any responsibility for the destitute, the Strangers' Home became a refuge where charity was offered in the form of food, lodging, and repatriation. In examining Anglo-Indian interactions and questions of social, political, legal, and moral responsibility, the dissertation simultaneously sheds light on how and where Indians fit within the notion of British subjecthood, a concept that remained undefined and contested throughout this period. At once belonging to and being separate from Britain, destitute Indians occupied an ambiguous zone of (un)belonging in the British world.</description><creator>Saini, Raminder</creator><contributor>J Elizabeth Elbourne (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>History and Classical Studies</subject><title>Imperial responsibilities: Britain's destitute Indians and questions of (un)belonging, 1834-1914</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50gz46z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xk90p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History and Classical Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f362x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'étude des interactions entre protéines et coordinats est essentielle au développement et à la découverte de molécule biologiquement active. Cependant, la nature complexe de l'environnement cellulaire naturel rend difficile l'analyse des processus biochimiques fondamentaux. Notre compréhension limitée des interactions protéine/coordinat dans leur milieu naturel a jusqu'ici empêché la découverte de nouveaux composés ciblés ce qui ralenti les progrès de l'industrie pharmaceutique. Toutefois les développements récents dans les champs des recherches en synthèse organique, en chimie biologique et en protéomique permettent d'identifier les cibles cellulaires de petite molécule grâce au développement d'une technique d'étiquetage par photo affinité (PhotoAffinity Labelling ou PAL), il s'agit de concevoir et de synthétiser une sonde chimique capable de modifier par covalence la cible recherchée après exposition a une lumière ultra violette. Bien que PAL se soit révélé efficace, la méthode rencontre ses propres limitations dues à des problèmes provenant des difficultés liées au développement de sondes chimiques convenables. Les méthodes de synthèses actuelles dans la préparation de diazines photoactives seront soulignées, ainsi que leurs utilités à identifier des cibles déjà décrites dans des publications récentes.Ici, nous allons décrire nos travaux dans l'application de PAL a une catégorie de petites molécules capables de réguler la différentiation de cellules souches musculaires utilisées pour le traitement thérapeutique de la dystrophie musculaire de Duchenne.  La synthèse à grande échelle de cette classe de petites molécules biologiquement actives sera abordé, ainsi que la conception et la synthèse d'une sonde PAL afin d'identifier leurs cibles cellulaires et d'illuminer leur mécanisme d'action.   Pour finir, nos travaux sur la synthèse atome-economique des 1,4-benzothiazines en utilisant notre méthodologie développée pour l'installation sélective de liaisons aryl carbone-soufre sera soulignée. </description><description>The investigation of protein-ligand interactions is essential in the development and discovery of biologically active small molecules.  However, due to the complex nature of the native cellular environment, the elucidation of these fundamental biochemical processes remains challenging. Our lack of understanding of protein-ligand interactions in their native biological setting has hindered the discovery of new drug targets, and has influenced the progression of the pharmaceutical industry. Owing to the advancements made in the fields of organic synthesis, chemical biology, and proteomics, the ability to identify cellular targets of small molecules has come to fruition through the development of photoaffinity labelling (PAL), which involves the design and synthesis of a chemical probe capable of covalently modifying the target of interest through exposure to UV-light. Although PAL has proven to be effective, this technique harbors its own set of limitations which originate from the challenges associated with the development of a suitable chemical probe. In summarizing the requirements involved in a PAL experiment, current synthetic methods for the preparation of photoactive diazirines will be outlined, as well as their use for target identification studies in the recent literature. Herein, we describe our efforts to apply PAL to a class of small molecules capable of regulating muscle stem cell differentiation to be used as therapeutic treatment for Duchenne's Muscular Dystrophy. The large-scale synthesis of this class of biologically active small molecules will be discussed, along with the design and synthesis of a PAL probe in order to identify their cellular target(s), and shed light on their mechanism of action.Lastly, our work toward and atom-economical synthesis of 1,4-benzothiazines using our developed methodology for the selective installation of aryl carbon-sulfur bonds will be outlined. </description><creator>Halloran, Matthew</creator><contributor>Jean-Philip Lumb (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Chemistry</subject><title>Small molecule inhibitors of Eukaryotic Translation Initiation Factor 2A</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kq38d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f362x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547t696</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Au Canada, la conception sismique des structures en acier se base sur le principe de la conception basée sur la capacité, qui bénéficie de la ductilité inélastique des systèmes de résistance aux charges sismiques (SRCS). En particulier pour les contreventements en treillis concentriques, les catégories de conception de ductilité modérée (MD) et ductilité limitée (LD) exigent que les éléments structuraux et les connexions sur le trajet de la charge latérale soient conçus pour la capacité probable des diagonales en traction et en compression. Cependant, il existe également la catégorie Construction Conventionnelle (CC) décrite à la clause 27.11 de la norme CSA S16-14 qui dit que l'ingénieur est autorisé à déroger aux principes de conception basés sur la capacité et à concevoir un SRCS dont le comportement devrait être principalement élastique. Ces systèmes de type CC sont conçus avec de faibles valeurs R (Ro = 1,3 et Rd = 1,5) et ne dépendent donc pas de la déformation et du flambement des diagonales pour dissiper l'énergie sismique. Au lieu de cela, la dissipation d'énergie peut se produit par des déformations localisées des connexions et du frottement dans ces jointures. La norme CSA S16-14 impose à l'ingénieur d'augmenter les forces sismiques par un facteur 1,5 s'il ne peut pas démontrer que les connexions sur le trajet de la charge latérale ont un mode de rupture ductile. Ceci s'avère difficile pour les ingénieurs car aucune directive ni recommandation n'est donnée pour déterminer la ductilité de ces connexions. En conséquence, la quantification du niveau de ductilité de ces composantes devient un facteur important dans la conception de ces systèmes. Bien que les diagonales de type CC soient largement utilisés dans tout le pays, il existe très peu de recherche sur la ductilité de ces systèmes, en particulier dans le cas des diagonales en forme de I avec des connections boulonnés. L'objectif de cette recherche était donc d'observer le comportement et la ductilité des diagonales en forme de I et de leurs connexions boulonnées sous une charge sismique cyclique inversée. Six spécimens, incluant deux types de connexions boulonnés et deux tailles de section en forme de I, ont été testés. Ces connexions ont été conçues conformément à la norme CSA S16-14. La pénalité de 1,5 de l'article 27.11 n'a pas été incluse. Le protocole de chargement a été développé à partir de données statistiques provenant d'une étude numérique non linéaire de cinq bâtiments. Les résultats des essais ont montré que les spécimens type CC étaient capables d'atteindre des taux de dérive entre étages de 1% à 2%.</description><description>In Canada, the seismic design of steel structures involves the principle of capacity based design, which takes advantage of the inelastic ductility of the Seismic Force Resisting System (SFRS). Specific to concentrically braced frames, the moderate ductility (MD) and limited ductility (LD) categories both require that the members and connections in the lateral load carrying path be designed for the probable capacity of the braces in tension and compression. However, there also exists the Conventional Construction (CC) category as outlined in Clause 27.11 of the CSA S16-14 Standard, for which the engineer is allowed to waive capacity based design principles and design a SFRS which is expected to behave principally elastically when subjected to design-level earthquakes. These Type CC systems are designed using low R-values (Ro = 1.3 &amp; Rd = 1.5), and hence do not depend on the yielding and buckling of a fuse element (brace) to dissipate earthquake energy. Instead, the energy dissipation is assumed to occur due to localized yielding of connections and through friction within these joints. The CSA S16-14 Standard requires the engineer to increase the seismic forces by a factor of 1.5, if it cannot be demonstrated that the connections in the lateral load carrying path have an expected failure mode that is ductile. This has proven to be challenging to engineers because no guidelines or recommendations are provided to determine the ductility of connections. As a result, quantifying the level of ductility of these components becomes an important factor in designing Type CC systems under seismic loading. While Type CC braced frames are used extensively throughout the country, there is very little research available to give insight on the ductility of these systems, particularly in the case of W-shaped braces with bolted end connections. As such, the objective of this research was to measure the response of full-scale W-shape braces and their bolted connections under reversed cyclic seismic loading. Six brace specimens were tested, including two common bolted connection types and two W-shape section sizes. These connections were designed following the provisions in CSA S16-14 without any capacity design rules. The 1.5 penalty from Clause 27.11 was not included. The loading protocol was developed using statistical data from a nonlinear numerical study of five buildings designed with Type CC braces. Test measurements indicated that that Type CC brace specimens were able to achieve storey drift ratios of 1%-2%.</description><creator>Rudman, Alina</creator><contributor>Colin Andrew Rogers (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Civil Engineering &amp; Applied Mechanics</subject><title>Testing of conventional construction W-shape brace members and their bolted end connections undergoing reversed cyclic loading</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35tb67s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547t696</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602326w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Protein tyrosine phosphatase -PEST (PTP-PEST, PTPN12) is a cytosolic ubiquitous protein, which in addition to its PTP domains, contains five proline-rich motifs allowing its interaction with various protein complexes. PTP-PEST plays a multidimensional regulatory role in cellular motility, morphology and adhesion via its association with different substrates to control actin organization during focal adhesion turnover and formation of membrane protrusions. As recent reports showed ambivalent roles of PTP-PEST in cancers, including pancreatic cancer, and with the increasing number of PTP-PEST binding proteins, we hypothesize that distinct PTP-PEST protein complexes are at the origin of its cellular functions. Hence, we aimed to study the PTP-PEST interactome using multiple proteomics approaches and characterize its function in pancreatic cancer progression. First, using a modified yeast two-hybrid assay, we identified SKAP-Hom as a novel PTP-PEST substrate and interacting partner via proline-rich motif 1 (P1):SH3 domain module. We also showed that SKAP-Hom phosphorylation regulation at Y260 by PTP-PEST and Fyn kinase in mouse embryonic fibroblasts (MEFs) is important in proper cell migration. Second, we performed functional assays using MEFs expressing PTP-PEST catalytic and non-catalytic motif mutants. Our data suggest that PTP-PEST proline-rich motifs have differential effects on major cell tumorigenic properties such as proliferation, adhesion, migration and invasion. Next, we utilized BioID/MS strategy to unravel 12 novel PTP-PEST binding partners that differentially bind its proline-rich motifs. Subsequently, novel as well as known binding proteins were integrated in an updated PTP-PEST interactome network. Last, we studied the role of PTP-PEST in pancreatic cancer progression using CRISPR/Cas9-mediated downregulation in pancreatic cancer cell lines. In vitro assays showed that PTP-PEST depletion reduces cell proliferation, migration, adhesion and invasion in human and mouse pancreatic cancer cell lines. On the other hand, mouse pancreatic cancer models show that PTP-PEST inhibits in vivo subcutaneous and orthotopic tumor growth. PTP-PEST-deficient tumors had a growth advantage compared to WT counterparts and exhibited less collagen deposition accompanied by lower immune cell infiltration. In summary, our results suggest that PTP-PEST, via its proline-rich motifs, regulates major cell functions in multiple cell types. Additionally, while we showed that this PTP is important in pancreatic cancer cell regulation in vivo and in vitro, its role in human cancers requires further investigation. This thesis demonstrates that PTP-PEST protein-protein interactions and its enzymatic activity may functionally be of equal importance, thus providing multiple levels of regulation when the opportunity of targeting this PTP in cancer comes.</description><description>La protéine tyrosine phosphatase-PEST (PTP-PEST, PTPN12) est un enzyme qui contient un site catalytique ainsi que cinq domaines riches en proline. Elle est associée à l'adhésion, la prolifération et à la migration cellulaire. Elle joue un rôle multidimensionnel dans la motilité cellulaire en s'associant avec plusieurs complexes protéiques pour réguler la polymérisation de l'actine au niveau de points d'adhésion et de protrusions membranaires. PTP-PEST suscite de plus en plus d'intérêt grâce à la multitude de ses interactions protéines-protéines qui sont importantes dans la signalisation cellulaire. De plus, une étude récente a démontré la participation de PTP-PEST dans la régulation de la migration des cellules cancéreuses du pancréas. Nous postulons, qu'à travers un réseau d'interaction de protéines, PTP-PEST contrôle les caractéristiques tumorales des cellules. Notre objectif est premièrement, d'identifier de nouveaux substrats et partenaires protéiques de PTP-PEST et deuxièmement d'étudier le mécanisme par lequel PTP-PEST contrôle la progression du cancer du pancréas. En utilisant une méthode modifiée de double-hybride dans la levure, nous avons identifié et caractérisé SKAP-Hom comme nouvelle protéine de liaison de PTP-PEST. Par la suite, on a démontré que cette nouvelle interaction est importante pour la migration des fibroblastes. À partir d'une étude de fonctions biologiques des domaines riches en proline de PTP-PEST, nous avons conclu que ces domaines ont des rôles divers dans la migration, prolifération, adhésion et invasion cellulaire. Afin de détecter des nouvelles protéines de liaison des domaines riches en proline, nous avons établi une stratégie de BioID avec la spectrométrie de masse qui a abouti à la découverte de 12 nouvelles protéines de liaison de PTP-PEST. Nous avons produit une mise-à-jour du réseau d'interactions des protéines de liaison à PTP-PEST. En utilisant une stratégie de CRISPR/Cas9, l'expression de PTP-PEST a été diminuée dans des lignées cellulaires du cancer pancréatique. La diminution de PTP-PEST dans ces cellules a engendré une réduction de prolifération, d'adhésion, d'invasion ainsi que de migration. L'injection sous-cutanée ainsi qu'orthotopique des cellules murines du cancer pancréatique dans le pancréas des souris C57BL/6 a montré que les cellules sous-exprimant PTP-PEST forment des tumeurs d'une dimension plus importante. Comme le microenvironnement de la tumeur est un élément majeur du cancer du pancréas, une étude histologique a été mise en place pour évaluer les différents éléments du microenvironnement des tumeurs pancréatiques murines. Nous avons découvert que la quantité de collagène et de cellules immunitaires associés aux tumeurs sous-exprimant PTP-PEST était moins importante en comparaison aux tumeurs de souche sauvage. En conclusion, nous avons démontré des rôles importants des divers motifs de PTP-PEST dans plusieurs évènements cellulaires ainsi que l'implication de cette phosphatase dans la progression du cancer pancréatique. Ce projet améliorera la compréhension des liaisons protéiques de PTP-PEST et de sa fonction dans le cancer du pancréas afin de mieux cibler les traitements existants et d'initier de nouvelles pistes thérapeutiques.</description><creator>Ayoub, Emily</creator><contributor>Michel Tremblay (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Biochemistry</subject><title>Lessons from protein tyrosine phosphatase-pest interactome: towards a better understanding of pancreatic cancer progression</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wj29z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602326w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zw75x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Une large proportion des cas d'infertilité dans les couples peut être attribuée à un facteur mâle, souvent causé par le mode de vie ou l'exposition à des substances toxiques. Parmi ces substances, la cyclophosphamide (CPA), agent alkylant antinéoplastique et immunosuppresseur, est reconnue pour ses effets toxiques sur les gamètes mâles. De nombreux troubles de la fertilité sont en effet rapportés chez les hommes ayant été traités à la CPA. En outre, l'exposition de rats mâles à la CPA altère la qualité de leurs spermatozoïdes, entraînant des effets néfastes sur leur progéniture dès le début du développement embryonnaire. Le but de ces travaux de thèse était de mieux comprendre comment réagissent les cellules germinales mâles face à un traitement chronique à la CPA en faisant l'analyse de leur transcriptome. Notre premier objectif était d'évaluer l'effet de la CPA sur l'expression des microARNs dans les spermatocytes pachytènes et les spermatides rondes. Nous avons ainsi démontré pour la première fois qu'une exposition à une substance thérapeutique peut altérer l'expression des microARNs, des changements potentiellement associés à la réponse physiologique des cellules germinales aux substances toxiques. Dans un deuxième temps, nous avons évalué l'effet de la CPA sur l'expression des ARN messagers dans les spermatocytes pachytènes et spermatides rondes. Nous avons non seulement démontré que la CPA modifiait l'expression de transcrits impliqués dans les complexes de zinc, mais surtout que l'expression de transporteurs de zinc de la famille ZIP et le transport de zinc lui-même étaient accrus dans les spermatocytes pachytènes. Ces résultats établissent le rôle fondamental du zinc dans la réponse physiologique des cellules germinales à la CPA. Enfin, dans un troisième objectif, nous avons évalué le potentiel du zinc dans la protection des cellules germinales contre les dommages causés par la CPA. Nous avons ainsi pu observer que, dans les cellules germinales mâles, une supplémentation en zinc produit une diminution des niveaux de stress oxydant et des dommages à l'ADN associés au traitement à la CPA. Considérés dans leur ensemble, ces résultats permettent une meilleure compréhension de la réponse physiologique des cellules germinales face aux substances toxiques, et mettent en lumière le potentiel du zinc dans la protection des cellules contre les effets nocifs de la CPA.</description><description>Male factor infertility accounts for a large proportion of infertility cases and for the most part may in fact be related to lifestyle and/or exposure to toxic substances.  Cyclophosphamide (CPA) is an alkylating agent commonly used in chemo- and immunosuppressive therapies and is a known germ cell toxicant. Men often become infertile after being treated with this drug. In rats, paternal CPA treatment leads to decreased sperm quality as well as defective early embryo development and negative progeny outcomes. The goal of the studies presented in this thesis was to evaluate the effect of chronic CPA treatment on the male germ cell transcriptome in order to gain a better understanding of how these cells respond to such an insult. In the first objective, we evaluated the effect of CPA treatment on the expression of microRNAs in isolated pachytene spermatocytes and round spermatids. We showed for the first time that a therapeutic drug such as cyclophosphamide alters the expression of miRNAs in male germ cells and that these may be involved in the germ cell response to toxic exposures.  In the second objective we evaluated the effect of CPA treatment on genome wide gene expression in male germ cells. In addition to many transcripts involved in zinc binding being altered in both cell types following CPA treatment, we found that the expression of members of ZIP family of zinc transporters and zinc transport was increased in pachytene spermatocytes. This led us to believe that zinc may play an important role in the male germ cell response to CPA. In the third objective we examined whether zinc could protect male germ cells from CPA toxicity. We found that zinc supplementation decreased CPA induced oxidative stress and DNA damage in male germ cells. Collectively, the studies presented in this thesis contribute to our basic understanding of male germ cell responses to toxic substances and suggest a potential role for zinc in protecting male germ cells against detrimental effects of CPA treatment. </description><creator>Downey, Anne Marie</creator><contributor>Bernard Robaire (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics</subject><title>The male germ cell response to CPA treatment: A potential role for zinc</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870z274.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zw75x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322g63x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Lower vertebrates have an active neurogenic stem cell niche located in a peripheral domain of the retina called the ciliary margin zone (CMZ). Müller glial cells and the retinal pigment epithelium (RPE) also behave like latent progenitors. These three cell types can produce neurons throughout life.  The production of de novo neurons allows retinal regeneration and growth. Unlike the lower vertebrates, the mammalian retina is unable to restore following injury. However, it also contains some of these latent progenitor sources, such as the Müller glia and the RPE. To which extend these sources of cells produce or could be activated to make new neurons in vivo, and whether an active CMZ is also present is unclear. In our laboratory, we are interested in studying these stem cell/latent progenitor source. More precisely, we first focus on the CMZ.  In lower vertebrates, the CMZ cooperates with retinal domain progenitors to build the mature retina. In mammals, it is believed that the CMZ lacks neurogenic potential and that the retina develops from one pool of multipotent retinal progenitor cells (RPCs). Here we identify a population of Msx1-expressing progenitors in the mouse CMZ that is both molecularly and functionally distinct from RPCs. Using genetic lineage tracing, we report that Msx1 progenitors have unique developmental properties compared to RPCs. Msx1 lineages contain both neural retina and non-neural ciliary epithelial progenies, and overall generate fewer photoreceptors than classical RPC lineages. Furthermore, we show that the endocytic adaptor protein Numb regulates the balance between neural and non-neural fates in Msx1 progenitors. These results uncover a population of CMZ progenitors that is distinct from classical RPCs and contributes to mammalian retinogenesis. Because retinal degeneration is permanent in mammals, we also investigated whether Numb, via its inhibitory control of Notch signalling, could regulate the Müller glia response to injury and promote neurogenesis in the adult mammalian retina. Using inducible Müller glia-specific gene inactivation, we show that Numb expression in Müller glia does not promote cell cycle entry. Instead, we found that Numb functions in Müller glia to maintain photoreceptor cell survival and retinal polarity. Loss of Numb in Müller glia breaks the outer limiting membrane (OLM), which is the apical adherens junction network that preserves retinal structure integrity. The polarity complex protein Crb1 is necessary to maintain the OLM, and mutations in Crb1 are associated with retinal epithelium polarity defect leading to vision loss. We find that Numb binds Crb1 and controls its levels at the OLM. Consequently, these findings could bring the molecular basis for the pathogenesis of human retinal degenerative diseases. Together, these studies uncovered novel roles for Numb in mammalian retina. KEYWORDS: Retina, ciliary margin, lineage, fate decision, mouse genetics, conditional knockout, Numb, neurogenesis, Müller glia, outer limiting membrane. </description><description>Les vertébrés inférieurs possèdent une population de cellules souches actives située dans un domaine périphérique de la rétine appelée zone marginale ciliaire (ZMC). Ils ont également des cellules progénitrices latentes, telles les cellules gliales de Müller ou l'épithélium pigmentaire rétinien, lesquels peuvent produire des neurones tout au long de la vie de l'animal. La production de nouveaux neurones permet la régénération et la croissance de la rétine. Contrairement aux vertébrés inférieurs, la rétine des mammifères ne peut se réparer en cas de dommage. Toutefois, cette dernière possède certaines de ces sources de progéniteurs latents, tels les cellules de Müller et l'épithélium pigmentaire rétinien. Jusqu'à quel point ces cellules pourraient produire de nouveaux neurones in vivo reste à déterminer, tout comme l'est la présence d'une ZMC active. Dans notre laboratoire, nous nous intéressons à ces sources de cellules souches/progéniteurs latents. Plus précisément, nous nous intéressons à la ZMC. Chez les vertébrés inférieurs, la ZMC coopèrent avec des progéniteurs de la rétine pour construire la rétine adulte. Chez les mammifères, la croyance est que la ZMC ne possède aucun potentiel neurogénique et que la rétine ne se développe qu'à partir d'une seule source de cellules, soit les progéniteurs de la rétine. Nos travaux ont permis d'identifier une nouvelle population de progéniteurs située dans la ZMC de la souris qui exprime le marqueur Msx1, et qui est à la fois moléculairement et fonctionnellement distincte des progéniteurs de la rétine. En utilisant le traçage génétique des lignées cellulaire, nous avons démontré que les progéniteurs exprimant Msx1 ont des propriétés uniques par rapport aux progéniteurs de la rétine. Les lignées Msx1 génèrent à la fois des cellules de la rétine neurale et des cellules épithéliales ciliaires non-neuronales. De plus, les cellules Msx1 de la ZMC produisent généralement moins de photorécepteurs que les lignées de progéniteurs rétiniennes classiques. En outre, nous montrons que la protéine adaptatrice endocytique Numb régule l'équilibre entre le destin neural et non-neural des progéniteurs Msx1. Ces résultats révèlent qu'il existe bel et bien une population de progéniteurs de la ZMC distincte des progéniteurs rétiniens classiques et qui contribue à la rétinogenèse chez les mammifères. Puisque les dommages à la rétine sont permanents chez les mammifères, nous avons également étudié si Numb, via son effect inhibiteur sur la signalisation de Notch, pourrait potentialiser la réponse des cellules de Müller suite à un dommage à la rétine chez les mammifères adultes. En utilisant un système inductible de délétion de gène spécifique aux cellules de Müller, nous avons montré que l'expression de Numb dans les cellules de Müller ne favorise pas leur dédifférentiation. Au lieu de cela, nous avons constaté que Numb contrôle la survie à long terme des photorécepteurs et la polarité de la rétine. La perte de Numb dans les cellules de Müller brise le réseau de jonctions adhérentes apicales, nommée membrane limite externe, qui préserve l'intégrité de la structure de la rétine. La protéine nécessaire à la polarité, Crb1, est requise pour maintenir la membrane limite externe, et les mutations dans Crb1 sont associées à un défaut de polarité de l'épithélium rétinien conduisant à une perte de vision. Nous avons constaté que Numb se lie à Crb1 et en contrôle le niveau à la membrane limite externe. Par conséquent, ces résultats pourraient apporter une base moléculaire pour identifier la cause des maladies dégénératives rétiniennes humaines. Nos travaux ont ainsi révélés de nouveaux rôles jusqu'ici inconnus pour Numb dans la rétine des mammifères. MOTS-CLÉS: Rétine, zone marginale ciliaire, lignée, décision du destin cellulaire, génétique de la souris, knock-out conditionnel, Numb, neurogénèse, cellule de Müller, membrane limite externe.</description><creator>Bélanger, Marie-Claude</creator><contributor>Michel Cayouette (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Neurogenesis in the mammalian retina: the role of the endocytic adaptor protein Numb</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55mf13k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322g63x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225d353</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La fusion par laser sur lit de poudre (LPBF, en anglais) est un des procédés de fabrication additive qui utilise un laser comme source de chaleur et fabrique des composants à partir de poudres métalliques. Dans cette étude, un système de fusion au laser pulsé sur lit de poudre (PLPBF, en anglais) fabriqué sur mesure a été utilisé pour concevoir une série d'échantillons d'acier ultra-haute résistance AerMet 100 destinés à la caractérisation des matériaux et à l'évaluation des propriétés mécaniques. La phase initiale de la recherche vise à étudier la faisabilité de la fabrication additive d'AerMet 100. Des spécimens sans fissure ont été fabriqués avec succès grâce au système LPBF pulsé sur mesure. Deux traitements thermiques post-PLPBF, un traitement de relaxation des contraintes et un traitement thermique en trois étapes, ont été appliqués aux échantillons conçus par fabrication additive (AM, en anglais) pour l'étude de l'évolution de la microstructure. La microstructure des zones accumulées, affectées thermiquement (HAZ, en anglais) et du substrat par rapport aux échantillons tel que déposés, libérés de stress et soumis à un traitement thermique a été caractérisée par microscopie électronique à balayage (SEM, en anglais), spectroscopie de rayons X à dispersion d'énergie (EDS, en anglais) et diffraction des rayons X (XRD, en anglais). Les résultats de la XRD ont indiqué que les phases prédominantes de la zone d'accumulation à l'état tel que déposé sont la martensite et l'austénite. Les résultats de dureté des échantillons post-traités thermiquement montrent une dureté similaire ou supérieure à un échantillon brut d'AerMet 100 (606HV) traité thermiquement. L'existence de carbures M23C6 riches en Cr dans l'échantillon libéré de stress a été détectée par XRD; leur présence a renforcé la matrice de martensite ce qui a entraîné une augmentation de la dureté. L'élimination de l'austénite et la structure martensitique homogénéisée dans l'échantillon traité thermiquement a amélioré la dureté.</description><description>Laser powder bed fusion(LPBF) is one of the additive manufacturing processes which uses a laser as a heat source and fabricates components from metallic powders. In this study, a custom-built pulsed laser powder bed fusion (PLPBF) system was used to fabricate a series of ultra-high strength steel AerMet 100 specimens for materials characterization and mechanical property evaluation. The initial phase of the research aims to study the feasibility of additive manufacturing of AerMet 100. Crack-free specimens were successfully fabricated through a custom-built pulsed LPBF system. Two post-PLPBF heat treatments, stress relief and three-step heat treatment, were applied to the AM fabricated specimens for microstructure evolution study. The microstructure of build-up, heat affected zone (HAZ) and substrate with respect to as-deposited, stress-relieved and heat-treated samples was characterized using scanning electron microscopy (SEM), Energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDS), and X-ray diffraction (XRD). The XRD results indicated that the predominant phases of build-up area in the as-deposited condition are martensite and retained austenite. The hardness results showed a similar or superior hardness of post heat-treated samples to a wrought heat-treated AerMet 100 (606HV). The existence of Cr-rich M23C6 carbides in the stress-relieved sample were detected by XRD; their presence strengthened the martensite matrix, which resulted in an increased hardness. The elimination of retained austenite and homogenized martensitic structure in the heat-treated sample improved the hardness.</description><creator>Chen, Mingyang</creator><contributor>Mathieu Brochu (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Mining and Materials</subject><title>Laser powder bed fusion of ultrahigh strength steel AerMet 100</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cw37d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225d353</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sm681</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this work we study the Poisson interface problem and a numerical method for its solution, the Correction Function Method. The Poisson interface problem complements the classical Poisson problem, a partial differential equation given in terms of the Laplacian operator, with jump conditions on the solution and its normal derivative along a co-dimension one interface inside the domain. Interface problems arise whenever materials with different properties come into contact, and thus have important applications in many fields of physics and engineering. The Correction Function Method (CFM) is a general framework to solve the Poisson interface problem in the wider context of finite difference methods. In essence, it modifies the finite difference stencils for nodes near the interface in order to take into account the jump conditions. However, these modifications are incorporated, using correction terms, to the right-hand side of the linear system deriving from the finite difference approximation of the partial differential equation, leaving the coefficient matrix identical to the one resulting from the regular Poisson problem. This is essential as many efficient linear solvers, termed "Fast Poisson solvers", are specifically designed to solve this system; by keeping the same matrix we can use them with no modification. In order to account for the multiple possible geometric configurations of the interface with respect to the finite difference stencil, we compute the correction terms locally using a functional minimization approach. Our specific implementation of the CFM is shown to be fourth-order accurate. We also present preliminary work towards a CFM-based Navier-Stokes solver for higher-order numerical simulation of multiphase flow.</description><description>Dans ce mémoire, on étudie le problème de Poisson avec interface ainsi que'une méthode numérique de résolution de ce problème, la méthode de la fonction de correction (« Correction Function Method » ou CFM). Le problème de Poisson avec interface est basé sur le problème de Poisson classique, une équation aux dérivées partielles faisant intervenir l'opérateur laplacien. Il y ajoute des conditions de saut sur la solution ainsi que sur sa dérivée normale le long d'une interface de co-dimension un à l'intérieur du domaine de définition de l'équation. Les problèmes d'interface apparaissent lorsque deux matériaux ayant des propriétés différentes sont mis en contact, et ont donc des applications importantes dans plusieurs domaines en physique et en génie. La méthode de la fonction de correction fournit un cadre général pour la résolution numérique du problème de Poisson avec interface dans le contexte des méthodes de différences finies. Essentiellement, la méthode modifie les formules de différence finies pour les noeuds de discrétisation situées à proximité de l'interface, de façon à incorporer les conditions de saut. Toutefois, ces modifications sont apportées, à l'aide de termes de correction, au terme de droite du système linéaire résultant de la discrétisation par différences finies; la matrice de coefficients reste la même que pour le problème de Poisson standard. Ceci est essentiel puisque de nombreux solveurs linéaires efficaces, appelés « Fast Poisson solvers (solveurs de Poisson rapides) », sont spécifiquement conçus pour résoudre ce système. Le fait de garder la même matrice permet donc de les utiliser sans modifications. Afin de prendre en compte les multiples configurations géométriques de l'interface par rapport à la grille de discrétisation, les termes de correction sont calculés localement en minimisant une fonctionnelle. On montre que notre implémentation spécifique de la CFM converge à l'ordre quatre. On présente aussi des résultats préliminaires en vue de la conception d'un solveur des équations de Navier-Stokes basé sur la CFM, pour la simulation numérique à ordre élevé des écoulements multiphases.</description><creator>Blain, Philippe</creator><contributor>Gantumur Tsogtgerel (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Jean-Christophe Nave (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Mathematics and Statistics</subject><title>Numerical solution of the Poisson interface problem using the Correction Function Method framework</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d653q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sm681</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278w531</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'acylation de mono- et oligosaccharides catalysée par des hydrolases d'esters carboxyliques dans des milieux non conventionnels a été explorée, et ce dans le but de synthétiser des composés ayant de potentielles propriétés bioactives complémentaires. Deux préparations de FAE (EC 3.1.1.73) de Humicola insolens ont été évaluées pour leur spécificité vis-à-vis le substrat et leur activité enzymatique, en utilisant des saccharides feruloylés soit synthétiques soit isolés à partir de son de blé et de betterave sucrière, l'un d'entre eux présentant une activité plus élevée et une spécificité plus large parmi les substrats testés. Cet enzyme a ensuite été sélectionné pour évaluer la feruloylation du xylobiose, du raffinose et de xylo-oligosaccharides (XOS) dans six systèmes de microémulsions sans tensioactif, comme milieux réactionnels. La bioconversion la plus élevée (57%) avec l'enzyme libre a été obtenue dans le cas du xylobiose dans la microémulsion composée de n-hexane / 1,4-dioxane / eau (51: 46: 3, v / v / v), ce système générant des résultats supérieurs pour tous les acyl-accepteurs évalués. L'estérification de FAE a été confirmée par spectrométrie de masse révélant une feruloylation simple et multiple du substrat glycosidique. Les supports mésoporeux hétérofonctionnels portant des groupements métal-chélaté et époxy ont donné à la fois le rendement d'immobilisation FAE le plus élevé et l'activité FAE la plus élevée, et ce par gramme de support. L'optimisation de l'immobilisation de FAE sur des supports époxydes mésoporeux métal-chélaté a été réalisée via la méthodologie RSM, permettant de déterminer le temps d'immobilisation optimal (27,7 h), le pH du tampon d'immobilisation (5.0) et interaction entre l'enzyme et le support d'immobilisation (22,75 mg) / g) ainsi que la molarité du tampon d'immobilisation (0,86 mol / L). Le rendement d'activité enzymatique et la rétention du rendement d'activité spécifique ont été augmentés de 33% et 47% respectivement par rapport aux conditions non optimisées. La thermo stabilité enzymatique du FAE immobilisé a été augmentée après incubation post-immobilisation à pH 10,0, tandis qu'une augmentation de la taille des pores de support a amélioré l'activité hydrolytique et l'efficacité d'estérification du biocatalyseur immobilisé. Il a été déterminé que l'époxy-FAE macroporeux immobilisé et stabilisé de manière optimale conservait jusqu'à 92,9% de l'activité de féruloylation de l'enzyme libre. Des réactions de synthèse d'esters acides gras / saccharides ont été effectuées dans un mélange acide laurique / tert-butanol (90/10; v / v) à 55 ° C en utilisant Novozym® 435 comme biocatalyseur, avec un rendement de bioconversion et une productivité de 19,7% et 9,45 μmol. / L min, respectivement, avec une concentration en fructose (broyé par boulets) de 0,2 mol / L. Une augmentation de la teneur en acides gras du milieu réactionnel a eu un effet négatif sur l'estérification. L'estérification de l'acide myristique catalysée par une lipase immobilisée avec substrats fructose et fructo-oligosaccharides dans des milieux réactionnels à faible teneur en solvant (10%, v / v) a également été étudiée. On a déterminé que la longueur de la chaîne d'accepteur d'acyle était inversement proportionnelle au rendement de la réaction. Un rapport 1: 1 entre acide oléique et acide laurique / myristique dans la réaction diminuait la viscosité et le point de fusion des milieux, mais diminuait également de moitié le rendement d'estérification. Le rendement maximal en myristate de fructose (22%) a été obtenu en utilisant 0,2 mol / L de fructose et 5% (p / v) de Lipozyme® RM IM dans un milieu réactionnel composé de 10% tert-butanol, 10% acide oléique et 80% acide myristique, en utilisant la méthodologie RSM basée sur un modèle composite central à 5 niveaux et 3 facteurs. Sans addition d'acide oléique, le rendement maximal (25,5%) a été obtenu avec 0,2 mol / L de fructose et 6% (p/v) d'enzyme. </description><description>Acylation of mono- and oligosaccharides catalyzed by carboxylic ester hydrolases in non-conventional media was explored to synthesize compounds with potential bioactive properties.  Multienzymatic Depol 740L from Humicola insolens and a pure feruloyl esterase (FAE) preparation from the same source were evaluated for their specificity and activity using synthetic and isolated feruloylated saccharides from wheat bran and sugar beet, with the FAE preparation showing higher activity and broader specificity among the substrates tested. It was then selected to evaluate the feruloylation of xylobiose, raffinose and xylo-oligosaccharides in 6 different surfactantless microemulsions as reaction media. The microemulsion composed by n-hexane/2-butanone/water (51:46:3, v/v/v) showed consistently higher bioconversions with all the acyl acceptors evaluated. MS analysis revealed simple and multiple feruloylation of the glycoside substrates. Heterofunctional supports bearing metal-chelate and epoxy groups achieved highest FAE immobilization yield and highest activity per gram of support. More specifically, FAE immobilized onto a porous metal-chelate-epoxy support modified retained 35% of the feruloylation capacity of the free FAE when xylobiose was present as the acyl acceptor. Optimization of the FAE immobilization onto mesoporous metal-chelate-epoxy supports by response surface methodology (RSM) was performed, where optimal immobilization time (27.7 h), pH of the immobilization buffer (5.0) and interaction between the ratio of enzyme to immobilization support (22.75 mg/g) with the immobilization buffer molarity (0.86 mol/L) were determined. Enzymatic activity yield and retention of specific activity yield were increased by 33% and 47%, respectively, when compared to unoptimized conditions. Enzyme thermostability of the immobilized FAE was enhanced following a post-immobilization incubation at pH 10.0, while an increase of support pore size improved hydrolytic activity and esterifying efficiency of the immobilized biocatalyst. It was determined that optimally immobilized and stabilized FAE retained up to 92.9% of the feruloylation activity of the free enzyme. Carbohydrate fatty acid ester synthesis reactions were performed in a mixture of lauric acid/tert-butanol (90/10; v/v) at 55 °C using Novozym® 435 as the biocatalyst, where bioconversion yield and productivity of 19.7% and 9.45 µmol/L min, respectively, were obtained with a ball-milled fructose concentration of 0.2 mol/L. An increase in reaction media fatty acid content adversely   affected esterification. The enhancement of polar substrate solubility and an increase in acylation reaction productivity were significant benefits of the combined low-solvent and mechanical milling of reaction substrates for lipase-catalyzed esterification approach.The immobilized lipase-catalyzed esterification of myristic acid with fructose and fructooligosaccharides in low solvent reaction media (10%, v/v) was also studied. The acyl acceptor chain length was determined to be inversely proportional to the reaction yield. A 1:1 ratio of oleic to lauric/myristic acid in the reaction decreased the viscosity and the melting point of the media but also decreased the esterification yield by half. Maximum fructose myristate yield (22%) was obtained using 0.2 mol/L of fructose and 5% (w/v) of Lipozyme® RM IM in a reaction media composed of 10% tert-butanol, 10% oleic acid, and 80 % myristic acid, using RSM based on a 5-level and 3-factor central composite design. Without addition of oleic acid, maximum yield (25.5%) was obtained with 0.2 mol/L of fructose and 6% (w/v) of enzyme. At these latter conditions, 6 consecutive reactions were catalyzed before a reduction in synthetic activity was observed. ESI-MS analysis confirmed the production of mono- and diesters, and the selectivity of this enzyme for saturated fatty acids over unsaturated fatty acids.</description><creator>Tamayo Cabezas, Juan</creator><contributor>Salwa Karboune (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</subject><title>Biocatalytic Acylation of Carbohydrates to Produce Feruloylated Oligosaccharides and Carbohydrate Fatty Acid Esters as Potential Functional Ingredients: Novel Approaches for Efficient Enzymatic Synthesis by Carboxylic</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s7128.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278w531</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21th69j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dans cette thèse, nous tenterons de comprendre si l'étude de données concernant deux populations — des patients ayant subi des dommages au cortex préfrontal ventromédian (VM) et des individus diagnostiqués psychopathes ou présentant des caractéristiques de la personnalité psychopathe — permet de déterminer quel élément a une plus grande influence sur la cognition morale, l'émotion ou la raison. De récentes recherches en psychologie et en neurosciences ont mis en évidence le rôle de l'émotion (mais pas celui de la raison) sur la cognition morale en utilisant souvent des données concernant ces populations prouvant ainsi que l'émotion est nécessaire à un comportement moralement sain. En effet, ces deux populations affichent de manière caractéristique des comportements sociaux et moraux aberrants dans la vie de tous les jours et ont obtenu des résultats anormaux sur des tests de laboratoire visant à évaluer l'émotion et la cognition morale, ce qui nous incite à conclure qu'ils présentent des déficits dans leur capacité à ressentir les émotions subjectivement et à les identifier objectivement. Néanmoins, de plus en plus de données suggèrent que ces deux populations auraient également des troubles d'attention, des difficultés à comprendre et à traiter l'information et une capacité réduite à déterminer les valeurs dans le processus de prise de décision, ce qui pourrait expliquer leurs comportements immoraux et leurs résultats anormaux. Il est important de noter que ces processus de traitement de l'information ne sont pas uniquement liés à l'émotion, mais aussi à la raison. Par conséquent, les termes « émotion » et « raison » pourraient s'avérer trop généraux pour décrire les déficits de ces populations. Il serait donc incorrect d'utiliser des données concernant ces populations pour tenter d'élucider le rôle de l'émotion dans la cognition morale au sein de la dichotomie émotion-raison puisque ces données décrivent les déficits de ces populations de façon imprécise et inexacte.</description><description>This dissertation examines whether using data from two populations, patients with ventromedial prefrontal cortex (vmPFC) damage (vmPFC patients) and individuals diagnosed with psychopathy or who score high in having psychopathic characteristics, is appropriate to make assertions regarding the age-old dichotomic Emotion-Reason debate of whether emotion or reason is more influential for moral cognition. Recent work in psychology and neuroscience has largely supported the necessary and/or sufficient roles of emotion, but not reason, in moral cognition, often using data from these populations as evidence that emotion is necessary in order to behave morally. Specifically, both populations characteristically display aberrant social and moral behaviors in the real world and perform abnormally on laboratory tests that measure emotion and moral cognition. From this, both populations are believed to have specific deficits in the capabilities to subjectively experience and objectively identify emotion. However, increasing evidence demonstrates that both populations also have basic information processing deficits in attention and the ability to assess value about the world that could alternatively explain the populations' abnormalities. Importantly, these information processes are necessary for the higher-order processes of both emotion and reason and are not specific to emotion. Therefore, using the broad terms "emotion" and "reason" may be the wrong level of description when explaining the deficits of the populations. Using data from these populations to support the necessary role of emotion in moral cognition in attempts to adhere to the age-old Emotion-Reason debate is then inappropriate because it inaccurately describes the deficits which the populations actually have.</description><creator>Garr, Anna</creator><contributor>Ian Jeffrey Gold (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>The impact of information processing deficits on moral cognition: evidence from vmPFC patient and psychopathic populations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dp65f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21th69j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26z0632</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Aspergillus fumigatus est un champignon ubiquitaire pouvant provoquer des pneumonies potentiellement mortelle chez les patients immunocompromis. Une première composante contribuant à la virulence d'A. fumigatus réside dans la complexité de sa paroi cellulaire et sa capacité à former de biofilms. Ces parois et biofilms sont composés presque de polysaccharides possédant chacun des fonctions uniques. L'un des polysaccharides les plus exposés et jouant un rôle clé dans la virulence est le galactosaminogalactane (GAG). Cette molécule est essentielle à l'adhérence et la formation de biofilm, ainsi qu'au masquage d'autres polysaccharides pariétaux fortement immunogènes. Cependant, celui-ci lorsque purifié présente lui aussi des effets directs sur le système immunitaire suggérant que les mammifères ont la capacité de le reconnaître et d'enclencher une réponse immunitaire subséquente.Nous avons émis l'hypothèse que la reconnaissance du GAG par les récepteurs de mammifères joue un rôle dans la réponse immunitaire contre les infections provoquées par A. fumigatus. Nous avons également postulé que la dégradation de ce polysaccharide pourrait constituer une nouvelle stratégie de thérapie.La lectine de mammifère galectine-3 (Gal3) est un membre d'une famille de lectine caractérisée par leur capacité de liaison aux polysaccharides contenant du galactose, et connue pour leur implication dans une multitude de maladies infectieuses. Nous avons postulé que la Gal3 pourrait lier le GAG et être impliqué dans la réponse immunitaire provoquée par A. fumigatus. La Gal3 a été retrouvé en plus grande abondance dans le fluide bronchoalvéolaire de souris souffrant d'aspergillose indiquant une sécrétion de cette molécule lors d'une infection. La Gal3 a aussi montré des capacités de liaison au GAG. Contrairement à ce qu'il a été précédemment observé avec d'autres espèces fongiques, la liaison de la Gal3 aux hyphes d'A. fumigatus ne semble pas inhiber la croissance du champignon. Néanmoins, les souris déficientes en Gal3 sont plus sensibles à A. fumigatus, révélant que la Gal3 joue tout de même un rôle bénéfique dans la réponse de l'hôte. Cette lectine a de plus démontré améliorer la migration des neutrophiles hors des vaisseaux sanguins vers le site d'infection. Des expériences de transfert adoptif de neutrophile ont montré que même si l'apport extrinsèque de Gal3 est requis pour la sortie des neutrophiles à partir du système vasculaire, la Gal3 intrinsèque aux neutrophiles est dispensable à ce procédé de migration.Après avoir étudié la capacité de récepteurs de mammifère à interagir avec GAG, nous avons également étudié les protéines impliquées dans la voie de biosynthèse de ce polysaccharide. L'une des protéines, Sph3, présente un domaine glycoside hydrolase capable de cliver GAG. Ce domaine, Sph3h, a été exprimé en système hétérologue, purifié et sa capacité de disruption de biofilm d'A. fumigatus évaluée. Le traitement des biofilms avec quelques nanomolaires de Sph3h a diminué la quantité de GAG détectable à la surface des hyphes, ainsi que l'adhérence du biofilm. L'hydrolyse du polymère a aussi permis de rendre A. fumigatus de prévenir in vitro les dommages occasionnés aux cellules épithéliales par le champignon. In vivo, une dose unique de Sph3h atténué la virulence d'A. fumigatus dans un modèle d'aspergillose invasive. De plus, une glycoside hydrolase similaire produite par la bactérie Pseudomonas aeruginosa a aussi été en mesure de dégrader le biofilm formé par A. fumigatus, suggérant que cette stratégie thérapeutique pourrait avoir des activités traversant les règnes du vivant.Ensemble, les découvertes de cette étude illustrent la diversité avec laquelle les protéines interagissent avec les polysaccharides de la paroi fongique. Nous avons identifié un nouveau rôle de la Gal3 dans le contexte de l'immunologie fongique, et identifier une nouvelle avenue de thérapie basée sur la dégradation de biofilm microbien utilisant des glycoside hydrolases.</description><description>Aspergillus fumigatus is a ubiquitous mould that can cause life-threatening pneumonia in immunocompromised patients. A primary component contributing to the virulence of A. fumigatus is its complex cell wall and ability to form robust biofilms. The cell wall of A. fumigatus is composed almost exclusively of polysaccharides, each with their own unique function. One outer cell wall polysaccharide important for virulence is galactosaminogalactan (GAG), which is essential in mediating adherence and biofilm formation, as well as masking inner cell wall components that have immune-reactivity. However, purified GAG has direct effects on the immune system, suggesting that mammalian systems are able to recognize and respond to this molecule.We hypothesize that the recognition of GAG by mammalian protein receptors plays an important role in the immune response towards an A. fumigatus infection. Furthermore, given the central role GAG plays in the virulence of A. fumigatus, we hypothesize that enzymatic degradation of this polysaccharide could form the basis of a novel treatment strategy.The mammalian cytosolic lectin galectin-3 (Gal3) is a member of a family of lectins characterized by their ability to bind to galactoside-containing carbohydrates that has been implicated in a broad range of infectious diseases and other disorders. Because of this observation, we postulated that it could potentially bind to A. fumigatus GAG, and may be involved in the immune response against this pathogen. Gal3 was upregulated in the serum and bronchoalveolar lavage fluid of humans and mice with pulmonary aspergillosis, respectively, indicating that Gal3 is released during an Aspergillus infection. Gal3 bound to native GAG on the surface of the hyphae. Despite binding to the surface of A. fumigatus, Gal3 did not inhibit fungal growth, unlike previous observations with other fungi. However, Gal3 deficient mice were more susceptible to Aspergillus infection, revealing that Gal3 still played a beneficial role to the host. Gal3 was found to aid in the migration of neutrophils out of the vasculature and to the site of infection. Neutrophil adoptive transfer experiments revealed that while extrinsic Gal3 was required for optimal neutrophil egress from the pulmonary vasculature, neutrophil intrinsic Gal3 was dispensable for this process.In addition to investigating the capacity of mammalian proteins to interact with GAG, we also studied the proteins involved in the biosynthesis of the polysaccharide. One protein, Sph3, contained a glycoside hydrolase domain capable of cleaving the GAG polysaccharide chain. The hydrolase domain of Sph3, Sph3h, was expressed and purified, and evaluated for its ability to disrupt A. fumigatus biofilms. Treatment of A. fumigatus biofilms with nanomolar concentrations of Sph3h markedly reduced the amount of detectable GAG on the surface of hyphae, as well as the adherence of the fungus. Hydrolysis of GAG increased the susceptibility of A. fumigatus to a variety of classes of antifungal compounds, and prevented the fungus from damaging human airway epithelial cells in vitro. A single dose of Sph3h was well tolerated by mice, and attenuated the virulence of A. fumigatus in a mouse model of invasive aspergillosis. Additionally, a similar glycoside hydrolase produced by the Gram-negative bacteria Pseudomonas aeruginosa was also able to disrupt A. fumigatus biofilms, suggesting that this therapeutic strategy could have cross-kingdom activity. This study has laid the foundation for the development of a new therapeutic strategy in combating recalcitrant biofilm infections.Collectively, the findings of this thesis illustrate the diversity with which both mammalian and microbial proteins interact with the polysaccharides of the fungal cell wall. We have identified a new role for Gal3 in the context of fungal immunology, and a novel avenue of therapeutic development through degradation of microbial biofilms with glycoside hydrolases.</description><creator>Snarr, Brendan</creator><contributor>Donald Sheppard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Microbiology &amp; Immunology</subject><title>Targeting the aspergillus fumigatus cell wall with polysaccharide-specific proteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591b66w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z0632</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j67316286</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The growing ubiquity of internet-connected devices has led to increased interest in the Internet of Things. As the pace of IoT development accelerates, new paradigms are being developed that can fully utilize the potential benefits of this new computing trend. One such paradigm is fog computing, in which data processing is moved toward the edge, allowing more localized devices to handle tasks that would have previously been assigned to the cloud. In this thesis we introduce JAMScript, a new programming language specifically designed for fog computing. JAMScript combines the C and JavaScript programming languages, allowing the ability to leverage the benefits of each language in a single program. JAMScript takes advantage of this shared language space to provide edge computing optimized functionality, such as remote multi-language activities, shared persistent variables, conditional execution constructs and data stream management. We explain the design and implementation of the JAMScript compiler and provide details about how applications can be developed using JAMScript. We then provide example programming patterns where JAMScript's unique features allow building complex applications with minimal effort.</description><description>L'omniprésence croissante des appareils connectés à Internet a suscité un intérêt croissant pour l'Internet des objets. Comme le développement d'IdO s'accélère, de nouveaux paradigmes en cours de développement peuvent tirer parti des avantages potentiels de cette nouvelle tendance informatique. L'un de ces paradigmes est l'informatique de brouillard; Le traitement des données est déplacé vers le bord, ce qui permet aux dispositifs plus localisés de gérer les tâches qui auraient été normalement assignées au nuage. Au cours de cette thèse, nous introduisons un nouveau langage de programmation spécialement conçu pour l'informatique de brouillard, JAMScript. JAMScript combine les langages de programmation C et JavaScript, permettant la possibilité de tirer parti des avantages de chaque langue dans un seul programme. JAMScript profite de cet espace total de langage pour fournir des fonctionnalités optimisées de traitement informatique, telles que les activités multilingues à distance, les variables permanentes partagées, les utilitaires de construction d'exécution et la gestion des flux de données. Nous expliquons la conception et la mise en œuvre du compilateur JAMScript et fournissons des détails sur la manière dont les applications peuvent être développées à l'aide de JAMScript. Nous poursuivrons en présentant quelques exemples de schémas de programmation où les fonctionnalités uniques de JAMScript permettent de créer des applications complexes avec un effort minimal.</description><creator>Wenger, Robert</creator><contributor>Muthucumaru Maheswaran (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Computer Science</subject><title>Design and implementation of a compiler for a fog and IoT programming language</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wg06s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j67316286</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:08612q905</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background: Birth asphyxia often leads to long-term neurological sequelae including visual impairments. These impairments are typically associated to injuries to the visual pathways within the brain, but they may also be due to injuries to the retina itself. Therapeutic hypothermia is currently the only available treatment for this condition, and although it has been shown to have neuroprotective effects (i.e., prevention of brain injury), many asphyxiated newborns still develop injury and long-term neurological deficits. Objective: To investigate the neurorestorative effect of sildenafil on retinal neurons, glial cells and vasculature, following hypoxia-ischemia (HI). Methods: Neonatal HI was induced in rat pups at postnatal day 10 (P10) by left common carotid artery ligation followed by 2-hour exposure to 8% oxygen. Subsequently, animals were randomized to receive a vehicle solution or 2 mg/kg, 10 mg/kg or 50 mg/kg of sildenafil, twice per day for 7 consecutive days. Immunohistochemistry on radial sections of the retina was performed at P30 to examine inner retinal neurons (i.e., retinal ganglion cells, bipolar cells, horizontal cells, amacrine cells) and glial cells (i.e., astrocytes, Muller cells and microglia). Immunohistochemistry on flatmount preparations of the retina was performed at P30 to assess retinal vasculature. Western blots were performed at P12, P17 and P30 to assess markers of neuronal regeneration (DCX and Sox2), axonal regeneration (Gap43) and cell death (PARP). ELISA analysis was performed at P12 and P17 to measure inflammatory cytokine IL1-b levels. Results: HI caused a significant loss in inner retinal neurons at P30, a decrease in the number of immature neurons indicated by a decrease in DCX levels at P12, P17 and P30, as well as an increase in cell death indicated by an increase in PARP expression at P12 compared to sham. HI also led to a significant increase in IL1-b levels at P12, and the increase in the number of astrocytes and Muller cells at P30 indicating persistent inflammation. In addition, HI induced a loss of blood vessels within the deeper plexus of retinal vasculature. Sildenafil administration restored the number of inner retinal neurons, and returned DCX and PARP expression back to sham levels. Sildenafil also reduced inflammation by reducing IL1-b levels and gliosis, and improving retinal vascularization within the deep plexus.  Conclusion: Sildenafil improved retinal injuries following HI by reestablishing retinal neuron numbers, reducing inflammation and improving retinal vasculature. </description><description>Contexte: L'asphyxie à la naissance mène souvent à des complications neurologiques à long-terme, incluant des déficiences visuelles, dues à des dommages à la rétine et/ou le cerveau des nouveau-nés atteints. Actuellement, le seul traitement disponible est l'hypothermie thérapeutique. Mais, malgré le fait que ce traitement démontre des effets protecteurs (i.e., évitement des dommages au cerveau), de nombreux enfants développent tout de même des dommages au cerveau et des déficiences neurologiques à long terme.  Objectif: Investiguer les effets réparateurs du sildénafil sur les neurones, les cellules gliales, et les vaisseaux sanguins de la rétine, à la suite d'une hypoxie-ischémie. Méthodes: L'hypoxie-ischémie (HI) a été induite auprès de ratons au jour de vie postnatal 10 (P10) par la ligature de l'artère carotide commune gauche, suivie d'une exposition de 2 heures à 8% d'oxygène. Par la suite, ils étaient randomisés à recevoir 0 mg/kg, 2 mg/kg, 10 mg/kg or 50 mg/kg de sildénafil, 2 fois par jour, pour 7 jours consécutifs. De l'immunohistochimie a été effectuée sur des sections radiales de la rétine à P30 pour évaluer les neurones des couches internes de la rétine (i.e., cellules ganglionnaires rétiniennes, cellules bipolaires, cellules horizontales et cellules amacrines) ainsi que les cellules gliales (i.e., astrocytes, cellules de Muller et microglies). Des montages plats rétiniens ont été réalisés à P30 et les points de ramification des différents plexus vasculaires rétiniens ont été comptés. Des western blots ont été effectués à P12, P17 et P30 pour évaluer des marqueurs de régénération neuronale (DCX et Sox2), de régénération axonale (Gap43) et de mort cellulaire (PARP). Des analyses ELISA ont été réalisées à P12 et P17 pour mesurer les niveaux de la cytokine inflammatoire IL1-b. Résultats: L'exposition à l'HI a causé une diminution du nombre de neurones au sein des couches internes de la rétine à P30, une diminution de neurones immatures indiqué par une baisse d'expression de DCX à P12, P17 et P30, ainsi qu'une augmentation de la mort cellulaire indiquée par la hausse d'expression de PARP à P12. L'HI a également mené à une augmentation du niveau de IL1-b à P12, et à l'activation des astrocytes et des cellules gliales de Muller à P30, suggérant une inflammation persistante. En plus, HI a induit une perte de vaisseaux sanguins au niveau profond du plexus vasculaire rétinien. L'administration de sildénafil a permis de rétablir le nombre de neurones, de réaugmenter l'expression de DCX et de rebaisser l'expression de PARP à des niveaux comparables aux animaux témoins. Le sildénafil a aussi réduit l'inflammation en diminuant l'expression de IL1-b et l'activation des cellules gliales, et a amélioré la vascularisation du plexus vasculaire profond. Conclusion: Le sildénafil semble améliorer les dommages rétiniens suite à l'HI en ramenant le nombre de neurones de la rétine, l'inflammation et la vascularisation du plexus profond à des niveaux comparables aux animaux témoins. </description><creator>Balian, Palig</creator><contributor>Pia Wintermark (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Therapeutic effects of sildenafil on retinal injury following neonatal hypoxia-ischemia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687k47j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612q905</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pg15bh35c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Small diameter vascular grafts are required for surgical applications in coronary bypass procedures, hemodialysis patients with end-stage renal disease and reconstructive operations. When autologous vessels are not available, synthetic materials such as Dacron and polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE) are the only viable options. These synthetic materials have been successful for large vessel applications (greater than 8 mm) but their use for small vessel applications (below 6 mm) is increasingly poor as a result of anastomotic intimal hyperplasia and thrombosis. Patency rates of 40% at 6 months and 25% at 3 years (Rocco et al., 2014) have been reported demonstrating a need for a better material with optimal mechanical properties, biocompatibility, non-immunogenicity, porosity, degradability, cost efficiency and processability. Here we propose the utilization of acellular and absorbable gel spun silk vascular graft as an alternative material to the current synthetic materials in patients where autologous vessels are not available. Gel spinning conditions had been previously optimized in vitro (Lovett et al., 2010) for their luminal smoothness, porosity, and degradation profiles. Here I demonstrate the ability to make drug bulk modified silk tubes post modified via water annealing. Silk tubes were made using four different types of drugs: Argatroban, Eptifibatide, Heparin and Sirolimous. Their release kinetic study was quantified using LCMS. Furthermore, bilayered gel spun scaffolds were made using two different layers paving the way for bilayered grafts with multiple functionality for future in vivo work.</description><description>Des greffes vasculaires de petit diamètre sont nécessaires pour les applications chirurgicales dans les procédures de pontage coronarien, pour les patients hémodialysés présentant une insuffisance rénale terminale et les chirurgies de reconstruction. Quand des vaisseaux autologues ne sont pas disponibles, des matériaux synthétiques tels que le Dacron et le polytétrafluoroéthylène (PTFE) sont les seules options viables. Ces matériaux ont été utilisé avec succès pour les applications de grands vaisseaux (plus grands de 8 mm), mais on eu moins de succès avec les petits vaisseaux (inférieures à 6 mm) à cause de l'hyperplasie intime anastomotique et la thrombose. Les taux de perméabilité de 40% à 6 mois et de 25% à 3 ans (Rocco et al., 2014) ont démontré un besoin de meilleur matériel avec des propriétés mécaniques optimales, biocompatible, non-immunogène, poreux, dégradable, et un temps de production court et rentable. Nous proposons ici l'utilisation de la greffe vasculaire en soie filée en gel acellulaire et résorbable en tant que matériel alternatif aux matériaux synthétiques actuels chez les patients pour lesquels des vaisseaux autologues ne sont pas disponibles. Les conditions de filage en gel avaient été préalablement optimisées in vitro (Lovett et al., 2010) pour leur finesse de paroi, porosité et profils de dégradation. Ici, je démontre la capacité de fabriquer des tubes de soie modifiés avec des médicaments par une modification incorporée et suivi d'un traitement de recuit à l'eau "Water Annealing".  Les tubes de soie ont été fabriqués à l'aide de quatre types de médicaments différents: Argatroban, Eptifibatide, Héparine et Sirolimous. Leur étude cinétique de libération a été quantifiée par LCMS. De plus, des échafaudages à double couche en gel ont été faits de deux couches différentes ouvrant la voie à des greffes bicouches avec de multiples fonctionnalités pour de futurs travaux in vivo.</description><creator>Lyakhovich, Yuliya</creator><contributor>Kevin J Lachapelle (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Surgery</subject><title>Silk as a biomaterial for tissue-engineered vascular conduits</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zg77c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bh35c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mp64d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Understanding the biophysics of DNA and RNA at the single-molecule level is critical to advancing the fields of molecular biology, diagnostics, and pharmaceuticals, and developing new treatments for genetic disorders. Single-molecule microscopy techniques have generated new knowledge of the interactions between nucleic acids and proteins, drugs, and other nucleic acid molecules. However, these techniques have either limited observation times, are limited to low concentrations, or require molecular tethering. Recently, Convex Lens-induced Confinement (CLiC) has emerged to address these challenges. In CLiC, molecules are introduced between two glass surfaces that are gradually pressed together to confine molecules in a nanoscale gap between them. In this thesis, we implement CLiC to trap, manipulate, and image single DNA and RNA polymers. First, we combine CLiC with nanofluidic grooves embedded in the bottom glass surface to demonstrate gentle loading and linearization of long DNA polymers within the grooves, which become closed nanochannels upon application of confinement. We study the DNA extension as a function of applied confinement. We then introduce grooves with circular geometries to suppress DNA drift due to the confinement gradient inherent in the CLiC chamber geometry, and use confinement to enhance self-ligation of long linear DNA. Next, we demonstrate an alternative method to stretch DNA using a thin wire rotating in solution. DNA close to the wire surface are stretched by the rotation. This method has potential applications in stretching very long, fragile DNA. We then present a miniaturized, microfabricated version of the CLiC imaging chamber with improved mechanical performance and pneumatic control of the confinement, and use it to demonstrate linearization of DNA in nanogrooves with a reduced confinement gradient. Finally, we replace nanogrooves with micropits and apply CLiC to detect the binding of antisense oligonucleotides (ASOs) to a small target RNA molecule, with the eventual goal of developing a platform to study and optimize ASO binding at the single-molecule level. The methods developed here can be applied to study a wide range of biological processes, including DNA transcription, translation, and repair, molecular search processes, and gene editing tools such as CRISPR-Cas9. The results presented in this thesis show how we can use nanoconfinement to measure the interactions and mechanical properties of individual macromolecules.</description><description>Comprendre la biophysique de l'ADN et l'ARN au niveau des molécules individuelles est essentiel pour faire progresser les domaines de la biologie moléculaire, du diagnostic et des produits pharmaceutiques et pour développer de nouveaux traitements pour les maladies génétiques. Les techniques de microscopie pour observer des molécules individuelles ont généré de nouvelles connaissances sur les interactions entre les acides nucléiques et les protéines, les médicaments, et d'autres molécules d'acides nucléiques. Cependant, ces techniques ont soit un temps d'observation limité, soit limité à des concentrations trop bas, soit nécessitent que les molécules soient attachées à une surface. Récemment, le confinement induit par une lentille convexe (CLiC) a été introduit pour relever ces défis. Dans CLiC, les molécules sont introduites entre deux surfaces de verre qui sont progressivement pressées l'une contre l'autre pour les confiner dans un espace nanométrique entre les surfaces. Dans cette thèse, nous implémentons CLiC pour confiner, manipuler et imager des polymères individuelles d'ADN et d'ARN. Tout d'abord, nous utilisons CLiC avec des rainures nanofluidiques incorporées dans une des surfaces du verre pour démontrer l'introduction et la linéarisation doucement de longs polymères d'ADN dans les rainures, qui deviennent des nanocanaux fermés lors de l'application du confinement. Nous étudions l'extension de l'ADN en fonction du confinement appliqué. Nous introduisons ensuite des rainures avec des géométries circulaires afin de supprimer la dérive de l'ADN en raison du gradient de confinement inhérent à la géométrie de la chambre CLiC, et utilisons le confinement pour améliorer l'auto-ligature de l'ADN long et linéaire. Ensuite, nous démontrons une méthode alternative pour étirer l'ADN en utilisant un fil fin qui tourne en solution. L'ADN proche de la surface du fil est étiré par la rotation. Cette méthode a des applications potentielles dans l'étirement d'ADN très long et fragile. Nous présentons ensuite une version miniaturisée et microfabriquée de la chambre d'imagerie CLiC avec une performance mécanique améliorée et un contrôle pneumatique du confinement, et nous l'utilisons pour démontrer la linéarisation de l'ADN dans des rainures nanofluidiques avec une gradient de confinement réduit. Enfin, nous remplaçons les rainures nanofluidiques par des micro-trous et appliquons CLiC pour détecter la liaison d'oligonucléotides antisens (ASO) à une petite molécule d'ARN cible, dans le but ultime de développer une plateforme pour étudier et optimiser la liaison des ASO au niveau des molécules individuelles.Les méthodes développées ici peuvent être appliquées à l'étude d'un large éventail de processus biologiques, y compris la transcription, la traduction et la réparation de l'ADN, les processus de recherche moléculaire, et les techniques d'édition des gènes tels que CRISPR-Cas9. Les résultats présentés dans cette thèse montrent comment nous pouvons utiliser le nanoconfinement pour mesurer les interactions et les propriétés mécaniques de macromolécules individuelles.</description><creator>Berard, Daniel</creator><contributor>Sabrina Leslie (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Physics</subject><title>Imaging and manipulation of single nucleic acids with convex Lens-induced confinement</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cw38p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mp64d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g732dc21n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, we theoretically study novel ways to use parametric driving in bosonic systems as a resource to generate interesting properties and states. We parametrically drive a topologically trivial bosonic system and show that properly tuning the phases and strengths of the drive induces a topological phase transition. We study the phase diagram and show that parametrically-driven topological bosonic systems are distinct from their fermionic analogues as well as topological systems without parametric driving. For a finite-sized system, we use standard input-output formalism to study the transport of classical signals. We show that parametrically-driven topological bosonic systems mediate protected chiral inelastic transport in conjunction with the usual chiral elastic transport. When weakly coupled to a zero-temperature environment, we show that parametrically driving a bosonic system can lead to interesting steady-states. Under certain circumstances, we show that it is possible to obtain a steady-state for non-conserved bosons, such as photons, that is thermally occupied at a finite temperature and chemical potential. In a different scheme, we study how vacuum fluctuations propagate in parametrically driven topological bosonic systems. We show how to obtain parametrically-unstable edge states, while maintaining stable bulk modes, by choosing the frequency and phasesof the drive accordingly. Furthermore, we show how to exploit this property to realize a topologically-protected, travelling-wave amplifier. Such a device is experimentally cost-heavy to produce: requires parametrically driving many lattice sites. We thusnumerically study if it is possible to achieve a resource-efficient device with similar amplifying properties. We show that we can greatly reduce the number of parametrically driven sites, increasing the resource-efficiency.Finally, we study the effects of having different loss rates for the bosonic modes in travelling-wave parametric amplifiers. We study two different loss models and show that having loss asymmetry can greatly deteriorate the squeezing of collective output quadratures while leaving your state strongly entangled. As several protocols require the use of squeezed collective quadratures, we propose a correction scheme which allows one to regain some level of squeezing for the collective quadratures. Furthermore, we show that asymmetry increases the amount of noise added by the amplifier.</description><description>Dans cette thèse, nous étudions d'un point de vue théorique de nouvelles façons d'utiliser la modulation paramétrique dans des systèmes bosonique comme une ressource pour générer des propriétés et des états intéressants. Nous modulons de manière paramétrique un système de bosons topologiquement trivial et nous montrons que le réglage correct des phases et des amplitudes de la modulation induit une transition de phase topologique. Nous établissons le diagramme de phase et nous montrons que les systèmes de bosons topologiques à modulation paramétrique sont distincts de leurs analogues fermioniques ainsi que des systèmes topologiques sans modulation paramétrique. Pour un système de taille finie, nous utilisons le formalisme d'entrée-sortie standard pour étudier le transport des signaux classiques. Nous montrons que les systèmes de bosons topologiques à modulation paramétriques peuvent servir de médiateur pour le transport inélastique et chiral en conjonction avec le transport élastique et chiral habituel. Lorsque faiblement couplé à un environnement à température nulle, nous montrons que la modulation paramétrique d'un système bosonique peut conduire à des états d'équilibre intéressants. Nous montrons qu'il est possible d'observer sous certaines conditions un état d'équilibre pour des bosons non conservés, comme par exemple des photons, qui est thermiquement occupés à une température finie et à un potentiel chimique non-nulle.Dans un second temps, nous étudions comment les fluctuations du vide se propagent dans des systèmes de bosons topologiques à modulation paramétrique. Nous montrons comment obtenir des états de bord paramétriquement instables, tout en maintenant les modes de volume stables, en choisissant la fréquence et les phases de la modulation en conséquence. Nous exploitons ensuite ces proprietés pour réaliser un amplificateur à ondes de déplacement topologiquement protégé. Un tel dispositif est expérimentalement coûteux à produire puisqu'il nécessite la modulation paramétrique de nombreux sites. Nous étudions donc numériquement la possibilité de réaliser un dispositif économe en ressources sans compromettre l'amplification. Nous montrons que nous pouvons réduire considérablement le nombre de sites modulé paramétriquement, augmentant ainsi l'efficacité des ressources du dispositif. Enfin, nous étudions les effets d'avoir des taux de relaxation non-uniform pour les modes bosoniques présent dans les amplificateurs paramétrique à ondes de déplacement. Nous étudions deux modèles de perte différents et montrons que l'asymétrie de pertepeut grandement détériorer la compression de la quadrature collective de sortie tout en laissant l'état fortement intriqué. Comme plusieurs protocoles nécessitent l'utilisation de quadrature collective compressée, nous proposons un protocol de correction d'erreur qui permet de retrouver un certain niveau de compression pour les quadratures collectifs. De plus, nous montrons que l'asymétrie augmente la quantité de bruit produite par l'amplificateur.</description><creator>Houde, Martin</creator><contributor>Clerk, Aashish (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Pereg-Barnea, Tamar (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Physics</subject><title>Parametric driving as a route to topological states and quantum devices</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430699k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732dc21n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4x51hm505</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Music journalist Jude Rogers observed that at the dawn of the twenty first century "eccentric folk music of the late 1960s became covetable again" (2008). Rogers explains that the resurgence of interest in this "eccentric folk music" is due in part to the re-release of Vashti Bunyan's Just Another Diamond Day, originally released in 1970, and re-released in 2000. The "psychedelic," "eccentric," or "freak" folk—as Bunyan's music is now labelled—of the late 1960s and early 1970s in North America and Western Europe has recently become celebrated despite its lack of commercial success in the 1960s/70s. Freak folk has thus gone from a genre that was virtually ignored at the time of its emergence to one that has attracted a niche market. I examine the reception of freak folk in order to understand its resurgence within and relevance to the contemporary popular music landscape. Moreover, given that freak folk artists have been predominantly female, I will attend to the ways in which the gender identity of these artists shaped freak folk's reception history.Following the trajectory of Bunyan's reception, I postulate that there is more ideological room in popular music now for the progressive aesthetics of female freak folk musicians, than was the case in the 1960s/70s. I hold that this in part accounts for the contemporary resurgence in freak folk. To come to this conclusion, I analyze twentieth-century press coverage of women musicians in early freak folk and contrast these to critical reports of other female musicians in the folk milieu, and to predominantly male psychedelic folk ensembles. I hold that the discourse surrounding women in folk/psychedelic folk reveals the workings of gendered aesthetic language. In contrast to the coverage of male artists—who may have displayed similar musical experimentation—I suggest that female artists in 1960s/70s Britain and North America were held up against heightened standards of respectability, and received far less encouragement to push against musical convention. Later in the 2000s, Bunyan' work (like that of other female freak folk musicians in her field) re-emerged to attract critical appraisal and a niche audience. In all, I examine various factors contributing to this disjointed reception history, centering my analysis on gender, the press, and shifting attitudes toward women in experimental folk.</description><description>Le journaliste musical Jude Rogers a observé qu'à l'aube du vingt-et-unième siècle, la musique folk excentrique de la fin des années 1960 était de nouveau convoitée (2008). Rogers explique que l'intérêt renouvelé pour cette « musique folk excentrique » est dû en partie à la réédition de Just Another Diamond Day de Vashti Bunyan, initialement sorti en 1970 et ensuite resorti en 2000. Le « psychédélique », « le folk excentrique », ou « freak » - comme la musique de Bunyan est maintenant étiquetée - de la fin des années 60 et du début des années 70 en Amérique du Nord et en Europe occidentale a récemment été célébré malgré son manque de succès commercial dans les années 60/70. Freak folk est ainsi passé d'un genre pratiquement ignoré au moment de son émergence à un genre qui a attiré un marché de niche. J'examine la réception du folk excentrique afin de mieux comprendre sa résurgence et sa pertinence pour le paysage musical populaire contemporain. En outre, considérant que les artistes folkloriques ont été à prédominance féminine, je vais considérer la manière dont l'identité de genre de ces artistes a façonné l'histoire de la réception ce cette musique.Suivant la trajectoire de la réception de Bunyan, je postule qu'il y a une augmentation de réception idéologique dans la musique populaire pour l'esthétique progressive des musiciens féminins que durant les années 60/70. Je soutiens que cela explique en partie la résurgence contemporaine de folk excentrique. Pour en arriver à cette conclusion, j'analyse la couverture médiatique de femmes musiciennes au début du vingtième siècle et les compares aux critiques d'autres musiciennes du milieu populaire et aux ensembles folkloriques à prédominance masculine. Je considère que le discours sur les femmes dans le folk / psychédélisme révèle le fonctionnement du langage esthétique sexué. Contrairement à la couverture des artistes masculins, qui ont peut-être fait preuve d'une expérimentation musicale similaire, les femmes britanniques et nord-américaines des années 60/70 ont été confrontées à des normes élevées de respectabilité et ont reçu beaucoup moins d'encouragements contre les conventions musicales. Plus tard dans les années 2000, le travail de Bunyan, comme celui d'autres musiciens folkloriques dans son domaine, a refait surface pour attirer une évaluation critique et un public de niche. En résumé, j'examine divers facteurs contribuant à cette histoire de réception désarticulée, centrant mon analyse sur le genre, la presse et les attitudes changeantes à l'égard des femmes dans le monde expérimental.</description><creator>Smith Blackburn, Kaiya</creator><contributor>David Brackett (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Music</subject><title>A long-awaited Diamond Day: examining the reception history of freak folk</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75rb075.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hm505</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9880vt12r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction : Une iléostomie de protection est la méthode chirurgicale la plus fréquemment utilisée pour la dérivation intestinale, parce que ça réduit le risque d'une fuite anastomotique du colon ou rectum ainsi que ces séquelles. Cependant, une deuxième opération est nécessaire afin de restaurer la continuité intestinale. L'iléus postopératoire est la complication la plus importante après la fermeture de l'iléostomie. L'objectif de cette thèse était d'identifier l'incidence et les indicateurs d'iléus postopératoire après la fermeture de l'iléostomie, de développer et valider un modèle prédictif pour l'iléus postopératoire après la fermeture de l'iléostomie, et de décrire une nouvelle intervention pour réduire l'iléus postopératoire après la fermeture de l'iléostomie.Méthode : Une revue systématique était réalisée pour identifier l'incidence et les indicateurs d'iléus postopératoire après la fermeture de l'iléostomie. Une méta-analyse était réalisée pour déterminer l'incidence groupée d'iléus postopératoire après la fermeture de l'iléostomie, et les analyses stratifiées étaient réalisées pour identifier l'impact de la définition d'iléus postopératoire sur l'incidence. Une analyse des dossiers médicaux était réalisée pour identifier un groupe de patients qui subissaient une fermeture de l'iléostomie dans deux hôpitaux universitaires. Ce groupe était utilisée pour développer un modelé prédictif pour l'iléus postopératoire. Le modèle final était le modèle avec la zone sous la courbe la plus haute, et le calibrage du modèle était évalué avec le test de l'ajustement Hosmer-Lemeshow. Le modèle final était validé à l'extérieur dans un groupe indépendant des patients similaires qui subissaient une fermeture de l'iléostomie dans un autre hôpital tertiaire universitaire. Enfin, un protocole d'un essai contrôlé randomisé pour évaluer l'effet de la stimulation intestinale préopératoire afin de réduire l'iléus postopératoire après la fermeture de l'iléostomie était décrit. Résultats : Soixante-sept études avec 9,528 patients ont étaient inclues dans la revue systématique et la méta-analyse. L'incidence groupée d'iléus postopératoire était 8.0% (intervalle de confiance [IC] 95% 6.9-9.3% ; I2=74%). L'incidence d'iléus postopératoire dépends de sa définition : les études avec une définition robuste ont eu l'incidence la plus haute (12.4%, IC 95% 9.2-16.5% ; I2=79%) et les études sans définitions précises ont eu l'incidence la plus base (6.7%, IC 95% 5.3-8.3% ; I2=61%). La revue systématique a identifié l'anastomose manuelle (contre une anastomose mécanique) ainsi qu'un délais plus long entre la création et la fermeture d'iléostomie comme étant les indicateurs les plus souvent associés avec l'iléus postopératoire. Néanmoins, la plupart des études n'étaient pas construit dans le but d'évaluer l'iléus postopératoire. L'incidence d'iléus postopératoire dans notre groupe de 531 patients qui subissaient une fermeture de l'iléostomie était 16.8%. Le modèle prédictif avec la zone sous la courbe la plus haute avait cinq facteurs : l'âge, le risque opératif de la Société d'Anesthésiologiste Américaine, le diagnostic et son traitement, la durée de la période entre la création et la fermeture d'iléostomie, et la durée de l'opération pour la fermeture de l'iléostomie (zone sous la courbe = 0.68, IC 95% 0.61-0.74). La validation à l'extérieur a montré une bonne performance (zone sous la courbe = 0.72, IC 95% 0.63-0.81) et calibrage (p=0.53).Conclusions : L'iléus postopératoire est une complication importante après la fermeture de l'iléostomie du point de vue de sa fréquence et l'impact sur le patient. J'ai développé et validé le premier modèle prédictif pour l'iléus postopératoire après la fermeture de l'iléostomie, et j'ai décrit une nouvelle intervention pour réduire l'iléus postopératoire après la fermeture de l'iléostomie.</description><description>Introduction: Loop ileostomies are the most common surgical method of fecal diversion, and are constructed to protect a distal colonic or rectal anastomosis. Loop ileostomies have been shown to decrease both the rate and sequelae of anastomotic leak; however, they come at the cost of requiring a second operation to restore intestinal continuity. Among all postoperative morbidities observed after loop ileostomy closure, postoperative ileus (POI) is the most clinically significant. The overall goal of this thesis was to identify the incidence and predictors of POI after loop ileostomy closure, to develop and validate a prediction model for POI after loop ileostomy closure, and to describe a novel intervention to reduce POI after loop ileostomy closure. Methods: A systematic review was performed to examine the prevalence of POI among patients who underwent loop ileostomy closure and identify potential risk factors for its occurrence. A meta-analysis was performed to determine the pooled incidence of POI after loop ileostomy closure, and stratified analyses were used to identify the impact of POI definition on the estimate of POI incidence. Chart review was then performed to identify a cohort of patients that underwent loop ileostomy closure at two university-affiliated hospitals. This cohort was used to develop a prediction model for POI. Model selection was based on the highest area under the receiver operating curve (AUC), and model calibration was assessed with the Hosmer-Lemeshow goodness-of-fit test. The final model was then externally validated using an independent cohort of similar patients from another university-affiliated hospital. Finally, a study protocol for a randomized controlled trial evaluating the use of preoperative bowel stimulation before loop ileostomy closure to reduce POI was described. Results: Sixty-seven studies including 9,528 patients were included in the systematic review and meta-analysis. The pooled estimate of POI was 8.0% (95% confidence interval [CI] 6.9-9.3%; I2=74%). The estimate of POI varied by definition: studies with a robust definition for POI (n=8) demonstrated the highest estimate of POI (12.4%, 95% CI 9.2-16.5%; I2=79%) while studies that did not explicitly report a definition (n=38) demonstrated the lowest estimate (6.7%, 95% CI 5.3-8.3%; I2=61%). The systematic review revealed that hand-sewn small bowel anastomosis technique and a longer intersurgery length (defined as the time, in days, from ileostomy creation to ileostomy closure) were the factors most commonly associated with POI after loop ileostomy closure. However, most studies were underpowered and had not aimed to study POI. The incidence of POI in our development cohort of 531 patients who underwent loop ileostomy closure was 16.7%. The final prediction model with the highest AUC included five variables: age, American Society of Anaesthesiologists score, underlying pathology / treatment, intersurgery length, and ileostomy closure operative time (AUC=0.68, 95% CI 0.61-0.74). On external validation, the model maintained good discrimination (AUC=0.72, 95% CI 0.63-0.81) and calibration (p=0.53). Conclusions: POI is a clinically important complication after loop ileostomy closure in terms of frequency and impact. I have developed and validated the first prediction model for POI after loop ileostomy closure, and described a novel intervention to reduce POI after loop ileostomy closure.</description><creator>Garfinkle, Richard</creator><contributor>Marylise Boutros (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Kristian Filion (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Epidemiology and Biostatistics</subject><title>Bowel recovery after loop ileostomy closure: Can we predict failure and is there room for intervention?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g7322.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vt12r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54kq39p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>DNA repair is of particular importance in the rapidly-dividing progenitor cells of developing organs. Unrepaired damage in these cells may disrupt embryonic development and be propagated throughout an entire cell lineage of the adult organ. We hypothesize that specific DNA repair programs are activated during embryogenesis to protect the genome in this critical phase and that, in the developing kidney, a panel of DNA repair genes are activated to accompany the burst of cell division during nephrogenesis. Furthermore, we hypothesize that activation of a subset of the DNA repair genes in nephron progenitor cells (NPCs) is elicited by Wilms Tumor 1 (WT1) and therefore loss of WT1 might compromise DNA repair in the developing kidney. Loss of WT1 from NPCs is known to cause clones of developmentally-arrested cells that carry a high risk of acquiring activating mutations of the CTNNB1 gene. Constitutive CTNNB1 activation is associated with malignant transformation into a Wilms tumor. However, the mechanism underlying this apparent genomic instability of NPCs, following loss of WT1, is unknown. In this project, we quantified the expression of 84 DNA repair genes in embryonic versus adult mouse kidney. We identified 7 genes with a 20-fold or greater upregulation in the embryo compared to the adult. To isolate NPCs from the embryonic mouse kidney, we used a transgenic mouse model consisting of Cited1-driven Cre recombinase crossed with a tdTomato reporter strain. Using Reverse Transcription quantitative Polymerase Chain Reaction (RT-qPCR), we showed that expression of the DNA repair gene Neil3 was 15-fold higher in NPCs compared to total kidney. When we examined Neil3 expression in another rapidly-dividing embryonic kidney lineage, the Hoxb7/GFP-tagged ureteric bud lineage, we saw no enrichment relative to total kidney. We adapted our Cited1-driven Cre recombinase system to allow isolation of NPCs carrying an inducible Wt1 knockout mutation. Using RT-qPCR, we confirmed that enrichment of Neil3 in NPCs with conditional ablation of Wt1 was reduced by 60% compared to NPCs with wildtype Wt1. We propose that WT1-mediated activation of a DNA repair program that may include Neil3 is critical for maintaining genomic stability in rapidly-proliferating NPCs. Loss of this DNA repair activity could contribute to development of the activating mutations driving Wilms tumor.   </description><description>La réparation de l'ADN est particulièrement importante pour les cellules progénitrices qui se divisent rapidement pour former les organes. Les dommages qui n'ont pas été réparées dans ces cellules peuvent perturber le développement embryonnaire et être propagées à travers tout l'organe. Notre hypothèse est que des programmes de réparation d'ADN sont activés durant l'embryogénèse afin de protéger le génome durant cette phase cruciale. Lors du développement rénal, une panoplie de gènes de réparation de l'ADN est activée pendant la période de division rapide de la néphrogénèse. De plus, nous proposons qu'il y a un sous-ensemble des gènes responsables de la réparation de l'ADN qui est activé dans les cellules rénales progénitrices (NPCs) et que celui-ci dépend du gène suppresseur de tumeur de Wilms, WT1.  Nous formulons l'hypothèse que la perte de WT1 compromet l'activation du système de réparation de l'ADN qui protège normalement les NPCs. La perte de WT1 dans les NPCs génère des clones de cellules dont le développement a été interrompu. Ces clones ont un risque élevé d'incorporation des mutations activantes du gène CTNNB1. L'activation constante de ce dernier est associée à la transformation maligne en tumeur de Wilms. Le mécanisme qui sous-tend cette apparente instabilité génomique des NPCs, suivant la perte de WT1, est inconnu. Dans cette étude, nous quantifions l'expression de 84 gènes de réparation de l'ADN dans les reins embryonnaires et adultes, chez la souris. Nous avons identifié 7 gènes dont l'expression était au moins 20 fois plus élevée dans embryon que dans adulte. Pour isoler les NPCs, nous avons utilisé un modèle de souris transgénique dont la Cre recombinase est contrôlée par le promoteur de Cited1 croisé avec une lignée de souris qui possèdent le gène rapporteur tdTomato. En utilisant la réaction en chaîne de la polymérase de transcription inverse quantitative (RT-qPCR), nous avons observé que l'expression du gêne de réparation Neil3 était 15 fois plus élevé dans les NPCs par rapport au rein dans son ensemble. Lorsque nous avons examiné l'expression de Neil3 dans une autre lignée cellulaire de reins embryonnaires dérivée du bourgeon urétéral marquée par Hoxb7/GFP, nous n'avons pas  observé une telle augmentation. Nous avons adapté notre système Cited-1/Cre recombinase afin de permettre l'isolation de NPCs qui possèdent une mutation knock-out inductible de Wt1. En utilisant la RT-qPCR, nous avons confirmé que l'enrichissement de Neil3 dans NPCs avec l'ablation conditionnelle de Wt1 est réduit de 60% par rapport aux NPCs sans l'ablation. Nous proposons que l'activation du programme de réparation de l'ADN dépendant de WT1, qui peut inclure Neil3, est critique pour maintenir une stabilité génomique dans les NPCs en prolifération rapide. La perte de cette activité de réparation de l'ADN peut contribuer au développement des mutations activantes qui causent les tumeurs de Wilms.</description><creator>Hammond, Leah</creator><contributor>Paul Rowland Goodyer (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Human Genetics</subject><title>DNA repair in kidney development and Wilms tumor</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cz87f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kq39p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5h73pz270</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nous avons effectué des calculs 3+1D d'hydrodynamique visceuse de collisions d'un système proton-plomb (p-Pb) et d'un système plomb-plomb (Pb-Pb) à haute énergie du LHC (Grand collisionneur de hadrons). Nous avons démontré que les données des événements p-Pb à haute multiplicité peuvent être décrites par un modèle hydrodynamique. Nous avons suggéré un test plus rigoureux de l'applicabilité de la théorie hydrodynamique à de petits systèmes, en étudiant la dépendance de corrélation de paires de particules. Nous avons calculé un observable approprié, ??ₙ, et avons fait des prédictions sur sa valeur et sa dépendance de centralité. Ces prédictions ont été confirmées par la suite. Cela suggère que nous avons correctement décrit la nature de la corrélation constatée dans les petits systèmes de collision, et fournit un outil permettant de déterminer à partir d'où la description hydrodynamique n'est plus valide. Enfin, nous avons examiné ce que l'on pouvait apprendre de ??ₙ, en découvrant que, contrairement à la plupart observables communément considérés, ??ₙ est moins sensible à la viscosité qu'aux aspects de l'état initial du système, comme l'échelle de longueur transverse des fluctuations.</description><description>We performed 3+1D viscous hydrodynamic calculations of proton-lead (p-Pb) and lead-lead (Pb-Pb) collisions at top LHC (Large Hadron Collider) energy. We show that existing data from high-multiplicity p-Pb events can be well described in hydrodynamics. %, suggesting that collective flow is plausible as a correct description of these collisions. We proposed a more stringent test of the hydrodynamic behavior in small systems by studying the detailed momentum dependence of two-particle correlations. We calculated a relevant observable, ??ₙ, and made predictions for its value and centrality dependence. These predictions were subsequently confirmed. This provides a non-trivial confirmation of the nature of the correlations seen in small collision systems, and a tool for determining where the hydrodynamic description stops being valid. Lastly, we probed what can be learned from ??ₙ, finding that, contrary to most of the commonly considered observables, it is less sensitive to viscosity than to the aspects of the initial state of the system, such as the transverse length scale of the fluctuations. </description><creator>Kozlov, Igor</creator><contributor>Charles Gale (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Physics</subject><title>Exploring the collective behavior of small collision systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343v250.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73pz270</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77ft730</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'« affaire Lavalette » a frappé Paris pendant l'été 1761.  Causée par le père Antoine Lavalette, un prêtre Jésuite à la Martinique, il s'agit du premier d'une série de scandales coloniaux arrivant à Paris à la fin de la Guerre de Sept Ans et menant ultimement à l'expulsion des Jésuites de France en 1764.  Avant la guerre, Lavalette avait créé un réseau d'échanges de capitaux pour des sujets colonials qui avaient besoin d'envoyer de l'argent en France.  Le réseau s'effendre au commencement de la guerre menant ses créanciers à chercher justice dans un procès auprès de la juridiction consulaire.  Cette thèse aborde des activités commerciales de Lavalette dans le contexte globale de la Compagnie de Jésus afin d'interroger la teneur de ces activités commerciales considérés comme acceptables pour les ecclésiastiques.  Elle examine comment Lavalette a utilisé la circulation des denrées et le langage du « crédit » afin d'emprunter plus de 2 millions de livres.  Cette recherche discoute aussi les efforts des créanciers afin de traiter la Société de Jésus comme une société des marchands ainsi sujette à la juridiction consulaire.  Finalement, cette thèse raconte les efforts de Lavalette pour maintenir sa solvabilité pendant la Guerre de Sept Ans ansi que la victoire de ses supérieurs Jésuites afin de mettre fin à ses activités commerciales.        </description><description>The "Lavalette Affair" rocked Paris in the spring of 1761.  Caused by a Jesuit priest on Martinique, Fr. Antoine Lavalette, it was the first of several colonial scandals to hit the French public sphere in the wake of the Seven Years War and the spark which led to the Jesuits' 1764 expulsion from France.  During the interwar years, Lavalette had created a currency exchange network for colonial subjects looking to transfer their money back to France without losing value from the lopsided transatlantic exchange rate.  This network collapsed at the onset of the war, leading his creditors to seek redress from the French courts.  This dissertation contextualizes Lavalette's activities within the Society of Jesus' global presence to determine how his activities fit the acceptable actions for priests.  It examines how Lavalette used transatlantic flows of commodities and the language of credit to borrow over 2 million livres.  This research discusses how Lavalette's creditors attempted to treat the Society of Jesus as a merchant house (société) under the jurisdiction of merchant courts.  Finally, this thesis recounts Lavalette's efforts to stay afloat during the Seven Years War and the ultimately successful efforts of the Jesuit superiors to shut him down.  </description><creator>Dial, Andrew</creator><contributor>Allan Greer (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Catherine Desbarats (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>History and Classical Studies</subject><title>The "Lavalette Affair": Jesuits and money in the French Atlantic</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j96023275.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77ft730</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History and Classical Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn00b114c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:03:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'utilisation des technologies numériques à des fins personnelles sur le lieu de travail est devenue un sujet controversé dans plusieurs milieux de travail à travers le monde. Les employeurs•e•s tendent à traiter cet usage d'Internet comme du relâchement, du « temps volé », et du sabotage. Pour les employé•e•s, l'usage d'Internet à des fins personnelles peut permettre de s'occuper d'affaires familiales ; de prendre une pause au milieu d'une journée de travail intense et de passer d'une tâche de travail à une autre. Plusieurs chercheuses et chercheurs se sont penché•e•s sur la question du lien entre cette utilisation d'Internet à des fins personnelles au travail et ses conséquences sur la productivité, mais peu se sont interrogé•e•s sur les facteurs encourageant ses différents types d'utilisation. Le but de cette thèse est d'interroger les indicateurs qui permettent d'expliquer comment les différents groupes d'employé•e•s utilisent au travail les technologies numériques à des fins personnelles et comment le justifient-il•elle•s. Afin de répondre à cette question, j'utilise la démarche de recherche à méthodes mixtes dans laquelle j'ajoute 30 entrevues approfondies semi-structurées à un sondage auprès de 654 employé•e•s au Canada, en Suède, en Grande-Bretagne et aux États-Unis. Les résultats démontrent que les caractéristiques sociodémographiques, ainsi que les caractéristiques professionnelles importent lorsqu'il s'agit de quantifier et de définir l'usage d'Internet à des fins personnelles au travail. Les jeunes employé•e•s, ainsi que les travailleur•euse•s contractuel•le•s, c'est-à-dire celles et ceux qui sont en situation de précarité d'emploi, ont davantage tendance à s'adonner de manière importante à utiliser l'Internet au travail à des fins personnelles. L'utilisation augmentée d'Internet à des fins personnelles au travail par les femmes est motivée par leurs perspectives d'emploi incertaines, tandis que ce qui explique la même activité chez les hommes c'est la très grande flexibilité d'emploi. Rien ne semble indiquer que les employé•e•s utilisent Internet à des fins personnelles au travail comme moyen de sabotage. Plutôt c'est la distribution inégale des tâches au travail — qui caractérise les emplois  à court terme axés sur des projets où des périodes de travail calmes peuvent être suivies de périodes de travail très intenses — ce qui encourage ce type de comportement.Cette dissertation contribue de diverses manières à la littérature scientifique sur l'utilisation d'Internet à des fins personnelles au travail. Premièrement, tandis que la plupart des études antérieures sur le sujet se sont intéressées principalement à savoir comment les conditions structurelles facilitaient ou empêchaient l'utilisation d'Internet à des fins personnelles au travail, la présente recherche cherche à comprendre comment les caractéristiques et les motivations au niveau individuel et au niveau du groupe interagissent avec le cadre structurel. Deuxièmement, les études portant sur le sujet se sont intéressées à des cas particuliers (pays et entreprises), tandis que la présente recherche offre une perspective comparative en étudiant les dynamiques d'utilisation d'Internet à des fins personnelles dans quatre économies fortement développées, c'est-à-dire le Canada, la Suède, la Grande-Bretagne et les États-Unis. Finalement, puisque le travail ne structure pas uniquement notre temps et nos activités quotidiennes, mais qu'il définit aussi nos identités et nos aspirations, cette dissertation apporte des connaissances sur les conséquences de processus tels que la numérisation du travail et l'essor des emplois non linéaires axés sur des projets sur la compréhension et l'opinion des travailleurs et des travailleuses contemporain•e•s sur la conciliation travail-vie personnelle.</description><description>The use of digital technologies for personal purposes in the workplace has become a contentious issue in many workplaces around the world. Employers tend to treat personal Internet use at work (PIUW) as slacking, "time theft", and sabotage. For the employees, PIUW can be a way to take care of important family matters, to take a break in the middle of an intensive workday, and to switch from one job task to another. While the relationship between PIUW and productivity has been extensively studied, the factors that motivate different types of personal Internet use at work remain an uncharted territory. The central question of this thesis is which predictors explain how different groups of employees engage in and justify the use of digital technologies for personal purposes in the workplace. In order to answer this question, I use a mixed methods approach combining a survey of 654 employees with 30 semi-structured in-depth interviews in Canada, Sweden, the U.K. and the U.S.A. The results show that both socio-demographic and occupational characteristics matter when it comes to the quantity and the quality of personal Internet use at work. Younger employees, as well as those who work on projects and experience job precarity, are more likely to engage in high levels of PIUW. Women's PIUW is motivated by uncertain job prospects, whereas men's use of digital technologies for personal purposes can be explained by high levels of job flexibility. Furthermore, restrictive policies on PIUW have a significant effect on the personal online activities associated with networking and communication but not on entertainment-oriented PIUW. Finally, there is little evidence that employees use PIUW as a means of intentional sabotage. Rather, the uneven distribution of work tasks that characterizes project-based employment, where periods of little or no work are suddenly followed by intensive labor, is partly motivating this behavior. This dissertation makes several contributions. First, while most previous studies in this area focused on how structural conditions facilitated and/or curtailed PIUW, this work focuses on how individual-level and group-level characteristics and motivations interact with structural arrangements. More specifically, I explore how interactions between gender, age, and occupational status within organizations affect the extent of PIUW, and whether different groups of workers tend to engage in different kinds of "non-productive" online activities. Second, while previous research has focused on individual cases (specific countries and companies), this work offers a comparative perspective by investigating the dynamics of PIUW in four highly developed economies (Canada, Sweden, the U.K. and the U.S.A.). This comparison explains the effects of different labor contexts and more general cultural contexts over workers' engagement in "non-productive" workplace activities. Finally, since labor not only structures our time and everyday activities but also defines our identities and aspirations, this dissertation also provides insights into the effects of processes such as the digitization of work and the rise in non-linear, project-based employment on contemporary workers' understanding of and views about their work-life balance.</description><creator>Miltsov, Alexandre</creator><contributor>Eran Shor (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Sociology</subject><title>Slacking, resisting, withdrawing? A comparative study of personal internet use at work</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g9645.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b114c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):3575</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>