<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:30:33Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):35300" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j3332766</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Aguaruna Indigenous People live along the Rio Cenepa in the  Peruvian Amazon. This thesis describes the Aguaruna traditional food system (TFS)  and defines its nutritional importance. Nutritional status of women and young  children were assessed using anthropometry. Dietary intakes and dietary diversity  were recorded using repeat 24 hour recalls. Subsequently, the relative nutrient  contributions of local foods were analyzed. A market survey was conducted to compare  the nutrient value and relative cost of seasonal local foods with imported products.  Anthropometry suggested a healthy population, although the Agauruna had short  stature. They purchased &lt;1 % of their food, and group dietary assessments  estimated adequate intakes of energy, protein, fat, iron, zinc, vitamin C and  vitamin A. Higher traditional food diversity was associated with greater  macronutrient, vitamin and mineral intakes (Spearman's rho = 0.29 to r = 0.60). The  Aguaruna TFS provides excellent nutrition and should be promoted and  protected.</description><creator>Roche, Marion Leslie</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Aguaruna Indians -- Peru -- Nutrition.</subject><subject>Aguaruna Indians -- Food -- Peru.</subject><title>Traditional food, dietary diversity and nutritional status of the Aguaruna in the Peruvian Amazon</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375w88c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j3332766</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20st098</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The protein synthesis inhibitors cycloheximide and anisomycin  were administered during training in an attempt to block the consolidation of the  memory for a morphine conditioned place preference. The systemic injection of  2.5mg/kg of cycloheximide post-training failed to block consolidation, though there  was a trend towards an attenuated preference, however cycloheximide produced a  conditioned place aversion if paired with one compartment. To examine the effect of  more complete protein synthesis inhibition and reduce the aversive effects, the less  toxic protein synthesis inhibitor anisomycin was infused into the lateral ventricles  of the brain either pre-, post- or 3 hours following training. Post-training  infusions of anisomycin blocked the formation of a conditioned place preference,  while pre-training and 3 hours post-training infusions showed no significant effect  over two conditioning pairings. It was concluded that drug conditioning in the place  preference paradigm requires protein synthesis for memory consolidation as do other  learning paradigms.</description><creator>Robinson, Michael, 1980-</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Memory.</subject><subject>Memory -- Physiological aspects.</subject><title>Memory consolidation for a morphine conditioned place preference blocked by protein synthesis inhibition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r852k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20st098</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h497t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Obstructive sleep apnea (OSA) is a disease process characterized  by collapse of the upper airway during periods of sleep leading to the cessation  airflow despite persistent respiratory efforts. The aim of this research project is  to investigate for associations and correlations between OSA and other clinical  entities using two separate prospective studies. The initial objective was to  evaluate the prevalence of laryngopharyngeal reflux (LPR) in patients with OSA. LPR  was present in 26/28 (93%) of OSA patients. Moreover, there were significant  correlations between LPR and OSA severity (eg. r = 0.57, p = 0.001). The second  objective of this research study was to determine the prevalence of OSA in patients  with cancer of the oral cavity and oropharynx, and to correlate the presence of OSA  and the occurrence of postoperative morbidities. OSA was present in 76% of patients.  Overall, postoperative complications were observed in 67% of OSA and 25% of non-OSA  patients, although this difference was not yet significant (p = 0.27, Fisher exact  test).</description><creator>Payne, Richard J., 1973-</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Upper airway dysfunction in obstructive sleep apnea and its relationship to laryngopharyngeal reflux and postoperative morbidities in cancer of the oral cavity and cancer of the oropharynx</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752h270.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h497t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Otolaryngology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s4655h192</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The verification of VLSI circuits, which are ever increasing in  size and complexity, is bottlenecked during simulation within the circuit design  process. Distributed simulation on a cluster of workstations or a shared memory  multiple processor computer attempts a cost-effective solution. The key factor in  performance of these simulations is the development of distributed simulation  algorithms that make use of the circuits' underlying properties. This study presents the design and implementation of a  distributed simulation framework to better produce and test simulation algorithms.  The framework includes a technique to generate circuits, since large commercial  circuits are hard to obtain, a Verilog compiler, and a simulator template to ease  implementation.</description><creator>Pekofsky, Gregory</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>GCS : a framework for distributed verilog simulation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mg04j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655h192</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05fc138</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This project was designed to investigate the impact of natural  levels of ultraviolet-B radiation on the genomic mutation rate in Arabidopsis  thaliana. UV-B radiation is a known mutagen, but plants may have evolved mechanisms  to cope with any genomic damage induced by routine exposure to this radiation. In an  attempt to determine whether the genomic mutation rate in a plant species is  elevated in the presence of UV-B, two eleven generation mutation accumulation  studies were preformed. One study incorporated levels of UV-B similar to that  encountered on a clear mid-summer's day, while the other was performed in the  absence of this mutagen. Mutation rate estimates, obtained primarily from maximum  likelihood analysis of phenotypic data, were not significantly greater than zero,  both in the presence and absence of UV-B. No evidence was found to support the  notion that the genomic mutation rate is increased by exposure to natural levels of  UV-B.</description><creator>MacKenzie, Joanna Leigh</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Arabidopsis thaliana -- Effect of ultraviolet radiation on</subject><subject>Arabidopsis thaliana -- Genetics</subject><subject>Plant mutation</subject><title>The effects of ultraviolet-B radiation on mutational parameters in Arabidopsis thaliana /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462603n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fc138</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c804b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In criminal investigations involving glass evidence, refractive  index (RI) is the property of glass most commonly used by forensic examiners to  determine the association between control samples of glass obtained at the crime  scene, and samples of glass found on a suspect. Previous studies have shown that an  intrinsic variability of RI exists within a pane of float glass. In this thesis, we  attempt to determine whether this variability is spatially determined or random in  nature, the conclusion of which plays an important role in the statistical  interpretation of glass evidence. We take a Bayesian approach in fitting a spatial  model to our data, and utilize the WinBUGS software to perform Gibbs sampling. To  test for spatial variability, we propose two test quantities, and employ Bayesian  Monte Carlo significance tests to test our data, as well as nine other specifically  formulated data-sets.</description><creator>Maimon, Geva</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Statistics.</subject><title>A Bayesian spatial analysis of glass data /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j619g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c804b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6q182k673</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In vitro, les myotubes diaphragmatiques expriment de façon constitutive CCR1, le récepteur de la famille des chemokines C-C. Il a été démontré que CCR1 et son ligand, CCL3 (MIP-1α), sont directement impliqués dans le processus de la réparation musculaire in vitro. De plus, des études in vivo dans la souris MDX ont démontré que l'expression de ces molécules augmente dans le diaphragme dystrophique. Ceci suggère un rôle pour CCR1 dans l'inflammation et la réparation musculaire. Dans cette étude, le rôle de CCR1 a été étudié avec un focus sur l'infiltration des cellules dans le muscle blessé suite à une blessure par congélation dans le modèle animal. Cette étude suggère qu'il n'y a aucune différence dans la réparation musculaire et l'infiltration cellulaire entre la souris CCR1 -/- et le contrôle. De plus, il n'y a aucune différence significative dans la force musculaire entre ces deux modèles à 3,7 et 14 jours suite à la blessure. L'étude individuelle des populations cellulaires (macrophages, cellules T CD4+ et CD8+) n'a montré aucune différence significative. Nos résultats suggèrent que malgré le rôle de CCR1 dans la prolifération et la migration de myoblastes in vitro, CCR1 n'est pas implique dans cette régénération post-traumatique in vivo. </description><description>Diaphragmatic myotubes are known to constitutively express CCR1, a chemokine receptor in the C-C chemokine family, when cultured in vitro. It has been shown that CCR1 and its ligand CCL3 (MIP-1α) are directly involved in muscle repair responses in vitro. Furthermore, in vivo experiments, carried out in the MDX mouse model of muscular dystrophy, showed that these molecules were up-regulated in the dystrophic diaphragm muscle thus suggesting a role for CCR1 in inflammation and muscle healing. In this study, indeed, the role of CCR1 was investigated, with focus on inflammatory cell infiltration within the injured muscle using the freeze injury murine model. This study suggested that there is no significant difference in muscle regeneration or infiltration between CCR1-/- mice and their wild-type controls. There was also no difference in the muscle force between the knockout and their controls at 3, 7, and 14 days post injury. Investigation of individual infiltrating cell (macrophage, CD4 T-cells, CD8 T-cells) populations in the injured tissue yielded no significant difference. These data suggest that, although CCR1 has been found to play a role in myoblast proliferation and migration in vitro, it does not seem to have any apparent effect on muscle regeneration in vivo in the context of the freeze-injury model.</description><creator>Yim, Hoi Wing</creator><contributor>Basil Petrof (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery</subject><title>The role of C-C chemokine receptor 1 in skeletal muscle regeneration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xf815.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182k673</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17ct49s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les composés volatiles et semi-volatiles organiques de sources anthropogéniques sont des polluants atmosphériques participant à la formation d'ozone troposphérique. Nous avons associé l'adsorption et la photolyse par rayons ultraviolets, pour enlever et détruire ces composés. Nous avons synthétisé des nanoparticules de magnétite, un matériel abondant dans la nature, afin d'éviter la création d'un autre problème de pollution comme il est parvenu avec l'utilisation des fluorocarbure chlorés. L'efficacité d'enlèvement par adsorption atteint un maximum de 98 % pour les composés aromatiques et un maximum de 30% pour les alcanes légers. Les particules ont été regénérées, caractérisées (MET, XRD, BET), et réutilisées; aucune baisse en efficacité d'enlèvement n'est notée. Les expériences de photolyse atteignent une réduction maximale de 30% pour les composés aromatiques et de 20% pour les alcanes légers. Sous nos conditions expérimentales, aucune amélioration n'est notée par l'association des deux processus (adsorption et photolyse). La réduction par adsorption est attribuée aux forces d'attraction London pour les alcanes et aux propriétés acides et basiques pour les aromatiques. La réduction par photolyse s'explique par la formation de radicaux réactifs.</description><description>Anthropogenic volatile organic compounds (VOCs) and semi-volatile organic (SVOCs) compounds are atmospheric pollutants contributing to the photochemical formation of tropospheric ozone. We combined adsorption and UV photolysis techniques for the removal and degradation of selected VOCs and SVOCs. For adsorption, we synthesized magnetite nanoparticles, a naturally occurring material, to avoid unknown detrimental impacts associated with new materials, as was the case with chlorofluorcarbons. The removal efficiency with magnetite was up to 98 % for aromatics, and 30% for light alkanes. Magnetite nanoparticles were regenerated, characterized (TEM, XRD, BET), and reused with no decrease in reported removal efficiencies. Photolysis alone removed up to 30% of aromatics, and less than 20% of light alkanes. The combination of adsorption, and photolysis did not improve the removal efficiency. Adsorption was attributed to London dispersion interactions for light alkanes, and to acid-base properties for aromatics. Reductions by photolysis were attributed to reactive radicals.</description><creator>Eltouny, Nermin</creator><contributor>Parisa A Ariya (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Chemistry - Analytical</subject><title>Reduction of anthropogenic volatile and semi-volatile organic compounds by nanomaterials and photolysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m717r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17ct49s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dw13t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this thesis is to design numerical algorithms  for estimation of linear discrete-time dynamic system models, which can be written  in the block-angular form. These models arise in some applications, such as  navigation or communication. The estimation problem for the standard linear  discrete-time dynamic systems usually can be solved by using the Kalman filter.  However, we realize that for our specific models applying the conventional Kalman  filter algorithms is not efficient or may cause numerical instability. In this  thesis, we present an approach of using the recursive least squares technique to  compute the estimates of the system states. Our approach is computationally  efficient because we take full account of the structures of the models and is  numerically reliable because we use orthogonal transformations in the  computation. The general approach is then extended to positioning problem. We  mainly consider the short-baseline relative positioning with combined code and  carrier-phase measurements in global positioning system. Because of much more  special structures existing in the mathematical models for positioning; we modify  the general approach to further utilize these structures for efficiency. Fixing the  integer ambiguity vector and handling its dimension change are also discussed.  Finally, the real data tests are given to demonstrate the effectiveness of our  algorithm.</description><creator>Huang, Mengjun, 1977-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><subject>Remote Sensing.</subject><title>Numerical methods for estimation of linear, discrete-time, dynamic systems in the block-angular form and applications in GPS</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gn786.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dw13t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v598m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of Total Skin Electron Therapy (TSET) is to deliver a  uniform dose to the patient's entire skin to a limited depth while sparing the body  organs. Due to the laborious commissioning process, it is helpful to use the Monte  Carlo (MC) method for the procedure and treatment planning. Calculations of  dosimetric quantities were performed with EGSnrc/BEAM MC codes as well as with the  fast MC code XVMC. The linac model for a 6 MeV Varian CL21EX accelerator was  established by measuring the electron focal spot size with a slit camera. Using this  measured focal spot value in our proposed divergent beam model, an improved result  for large field profiles can be achieved. Measured PDDs and profiles under standard  set-up and TSET conditions were compared to MC calculations. Overall, satisfactory  results were obtained except for simulations with an additional scattering filter,  suggesting the composition, density and dimensions of the filter need to be  confirmed.</description><creator>Huang, Vicky W.</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Biophysics, Medical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><subject>Physics, Radiation.</subject><title>Validation of total skin electron therapy by the Monte Carlo technique</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jp25k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v598m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj139248j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The highly conserved p24 family of proteins are abundant  components of the early secretory pathway, although their specific function remains  unclear. In the yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae, deletion of the eight members of  this family results in no marked phenotype, whereas in mice, deletion of a single  p24 family member, p23, results in embryonic lethality. In addition, in the fly  Drosophila melanogaster, two of the nine p24 proteins have been shown to be  necessary for dorsoventral patterning of the embryo. Here, I attempt to determine the function of these proteins by  finding new genetic interactors of the p24s using a synthetic genetic array (SGA)  analysis in yeast. 44 yeast non-essential genes, when deleted, were identified as  being synthetically lethal or sick with the p24s. Many of these interactors are  involved in the secretory pathway. To determine the causes of cell death or growth  reduction of the double deletion mutants, I studied their ability to secrete the ER  protein Kar2p. In many cases of these double deletion mutant strains, Kar2p  secretion was exacerbated compared to the p24 deletion alone. This may reflect the  loss of fidelity of the transport between the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) and the  Golgi apparatus as well as ER retention.</description><creator>Garneau, Edith</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Synthetic lethal relationships of the genes encoding the p24 family of proteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q6934.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139248j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qb98mg063</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents a new approach to recommender systems.  Previous recommender systems based on collaborative filtering typically solicit user  feedback on domain items as overall ratings which are then recorded as numeric  values. This paradigm limits the semantic richness of the user's interaction with  the system and the depth to which the system can understand user preferences. We  propose a new recommender system, Recommendz, which allows the user to comment not  only about the overall quality of the item but also about the quantity and quality  of features of the item. This allows the user to justify his or her ratings and  allows the system to compare users not only with respect to overall preference, but  also to compare the reasons behind those preferences. We have developed an implementation of our approach, and have  collected extensive empirical data based on movie ratings. We demonstrate the  effectiveness of our approach, and describe the details of the  implementation.</description><creator>Garden, Matthew</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>On the use of semantic feedback in recommender systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rf14z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mg063</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mj629</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sustainable parasite control in livestock depends on  anthelmintic drugs. The nematode Haemonchus contortus, the most important intestinal  parasite of sheep and goats has developed resistance to all classes of anthelmintics  including moxidectin, the most potent of the macrocyclic lactones. Pyrosequencing  was used to screen H. contortus laboratory and field strains for single nucleotide  polymorphisms (SNPs) associated with resistance in three genes, and determine their  involvement in field resistance to macrocyclic lactones. Specific SNPs increased in  frequency in ivermectin/moxidectin laboratory selected strains for all three genes.  These did not protect a resistant field strain from a field dose of ivermectin and  were not the major mechanism of resistance in the field strain. A gamma-aminobutyric  acid chloride receptor SNP may be a potential marker for moxidectin resistance in  the field. This study indicates results obtained from laboratory strains selected  with sub-therapeutic doses of drug may not reflect the situation in the  field.</description><creator>Galazzo, Daniel</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Drug resistance.</subject><subject>Haemonchus contortus -- Molecular genetics.</subject><subject>Anthelmintics.</subject><subject>Avermectins.</subject><subject>Chloride channels.</subject><title>A comparison of laboratory and field resistance to macrocyclic lactones in Haemonchus contortus /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hj643.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mj629</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:76537180x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We put strong constraints on Lorentz violation by studying the  inner structure of highly energetic protons. Our work is in direct continuation of  previous analysis based on dimensions 4, 5 and 6 Lorentz violating operators. Our  original contribution is due to the study of the inner structure of hadrons and  their relation with Lorentz violating operators. The strength of the constraints  arising from this new analysis should discourage us to propose new general theories  that are Lorentz violating.</description><creator>Gagnon, Olivier</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>Limits on Lorentz non-invariance from high energy cosmic rays</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sg88z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537180x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fh70f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Properly assembled elastic fibers play an important role in  providing skin with the properties of elasticity and resilience to allow for  considerable mobility, but the mechanisms involved in elastic fiber assembly remains  unknown. Fibulin-5 is an extracellular 66kDa glycoprotein synthesized and secreted  by fibroblasts in skin, and has the ability to bind to tropoelastin. This study  addresses (1) the role of fibulin-5 in the ultrastructure of elastic fibers in skin,  and (2) its function in the cutaneous mechanical properties by using wild type and  fibulin-5 null mice. In the first part, skin of fibulin-5 null mice as well as wild  type mice was investigated in order to gain insight into the function of fibulin-5  in elastic fiber assembly. Using light and electron microscopy, the dramatic defects  of dermal elastic fibers in the absence of fibulin-5 were analyzed. Interestingly,  in the immunoelectron microscopy for LOXL-1, an enzyme responsible for the elastin  cross-links, fibulin-5 null mouse skin exhibited similar immunoreactivity for LOXL-1  to wild type skin. Moreover, in the wild type skin, fibulin-5 localized to the  microfibril-elastin interface at the edges and within the elastic fiber. In the  second part of this study, the function of fibulin-5 in skin biomechanics was  studied in order to determine its role in skin strength and elasticity. By using  tensile tests, fibulin-5 null mouse skin was found to be significantly stiffer and  weaker than wild type skin. Taken together, the defective elastic fibers in the  absence of fibulin-5 suggest that fibulin-5 is involved in a secondary step of  cutaneous elastic fiber assembly and in the mechanical properties of adult mouse  skin.</description><creator>Choi, Jiwon, 1977-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>The role of fibulin-5 : in the ultrastructural and biomechanical properties of skin</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mv729.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fh70f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150j777</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Malaria is a worldwide disaster that is still killing two  million lives annually. The recent rise of the epidemic is mainly attributed to the  emergence of resistance to the most effective, affordable and safe antimalarial,  chloroquine. Unfortunately, neither the mechanism of action of these  4-aminoquinolines nor the basis of chloroquine resistance is well understood. It has  been noted that a known channel blocker, verapamil, is able to modulate chloroquine  resistance. In this study, a chemical biology approach was taken to gain  some light into these mechanisms. The design, synthesis and characterization of  fluorescent and photoreactive probes, analogues of chloroquine and verapamil, are  presented. These can be used in fluorescent microscopy and photoaffinity labeling  experiments to identify a putative chloroquine export protein, Plasmodium falciparum  chloroquine resistance transporter (PfCRT). As a result of the hemoglobin degradation pathway, the  liberated, toxic heme is sequestered by P. falciparum into an insoluble inert  crystal, hemozoin. Hemoglobin proteases knockout parasites were generated. Their  hemozoin was isolated, analyzed by synchrotron powder X-ray diffraction, and imaged  using scanning electron microscopy.</description><creator>Chatain, Guillaume C.</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Towards an understanding of hemozoin formation and chloroquine resistance in Plasmodium falciparum</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zb659.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150j777</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rp25s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the packaging industry, cushioning products are usually made  of plastic materials, such as polystyrene. The insulation and lightweight character  make it more popular and convenient to use. However, the extensive use of it creates  more waste leading to an environmental problem. Usually the cushioning foams are  discarded after being used for inbox protection as packaging material; eventually  they end up in a landfill. Most plastic foams are not biodegradable, which cannot be  composted and will create more and more waste that affects the ecological system. In  the mean time, foams made up of bio-degradable materials are considered. In general,  biodegradable plastics are starch-based or cellulose-based, and the biodegradable  components can be found in corn (e.g. corn starch, and corn cob). Instead of  extracting the corn component, here popped corn kernel will be investigated for its  suitability in packaging applications.</description><creator>Cheng, Hoi Po, 1975-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Popcorn.</subject><subject>Plastic foams.</subject><subject>Packaging -- Environmental aspects.</subject><title>Popcorn for cushioning purpose</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732d956b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rp25s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1j92g813g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recent studies have demonstrated that applied hydrostatic  pressure can affect the functional properties of whey protein isolate (WPI). In this  work, the effects of applied hydrostatic pressure on the tertiary and secondary  structure of whey proteins were investigated by spectroscopic and rheological  techniques to elucidate the molecular basis of such pressure-induced changes in  protein functionality. The individual protein components of WPI and various samples  of WPI obtained from different sources were subjected to different single-cycle  pressure treatments of up to 400 MPa in 100 MPa increments with 30-min holding time  as well as to pressures ranging from 450 to 650 MPa without a holding time.  Electrospray ionization-mass spectrometry, circular dichroism, and Fourier transform  Raman spectroscopic studies of pressure-treated samples of beta-lactoglobulin, the  major protein component of WPI, revealed significant changes in tertiary structure.  Fourier transform infrared spectroscopic studies revealed that the secondary  structure of beta-lactoglobulin was also sensitive to applied pressure and holding  time. The secondary and tertiary structure of alpha-lactalbumin, the second most  prevalent protein in WPI, was unaffected by applied hydrostatic pressure. The  spectroscopic behaviour of the various samples of WPI subjected to pressure  treatment was variable and indicated that the response of WPI to applied hydrostatic  pressure is dependent on the method used to isolate the WPI from whey. The  rheological profiles of beta-lactoglobulin, alpha-lactalbumin, and WPI samples after  various pressure treatments were also recorded. Both beta-lactoglobulin and WPI  exhibited marked increases in viscosity with increasing pressure, whereas  alpha-lactalbumin remained solutions exhibited no significant change in viscosity.  These studies have furthered the understanding of the effects of applied hydrostatic  pressure on the molecular structure and rheological pr</description><creator>Alvarez, Pedro</creator><date>2004</date><subject>High pressure (Technology)</subject><subject>Milk proteins.</subject><subject>Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy.</subject><subject>Whey.</subject><title>Effect of applied hydrostatic pressure on the structure and rheological properties of whey proteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vk62b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g813g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322d94h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The extreme susceptibility to infection with Salmonella  Typhimurium of wild-derived MOLF/Ei has been linked to one chromosomal region  (Ity3). Toll-like receptor 5 (Tlr5) is located within the Ity3 interval and its  candidacy as a Salmonella-susceptibility gene was evaluated in vitro and in vivo by  comparing the Tlr5 C57BL/6J and MOLF/Ei alleles (85). In vitro studies using  NF-kappaB-dependent reporter genes showed that sequence variants found within the  coding region of MOLF/Ei Tlr5 did not affect the response of Tlr5 to flagellin  compared to C57BL/6J. MOLF/Ei promoter had a slightly stronger basal activity than  the C57BL/6J allele. In vivo study using Ity3 congenic mice showed that mice  homozygous for MOLF/Ei allele at Ity3 had a stronger response to flagellin as  measured by IL-6 secretion in the serum. Finally, we can conclude that Tlr5 is  involved in the disease phenotype underlying Ity3 however, it is not clear if the  impact of Tlr5 is primary or secondary.</description><creator>Angers, Isabelle</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Validation of the candidacy of toll-like receptor 5 (Tlr5) as a Salmonella susceptibility gene</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930bx74m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322d94h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wm117p43h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis treats three topics in mechanics of helices, each  being covered in a separate part. The first part focuses on the determination of a  spectral (i.e., frequency dependent) finite element of a helix. The helix is treated  as a straight, linear elastic element, exhibiting coupling of axial with torsional  responses. Explicit forms of all the coefficients of the stiffness matrix are  derived and their dependencies on the frequency and the parameter describing the  said coupling are plotted. In general, the growth of that parameter leads to a  progressively denser occurrence of the resonances of both axial and torsional  motions. In the second part, mechanics of helically shaped elastic  strands is studied. Explicit forms of four constitutive coefficients of the helix  are derived according to the formulation of Costello (1990). By performing  parametric studies of the derived coefficients, it is shown that the coupling  coefficients relating axial with torsional responses are not in perfect agreement.  Thus, the reciprocity relations dictated by the Maxwell-Betti theorem are not  recovered exactly, whereby an improvement on the theory of Costello remains an open  challenge. In the third part, the viscoelastic response of the helix is  studied and its constitutive differential equations are derived by assuming three  specific types of viscoelastic models (Kelvin, Maxwell, or Zener) for a material at  the micro level. Solutions to these constitutive differential equations are  expressed for creep and relaxation behaviors of the helix. It is found that the  effective viscoelastic response of the helix is generally different, and more  complex in type than the material response of viscoelastic helical strands  themselves.</description><creator>Shahsavari, Hossein</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Topics in mechanics of helices</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278t580.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117p43h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj236257r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Birchtree is an ultramafic ore body and prior to 2003,  represented one third of the production for Inco's Thompson operation. The  ultramafic host rocks are high in MgO which, when processed through the smelter,  promotes problems in the roasters and converters due to the high liquidus  temperature. In October 2003, production from Birchtree mine ramped up to more than  half of the total feed to the mill. The mill cannot produce a suitable concentrate  for the smelter with current circuit configuration and operating practices. The  target for the mill was to produce a nickel concentrate with less than 3%  MgO. Continuous mini flotation cells were used to explore processing  options. Two campaigns were carried out. The first looked at rejecting the magnesium  silicate minerals with the use of reagents from the rougher and scavenger  concentrates. Reagents included sodium silicate, guar gum and two types of CMC.  Results indicated that current plant practice of CMC addition to the scavenger  circuit favours minimizing MgO grade in concentrate. The second campaign focused on rejecting MgO minerals from the  rougher-cleaner concentrate with the use of a dilute CMC solution. Flotation  retention time, CMC dosage rate, and conditioning time, were varied. Results  indicate that 0.1 g CMC per kilogram of solid in slurry produced a concentrate  grading &lt;3.0% MgO.</description><creator>Sedore, Laila</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>MgO rejection from Birchtree ore at Inco's Manitoba division</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bf502.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236257r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x196z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Verification of timing performance in integrated circuits (ICs)  is becoming more difficult as clock frequencies and levels of integration increase.  As a result, on-chip timing measurement has become a very attractive solution  because it helps to overcome the bandwidth and test access limitations inherent in  traditional off-chip test systems. Flash time-to-digital converters (TDCs) are well-suited for use  in on-chip timing measurement systems because they can be operated at high speeds,  offer low test time, and are relatively easy to integrate. However, clock jitter in  modern ICs is often on the same order of magnitude as the temporal resolution of the  TDC itself. Therefore, techniques are required to increase the resolution of these  devices, while ensuring timing accuracy. This thesis presents a high-resolution flash TDC that exploits  the random offsets on flip-flops or arbiters to perform time quantization. It also  describes a novel technique based on additive temporal noise to accurately calibrate  the measurement device. Simulation and experimental results reveal that this method  can calibrate the high-resolution flash TDC down to 5 ps within reasonable error  limits. In addition, accurate timing measurement of jitter below 14 ps has been  experimentally validated using a custom flash TDC fabricated in a 0.18-mum CMOS  process. A review of the most common circuit techniques for timing  measurement is also included in this thesis. Furthermore, a calibration system  implementation that can be used to reduce the temporal resolution requirements of  phase-generation circuitry is proposed.</description><creator>Levine, Peter, 1978-</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>High-resolution time measurement and calibration for on-chip test systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r853v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x196z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k643b1827</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Proteomics is the post-genomic science that aims to identify and  characterize the entire protein complement of a cell or organism. Mass spectrometry  followed by database search is the core technology used in high-throughput protein  identification. A major challenge in Proteomics is the random and chemical noise  that corrupts mass spectra. This noise can alter the measured mass-to-charge ratio  (m/z) and bias peak intensities, thus leading to errors in peptide ion peak  detection. Thus, noise reduction by filtering is necessary prior to data  analysis. As mass spectrometer response varies with m/z, an invariant  filter would not be optimal; therefore, a time-varying filter was developed to  denoise mass spectra. This involved conversion of spectra from the m/z domain to the  time domain equivalent, modeling spectral peak shape and Fourier-transforming the  model to determine its frequency content. The process was completed by filter design  and implementation. The application of this filter to experimental spectra resulted  in improved signal-to-noise ratio (by factor of 45), enabled detection of low  abundance peptide ions, and increased the accuracy of peptide mass  assignment.</description><creator>Lekpor, Kossi</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Time-varying filtering of time-of-flight mass spectra for proteomics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wq768.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b1827</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s1784m356</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Among the apparently simplest methods to determine bubble size  in flotation systems are photographic techniques, ranging from photography through  transparent walls to imaging of extracted bubbles. All capture images, which to  varying degrees include overlapping, touching or out of focus bubbles. As manual  counting limits the total number of bubbles, image analysis software is used to  automate the process. Accuracy is thus dependent on image treatment, including  counting method and filters. The McGill bubble size analysis method yields single plane,  backlit images and utilises software that filters by shape factor. Proven effective  for bubble size distributions ranging from approximately 0.5 to 3 mm, regular trends  are observed when number (D10) and Sauter (D32) mean diameters are compared. When  the method was extended to wide distributions typical of jetting spargers (e.g.,  0.2--15 mm), no similar trends were evident. Revision of the analysis process for  these two-phase systems included counting by number of holes, which reduced  dependence on bubble shape. This allowed for inclusion of small and large bubbles,  while excluding bubble clusters. A diameter assignment protocol reflecting  individual bubble shape was also developed. Revised output distributions showed  increased symmetry, and the D32 vs. D10 trend was recovered. Impact of sample tube diameter on the output bubble size  distributions, and types of bias introduced were also investigated. A means of  selecting an appropriate sample tube diameter for a given bubble population is  presented.</description><creator>Bailey, Marta E.</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Analysis of bubble size distributions using the McGill bubble size analyser</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kr037.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s1784m356</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62f878q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:51:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Specularities and shadows often confound algorithms designed to  solve computer vision tasks such as image segmentation, object detection and  tracking. In this thesis, an illumination compensation technique that detects and  removes both specularities and shadows is proposed. The method requires no camera  calibration or other a priori information regarding the scene. This thesis also  introduces two new illumination invariant representations based on the Retinex: the  R ⌢ image and the R ⌢EDGE image. Potential specularities are initially detected and a wavefront  grown outwards from the center of the specularity. This continues until the  specularity boundary or a material boundary is reached. The latter is detected by  the newly discovered illumination invariant R ⌢ and R ⌢EDGE  images that are introduced in this thesis. Upon reaching the specularity boundary,  the wavefront contracts inwards, coloring in the specularity as it contracts, until  the specularity no longer exists. After treating specularities, shadows are dealt with. Support  Vector Machines are trained to identify shadow boundaries based on their boundary  properties. This boundary information is used to identify shadowed regions in the  image and then assign them the color of non-shadow neighbors of the same  material. Illumination compensation as proposed in this thesis was found  to increase the accuracy of image segmentation, skin detection and face  recognition.</description><creator>Bhattacharyya, Jisnu</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Detecting and removing specularities and shadows in images</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26xx83z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62f878q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):35325</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>