<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:02:24Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):15650" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tq57nv42q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main purpose of nuclear power reactors is the release of energy arising from the initiation and maintenance of the fission chain reaction in nuclear fuels. It was known that the U235 isotope, present in 0.72% abundance in natural uranium, was fissionable with thermal neutrons but that the U238 isotope present in 99.28% abundance could only be caused to fission with neutrons of higher energy. In addition, the U238 nucleus was capable of capturing thermal neutrons and would therefore act as a parasite in the nuclear chain reaction. This parasitic capture was soon recognized to lead to the formation of Pu239 in the following way.</description><creator>Marsden, Donald. A.</creator><contributor>Yaffe, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Mass distribution in thermal neutron fission of Pu239.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sh156.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57nv42q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ms35tc79s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>To observers of the Canadian political scene, it is a well known fact that federal cabinet ministers are appointed to represent various aspects of federalism such as province, race, religion, region, economic and other sectional interests. A cabinet minister may represent more than one of these aspects. This practice is followed regardless of which party is in power and usually supersedes such considerations as political or administrative experience. The pattern of representation in the Canadian federal cabinet has changed considerably since Confederation. In the immediate post Confederation era, the first consideration was provincial representation. A certain number of cabinet ministers were appointed to represent each of the four provinces according to their population using Quebec’s and Ontario’s populations as the basis.</description><creator>Marko, Anne. M.</creator><contributor>Mallory, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Economics and Political Science.</subject><title>Federal representation in the Canadian Cabinet July 1, 1867 – June 21, 1957.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qn28c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tc79s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics and Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dw90h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Interest in the role of the Nucleus Caudatus (N.C.) on neural processes started when in 1873 Ferrier obtained strong contralateral pleurothotonos in animals upon stimulation of this structure (Ferrier, 1873 and 1876). For years research was concerned with the contribution of the N.C. to motor output. Results have suggested that the N.C. is a regulatory structure. Reports are at variance to some extent. Some claim an inhibitory action, ethers a facilitatory action and still others claim to have demonstrated both. Among the first authors to report on an inhibitory action of the N.C. on the motor system were Mettler et al. (1939).</description><creator>Marco, Luis. A.</creator><contributor>Jasper, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Neurology and Neurosurgery.</subject><title>Electrographic studies of the caudate nucleus in the cat.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nm77x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dw90h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Health Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s1784q06c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The technique of electron nuclear double resonance (ENDOR) was used to study the energy levels of Cr3+ in the cubic crystalline electric field of magnesium oxide, MgO. The experiment was carried out at a temperature of 4.2-°K- on single crystals with a Cr3+ concentration of about .02%. The spacings between the hyperfine energy levels were accurately measured and the results used to check the accuracy of the spin-Hamiltonian. The hyperfine structure constant was found to be A= 49.27 +/- .02 MC/S (or 16.42 t +/- .02 cm-1). The ratio of the energy level splittings due to the nuclear magnetic moment and electronic magnetic moment was determined as 9N’BN/9B = .87 ± .02 x 10-4.</description><creator>Manoogian, Armen.</creator><contributor>Fry, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>The double resonance of chromium in magnesium oxide.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612s14r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s1784q06c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s161980s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tests have been conducted to determine heat transfer rates for both laminar and turbulent incompressible flow of air over flat plates with unheated starting lengths. The range of Reynolds numbers covered and based on the distance from the leading edge extended up to 2.5 x 10^6. The results were compared with the various starting length correction factors that have been proposed up-to-date. The experimental results in the laminar regime confirm those obtainable by the usual analytical approach. In the turbulent range beyond Reynolds numbers of 1 x 10^6, the results indicate agreement with the correction factor proposed by Reynolds, Kays and Kline in preference to those of Rubesin and Max Jacob.</description><creator>Malhotra, Vasdev. S.</creator><contributor>Stachiewicz, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering.</subject><title>Effect of unheated starting lengths on convective heat transfer from flat plates.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dw91s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161980s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tz78t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is well known that a response may be markedly affected when the situation in which it is customarily performed is altered in some of its stimulus characteristics. Apart from experiments in which a change in the stimulus characteristics of the experimental situation constitutes a confounding variable, there are studies in which such stimulus change is the chosen experimental variable. Perhaps the best known of this latter type of studies, certainly the ones most rigorously controlled, are those usually described under the label of "stimulus generalization”. Though the concept of stimulus generalization was derived from experiments on conditioning (Pavlov, 1927; Bass and Hull, 1934; Hovland, 1937a, 1937b), it has also been used to describe, and sometimes to explain the results of studies in a wide variety of research areas.</description><creator>Maheux, Victor.</creator><contributor>Bindra, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Psychology.</subject><title>Distraction effects and stimulus generalizations.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sf01r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tz78t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429d95w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A photomagnetometer is an instrument capable of measuring changes induced by external radiation in the macroscopic magnetic moment of a solid. The system described here is a source-modulated detector. The solid being studied is fixed in the presence of a uniform magnetic field and radiation in the optical region modulated at a low frequency (1000 c.p.s.) is allowed to strike the solid. Any changes in the magnetic moment are measured by the voltage induced in detection coils suitably arranged adjacent to the sample. These signals are detected by a phase sensitive electronics system. The sensitivity, frequency response, and thermal noise level of the system were measured. Studies were made of the spurious signals which can arise from vibration of the detection coils in the magnetic field, irregularities in modulation due to imperfections in the chopping disc, and stray light falling on the detection coils. The bandwidth of the electronic detection system, and the photomagentism to be expected in a small parallelepiped of solid arising from the photogeneration of free carriers were calculated. The characteristics of the important component instruments were measured.</description><creator>MacKinnon, John. A.</creator><contributor>Stevenson, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>Sensitivity of a photomagnetometer.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612s151.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429d95w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128nj29f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis describes an investigation of the coalescence of fluid drops at flat interfaces and in laminar shear flow. The investigation was undertaken as one of a series which have been conducted in this laboratory on the behaviour of suspensions of fluid and rigid particles. The method of presentation requires some explanation. Part I deals briefly with the nature of the problem, a short review of the background and the objectives and scope of the investigations. The main experimental work is presented in Parts II, III, and IV. These parts have been written to achieve brevity without loss of clarity and to permit publication in the scientific literature without further modification.. For this reason certain experimental and technical details have been omitted from the main text and presented in Appendices V to VIII. Concluding Remarks and Suggestions for Further \iork are given in Part V. Some results of experiments on the effect of emulsifiers on coalescence and the action of defoamers are contained in Appendices I and II, and the experimental verification of a previously derived theoretical equation for the approach of a sphere to a plane interface is given in Appendices III and IV.</description><creator>MacKay, George. D.</creator><contributor>Pavlasek, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Chemistry</subject><title>Some mechanisms of coalescence of liquid drops.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75rc47b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nj29f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v692t988m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study considers the geographical distribution of total ozone through its correlation with various meteorological parameters. In particular, the seasonal and latitudinal variations of these correlations are examined. The relationships obtained are then used to prepare maps of total ozone distribution on a daily basis for each fifth day for the period October 1958 to March 1959, and for each tenth day for the period April 1959 to September 1959. The results provide an improved description of the behaviour and distribution of total ozone on a hemispheric scale.</description><creator>MacDonald, Violet. D.</creator><contributor>Boville, B. W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Meteorology.</subject><title>Hemispheric analysis of total ozone observations.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988p46f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t988m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rh931</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present law governing the liability of manufacturers to make reparation for harm caused by defects, attributable to negligence, in their products has been hammered out over a period of rather more than a century by the courts which, on both sides of the Atlantic, administer the principles of the Anglo-American system, and finds its origin in an English case, Winterbottom v. Wright (1). The sole parallel between this case and those immediately concerning the aircraft manufacturer is that both are derived from allegedly defective vehicles: for the rest, Winterbottom v. Wright did not involve a manufacturer, and was not tried on the issue of the tort of negligence. Its importance in the law of products liability, and the solution to the paradox, lie not in what was decided in the case but in the misinterpretation of the decision by later courts, and in their application of that misinterpretation to cases which were properly based on the tort of negligence.</description><creator>Lyon, James. T.</creator><contributor>Rosevear, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Air and Space Law.</subject><title>Liability of the aircraft manufacturer.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50h079w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rh931</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v6328</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This is a study of the formation of the microwave optical image, based on diffraction and aberration theories. The work is essentially in two parts. The first part is concerned with the Kirchhoff vector and scalar diffraction theories. Expressions are derived for the vector image fields and for the time-averaged Poynting power flow in the image region of an ideal system. A plot of the power flow is given. The second part considers the effects of aberrations on the image structure. A new general diffraction integral is developed and ''diffraction aberrations" are found to arise from the inclined aperture. It is shown that there exists a unique relation between the shape and positions of the Airy dark rings and the various aberrations. Methods of measuring the aberrations in a physical system are proposed. A general theorem concerning the phase change round a closed path linked with the Airy rings is proved rigorously, and finally the axial wavelength is shown to be longer than the free-space wavelength. Microwave measurements at X-band confirm the validity of the General Diffraction Integral and of the Airy ring versus aberrations relationships. The three-dimensional structure of the image field for a system with astigmatism is presented in full, in terms of contour maps of phase and intensity. Agreement between theory and experiment is good.</description><creator>Lum, Yun. F.</creator><contributor>Pavlasek, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Electrical Engineering.</subject><title>Diffraction-aberration theory of microwave optical image formation.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z7091240.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v6328</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hh63t044s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Interest in the sulphur status of soils stems from the fact that sulphur is an element essential for the growth of all plants. Although sulphur deficiencies have not so far been reported in the Province of Quebec, they are of considerable importance in some areas of North America, and the prevailing trend towards use of more concentrated fertilizers containing little or no sulphur in incidental impurities, has caused some workers to wonder whether such deficiencies should in the future be expected to occur in the province.</description><creator>Lowe, Lawrence. E.</creator><contributor>DeLong, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>The sulphur status of Quebec soils with particular reference to the amount of organically combined sulphur and the nature of its combinations.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tq466.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63t044s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999b20x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of neurochemistry, or the biochemistry of the nervous system, is to discover the nature or those substances involved in the changes which enable nerve cells to accomplish their unique function as highly specialized conducting cells, to study the metabolism or these substances and to determine how and to what extent they regulate these functional changes. Hence the aim or neurochemical research on gamma-aminobutyric acid is simply to further our understanding of the neuron at the molecular level and of the way in which active molecules like gamma-aminobutyric acid regulate, or are involved in, neuronal function.</description><creator>Lovell, Richard. A.</creator><contributor>Elliott, K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>On the equivalence, content and state of gamma-aminobutyric acid and factor I in mammalian brain.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731756k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999b20x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nm786</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Lorimer, Peter. J.</creator><contributor>Schwerdtfeger, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>A study of T2 – groups.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72pb93b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nm786</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:765374467</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An instrument based on the Chapman Printing Smoothness Tester has been devised to measure the distribution of paper surface roughness variations in the wavelength region between 1/6 and 1/90 of an inch. The measurement is made by scanning a small spot of light over the contact interface between a smooth glass block and the paper surface. Light scattered from the interface at a shallow angle is proportional to the area of optical contact lying within the spot, and is detected by a sensitive photomultiplier tube. A frequency analysis of this time-varying photomultiplier signal yields a band-limited noise spectrum corresponding to the random distribution of optical contact areas, along with distinct peaks at the frequencies corresponding to the regular patterns of the woven wire screen upon which the paper was initially formed, (the wire mark). A quantitative assessment of the wire mark intensity may be made by taking the ratio of the average component of the photomultiplier tube signal at the frequency of the wire mark pattern to the total average value of the signal.</description><creator>Lindsay, Robert. A.</creator><contributor>D’Ombrain, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Electrical Engineering.</subject><title>The development of a wire mark meter.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859k19s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/765374467</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hh63t0452</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A disturbed mind will seek a solution. The desire to learn the How’s, What’s and Why’s of a problem prompted the author to search for an answer to this problem. In recent years an increasing number of patients presenting vestibular symptoms, particularly postural vertigo, after head. Injury has been observed. Various opinions have been expressed regarding the frequency of occurrence of vestibular symptoms, the types of positional nystagmus and the probable sites of lesions resulting from head trauma. However, there has been no uniformity of opinion. The purpose of the present investigation is to study the effects of head injury on vestibular function.</description><creator>Lim, Manuel. G.</creator><contributor>Gannon, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Otolaryngology.</subject><title>The effect of head injury on vestibular function an electronystagmographic study.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nv430.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63t0452</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Health Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42nc37m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A test system for determining the frequency response of processes with long time constants is described. The exciting signal is provided by a sine wave generator which has a continuously variable frequency in the range of 10 cps to 1.4 cycles per day, as well as variable amplitude and bias. The input to and output from the process is obtained automatically by an analogue to digital converter which may be made compatible with a wide variety of input signals. The converter output is in the form of a paper tape which may be converted into standard IBM data cards. These are utilized as an input to an IBM 1410 Computer which is programmed to compute and plot the frequency response.</description><creator>Levine, Martin. D.</creator><contributor>D’Ombrain, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Electrical Engineering.</subject><title>An automatic test system for determining the frequency response of processes with long time constants.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r4623.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42nc37m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m538x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An Antigen is a substance, which, when introduced parenterally into an animal, induces the production of a specific serum globulin which has the unique property of combining specifically with the antigen. Most proteins are antigenic, but antigenicity is not confined only to proteins. Thus, conjugated proteins (Felton, 1934), polysaccharides (Avery, et al 1931), and lipids (Boivin et al, 1935) have shown to be antigenic. One can not state unequivocally what physical and chemical characteristics make a substance antigenic. </description><creator>Leure-duPree, Alphonse.</creator><contributor>Leblond, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Anatomy.</subject><title>Immunochemical and physic-chemical characterization of the human soluble lens proteins.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fs309.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m538x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Health Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv935647q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In recent years, the study of antibody synthesis in vitro has aroused considerable interest. Not only does it enable the immunologists to study the phenomenon of antibody formation at a cellular level, free from various factors often associated in a whole body, but also it serves as a model for biochemists in the study of biosynthesis of a specific protein. An antigen is a complex molecule, and very often it contains more than one determinant group that can elicit antibody response. The antibody thus demonstrated in an in vitro system against a microbial antigen cannot necessarily be equated with a measure of immunity against the infection.</description><creator>Leung, Franklin. C.</creator><contributor>Vas, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Bacteriology and Immunology.</subject><title>Studies on biological characteristics of antibody produced in vitro.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k868d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935647q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g366k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Despite the accepted synthesis between the “real" and “monetary" economies, questions remain unanswered in the financial sector of the economy. Though these sectors were once considered separate, "real" or “value theory" methodology has dominated study of both areas. This thesis advances the proposition that the “financial sector” cannot be studied using the analytic tools of "value theory” alone. In particular, controversy continues concerning the relevance of the "expectations” hypothesis of the term structure of interest rates as opposed to the “institutional” hypothesis. Our thesis attempts a rigourous exposition of the “institutional” hypothesis. We describe how this hypothesis is a logical implication of the “balance effect”.</description><creator>Lermer, George.</creator><contributor>Weldon, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Economics and Political Science.</subject><title>An institutional model of the term structure of interest rates.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pr32q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g366k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics and Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h795w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette étude, fondée sur l'analyse de certains contes du terroir de la région de Québec, vise à présenter le portrait des Canadiens français tel qu'il a été esquissé par le Frère Marie-Victorin, Mgr Camille Roy, l’abbé Lionel Groulx, le Frère Gilles, Georges Bouchard et le plus important de tous, Adjutor Rivard. Nous n’avons donc pas l'intention d'étudier l’œuvre entière de ces écrivains, étant donné qu’elle n’est pas purement littéraire comme dans le cas du Frère Marie-Victorin, qui traite de sujets scientifiques dans la majeure partie de son œuvre gigantesque; l'abbé Lionel Groulx qui trace notre passé dans une quinzaine d'ouvrages historiques, et Adjutor Rivard qui s’est beaucoup intéressé à la linguistique du parler canadien-français.</description><creator>Lebel, Sister Mary.</creator><contributor>Reverchon, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>French.</subject><title>Le caractère des canadiens français vus dans quelques œuvres du terroir.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515r858.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h795w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1831cp46p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis describes an investigation on the fractionation and physicochemical characterization of .xylan from white birch. The work forms part of a current series of macromolecular etudies in Wood and Cellulose Chemistry. After a Preface and General Introduction, the work is presented as a series of Parts written in the form of scientific papers and are to be submitted for publication with little modification. Part I deals with the preparation and properties of various xylan fractions. Part II is a study of the molecular weight and configuration of the polysaccharide in solution. Part III is an investigation on the viscosity-temperature relationships tor dilute solutions of xylan in dimethyl sulfoxide. The main text ot the thesis ends with concluding remarks, suggestions tor further work and claims for original research. Additional details are given in a series of Appendices. Appendix I is a report on some physical properties of dimethyl sulfoxide-water mixtures and has already been published by Dr. D.A.I. Goring and the author.</description><creator>Lebel, Roland. G.</creator><contributor>Goring, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Chemistry</subject><title>Molecular size and configuration of xylan.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h7965.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cp46p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pk84r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The pathology of our native larch, Larix laricina (Du Roi) Koch, has never been carefully investigated in the province of Quebec. One of the explanations of this apparent lack of interest in diseases of this tree species is the very important infestation by the larch sawfly (Pristiphora Erichsonii Htg.), which, at the beginning of the present century, greatly reduced the best stands of larch in Northeast America. Usually the Eastern larch, commonly called tamarack, provides a hard, heavy and non-porous wood of high technical value. Its resistance to decay outweighs any other conifer of Eastern and Central Canada (2).</description><creator>Lavallée, André.</creator><contributor>Estey, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Plant Pathology.</subject><title>Leucostoma canker of larch in Quebec.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tg573.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pk84r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agriculture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3n204261f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although much information has accumulated in recent years on the cellular origin and mechanism of antibody synthesis, very little is known about the way in which antigens exert their effect on the induction of antibody formation. A number of investigators (1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6) feel that antigens probably must be split into fragments to initiate antibody production and that these subunits may correspond in size to the dimensions of the antibody-combining sites (3). Antibodies reacting with antigenic fragments prepared in vitro have been found in rabbit antisera against human and bovine serum albumin (4, 7, 8, 9) and some of these antibodies appeared to be directed against antigenic groups not present on the surface of the native protein (9).</description><creator>Larose, Claude. L.</creator><contributor>Rose, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology</subject><title>The fate of soluble protein antigens.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42nc38w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n204261f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m039k869p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:51:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis discusses correlation of the Silurian and Devonian rocks between the Lake Temiscouata and the Lake Matapedia areas. In certain correlations, two solutions are possible; the writer has proposed those which appear most logical at the present. The area is located in the Northern Appalachian Highlands, between the Matapedia and Temiscouata river valleys. The writer has not mapped this entire area by himself, his main work has been directed in the center part of the area. However, for a better understanding of the correlation of Silurian strata between the two extremities, it became necessary to include work done by other workers in both the Matapedia valley, and Lake Temiscouata valley.</description><creator>Lajoie, Jean.</creator><contributor>Stearn, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1963</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>The Siluro-Devonian stratigraphy of the Matapedia-Temiscouata area.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fq42x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k869p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):15675</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>