<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:03:15Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):15875" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cm18m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The soybean genome has between 46,000-66,000 protein coding genes, which determine the traits of the soybean plant. Out of these thousands of genes only a few gene promoters have been studied and well characterized. Promoter evaluation is very important especially for biotechnology applications as they determine gene expression levels, patterns and their profiles. Some of these characterized promoters in soybean are the lectins promoters of Le1, Le2, Le3 genes. In this study we have cloned the Le4 gene promoter and transformed into Arabidopsis thaliana by floral dip transformation technique to determine the expression profile using gusA as reporter gene. The expression profile was compared with plants already transformed with the promoters from Le1, Le2 and Le3. Part of the project was conducted in silico, in which promoter sequences of these homologues were retrieved from Phytozome (www.phytozome.net) and DNA motifs present in these promoters were predicted using PLACE database. The protein 3D structure of Le1 was used as template to compare with Le4.</description><description>Le génome du soja contient 46,000 à 66,000 gènes codant pour des protéines, qui déterminent les traits de la plante de soja. Cependant, parmi ces milliers de gènes, seulement quelques promoteurs de gènes ont été étudiés de façon approfondie. L'évaluation du promoteur est très importante, surtout pour les applications de biotechnologies, car elles déterminent les niveaux d'expression, les habitudes et les  profils des gènes. Certains de ces promoteurs caractérisés dans le soja sont les promoteurs de lectines des gènes Le1, Le2 et Le3. Dans cette étude, nous avons cloné le promoteur du gène Le4 dans un vecteur binaire. Puis, nous l'avons transformé en Arabidopsis thaliana par la technique « floral dip transformation » afin de déterminer le profil d'expression en utilisant gusA comme étant un gène rapporteur. Le profil d'expression a été comparé avec les promoteurs déjà transformés à partir des gènes Le1, Le2 et Le3. Une partie du projet a été réalisée « in silico » dans lesquelles des séquences promotrices de ces homologues ont été récupérées à partir du programme Phytozome (www.phytozome.net). Des motifs d'ADN présents dans ces promoteurs ont été prédits en utilisant la base de données PLACE. Les motifs uniques ont été comparés. La structure des protéines en 3D de Le1 a été utilisée comme modèle pour comparer avec le gène Le4.</description><creator>Chragh, Muhammad</creator><contributor>Martina Stromvik (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Cloning and profiling of the soybean legume lectin Le4 promoter</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920g135g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cm18m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tx31qn30d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse analyse les caractéristiques des radiations d'un téléphone mobile cellulaire semi-peuplé utilisant deux antennes imprimées en F-inversé (PIFAs). L'enquête est réalisée à trois fréquences différentes; la bande LTE 13 (746-786 MHz), GSM-900 (890-960 MHz) et GSM-1800 (1710-1880 MHz). Le téléphone mobile est constitué d'une batterie et d'un écran LCD dont le but est de rendre le modèle étudié plus réaliste. Le modèle utilisé vise d'abord à représenter la conception des PIFAs et ceci avec d'autres composants. Par référence a la méthode de conception qui a été décrite, les antennes de trois semi-peuplées téléphones mobiles sont conçus pour satisfaire des objectifs spécifiques de performance opérationnelle. Les deux PIFAs fabriques pour les mobiles GSM-1800 ont un gain maximal de 2.98 dB and 3.18 dB, coefficients de réflexion inférieur à -9 dB et un couplage maximal mutuel des -7.9 dB. De plus, les deux PIFAs fabriques pour les mobiles GSM-900 ont un gain maximal de -0.02 dB and -3 dB, coefficients de réflexion ci-dessous -10.5 dB et un couplage maximal mutuel de -6 dB. Enfin, les deux PIFAs fabriques pour les mobiles LTE-Band 13 atteignent un gain maximal de 0.19 dB and -11 dB, un coefficient de réflexion ci-dessous -4.5 dB et un couplage maximal mutuel de -11 dB. Les trois modèles indiquent que la présence d'autres composants provoquent la dégradation des performances des radiations. Néanmoins, les trois mobiles répondent à toutes les caractéristiques de rendement sauf celui pour le couplage mutuel. Des simulation utilisant des  vecteurs pleine-onde pointant sont effectuées pour investiguer le couplage entre les PIFAs. Les simulations indiquent que le tranfert de la puissance couplée entre les antennes pour les mobiles GSM-1800 et GSM-900 se déroule en dehors du mobile. Alors que la puissance couplée entre les antennes de téléphones LTE-bande 13 se fait à travers la structure et le substrat-lié du mobile.   Une récapitulation des différentes techniques de réduction des couplages mutuels a été présentée. Une méthode visant les ondes spatiales  i.e., utilisation d'un radiateur parasite, est appliquée aux mobiles GSM 1800 et GSM--900. Le radiateur parasite parvient à rendre le couplage maximal, pour les antennes GSM-1800, au-dessous de -18 dB et pour les antennes GSM-900 au-dessous de -17,5 dB.Le couplage mutuel de la LT-bande 13 est réduite en utilisant une structure de bande-interdite électromagnétique, qui apporte avec succès le couplage maximal mutuel pour les antennes à moins de -12,2 dB.En conclusion, la structure PIFA est une option viable pour une utilisation d'un téléphone mobile pour les bandes de fréquences d'une enquête, et ceci en appliquant les techniques de réduction mutuelles de couplage appropriées.</description><description>This thesis investigates the radiation characteristics of a semi-populated cellular mobile handset that uses two Printed Inverted-F Antennas (PIFAs). The investigation is carried out at three different frequencies; the LTE Band 13 (746-786 MHz), GSM-900 (890-960 MHz) and GSM-1800 (1710-1880 MHz).  The mobile handset is populated with the components that affect the antenna properties the most, a battery and an LCD screen, to make the investigated model more realistic. A methodology is first presented to design the PIFAs in the presence of other components on the board.  Using the outlined method, antennas for three semi-populated mobile handsets are designed to satisfy specific operational performance targets. The two PIFAs fabricated for the GSM-1800 handset have a maximum gain of 2.98 dB and 3.18 dB, reflection coefficients of below -9 dB and a maximum mutual coupling of  -7.9 dB.  The two fabricated PIFAs of the GSM-900 handset exhibit a maximum gain of -0.02 dB and -3 dB, reflection coefficients of below -10.5 dB and a maximum mutual coupling of -6 dB.  The measured gain values for the two PIFAs of LTE-Band 13 handset prototype are 0.19 dB and -11 dB, while both achieving reflection coefficients of below -4.5 dB and a maximum mutual coupling of -11 dB.  The three designs all indicate that the presence of the components on the handset degrade radiation performance. The three handsets nevertheless are well designed to meet all the performance targets except for the mutual coupling. Fullwave pointing vector simulations are conducted to investigate the coupling between the PIFAs showing that the power transfer between the GSM-1800 and GSM-900 PIFAs mostly takes place through radiation.  The power coupled between the LTE-Band 13 handset antennas on the other hand is majorly through the handset's structure and substrate-bound modes.A survey of different mutual coupling reduction techniques is presented. A method that targets coupling through space-waves, i.e., the use of a parasitic radiator, is applied in this work to the GSM-1800 and GSM-900 handsets.  The parasitic radiator succeeds in bringing the maximum coupling between the GSM-1800 handset antennas to below -18 dB and below -17.5 dB for the GSM-900 handset antennas. The mutual coupling between the LTE-Band 13 handset antennas is reduced by using an Electromagnetic Band-Gap structure, which successfully decreases it to below -12.2 dB.</description><creator>Wahidi, Ashar</creator><contributor>Ramesh Abhari (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Design and optimization of multiple printed inverted-F antennas (PIFAs) on a semi-populated mobile handset</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451n145.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qn30d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:02871058h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis problematizes the way in which the Vietnamese Buddhist Thích Nhất Hạnh is represented sympathetically in academic discourse, and investigates how this representation conceals Orientalist methodologies which can inform scholarship about modern or engaged Buddhism. This study uses the framework of Jane Naomi Iwamura's conception of the Oriental Monk, and focuses on two texts in particular: Sallie B. King's Socially Engaged Buddhism and David Loy's The Great Awakening: a Buddhist social theory. Analyzing these two works not only reveals ways in which scholars might attempt to 'purify' and appropriate Asian religion, but also raises questions concerning the viability of the project of defining the 'Buddhistness' of modern Buddhisms in light of the obligations of scholars who hold authority in Buddhist communities. This thesis does not attempt to offer alternative definitions of modern Buddhism or to demonize the 'scholar-practitioner', but rather brings to the forefront serious methodological problems in the academic study of modern Buddhist figures and traditions.</description><description>Cette thèse problématise la façon dont le bouddhiste vietnamien Thích Nhất Hạnh est représenté avec sympathie dans le discours académique, et elle examine comment cette représentation cache les méthodologies Orientalistes qui peuvent informer sur les bourses d'études du bouddhisme moderne ou engagé. Cette étude utilise le concept de Jane Naomi Iwamura à propos du Moine Oriental, et se concentre particulièrement sur deux textes: «Socially Engaged Buddism» de Sallie B. King et «The Great Awakening» de David Loy. L'analyse de ces deux œuvres révèle non seulement comment les spécialistes pourraient tenter de «purifier» et de s'approprier la religion asiatique, mais soulève également des questions quant à la viabilité du projet de définition de la «Bouddhistesse» des bouddhismes modernes à la lumière des obligations des spécialistes qui détiennent une autorité dans les communautés bouddhistes. Cette thèse ne cherche pas à proposer d'autres définitions du bouddhisme moderne ou à diaboliser le «chercheur-praticien», mais elle met plutôt au premier plan de sérieux problèmes méthodologiques dans l'étude académique des personnages et traditions bouddhistes modernes.</description><creator>Temprano, Victor</creator><contributor>Lara E Braitstein (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Religion - Religion General</subject><title>The scholar and the sage: Sallie B. King, David Loy, and Thích Nhất Hạnh</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042x637.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02871058h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62fc82x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Natural materials are often characterised by a cellular microstructure which allows them to achieve a wide range of mechanical properties. This microarchitecture has provided inspiration for the development of high performance manmade structures and artificial materials. Among cellular solids, lattice materials are a subset characterised by an ordered, periodic, microstructure that can be tailored to achieve specific combinations of stiffness strength and density. This thesis presents a methodology for the derivation of constitutive models for lattice materials. The approach presented here is based on a multiscale mechanics framework. The macroscopic stress-strain relationships of the material are obtained from the microscopic parameters of the lattice. In addition, the internal forces in the lattice elements are calculated as a function of the macroscopic strain. Under the hypothesis of linear behaviour, the method has been applied to evaluate the macroscopic stiffness and strength of a selection of two-dimensional and three-dimensional lattices. Performance comparison among the alternative cell topologies is accomplished using material charts for stiffness, buckling and plastic yielding. The method has also been applied to investigate the linear properties of lattices with multiple hierarchical levels.Non linear constitutive models for lattices have been introduced here for the first time. In particular, these models develop macroscopic stress-strain relationships which capture the effect of geometric non linearity. Applied to hexagonal and triangulated lattices, the models have been demonstrated to effectively capture strain hardening due to reorientation of lattice elements and structural softening due to microscopic buckling of the struts.</description><description>Les matériaux naturels sont souvent caractérisés par une microstructure cellulaire qui permet une vaste gamme de propriétés mécaniques. Cette microarchitecture peut être util pour le développement de matériaux et de structures a haute performance. Comme plusieurs matériaux cellulaires, les matériaux en treillis possèdent un sous-ensemble caractérisé par une microstructure ordonnée et périodique, qui peut être adaptée pour cibler des valeurs spécifiques de force, rigidité et densité. Cette thèse présente une méthodologie pour la dérivation de modèles de comportement pour les matériaux en treillis. L'approche suivie ici est basée sur un schéma multi-échelle. Les relations macroscopiques contraintes-déformation des matériaux sont obtenues à partir des paramètres microscopiques du treillis. En outre, les forces internes dans les éléments du treillis sont calculées en fonction des composantes du tenseur des déformations macroscopiques. Dans l'hypothèse d'un comportement linéaire, la méthode a été appliquée pour évaluer la rigidité macroscopique et la résistance de plusieurs matériaux avec des topologies bidimensionnelles et tridimensionnelles. Des cartes des matériaux pour la rigidité, la déformation plastique et le flambage ont été produites afin de permettre une comparaison de topologies cellulaires différentes. La méthode a aussi été appliquée à l'étude des propriétés linéaires des treillis avec plusieurs niveaux hiérarchiques.Des modèles constitutifs non-linéaires pour les matériaux en treillis sont décrits. Ces modèles permettent d'obtenir des relations macroscopiques entre contraintes et déformations qui peuvent capter l'effet de la non-linéarité géométrique. Appliqués aux treillis hexagonaux et triangulés, les modèles capturent l'écrouissage dû à la réorientation des éléments du treillis, et l'adoucissement structural en raison du flambage microscopique des poutres du treillis.</description><creator>Vigliotti, Andrea</creator><contributor>Damiano Pasini (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical </subject><title>Constitutive models for lattice materials</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qw37p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fc82x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hk13d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The mechanisms whereby immune cells infiltrating the central nervous system in multiple sclerosis (MS) contribute to tissue injury remain to be defined. CD4 T cells are implicated as key mediators of the deleterious inflammation observed in MS. Myelin reactive CD4 T cells expressing CD56, an NK cell marker, were previously shown to be cytotoxic to human oligodendrocytes in vitro. We sought to determine whether myelin reactive CD4 T cells could also express and utilize other NK associated markers to mediate oligodendrocyte directed cytotoxicity. We observed that myelin reactive CD4 T cell lines, as well as short term PHA-activated CD4 T cells can express NKG2C, the activating receptor that interacts with HLA-E, a non-classical MHC class I molecule. These cells co-expressed CD56, had elevated levels of cytotoxic molecules FasL, granzyme B and perforin compared to their NKG2C-negative counterparts and mediated significant in vitro cytotoxicity towards human oligodendrocytes induced to express HLA-E with pro-inflammatory cytokines. A significantly elevated proportion of ex-vivo peripheral blood CD4 T cells from MS patients expressed NKG2C compared to controls. Our immunohistochemical analysis demonstrated that MS tissue sections displayed HLA-E+ oligodendrocytes and NKG2C+ CD4 T cells. Our results implicate a novel mechanism through which infiltrating CD4T cells could contribute to tissue injury in MS.</description><description>La sclérose en plaques (SEP) est caractérisée par l'infiltration de cellules immunes au sein du système nerveux central (SNC). Les mécanismes par lesquels ces cellules contribuent à la formation des lésions typiques de cette pathologie restent à élucider. Les cellules T CD4 jouent un rôle important dans l'inflammation observée en SEP. Des travaux antérieurs ont démontré que des cellules T CD4 spécifiques à la myéline et exprimant le CD56, un marqueur des cellules NK, ont une activité cytotoxique in vitro dirigée contre les oligodendrocytes humains. Nous avons déterminé si les cellules T CD4 réactives à la myéline expriment et utilisent d'autres marqueurs NK impliqué dans cette cytotoxicité contre les oligodendrocytes. Nous avons observé que des lignées de cellules T CD4 spécifiques pour la myéline, ainsi que des cellules T CD4 activées par la PHA peuvent exprimer le NKG2C, le récepteur activateur qui interagit avec le HLA-E, une molécule non-classique du CMH de classe I. Les cellules T CD4 positives pour le NKG2C co-expriment le CD56, des niveaux élevés de molécules cytotoxiques tels que le FasL, le granzyme B et la perforine par rapport à leurs homologues n'exprimant pas le NKG2C. Nous avons aussi montré que ces cellules sont cytotoxiques envers des oligodendrocytes humains, qui expriment le HLA-E suite à un traitement avec des cytokines des inflammatoires. La proportion des cellules T CD4 exprimant le NKG2C est significativement plus élevée dans les échantillons de sang ex-vivo provenant de patients atteints de la SEP par rapport à ceux des témoins. Nous avons observé par immunohistochimie sur des coupes de tissus de patients atteints de la SEP la présence d'oligodendrocytes exprimant le HLA-E ainsi que des cellules T CD4 arborant le NKG2C. Nos résultats révèlent un nouveau mécanisme par lequel les cellules T CD4 pourraient contribuer directement à la formation des lésions tissulaires observées dans le SNC des patients atteints de la SEP.  </description><creator>Zaguia, Fatma</creator><contributor>Nathalie Arbour (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Jack P Antel (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health Sciences - Immunology</subject><title>Cytotoxic NKG2C+ CD4 T cells target oligodenfrocytes in Multiple Sclerosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zf67g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hk13d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6395wc12k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Zellweger spectrum disorder (ZSD) is due to defects in any one of 13 PEX proteins, encoded by PEX genes, which are required for peroxisome biogenesis. ZSD features neurologic, hepatic and renal abnormalities; however, one common mutation, PEX1-p.Gly843Asp (G843D), confers a milder phenotype and represents 30% of all ZSD alleles. Thus, identifying treatments for this allele will benefit many patients. We recently showed that PEX1-G843D behaves as a misfolded protein amendable to improved function by chemical and pharmacologic chaperones. In a small molecule screen, we reported recovery of peroxisomal matrix enzyme import by acacetin diacetate, a flavonoid that may bind to the ATP binding site of PEX1-G843D to improve conformation. In order to develop a lead compound from this library 'hit', we evaluated an additional 34 flavonoids for peroxisomal matrix enzyme import recovery using a patient fibroblast cell line hemizygous for PEX1-G843D and expressing a GFP-tagged peroxisome targeting signal (PTS1-GFP reporter). Eight flavonoids were identified as potential pharmacologic chaperones. Based on these compounds, additional flavonoid derivatives were produced and tested to determine the minimal pharmacophore. Relevant functional groups that enhanced or decreased efficacy were identified from these compounds, with diosmetin as the most effective one. These findings will aid in determining structure activity relationships, as knowledge of chemicals that are effective and ineffective will be used to determine the interactions that are important in developing a pharmacophore model. To determine how the flavonoids may be affecting PEX1 and associated proteins, PEX6 and PEX5, subcellular fractions were analyzed by SDS-PAGE and Blue Native PAGE to evaluate protein localization and complex formation. This was first done in wild type and various null cell lines to determine what to expect in normal and diseased states. It was found that PEX1 and PEX6 are dependent on each other and on PEX26 for stable levels and peroxisomal localization, and that PEX5 is dependent on these three proteins for stable levels and cytosolic localization. It was also determined that PEX1 is present in the cytosolic fraction as a monomer and a trimer, and in the peroxisomal fraction as a hexamer and dodecamer. Flavonoid treatment did not appear to affect the localization of PEX1 or PEX6 or complex formation. Thus, we propose that the flavonoids interact with a partially folded population of PEX1 that is already able to interact with PEX6 and localize to the peroxisomal membrane.  In addition, we propose that this interaction of protein and drug enhances the residual ATPase activity of the PEX1 complex, thus improving matrix protein import, as observed in the cell-based experiments.  </description><description>Le trouble du spectre de Zellweger (Zellweger Spectrum Disorder – ZSD) est dû à des defaults dans l'une des treize protéines PEX, codées par les gènes PEX, nécessaires pour la biogenèse des péroxysomes. ZSD a des caractéristiques neurologiques, hépatiques et des anomalies rénales. Cependant, une mutation fréquente, PEX1-p.Gly843Asp (G843D), confère un phénotype moins sévère et représente 30% de l'ensemble des allèles ZSD. Ainsi, l'identification de traitements pour cet allèle sera bénéfique à de nombreux patients. Nous avons récemment montré que PEX1-G843D se comporte comme une protéine mal conformée, dont la fonction peut-être améliorée par des protéines chaperons chimiques ou pharmacologiques. En examinant une série de petites molécules, nous avons observé une amélioration dans l'importation d'enzyme de la matrice du péroxysome par le diacétate d'acacétine, un flavonoïde qui peut interagir avec le site de liaison de l'ATP de PEX1-G843D, afin d'améliorer sa conformation. Afin de développer un composé de base à partir de cette bibliothèque de molécules, nous avons évalué trente-quatre autres flavonoïdes pour l'amélioration de l'importation d'enzyme de la matrice péroxysomale en utilisant une lignée de fibroblastes d'un patient hémizygote pour PEX1-G843D et qui exprime un signal de ciblage péroxysomal GFP (rapporteur PTS1-GFP). Huit flavonoïdes ont été identifiés en tant que protéines chaperons pharmacologiques potentielles. En utilisant ces composés comme base, des dérivés supplémentaires de flavonoïdes ont été produits et testés afin de déterminer le pharmacophore minimal. Les groupes fonctionnels pertinents, qui accroissent ou diminuent l'efficacité, ont été identifiés à partir de ces composés, la diosmétine étant la plus efficace. Ces résultats permettront d'élucider les relations structure-activité, de même qu'une notion des produits importants dans le développement d'un modèle de pharmacophore.Afin de déterminer comment les flavonoïdes pourraient affecter PEX1 et les protéines associées, PEX5 et PEX6, des fractions subcellulaires ont été analysées par SDS-PAGE et PAGE Bleu Natif, pour évaluer la localisation des protéines et la formation de complexe. Ceci fut tout d'abord effectué à l'aide de lignées nulles et de type sauvage, pour avoir une idée des états normaux et pathologiques. Il a été constaté que PEX1 et PEX6 sont dépendantes l'une de l'autre ainsi que de PEX26 pour leur stabilité et une localisation péroxysomale, et que PEX5 est dépendante de ces trois protéines pour sa stabilité et une localisation cytosolique. Il a été déterminé que PEX1 est présente dans la fraction cytosolique à l'état de monomère et de trimère, et dans la fraction péroxysomale à l'état d'hexamère et de dodécamère. Le traitement aux flavonoïdes n'a pas l'air d'avoir un effet sur la localisation de PEX1 et PEX6 ou sur la formation de complexe. Ainsi, nous proposons que les flavonoïdes interagissent avec une population de PEX1 qui a une mauvaise conformation, et qui est capable d'interagir avec PEX6 et de se localiser à la membrane péroxysomale. De plus, nous proposons que cette interaction protéine-composé améliore l'activité ATPase résiduelle du complexe PEX1, améliorant ainsi l'importation de protéines de la matrice, comme observé dans les expériences in vitro. </description><creator>MacLean, Gillian</creator><contributor>Nancy Braverman (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>Recovery of PEX1-Gly843Asp associated peroxisome dysfunction by flavonoid compounds in fibroblasts from Zellweger spectrum patients</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rp81f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395wc12k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qq71s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La maladie d'Alzheimer (MA) est une maladie neurodégénérative progressive caractérisée par un déclin cognitif et causant ultimement la mort. La caractéristique pathologique principale de la MA est l'accumulation de protéine bêta-amyloïde, qui peut agréger en plaques vers la phase terminale de la maladie. La bêta-amyloïde a une variété d'effets toxiques et affecte particulièrement le système cholinergique du cerveau, un réseau de neurones essentielles à l'apprentissage et à la mémoire. Dans cette étude, le modèle de souris McGill THY-1-APP, surexprimant le précurseur de la bêta-amyloïde, a été utilisé comme modèle pour caractériser chronologiquement et anatomiquement l'impact de la pathologie amyloide sur l'intégrité synaptique cholinergique. Comme point de comparaison, l'impact de la pathologie sur le système glutamatergique a également été étudié. Enfin, dans un effort pour protéger le système cholinergique de la toxicité de la bêta-amyloïde, un inhibiteur de matrix métalloprotéinase 9 (MMP9i) a été administré à des souris transgéniques et « wild type » âgées. Cette étude a été incapable de confirmer l'hypothèse selon laquelle il y a une augmentation compensatoire de la structure et la fonction cholinergique avant l'apparition de plaques d'amyloïde. Cependant, cette étude a pu confirmer les pertes cholinergiques et la résilience relative du système glutamatergique au stade plus avancé de la pathologie. De plus, le fait que, contrairement aux animaux transgéniques traités avec le véhicule, les animaux transgéniques traités avec l'inhibiteur ne démontraient pas de perte cholinergique significative suggère un potentiel thérapeutique de l'inhibiteur. Par contre, comme les transgéniques traités avec l'inhibiteur n'étaient pas statistiquement différents des animaux transgéniques traités avec le véhicule, une étude plus grande devra être faite avant de pouvoir tirer des conclusions. L'inhibiteur de MMP9 a échoué à améliorer les performances des souris transgéniques et « wild type » traitées sur un test de comportement pour la mémoire épisodique. L'auteur conclut que le MMP9i a peut-être un potentiel thérapeutique et mérite plus d'investigations, mais qu'une co-administration avec d'autres agents thérapeutiques pourrait être nécessaires pour corriger les troubles cognitifs.</description><description>Alzheimer's disease (AD) is a progressive neurodegenerative disorder characterized by cognitive decline and ultimately death. The primary pathological hallmark of (AD) is the presence of amyloid beta protein which can accumulate intracellularly and eventually aggregate into extracellular plaques. Amyloid beta has a variety of toxic effects and is particularly disruptive to the brain's cholinergic system, a neural network essential for learning and memory function. In this study, the McGill THY-1-APP mouse model of AD, which overexpresses the precursor of amyloid beta, has been used to profile the region and time-specific impact of amyloid pathology on cholinergic synaptic integrity. As a point of comparison, the impact of amyloid pathology on the glutamatergic system has also been investigated. Finally, in an effort to protect the cholinergic system from amyloid beta toxicity, a matrix metalloproteinase 9 inhibitor (MMP9i) has been administered to aged THY-1-APP transgenics and their respective C56Bl/6 wild type controls. This study was unable to confirm the cholinergic early up-regulation hypothesis which postulates that there is a compensatory increase in cholinergic structure and function prior to extensive amyloidosis and plaque deposition. However, this study was able to confirm end-stage cholinergic synaptic losses and the relative resilience of the glutamatergic system to amyloid toxicity. At the present time, whether or not administration of the MMP9i is capable of preventing end-stage cholinergic losses remains unclear as the results are inconclusive. On the one hand, with the relatively small sample sizes used, there is some preliminary evidence to suggest that administration has a protective effect. This is because the density of cholinergic boutons in transgenic THY-1-APP MMP9i-treated mice did not differ significantly from wild type C57Bl/6 vehicle-treated mice, while the density of cholinergic boutons was significantly lower in vehicle-treated THY-1-APP transgenic mice as compared to wild type C57Bl/6 vehicle-treated mice. On the other hand, the THY-1-APP transgenic MMP9i treated mice failed to attain a statistically significant elevation in cholinergic bouton density when compared directly with the THY-1-APP transgenic vehicle treated mice, suggesting that the drug was unable to prevent cholinergic bouton loss after all. Further testing will be required in animal models with a larger sample size and less variance before firm conclusions can be drawn as to the status of the MMP9i's putative protective ability. Finally, the MMP9 inhibitor failed to improve the performance of treated wild type C57Bl/6 mice or THY-1-APP transgenic mice on a behavioural test for episodic-like memory. The author concludes that the MMP9i is worthy of future investigation as a therapeutic agent and that if one hopes to correct cognitive dysfunction then co-administration of other therapeutic agents may also be necessary.</description><creator>Hackett, Aaron</creator><contributor>Claudio Cuello (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>The cholinergic system and pharmacological inhibition of MMP-9 in the McGill THY-1APP mouse model of Alzheimer's disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v923c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qq71s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43p1733</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Objectifs: Pour étudier l'effet de Oral Health Technology Assessment (OHTA) sur Evidence-Based Decision Making (EBDM) dans le programme de premier cycle de médecine dentaire. Méthodes: Cette étude a été réalisée à deux niveaux: 1) la revue de la littérature où les bases de données électroniques, y compris PubMed, MEDLINE, EMBASE, Cochrane Library, et CINHAL ont été fouillés, et 2) Une évaluation des besoins au moyen des entrevues avec des membres du corps professoral et diplômés stagiaires pour une évaluation systématique des technologies dentaires a été réalisée à l'Université McGill, faculté de médecine dentaire. Résultats: Notre évaluation préliminaire de l'évaluation des technologies dentaires dans les facultés canadiennes révèle un modèle de décisions prises au hasard, sans concerne envers l'adoption et l'utilisation de EBDM dans les programmes de premier cycle des facultés médecine dentaire. En plus, il n'y a aucune preuve de intégration de EBDM ou l'évaluation systématique des technologies dentaires dans les facultés dentaires. Conclusion: Dans la limite de cette étude, nos résultats suggèrent que l'évaluation systématique des technologies dentaires peuvent aider les facultés de médecine dentaire à intégrer EBDM dans leur curriculum et que les comités d'évaluation des technologies pourrait fournir aux membres du corps professoral et les étudiants les derniers développements dans les technologies dentaires qui peuvent être adaptés dans les curriculum dentaires.</description><description>Objectives: To investigate the effect of Oral Health Technology Assessment (OHTA) on Evidence-Based Decision Making (EBDM) in the undergraduate dental curriculum. Methods: This study was performed at two levels; 1) the literature review where electronic data bases including PUBMED, MEDLINE, EMBASE, COCHRANE LIBRARY, and CINHAL were searched, and 2) A need assessment by means of interviewing a few faculty members and graduating trainees for systematic evaluation of dental technologies was performed at the McGill University, faculty of Dentistry. Results: Our preliminary evaluation of assessing dental technologies in Canadian faculties reveals a random decision making pattern with no regards to adoption and utilisation of EBDM in undergraduate curriculum. There is also no evidence of either integrating EBDM or systematic evaluation of dental technologies in dental faculties. Conclusion: Within the limitation of this study our findings suggest that the systematic assessment of dental technologies may help faculties to integrate EBDM in their curriculum and that technology assessment committees could provide faculty members and students with the latest developments in dental technologies that are suitable for university dental clinics.</description><creator>Esfandiari, Mahsa</creator><contributor>Christophe Bedos (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Shahrokh Esfandiari (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health Sciences - Dentistry</subject><title>Can oral health technology assessment promote evidence-based decision making in undergraduate dental faculties?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d765q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p1733</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w95053995</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Freezing stress limits crop productivity and generates substantial economic losses every year. While most temperate cereal crops exhibit some degree of cold tolerance, they require exposure to low, non-freezing temperatures in order to acclimate. This involves the induced expression of cold-regulated (COR) genes. COR gene promoters contain sequences that are recognized by C-repeat Binding Factor 1 (CBF1), a transcription factor that may mediate gene expression via the SAGA (SPT-ADA2-GCN5-acetyltransferase) complex in response to cold stress. The goal of this study was to characterize the function of the adaptor protein ADA2, a member of the SAGA complex that may link CBF1 to chromatin remodeling proteins. Expression analysis confirmed that Brachypodium CBF1 and ADA2 were expressed synchronously in response to cold treatment. Bimolecular fluorescence complementation (BiFC) analysis demonstrated that ADA2 and CBF1 interact directly in planta. These results further support the hypothesis that the SAGA complex exists in Brachypodium and that it may play an important role in mediating the cold response mechanism. </description><description>Pour les pays nordiques, les épisodes de gel précoces et tardifs limitent considérablement le rendement des cultures et génèrent de lourdes pertes économiques. Bien que la plupart des plantes céréalières cultivées au Canada possèdent d'emblée un certain niveau de tolérance au gel, elles nécessitent toutes une période d'exposition à de basses températures (de 2 à 10°C) afin de maximiser leurs niveaux de tolérance. Ce processus d'acclimatation repose sur l'expression induite des gènes COR (Cold-Regulated Genes) contrôlés en grande partie par le régulateur CBF1 (C-repeat Binding Factor 1). Récemment, il a été proposé que CBF1 pourrait interagir avec le complexe chromatinien SAGA dans le but d'accomplir sa fonction. Cette interaction serait médiée par une sous-unité du complexe SAGA, la protéine adaptatrice ADA2. Cette dernière représenterait donc le lien moléculaire unissant les mécanismes de régulation génique traditionnels et chromatiniens impliqués dans le développement de la tolérance au gel des plantes. Le but de cette étude était de caractériser l'interaction physique entre CBF1 et ADA2 dans un contexte in planta. Des analyses d'expression en temps réel ont démontré que BradiCBF1 et BradiADA2 sont exprimés de façon similaire en réponse aux basses températures. De plus, des analyses d'interactions utilisant la technique de complémentation bimoléculaire de fluorescence (BiFC) ont démontré pour la première fois une interaction in planta entre les protéines BradiCBF1 and BradiADA2. Les résultats présentés ici suggèrent fortement qu'un complexe apparenté au complexe SAGA existe chez Brachypodium distachyon et que ce dernier pourrait jouer un rôle important lors du développement de la tolérance au gel chez les plantes céréalières.</description><creator>Demone, Jordan</creator><contributor>Jean-Benoit Charron (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Characterizing the role of the transcriptional adaptor ADA2: an integrating node in the cold response mechanism in «Brachypodium distachyon»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wv011.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95053995</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059cb956</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La grande perche du Nile piscivore (Lates Niloticus) a été introduite dans le bassin du lac Victoria dans les années cinquantes et soixantes pour devenir une des espèces les plus précieuses pour l'économie de la pêche en intérieure de l'Afrique de l'est. Un taux de mortalité très élevé relié à la pêche contribuerait à des changements écologiques dramatiques pour l'espèce (réduction de la taille du corps et de la biomasse; changements dans la distribution et le régime alimentaire), et renforcerait les conventions de divergence écologique dans certains lacs de la région. Dans cette thèse, j'utilise une approche écologique évolutive pour explorer l'écosystème associé à la divergence écologique de la perche du Nile dans le lac Nabugabo en Uganda.  J'identifie le domaine vital, les schémas de mouvement et l'utilisation de l'habitat de la perche du Nile, et quantifie ainsi la divergence des phénotypes dans les différents habitats et toute l'ontogenèse de la perche du Nile. En utilisant la technique de la radiotélémesure, j'ai traqué 14 perches du Nile pendant 5 mois et avec l'ArcGIS 9.3, j'ai quantifié les schémas de mouvements dans le lac Nabugabo. J'ai associé les données des schémas de mouvement avec des données écologiques détaillées pour quantifier l'utilisation de l'habitat dans les zones de pêche intense du lac. La géométrie morphométrique et les analyses de couleur ont été utilisées pour quantifier les divergences dans la taille, forme et couleur des différentes classes de perche du Nile dans les habitats distincts de bord de forêts et de marécages. La perche du Nile a démontré des niveaux de mouvements journaliers peu élevés pour un domaine vital plutôt restreint; Elle préférait les régions du lac de basse température à oxygène hautement dissous. La géométrie morphométrique et les analyses de couleur ont révélé des divergences phénotypiques associées à l'écosystème dans la forme et la couleur de la perche, bien que ces tendances n'aient pas été constantes à travers toutes les classes de tailles. La source de la divergence phénotypique (génétique contre plastique) demeure inconnue; par contre, le niveau de ténacité au choix du site manifesté par la perche du Nile suggère que l'isolation écologique entre le bord de forêt et les marécages serait plus élevé que prévu. Ces résultats ont des implications importantes pour le développement d'une juridiction territoriale dans les Unités de Gestion des Plages (UPG), la structure décentralisée qui gère la pêche dans la région. Sachant que la perche du Nile, une des plus espèces les plus importantes pour la pêche commerciale dans le bassin du lac Victoria, démontre des domaines vitaux définissables fournit une raison biologique pour favoriser des délimitations territoriales de pêche par les UGP. Ces délimitations de ressources clairement définies pourraient motiver les membres des UPG à suivre le règlement des consignes de pêche et devenir essentiel pour améliorer l'efficacité des UGP.</description><description>The large piscivorous Nile perch (Lates niloticus) was introduced to the Lake Victoria basin in the 1950s and 1960s and eventually became one of the most valuable commercial species of East Africa's inland fisheries. Intense fishing-induced mortality may be contributing to dramatic ecological change in this species (reductions in body size and biomass; shifts in distribution and diet), and reinforcing patterns of ecological divergence in some lakes in the region. In this thesis I use an evolutionary ecology approach to explore habitat associated ecological divergence in the Nile perch in Lake Nabugabo, Uganda. I describe home range, movement, and habitat selection of Nile perch, and quantify divergence in phenotypic traits between major habitat types and across Nile perch ontogeny. Using radio telemetry I tracked 14 Nile perch for 5 months and used ArcGIS 9.3 to quantify movement patterns throughout Lake Nabugabo. I used movement data in combination with detailed ecological information to quantify habitat selection in the heavily fished inshore zones of the lake. Geometric morphometric and colour analyses were used to quantify divergence in body shape and skin colour across different size classes of Nile perch from ecologically distinct wetland and forest edge habitats. Nile perch exhibited low levels of daily movement and relatively small home ranges; and they preferred regions of the lake characterized by low temperature and high dissolved oxygen. Geometric morphometric and colour analyses revealed habitat-associated phenotypic divergence in both skin colour and body shape, although not all trends were consistent across size classes. The source of phenotypic divergence (genetic vs. plastic) remains unknown; however the level of site tenacity exhibited by Nile perch suggests that ecological isolation between forest edge and wetland fish may be higher than expected. These results have important implications for development of territorial jurisdiction by Beach Management Units, the decentralized structure of fisheries management in the region. Knowing that Nile perch, one of the most important commercial catches in the Lake Victoria basin, have definable home ranges provides a biologically relevant rationale for the insertion of territorial boundaries for BMUs. Clearly defined resource-use boundaries may provide additional incentives for members to follow fishery rules and may prove to be instrumental in improving BMU efficacy.</description><creator>Nyboer, Elizabeth</creator><contributor>Lauren Chapman (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Ecology</subject><title>Movement, home range, and ecological divergence in the commercially fished Nile perch in Lake Nabugabo, Uganda</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gp47q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059cb956</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128nj31g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In species with complex life cycles such as amphibians, population regulation can occur in one or multiple stages. Density effects in the larval, aquatic stage of the amphibian life cycle have been widely documented, leading many researchers to assume that this is the stage in which amphibian populations are regulated.  However, recent evidence suggests that factors affecting survival and reproduction in the terrestrial stage may play a greater role in the growth and decline of amphibian populations than previously thought. I review the evidence for density-dependent population regulation in the terrestrial stage of amphibians and argue that variation in body size may be an important mechanism linking population density to changes in population growth rate (CHAPTER ONE). I used data from a 23-year population survey at Long Point, Ontario and conducted summer growth-rate surveys to examine the body size-abundance relationship in Fowler's Toad (Anaxyrus fowleri). Over the past 10 years of the population survey at Long Point, we observed a significant increase in body size (R² = 0.874, p = &lt;0.001) that was coincident with a previously detected negative trend in abundance. The age structure of this population is highly unstable, but overall the average age is getting older (R² = 0.325, p= &lt; 0.01) (CHAPTER TWO). Somatic growth rates in Fowler's toad toadlets are also highly variable and are significantly inversely correlated with the density of adults (R² = 0.98, p = 0.010) (CHAPTER THREE). The single most important factor influencing average body size on a long time-scale is abundance (R² = 0.713, p = &lt;0.001) (CHAPTER FOUR). Therefore, body size variation in these toads is likely related to density-dependent resource availability for growth in the terrestrial stage.</description><description>Pour des espèces ayant des cycles de vie complexes tels les amphibiens, la régulation de leur population peut se produire dans un ou plusieurs stades. Les effets de la densité au stage larvaire aquatique du cycle de vie de l'amphibien ont été largement documentés amenant plusieurs chercheurs à assumer que c'est à ce stage que la régulation de leur population se produit. Toutefois, des preuves récentes suggèrent que des facteurs affectant la survie et la reproduction au stage terrestre peuvent jouer un plus grand rôle dans la croissance et le déclin de la population des amphibiens contrairement à ce que l'on pensait auparavant. Je fais la revue de la preuve de la régulation de la population qui dépend de la densité au stage terrestre des amphibiens et j'argumente que la variation de la masse corporelle pourrait être un mécanisme important reliant la densité de la population aux changements du taux de croissance de la population (CHAPITRE UN). J'ai utilisé les données d'un relevé de la population sur une période de 23 ans à Long Point, Ontario et mené des relevés du taux de croissance durant l'été afin d'examiner la relation entre la dimension et la masse corporelle du crapaud de Fowler (Anaxyrus fowleri). Durant les 10 dernières années du relevé de la population à Long Point, nous avons remarqué une augmentation significative de la masse corporelle (R² = 0.874, p = &lt;0.001) qui coïncidait avec une tendance négative de leur abondance détectée précédemment. La structure de l'âge de cette population est très instable, mais dans l'ensemble la moyenne d'âge est plus vieille (R² = 0.325, p= &lt; 0.01) (CHAPITRE DEUX). Les taux de croissance somatiques des petits du crapaud de Fowler sont hautement variables et inversement corrélatifs à la densité des adultes (R² = 0.98, p = 0.010) (CHAPITRE TROIS). Le seul facteur d'importance qui influence la dimension corporelle moyenne sur une longue période c'est l'abondance (R² = 0.713, p = &lt;0.001) (CHAPITRE QUATRE). Ainsi, la variation de la dimension corporelle de ces crapauds est vraisemblablement reliée à la croissance somatique laquelle dépend de la densité au stage terrestre. </description><creator>Middleton, Jessica</creator><contributor>David M Green (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Ecology</subject><title>Population ecology of a declining amphibian in relation to density</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m755p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nj31g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720h47k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Human activities, especially since the Industrial Revolution, have left a legacy of trace metal contamination that is potentially harmful for natural ecosystems and human health (e.g. As, Cd, Pb) and affected their geochemical cycles. Atmospheric metal pollution is recorded in different environmental archives such as lake and marine sediments, snow and ice and peat bogs. Among these archives, peat bogs have proven to be effective in reconstructing the history of atmospheric metal deposition throughout Europe, but few studies have been carried out in North America or in Quebec. Being an important natural wind corridor, oriented from south-west to north-east, the St. Lawrence Valley is affected by long-range transport of contaminants. The present study focuses on the reconstruction of the history of atmospheric As, Cd, Ni, Pb and Zn deposition in surface cores (&lt;100 cm) from three peat bogs along the St. Lawrence Valley. Core chronologies were established using 210Pb for the upper horizons and 14C dating for the deeper sections. Metal accumulation rates were computed from measured concentrations and core chronologies. Stable lead isotopes (204, 206, 207 and 208) were also analysed to distinguish natural and anthropogenic sources of Pb. Results show that the three cores recorded the onset of industrial activities around 1810-1850AD. As, Cd, Pb and, to a certain extent Ni deposition increased to reach a maxima in the 1940s and mid-1960s to early 1970s. Trace metals likely originated from coal-burning and ore smelting during the 19th and the first half of the 20th centuries. Thereafter, the dominant source of Pb became leaded gasolines additives until their phasing-out in the 1970s. Trace metal contents were greater in the two cores recovered in the southwestern part of the St. Lawrence Valley than in the one located 600 km to the northeast. This can likely be explained by their proximity to urban and industrial centers of St. Lawrence and Ottawa Valleys and U.S. Mid-West. The Pb isotope signatures suggest a long-range transport of contaminants from a common regional source (U.S. Mid-West, Great Lakes Region). A rapid decrease in metal accumulation rates since the 1970s suggest that the implementation of mitigation policies was effective in reducing atmospheric emissions of trace metal. Nevertheless, metal accumulation rates and stable Pb isotopes have not yet returned to pre-industrial values.</description><description>Les activités humaines, particulièrement depuis la Révolution Industrielle, ont perturbé le cycle géochimique de plusieurs métaux traces potentiellement toxiques (e.g. As, Cd, Pb) avec d'importantes répercussions pour les écosystèmes et la santé humaine. Plusieurs archives environnementales, tels les sédiments marins et lacustres, les tourbières, et les glaciers servent d'enregistrements historiques de la pollution atmosphérique. Parmi celles-ci, les tourbières sont reconnues comme étant des archives fiables pour la reconstruction des dépôts atmosphériques de métaux. Les tourbières ombrotrophes sont fréquemment utilisées en Europe pour reconstruire l'histoire des dépôts atmosphériques de polluants. Ce type d'étude est plus rare en Amérique du Nord, particulièrement au Québec. La vallée du St-Laurent est un corridor naturel important, dominé par des vents du sud-ouest vers le nord-est, et affecté par le transport de contaminants sur de longues distances. La présente étude a pour but la reconstruction historique des dépôts atmosphériques de As, Cd, Ni, Pb et Zn à partir de carottes de surface (&lt; 100 cm) récoltées dans trois tourbières ombrotrophes le long de la vallée du St-Laurent. La chronologie des carottes fût établie à l'aide de datations au 210Pb et 14C. À partir de ces chronologies, les taux d'accumulation de métaux traces d'origine atmosphérique furent calculés. Les isotopes stables du Pb furent aussi analysés afin de distinguer les sources naturelles et anthropiques du Pb. Les résultats démontrent que les trois carottes ont enregistré le début des activités industrielles entre 1810-1850AD. L'accumulation de As, Cd, Pb et, dans une certaine mesure, Ni a augmenté de façon constante pour atteindre des maxima dans les années 1940 et à la fin des années 1960 et début 1970. Les contaminants provenaient probablement de la combustion de charbon et des usines métallurgiques du 19ième et début du 20ième siècle. Par la suite, la source principale du plomb fut celle des essences plombées (tétraéthyl-plomb) jusqu'à leur élimination graduelle dans les années 1970. Les taux d'accumulation de métaux sont plus importants dans les deux carottes récoltées dans le sud-ouest de la vallée comparativement à celle située à 600 km au nord-ouest. Ce phénomène peut être expliqué par la plus grande proximité des centres urbains et industriels du Mid-Ouest des États-Unis et des Grands Lacs ainsi que des vallées du St-Laurent et d'Ottawa des deux sites du sud-ouest par rapport à celui au nord-est. Les isotopes du plomb suggèrent que les contaminants furent transportés sur de longues distances et tiennent leur origine de sources régionales, telles que le Mid-Ouest des États-Unis ou la région des Grands Lacs. Une diminution rapide des taux d'accumulation de métaux à partir des années 1970 suggère que les mesures de mitigation des émissions atmosphériques mises en place durant cette période furent efficaces. Par contre, les taux d'accumulation et la signature isotopique du Pb montrent que des sources anthropiques de métaux persistent puisqu'ils demeurent différents des valeurs préindustrielles.</description><creator>Pratte, Steve</creator><contributor>Alfonso Mucci (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Michelle Garneau (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Geochemistry</subject><title>History of atmospheric trace metal deposition along the St.Lawrence Valley (Quebec) using peat bog records</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290f145.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720h47k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65vc14j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Canadian seismic design provisions for cold-formed steel framed/steel sheathed shear walls have been developed from previous research at McGill University with the intent of being incorporated into the Canadian section of the North American Lateral Design Standard for Cold-Formed Steel Framing (AISI S213), and ultimately to provide guidelines for design of these systems in the National Building Code of Canada and CSA-S136 Specification.In this previous research, a limited number of shear walls displayed unfavourable damage due to twisting deformations of the chord-studs and by local buckling. Also, the shear walls tested in previous research were only laterally loaded. The objective of the current research program was to address this unfavourable failure mode by evaluating the performance of cold-formed steel framed/steel sheathed shear walls, constructed with blocked stud members, which were tested under combined gravity and lateral loading. In total, fourteen single-storey shear walls (8 configurations) were subjected to monotonic and CUREE reversed cyclic lateral loading protocols. The Equivalent Energy Elastic-Plastic (EEEP) approach was used to analyse the test data and determine nominal shear resistance values. Relevant design parameters were determined: a resistance factor, phi, of 0.7, an overstrength value of 1.4, and ductility and overstrength seismic force modification factors (Rd = 2.0 and Ro = 1.3). Dynamic analysis of a two storey representative building model was carried out to validate the 'test-based' R-values following a methodology adopted from FEMA P695 to evaluate the seismic performance of a building system.The research program indicated that the blocking reinforcement detail had adequately resolved chord-stud twisting deformations and that the chord-studs, once designed to carry the combined gravity and lateral forces following a capacity based approach, would not fail thereby preventing any detrimental collapse of the framing system.</description><description>Les dispositions de conception sismique pour les murs de refend (dotés de cadres ou de revêtements en acier laminé à froid) mises au point précédemment à l'Université McGill avaient pour but d'être ajoutées aux dispositions canadiennes présentées dans le North American Lateral Design Standard for Cold-Formed Steel Framing (AISI S213) et de proposer des lignes directrices qui pourraient être intégrées au Code national du bâtiment du Canada et à la norme CSA-S136. Au cours de ces recherches, un nombre limité de murs de refend ont été endommagés par le voilement local et les déformations des membrures-montants liées à la torsion. Les murs de refend avaient été uniquement testés sous l'effet d'une charge latérale. Ce programme de recherche tente de comprendre ce processus de défaut défavorable en évaluant la performance des murs de refend (dotés de cadres ou de revêtements en acier laminé à froid) construits à l'aide montants munis de cales et testés sous l'effet combiné de la gravité et de la charge latérale. Un total de quatorze murs de refend à un étage (8 configurations) ont été soumis aux protocoles de chargement monotone et de chargement cyclique-réversible de CUREE. La méthode équivalente de l'énergie élasto-plastique (EEEP) a été appliquée pour analyser les données des essais et déterminer les valeurs nominales de résistance au cisaillement. Les paramètres pertinents de conception ont été déterminés: un facteur de résistance (phi= 0.7), une valeur de sur-résistance de 1.4 et des facteurs de modification de force sismique reliés à la ductilité et à la sur-résistance (Rd = 2.0 et Ro = 1.3). Une analyse dynamique a été menée sur un modèle représentatif d'un bâtiment à deux étages pour valider les valeurs de R obtenues lors des essais. Une méthode adoptée par le FEMA P695 a servi à évaluer la résistance sismique d'un système de construction.Ce programme de recherche a montré que le dispositif de blocage de l'armature empêche adéquatement les déformations des membrures-montants liées à la torsion. Grâce à une approche de conception par capacité, des membrures-montants peuvent résister à l'action combinée de la gravité et des forces latérales, et ainsi prévenir l'effondrement de l'ossature du bâtiment.</description><creator>DaBreo, Jamin</creator><contributor>Colin Andrew Rogers (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Civil</subject><title>Impact of gravity loads on the lateral performance of cold- formed steel frame/ steel sheathed shear walls</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b467r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65vc14j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21tj99g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le paysage rural de la République Populaire de Chine s'est considérablement transformé depuis la collectivisation dans les années 50 jusqu'aux réformes de dé-collectivisation instauré par Deng Xiaoping en 1979. Au milieu des années 80, chaque ménage rural est redevenu responsable de sa propre production agricole et la sécurité alimentaire semble s'être améliorée, même dans les régions les plus reculées. Pour intensifier la transition agraire et le développement rural, l'état a commencé à la fin des années 90 à subventionner les cultures commerciales au niveau provincial, à travers sa « Stratégie de développement de l'ouest du pays ». L'objectif de ce mémoire est premièrement d'examiner l'importance des cultures commerciales subventionnées par l'état pour les agriculteurs, particulièrement issus des minorités ethniques (Yi, Hmong, Yao, et Zhuang) et de la majorité Han dans la Préfecture de Honghe, Yunnan; et deuxièmement d'évaluer les effets des phénomènes climatiques extrêmes sur leurs moyens d'existence et d'étudier les mécanismes de survie auxquels ils ont recours. Pour remplir cet objectif, j'utilise un cadre théorique incorporant les éléments clés des littératures sur les moyens d'existence durables, la sécurité alimentaire, ainsi que la vulnérabilité et la résilience à la variabilité du climat. Mes méthodes comprennent une analyse statistique des données quantitatives des récents phénomènes climatiques extrêmes dans la région et un travail ethnographique dans quatre cantons de la Préfecture de Honghe, notamment des entrevues non structurées avec les agriculteurs et semi-structurées avec les cadres locaux au cours de l'été 2011. Je constate que les cultures commerciales subventionnées par l'état ne s'accompagnent pas toujours d'une amélioration du capital financier des agriculteurs et que ces cultures sont de plus en plus exposées à de fortes précipitations et d'extrêmes températures, qui réduisent l'accès aux capitaux de subsistance, nécessaire au réinvestissement dans les cultures commerciales. Par conséquent, les agriculteurs développent des stratégies de survie et/ou d'adaptation selon leurs moyens d'existence choisis et le type de phénomènes climatiques, mais sont également affectés par leur emplacement et leur ethnicité. En somme, je remarque que l'accès des agriculteurs aux ressources est essentiellement fonction de trois variables : sociale, temporelle et spatiale ; celles-ci souvent ignorées par les cadres gouvernementaux.</description><description>The rural landscape of the People's Republic of China has changed dramatically from land collectivization in the 1950s to the decollectivization reforms initiated by Deng Xiaoping in 1979. By the mid-1980s each rural household had again become responsible for its own agricultural production, and food security began to improve, even within the most remote areas. To further this agrarian transition, in the late 1990s the central state devised the Western Development Strategy to advance its 'less developed' western regions, within which provincial governments subsidized cash crops. The aim of this thesis is first to examine the importance of cash crops and related subsidies for Han and minority nationality farmer households in Honghe Hani-Yi Autonomous Prefecture, Yunnan, China; second, to assess how extreme weather events affect these farmers' livelihoods and to investigate the coping mechanisms they employ. To answer this aim I draw on a conceptual framework that incorporates key elements from sustainable livelihoods, food security, and vulnerability and resilience to climate variability literatures. Focusing on four townships in Honghe Prefecture, southeast Yunnan, I completed statistical analyses of quantitative data regarding recent extreme weather events in the region and ethnographic fieldwork, including conversational interviews with farmers and semi-structured interviews with local officials completed in summer 2011. I find that state-sponsored cash crops do not always bring higher financial capital rewards and that cash crop farmers have been increasingly exposed to extreme precipitation and temperatures since the year 2000, which constrain their access to livelihood capitals, essential for (re)investing in cash cropping. In turn, farmers cope with and/or adapt to climate shocks according to their initial livelihood decision-making and the specifics of the event, while also being influenced by their location and ethnicity. In sum, I argue that farmers' vulnerability is rooted in social, temporal and spatial variables, many of which are not being considered by state officials.</description><creator>Champalle, Clara</creator><contributor>Sarah Turner (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Social Sciences - Geography </subject><title>Cash crops and climate shocks: flexible livelihoods in Southeast Yunnan, China</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rm78z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21tj99g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8049g849f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette étude porte sur l'utilisation de Géospatiales Web 2.0 et Modèle Climatique Global pour le communication du changement climatique. Le but de cette recherche a été d'intégrer les données, les modèles et les outils de la science du climat avec Geoweb pour faire progresser la communication du changement climatique. Plusieurs applications de GeoWeb ont été développés pour démontrer les solutions de cette intégration et de remplir deux objectifs de recherche: (1) développer une méthode d' utiliser les technologies GeoWeb pour communiquer du changement climatique, (2) améliorer l'accessibilité de Modèle Climatique Global en fournissant des outils pour engager personnes dans la pratique de la science du climat, ainsi que les procédures fondamentales liées à la modélisation du climat mondial. Ma méthode de recherche est d'étendre les fonctionnalités de Geoweb à des outils existants des sciences du climat, dans le but d'alléger l'interface et en augmentant l'interactivité de ces outils pour élaborer le processus scientifique de la modélisation du climat. Geoweb a le pouvoir de manipuler des ensembles de données du changement climatique provenant de diverses sources pour créer une visualisation interactive du changement climatique. Ce pouvoir peut être encore améliorée si l'on intègre Geoweb avec analyse scientifique des données climatiques et des systèmes de visualisation. Néanmoins, les technologies GeoWeb qui fournissent une visualisation 2D sont plus stables, plus rapide et couramment utilisée que la visualisation 3D. Il est plus robuste à utiliser Geoweb pour la sortie des modèles climatiques. Au lieu de cela, en utilisant Geoweb pour d'autres aspects du modèle climatique global nécessite des coopérations étroites entre les scientifiques de modélisation du climat et des experts en technologie de GeoWeb en raison de sa complexité. Il est essentiel d'équilibrer un outil facile à utiliser l'interface utilisateur et la complexité des informations transférées. Suite à cette étude, il est à espérer que beaucoup plus d'efforts de groupes mondiaux de modélisation du climat et des chercheurs en sciences GeoWeb peuvent être réunis pour faciliter la communication pour le changement climatique.</description><description>This study investigates the use of Geospatial Web 2.0 and Global Climate Models for climate change communication. The aim of this research has been to integrate the data, models, and tools of climate science with Geoweb to advance climate change communication. Several Geoweb applications have been developed to demonstrate the solutions for this integration and to fulfil two research objectives: (1) develop a method to employ Geoweb technologies for communicating climate change, (2) improve the accessibility of Global Climate Model by providing tools to engage people in the practice of climate science as well as the fundamental procedures involved in global climate modeling. My research method is to extend Geoweb functionality to existing climate science tools, with the goal of easing the interface and increasing the interactivity of those tools to elaborate the scientific process of climate modeling. Geoweb has the power to manipulate climate change datasets from diverse sources for creating interactive climate change visualization. This power can be further enhanced if we integrate Geoweb with scientific climate data analysis and visualization systems. Nonetheless, Geoweb technologies that provide 2D visualization are more stable, faster, and popularly used than the 3D visualization. It is more robust to use Geoweb for climate model output. Instead, employing Geoweb for other aspects of global climate model requires close cooperation between climate modeling scientists and Geoweb technology experts due to its complexity. It is crucial to balance an easy-to-use user interface and the complexity of information transferred. Following this study, it is hoped that much more efforts from global climate modeling groups and Geoweb science researchers can be drawn together to facilitate climate change communication.</description><creator>Zhou, Jian</creator><contributor>Renee Sieber (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Social Sciences - Geography </subject><title>Integrating geospatial web 2.0 and global climate model for communicating climate change</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80j014n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g849f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591c663</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La structure de pointe d'écoulement tourbillonnaire d'une aile delta élancée à 65 ° (DW65) et non élancée à 50 ° (DW50) a été étudiée au nombre de Reynolds de l'ordre 105. Un accent particulier a été mis dans la variation des quantités d'écoulement tourbillonnaire et les paramètres d'écoulement critique avec un changement de l'angle d'attaque et de la distance en corde. En outre, la progression de l'éclatement du tourbillon avec l'angle d'attaque a été documentée sur la base de la pression et de l'information sur la vitesse tridimensionnelle. On a également discuté d'un aperçu de l'évolution de la turbulence de sillage. De plus, les forces aérodynamiques de portance et de traînée ont été évaluées sur la base des analyses de l'enquête sur le sillage et comparées avec des mesures directes de l'équilibre des forces. Une attention particulière a été portée sur la caractérisation de la traînée fondée sur la dépendance de la portance où la formulation de Maskell a été adoptée pour l'estimation de la traînée induite. Les résultats ont montré que l'écoulement sur DW65 et DW50 ont quelques ressemblances qualitatives, mais elles sont quantitativement deux écoulements contrastés. Avant l'éclatement, dans le cas de DW65, l'écoulement tourbillonnaire est quasi axisymétrique, mais dans le cas de DW50, le tourbillon et le noyau axial ne correspondent jamais et même la définition de centre du tourbillon distinctif est souvent ambiguë, sauf à des angles d'attaque plus élevés.  D'ailleurs, le noyau axial était toujours accompagné par un déficit dynamique important. La variation de la quantité d'écoulement tourbillonnaire dans la direction de l'écoulement a montré un comportement auto similaire lorsqu'elle est portée contre la distance radiale réduite par semi-envergure locale. Pendant que, fait intéressant, pour la DW50, un comportement auto similaire a été montré seulement par la variation de la perte de pression totale aux environs du cœur de la pression. Il a été établi que l'écoulement sur DW50 a été marqué par une interaction active de l'écoulement tourbillonnaire et de la couche limite en raison de la proximité du tourbillon de la surface de l'aile. Pour la première fois, la progression de l'éclatement du tourbillon sur la surface de l'aile a été signalée sur la base de l'information du système d'écoulement tridimensionnel qui a élucidé les indicateurs respectifs d'éclatement pour les ailes delta élancées et non élancées. Enfin, les analyses des enquêtes ont été menées et des comparaisons de différents modèles informatiques de portage et de mesure directe ont été présentées. En outre, l'estimation de la traînée de profil est sensible à la définition de la région de sillage tandis que l'éclatement tourbillonnaire en amont du bord de fuite a entraîné une sous-estimation et une surestimation de la traînée induite et du CL, respectivement. Pour tous les cas de l'aile élancée et les cas de l'angle d'attaque de l'aile delta non élancée ont montré que la traînée induite a toujours constitué plus de 50% de la traînée totale. Les résultats fournis ici ont fourni un aperçu approfondi et étendu sur les caractéristiques tourbillonnaires et aérodynamiques de l'aile delta élancée et non élancée</description><description>The leading-edge vortical flow structure over a 65ᵒ slender (DW65) and a 50ᵒ non-slender (DW50) delta wing was investigated at Reynolds number of order 105. Particular emphasis was placed in the variation of vortex flow quantities and critical flow parameters with change in angle of attack and chordwise distance. In addition, the progression of vortex breakdown with angle of attack was documented based on pressure and three-dimensional velocity information. A glimpse of wake-vortex evolution was also discussed. Moreover, aerodynamic lift and drag forces were evaluated based on wake survey analyses and compared with direct force balance measurements. Special attention was focused on drag characterization based on lift dependency where Maskell formulation was adopted for the estimation of induced drag. The results showed that the flow over DW65 and DW50 has some qualitative resemblances but quantitatively they are two contrasting flows. Prior to the breakdown, in the case of DW65, the vortical flow is near-axisymmetric but in the case of DW50, the vortex and axial core never matches and even the definition of distinctive vortex center is often ambiguous except at higher angles of attack, moreover the axial core was always accompanied by large momentum deficit. The variation of vortex flow quantities in streamwise direction showed self-similar behavior when plotted against radial distance scaled by local semi-span while interestingly for DW50 self-similar behavior was showed only by the variation of total pressure loss about the pressure core. It was established that the flow over DW50 was marred by an active interaction of vortical and boundary layer flow due to the close proximity of vortex to the wing surface. For the first time the progression of vortex breakdown over the wing surface was reported on the basis of three-dimensional flow information which elucidated the respective indicators of breakdown for slender and non-slender delta wings. Lastly, wake survey analyses were carried and comparison of different lift computational models and direct measurement were presented. Moreover, the estimation of profile drag is sensitive to the definition of wake region whereas vortex breakdown upstream of trailing-edge resulted in underestimation and overestimation of induced drag and CL, respectively. For all the cases of slender wing and high angle of attack cases of non-slender delta wing showed that the induced drag always constituted more than 50% of the total drag. The results provided here provided a deepened and extended insight on vortical and aerodynamics characteristics of slender and non-slender delta wing. </description><creator>Dogar, Muneeb</creator><contributor>Timothy Lee (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical </subject><title>An experimental investigation of aerodynamics and flow characteristics of slender and nonslender delta wings</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mt45s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591c663</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999b216</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Radio Frequency Identification (RFID) technology is widely used for variousapplications from access control to object tracking systems. Automation and fasterservices provided by this technology have striking effects on our daily life. However,there are several security and privacy concerns about RFID systems that remainunsolved. During the past years, several attacks have been designed against MifareClassic and HID iClass, two of the most widely used RFID systems on the market.The aim of this study was to improve the security and privacy mechanisms of RFIDsystems through the development of tools and the methodology of system analysis, inthe hope to find the possible flaws before the adversaries do. As an example, effortswere made to partially analyze OPUS cards (the RFID-enabled public transportationpasses in Montreal) and several security and privacy violating specifications of thesecards were highlighted. It was revealed that the static identification number of thecard is transfered in the anticollision process which can be used to track the cardholder without his consent. In addition, the information about the last three usages ofthe card (the time, the date and the metro/bus station) are transferred unencryptedand before the authentication process. Only a linear conversion is applied to theinformation which can be reversed by a simple application such as the one developedand provided in this study.Furthermore, design modifications to improve the security and privacy level of RFIDsystems were provided. These modifications are categorized based on the cost andthe disruption of service that the application of these modifications imposes to themanufacturing company.Key Words: RFID Systems, Privacy, Security, OPUS Cards</description><description>Les technologies de radio identiﬁcation (RFID) sont fortement utilisées dans diverses applications qui vont du contrôle d'accès aux systèmes de traçabilité d'objets. L'automatisation et la rapidité accrue des services que ces technologies rendent possibles ont des effets marqués sur notre vie quotidienne. Cependant, les systèmes RFID comportent de nombreux problèmes de sécurité et de protection de la vie privée qui ne sont toujours pas résolus. Au cours des dernières années, de nombreuses attaques ont été conues contre la puce Classic de MIFARE ainsi que la puce iClass d'HID, deux des systèmes RFID les plus répandus sur le marché. Le but de cette étude est d'améliorer les mécanismes de sécurité et de protection de la vie privée des systèmes RFID par le développement d'outils et la méthodologie d'analyse des systèmes, dans l'espoir de découvrir les failles de sécurité potentielles avant que des adversaires ne le fassent. Par exemple, nous avons procédé à une analyse partielle des cartes OPUS (les cartes qui contiennent les titres de transport en commun utilisés à Montréal, qui font usage de la technologie RFID), et mis en évidence de nombreux éléments des spéciﬁcations de ces cartes qui représentent une faille de sécurité ou de protection de la vie privée. Nous avons découvert que le numéro d'identiﬁcation statique de la carte est transmis durant le processus anticollision, ce qui peut être utilisé pour suivre la trace du détenteur de la carte sans son consentement. De plus, des informations concernant les trois dernières utilisations d'une carte (l'heure, la date, et la station de métro ou d'autobus) sont transmis sans être chiffrés, et avant le processus d'authentiﬁcation n'ait lieu. Seule une conversion linéaire est appliquée sur l'information, et cette conversion peut être inversée par une simple application telle que celle que nous avons développé au cours de cette étude. De plus, nous présentons des modiﬁcations visant à améliorer le niveau de sécurité et de protection de la vie privée des systèmes RFID. Nous classons ces modiﬁcations sur la base de leur coût et de la gravité des interruptions de service que l'application de ces modiﬁcations ferait subir au manufacturier.Mots clés: Systèmes RFID, protection de la vie privée, sécurité, cartes OPUS</description><creator>Yassaei, Mahshid</creator><contributor>Claude Crepeau (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>José Manuel Fernandez (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>Security and privacy analysis of radio frequency identification systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vm55d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999b216</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j67317584</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La structure laminaire du neocortex est universelle. Au-delà de petites variations dans la structure et la composition cellulaire, l`organisation des 6 couches corticales est conservé à travers tout les mammifères. Pourtant, la fonction des différentes couches corticales est largement inconnue. Ici, nous examinons si les sources et puits de courent observés durant làctivité neuronale spontanée sont distribués de façon aléatoire dans les couches corticales ou si des motifs reproductibles peuvent être observé. Pour examiner cette question, nous avons enregistré des potentiels de champs locaux (LFP) avec une électrode linéaire positionnée perpendiculaire à la surface corticale de làire S1Fl du cortex somato-sensoriel du rat. Afin d`éliminer l`impact de la référence électrique commune, la densité de sources de courent (CSD) a été calculé à partir des LFP. De plus, le CSD a été filtré dans les bandes classiques de EEG. Ensuite, afin de réduire la dimensionnalité des données, lànalyse des composantes principales (PCA) a été appliqué. Finalement, les composantes temporelles indépendantes (tICA) ont été calculées pour chaque bande de fréquence en utilisant làlgorithme FastICA. La reproductibilité du motif laminaire fût testée pour chaque composante.Nos résultats suggèrent des motifs laminaires de dipôles de source de curent qui sont reproductible à travers les différentes sessions et sujets. Pour la majorité des bandes de fréquence, la contribution maximale à l`énergie du signal vient des couches 4, 5a et 5b. La profondeur des dipôles dépend de la bande de fréquence. Dans la bande delta (1-4 Hz), le dipôle majeur est situé dans la couche 6. Dans la bande theta (5-8 Hz) et alpha (9-14 Hz), les dipôles reproductibles sont situés dans les couches 4, 5a et 5b. Dans la bande beta (15-30 Hz) un dipôle a été observé dans les couches 5a et 5b. Finalement, dans la bande gamma (30- 50 et 50-100 Hz), le dipôle majeur est situé dans les couches 3 et 4.Nos résultats suggèrent que les sources et puits de curent observées durant làctivité neuronale spontanée présentes de motifs laminaires reproductibles et ne sont donc pas aléatoires. Nos supposons que ces composantes indépendantes reflètent des contributions séparées du thalamus et des autres régions corticales.</description><description>The laminar structure of the neocortex is universal. In spite of some variation in structure and cell type, the composition of the 6 cortical laminae is conserved in virtually all neocortical areas and amongst all mammalian species. However, the function of cortical layers remains largely unknown. Here we seek to determine whether laminar-specific spontaneous current sources and sinks are distributed randomly, or whether they show repeating patterns. We further aim to investigate whether the time-course of current sources and sinks can be decomposed into separate independent components.To this end, we recorded Local Field Potentials (LFPs) from a linear array of equally spaced electrodes positioned locally perpendicular to the cortical manifold in rat somatosensory area S1Fl. The frequency-band specific Current Source Density (CSD) was derived from the filtered LFPs, which warded off the effects of volume conduction and resulted in reference independent signals.  Principal Component Analysis (PCA) was applied to the CSD data in order to reduce dimensionality and noise, and to perform whitening. Temporal Independent Component Analysis (ICA) was then applied to each of the frequency-band specific CSD with reduced dimensions using the FastICA methods. The column vectors of the mixing matrix represent the spatial weights or 'strength of neural activation' across cortical layers, associated with each independent component. We tested the repeatability and reliability of the pattern of laminar activity across the cortex.The results show patterns of laminar-specific dipoles of current sources and sinks that are repeatable across sessions/subjects. Across most of the frequency bands, the maximum contribution towards the signal power is from layers 4, 5a and 5b. The cortical depth of dipoles depends on the frequency band. In the delta (1-4 Hz) band, a prominent dipole was observed in layer 6. In the theta (5-8 Hz) and alpha (9-14 Hz) bands, repeating dipoles overlap with layers 4, 5a and 5b. In the beta (15-30 Hz) band, a dipole was observed in layers 5a and 5b. In the low and high gamma bands (30-50 and 50-100 Hz, respectively), prominent dipoles overlapped with layer 3 and 4. Our findings suggest that spontaneous current sources and sinks emerge in a non-random, laminar and frequency-band specific manner, showing independent components that are consistent across runs and animals. We hypothesize that these independent components reflect separate contributions of thalamo-cortical input and of spontaneous activity of cortical origin.</description><creator>Vijayaraghavan Iyengar, Anupama</creator><contributor>Doina Precup (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Amir Shmuel (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Independent component analysis of spontaneous laminar specific current sources and sinks in area S1 of the rat brain</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988p53v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j67317584</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wk68v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, a laboratory scale-pilot twin roll casting plant at CANMET-MTL is considered for modelling for control synthesis. Three important parts of the plant are considered for modelling: feeding system, solidification process and deformation process. The TRC machine is multi-input multi-output (MIMO) and nonlinear in nature. A simplified 2 X 2 feedback linear dynamical model is developed based on first principles and engineering intuition due to the lack of experimental data from the TRC machine. The proposed manipulated variables are the melt inflow rate and rollers angular velocity whereas the corresponding controlled variables are the head-box melt level and roll separating force. In this model, the effect of metallostatic pressure on solidification front position is modelled as a spring-damper mechanical system. Different parameter values of the first-order model are empirically tested until smooth movement of the solidification fronts is obtained. Casting speed is optimized using a theoretical model validated using numerical simulation data. The proposed model is mainly used to control the roll separating force in steady-state and maintain nominal performance. Therefore, simple proportional-integral (PI) decentralized controllers are designed using a trial-and-error method as a first attempt to control the process. Then a design of multivariable H-infinity optimal control is carried out using MATLAB hinfsyn function.</description><description>Dans cette thèse, un procédé pilote de coulée en bande à double rouleau de magnésium du laboratoire CANMET-MTL est considéré pour la modélisation orientée pour la conception de contrôleurs. Trois sections importantes de ce procédé sont considérées pour la modélisation: le système d'alimentation, le processus de solidification et le processus de déformation. La machine de coulée à double rouleau (twin-roll casting-TRC) est de nature multientrées-multisorties et non linéaire. Un modèle dynamique linéaire simplifié 2 X 2 est développé en se basant sur des principes physiques et une intuition d'ingénierie dû au manque de données expérimentales sur la machine TRC. On propose les variables manipulées comme étant le débit d'entrée de métal en fusion ainsi que la vitesse angulaire des rouleaux, alors que les variables contrôlées correspondantes sont le niveau de liquidus dans la boîte d'alimentation et la force de séparation des rouleaux. Dans ce modèle, l'effet de la pression métallostatique sur la position du front de solidification est modélisé par un système mécanique composé d'un ressort et d'un amortisseur. Différentes valeurs de paramètres de ce modèle de premier ordre sont testées de façon empirique jusqu'à ce qu'un mouvement sans à-coups du front de solidification soit obtenu. La vitesse de coulée est optimisée en utilisant un modèle théorique validé par l'utilisation de données de simulation numérique. Le modèle développé est utilisé principalement pour réguler la force de séparation des rouleaux en régime permanent et pour maintenir la performance nominale. En conséquence, de simples régulateurs décentralisés de type proportionnel-intégral (PI) sont conçus en guise de premier essai pour contrôler le procédé. Puis, un contrôleur multivariable H-infini est conçu en utilisant la fonction hinfsyn dans Matlab.</description><creator>Alkefer, Osama</creator><contributor>Benoit Boulet (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Magnesium twin roll casting machine - modelling and control</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80j015x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wk68v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50h081x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Lenstra, Lenstra and Lov\'{a}sz (LLL) reduction is the most popular lattice reduction and is a powerful tool for solving many complex problems in mathematics and computer science. The blocking technique casts matrix algorithms in terms of matrix-matrix operations to permit efficient reuse of data in the algorithms. In this thesis, we use the blocking technique to develop two floating point block LLL reduction algorithms, the left-to-right block LLL (LRBLLL) reduction algorithm and the alternating partition block LLL (APBLLL) reduction algorithm, and give the complexity analysis of these two algorithms. We compare these two block LLL reduction algorithms with the original LLL reduction algorithm (in floating point arithmetic) and the partial LLL (PLLL) reduction algorithm in the literature in terms of CPU run time, flops and relative backward errors. The simulation results show that the overall CPU run time of the two block LLL reduction algorithms are faster than the partial LLL reduction algorithm and much faster than the original LLL, even though the two block algorithms cost more flops than the partial LLL reduction algorithm in some cases. The shortcoming of the two block algorithms is that sometimes they may not be as numerically stable as the original and partial LLL reduction algorithms. The parallelization of APBLLL is discussed.</description><description>Le Lenstra, Lenstra et réduction Lovasz (LLL) est la réduction de réseaux plus populaire et il est un outil puissant pour résoudre de nombreux problèmes complexes en mathématiques et en informatique. La technique bloc LLL bloquante reformule les algorithmes en termes de matrice-matrice opérations de permettre la réutilisation efficace des données dans les algorithmes bloc LLL. Dans cette thèse, nous utilisons la technique de blocage de développer les deux algorithmes de réduction bloc LLL en points flottants, l'algorithme de réduction bloc LLL de la gauche vers la droite (LRBLLL) et l'algorithme de réduction bloc LLL en partition alternative (APBLLL), et donner a l'analyse de la complexité des ces deux algorithmes. Nous comparons ces deux algorithmes de réduction bloc LLL avec l'algorithme de réduction LLL original (en arithmétique au point flottant) et l'algorithme de réduction LLL partielle (PLLL) dans la littérature en termes de temps d'exécution CPU, flops et les erreurs de l'arrière par rapport. Les résultats des simulations montrent que les temps d'exécution CPU pour les deux algorithmes de réduction blocs LLL sont plus rapides que l'algorithme de réduction LLL partielle et beaucoup plus rapide que la réduction LLL originale, même si les deux algorithmes par bloc coûtent plus de flops que l'algorithme de réduction LLL partielle dans certains cas. L'inconvénient de ces deux algorithmes par blocs, c'est que parfois, ils peuvent n'être pas aussi stable numériquement que les algorithmes originaux et les algorithmes de réduction LLL partielle. Le parallélisation de APBLLL est discutée.</description><creator>Xiao, Yancheng</creator><contributor>Xiao-Wen Chang (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>Two floating point LLL reduction algorithms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52jc448.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50h081x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g3684</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les plaques composites à renforts fibreux constituent en des ensembles de couches assemblées selon leur épaisseur de manière uni- ou multidirectionnelle afin d'obtenir des propriétiés de déformabilité ou de résistance optimales. Cette thèse se propose d'étudier les propriétiés élastiques effectives d'un composite à matrice de polyester renforcé par des fibres de carbone unidirectionnelle. Une simulation numérique est utilisée pour determiner les propriétiés élastiques equivalents dans l'hypothèse d'un comportement isotrope transverse au moyen d'un arrangement des fibres obtenu expérimentalement. Les estimation de ces constates élastiques obtenue par voie numérique sont comparées avec plusieurs estimations théoriques basées sur l'hypothèse d'un arrangement régulier des fibres et sur les fractions volumiques des constituants et leurs propriétés. Le travail est également étendu à l'identification des modules de glissement en plan et hors-plan d'une bande rectangulaire composite en polymère renforcée par des fibres de carbone. Les modules de glissement sont obtenus à partir de la rigidité torsionnelle déterminée expérimentalement et de technique de réduction de données basées sur le modèle de torsion de plaques rectangulaires orthotropes de Lekhnitskii. Cette etude examine également le comportement flexionnel d'une telle plaque rectangulaire chargée ponctuellement pour différentes conditions aux limites appliquées. L'assemblage du laminé est utilisé pour construire un modèle numérique de la plaque. La plaque laminée de composite utilisée dans les investigations expérimentales consiste en un ensemble de 11 couches à matrice polyester renforcée par des fibres de carbone. La fraction volumique de fibre dans la plaque est approximativement de 66%. Les résultats expérimentaux obtenus pour la déformée de la plaque ont été utilisée en vue de valider l'approche numérique qui prend en compte les grandes déflections sous l'hypothèse de petites déformations. Le travail investigue aussi l'effet d'une fissure sur le comportement global d'une plaque composite circulaire pour des conditions aux limites fixées et pour différentes configurations de fissures à travers la plaque, et soumise à une pression d'air uniforme. En particulier, l'influence de la longueur de fissure et de son orientation sur la réponse globale pression-déplacement est étudiée. L'assemblage de couches fissurées est également utilisé afin de construire un modèle non linéaire matériel de la plaque fissurée.</description><description>Fibre-reinforced composite plates consist of bonded layers of either unidirectionally or multi-directionally reinforced sub-elements, which are arranged in a way to achieve optimum deformability and failure characteristics. This thesis examines the effective elasticity properties of a unidirectionally reinforced carbon fibre-polyester composite. A computational simulation of an experimentally determined fibre arrangement is used to derive the effective elasticity properties of the transversely isotropic composite. The computational estimates for the elastic constants are compared with several theoretical estimates for the effective elasticity properties that are based on regular arrangement of the reinforcing fibres, their volume fraction and the elasticity properties of the constituents. This study also examines the flexural behavior of a locally loaded rectangular Carbon Fibre-Reinforced Polymer (CFRP) composite plate under different edge support conditions. The assembly of the laminae is used to construct a computational model of the plate. The layered composite CFRP plate used in the experimental investigation consisted of 11 layers of a polyester matrix reinforced with carbon fibres. The bulk fibre volume fraction in the plate was approximately 66%. The experimental results for the deflected shape of the plate were used to establish the validity of a computational approach that accounts for large deflections of the plate within the small strain range. This thesis also examines the role of a crack on the overall flexural behaviour of a circular layered composite CFRP plate with fixed boundary and different through crack configurations, which is subjected to uniform air pressure loading. In particular, the effect of crack length and orientation on the overall pressure-deflection behaviour of the plate is investigated. The assembly of the cracked laminae is also used to construct a non-linear model of the cracked plate. </description><creator>Nikopour Deilami, Hasan</creator><contributor>Selvadurai, A. P. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Civil</subject><title>Mechanics of fibre reinforced composite plates: Experiments and computational modelling</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kk730.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g3684</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cf95jf744</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Existing theories of liberal multiculturalism do not adequately address the notion of ethnicity, which remains an important way that people recognize themselves and their identities. Taking the effects of ethnicity seriously forces us to theorize ways that individuals and groups access political and social belonging. This thesis proposes a revised understanding of patriotism and diaspora as multicultural strategies to manage ethnic diversity in the hopes of improving our analytical framework. </description><description>Les théories actuelles du multiculturalisme libéral ne répondent pas adéquatement à la notion d'ethnicité, qui reste un moyen important pour que les gens se reconnaissent eux-mêmes et leurs identités. En prenant les effets de l'appartenance ethnique au sérieux, nous devons forcément oblige à théoriser sur  les moyens queles individus et les groupes utilisent pour accéder à l'appartenance sociale et politique. Cette thèse propose une compréhension révisée du patriotisme et de la diaspora en tant que stratégies multiculturelles pour gérer la diversité ethnique en vue d'améliorer notre cadre d'analyse.</description><creator>Power, Catherine</creator><contributor>Jacob Levy (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Political Science - General</subject><title>On the problem of ethnicity in multicultural theory: patriotism and diaspora reconsidered</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b6994.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jf744</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n870zv130</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:54:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Contexte: L'endocardite infectieuse (EI) est une infection de la couche la plus interne du cœur. Les lignes directrices de l'American Heart Association concernant la prévention de l'EI ont progressivement évolué au cours des dernières décennies. Selon les recommandations révisées en 2007, le nombre de groupes ciblés pour l'antibioprophylaxie avant des interventions dentaires invasives a considérablement diminué. Les données probantes sur ces lignes directrices sont limitées. Précisément, le risque de l'EI chez les patients atteints de cardiopathie congénitale (CPC) est inconnu. Nous avons cherché à déterminer l'incidence cumulative et les facteurs prédictifs liés au développement d'EI chez les enfants ayant une CPC. Méthodologie: En utilisant une cohorte des patients atteints de CPC qui provenait des données administratives du Québec, nous avons identifié tous les patients ayant CPC qui étaient des enfants (0-18 ans) pendant une partie ou toute la période entre 1990 et 2005. Une étude cas-témoins nichée dans la cohorte, dont les cas et les témoins étaient appariés sur le temps d'observation, a été menée afin d'analyser les facteurs prédictifs du développement de l'EI lors de l'enfance. L'incidence cumulative dès la naissance jusqu'à l'âge de 12 ans a été décrite chez le sous-ensemble des enfants nés au cours de la période d'observation et a été déterminée par le complément de l'estimateur de Kaplan-Meier. L'EI incidente a été définie comme le premier diagnostic CIM-9 (Classification internationale des maladies) dans le registre des congés hospitaliers. Deux autres définitions d'issue comportaient l'examen manuel des diagnostics d'EI au congé hospitalier, ainsi que tous diagnostics d'EI rendus en milieu hospitalier. Résultats: 39 977 enfants (0-18 ans) atteints de CPC sont suivis pendant 336 661 patients-années dont 118 cas de l'EI sont observés. Parmi ceux-ci, 63 cas sont survenus chez 22 589 enfants qui sont suivis dès la naissance jusqu'à l'âge de 12 ans. Le risque moyen de l'EI avant l'âge de 12 ans était 3,7 pour 1000 enfants (intervalle de confiance [IC] à 95%: 2,9 – 4,9). Selon les différentes définitions de l'EI, ce risque variait de 2,1 à 11,3 cas pour 1000 enfants. La chirurgie cardiaque 6 mois avant la date index était fortement associée à l'EI, le rapport de taux ajusté [RR] 10,74 (IC à 95%: 3,79 – 30,45). Les RR (IC à 95%) pour les types de CPC par rapport aux lésions des shunts étaient: CPC cyanogène 5,51 (3,20 – 9,48); communication auriculoventriculaire 3,98 (1,89 – 8,36); lésions du côté gauche 2,48 (1,35 – 4,55); lésions du côté droit 1,54 (0,64 –3,71); autre CPC 1,94 (1,02 – 3,65). Le jeune âge était un facteur prédictif fort: âge &lt; 3 ans 2,94 (1,92 – 4,52); âge 3-6 ans 0,72 (0,38 – 1,37); par rapport à l'âge 6-18. Qualitativement ces résultats étaient insensibles aux définitions de l'EI. Conclusions: Nous avons démontré que le risque de l'EI chez les enfants étaient le plus élevé au cours des premières années de la vie, variait considérablement par le type de CPC, et était fortement associé à la chirurgie cardiaque dans les 6 mois précédents. Ces résultats aident à identifier des enfants à haut risque de l'EI et devraient contribuer à orienter les prochaines modifications aux lignes directrices sur la prévention de l'EI. </description><description>Background: Infective endocarditis (IE) is an infection of the innermost layer of the heart. The American Heart Association guidelines for IE prevention have gradually evolved over the last decades, with the 2007 recommendations reducing the groups of patients indicated for antibiotic prophylaxis before invasive dental procedures. The evidence base for the guidelines is limited. Specifically, the risk of IE in a population-based cohort of patients with congenital heart disease (CHD) has not been reported. We sought to determine the cumulative incidence and predictors of the development of IE in children with CHD.Methods: We identified all patients with CHD who were children (0-18 years) during all or part of the observation period from 1990-2005 using a cohort of patients with CHD in Quebec derived from the province's administrative databases. Predictors of childhood acquisition of IE were analyzed using a calendar time-matched nested case-control design. Cumulative incidence from birth to age 12 was described in the subset of children born during the observation period and was computed as the complement of the Kaplan-Meier estimator. Incident IE was defined as the first ICD-9 diagnosis in the hospital discharge records. Two alternative definitions of the outcome involved a manual review of discharge diagnoses and any hospital-based IE diagnoses.Results: 39,977 children (0-18 years) with CHD were followed for 336,661 patient-years and 118 cases of IE were observed. Of these, 63 cases occurred in 22,589 children followed from birth to age 12. Overall, the average risk of IE by age 12 was 3.7/1,000 children (95% confidence interval [CI] 2.9 – 4.9). It ranged from 2.1-11.3 cases/1,000 children based on the alternative outcome definitions. IE was strongly associated with cardiac surgery 6 months before the index date, adjusted rate ratio [RR] 10.74 (95% CI: 3.79 – 30.45). The RRs (95% CI) for CHD types compared to shunt lesions were as follows: cyanotic CHD lesions 5.51 (3.20 – 9.48); endocardial cushion defects 3.98 (1.89 – 8.36); left-sided lesions 2.48 (1.35 – 4.55); right-sided lesions 1.54 (0.64 – 3.71); other CHD 1.94 (1.02 – 3.65). Young age was a strong predictor: age &lt; 3 years 2.94 (1.92 – 4.52); age 3-6 years 0.72 (0.38 – 1.37); with age 6-18 as the reference group. These findings were qualitatively insensitive to the definition of IE.Conclusions: We documented that the childhood risk of IE was highest in the earliest years of life, varied substantially by CHD lesion, and was strongly associated with cardiac surgery in the previous 6 months. These results help identify children who are at elevated risk of IE and should inform the development of future IE prevention guidelines.</description><creator>Rushani, Dinela</creator><contributor>Ariane Marelli (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Jay Kaufman (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</subject><title>Cumulative incidence and predictors of infective endocarditis in children with congenital heart disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jz00j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zv130</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483n737</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:55:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cultivé dans le monde entier dans les zones tempérées, le pois sec (Pisum sativum L.) est cultivé pour sa richesse en protéines et sa capacité d'améliorer les conditions du sol.  Enfin de faciliter de futurs travaux de recherche, une population en ségrégation a été développée par « Single Seed Descent » après des croisements entre des lignes parentales.  Les véritables hybrides ont été identifiés au stade plantule en identifiant les polymorphes ADN hautement répétitif (AHR).  Les AHRs ou microsatellites sont des utiles précieux pour les évaluations de la diversité génétique car la connaissance de la diversité génétique est essentielle pour le développement de nouveau matériaux génétiques et des lignées d'élites.  Cinquante microsatellites et quatre marqueurs de transposons (deux transposons d'ADN et deux transposons d'ARN) ont été employé avec succès afin d'évaluer la diversité génétique de 35 accessions de Pisum.  Les statistiques par paires de la similarité  génétique ont varié entre 0.045 et 0.838.  L'information du contenu polymorphique (PIC) a varié entre 0.055 et 0.887 (moyen de 0.668).  Les marqueurs moléculaires qui ont été exploré  dans cet étude ont le potentiel d'identifier des nouvelles ressources pour la sélection assisté par marqueurs et pour le développement de lignées élites en réponse aux changements climatiques, à la diminution des terres et de l'eau disponible et des ressources énergétiques. </description><description>Field pea (Pisum sativum L.) is an important cool-season crop cultivated globally for its protein-rich seed and soil fertility benefits. A segregating population was developed by Single Seed Descent (SSD) methods following controlled crosses between parents that can establish a source for future studies including genetic mapping. True hybrids were identified at seedling stage using polymorphic Simple Sequence Repeats (SSRs). SSRs or microsatellites are also valuable tools for assessing genetic diversity in plants as knowledge of genetic diversity is essential for the development of new desirable germplasm and elite breeding lines. Fifty microsatellites and four transposon-based markers (2 DNA-transposons &amp; 2 RNA-transposons) were successfully employed in this study to assess genetic diversity in 35 diverse Pisum accessions. Pairwise genetic similarity ranged from 0.045 to 0.838. Polymorphic Information Content (PIC) ranged from 0.055 to 0.887 with a mean of 0.668. The Molecular markers explored in this investigation have potential to identify new resources for Marker-Assisted Selection (MAS) and future  development of elite pea breeding lines in response to climate change and declining land, water and energy resources.</description><creator>Ahmad, Sajjad</creator><contributor>Jaswinder Singh (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Agriculture - General</subject><title>Assessment of genetic diversity in Pisum germplasm for field pea improvement</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k35697799.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483n737</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1c18dk181</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:55:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Plusieurs études ont été réalisées pour étudier la dépendance énergétique des films dosimétriques GAFChromic® et ont montré que les modèles de film différents sont équivalents d'eau à environ 100 keV et leur réponse est indépendante de l'énergie à environ 100 keV. L'objectif de notre étude est d'étudier la dépendance énergétique des film commerciaux pour étudier la physique derrière la variation d'énergie ainsi que la dépendance énergétique intrinsèque de développer un nouveau prototype avec une réponse uniforme énergétique aux basses énergies (3.0 100 keV). L'étude se compose de deux éléments. Le premier est l'évaluation de la réponse énergétique de trois différents films dosimétriques GAFChromic® (EBT, EBT2 et EBT3), qui ont été fabriqués à jour, qui est effectuée par l'irradiation des films à une dose fixe de 2 Gy à l'eau à différentes qualités de rayonnement et mesurer la réponse correspondante au film, c'est à dire la variation nette de la densité optique, à l'aide d'un scanner à plat de documents. Puis, en utilisant le code Monte Carlo, DOSRZnrc, qui est l'un des codes d'utilisateur du code EGSnrcMP (Electron-Gamma-Shower) pour calculer la dose absorbée a lèau correspondant à la dépendance énergétique des films. Le deuxième élément est le réglage de la composition de la couche sensible des films à ainsi réduire la dépendance énergétique de la réponse du film à basse énergie avec l'aide des simulations de Monte Carlo. En utilisant ce procédé la réalisation de prototypes de nouveaux films basé sur l'éventuelle nouvelle compositions élémentaires ont été tester expérimentalement pour la dépendance énergétique. L'amélioration de la dépendance énergétique aux basses énergies va rendre les films dosimétriques plus adapté pour la dosimétrie de haute qualité. Puisque le spectre de rayons X changes la qualité et la quantité avec la profondeur en pénétrant dans les tissus du patient, il est très important que la réponse d'un détecteur en fonction de la qualité du faisceau être le plus plat possible pour minimiser l'incertitude et lèrreur dans la détermination de la dose. Donc, améliorer la dépendance énergétique aux basses énergies donnera lieu à l'amélioration de la précision de la dosimétrie du film. Il serait très pratique pour la dosimétrie d'avoir une courbe de calibration pour les films qui fonctionne dans une large gamme d'énergies. Donc par exemple, vous pourriez d'établir la courbe de calibration au faisceau de Cobalte-60 et l'utiliser pour la dosimétrie au energies de kilovoltage ainsi que d'autres faisceaux de haute energies.</description><description>Many studies have been conducted to investigate the energy dependence of External Beam Therapy (EBT) GAFCHROMICTM dosimetry films and showed that the different film models are water equivalent down to about 100 keV and their response is energy independent down to about 100 keV. The purpose of our study is to investigate the energy dependence of commercially available films to understand the physics behind the energy variation of the films response as well as the intrinsic energy dependence and to develop a new prototype with more uniform energy response at low energies (≤100 keV). The study is comprised of two components. The first component is evaluating the energy dependence of three different commercial GAFCHROMICTM dosimetry film models that represent the three different film configurations, EBT, EBT2 and EBT3 that have been manufactured up to date. The energy dependence evaluation can be further divided into two parts. The first part is experimentally evaluating the energy dependence of the response by irradiating the films to a fixed dose of 2Gy to water at different beam qualities (ranging from 50kVp to 60Co) and then measuring the corresponding response of the film, i.e. net optical density change, using a flat bed document scanner. The second part of the energy dependence evaluation is using the DOSRZnrc Monte Carlo code, which is one of the user codes of the EGSnrcMP (Electron-Gamma-Shower) Monte Carlo code, to calculate the corresponding absorbed dose to water energy dependence of the films, i.e. the ratio of dose to water to dose to the active volume of the film, using the experimental beams spectra, which were calculated using SpekCalc, an x-ray spectrum generating software, by matching the measured HVL, tube potential and added filtration of the experimental beams. The first component of our study would help us 1) understand the physics behind the energy variation of the film response, 2) evaluate the intrinsic energy dependence of the film, i.e. dose to film sensitive layer per unit film response as a function of beam quality, using the measured energy response and the corresponding absorbed dose to water energy dependence, 3) guide us to what can be done to improve the energy dependence at low energies. The second component of the study is adjusting the film sensitive layer composition with the guidance of Monte Carlo simulations of the absorbed dose to water energy dependence of the film to reduce the energy dependence of the film response at low energies, and making new film prototypes based on the new possible elemental compositions, then experimentally evaluating their energy response. Improving the energy dependence of the EBT GAFCHROMICTM  dosimetry film at low energies will make it more suitable for high quality clinical dosimetry. It would be very convenient for clinical dosimetry to have one film dosimetry calibration curve that works at kilovoltage and megavoltage beam qualities. This would allow us to create the film dosimetry calibration curve at, for example, 60Co and then use it for film dosimetry at kilovoltage and other megavoltage beam qualities. On the other hand, since the x-ray spectrum changes in quality and quantity with depth as it penetrates into patient tissue, it is very important that the response of the detector as a function of beam quality be as flat as possible to minimize the uncertainty and error in dose determination. Thus, improving the energy dependence at low energy will result in improving the accuracy of film dosimetry.</description><creator>Bekerat, Hamed</creator><contributor>Slobodan Devic (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Jan Peter Frans Seuntjens (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Physics - Radiation </subject><title>Improving the energy response of external beam therapy (EBT) GAFCHROMIC Dosimetry films at low energies (s100keV)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cp487.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dk181</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Medical Physics Unit</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):15900</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>