<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:24:15Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33825" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj430643q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two classes of antimigraine drugs specifically target serotonin (5-HT) receptors: agonists of the 5-HT1B/1D receptors and antagonists of the 5-HT2B/2C receptors. They are respectively used in symptomatic and prophylactic treatments. The study of their mechanisms of action can assist in better uncovering the mechanisms underlying migraine. Using molecular, pharmacological, immunocytochemical and histochemical approaches, we have studied the distribution and the role of the 5-HT receptors targeted by these medications in human trigeminal ganglion (TG) and extracerebral vessels (PV), two tissues of primary importance in migraine pathology. We first focused our study of symptomatic treatment on sumatriptan, a drug which works with high efficacy but can trigger cardiac adverse-effects. Two mechanisms have been suggested to explain its therapeutic effect during migraine headache: the contraction of overly dilated PV and the inhibition of a neurogenic inflammation within meningeal tissues following the stimulation of TG. Sumatriptan's cardiac effects have been associated with the contraction of coronary artery (CA) in high-risk patients. In order to help develop drugs which minimize such harmful side-effects, we have identified in human the type and distribution of sumatriptan-sensitive receptors in TG, PV and CA. As sumatriptan has a high affinity for the 5-HT1B, 5-HT1D and 5-HT1F receptor subclasses, we used reverse transcriptase-polymerase chain reaction (RTPCR) to distinguish between them. We have demonstrated the non-selective distribution of the RNA for the 5-HT1D and 5-HT1F receptors in human TG and some PV whereas the 5-HT1B receptor mRNA was mainly expressed in PV. 5-HT1B and 5-HT1F receptor RNA have also been detected in the CA. We then used an in vitro vascular reactivity assay with receptor-selective agonists and showed that of these three receptor subclasses, only the 5-HT1B receptor elicits vasoconstriction in PV. Agonists for 5-HT1D and 5-HT1F could therefore potentially be anti-migraine compounds devoid of vascular adverse-effects. We followed this study by examining the medications used in prophylaxis which are antagonists at either 5-HT2B or 5-HT2C receptors. It has been suggested that stimulation of such receptors in the endothelium of cerebral vessels could trigger migraine via the release of nitric oxide, a compound both nociceptive and vasodilator. We have successfully demonstrated using RT-PCR that the 5-HT2B but not the 5-HT2C receptor RNA is present in cerebral vessels. We further utilized RT-PCR and immunocytochemistry to precisely localize the receptor and show its presence not, only in the endothelium but also the smooth muscle of cerebral vessels. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Bouchelet, Isabelle.</creator><contributor>Hamel, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Les recepteurs de la serotonine dans les traitements de la migraine : aspects neuronaux et vasculaires chez l'humain</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mk61rj81v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430643q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f1881n707</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>1. Distribution of the two photosystems (PS I and PS II) in the thylakoid membranes of the alga Euglena gracilis. The distribution of photosystem I and II (PS I and PS II) in the alga Euglena gracilis Z strain was studied by electron microscopic immunocytochemistry. In this alga, the thylakoids are not organized in gram structures, as they are in higher plants. Two different antibodies were used to identify PS I. One is directed against particles of PS I from maize and the other against the 60 and 62 kDa PS I reaction centre proteins of the cyanobacterium Synechococcus elongatus. Both antibodies demonstrated the presence of PS I in the two types of thylakoid membranes, appressed (AM) and non-appressed (NAM). Quantitative analysis showed that 60--74% of PS I is in the AM and 26--40% is in the NAM, and since about 80--90% of the membranes are AM, that PS I is more concentrated in the NAM. An antibody directed against the CP47 protein of PS II also revealed labelling in both types of thylakoid membranes (54% in AM and 46% in NAM). PS II is again more concentrated in the NAM. I demonstrated by the photo-oxidation of 3,3'-diaminobenzidine that there is PS I activity in the two types of membranes and, moreover, that there are changes in this activity during the light cycle of the cell. My results indicate that the distribution of PS I and PS II in Euglena gracilis Z strain is different from that of higher plants and is similar to that seen in green algae. The possible evolutionary significance of our observations are discussed. 2. Localization of the protein CP47 (plastid protein) in the mitochondria of euglenoids. The localization of the CP47 protein to the mitochondria of euglenoids was studied by electron microscopic immunocytochemistry. My results demonstrate that this protein, which is coded by chloroplast DNA in all algae and plants, is present in whole or in part in the mitochondria of Euglena gracilis and related euglenoids. I used two different antibodies against the protein CP47 (anti-CP47 from Chlamydomonas reinhardtii and S. elongatus) to test wild-type, light-grown, cells of Euglena. Both antibodies selectively labelled the mitochondria. These results furthermore suggest that this labelling is particularly associated with mitochondrial cristae. Anti-CP47 from S. elongatus also labelled the mitochondria of other euglenoids, such as dark-grown cells of Euglena gracilis, the mutant Y9Z1NaL, and Astasia longa. Since the CP47 protein is present in dark-grown cells and in the mutant Y9Z1NaL, which are organisms that do not have an active psbB gene, I suggest that a gene transfer has occurred from the plastid to the mitochondria during evolution. Because our results show the presence of CP47 in the mitochondria of Astasia longa, I postulate that the transfer occurred before the branching of Astasia from Euglena.</description><creator>Bonavia-Fisher, Bruna.</creator><contributor>Gibbs, S. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Thylakoids.</subject><subject>Euglena gracilis.</subject><subject>Photosynthesis -- Molecular aspects.</subject><title>Evidence that a chloroplast membrane protein is located in the mitochondria of photosynthetic and non-photosynthetic euglenoids</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977w72m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881n707</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dp025</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A series of full-scale, reversed cyclic tension and compression tests was conducted to aid in the development of constitutive relationships for predicting the seismic response of concrete elements. These specimens were constructed using normal and high-strength concrete and contained varying amounts of transverse reinforcement consistent with both beam and column detailing requirements for different ductility levels. The influence of several parameters was investigated, including the effect of confinement, bar buckling and concrete strength. Reversed cyclic loading tests were carried out on conventionally reinforced nominally ductile and ductile coupling beams constructed with normal and high-strength concrete. These tests investigated the effect of the design and detailing of the transverse reinforcement, as well as the strength of the concrete. Analytical models for the prediction of the reversed cyclic loading response of concrete and steel are presented and used to predict the reversed cyclic tension-compression response of the axially loaded specimens tested. These tension-compression models were used to develop a plane sections analysis program, which was capable of evaluating the reversed cyclic moment-curvature response of concrete members. These models were very effective at predicting the reversed cyclic responses of the axially loaded specimens, the coupling beams and a flexural wall.</description><creator>Bristowe, Stuart.</creator><contributor>Mitchell, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Seismic response of normal and high-strength concrete members</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hk852.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dp025</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rw16h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores the experiences of Canadian academic women in terms of location, space and voice. Within this qualitative study, the spaces of and for women within the university are examined by way of women's subjective experiences of 'value' and 'being valued'. Differences in experiences between women based on age, colour, tenure and academic rank are described through the voices of thirty academic women. The study argues that the "illusionary practices of equity" operating within the university milieu, exacerbate the tensions inherent in contradictory subject locations that women occupy within academe. The struggles of representation and identity within these contested spaces raise the challenges of whose voice will have space within the privileged locations of higher learning.</description><creator>Correa, Elaine.</creator><contributor>Ghosh, Ratna (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Jackson, Nancy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Sex discrimination against women -- Law and legislation -- Canada.</subject><subject>Women college teachers -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- Canada.</subject><title>Get out of my space! :"illusionary practices of equity"</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977w71b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rw16h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xs55md55w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Copper solubility in water vapor and liquid was measured in the HCl-NaCl-H 2O system at temperatures up to 400°C and vapor-saturated pressure by two series of experiments. The thermodynamic data from these experiments were then applied to model the genesis of volcanogenic massive sulfide deposits and the partitioning of copper between vapor and liquid. The solubility of copper in liquid was measured in vapor-saturated aqueous HCl/NaCl solutions at temperatures ranging from 40 to 300°C, total chloride concentrations from 0.01 to 1 m, and pH from 0 to 3.5. Copper was found to dissolve primarily as CuCl(aq), CuCl2- and CuCl32-. Data collected from the experiments were regressed to determine the equilibrium constants as functions of temperature (K): Cu(s) + 1/4O2(g) + H+ + xCl- = CuClx1-x +1/2 H2O(l), where x varied from 1 to 3. Data obtained on the solubility of copper in the liquid phase were used to model gold-copper and gold-zinc mineralization in VMS deposits. Equilibrium path calculations, employing EQ3/6, predict temperatures of precipitation, the paragenetic sequence of minerals, and the chemical composition of chimneys associated with vents on the seafloor at 21°N, East Pacific Rise. The modeling results suggest that the co-precipitation of gold with copper and zinc at different temperatures is determined by the behavior of their complexes in the solution. However, among the models simulated, only the conductive cooling model and combined mixing and cooling model predict the co-precipitation of gold and copper at high temperature (&gt;300°C) and gold-zinc at low temperature (&lt;250°C), which is common in VMS deposits. The solubility of CuCl(s) in the vapor was measured in a vapor-saturated H2O(I)-H2O(v)-NaCl-HCl (NaCl/HCl; 9:1) system at temperatures ranging from 360 to 400°C, and total chloride concentration from 0.01 to 5 m. At 360°C, the copper solubility can be described by the reaction: CuCl(s) + H2O(v) = CuCl⁺H2O(v), and the equilibrium relationship for this reaction by KC = mCuCl⁺H2Ov /rH2Ov , where mCuCl⁺H2Ov is the molality of copper in the vapor phase and rH2Ov is the density of water vapor; the log KC value is ~-2.01. At 380°C and 400°C, copper solubility is controlled by the reaction: CuCl(s) + 4 H2O(v) = CuCl ⁺ 4H 2O(v). The equilibrium relationship for this reaction is KC = mCuCl⁺4H2O v/r4 H2Ov , and the values of log KC values are 0.22 and 1.17 at 380 and 400°C, respectively. Partition coefficients for copper between vapor and liquid were calculated for the CuCl-NaCl-HCl-H2O(l)-H2O(v) system at the following conditions, where T = 400°C, P = water vapor saturated pressure, mNaCl = 0.5--2.3m, and mHCl = 0.001 m. The close similiarity of the partition coefficients for copper to those of sodium under the same conditions suggests that partitioning data for NaCl can be used to estimate copper (I) chloride partition coefficients at conditions for which no data are available.</description><creator>Xiao, Zhifeng, 1966-</creator><contributor>Williams-Jones, A. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Geology.</subject><subject>Geochemistry.</subject><title>Experimental and theoretical studies of the solubility of copper in liquid and vapor in the system NaC1-HC1-HO</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v838225m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55md55w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924d40b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Experiments were carved out in a stirred tank reactor with both two phase and three phase systems. A systematic examination of the effect of solid particles on parameters such as volumetric liquid-side mass transfer coefficient kLa, specific interfacial area a, gas holdup epsilong, bubble size dB, and average bubble residence time tau, was conducted. Both dimensional and dimensionless correlations were generated and conclusions were drawn. The work was carried out in the context of the industrial experience that stirred tank reactors are widely used in both metallurgical and chemical engineering processes that often involve gas absorption in two and three phase systems. The effect of solids loading on the oxygen absorption rate in stirred tank reactors is complex due to the interactions between bubbles and solid particles, and also between other parameters. The measurement of some parameters, such as bubble size, specific interfacial area, volumetric mass transfer coefficient, is difficult, and there are many discrepancies in the literature with respect to the form of the correlation for oxygen absorption rate and bubble size and also the explanation of the internal mechanisms. The present work found that kLa decreased with increasing solids volume fraction. This decrease was as much as 50% when solids loading was increased from 0 (water) to 14 vol% at a superficial gas velocity of 0.64 cm/s and a impeller speed of 400 rpm. The primary reason for this was due to the enhancing effect of solids on bubble coalescence and the increase of slurry density. Kolmogroff's turbulence theory was proved not applicable to the present STR and conditions. The cause for this was believed to be due to the fact that the power density in the STR was far from homogeneous, and the dynamic equilibrium between bubble breakup and the bubble coalescence was not established. Bubble size, dB, was found to be increased by increasing solids volume fraction. The increase was due to the direct enhancing effect of solids on bubble coalescence and due to less bubble recirculation, i.e., change of the bulk flow pattern, with increased solids loading. There was no direct relationship found between a change of the apparent viscosity of slurry and a change of bubble size. Therefore, the manner by which many people incorporated apparent viscosity into the correlation of dB is inappropriate. To properly describe the extent of bubble coalescence in three phase systems, a new parameter, the coalescence factor, fc, was defined in the present work. It was found that the coalescence factor decreased with increasing solids volume fraction and power input, but decreased with increasing superficial gas velocity.</description><creator>Xia, Qi, 1962-</creator><contributor>Harris, Ralph (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Gas absorption kinetics in STR's</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128ng355.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924d40b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x0715</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objectives of this research were to determine the prevalence of anemia, and identify risk factors for anemia, in 9-month-old Cree infants living in northern Quebec. The prevalence of anemia (hemoglobin &lt;110 g/L) was 25--32%, depending on the study sample. Iron deficiency was present in 28.2% of infants who could be classified and 14.4% had iron deficiency anemia. Fewer than 2% of infants had low birth weight (&lt;2500 g) so most infants should have been born with adequate iron stores. One cause of anemia that was identified was a diet that was low in iron. Only 15.1% of infants were reported by guardians to eat meat daily and 28.5% were reported to never eat meat. Infants who were breastfed or cow's milk fed did not obtain sufficient iron for effective erythropoiesis. Compared with formula that was predominantly iron fortified, the odds ratio (OR) for anemia was 7.9 (95% CI 3.4--18.2) for breast milk and 5.0 (95% CI 2.0--12.7) for cow's milk. When milk type was controlled for, weight gain since birth was significantly associated with microcytic erythrocytes (OR comparing the highest tertile of weight gain to the lowest tertile 2.9, 95% CI 1.2--6.6). This indicates that fast-growing infants were not meeting their iron needs for growth. Another risk factor for anemia that was identified was common childhood infections. The prevalence of anemia among infants reported as recently unwell with an infection was higher than among infants reported as recently well (31.1% vs. 19.0%, chi2 = 4.27, p = 0.039). The prevalence of elevated blood lead was 2.7% and is not a major public health problem. No evidence for vitamin A deficiency was found. Serum retinol was positively associated with all iron status indicators. Cree infants who were given supplements containing vitamin A had a lower prevalence of anemia (hemoglobin &lt;105 g/L) (10.8% vs 23.2%, chi2 = 5.97, p = 0.015). These results suggest a role for vitamin A in iron metabolism. To prevent anemia in aboriginal i</description><creator>Willows, Noreen D.</creator><contributor>Gray-Donald, Katherine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Cree Indians -- James Bay Region -- Food.</subject><subject>Iron deficiency anemia -- James Bay Region.</subject><subject>Iron deficiency diseases in infants -- James Bay Region.</subject><subject>Infants -- Nutrition -- James Bay Region.</subject><title>Anemia in James Bay Cree infants of northern Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354g996.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x0715</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zc83f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Oligonucleotides containing the modification 2-fluoro-2-deoxy-beta-D-arabinose (2'F-ANA) were synthesized via solid phase synthesis in order to investigate their ability to bind to nucleic acids (DNA and RNA). The ability of this modification to serve as a suitable antisense oligonucleotide construct was also evaluated. All four nucleobase monomers (thymine, cytosine, adenine and guanine) were prepared for solid phase oligonucleotide synthesis, from which homopolymeric and heteropolymeric base sequences were assembled. These molecules bound with very good affinities to both DNA and RNA targets. Structural studies via NMR experiments demonstrated that in a 2'F-ANA/RNA duplex the 2'F-ANA residues adopt an O4' -endo conformation, similar to what has been proposed for the structure of DNA in a DNA/RNA hybrid. A 2'F-ANA oligopyrimidylate formed a triple-helical complex with duplex DNA and hybrid DNA(Pu):RNA(Py) with an affinity higher than that of a corresponding DNA strand. Also, a cytosine-rich 2' F-ANA strand was found to form a complex at acidic pH which has properties similar to that of i-motif DNA. Finally, 2'F-ANA strands when hybridized to RNA were found to activate RNase H, an enzyme that is involved in the mechanism of action of antisense drugs. 2'F-ANA is the first example of an antisense analogue that demonstrates improved binding to RNA relative to DNA and still retains the ability to elicit RNase H activity.</description><creator>Wilds, Christopher James.</creator><contributor>Damha, Masad Jose (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Synthesis, physicochemical and biological properties of oligonucleotides containing 2-fluoro-2-deoxy-℗-D-arabinose</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429b87s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zc83f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20sv45b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We base the notion of state aggregation for finite state machines (FSM) on the dynamical consistency (DC) relation ([17]) between the blocks of states in any given state space partition pi. In this framework, we present the new notion of ST dynamical consistency (ST-DC) for source-target (ST) FSMs where there is a preferred sense of flow from a set of source states (S) to a set of target states (T). It is proven that if a partition pi is ST in-block controllable (ST-IBC), the partition machine of an ST FSM M based on pi, Mpi (i.e. high level abstraction of M based on pi), is controllable if and only if M itself is controllable. We also prove that all ST-IBC partition machines of M form a lattice and any chain from the top to the bottom of this lattice provides a hierarchical feedback control structure. This methodology is next extended to optimal control problems for discrete event systems (DES) modelled by finite state machines. A partition machines based scheme called hierarchically accelerated dynamic programming (HADP) is introduced which significantly speeds up the standard dynamic programming procedure (up to several orders of magnitude) at the cost of a certain degree of sub-optimality. We present necessary and sufficient conditions for the HADP procedure to generate globally optimal solutions and, further, give bounds on the degree of sub-optimality. An example called the Broken Manhattan Grid (BMG) system is used to illustrate the implementation of HADP, and flexible and generalisable code for this example is described. Many complex systems appear in the form of the product of multiple interacting sub-systems. A formulation of multi-agent systems is presented where the dynamics of the agents are described by default specifications, of a sets of forbidden state-event relational pairs, denoted R . Such systems are called relational multi-agent product systems (MA( R )). The application of the HADP methodology to relational multi-agent product systems is analysed. A multi-machine system consisting of a time counter and agents called a timed multi-agent relational product (TMA( R )) is formulated. To apply hierarchical control to the routing problem for networks, we consider two conceptual classes of networks: first, link network systems (LN), and, second, buffer network systems (BN). The notions of dynamical costs and network states are introduced. In particular, the notion of throughput-independent ST-IBC (TI-ST-IBC) partitions is used to formulate the incremental HADP ( IHADP) methodology. For the multiple objective optimisation problem of LNs, a notion of (vector) network state is introduced to carry the information describing the available transmission capacity of each link. For buffer network systems, the notion of (matrix) network states is given.</description><creator>Shen, Gang, 1968-</creator><contributor>Caines, Peter E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Hierarchical control for finite state machines</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn00b0501.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20sv45b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53jz89n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The overriding objective of this research was to develop an understanding of Iran's policy environment, within which the country's mining sector operates, in relation to that of the rest of the world. In an effort to diversify the country's economy, the first five-year development plan (FFYDP) provided a solid structure for the development of the Iranian mining sector. Although the plan attached high priorities to increasing the share of the private sector in mineral activities, the actual capital invested by this sector in mining projects was much less than anticipated during the plan period. This observation constitutes the early context for this research. To develop that understanding, a multi-level methodology for both the Iranian policy environment and its international counterparts was adopted. For Iran's policy environment, this multi-level methodology covered: (1) A comprehensive assessment of government Policies for the mineral sector as well as the sector's performance during the FFYDP. (2) A thorough examination of the views and comments of all active stakeholders, including Ministry of Mines and Metals (MMM) officials, mining company executives, and co-operatives and individual operators. This information collection was accomplished in three phases: informal discussions, interviews, and formal questionnaires with debriefing follow-ups, where the respondents made many comments on most aspects of the formal questionnaire. (3) An objective examination of financial statements of mining enterprises was also performed. The comparison of Iran to the international context consisted of two major parts: (1) An assessment of the policy environment of three mineral-endowed developing countries through case studies, and (2) A detailed examination of the views and comments of large international mining enterprises. This parallel and comparative approach has led to an overall finding that Iran's mineral policy environment has been relatively ineffective in attracting additional investment to the sector. To remedy this situation, policy recommendations, based on the analysis and implication of all components of the above research, are put forward. However, some challenging research questions remain, a list of which constitute promising areas of future research.</description><creator>Sheikholeslami Salmasi, Kamaleddin.</creator><contributor>Bilodeau, M. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Political Science, General.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><subject>Economics, General.</subject><title>Assessment and comparative analysis of Iran's mineral policy : lessons and recommendations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wk96r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53jz89n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fx719n892</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>To determine the effects of exposure to nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) on the risk of invasive female breast cancer we carried out a nested case-control study, using the beneficiaries of the Saskatchewan Prescription Drug Plan (SPDP) from 1981 to 1995 with no history of cancer since 1970 as the source population. Four age-matched controls were randomly selected for each case using incidence density sampling. Dispensing rates, calculated over successive time periods, characterized NSAID exposure according to dosage and the timing of exposure. We accrued 5,882 cases and 23,517 controls. Increasing NSAID exposure during the period 7--12 months preceding diagnosis was associated with a trend towards an increasing rate ratio (RR) for the diagnosis of breast cancer (p trend = 0.003), which was attributed to detection bias because it was markedly reduced by eliminating from the analysis the cases with tumours most likely to have been detected by screening (≤ 2 cm diameter). Increasing NSAID exposure 2--5 years preceding diagnosis was associated with a trend towards a decreasing RR (p-trend = 0.003); for the highest exposure level RR = 0.76, 95% CI: 0.63--0.92. This protective effect could not be attributed to confounding by other risk factors. Confounding by risk factors not in the SPDP database was studied in analyses adjusted with data obtained by interviewing samples of subjects accrued from mid1991 to mid-1995, selected according to both disease and exposure status. Increasing NSAID exposure 2--5 years and 6--10 years before diagnosis was associated with trends towards decreasing RRs for having a primary tumour &gt;5 cm diameter at diagnosis (p-trend = 0.06 and 0.02, respectively). NSAID exposure did not alter the risk of regional lymph node metastasis. However, increasing NSAID exposure 2--5 years and 6--10 years before diagnosis was associated with trends towards decreasing RRs for having distant metastases at diagnosis (p-trend = 0.0003 and 0.03, respectively). The use of NSAIDs may retard the growth of established, undiagnosed breast cancers and may decrease the risk of distant metastasis.</description><creator>Sharpe, Colin R.</creator><contributor>Collet, Jean-Paul (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>Population-based case-control study of the effects of nonsteroidal antiinflammatory drugs on the risk of breast cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515q00r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719n892</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xt42n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Superantigens (SAgs) are bacterial (bSAgs) or viral (vSAgs) proteins that can trigger a large number of T lymphocytes bearing specific Vbeta regions. This results in either anergy or deletion of those activated T cells. SAgs have long been implicated in various disease as well as autoimmune conditions. SAgs require binding to the Major Histocompatability Complex (MHC) class II molecules on antigen presenting cells (APC) to be presented to their responsive T cells. The work presented in this thesis represents a study of the different cellular factors implicated in MHC class II maturation pathway that could affect its ability to present viral SAgs and how this affects the functional outcome for SAg induced stimulation. Here, we show that the binding site of vSAgs on MHC class II molecules spans the peptide-binding groove and is highly affected by the nature of the peptide present in the groove. In addition, cellular factors that can alter the peptide repertoire presented by MHC class II molecules like MHC polymorphism and chaperones e.g. HLA-DM have a drastic effect on vSAg function. In the second part of the study we address the role of proteolytic processing in vSAg function. Unlike what was previously observed, we demonstrate that vSAg processing by pro-protein convertases is not essential for vSAg activity. In addition, we demonstrate alternative proteolytic processing by the cathepsin family of proteases. This study delineates the different modes of interaction of bacterial versus retroviral superantigens with MHC class II molecules. While bSAgs are potent stimulators of the immune system that resemble nominal peptide antigens in their kinetics of interaction with the TCR, they bind MHC and are presented in a different manner. On the contrary, vSAg interaction with both MHC and the TCR and their processing requirement tend to mimic more closely interaction of nominal peptide antigens.</description><creator>Shoukry Mohamed, Naglaa.</creator><contributor>Sekaly, Rafick P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><title>Study of the cellular factors affecting presentation of retroviral superantigens by Major Histocompatibility Complex (MHC) class II molecules</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r022m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xt42n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hr439</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette dissertation explore le role de l'architecture en tant que langage expressif, a travers la theorie de caractere en France a la fin du dix-huitieme siecle. Depuis l'Antiquite, Vitruve avait etabli le role expressif de l'architecture dans sa definition du terme "decorum". Pour Vitruve, toutefois, l'architecture exprimait un ordre qui transcendait sa materialite, l'ordre de l'univers. Vers la fin du dix-septieme siecle, des changements culturels importants transformerent la nature meme de l'architecture. Le questionnement des fondations naturelles de l'architecture plongea la discipline dans une crise potentielle de la signification architecturale. Les architectes du dix-huitieme siecle commencerent a explorer le pouvoir expressif de l'architecture en tant que produit d'une imagination personnelle et specifique au contexte culturel, et essayerent de preserver sa signification de facon a ce que l'architecture demeure un langage commun. L'architecte francais et theoricien Nicolas Le Camus de Mezieres (1721--ca.1793) developpa une theorie de l'architecture suivant laquelle le caractere d'un batiment se devait d'exprimer sa destination ou le statu social du client pour lequel il etait construit. Contrairement aux theories de caractere precedentes en architecture, celle de Le Camus etait basee de facon explicite sur une analogie entre l'architecture et le theatre: le mode d'expression en architecture suivait une progression temporelle typique du deroulement dramatique dans une piece de theatre; l'augmentation graduelle de l'ornementation des portes et des seuils successifs rappelait la succession des decors dans une performance de theatre. Cette etude examine les theories d'expression au theatre qui influencerent de facon explicite les theorie architecturales de Le Camus, telles que la mise en scene et le jeu des acteurs. Une etude plus poussee du role social et politique du theatre dans sa forme construite met en evidence l'innovation architecturale de l'oeuvre batie de Le Camus. Alors que les etudes precedentes sur Le Camus de Mezieres mettent l'emphase sur son plus important traite architectural, Le genie de l'architecture, ou l'analogie de cet art avec nos sensations, cette dissertation analyse egalement le vaste repertoire des oeuvres ecrites de Le Camus, incluant ses pieces de theatre, son roman, et une description d'un jardin pittoresque. Ces ouvrages revelent l'objectif reel qui sous-tend la theorie architecturale de Le Camus: la volonte d'exprimer la tension erotique d'une architecture des sens.</description><creator>Pelletier, Louise, 1963-</creator><contributor>Castro, Ricardo (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Le Camus de Mézières, Nicolas, 1721-1789</subject><subject>Architecture -- Composition, proportion, etc.</subject><subject>Architecture -- Philosophy.</subject><title>Nicolas Le Camus de Mézières's architecture of expression, and the theatre of desire at the end of the Ancien Régime, or, the analogy of fiction with architectural innovation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b499q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hr439</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322g01x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Methylenetetrahydrofolate dehydrogenase and methenyltetrahydrofolate cyclohydrolase are enzymatic activities that interconvert one-carbon substituted tetrahydrofolates, providing necessary precursors for biosynthetic processes. A gene encoding a D/C enzyme was cloned from the genome of Photobacterium phosphoreum. The recombinant P. phosphoreum D/C enzyme can utilize both NAD and NADP, a property shared with the human mitochondrial D/C enzyme. Phylogenetic analysis revealed a 10% higher overall identity between bacterial D/C and mitochondrial D/C amino acid sequences compared to those from eukaryotic trifunctional enzymes. The P. phosphoreum D/C enzyme, the human mitochondrial D/C enzyme, and the D/C domain from the human trifunctional enzyme have widely different ratios of forward dehydrogenase and forward cyclohydrolase turnover numbers. However, their forward channeling efficiencies are all approximately 50%. In the reverse direction, hydride transfer of the dehydrogenase activity is not rate-limiting as it is in the forward direction. Instead, the reverse cyclohydrolase activity is rate-limiting, with channeling of methenyltetrahydrofolate from cyclohydrolase to dehydrogenase occurring at approximately 100% efficiency. The NADP-utilizing enzymes exhibit to a two-fold stimulation of the reverse cyclohydrolase activity in the presence of the dinucleotide 2' phosphate. This suggests that NADP-utilizing D/C enzymes have been optimized to catalyze the reverse reaction to facilitate efficient methylenetetrahydrofolate production. Mutations of residues involved in NADP binding were performed on the human cytoplasmic D/C domain. Although these mutants exhibited widely different ratios dehydrogenase and cyclohydrolase specific activities, forward channeling efficiencies did not change. As well, partial channeling in the forward direction could not be explained by premature dissociation of the dinucleotide cofactor since forward channeling efficiencies could not be impr</description><creator>Pawelek, Peter D.</creator><contributor>MacKenzie, R. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Substrate channeling and cofactor usage in bifunctional methylenetetrahydrofolate dehydrogense-cyclohydrolases</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j0576.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322g01x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hr44k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis focuses on a universal multifractal, Fractionally Integrated flux model. Although this type of model is one of the first continuous multiplicative cascade models developed, and in fact the first chapter of this thesis dates back six years, it still remains an excellent model for a wide range of systems. Using the framework of GSI, extended in this thesis, it has been shown here that sea ice, cloud radiances and topography are all fields that can be modeled by universal multifractals. The multifractal parameters of such fields are given, and classification of anisotropies using GSI parameters is made. In addition, the anisotropic universal multifractal model is used for magnetization, and the implications for magnetic anomaly field are examined. The model agrees not only with magnetization data, but with the magnetic field data, and correctly predicts what could otherwise be considered an anomalous scale break. This theory is easily generalized to gravitational potential fields and rock density, and has applications in the modeling of other physical systems.</description><creator>Pecknold, Sean.</creator><contributor>Lovejoy, Shaun (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Geophysics.</subject><title>Modeling anisotropic geophysical fields using generalized scale invariance and universal multifractals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773x39g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hr44k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gj05w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores the nature of voice in Malagasy, a language spoken in Madagascar. In chapter 2, it is claimed that different passives promote arguments from different structural positions. Evidence is provided for a particular position, [Spec, v2P], where a certain class of elements ("displaced themes") may be generated. One particular passive, the a-prefix, promotes to subject elements in this position. In chapter 3, arguments are presented in favour of a structural analysis of circumstantial topic (CT). CT morphology licenses all arguments of the verb. Due to a requirement that all clauses have a subject (the Extended Projection Principle), some element other than a DP structurally Case marked by the verb must raise to subject. Finally, chapter 4 addresses the left periphery in the Malagasy clause, in particular the structural positions of topic and focus.</description><creator>Paul, Ileana M.</creator><contributor>Travis, Lisa (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Malagasy language -- Topic and comment.</subject><subject>Malagasy language -- Passive voice.</subject><title>Malagasy clause structure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qk44b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gj05w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2j62s6475</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Medicinal plants, as part of traditional ingestion practices, may contain antioxidants to combat the oxidative stress which is implicated in prediabetes as well as many of the complications of diabetes, As Indigenous Peoples move further from their traditional lifestyles, and therefore their use of medicinal plants, incidence of diabetes has increased dramatically, Those medicinal plants of the boreal forest that have been used for 3 or more symptoms of diabetes or its complications were selected for analysis. Three different assays (DPPH, NBT/xanthine oxidase and DCF/APPH) determined the antioxidant activity of 35 medicinal plant species. The majority of the species (89%) had free radical scavenging activity significantly greater than the market produce tested (Tukey, P &lt; 0.05), 63% had superoxide scavenging activities similar to vitamin C, and eight species had free radical scavenging activity similar to green tea. Considering that many of these species are also used for food or beverage they represent an antioxidant benefit to the traditional lifestyle. Among the parts used medicinally, roots and barks were used the most frequently with activity in the order of fruit &gt; bark &gt; leaves &gt; roots. The perennials selected had activity in rank trees &gt; shrubs &gt; herbs and the activity associated with habitat found rocky areas &gt; woodland &gt; wet/boggy habitats. Species used for symptoms such as diarrhea, rheumatism, tonic and heart/chest pain were typically high in antioxidant activity. Using cluster analysis it was determined that species used for diarrhea and heart disease as well as those used for a combination of tonic, sores, urinary, blood, pregnancy and boils could also be species with high antioxidant activity. The greater the number of symptoms a species was used for, the greater the activity. Three species with high antioxidant activities, Rhus hirta, Cornus stolonifera and Solidago canadensis, inhibited TNF production in human macrophage cells suggesting a po</description><creator>McCune, Letitia M.</creator><contributor>Johns, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Taigas -- Canada.</subject><subject>Non-insulin-dependent diabetes -- Nutritional aspects.</subject><subject>Antioxidants -- Health aspects.</subject><subject>Medicinal plants -- Canada.</subject><subject>Indians of North America -- Ethnobotany -- Canada.</subject><title>Antioxidants in Canadian boreal forest : indigenous medicinal plant treatments in relation to non-insulin dependent diabetes mellitus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s1818.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s6475</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zs25xb226</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of this thesis is to question conventional definitions of work through the detailed study of a professional group---specifically rural clergy---whose work falls outside the parameters of accepted definitions of work. According to the feminist literature, work and non-work are differentiated typically by dichotomies which privilege a masculine model of work and devalue women's experience; thus, "real work" is defined as an activity which is paid rather than unpaid, public rather than private, instrumental and intellectual rather than emotional. Professional work definitions also obscure the way in which "work" relies on activities which are linked with the feminine in these dichotomies. Through in-depth qualitative interviews with rural clergy, I explore the extent to which women and men draw on these gendered dichotomies to define work. In some ways, the approach of clergy counters conventional work norms: for them, emotional labour is a priority, work is not limited to a specific time or place, and public and private lives frequently overlap. I demonstrate how clergy define their work in terms of obligation, context, visibility, and time. Furthermore, I also argue that clergy delineate work in terms which still reflect a masculinized work norm specific to their profession. This "clergy masculinized mode" professionalises emotional labour by separating it from the facilitating work of female volunteers; it assumes a worker free from domestic demands in order to fulfil professional obligations within a flexible time frame; and it overlooks how the overlap of the public and private spheres is sustained by the work of wives. Thus, delineating work is particularly problematic for female clergy because professional demands are confounded with demands for adjunct work typically performed by women. My findings (1) highlight alternative markers of work which are suggestive for feminist theory; (2) point to a gap in theorizing about the gendering of work when con</description><creator>Mellow, Muriel, 1960-</creator><contributor>Tancred, Peta (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Sex role in the work environment.</subject><subject>Rural clergy.</subject><title>Defining work : gender, professional work, and the case of rural clergy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b277k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xb226</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50gx799</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The epigenetic modification of DNA by methylation at cytosine in CpG dinucleotides plays an important role in X-chromosome inactivation, genomic imprinting, host defense and cancer. In this thesis, I investigated the role of the predominant mammalian DNA methyltransferase, Dnmt1, in the establishment and maintenance of DNA methylation patterns in the germline. In a comparative study of the expression of Dnmt1 during male and female germ cell development, I identified putative windows in which Dnmt1 may set down sex-specific methylation patterns for imprinted genes, I also identified and characterized sex-specific exons in the 5' region of Dnmt1 which control the production and localization of enzyme during specific stages of gametogenesis by a mechanism that involves alternative splicing. An oocyte-specific 5' exon is associated with the production of a functional Dnmt1 protein that is truncated at the N-terminus, accumulates to high levels during oocyte growth and later persists through preimplantation development, while a spermatocyte-specific 5' exon leads to the production of a larger, nontranslated message. I further examined the dynamics in the expression of the oocyte-specific Dnmt1 isoform in populations of isolated oocytes obtained at different stages of development and their association with the methylation status of the maternally imprinted Snrpn gene. The data suggest that the tightly regulated expression of the oocyte-specific Dnmt1 during postnatal oogenesis may play a role in the establishment of maternal methylation imprints at this time, Furthermore, since the oocyte-specific isoform persists during preimplantation development, at a time when the somatic isoform of Dnmt1 is not detected, I propose that the oocyte isoform may also be important for the propagation of maternally- and paternally-derived imprints in the early embryo.</description><creator>Mertineit, Carmen.</creator><contributor>Trasler, Jacquetta M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Regulation and expression of DNA methyltransferase in the mouse germline</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v9607.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gx799</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj139369h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Conversion to Islam in the Ottoman Balkans initially followed a pattern similar to the one established by Bulliet for the regions incorporated in the course of the seventh and eighth centuries into the Islamic realm. By the early eighteenth century, close to forty percent of the Balkan population belonged to the Muslim community. However, Islamization came to a sudden halt in most of the Balkan lands in the second quarter of the eighteenth century. I have sought an explanation for this phenomenon in kisve bahasi petitions, which reflect the unique economic and social conditions in the Ottoman Empire during the period 1670s--1730s. The transformation from religious syncretism to religious conservatism in the second part of the seventeenth century changed the nature of conversion by introducing ceremonies and documentation of conversion. I argue that the practice of granting kisve bahasi evolved into an institution of conversion, which substituted to a certain extent for the devsirme institution. For the socially weak, the kisve bahasi institution served as a form of social welfare. Conversion to Islam for the new Muslims converted through the kisve bahasi institution was, therefore, primarily a pragmatic rather than spiritual affair. I also argue that the process of conversion in the Balkans was cut short by a premature "laggards" stage in the period 1670s--1730s. This development, which points to the uniqueness of the process of conversion in the Balkans, may have been due to the rise of a more prosperous class of non-Muslims as a result of the Ottoman Empire's integration into the world economy.</description><creator>Minkov, Anton.</creator><contributor>Turgay, A. Uner (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Balkan Peninsula -- History.</subject><subject>Islam -- Balkan Peninsula -- History.</subject><subject>Muslim converts -- Balkan Peninsula.</subject><title>Conversion to Islam as reflected in kisve bahasi petitions : an aspect of Ottoman social life in the Balkans, 1670-1730</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053h73p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139369h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440v32n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Using a data sample of integrated luminosity ∫ Ldt = 28.9 +/- 1.2 pb-1 of proton-antiproton collisions at a center-of-mass energy s = 1.8 TeV collected with the CDF detector at the Fermilab Tevatron collider, we searched for "penguin" radiative decays of B0d and B0s mesons which involve the flavor-changing neutral-current transition of a b quark into an s quark with the emission of a photon, b→sg . Specifically, we searched for the decays B0d→K*0g, K*0→K+p- and B0s→fg, f→K+K- , as well as for the charge conjugate chains. In order to collect such decays, we designed a specialized trigger which required information on all the decay products of the B meson decay chain, the first such trigger in a hadron collider environment. This "penguin" trigger collected data during the last quarter of the 1994--1996 data taking period. After all selection criteria, we are left with one candidate B0d→K*0g decay and no B0s→fg candidates in the entire data sample. We then proceed to set upper limits on the branching fractions of the penguin channels. We exploit the topological similarity between the B¯→e-D0 X,D0→K-p + and the penguin decays, by forming ratios of branching fractions between the penguin and the B¯→e-D0 X channels. Uncertainties associated with the B meson production cross section, common efficiency corrections and other systematic effects are minimal in the ratio of branching fractions. The uncertainty on the B¯→e-D0 X yield is the biggest contribution to the total uncertainty on the penguin branching fraction. We assume equal production rates for B+u and B0d mesons, while the probability of producing B0s mesons relative to B0d mesons, fs/fd, is taken to be 1/3. The inferred upper limits on the ratios of branching fractions are B(B0 s→fg)B( B¯→e-D0 X)&lt;3.5x10-3 at90% C.L. B(B 0d→K*0g) B(B¯→e- D0X)&lt;1.9x10-3 at90%C.L. Relative branching fraction measurements were combined with the branching fraction measurement of the B¯→e-D0 X,D0→K-p + decay chain, B(B¯→e- D0X)xB(D0→ K-p+) = (294 +/- 40) x 10-5, to extract the following absolute branching fraction limits B(B0s→ fg)&lt;2.8x10-4 at90%C.L. B(B0d →K*0g)&lt;1.5x10-4 at90% C.L. The upper limit for the B0d→K*0g decay is consistent with the branching fraction measurement reported by the CLEO collaboration, B(B0d→K*0 g) = (4.0 +/- 1.9) x 10-5, while the upper limit for the as yet unobserved B0s→fg decay is the most constraining one set to date.</description><creator>Kordas, Kostas.</creator><contributor>Ragan, Ken (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>Search for penguin decays of B mesons at CDF</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z707b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440v32n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074w94x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dart shooting, a bizarre component of mating behaviour seen in several species of terrestrial snails, has bewildered scientists for centuries. The hermaphroditic snail Helix aspersa pushes a calcareous "love dart", covered with mucus, through the skin of its partner at the end of an elaborate courtship. I address both why this dart shooting behaviour is performed and how it is controlled by the brain. I find that the dart cannot serve as a nuptial gift of calcium because it is rarely internalised by the recipient and contains only a small amount of calcium. However, most shot darts penetrate the skin and come into contact with the blood. I demonstrate that mucus, produced by the digitiform glands and carried on the dart, causes contractions in the female organs. The contractions suggest that more sperm will reach the sperm storage organ as a result of dart shooting, which is important in sperm competition because snails store sperm from several partners before laying eggs. This introduction of a bioactive substance can be explained by either mate choice or mate manipulation. My findings show that dart shooting is an optional component of mating behaviour, which supports the mate manipulation hypothesis. I conclude that the dart transfers a substance to manipulate the storage of the donated sperm. Many species transfer bioactive substances into conspecifics. I propose the term "allohormones" for such substances to distinguish them from hormones and pheromones. To investigate how the central nervous system controls dart shooting and other mating behaviours, I used an in vivo approach. The right mesocerebrum has been proposed as the control centre for mating behaviour based on in vitro findings. I demonstrate, by electrically stimulating and recording from right mesocerebral neurones in the intact animal, that these neurones are involved in dart shooting and penial eversion. I also test the hypothesis that different neuropeptides mediate different mating behaviours, and I find that APGWamide is responsible for genital eversion. From my results, together with data obtained using other gastropods, I conclude that the anteromedial portion of the right cerebral ganglion is an evolutionarily conserved region for the control of mating behaviour.</description><creator>Koene, Joris M.</creator><contributor>Chase, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Brown garden snail -- Reproduction.</subject><subject>Brown garden snail -- Sexual behavior.</subject><title>Behavioural and neurobiological aspects of dart shooting in the garden snail Helix Aspersa</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nw33f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074w94x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074w956</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is concerned with the syntactic properties of cleft constructions in Japanese within the Principles and Parameters framework with some consideration of the Minimalist Program. The constructions in question are divided syntactically into two sub-parts, a focus element and a presuppositional clause. This thesis claims that the focused element's position is not derived via a process of movement such as scrambling, but is instead base-generated in a predicate position occupied by a single constituent. Presuppositional clauses of clefts are argued to involve movement of a null operator, which is analyzed on a par with topicalization. This is supported by various syntactic parallelisms between cleft and topic constructions in this language. While the presuppositional clause is marked by a nominalizer, it is shown that it does not project a nominal category; in this sense, cleft constructions are analogous to head-internal relative clauses. Furthermore, one of the most interesting properties of the cleft construction, the syntactic phenomenon of 'connectivity', is closely examined. I propose that long-distance cleft constructions in Japanese have peculiar structures: a null operator originates adjoined to the highest complement clause, and its thematic position is occupied by pro. This analysis is supported by empirical facts which involve binding relations, weak crossover effects, interactions with another A'-dependency, and clefting adjunct PPs. It is shown that these types of resumptive A '-dependencies are observed across languages as well as in different constructions within the Japanese language. Finally, the discussion is extended to so-called sluicing in Japanese. This thesis observes similar syntactic behavior in sluicing and clefts, which leads to the argument that sluicing sentences are derived from cleft constructions.</description><creator>Kizu, Mika.</creator><contributor>Baker, Mark (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Focus (Linguistics)</subject><subject>Grammar, Comparative and general -- Topic and comment.</subject><subject>Japanese language -- Syntax.</subject><title>Unbounded dependencies in cleft constructions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hb40d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074w956</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05fd461</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>At the end of the nineteenth century, English-Canadians and Americans faced each other across the border with old animosities. Many Canadians adhered to familiar ideas of Loyalism, imperialism and anti-Americanism to differentiate the Dominion from the republic. In the United States, on the other hand, lingering notions of anglophobia and "Manifest Destiny" caused Americans to look upon the British colony to the north as a dangerous and unnatural entity. America's rise to world power status and the Anglo-American rapprochement, however, forced Americans and Canadians to adapt to the new international reality. Emphasizing their shared language, civilization, and forms of government, many English-speaking North Americans drew upon Anglo-Saxonism to find common ground. Indeed, Americans and Canadians often referred to each other as members of the same "family" sharing the same "blood," thus differentiating themselves from other races. As many of the events of the rapprochement had a North American context, Americans and English-Canadians often drew upon the common lexicon of Anglo-Saxon rhetoric to undermine the old rivalries and underscore their shared interests. Though the predominance of Anglo-Saxonism at the turn of the century proved short-lived, it left a legacy of Canadian-American goodwill, as both nations accepted their shared destiny on the continent and Canada as a key link in the North Atlantic Triangle.</description><creator>Kohn, Edward P (Edward Parliament), 1968-</creator><contributor>Miller, Carman (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Canada -- Foreign public opinion, American.</subject><subject>United States -- Foreign public opinion, Canadian.</subject><subject>Canada -- Foreign relations -- United States.</subject><subject>United States -- Foreign relations -- Canada.</subject><title>This kindred people : Canadian-American relations and North American Anglo-Saxonism during the Anglo-American rapprochement, 1895-1903</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nc79v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fd461</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rb68xd42t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Apolipophorin-III is a hemolymph protein known for its role in lipid transport. Apolipophorin-III isolated from the hemolymph of last instar larvae of Galleria mellonella bound to the surface of the insect pathogenic Gram-negative bacterium Xenorhabdus nematophilus and to the lipid A moiety of its lipopolysaccharide. This binding reduced the toxicity of the lipopolysaccharide to hemocytes and decreased the inhibitory effect of the lipopolysaccharide on phenoloxidase. Apolipophorin-III also bound to the Gram-positive bacterium Micrococcus lysodeikticus; this enhanced the activity of hen egg lysozyme on the organism as well as the lytic activity of G. mellonella cell-free hemolymph. The involvement of apolipophorin-III in the immune responses of G. mellonella larvae to lipoteichoic acids, surface components of Gram-positive bacteria, was examined. Lipoteichoic acids from Bacillus subtilis, Enterococcus hirae and Streptococcus pyogenes caused a dose- and time-dependent drop in the total counts of circulating hemocytes and a partial or complete depletion of plasmatocytes depending on the species of lipoteichoic acid. All lipoteichoic acids tested activated phenoloxidase in vitro; however, in vivo, only B. subtilis lipoteichoic acid elevated the phenoloxidase activity while the other two suppressed it. Binding of apolipophorin-III to lipoteichoic acids was demonstrated. Apolipophorin-III prevented the complete depletion of plasmatocytes and depressed the activation of phenoloxidase by lipoteichoic acid from B. subtilis. The concentration of apolipophorin-III in hemolymph two hours post injections of lipopolysaccharides or lipoteichoic acids into larvae of G. mellonella did not change with respect to control insects that received phosphate-buffered saline. The concentration of apolipophorin-III in hemolymph at the end of the feeding larval stage was 8--12 mg/mL of hemolymph. Apolipophorin-III was present in significant amounts in the prepupal, pupal and adult stages. The protein was detected immunologically in hemocyte lysates, plasma and fat body. Non-denaturing polyacrylamide gels and immunoblots of fresh hemolymph suggested that apolipophorin-III is associated with a 77 kDa protein.</description><creator>Halwani, Adla E.</creator><contributor>Niven, Donald F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Honeybee -- Parasites -- Biological control.</subject><subject>Apolipoproteins.</subject><subject>Xenorhabdus.</subject><subject>Greater wax moth -- Immunology.</subject><subject>Greater wax moth -- Biological control.</subject><title>Role of apolipophorin-III in the immediate antibacterial responses of Galleria mellonella larvae (Lepidoptera:Pyralidae)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10ws00b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xd42t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33850</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>