<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:55:44Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):1250" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v756h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Globular proteins are important ingredients in many food formulations because of their nutritional value and their various functional properties such as gel formation. Proteins form gels by polymerization into a three-dimensional matrix. The rheological properties of the resulting viscoelastic solids can be obtained by Instron measurements. In the present work, gels were obtained by heating solutions of bovine serum albumin (BSA) in D$ sb2$O and egg albumin in H$ sb2$O under different conditions (i.e., pH, salt concentration, protein concentration, time of heating and temperature), and their gel strengths were measured by a compression test (Universal Testing Machine LRX). The Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectra of the same gel samples were recorded in order to investigate the changes in protein structure at the molecular level accompanying gel formation. Intermolecular $ beta$-sheet formation was found to increase as gel formation progresses at the expense of intramolecular $ beta$-sheet and $ alpha$-helix structures. For BSA, maximum gel strength was obtained around pH 7. The addition of salt had little effect on the gel strength while increase in protein concentration, time of heating and temperature increased the gel strength. The rate of denaturation of BSA and ovalbumin and of mixtures of these proteins in the ratios 9:1, 1:1, and 1:9 was also investigated by measuring the peak height of an aggregation band at 1618 cm$ sp{-1}$; some inhibitory effects of BSA on ovalbumin aggregation were observed. Correlations between the measured gel strengths and the amide I band profile in the FTIR spectra were examined using partial-least-squares (PLS) regression. These studies reveal that gel strengths of a particular protein gel could be adequately predicted from their infrared spectra without the need to carry out the rheological compression measurements.</description><creator>Rejaei, Ali Reza</creator><contributor>Ismail, Ashraf A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Colloids.</subject><subject>Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy.</subject><subject>Gelation.</subject><subject>Globular proteins.</subject><title>Correlation of FTIR spectra of protein gels to rheological measurements of gel strength</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nt086.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v756h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sf668</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis focuses on diffusion channel design for broccoli storage, an important cash crop and consumer commodity in Canada. Experiments were first conducted to determine the respiration rate of broccoli in modified atmosphere conditions created by the produce metabolic activity inside closed chambers, at four different temperatures in the cold room of 3, 7, 13, and 24$ sp circ$C. The respiration rate decreased with a reduction of O$ sb2$ concentration inside the chamber. A model to predict the respiration rate of broccoli as a function of O$ sb2$ concentration at different temperatures was developed. Experiments were then carried out to determine the cross sectional area and length of diffusion channel leading to various final O$ sb2$ (steady-state) concentrations during the storage of broccoli. Combinations of cross sectional area of 0.04, 0.18, and 1.15 cm$ sp2$ and length of 0.6, 3, 7, 12, 18, and 25 cm were tested. The carbon dioxide produced through respiratory process was absorbed by placing hydrated lime inside the chambers such that the two-component molecular diffusion model by Ratti et al. (1993) could be evaluated. The length and cross sectional area of diffusion channel have a significant effect on the final level of O$ sb2$ (steady-state) concentration. The Ratti model then served as a basis for a modified model for predicting the length of diffusion channel required to obtain a given O$ sb2$ concentration as a function of the mass of stored broccoli and the cross sectional area of the diffusion channel. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Ramachandra, Mariyappa</creator><contributor>Raghavan, G. S. V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Protective atmospheres.</subject><subject>Broccoli -- Storage</subject><title>Diffusion channels for broccoli storage</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns0647872.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sf668</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pj38f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The adoption of software development principles and methodologies embodying best practices and standards is essential to achieving quality software products. Many organizations world-wide have implemented quality management systems that comply with the requirements of the ISO 9001 standard, or similar schemes, to ensure product quality. Meeting the requirement of ISO 9000 can be costly in time, effort and money. The effort primarily depends on the size of the organization, and the status of the quality management system. The focus of this thesis is on the development of an effort estimation model for the implementation of ISO 9001 in software organizations. In determining this effort, a survey of 1190 registered organizations was conducted in 1995, of which 63 were software organizations. A statistical regression model for predicting the effort was developed and validated. The proposed effort estimation model forms a foundation for building and comparing related effort estimation models for ISO 9000 and other process improvement frameworks.</description><creator>Rahhal, Silas</creator><contributor>Madhavji, Nazim H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>An effort estimation model for implementing ISO 9001 in software organizations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mk97m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pj38f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75r983s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A one year water table management field study was conducted on a Soulanges sandy loam soil in Soulanges county, Quebec. Two controlled water table levels, i.e. 0.5 m and 0.75 m from the soil surface, as well as free outlet conventional drainage treatments were established in monocropped corn (Zea mays L.) and corn intercropped with ryegrass (Lolium multiflorum Lam) plots. Cropping system showed no significant effects on evapotranspiration, and on soil moisture distribution. It was observed that the 0.5 m and 0.75 m controlled water tables (CWT) provided the same soil moisture trends in both cropping systems. The soil moisture was always higher in controlled water table plots compared to freely drained plots. The water use efficiency of 0.75 m CWT in both cropping systems was high compared to 0.5 m CWT. The soil moisture contents at three depths were only 2% to 10% less in intercropped plots compared to monocropped plots. The soil moisture was 12 to 13% higher in CWT plots compared to freely drained plots for both cropping systems. The soil moisture in 0.5 m CWT and 0.75 m CWT plots was not significantly different. The average water table levels in monocropped plots were not significantly different from intercropped plots.</description><creator>Qureshi, Suhail Ahmad</creator><contributor>Madramootoo, Chandra A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Soil moisture.</subject><subject>Corn.</subject><subject>Companion planting.</subject><subject>Water table.</subject><title>Soil water balance of intercropped corn under water table management</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nd20c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75r983s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hq37vq53x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Humans can only survive the low barometric pressure of altitudes above 6000m by making a complex series of adaptations. The energetics of human survival at such extreme altitudes have not been widely studied. Objectives were to compare the doubly labelled water (DLW) and intake-balance (IB) methods to estimate daily energy expenditure while climbing between 6000 and 8046m and to investigate the putative metabolic cost involved with the process of acclimatization to extreme altitude. Reliability of the DLW method to provide an accurate and portable means to measure human energy expenditure depends upon a series of assumptions regarding the flux of tracer and tracee across the physiological compartments of measurement. Additional objectives were to review and examine the proficiency of these assumptions to account for perturbations experienced while using DLW while climbing at extreme altitude. Findings suggest that the use of DLW at extreme altitudes requires special consideration towards elevated rates of fractional isotope loss, inter-subject isotope transfer, alterations in total body water, changes in background isotopic abundance, and choice of sampling technique. Revised strategies directed at achieving these aims are calculated. Results from extreme altitude indicate that IB and DLW techniques each provide similar estimates of group mean energy expenditure despite substantial changes in body weight and composition and that the metabolic cost for the process of acclimatization accounts for roughly 12% of total daily energy expenditure. Problems associated with maintaining energy balance while climbing at extreme altitude are related to low energy intakes, approximately only 70% of energy demands, and energy expenditure values that are comparable to those of highly trained endurance athletes at sea-level.</description><creator>Pulfrey, Simon M.</creator><contributor>Jones, Peter J. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Bioenergetics.</subject><subject>Altitude, Influence of.</subject><subject>Mountaineering -- Physiological aspects.</subject><subject>Mountaineers -- Nutrition.</subject><title>Energy expenditure and requirement while climbing at extreme altitude</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn3013404.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vq53x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87ps63n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study set out to determine the type of proxy more likely to provide reliable information on the perceived health-related quality of life of elderly patients needing care and rehabilitation, according to their current living situation. A sub-objective was to estimate floor effects of the scale used to assess health-related quality of life when employed in a sample of elderly individuals. In this interrater reliability study, the self-perceived quality-of-life scores of elderly patients were compared to their quality-of-life scores, as provided by two different proxies. Eighty-three consenting elderly patients completed a generic health-related quality of life questionnaire, the SF-36, and named a significant other and a health caregiver who knew them well. These individuals completed the same questionnaire on behalf of the patient. Questionnaires were completed in English or French. When concordance between respondents was examined, results indicated poor to moderate agreement regardless of the type of proxy or the patient's living situation. Trends in under reporting quality of life by proxies were found but it was difficult to identify good predictors of agreement. The addition of two items at the bottom end of the physical functioning subscale modified a floor effect without significantly altering the internal consistency of the subscale. The study indicated that the use of proxies to assess the quality of life of elderly patients needing care and rehabilitation does not always provide reliable results and other methods of obtaining the information should be investigated.</description><creator>Pierre, Uriel</creator><contributor>Wood-Dauphinee, Sharon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><subject>Gerontology.</subject><title>The use of proxies to assess quality of life of elderly patients</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rw56g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87ps63n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945s944</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examined the influence of activated and chronic interpersonal expectations on primary and secondary appraisal of a stressful life event. Fifty-one female undergraduates were asked to imagine themselves facing an unplanned pregnancy, after which affective state and coping strategies were assessed. A subliminal priming technique was used during the experimental session to activate either positive, negative or neutral interpersonal expectations. Chronic interpersonal expectations were assessed in a telephone interview, using the Collins and Read (1990) attachment scale. Activated negative interpersonal expectations reduced positive affect; chronic interpersonal anxiety heightened overall negative affect, while chronic comfort with closeness and feeling one can depend on others were associated with less feelings of depression. Both activated and chronically accessible positive interpersonal expectations increased intentions to seek emotional support. Chronic anxiety in relationships was related to hostile coping, while a lack of comfort with closeness and depending on others were conducive to self-blaming. Implications of these findings for close relationships and stressful life events and for future priming research are discussed.</description><creator>Pierce, Tamarha</creator><contributor>Lydon, J. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Young women -- Social networks.</subject><subject>Adjustment (Psychology)</subject><subject>Pregnancy, Unwanted -- Decision-making.</subject><subject>Life change events -- Decision-making.</subject><title>Experimental priming of interpersonal expectations and coping with an unplanned pregnancy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Tamarha Pierce, 1995</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999870q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945s944</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tx185</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The following studies were done to identify factors that influence the virulence of Xenorhabdus nematophilus and the interactions of the bacterium with the nonself defence systems of nonimmune Galleria mellonella. Isolates of X. nematophilus that are qualitatively similar in biochemical properties differed significantly in virulence for G. mellonella larvae. The production of enzymes such as proteases could not account for differences in the virulence of the isolates. Growth conditions, influenced the growth rate and the interactions of the bacterium with nonimmune G. mellonella larvae. In general, X. nematophilus cells grown under aerobic conditions were more susceptible to the nonself defences of G. mellonella larvae than those grown under less than ideal conditions, resulting in increased clearance of the bacteria from the hemolymph (blood) of the insects. Clearance of the bacteria from the hemolymph of the insect was positively correlated with culture condition, culture age, and attachment to insect hemocytes in vitro. Isolates of X. nematophilus produced flagella and fimbriae when grown under microaerobic and aerobic conditions. The type of fimbriae produced was influenced by culture conditions. The injection of both flagella and fimbriae in picogram quantities into nonimmune G. mellonella caused an increase in total hemocyte counts within these insect larvae. The injection of fimbrial and flagellar antigens into G. mellonella larvae caused changes in the hemocyte types found in circulation in the insect's hemolymph. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Maxwell, Philip W. (Philip William)</creator><contributor>Dunphy, Gary (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Greater wax moth -- Biological control.</subject><subject>Steinernematidae.</subject><subject>Xenorhabdus.</subject><subject>Greater wax moth -- Parasites.</subject><title>The interaction of surface components of Xenorhabdus nematophilus (Enterobacteriaceae) with the hemolymph of nonimmune larvae of the greater wax moth, Galleria mellonella (Lepidoptera; Galleridae)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945s95d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tx185</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k0698957t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The physical state of the seedbed is of importance to the plant environment as it influences some important processes in the soil such as seedling emergence, water and solute transport, and ease of root penetration. This is affected to a large extent by tillage process, the tillage implement type and the geometry of the implement used. A field experiment was carried out on a clay soil to determine the effect of the geometry of bladed tillage implements on some soil physical properties after tillage. The soil properties evaluated were bulk density, mean clod size distribution and total pore space after tillage and the extent of loosening achieved. Implement parameters considered were blade width, rake angle and depth of operation of the implement. Two blade widths of 75 and 150 mm were evaluated in combination with three rake angles of 30, 60 and 90 degrees. Each tillage implement was drawn through the soil at four operating depths of 100, 150, 200 and 250 mm. Larger rake angles were observed to result in larger mean aggregate sizes and greater bulk density reductions when compared to smaller rake angles. Greater reduction in bulk density was observed with the wider of the two blade widths evaluated. Mean clod size after tillage was also observed to be large for the wider of the two widths evaluated. Irrespective of width and rake angle, greater operating depths resulted in larger mean clod sizes and greater reductions in bulk density as compared to shallower operating depths. Fractal analysis showed the extent of fragmentation to be greater at shallower operating depths, hence the small mean clod sizes obtained.</description><creator>Masiyandima, Mutsa Cecelia</creator><contributor>McKyes, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Soil structure.</subject><subject>Soils -- Density.</subject><subject>Tillage -- Equipment and supplies.</subject><subject>Soil porosity.</subject><title>The effect of tine geometry on soil physical properties</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811km72d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698957t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225d086</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ornithine-$ delta$-biaminotransferase (OAT) is a mitochondrial matrix a enzyme which catalyzes the reversible conversion of ornithine to glutamic semialdehyde. In the retinoblastoma cell line Y79, the 5$ sp prime$ UTR of the OAT mRNA is alternatively-spliced. Previous work has shown that the two alternatively-spliced 5$ sp prime$ UTR are translated with different efficiencies. The alternatively-spliced 5$ sp prime$ UTRs were isolated and subcloned. Expression vectors were constructed containing each of the OAT 5$ sp prime$ UTRs and the human growth hormone as a reporter gene. Transient transfection expression analysis in COS-1 cells confirmed that the 5$ sp prime$ UTRs conferred differential expression on the reporter gene. The shorter 5$ sp prime$ UTR was expressed at a level 3-fold higher than that of the longer 5$ sp prime$ UTR. RNA mobility shift assays were performed to determine whether a transacting factor was interacting with one of the alternatively-spliced 5$ sp prime$ UTRs. A binding activity was detected that bound to the longer, exon 2-containing 5$ sp prime$ UTR with a significantly higher affinity than the shorter 5$ sp prime$ UTR. Competition studies demonstrated that this binding activity was specific for the longer 5$ sp prime$ UTR.</description><creator>MacDonald, Heather R. (Heather Ruth)</creator><date>1995</date><subject>Ornithine aminotransferase</subject><subject>Aminotransferases</subject><subject>Gene expression</subject><title>The role of the 5 ́untranslated region in gene expression of ornithine aminotransferase</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m884t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225d086</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zd19m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effect of maternal dietary glucose on perinatal phosphoenolpyruvate carboxykinase (PEPCK) gene expression was investigated in this study. Pregnant rats were fed isoclaoric diets containing graded levels of glucose (0%, 12%, 24% and 60%) from gestation day 2 to lactation day 15. The developmental profiles of PEPCK gene expression in fetal and neonatal liver and kidney were analyzed by northern blot. In the liver, feeding glucose free and glucose restriction (12% and 24%) diets precociously induced PEPCK gene expression at day 21 of gestation. In the kidney, PEPCK mRNA (2.8 kb) was detected at birth in the glucose free group, 12-16 hours postnatally in control group; it was not visualized until day 3 in the 12% and 24% glucose restriction groups. In our study, two species of RNA (1.8 kb and 2.8 kb) were hybridized with PEPCK cDNA probes, and there was a relationship between maternal dietary glucose levels and the 1.8 kb RNA fragment in the kidney.</description><creator>Liu, Xu-Jing</creator><contributor>Koski, K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Hypoglycemia.</subject><subject>Pregnancy -- Nutritional aspects.</subject><subject>Low-carbohydrate diet.</subject><subject>Gene expression.</subject><subject>Fetus -- Nutrition.</subject><title>Effects of maternal dietary carbohydrate on phosphoenolpyruvate carboxykinase development in the fetus and neonate</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526f322.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zd19m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p0969243</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The tidal flow characteristics around L'Anse du Petit Mitis were described using velocity data from six moored current metres. L'Anse du Petit Mitis is a shallow bay in the lee of the downstream slanting Pointe Mitis. The predominantly M$ sb2$ current showed the following signs of tide induced transient recirculation within the bay: the M$ sb2$ phase within the bay is 65$ sp circ$ ahead of that outside of the bay; the amplitude of the M$ sb4$ and Eulerian mean constituents are relatively large within the bay; and the M$ sb2$ tidal ellipse and the Eulerian mean are oriented towards the tip of Pointe Mitis. The effects of tide induced transient recirculation were not found to extend to the station furthest within the bay. Flow in the bay region was found to be an order of magnitude weaker than the free stream tidal flow.</description><creator>Laval, Bernard E.</creator><contributor>Ingram, Grant (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Physical Oceanography.</subject><title>Tidal flow modification by a small bay in the lower St. Lawrence estuary</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j7548.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p0969243</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sf67j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The onset of acute graft-versus host disease (aGVHD) is accompanied by macrophage priming and the presence of bacteria derived lipopolysaccharide (LPS) in the sera and organs of transplanted animals. Priming of macrophages occurs despite suppression of T cell function. We have investigated whether interleukin 12 (IL-12) mediates the continued production of interferon gamma (IFN-$ gamma$) during the state of T cell immunosuppression accompanying aGVHD. AGVHD was induced in non-irradiated AxC57BL/6 mice by an injection of C57BL/6 lymphoid cells. Despite T cell immunosuppression, macrophages remained primed as shown by their expression of inducible nitric oxide synthase (iNOS) mRNA and production of nitric oxide (NO) in response to exogenous LPS. Continued exposure to IFN-$ gamma$ was found to be required in order to maintain the primed state of macrophages during aGVHD; IFN-$ gamma$ mRNA within target organs of aGVHD including thymus, salivary gland, and lung was increased between day 7 and 14 after transplantation and was accompanied by the induction of the p40 peptide of IL-12 and iNOS mRNA. p40 peptide mRNA was also increased in macrophages purified on day 14 of aGVHD. These results provide evidence for localized production of IFN-$ gamma$ in aGVHD target organs and suggest that it is mediated by LPS induced IL-12 production by macrophages.</description><creator>Kichian, Krikor</creator><contributor>Lapp, W. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Interferon gamma regulatory mechanisms during acute graft-versus-host disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f564k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sf67j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w0325040</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to evaluate the effect of non-invasive, low-intensity, pulsed ultrasound on bone growth into tantalum porous implants. Three transcortical cylindrical implants were inserted into both femora of 12 dogs. One leg underwent daily ultrasound stimulation for 40 consecutive minutes with the transducer positioned over the central, or "target" implant, while the contralateral leg served as the control. Six dogs were each treated for periods of two and three weeks. A quantitative analysis was performed to determine the volume fraction of bone ingrowth. At two weeks, there was 12.4 $ pm$ 5.4% bone ingrowth in the stimulated femora compared with 12.7 $ pm$ 6.5% in the controls (p = 0.74). At three weeks, bone growth into the stimulated and control implants was 21.1 $ pm$ 6.5% and 22.7 $ pm$ 7.3%, respectively (p = 0.53). Although a prior study showed that 20 minutes of ultrasound stimulation had a positive effect on bone ingrowth, the results of this study suggest that a treatment of 40 consecutive minutes does not enhance the amount of bone growth into porous metallic implants.</description><creator>Kay, Andrew Brian</creator><contributor>Bobyn, J. Dennis (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>The effect of non invasive low intensity pulsed ultrasound on bone growth into porous tantalum implants</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h386d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w0325040</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:12579v389</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the present studies we attempted to answer the following questions: (i) Does low temperature alter the phosphorylation level of proteins in isolated nuclei? (ii) Does the nuclear phosphoprotein population change during a prolonged exposure of seedlings to cold? (iii) Do heat-stable proteins accumulate in the nucleus during a prolonged exposure of seedlings to cold? (iv) Are the answers to the above three questions related to freezing tolerance? A possible relationship between the observed cold-induced changes in phosphoproteins and the level of freezing tolerance was explored by comparing the results of experiments conducted on two cultivars (Apica and Trek) of alfalfa (Medicago sativa L.) which markedly differ in their capacity for cold acclimation. We show that the phosphorylation level of several nuclear proteins is subject to rapid and reversible enhancement by low temperature. Several phosphoproteins were found to be constitutively present in the nucleus of both cultivars. The cold-induced stimulation of the phosphorylation of many of these proteins was much greater in the relatively freezing tolerant cultivar Apica than in the relatively freezing sensitive cultivar Trek. Population of nuclear phosphoproteins was found to be considerably more complex in Apica than in Trek. During a prolonged exposure of the seedlings to 4$ sp circ$C, additional phosphoproteins were imported into the nucleus of Apica seedlings but not those Trek. Some heat-stable proteins were constitutively present in the nucleus of both cultivars. However during the 4-day cold treatment, a large accumulation of several additional heat-stable proteins was observed in the tolerant, but not the sensitive, cultivar. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Kawczyński, Wojciech</creator><contributor>Dhindsa, R. S. (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Phosphoproteins</subject><subject>Alfalfa -- Effect of cold on</subject><subject>Cold adaptation</subject><subject>Plant cellular signal transduction</subject><title>Effects of low temperature on nuclear proteins of alfalfa</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mx53h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579v389</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pg15bh14m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Accurate and efficient array dependence analysis is a crucial phase of optimizing/parallelizing compilers. The results of array dependence analysis are required for many automatic parallelism detection analyses and transformations. This thesis is concerned with the development of a dependence analysis for a certain class of loopnests in the imperative programming language C. In particular, this thesis addresses the problems of incorporating such a framework in a language that supports pointers. We propose a practical and efficient dependence testing framework built upon previously existing methods. To perform any dependence testing, a support analysis is required in order to establish a suitable environment. This support analysis has three major functions. First, it filters certain loopnests that are amenable for analysis. Second, it exposes array subscripts in terms of affine functions of loop indices. The last function is the collection of array subscript pairs in loopnests. The support analysis incorporates analysis information such as points-to information, constant propagation information and reaching definition information to yield more accurate dependence tests. An important contribution of this thesis is a statistical profiler which is used to collect information for experiments. The statistical profiler has several flags that an be set "ON" or "OFF" to support different research scenarios. Different flag settings are used for observing the effects of loop normalization, points-to analysis, constant propagation, nonperfect loopnests, delinearization and linearization on the results of the dependence testing. This thesis includes experimental results from running some benchmarks under five different scenarios. This work has been integrated into the McCAT optimizing/parallelizing C compiler. The tool is called McADT (The McCAT-Array Dependence Tester).</description><creator>Justiani, J., 1962-</creator><contributor>Hendren, Laurie J. (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>A practical array dependence analysis for anoptimizingparallelizing C compiler</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b8158.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bh14m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526f33b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sjogren's syndrome (SS) is an autoimmune disease characterized by lymphocytic infiltration of exocrine glands and a 43-fold greater risk for lymphoma development. This condition may occur as an isolated disorder, or in association with other rheumatic diseases. This study investigates the role of the Epstein-Barr virus (EBV) lytic protein p17, an inhibitor of apoptosis, in the pathology of SS. Using an enzyme-linked immunosorbent assay, a small subset (18-40%) of rheumatic patients, regardless of SS status, was found to have an elevated immune response to p17, compared to healthy individuals. Using immunofluorescence analysis, rheumatic patients were found to have an increased incidence and protein load of EBV lytic proteins, compared to healthy individuals. The particularly high load of EBV p17 could stimulate antibody production and, through the inhibition of apoptosis. render the cells more susceptible to the neoplasia that is characteristic of SS.</description><creator>Johnson, Nicole, 1971-</creator><contributor>Newkirk, Mariana (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>The association of Epstein-Barr virus with Sjügren's syndrome and lymphoproliferation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gv72j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526f33b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207tr39r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis applies Markov chain methods to evaluate the reliability of multipath switching networks and optical amplified systems in long-haul communication systems. When conventional methods proved impractical to evaluate the reliability of multipath switching networks and optical amplified systems, some practical methods based on Markov chains were developed by Whitmore and others (1987, 1988, 1991) and used successfully to evaluate the reliability of such systems. This work aims at describing the details of Markov chain methods for reliability calculation, and demonstrating their application to reliability evaluation of multipath switching networks and optical amplified systems.</description><creator>Huang, Yilan</creator><contributor>Whitmore, G. A. (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Statistics.</subject><title>Applications of Markov chains to reliability of long-haul communication systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tp036.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tr39r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816p577</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In string theory, some techniques have been developed to calculate scattering amplitudes. Because of the $SL(2, doubc)$ invariance for tree-level amplitudes, a physical inconsistency arises; the amplitudes, instead of being finite, diverge. Two techniques can be used to remedy this problem. To avoid the overcounting configurations, we can (a) divide the amplitude by the $SL(2, doubc)$ volume or (b) insert three ghosts in the amplitude integral. Independently of which one of the two ways is followed, a number of two-dimensional integrations over the complex plane remain to be performed. This thesis explores some ways to replace some of these two-dimensional integrals by two unidimensional contour integrals. Consequently, this transformation reveals a new way to think about the ghosts and their role in amplitude calculations. In fact, we can consider the ghosts as perpendicular vectors to the contour along which the integration is performed.</description><creator>Gagnon, Martin B.</creator><contributor>Myers, Robert C. (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>On the role of ghosts in string theory</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xd77x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816p577</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pg15bh15w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The neuregulins (GGF/ARIA/NDF/Heregulin) are pleiotrophic growth factors that are involved in the development of the nervous system. The neuregulin receptors, erbB2, erbB3, erbB4, are members of the erbB/epidermal growth factor receptor family of receptor tyrosine kinases. Immunoblot analysis with antisera to peptides derived from the carboxy terminus of erbB2, erbB3, erbB4 demonstrate that the three receptors have unique spatial distribution in the brain and have expression patterns which are differentially regulated during development. At a cellular level, erbB2 and erbB4 are expressed by glia and neurons while expression of erbB3 is restricted to glia. We have also found that the distribution of erbB3 is developmentally regulated in avian muscle. Moreover, following denervation in adult rats, erbB3 and erbB4 protein levels are increased sciatic nerve, and in muscle, erbB3 is elevated at 16 and 24 days after denervation.</description><creator>Francoeur, Jason</creator><contributor>Carbonetto, Salvatore (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Anatomy.</subject><title>Distribution of erbB2, erbB3, and erbB4 in the developing avian nervous system and in mammalian lesioned sciatic nerve and denervated muscle</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cc921.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bh15w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859h65g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Seventy-eight harbour porpoises, Phocoena phocoena, (33 females, 45 males) were obtained from the summer (June-September) cod fishery incidental-by-catch in the Gulf of St. Lawrence, and examined for the presence of cranial sinus nematodes. This is the first quantitative and in-depth study of the distribution of Stenurus minor (Kuhn, 1829) Baylis and Daubney, 1925 in the cranium of by-caught harbour porpoises. Stenurus minor was present in the cranial sinuses of all adult porpoises ($&gt;$1yr, n = 66, x = 2362, range 87-8920) and absent in all young-of-the-year ($&lt;$1yr, n = 12). Only fifth-stage worms were observed and these were equally distributed between the right and left side ot the skull (mean intensity = 1158 and 1213 in the left and right side, respectively). Female S. minor were predominant (1:1.8 sex ratio). Mean intensity of S. minor was similar among all infected porpoises, suggesting an annual loss and recruitment of this parasite. Parasite load had no apparent effect on porpoise body condition (measured as % blubber weight of carcass). No gross lesions associated with the presence of numerous S. minor in the cranial sinuses, were observed. There was an inverse relationship between the intensity of S. minor and mean worm-length, suggestive of a "crowding effect". Mean worm-length in lightly infected porpoises was 17.8 $ pm$ 0.2 mm and 16.1 $ pm$ 0.2 mm in heavily infected animals. Possible life-cycles and modes of transmission are examined in light of our findings. The absence of S. minor in porpoises less than 1 year old suggests heteroxenous transmission of this parasite, via an intermediate host in the food chain. Transmammary and or transplacental transmission is unlikely.</description><creator>Faulkner, Jacqueline</creator><contributor>Whoriskey, Fred (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Measures, Lena (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Lungworms.</subject><subject>Harbor porpoise -- Parasites.</subject><title>Study of the cranial sinus nematode, Stenurus minor (Metastrongyloidea), in the harbour porpoise, Phocoena phocoena</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fd88j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859h65g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v757s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tolerating and minimizing the overhead of communication/synchronization are crucial for getting good performance on parallel machines. In this thesis we evaluate one of the approaches proposed to achieve this goal. This approach is to provide architectural support, consisting of an extra processor, on every node of a parallel machine. This processor is responsible for communication/synchronization and scheduling threads of computation. As a mean to achieve this, we built a user-level communication/multi-threading package called the Threaded Communication Library (TCL) which provides communication/synchronization primitives for programs running under a multi-threaded program execution model. This library was implemented on the GMD MANNA parallel machine, which consists of a number of nodes connected by a hierarchy of cross-bar switches. Every node contains two Intel i860 processors. Two versions of TCL were implemented: a Dual-Processor version which dedicates one processor on a node for non-computational tasks as indicated above, and a Single-Processor version which performs these tasks with computation on the same processor. We implemented a number of benchmark programs using the two TCL versions to compare and to study their performance. Our results indicate that (1) for applications with asynchronous communication demands, the dual-processor version can efficiently overlap communication and computation for faster execution, and (2) for applications with more regular communication requirements, the cache effect on the computation processor and the memory bus contention cannot be ignored, and may result in the single-processor version achieving better performance.</description><creator>Elmasri, Nasser</creator><contributor>Gao, Guang R. (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>TCL : experiences on a multiprocessor with dual-processor nodes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jt296.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v757s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74cs55z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Acute tryptophan (trp) depletion, which purportedly decreases brain serotonin, lowers mood in normal males with a multigenerational family history of major affective disorder (FH+), but not in male controls. In the present study, the hypothesis that a mood lowering response to acute trp depletion may reflect a susceptibility to depression was investigated further. As both a family history of major affective disorder (MAD) and female sex are considered to be risk factors for depression, the effects of trp depletion on mood were investigated in control and FH+ women. The temporal stability of mood change to trp depletion, when rechallenged at least one month later, was also assessed in order to appraise its utility as a putative susceptibility marker. Subjects ingested a trp deficient amino acid mixture on two separate occasions and a balanced control mixture containing trp on another occasion. Compared to the balanced condition, control women exhibited a significant lowering of mood following the trp depletion, whereas in a previous study control men did not. The sex difference in the mood response to trp depletion among controls is consistent with the fact that women are at greater risk for depression than men. Unlike controls, FH+ women showed no lowering of mood, which suggests that serotonin may not be as important in the etiology of depression in these women. The mood response to trp depletion exhibited poor temporal stability, which does not support its use as a susceptibility marker of depression in normal subjects. Its utility as a putative phenotypic marker for MAD awaits further study in FH+ subjects who respond to trp depletion. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Ellenbogen, Mark Alexander</creator><contributor>Young, S. N. (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Psychology, Clinical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Nutrition.</subject><title>Mood response to acute trytophan depletion in women at genetic risk for major affective disorder and controls</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b3226.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cs55z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t409g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Three cultivators, Rabewerk, Kongskilde and Hiniker, and three intercrops, soybean, lupin and red clover + rye grass were investigated for their impact on the incidence of ear rot of corn, a common disease of maize in eastern Canada. Wheat was seeded in the corn rows to serve as an additional indicator of cultivation and intercropping effects on the pathogen. An artificial inoculum of F. graminearum that produced perithecia and ascospores was used to mimic natural inoculum. In 1993 and 1994, the infection in the corn was not very severe and there were no differences between the treatments and the controls. In 1993 and 1994, at both sites, wheat seeds from cultivation trials showed a tendency for greater disease incidence in the non-cultivated herbicide treatment when compared to any of the other cultivator treatments. Cultivators till the soil and bury corn residues, this action led to the destruction of some of the inoculum and a subsequent reduction of the disease incidence in the cultivated plots. In the intercrop trial of 1993 and 1994, wheat infection was moderate to severe, except at L'Assomption in 1993, but no significant differences were observed among the treatments. It is believed that interplot interference, due to ascospores moving from one plot to the next, masked differences. The results indicated that weed cultivation would have a negligible or no effect on the development of fusarium ear rot of corn in Quebec. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Dupeux, Yann Alain</creator><contributor>Paulitz, T. (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Wheat fusarium culmorum head blight.</subject><subject>Fusarium graminearum</subject><subject>Corn -- Diseases and pests.</subject><subject>Companion planting.</subject><title>The effect of cultivation and intercropping on the incidence of ear rot of corn and head blight of wheat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nw60b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t409g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97ks48s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:05:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Transforming growth factor-$ beta$ (TGF-$ beta$) is a multifunctional polypeptide growth factor which is believed to play an important role in the growth and differentiation of uterine cells. Although the expression of TGF-$ beta$ in the uterus has been previously described, the receptors for TGF-$ beta$ in this tissue have not been characterized. In the present study, the cell surface receptors for TGF-$ beta$ were characterized on cultures of stromal cells prepared from human endometrial biopsies, and on a human endometrial epithelial cell line (RL95-2) using affinity labeling techniques. On stromal cells, five TGF-$ beta$ binding proteins were identified. Analysis of the sensitivity of these proteins to dithiothreitol and phosphatidylinositol-specific phospholipase C, together with results from immunoprecipitations with anti-TGF-$ beta$ receptor antibodies, confirmed that three of these binding proteins correspond to the cloned type I, II, and III TGF-$ beta$ receptors. The other two binding proteins exhibited characteristics of isoform-specific glycosyl-phosphatidylinositol-anchored TGF-$ beta$ binding proteins. On RL95-2 cells, three TGF-$ beta$ binding proteins, corresponding to the type I, II and III TGF-$ beta$ receptors, were identified. The number of receptors on endometrial cells and their relative affinity for TGF-$ beta$ was estimated by Scatchard analysis. These receptors are responsive to physiological concentrations of TGF-$ beta$ as demonstrated by the effect of TGF-$ beta$ on DNA synthesis in these cells. Accordingly, they have the potential to respond to TGF-$ beta$ expressed in the endometrium in an autocrine and/or paracrine manner.</description><creator>Dumont, Nancy</creator><contributor>Philip, Anie (advisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Characterization of transforming growth factor-b receptors in the human endometrium</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vt017.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97ks48s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):1275</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>