<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:00:41Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2800" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74cs702</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:26:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>According to Julia Kristeva, abjection is an unconscious process (a cut) every human being has to operate to be able to autonomize her or himself from the dyadic relationship with the mother. An autonomous subject then has access to what « sémiotique tensive » (influenced by the phenomenology of perception andstructuralism) calls « field of presence » from where she or he can enunciate and thus enter the Symbolic order. In this thesis, I posit that the field of presence changes from modernity to postmodernity, and that some avant-garde authors, such as Michel Butor in the 1960's, are articulating the shift from one to the other and modifying the relationship between subject and abject. My textual analyses focus on two of Butor's most innovative books : Mobile. Étude pour une représentation des États-Unis (published in 1962) and 6 810 000 litres d'eau par seconde. Étude stéréophonique (usually referred to by critics as Niagara, the title of its English translation, published in 1965). My hypothesis is that, on the level of enunciation, Mobile shows traces of a modem field of presence, where the margins are highly dysphoric (abject), while Niagara tends to represent a more postmodern one, using différent discursive stratégies to defuse the abject threat. I close with a reflection on the state of abjection as a subjectivity inducing process, the subject it exhausts in postmodern times, and the new relationship to the body (therefore, to perception and enunciation) it imposes.</description><creator>Girard, Stéphane</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Butor, Michel -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>Sémiotique tensive de l'abjection chez Michel Butor</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161838k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cs702</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4x51hm42g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:26:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Various sources on Kazakh history demonstrate that a Kazakh culture was generated out of the predominantly pastoral experiences of its people. For centuries, Kazakh communities were engaged in a definite set of practices prescribed by pastoralism. Firmly incorporated into the all-Union structure of Soviet republics, Kazakhstan made an impressive transformation from a predominantly pastoral to an agroindustrial region with one of the most vibrant economies in Central Asia. Sovereignty in 1991 pushed the historic trajectory of the Kazakh nation further ahead, prompting its citizens to engage in self-reflection, and attuning their collective memories to a new set of social and political realities. It also brought the country closer to the city, as hundreds of thousands Kazakh villagers left their homes for urban areas following the downfall of the 'transitional' economy that ensued in the wake of the demise of socialism. This thesis presents an analysis of data that was collected during twelve months of ethnographic fieldwork carried out primarily in Almaty, the former capital of Kazakhstan, in 1999. A principal aim in this study is to unravel emerging subjectivities and congealed meanings that have developed within the context of Kazakh rural to urban migration, especially that which occurred after the breakdown of the Soviet Union. It centers on important themes relating to Kazakh historic ancestry and culture, the colonial encounter, the city and its populace, as well as the recently achieved national independence, as they have unfolded in the narratives of recent arrivals to the city. How have the discourses of ancestry and modernity, mediated by their experiences of migration and displacement, been implicated in migrants' understandings of themselves and their nation? Special attention in my discussion is paid to the issue of whether the recent encounter of rural and urban worlds fostered the contemplation of specific narratives of the Kazakh nation, as it emerges from Socialism.</description><creator>Yessenova, Saulesh B.</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Rural-urban migration -- Kazakhstan</subject><subject>Kazakhs -- Ethnic identity.</subject><title>The politics and poetics of the nation : urban narratives of Kazakh identity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w66345907.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hm42g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj236427f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:26:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Vulvar vestibulitis syndrome is a highly prevalent and under-investigated pain syndrome. It is believed to be the most common form of dyspareunia, or painful intercourse, in pre-menopausal women. Despite the fact that pain is its defining characteristic, its conceptualization as a sexual dysfunction remains the predominant view. The first chapter of this thesis reviews support for a re-conceptualization of vulvar vestibulitis as a pain disorder, and contends that the pain component must be measured as it is in chronic pain patients, both objectively and subjectively. This paper is followed by a study in which tactile and pain thresholds in genital and non-genital body areas of 13 women with vulvar vestibulitis syndrome and 13 non-affected women were measured, while data about the intensity and unpleasantness of these sensations were collected. Results indicated that women with vulvar vestibulitis have decreased tactile and pain thresholds in both genital and non-genital body areas, as well as higher unpleasantness ratings in response to painful stimuli than controls, replicating data from the chronic pain literature. The third paper presents a pain conceptualization of vulvar vestibulitis according to classification criteria used by the International Association for the Study of Pain, and introduces the development of a vulvalgesiometer, a standardized method of genital pain measurement. Data collected with the vulvalgesiometer are presented in the fourth paper, a study in which 14 women with vulvar vestibulitis and 14 control women participated. Women with vulvar vestibulitis had significantly lower pain thresholds, higher pain unpleasantness ratings, and used adjectives similar to those reported during intercourse in response to painful stimulation. The vulvalgesiometer was used to elicit genital tactile and pain sensation in the two groups while brain activation patterns were measured via functional magnetic rdsonance imaging, the focus of the fifth paper. Results demonstrated that women with vulvar vestibulitis have augmentations of brain activity in the processing of both painful and non-painful genital stimulation as compared with non-affected women. Overall, findings from these studies suggest that the pain of vulvar vestibulitis can be reliably measured and that the pain perspective has important implications for both research and treatment of urogenital pain problems.</description><creator>Pukall, Caroline</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Pain -- Measurement.</subject><subject>Dyspareunia.</subject><title>Understanding vulvar vestibulitis syndrome through pain measurement : applications of multidimensional pain methodologies and development of novel assessment techniques</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rw63w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236427f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j3334539</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:26:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objectives of this research were to determine the impact of 4 different bedtime snack compositions on prevention of nocturnal hypoglycemia and to determine whether optimized titration and delivery of bedtime insulin using multiple daily injections of insulin (MDI) or continuous subcutaneous insulin infusion (CSII) could prevent nocturnal hypoglycemia in the absence of bedtime snacks. We also sought to determine whether 3 months of CSII therapy would improve catecholamine response and symptom awareness to experimentally-induced hypoglycemia. The need for and the most appropriate composition of bedtime snacks were dependent on the glycemic level at bedtime. No bedtime snacks were necessary at bedtime glycemic levels &gt; 10 mmol/L. At bedtime glycemic levels between 7-10 mmol/L , a standard snack and cornstarch-containing snack worked best and at bedtime glycemic levels &lt; 7mmol/L, a standard and protein-rich snack were most effective. Despite optimized titration and delivery of bedtime insulin, including the use of CSII, "the gold standard" of nocturnal insulin replacement, the incidence of nocturnal hypoglycemia over 181 nights was 54 episodes per 100 patientnights. However, there was a substantial reduction, by 36% (p=0.17), in the incidence of nocturnal hypoglycemia with the use of bedtime snacks. Therefore bedtime snacks, tailored to the bedtime glycemic level, are recommended for ail adults undergoing intensive management with MDI or CSII. Although, 3 months of CSII therapy did not improve catecholamine response and symptom awareness to experimentally-induced hypoglycemia, it did not deteriorate the responses either. Therefore, CSII therapy is a viable option in intensive management of adults with type 1 diabetes.</description><creator>Kalergis, Maria</creator><date>2002</date><subject>Hypoglycemia -- Prevention.</subject><subject>Diabetes.</subject><title>Prevention of noctural hypoglycemia in adults with type 1 diabetes undergoing intensive management</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cs71b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j3334539</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w37639176</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:26:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research analyses the dynamics of coastal resource management in the village of Las Canas, located in the province of Pinar del Rio, Cuba. More specifically, this study examines the environmental practices and discourses of individuals in the community of Las Canas, of researchers involved in a sustainable development project focused on the mangroves in the région, and of state représentatives from the Ministry of Science, Technology and Environment (CITMA), as well as other governmental agencies involved in the area of Las Canas. This research examines how, in a context of transformation characterized by environmental dégradation, deep économie crisis and state decentralization, thèse three catégories of social actors, that is, individuals, researchers, and state représentatives, exploit and protect natural resources and construct socio-environmental relations through linkages among themselves and with the environment.</description><creator>Doyon, Sabrina</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Mangrove forests -- Cuba.</subject><subject>Sustainable development -- Sociological aspects. -- Cuba</subject><subject>Coastal zone management -- Sociological aspects. -- Cuba</subject><title>L'environnement "révolutionnaire" : pratiques, discours et dynamique socio-environnementale de la gestion des ressources côtières à Cuba</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719p52m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w37639176</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bd902</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:26:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The giant Pascua Au-Ag-Cu high-sulphidation system is located in the El Indio belt in north-central Chile, and is hosted mainly by Triassic granitic rocks and locally by Miocene breccia bodies. Hydrothermal activity involved two distinct high-sulphidation alteration stages, the later of which was accompanied by main stage mineralization. The early hydrothermal activity consisted of extensive and pervasive advanced argillic alteration, local development of vuggy silica and distal argillic to propylitic alteration. This alteration was locally overprinted by an intermediate stage comprising argillic alteration, silicification and primary jarosite, more or less contemporaneously with the formation of Brecha Central, the main breccia body in the deposit. The superimposed second major hydrothermal event produced significant advanced argillic and vuggy silica alteration. The latter likely formed at pH near 0 owing to the limited buffering capacity of previously altered rocks. Termination of the second stage of alteration coincided with the main Au-Ag-Cu mineralizing event, in which Au dissolved in pyrite and enargite, formed inclusions in these minerals, and precipitated as isolated grains of native gold. Detailed EPMA and SIMS imaging and analyses of pyrite and enargite show that both contain Au, Ag, As, Cu, Se and Te and that their distribution is crystallographically controlled. The main trace element associations in the mineralized pyrite are As-Ag, Au-Cu and Se-Te. I suggest that the first two, As-Ag and Au-Cu, were the result of coupled substitution in the Fe site, whereas Te and Se replace S by direct anion exchange. The nature of the coupled substitutions observed in the gold-bearing pyrite underlines the fact that gold is not necessarily coupled with arsenic as previously thought and that arsenic can behave as a metal in the structure of pyrite. Approximately 55% of the gold in the deposit was scavenged from mineralizing fluids that were mainly under-saturated with respect to native gold and trapped into the structure of pyrite and enargite (50 and 5%, respectively). The remaining 45%, including - 7% as inclusions in sulphides, precipitated mainly in the form of native gold with lesser calaverite for which the gold depositional mechanism is interpreted to be an increase in pH that destabilized AuHS and AuCb". Substantial late-stage Ag-enrichment, characterized by halogen-bearing phases, is evident in the upper parts of the deposit and overprints previous alteration and mineralization. The silver enrichment event is interpreted to represent the waning stage of the hydrothermal system. Secondary leaching and weathering of pyrite, enargite and alunite created two supergene products, one dominated by secondary soluble sulphates such as voltaite, massive coquimbite, chalcanthite, and romerite, and one by jarosite. Abundant sulphides in vuggy silica altered rocks, which lacked the capacity to neutralize later oxidizing fluids, were the main locus of formation of the soluble sulphates. Elsewhere, the pH likely rose above 1, which inhibited precipitation of soluble sulphates and favoured formation of jarosite. Direct-ion SIMS images and trace element analyses of soluble sulphates indicate that these minerals likely contain gold in their structures.</description><creator>Chouinard, Annick</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Geochemistry</subject><title>Alteration, mineralization and geochemistry of the high-sulphidation Au-Ag-Cu Pascua deposit, Chile-Argentina</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515q66v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bd902</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67jt46v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:26:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation seeks to explain the viewpoint of Islamic international law {siyar) with respect to the various aspects of treaties {mu'abadat) with non-Muslims. The siyar deals with (the notion) of mutual relations between Muslims and non-Muslims during times of war and peace, and thus has become an intrinsic branch of the Shari'a. The varying nature of siyar and its changing interpretation throughout Islamic history captured the attention of a number of jurists and historians from both the classical and modem times, whose works have been frequently consulted throughout this study. In the course of classical and pre-modem Islamic history, treaty-making continued to evolve and contributed to shaping both political and social relations between Muslims and non-Muslims. Non-Muslim residents in Islamic territories {dar al-Islam), such as the abl al-dhimma and ahl al-aman, were dealt with as existing identities within Islam and were also dealt with by the means of contracts ('aqd), which determined their status under siyar. Relations between Muslims and non-Islamic territories {dar al-harb) were detennined by the conditions of peace and war, and treaties between the two were regulated according to the precedent set by siyar. The treaties selected for this dissertation cover the full spectrum of what Muslims and non-Muslims could do to develop and protect the interest of their communities. Thus, this study aims to shed some bight on a relatively untouched branch of Islamic law, while also elucidating the social ramifications of legal theory and practice.</description><creator>Bsoul, Labeeb Ahmed</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Islamic law.</subject><subject>International law (Islamic law)</subject><subject>Treaties</subject><title>International treaties (muahadat) in Islam : theory and practice in the light of siyar (Islamic international law)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257h14v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jt46v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77ft641</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:26:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Numerical notation systems are structured, visual, and primarily non-phonetic systems for representing number. This study employs a diachronic and comparative framework to examine over 100 systems used during the past 5000 years. The historical context of each system's origin, transmission, transformation, and decline is traced, linking systems together into phylogenies, but according priority to neither analogical or homological explanations. Structural aspects of numerical notation systems are compared and the limits of variability among them are established. A two-dimensional typology is presented that analyzes the intraexponential and interexponential structuring of each system, in addition to one or more numerical bases. In previous approaches, the only relevant factor considered was the presence or absence of positionality, which led inevitably to unilinear and progressivist conclusions. The analysis of historical relations among numerical notation systems permits a direct approach to questions of how and why they changed. The application of a multilinear cultural evolutionary framework reveals both synchronic and diachronic regularities among numerical notation systems. Where possible, these cross-cultural regularities are related to principles of cognitive psychology. Full explanations of the cultural evolution of numerical notation must also take account of social factors because changes in systems are always the product of decisions made in particular social contexts. Most numerical notation systems are used only for recording and communication, not computation, so it is illegitimate to evaluate their usefulness for functions for which they were never used. A model is presented that relates structural features of numerical notation systems to the contexts of their use and transmission. Because positional systems are most useful for functions related to administrative and scientific institutions that promote cultural hegemony, the observed trend towards positional numerals is a consequence of the dominance of societies that possess such institutions rather than the numerals' inherent superiority.</description><creator>Chrisomalis, Stephen</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Numeration -- History.</subject><title>The comparative history of numerical notation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r774p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77ft641</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zd368</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:26:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation describes the teaching and learning experiences of teachers and students in an interior design class. Student-teacher studio interactions were videotaped and documented during the 2000-2001 academic school year, in a three-year bachelor interior design university program. Phenomenological and interpretive methods were used for the gathering, analysis and interpretation of the data. The questions that guided the study include (1) What happens in the interior design class, (2) How do teachers respond to perceived problems of understanding, and how do I work with my colleagues to tailor the ways that we see students learning the design process, and (3) A study of the learning environment: what are the students doing and how do they respond to our ideas. The purpose was to understand meanings held in design processes as student-situated experiences in the design studio. The analysis was done as dialectic between narrative text and diagrammatic conceptual analysis. Individual conversations were interpreted and analysed through the use of reflective analytic memoing and visual diagrams conceptualising of the issues and emerging analysis. There were many underlying messages that became evident during the data analysis itself. The data revealed that students were frustrated by several underlying messages. Negotiations and dynamics operated in both the self-contained data group and within the larger social design studio milieu itself. The data captured many issues that remained unanswered until theoretical sampling was conducted later in the analysis phase. This theoretical sampling consisted of further conversations with the data group students, focus groups, individual conversations with colleagues and students, and a comparative teaching experience with a new group of students in the same studio class one year later. The culmination of the original data, the conversations, the comparative data analysis and subsequent reflective analysis revealed the difficulties in capturing the nature of the design process and in defining what is interior design. Clarification of meaning in interior design lays the foundation for the design process exploration. Emergent issues include the need for teacher and student reflexive thinking that reaches beyond the confines of the studio, and the importance of the interrelationship between the teacher and the student in creating the learning experience.</description><creator>Poldma, Tiiu Vaikla</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Education - Curriculum and Instruction</subject><title>An investigation of learning and teaching processes in an interior design class : an interpretive and contextual inquiry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752k000.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zd368</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514nn68x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:26:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation examines the evolution of the urban tissues of Quebec City's "faubourgs." It présents a diachronic morphological analysis of the structuration of the residential tissues of these neighborhoods between 1608 and 2001. It also provides a synchronic analysis of the syntax of the tissues as well as an architectural typology describing the main architectural types in terms of genesis and processes of derivation in successive types. Finally, it examines the practices of different groups of agents and their impacts on morphological change, while stressing the social and economic conditions under which these agents acted. The study is intended as a contribution to the fields of Urban Morphology and Urban History. This case study is among the first to apply in a North American context the theoretical framework and methods developed by the Italian school of process typology. It proposes also to envision morphological transformation through a theory of practice. Drawing heavily on cartographie documentation, urban iconography, and archival material on land development from notarial and religious sources, this urban morphogenetic study posits that the formation of the urban tissue can be better understood as the outeome of a dialectical interplay between purposeful planning practices, everyday "spontaneous" practices, and structurally resilient settlement configurations and urban form inherited from the past.</description><creator>Gauthier, Pierre</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Suburban homes -- History. -- Québec (Province) -- Québec</subject><subject>Suburbs -- History. -- Québec (Province) -- Québec</subject><title>Le tissu urbain comme forme culturelle : morphogenèse des faubourgs de Québec, pratiques de l'habiter, pratiques de mise en oeuvre et représentations</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881p26w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nn68x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Urban Planning</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj236428q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:26:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In response to the anthropological literature on old age and ageing that remains largely isolated from more contemporary anthropological theory, this thesis re-focuses anthropological attention on the experiences of ageing. Towards this end, I examine the way macro- (history, politics, economics) and micro-level processes (social relations, intergenerational relations, local contexts, individual histories) intersect to frame the cultural construction of old age, personal experiences of "being old", and the self. A central point of intersection between these processes comes from the recent history of social transformation in my fieldsite, Dodworth, a former coal-mining village. Since the late 1980s, this is an area that has been grappling with the rupturing effects of the closure of the coal-mining industry. Attending to these conditions and how they inform the everyday reality and the experiences of ageing and of the self are critical concerns in this thesis. My approach to the ageing self is one that privileges narrativity and temporality as key constitutive elements and which considers the potentially different position of older people in relation to time and to the self. Growing older is a complicated mixture of bodily and social change, and negotiating these shifts has crucial implications for one's sense of self and subjectivity. While "old age" is a category which is readily used in daily discourse and living, what old age is and who is old nevertheless resists anchoring. What old age, being old and ageing meant to my research participants are key questions in order to understand the experience of growing older in Dodworth. Throughout the thesis, I focus on the dialectics of interpersonal interactions in order to speak meaningfully about how the experience of old age is organised and constructed. Emerging in tandem with these issues is another major topic of this thesis: social memory. Talk in Dodworth about places, absences, and relations continually brought the past and present together and was involved in how a sense of self is created. What emerged was a three-dimensionality of memory, an individual and collective way of placing oneself and others in relation to spatial aspects of the villagescape.</description><creator>Degnen, Cathrine</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Autobiographical memory -- Social aspects.</subject><subject>Aging -- Anthropological aspects -- England -- Dodworth</subject><subject>Older people -- Social networks -- England -- Dodworth.</subject><title>Mining experience : the ageing self, narrative, and social memory in Dodworth, England</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945t09j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236428q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mp56q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:26:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Deregulation, globalization, and commercialization are drastically changing the space industry. But commercial space activities entail considerable risks. This thesis is primarily an analysis of the risks that private entities in the space industry need to manage in order to be commercially successful. Due to the trend towards a buyer's market, satellite manufacturers increasingly have been forced to accept risks that do not fall within their traditional core business. Consequently, manufacturing companies become risk managers for a variety of legal space risks. Therefore, the legal framework for the commercial management of legal risks is analyzed and solutions to identified problems are offered. This thesis studies trends in contemporary risk management practices in the private sector, which is dominated by market forces. It is argued that risk management of legal issues should form an integral part of overall space project management, the rationale being that losses in any phase of space activities, while certain to occur, are uncertain in time and scale. This thesis, therefore, scrutinizes legal risk management throughout the life cycle of space projects. Few space applications have become commercially viable. Today, satellite navigation provided by the U.S. GPS is widely used, especially because it is free of direct charges. In Europe, a competing system, Galileo, is being developed. It will provide users with different service levels, ranging from free services to more reliable and accurate navigation services. As this system has both, public and commercial benefits, the industry is expected to participate in a Public Private Partnership for the Galileo satellite constellation. This thesis makes specific proposals to manage the legal risks of the Galileo project. At the same time, the allocation of legal space risks between the various parties is studied. The thesis of the author is that the management process, which is used to control technical space risks, can provide satellite manufacturers with a supportive analogy for dealing with legal space risks. Risks will be studied for all project phases of Galileo, i.e., the feasibility study, the establishment of specifications, development, manufacturing, the launch, operations, replenishment, and the final disposition of satellites.</description><creator>Hörl, Kay-Uwe</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Risk management.</subject><subject>Artificial satellites in navigation -- Law and legislation.</subject><subject>Navigation (Aeronautics)</subject><subject>Space law</subject><title>Legal aspects of risks involved in commercial space activities</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977x13n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mp56q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:736666889</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:26:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The relationship of musicmaking to the city is a complicated one as it often takes very specific and complex spatial and social forms. The example of Montreal can be used to illustrate some of the ways in which these forms manifest themselves. By considering the way in which two particular cultural spaces, namely scene and bohemia, emerge in relation to musical activity, this project analyzes the nature of musicmaking and its role in shaping a unique experience of the city. It frames a case study of Montreal musicmaking to explore the ways in which scenes and bohemias are connected to city life. It also considers the way in which a particular image of the city manifests itself through musicmaking. The collective representation of Montreal as a bohemia by anglophone musicmakers works with and through a number of social divisions and cultural distinctions. It is argued that the nature of place-images and mythology in musicmaking is such that they have a profound effect on the sociomusical experience of the city. Montreal is privileged by many anglophone musicmakers as an ideal city in which to be culturally active, as the city's weak economic state is perceived to foster the conditions best suited to a flourishing bohemia. This project examines the relationship of musicmakers to Montreal, using a  variety of research methods and theories. Cognitive mapping, diaristic accounts and interviews are utilized to better apprehend how a chosen image of Montreal affects musical practice. The socioeconomic history of Montreal in the latter half of the twentieth century is used to frame an analysis of the emergence of an independent music scene in the city. By exploring a number of relevant factors, this project documents the ways in which musicmaking is structured in relation to the economic, political and social dimensions of Montreal.</description><creator>Stahl, Geoff</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Musicians -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Music -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Montréal (Québec) -- Intellectual life</subject><subject>Bohemianism -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>Crisis? what crisis? : Anglophone musicmaking in Montreal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pg16h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/736666889</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s463q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:26:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study is the first step toward a better understanding of the introduction of pervasive imitation at the end of the fifteenth century. The focus is on selected works of Loyset Compère: the ténor motet Omnium bonorum plena, two motetti missales cycles and twenty chansons. Four types of repetition have been identified in these works: imitation, free repetition, repeated modules and doubling. The main analysis is based on the statistical frequency of the different types of repetition. Percentage tables allow us to observe stylistic changes between early and late chansons and also underline some resemblances between late chansons and motetti missales. Different types of repetition tend to vary in length; imitation generally uses longer melodic lines than other types of repetition. I also studied pitch intervals of repetition used by Compère. I have noticed that unlike some composers of the time, Compère used pitch intervais other than the octave and unison, mainly the fifth and principally in his late chansons. Finally, I have constructed a System of modular classification which allowed me to identify unifying devices used by Compère in his motetti missales. The results presented in this thesis suggest that Loyset Compère was a major contributor to the evolution of pervasive imitation.</description><creator>Goulet, Marie-Maude.</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Polyphonic chansons -- 15th century -- Analysis, appreciation.</subject><subject>Music -- France -- 15th century -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Compère, Loyset, d. 1518</subject><subject>Motets -- 15th century -- Analysis, appreciation.</subject><title>Analyses et comparaisons des techniques répétitives utilisées dans les oeuvres séculaires et sacrées de Loyset Compère</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n5475.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s463q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tq57nt16w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:26:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The giant Pascua Au-Ag-Cu high-sulphidation system is located in the El Indio belt in north-central Chile, and is hosted mainly by Triassic granitic rocks and locally by Miocene breccia bodies. Hydrothermal activity involved two distinct high-sulphidation alteration stages, the later of which was accompanied by main stage mineralization. The early hydrothermal activity consisted of extensive and pervasive advanced argillic alteration, local development of vuggy silica and distal argillic to propylitic alteration. This alteration was locally overprinted by an intermediate stage comprising argillic alteration, silicification and primary jarosite, more or less contemporaneously with the formation of Brecha Central, the main breccia body in the deposit. The superimposed second major hydrothermal event produced significant advanced argillic and vuggy silica alteration. The latter likely formed at pH near 0 owing to the limited buffering capacity of previously altered rocks. Termination of the second stage of alteration coincided with the main Au-Ag-Cu mineralizing event, in which Au dissolved in pyrite and enargite, formed inclusions in these minerals, and precipitated as isolated grains of native gold. Detailed EPMA and SIMS imaging and analyses of pyrite and enargite show that both contain Au, Ag, As, Cu, Se and Te and that their distribution is crystallographically controlled. The main trace element associations in the mineralized pyrite are As-Ag, Au-Cu and Se-Te. I suggest that the first two, As-Ag and Au-Cu, were the result of coupled substitution in the Fe site, whereas Te and Se replace S by direct anion exchange. The nature of the coupled substitutions observed in the gold-bearing pyrite underlines the fact that gold is not necessarily coupled with arsenic as previously thought and that arsenic can behave as a metal in the structure of pyrite. Approximately 55% of the gold in the deposit was scavenged from mineralizing fluids that were mainly under-saturated with respect to native gold and trapped into the structure of pyrite and enargite (50 and 5%, respectively). The remaining 45%, including - 7% as inclusions in sulphides, precipitated mainly in the form of native gold with lesser calaverite for which the gold depositional mechanism is interpreted to be an increase in pH that destabilized AuHS and AuCb". Substantial late-stage Ag-enrichment, characterized by halogen-bearing phases, is evident in the upper parts of the deposit and overprints previous alteration and mineralization. The silver enrichment event is interpreted to represent the waning stage of the hydrothermal system. Secondary leaching and weathering of pyrite, enargite and alunite created two supergene products, one dominated by secondary soluble sulphates such as voltaite, massive coquimbite, chalcanthite, and romerite, and one by jarosite. Abundant sulphides in vuggy silica altered rocks, which lacked the capacity to neutralize later oxidizing fluids, were the main locus of formation of the soluble sulphates. Elsewhere, the pH likely rose above 1, which inhibited precipitation of soluble sulphates and favoured formation of jarosite. Direct-ion SIMS images and trace element analyses of soluble sulphates indicate that these minerals likely contain gold in their structures.</description><creator>Marong, Alhagi</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Nigeria -- Economic policy</subject><subject>Sustainable development -- Nigeria.</subject><subject>Petroleum industry and trade -- Nigeria.</subject><subject>Environmental law -- Nigeria</subject><title>The role of law in sustainable development : a case study of the petroleum industry in Nigeria</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268738g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57nt16w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qv145</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:26:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The interplay of religion and politics has been a consistent theme in the comparativepolitics of identity, and more specifically with regard to Middle Eastern politics Yetcoverage of religion and politics in the region is generally focused on the Muslimmajority and neglects the existence and impact of non-Muslim religious elements inMiddle Eastern societies. The most prominent of these are the various groups ofChristian Arabs.This work begins with a reassessment of common comparative theoretical approaches tothe study of religion and politics. It introduces a critical and dynamic constructivistapproach to religion, defining it as belief'. Using belief the political environment, andrelative demographics as a guide, it creates four general types of Christian groups as ameans to understand Christian group activation. These types match up with three generalmodes of engagement with the outside political culture in Middle Eastern contexts:competitive-nationalistic systems, neo-millet systems, and secular non-sectarian systems.These analytical tools are applied to the political activity of Christian groups in threeMiddle Eastern polities: Egypt, Lebanon, and Palestine. In Egypt, a stable neo-milletsystem is the result of the dominance of a single deferential organization amongChristians: the Coptic Orthodox Church. In Lebanon, years of competitive nationalisticpolitics have given way to an emergent neo-millet system as a result of the decline inidentity-based nationalistic parties and the increasing prominence of the traditionalChurch hierarchy. Among Palestinians, nominalism, deference, and voluntaristicactivism mix to create a neo-millet system with aspects of other systems of engagement.This study concludes that neo-millet systems are the natural outcome of a stronglyidentity-focused religious belief system among Arab Christians, one the author terms"tower-keep" theology. However, the dynamics of change fostered by new styles ofbelief, the challenges of responding to an eroding population base, and the influence ofdiaspora communities and coreligionists abroad all point to new systems of engagementto come in the future.</description><creator>Rowe, Paul Stanley</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Religion and politics -- Middle East.</subject><subject>Christians -- Middle East.</subject><title>Ancient crosses and tower-keeps : the politics of Christian minorities in the Middle East</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g480c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qv145</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053j33x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:26:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines the role of religion in the nationalist thought of Lionel Groulx (1878-1967). It attempts to demonstrate that Groulx's understanding of the Incarnation constitutes a paradigm whereby he developed a rationale for the synthesis of Catholicism and French-Canadian nationalism. Chapter 1, the Historical Background, precedes an examination of Groulx's thought in the light of his theological and philosophical education.(Chapter 2) Chapters 3 and 4 explain his construct of the Incarnation. Chapter 5 sets forth Groulx's conception of French Canada based on the Hebrew scriptures. Chapters 6 explores the implications of his incarnational thought for his nationalist pursuits. Chapter 7 summarizes the pivotal idea of "The Primacy of the Spiritual in the Nation," while Chapter 8 sheds light on Groulx's critical, if not negative understanding of Catholic Action. The conclusion reflects on the turn of events in French Canada which evolved so contrary to his aspirations. Despite his myriad activities, prodigious body of work, and such a long, varied career, Groulx remains an enigma primarily due to his transitional role between old religio-nationalist French Canada and secular, contemporary nationalist Quebec. The apologetic intent of his work compounds this enigma since Groulx thereby attempted to apply the conservative social doctrines and praxis of conventional Catholicism to the rapidly changing context of modern, increasingly nationalist Quebec. His thought, therefore, possesses many facets and eludes facile definition. Due to their segregated analyses of Groulx's thought, previous historical, political and ideological studies remain insufficient because they represent largely secular, anachronistic, specifically post-'Quiet Revolution' approaches that truncate the role of religion in the world view of a Catholic priest in French Canada at the turn of the twentieth century. These analyses do not sufficiently take into account the theological principles which shaped his nationalist thought. Writing as editor-in-chief of Le Devoir the day after Groulx died, Claude Ryan declared Groulx "the spiritual father of modern Quebec." However, this assessment largely stands or falls on the place of the 'spiritual' vis-a-vis the 'secular' in Groulx's thought, for the reversal of their respective importance in French-Canadian society announced the advent of modernity in Quebec. In fact, the contemporary debate concerning the proper roles and relationship of the secular and the spiritual in twentieth-century Quebec gave rise to Groulx's apologetic. This study seeks therefore to examine the spiritual and the temporal in Groulx's thought, and how he related the two so that we may come to a better understanding of Groulx's contribution to modern Quebec.</description><creator>Cornett, Norman F.</creator><date>2002</date><subject>Groulx, Lionel, 1878-1967</subject><subject>Nationalism -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Religion and state -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>The role of religion in Lionel Groulx's nationalist thought</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vn143.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053j33x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q634g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:26:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The nation-state is now the dominant form of sovereign statehood, however, a century and a half ago the political map of Europe comprised only a handful of sovereign states, very few of them nations in the modern sense. Balkan historiography often tends to minimize the complexity of nation-building, either by referring to the national community as to a monolithic and homogenous unit, or simply by neglecting different social groups whose consciousness varied depending on region, gender and generation. Further, Bulgarian and Serbian historiography pay far more attention to the problem of "how" and "why" certain events have happened than to the emergence of national consciousness of the Balkan peoples as a complex and durable process of mental evolution. This dissertation on the concept of nationality in which most Bulgarians and Serbs were educated and socialized examines how the modern idea of nationhood was disseminated among the ordinary people and it presents the complicated process of national indoctrination carried out by various state institutions. The historical data examined demonstrate that before the establishment of their sovereign states ordinary Serbs and Bulgarians had only a vague idea, if any, of their national identity. The peasantry was accustomed to defining itself in terms of religion, locality and occupation, not in terms of nationality. Once the nation state was established peasants had to be indoctrinated in nationalism. The inculcation was executed through the schooling system, military conscription, the Christian Orthodox Church, and the press. It was through the channels of these state institutions that a national identity came into existence.</description><creator>Bozeva-Abazi, Katrin</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Nationalism -- Serbia</subject><subject>Serbia -- History -- 1804-1918.</subject><subject>Nationalism -- Bulgaria</subject><subject>Bulgaria -- History -- 19th century.</subject><title>The shaping of Bulgarian and Serbian national identities, 1800s-1900s</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tt834.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q634g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p2676x98d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:26:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation offers the first comprehensive examination of realism in English-Canadian fiction of the early twentieth century. It argues for the existence of a "modern-realist" movement that is Canada's unique and unacknowledged contribution to the collection of international movements that makes up literary modernism. This argument involves a detailed analysis of the aesthetics, aims, preoccupations, and techniques of the modern realists, a reexamination of the oeuvres of the movement's most prominent writers, and a critical reevaluation of the "modernity" of Canada's three most significant realist sub-genres—prairie realism, urban realism, and social realism. This study also provides a literary-historical overview of the movement as a whole, which begins with the inauguration of the Canadian Bookman in 1919, and concludes with the emergence of a contemporary Canadian fiction in the 1950s. The conclusions arrived at in this work are based upon a reading of dozens of novels and works of short fiction, many of them unpublished and/or critically neglected and forgotten. The findings in this study are also based on original research into archival materials from seven institutions across Canada.</description><creator>Hill, Colin</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Canadian fiction -- 20th century -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Modernism (Literature)</subject><subject>Realism in literature.</subject><title>The modern-realist movement in English-Canadian fiction, 1919-1950</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x357p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676x98d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n009w460n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:26:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Visual art and written text have been described as historical sisters, linguistic twins and warlike enemies. These attempts to exclusively define the capabilities of each medium are inherently limited, contradictory and inaccurate. A better understanding of their individual capability and cooperative possibility can be achieved by examining the ways in which each functions in relation to the other on the composite page. William Blake's designs provide an excellent arena in which the functional interaction between the arts can be observed. Blake's visual additions to the poetry of Thomas Gray, Robert Blair and Edward Young demonstrate that the visual image is capable of interrupting the stability of exclusive textual meaning. However, this does not undermine the capability of either medium to assert meaningful possibility. Rather, the excess of Blake's visual imagery amidst another's poetic page produces a pluralisation of media and representative potential that avoids the extremes of hierarchical definition and all-inclusive meaninglessness. In contrast, Blake's own composites feature visual art and textual expression that both contribute to an overall evasion of definitive interpretation. However, their unpredictable interrelations and inconsistencies amplify and distort one another on the composite page, sustaining a relationship that is neither exclusively harmonic nor discordant. Thus, the non-synthetic "marriage" of contrary states that provides the subject matter of the Songs and the Marriage is also an accurate model for the overall relationship between visual art and text in Blake's designs. A consideration of historical context reveals the contradictory currents that direct and antagonise Blake's designs and suggests that the perception of the relationship between the "Sister Arts" often depends on such temporal conditions. While acknowledging the limitations imposed by historical circumstance, this study also recognises that late eighteenth-century uncertainties encourage innovative reconceptualisations of composite interaction. In both form and content, Blake's designs contain yet contend with a variety of perspectives, and are invaluable examples of the individual and interactive plenitude that visual art and text are capable of. Overall, Blake's work highlights the unique role that the multi-media space plays in creative and critical efforts to understand the functional capability of each representative medium.</description><creator>Saklofske, Jon A. H.</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Blake, William, 1757-1827 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>"Enough! or too much" : the functions of media interaction in William Blake's composite designs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397b45n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w460n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w3763918g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:27:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The p75 neurotrophin receptor (p75NTR) binds members of the neurotrophin family and plays important roles in the regulation of neuronal survival, apoptosis and growth during development and after nervous system injury. Many in vitro and in vivo studies have shown that p75NTR induces cell death, though the signaling events that link p75NTR activation to apoptosis are not thoroughly understood. p75NTR-dependent apoptosis is associated with an increase in Rac and Jun kinase (JNK) activity, and recent work from our laboratory has shown that the p75NTR interactor, NRAGE, activates a mitochondrial death pathway involving JNK-dependent cytochrome C release and activation of Caspase-9, Caspase-7 and Caspase-3. Despite this progress, several important details of p75NTR apoptotic signaling remain unknown. In particular, it is unclear what targets of p75NTR-dependent JNK activation result in mitochondrial cytochrome C release and caspase activation. BH3-domain-only proteins are members of the Bcl-2 family that induce the association of Bax and Bak which in turn facilitate release of mitochondrial proteins such as cytochrome C into the cytosol. Transcriptional activation of BH3-domain-only genes through c-Jun- or p53-dependent pathways is implicated in apoptosis in neuronal and non-neuronal systems. In the first part of this thesis, I examined whether p75NTR-induced apoptosis is correlated with accumulation of BH3-domain-only gene products. U373 human glioma cells and mouse cortical neurons were infected with adenovirus expressing p75NTR to constitutively activate p75NTR-dependent pathways, and alterations in mRNA levels of the BH3-domain-only family members Bim, Bmf, Hrk, Bik, Puma, and Noxa were determined by RT-PCR. The results from these experiments showed that p75NTRmediated cell death did not result in BH3-domain-only gene transcription. Subsequent studies in our laboratory established that the BH3-domain-only protein, Bad, is phosphorylated on Serine 128 in a JNK-dependent manner, and that this phosphorylation is a critical component of p75NTR-dependent apoptosis. The generation of animals that lack p75NTR expression has been a critical advance in understanding the in vivo role of this receptor. In the second part of this thesis, I analyzed the recently created p75NTRExonlv-/- mice, which were shown to produce a null mouse lacking all p75NTR gene products, in contrast to the previously constructed p75NTRExon1"-/- mouse, which maintains expression of an alternatively spliced form of p75NTR (s-p75NTR). Our studies revealed that  75NTRExonIV-/- mice continue to express a p75NTR gene product that encodes a truncated protein containing the p75NTR extracellular stalk region together with the entire transmembrane and intracellular domains. The gene product is initiated from a cryptic Kozak consensus/initiator ATG sequence within a region of Exon IV located 3' to the pGK-Neo insertion site, likely as a result of enhancer elements within pGK-Neo cassette. Characterization of this protein product indicated that it localized to the plasma membrane and overexpression of the p75NTRExonIV fragment in heterologous cells resulted in activation of JNK and cleavage of Procaspase 3, indicating that it can mediate pro-apoptotic effects in vivo. These results indicate that aspects of the p75NTRExonIV-/- phenotype may reflect a gain-of-function mutation rather than a loss of p75NTR function.</description><creator>Paul, Christine E.</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience</subject><title>Analysis of p75NTR-dependent apoptotic pathways and of p75NTR gene products</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dr77d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763918g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vj97h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:27:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Aging is the consequence ofan array of phenotypic variations that appear to involve intrinsic or  constitutional properties in all cells and systems, including qualitative and quantitative alterations in development, maturational structure and function. The aging process in bone involves a set ofchanges in bone cells differentiation, interaction and premature death. Osteoblasts are the cells most affected during the aging process in bone due to their complex mechanisms ofdifferentiation, their interaction with honnones and growth factors and their progression to apoptosis.</description><creator>Duque, Gustavo</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery</subject><title>Molecular changes in the aging osteoblast</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k727z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vj97h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:td96k4803</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:27:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Numerous studies have demonstrated that noncompliance causes increased morbidity and mortality from a wide variety of illnesses. Solutions to the problem require systematic evaluation of the determinants of noncompliance and identification of subgroups of patients who are vulnerable so appropriate interventions can be designed. Population-based research methods are needed to evaluate this problem.</description><creator>Fairchild, Carol J.</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</subject><title>Prescription refill compliance validation study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386m59z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k4803</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w6634591h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:27:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Little is known about the human orbitofrontal cortex and its role in encoding information, although studies in the monkey suggest that it plays an important role in memory. This thesis describes a series of functional neuroimaging studies that investigated the contribution of the orbitofrontal cortex when normal human subjects were engaged in encoding information.</description><creator>Frey, Stephen</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience</subject><title>On the orbitofrontal cortex and encoding</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848s688.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w6634591h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514nn696</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:27:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>tRNALys3 is selectively packaged into HIV-1 during viral assembly, and is placed upon the primer binding site (PBS) of the viral genome where it acts as the primer for reverse transcriptase. This Ph.D. project involved studying the factors involved in the regulation of tRNALys packaging, as well as the effect of overexpression of tRNALys3 in the virion.</description><creator>Gabor, Juliana</creator><date>2003</date><subject>Health Sciences - Immunology</subject><title>Role and regulation of tRNALys3 in the life cycle of human immunodeficency virus type 1</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720g13j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nn696</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2825</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>