<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:30:36Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):10675" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773z748</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Regeneration, function, and maintenance of integrity of the liver were studied in five groups of hemihepatectomized dogs with varying hemodynamic inflow to the residual half liver, and one group with intact livers but differentially ligated inflow to each half. Atrophy is distinguished from lack of regeneration, and is shown to be solely dependent upon adequacy of total volume of liver blood flow, and not any trophic substance or specific type of flow. This concept is extended to the problems of revascularization and atrophy of auxiliary liver transplants. A model is described and evaluated utilizing renal vein blood as "portal" inflow to the transplant, leaving intact portal blood supply to the damaged host liver. Excellent survival and function results, suggesting possible clinical application of this model as a temporary means of hepatic support with the expectation of potential recovery and regeneration of the host liver undeprived of its portal inflow.</description><creator>Wexler, Marvin J.</creator><contributor>MacLean, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>The physiological requirements for successful auxiliary liver transplantation as temporary hepatic support</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246w03x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773z748</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43p134d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The high familial rate of anencephaly and spina bifida was used to test whether spina bifida occulta is a minor form of neural- tube defects. Occulta's were identified from X-Rays taken in hospitals and reproductive histories obtained from the mothers, thus ascertaining dysraphic conditions in 100 families. Out of 525 brothers and sisters, 3 malformations (1 spina bifida, 2 spina bifida-like) were found whilst at least 25 were expected from the rate observed in studies in which anencephaly and spina bifida cystica were indicators. The findings do not support that the occult type belongs to the pathological line of major dysraphic malformations. A finer division of the cases, combined with a more complete ascertainment of other relatives in addition to the sibs would possibly bring to light situations where high neuro-dysraphical risk exists. Spina bifida occulta in general appears not to be a minor neural tube anomaly. Some of the defects may depend upon bony disturbances of later production.</description><creator>Tourillon, Paule</creator><contributor>McDonald, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Epidemiology and Health.</subject><title>Relationship between spina bifida occulta, spina bifada cystica and anencephaly</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526g40z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p134d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451m81t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The soluble fraction of a rat liver homogenate incubated in the presence of ATP is capable of sulfurylating a number of 17-deoxy- and 17-hydroxysteroids of the pregn-4-ene series, such as cortisol and 11-deoxycorticosterone. Under the same conditions sulfurylation of 11-deoxycorticosterone occurs in liver, kidney and gut, but is some 3 to 4 times more efficient in the female than in the male liver. This sex linked difference in rat liver sulfokinase activity is further demonstrated by the finding that sulfurylation of corticosterone is decreased by ovariectomy and brought back to the level observed in normal females by injection of estradiol-17β (at the dose of 6 µg/100 gm body weight) to castrated females; increased by orchidectomy and further enhanced by the administration of the same dose of estradiol- 17β to orchidectomized rats.</description><creator>Torday, John S.</creator><contributor>Giroud, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Studies on C-21 steroid sulfokinases in the rat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r418j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451m81t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085p32c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Caffeine (10^-4 g./ml.) was used to attempt to alter intracellular Ca levels in frog motor nerve terminaIs; the effects of this treatment on standard parameters of transmitter release were studied. These effects included: an increase of 30% in the amplitude of the end-plate potential (e.p.p.), with most of the increase deriving from an increased amplitude of the miniature end-plate potential (m.e.p.p.); an increase of 80% in the resting m.e.p.p. frequency; a transient increase of 15%, followed by a sustained depression of 50%, in m.e.p.p. frequency in 15 mM K; a slowing of the rate of decline of post-tetanic potentiation of m.e.p.p. frequency; and a marked reduction in post-tetanic potentiation of e.p.p. amplitude. The significance of these results for the mechanism of transmitter release is discussed, with particular reference to the control of Ca activity in the immediate vicinity of the transmitter release sites.</description><creator>Swenarchuk, Lauren E.</creator><contributor>Birks, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Physiology.</subject><title>Effects of caffeine on neuromuscular transmission in the frog</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xw07g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085p32c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c534fr966</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The object of this research involves two enzymes that form part of the enzymic mechanism of the pentose phosphate cycle, an outline of which is shown in Figure 1. The properties of all the enzymes and an account of the early work leading to the elucidation of the cycle can be found in a number of excellent reviews (1-5). The main function of the Embden-Meyerhof-Parnas pathway is generally regarded as being the breakdown of glucose and the production of energy. This, however, is not the case with the pentose phosphate cycle, since NADPH does not appear to be linked to the electron transport chain and its production is not accompanied by oxidative phosphorylation (7). NADPH, however, is important as a source of reducing power.</description><creator>Stuart, Allan L.</creator><contributor>Wood, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Purification and properties of D-ribulose-5-phosphate-3-epimerase and D-ribose-5-phosphate ketol isomerase</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/028710178.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fr966</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05ff96f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Transplantation antigen was isolated in its soluble form by injecting ultrasonicated lymphoid tissue in rat using the principle of biological filtration. The effect of biologically filtered antigen was studied in localized graft-versus-host reaction (Elkins' reaction). It showed almost complete suppression of reaction. The mechanism of action is postulated with the historical review of the subject. It is suggested that soluble antigen or one that bypasses macrophages is capable of inducing tolerance and opens the possibility of selective immunosuppression.</description><creator>Siddiquie, Naeemuddin M.</creator><contributor>Taguchi, Y. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Localized graft-versus-host reaction (Elkins’ reaction); its modification with biologically filtered antigen</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816q55w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05ff96f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rb68xf89x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>When rat brain is homogenised in plain sucrose solution about 20-35% of tissue GABA, L-glutamic acid, L-aspartic acid, L-alanine, L-glutamine and glycine are found to be occluded by brain particles. An extra 30% for GABA and 10-15% for the other five amine acids are bound if the medium contains 40 mM NaCl. These sodium-dependent bound forms are in rapid equilibrium with the free amine acids in the medium. The binding characteristics of L-glutamine resemble that of GABA. Both ouabain and protoveratrine inhibit the binding (sodium dependent) of these amino acids to brain particles. Their effects are greatest on GABA. Exchange, in contrast to binding, is not affected by these drugs.</description><creator>Shiu, Pak-Chung</creator><contributor>Elliott, K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>The binding and uptake of amino acids by brain tissues</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pw91w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xf89x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827f77z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The concept of delayed hypersensitivity is traced from the classical tubercular reaction to homograft rejection. Some of the mechanisms implicated are listed and special attention is given to migration inhibition. Prolongation of grafts by "tolerogenic antigen" is noted and it is speculated that such prolongation may be reflected in alterations of the migration inhibition phenomenon. A rat model for testing this hypothesis using peritoneal exudate cells is described. Problems in methodology are noted and discussed with suggestions of alternative techniques. The unrecognized non-syngeneic nature of recipient "Lewis" animals is noted as a major cause of experimental failure once the method had been mastered. Experimental proof of such immunologic differences is offered. An attempt is made to locate the phenomenon of migration inhibition within the framework of current immunologic activity.</description><creator>Shepherd, Robert R.</creator><contributor>Taguchi, Y. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Migration inhibition and homograft rejection in the rat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65vb727.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827f77z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j852x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The toxicity of high concentrations of bilirubin in the plasma has previously been demonstrated in vitro and in vivo. There are no methods presently available for removing bilirubin from plasma or other albumin containing solution. Techniques used to remove other toxic substances from the plasma of patients have had limited success in the removal of bilirubin. This lack of success is probably in large part due to the high degree of binding of bilirubin to albumin. The experiments described in this thesis were designed to test the bilirubin binding characteristics of several agents and to study the feasibility of using binding agents in extracorporeal hemoperfusion as a means of removing bilirubin.</description><creator>Saleh, Alfred</creator><contributor>Ruedy, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Pharmacology and Therapeutics.</subject><title>The effect of binding agents on the removal of bilirubin</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623g63h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j852x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g316c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The influence of starvation ketosis and ketone body infusions on renal ammoniogenesis was studied in man and dog. The stimulated ammonia production observed in fasting humans contrasted with the depressed ammoniogenesis reported in starving dogs. This discrepancy could not be ascribed to differences in hepatic ketogenesis between the two species but can perhaps be related to a better utilization of ketones by canine peripheral tissues. Owing to the complex metabolic adaptations that occur during starvation, the influence of ketones on renal ammoniogenesis could not be determined. However, the rate of ammonia excretion was depressed in both men and dogs infused with ketones. In dogs, ketones actually depressed renal ammoniogenesis without altering the systemic acid-base equilibrium. This effect was associated with a marked reduction of renal glutamine extraction. The possibility that ketones may influence renal ammoniogenesis through a direct metabolic effect within the kidney has been raised.</description><creator>Robitaille, Pierre</creator><contributor>Lemieux, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>The effect of ketone bodies on the renal metabolism of ammonia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sg72m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g316c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n009w544g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In autotransplanting the whole small intestine, one of the problems has been the difficulty of getting long term survivors consistently. Aside from the delicate mesenteric artery and vein anastomosis, the susceptibility of the organ to ischemia is quickly translated into irreversible mucosal damage. The objective of this project is to study a number of technical variations during small intestine autotransplantation and their effect on the intestinal mucosa during the operation and the immediate post-operative period. Over seventy small bowel autotransplantations were done on dogs and forty-four were included in the present study. Histologic and Biochemical studies were performed on tissue and blood of the animals pre-operatively, intraoperatively and in the immediate post-operative course. Various diets were used in the pre-operative feeding. A number of arterial perfusates and cooling temperatures were used after vascular severance of the organ. Intra-luminal perfusion of the bowel was also studied. The findings of this study will help develop an operative protocol for the study of longer term survivors in the auto or allo-transplantation model.</description><creator>Poulin, Eric</creator><contributor>Hinchey, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Autotransplantation of the small intestine</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fm26h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w544g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g158bm467</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A method has been described by which the total population of regenerating cutaneous nerves can be studied, and has been sequentially applied to free skin grafts in the rabbit. It has been shown that both myelinated and unmyelinated fibers regain their normal caliber quite early. However, a regenerating fiber population imbalance was found throughout the study. This was demonstrated by an increased number of nerve bundles, an increase in the number of unmyelinated fibers, a decrease in the number of myelinated fibers, and an absence of end corpuscles in the grafts. It is concluded that nerves enter the graft very shortly after their placement, and distribute in a random and imbalanced fashion. A fiber population distortion may also exist in man after skin grafting or nerve in jury, and effect diminished and distorted sensory function.</description><creator>Orgel, Michael G.</creator><contributor>Williams, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Nerve regeneration in free skin transplants</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505357n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bm467</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c3673</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>By the term coccidiosis we imply an infection with one or more of the several species belonging to the order Coccidia, a subdivision of the class Sporozoa whose members are parasitic forms reproducing typically by schizogony and which give rise to sporozoites enclosed in a resistant oocyst after syngamy has occurred. The seven species of coccidia occurring in the domestic chicken are all members of the genus Eimeria, a genus characterized by the formation of four sporoblasts within the oocyst and by the ultimate development of two sporozoites within each sporoblast in the infective stage. While the oocysts of each species differ in respect to shape, size and sporulation time it is most difficult, as pointed out by Becker (1934), to distinguish the species on the basis of oocyst characteristics alone. One should also take into consideration the location of the parasite in the intestine, the position of the parasite in the intestinal mucosa, the prepatent period and the macroscopic lesions. The problem of identifying species is further complicated by the possibility, of the occurrence of multiple species in a single host species. [...] Various experiments have, therefore, been conducted with the hope that the results obtained will contribute towards the solution of this controversial problem regarding the pathogenicity of Eimeria acervulina. </description><creator>Moynihan, Irwin William.</creator><contributor>Cameron, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Parasitology.</subject><title>The role of the protozoan parasite Eimeria Acervulina in disease of the domestic chicken.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207ts24b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c3673</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43p135p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The mixed leucocyte reaction and the delayed hypersensitivity antigens histoplasmin and tuberculin purified protein derivative were used in combinations to test the clonal selection theory in vitro. When histoplasmin was added to mixed leucocyte cultures containing sensitized cells from one donor, there was always an additive blastogenic effect. Experiments using different proportions of histoplasmin positive and negative cells in mixed cultures indicated that the response to histoplasmin was a specific one, and depended on the number of sensitized cells present in the cultures. Preincubating positive or negative donor cells with histoplasmin prior to setting up mixed cultures led to the same conclusion. On addition of both histoplasmin and tuberculin to unmixed and mixed leucocyte cultures containing sensitized cells, it was demonstrated that, under appropriate conditions, summation occurred. This summation, on multiple antigenic stimuli, supports a clonal proliferation mechanism in in vitro lymphocyte cultures.</description><creator>Odamtten, Solomon E.</creator><contributor>Bain, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Pathology.</subject><title>In vitro stimulation of lymphocytes by combinations of antigens and allogeneic cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gw820.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p135p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wm117s09t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the 1946 field season, three prospecting parties engaged by Mistassini Explorations Ltd. worked in, and northeast of, the Lake Mistassini region. The purpose was to investigate reports of lead, zinc, silver, and iron occurrences, and to outline the geology of the region as a basis for future prospecting. In addition, it was hoped that the contact of the Mistassini sediments and the Grenville gneisses to the east could be traced. The writer was in charge of No. 1 field party, which spent the season in the Lake Albanel area. Two other parties prospected the Takwa River country to the north, the headwaters of the Eastmain river, and the Otish Mountains, 120 miles northeast of Lake Mistassini.</description><creator>Neilson, J. M. (James M.)</creator><contributor>Gill, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>Stratigraphy and structure of the Mistassini series in the Lake Albanel area.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nm319.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117s09t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945v076</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bone marrow lymphoid cells ranged in nuclear diameter from 5.0 to 15.0 microns in smears. Smaller cells were predominantly pale; larger ones predominantly basophilic. Nearly all cells in DNA synthesis (determined by isotope uptake) were greater than or equal to 8.0 microns.</description><creator>Miller, Sandra C.</creator><contributor>Osmond, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Anatomy.</subject><title>Radioautographic studies of the proliferation of bone marrow lymphoid cells in the guinea pig</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x231m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945v076</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418r39x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ten centimeter radar echoes from rain and snow are discussed quantitatively from a theoretical and experimental point of view. Measurements of the power back-scattered by rain and snow are correlated with precipitation measurements made at the ground. The theory of ten centimeter radar echoes from rain has been checked by experiment. Radar echoes from continuous precipitation are analysed in height in a quantitative manner. The distribution of precipitation with height in non-convective meteorological situations is estimated from radar measurements.</description><creator>Palmer, Walter M.</creator><contributor>Marshall, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>Radar echoes from continuous precipitation.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580q81k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418r39x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q735z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Renal allografts were performed in dogs presensitized by 3-5 exchange skin grafts. Dogs were grouped in pairs, control and treated with sulfinpyrazone (125 mg/kg b.w.), a platelat release inhibitor. Urine flow for the control group was 7.5 hours and for the treated group was 33.1 hours. SeriaI determinations of renal artery and vein platelet and WBC counts showed little change from control in the treated group. However, in the control group there was a considerable fall in renal vein platelet counts at the time of anuria. No significant differences in WBC counts could be found in either group. Light microscopy showed platelet and fibrin plugging in peritubular and glomerular capillaries in control group, but little or none in treated group. Electron microscopy and tissue immunofluorescent staining confirmed these findings. It appears that sulfinpyrazone prevents the vascular lesion of hyperacute rejection in canine renal allografts.</description><creator>Merrick, Hollis W.</creator><contributor>MacLean, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>The role of platelets in hyperacute canine renal allograft rejection</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m9973.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q735z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72pb42v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>[...] Within recent times soil chemists (8, 26) have shown that different soils vary in their fixing capacity for phosphorus, and measurements of the fixing power of soils have been based on the solubilities of the phosphorus compounds in dilute acid solutions. It will be shown, however, in this paper that certain acid extractants have failed to give a true picture of the phosphorus-supplying ability of the acid clay soils of British Guiana, and that the estimation of exchangeable phosphorus of soils will undoubtedly reveal some of the misconceptions of phosphorus fixation. A clear conception of the mechanism of phosphorus fixation in acid soils, of the factors governing fixation, and of the distribution of the various forms in which phosphorus tends to accumulate and remain in acid soils, is required for a more economic utilisation of phosphatic fertilisers. This investigation has had a twofold objective; firstly to understand and elucidate what happens to the phosphorus when soils are flooded with water and with sugar solution, and secondly to study the factors inter-related with phosphorus response in the Blairmont clay soils. [...]</description><creator>Paul, Harry, 1914-</creator><contributor>DeLong, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>Investigation of the effects of flooding on the phosphorus status of soils.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jr95p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72pb42v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hg24j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis concerns studies of arterio-arterial counterpulsation, a mechanical method advocated for support of failing circulation in cardiogenic shock. Its experimental rationale is reviewed and the results of experiments, designed to determine its safety and effectiveness for prolonged application (4 hours), are presented. The findings in normal dogs demonstrated that counterpulsation was well tolerated. It maintained normal cardiac output, arterial pressure and peripheral circulation for three hours with slight deterioration in the final hour. These parameters correlated with a normal arterial lactate concentration during the first three hours. Plasma hemoglobin and blood gases did not change significantly.</description><creator>Merino, Francisco</creator><contributor>Rosensweig, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>Effects of Prolonged Counterpulsation of Peripheral Circulation in the Normal Dog and in Cardiogenic Shock</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956k02v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hg24j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x444t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Antibodies to human growth hormone were detected in 13 patients on long term HGH therapy for (2-7 years) by using immunofluorescence methods. No immunofluorescence was observed in human pituitary acidophils, however, hog pituitary acidophils showed strong fluorescence in all the thirteen patients studied when undiluted sera were used. On diluting the sera 1 to 8 immunofluorescence was inhibited completely in 4 patients who showed no binding to iodinated PGH. Acidophils stained were both somatotrophs and carminophils. Complete inhibition of fluorescent staining was only observed when these sera were incubated with both PGH and PLR and then used for immunofluorescent staining.</description><creator>Marwaha, Raj K.</creator><contributor>McGarry, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Immunofluorescent studies in pituitaries</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r623j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x444t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:73666785p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Grading of flax fibre in Canada, and in all other flax-producing countries, is done by professional graders who judge the flax by appearance (cleanness, glossiness, length of fibre, colour), by handle or feel (weight, softness), and by strength (breaking a few strands of fibre in the hands). Because this method is based on human judgment, two graders may award different grades to samples of the same fibre. It was felt that if some scientific method for ascertaining grades could be obtained, it would be a valuable contribution. Hence, a series of chemical determinations was made on flax fibre of various grades produced by water and dew retting in an attempt to assess the quality of flax fibre by chemical analysis. Concurrently, use was made of the Pressley Cotton Fibre Strength Tester to determine whether or not this machine could be adapted to flax fibre and yarn to differentiate between grades by means of physical tests. An investigation was made also of various types of chemical retting procedures. Because of the speed with which flax straw can be retted by chemical solutions, an attempt was made to determine if fibre of quality equal to that obtained by water and dew retting could be produced thereby. The chemically retted fibre then was subjected to the physical and chemical tests used in the attempts to appraise flax produced by water and dew retting. [...]</description><creator>Siminovitch, Helen Elizabeth.</creator><contributor>McFarlane, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>The validity of physical and chemical tests for determining the quality of flax fibre produced in various types of retting.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q7367.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666785p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930c144p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An investigation was undertaken to determine the feasibility of using rabbit leukocytes in the capillary migration technique. A procedure employing gelatin sedimentation and sucrose density gradient centrifugation was developed for harvesting appropriate white cell populations. Significant inhibition of migration was obtained when the cells from animals immunized with killed mycobacteria were tested with particulate antigen. PPD failed to give similar results under the same conditions of experiment. Migration inhibition was also obtained with cells harvested from animals immunized with ovalbumin. No conclusive results, however, were obtained in attempts to induce in vitro reactivity towards keyhole limpet haemocyanin. In those animals immunized with killed mycobacteria in addition to a soluble antigen (ovalbumin and KLH) a suppression of the delayed dermal response to old tuberculin was noted. The tuberculin reactivity appeared, however, at a later date in the KLH-immunized animals.</description><creator>Malloy, William F.</creator><contributor>Matheson, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Microbiology and Immunology.</subject><title>Capillary migration studies with rabbit leukocytes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612r715.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c144p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s3374</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>γ-crystallin and albuminoid from the lens of the dogfish eye produce, on hydrolysis in 6N HCI, a substance which fluoresces at 445nm. This substance was separated from the rest of the acid hydrolysate by salt gradient elution on cellulose phosphate and desalting on Bio-Gel followed by salt gradient elution of DEAE-cellulose. The fluorescent substance is characterized by a complicated UV absorption spectrum with peaks at 273 and 360nm and a shoulder at 305nm, and an activation spectrum which corresponds to the absorption spectrum except for the relative peak heights which differ slightly. It is soluble in water, ethyl acetate and dichloroethane and fluoresces weakly in the latter two solvents. It is ninhydrin-negative and does not appear on alkaline hydrolysis of the source proteins. The structure of the compound was not determined.</description><creator>Louis, Diana J.</creator><contributor>Lerman, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>A fluorescent compound obtained from two of the lens proteins of the dogfish eye</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021j242.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s3374</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53k1188</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:32:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tetracycline has been shown to inhibit protein synthesis in rat intestinal rings in vitro four hours after intraperitoneal administration. An inhibitory effect on the uptake of L-Iysine. L-alanine and cycloleucine was evidenced only at twelve hours after drug administration. Kinetic studies over time and concentration indicated reduced influx and Vmax. The findings suggest that a transport protein(s) which turns over rapidly becomes reduced in amount and rate limiting.</description><creator>Ling, Victor</creator><contributor>Morin, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1971</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Studies on intestinal amino acid transport in the rat: effects of tetracycline and calcium – vitamin D deprivation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04ds68n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53k1188</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):10700</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>