<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:24:38Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33925" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6q182m946</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A harmonic drive is a compact, light-weight and high-ratio torque transmission device which has almost zero backlash. Its unique performance features has captured the attention of designers in many industrial applications, especially in robotics. Despite widespread industrial application of harmonic drives, the torque control of this system has not been fully addressed. In this thesis the robust torque control of harmonic drive system is examined in detail. In order to measure the transmitted torque of a harmonic drive and for the purpose of a torque feedback scheme, an intelligent built-in torque sensing technique is developed in this thesis. Specifically, strain-gauges are mounted directly on the flexspline and therefore no extra flexible element is introduced into the system. To have maximum sensing accuracy, four Rosette strain gauges are employed using an accurate positioning method. Kalman filter estimation is employed to cancel the torque ripples, oscillations observed on the measured torque and caused mainly by gear teeth meshing. A simple forth order harmonic oscillator proved sufficient to model these torque ripples. Moreover, the error model is extended to incorporate any misalignment torque. By on-line implementation of the Kalman filter, it is shown that this method affords a fast and accurate way to filter torque ripples and misalignment torque from torque measurements. Based on experimental and theoretical studies, a systematic way to capture and rationalize the dynamic behavior of the harmonic drive systems is developed next in this thesis. Simple and accurate models for compliance, hysteresis, and friction are proposed, and the model parameters are estimated using least-squares approximation for linear and nonlinear regression models. A statistical measure of variation is defined, by which the reliability of the estimated parameter for different operating condition, as well as the accuracy and integrity of the proposed model is quantified. By these means, it is shown that a linear stiffness model best captures the behavior of the system when combined with a good model for hysteresis. Moreover, the frictional losses of harmonic drive are modelled at both low and high velocities. The model performance is assessed by comparing simulations with the experimental results on two different harmonic drives. Finally, robust Hinfinity -based torque controllers are designed and implemented for harmonic drive systems under constrained- and free-motion applications. A nominal model for the system is obtained in each case from ensembles of experimental frequency response estimates of the system, while the deviation of the system from the model is encapsulated by a multiplicative uncertainty. Robust Hinfinity -based torque controllers are designed using this information, and the controllers are implemented on two different setups using the Kalman filtered torque as an integral part of the torque-feedback loop. Exceptional performance results are obtained from the tune and frequency response of the closed-loop system, especially for the constrained-motion system. The further improve the performance of the free-motion system, a model-based friction-compensation algorithm is implemented in addition to the robust torque control. It is shown that the friction-compensation shrinks the model uncertainty at low frequencies. Hence, the performance of the closed-loop system is for tracking signals with low-frequency content.</description><creator>Taghirad, Hamid D.</creator><contributor>Belanger, P. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Robust torque control of harmonic drive systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149r400.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182m946</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z316q324x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this classroom-based study, the effects of input enhancement on the acquisition of a linguistic feature known to be problematic to francophone children learning English. were investigated. The research questions were: (1) Can L2 learners benefit from typographically enhanced input in their acquisition of third person singular possessive determiners? (2) Is typographically enhanced input more effective than unenhanced input? (3) Is typographically enhanced input more effective when combined with a book flood? To investigate these questions, three treatment conditions were implemented with Grade 6 ESL learners. Groups E and E+ received a typographically enhanced input flood. This did not include explicit reference to the learners' L1 nor was a pedagogical rule presented at any time. In addition to the typographically enhanced input, Group E+ was exposed to extensive reading and listening activities. To ensure that all groups in the study were exposed to written input containing the target features, Group U read unenhanced versions of the texts read by the other two groups. A pretest, immediate and delayed posttest design was used in this quasi-experimental study. Results indicated that all three instructional treatments improved the learners' acquisition of the target forms and that those in Group E+ received the greatest apparent benefits. At the immediate posttest, learners in Group E+ outperformed those in the other two groups on written tasks designed to measure their ability to recognize correct instances of the target forms. Learners in Group E+ also outperformed the others on an oral production task. On the delayed posttest five weeks later, however, Groups E and U had caught up with Group E+, and most of the between-group differences had disappeared. The finding that all learners had significantly increased in their accuracy and development of possessive determiners immediately following instruction suggests that the target forms were equally salient to the learners in the three groups. That all learners continued to improve but did not reach advanced developmental stages, however, suggests that the salience of these features in the input may not have been sufficiently explicit. The results are discussed in terms of the potential need for more explicit instruction in the acquisition of third person singular possessive determiners. This may be particularly important because of substantial differences in the way in which gender is marked in English and French.</description><creator>White, Joanna.</creator><contributor>Spada, Nina (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Foreign speakers -- Aids and devices.</subject><title>An input enhancement study with ESL children : effects of the acquisition of possessive determiners</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x076j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q324x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Second Language Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149r397</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There is evidence that amyloid deposition within the brain is of major importance in the pathogenesis of Alzheimer's disease (AD), but the mechanism of this deposition is not known, and several theories are currently under great debate. The present study of intraneuronal changes in the human brain with age and disease suggests a new explanation for amyloid plaque formation in the pathogenesis of AD. This work indicates that intraneuronal inclusions originally observed by Rees (1975), may contain amyloid peptide (Abeta), the beta-pleated form of which is the major component of the amyloid plaques in AD. We have therefore called them amylosomes. Using the techniques of histology, immunohistochemistry, computerized morphology, as well as protein isolation and analysis, we examined the distribution, size, density and chemical composition of amylosomes in the human brain throughout life. Amylosomes appear during early childhood and remain constant in size and number until advanced old age. Their protein content and immunostaining characteristics indicate they contain Abeta, and their dendritic location in regions where AD plaques form suggested a possible role in Abeta transport from the brain to the CSF. We therefore isolated and quantified human brain microtubule proteins (MT) and the dendritic microtubule-associated protein 2 (MAP2), assessed their ability to polymerize in vitro, quantified the MAP2 mRNA with age, and related these results to the apolipoprotein E (APOE) genotype, which is known to modulate the risk of AD. There was an age-related decrease in MT proteins and MAP2 and in their ability to polymerize, that was accelerated in individuals with APOE epsilon4 allele(s), the group at greatest risk of AD. These results are consistent with the proposal that amylosomes play a role in Abeta metabolism, and an age-related decrease in the dendritic MT transport system could lead to retention of amylosomes, within the brain, with deposition of the Abeta and plaque formation as a consequence. This theory can account for most of the important features of AD, and resolves a number of contradictory hypotheses, as well as suggesting relevant area for further investigation. A better understanding of the pathogenesis will hopefully reveal strategies for prevention and treatment of this common and presently incurable disease.</description><creator>Xu, Chun.</creator><contributor>Zorychta, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Richardson, John B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Human Development.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Amylosomes and microtubules in the human brain : relationship to aging and the pathogenesis of Alzheimer's disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z9511.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149r397</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278v942</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation considers the evolution of Rap music and Hip Hop culture from the perspective of two spatial modalities. It first introduces theoretical concepts of geographic scale and the inscription of socio-spatial values in order to examine Rap and Hip Hop's geo-cultural expansions from their primary enclaves of urban black America. The dynamics between race, social space, and youth are assessed both individually and in tandem as crucial elements in the expression and practices of Hip Hop. The dissertation challenges and extends research in the prevailing Rap "canon" by analysing the processes and structuring logics through which Rap has been integrated into the commercial system of localized music scenes and transnational music and media industries. It identifies the myriad forces that have either facilitated or constrained Rap's expansion at various moments in its history. The dissertation also focuses on the emergence of a pronounced spatial discourse in Rap music and Hip Hop. It isolates the articulation of spatial issues and an increasingly urgent emphasis on sites of significance and the homeplace of "the 'hood" as a significant but characteristic element of the genre. The ancillary Hip Hop media, including radio, music videos, Rap press, and the cinematic "'Hood" genre, are examined as important factors in the reproduction of spatial sensibilities in Hip Hop culture.</description><creator>Forman, Murray W.</creator><contributor>Szanto, George (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Rap (Music) -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Hip-hop -- United States.</subject><title>"The ‘hood comes first" : race, space and place in Rap music and Hip Hop, 1978-1996</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79407z938.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278v942</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j96022554</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study identified gender-related differences in post-exercise peripheral blood flow and body temperature in neutral environment (21ºC). The subjects were 11 male (22 +/- 4 years) and 14 pre-ovulatory female (23 +/- 3 years) recreational runners VO2max: 62 +/- 5 mL/kg • min for men and 55 +/- 5 mL/kg • min for women). Forearm blood flow rectal (Trec) and forearm skin temperatures (Tsk), and forearm vascular resistance (mean arterial pressure/forearm blood flow) were measured pre-exercise (pre), immediately after (t = 0), and every 15 minutes up to 105 minutes (t = 105) post-exercise (45-minute run at 75% of VO2max). ANOVA revealed main gender effects for Trec, Tsk, and forearm blood flow (men &gt; women) as well as for forearm vascular resistance (women &gt; men). Compared to pre-exercise, Trec at t = 0 showed a similar increase in men (1.3ºC) and women (1.2ºC). Trec decreased thereafter to reach pre-exercise level after 25 minutes in men. In women, Trec kept decreasing to reach a lower than pre-exercise level after 60 minutes (p &lt; 0.05). Tsk was similar at pre and t = 0 for both genders. In contrast, Tsk was lower in women than men (29.0 +/- 1.3 versus 30.7 +/- 1.5ºC) at t = 105 (p &lt; 0.05). Forearm vascular resistance was similar in men and women pre-exercise and decreased by about 50% in both groups at t = 0. Between t = 30 and t = 105, the women increased their forearm vascular resistance up to 35% more than did the men. These observations suggest the existence of gender-related differences in thermoregulatory and cutaneous blood flow responses during recovery from submaximal exercise.</description><creator>Marchand, Ingrid.</creator><contributor>Montgomery, David (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Perrault, Helene (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Exercise -- Physiological aspects -- Sex differences.</subject><subject>Body temperature -- Sex differences.</subject><subject>Blood flow -- Sex differences.</subject><title>Gender differences in post-exercise peripheral blood flow and skin temperature</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j2889.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j96022554</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:th83m111x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study explored general and special education teacher satisfaction with special education teacher roles in collaborative teams, whose objective was to include children with disabilities, and the evolutionary stage of the teams according to the integrated model of group development. Thirteen out of 21 targeted teams qualified for the sample. The Special Education Teacher-General Education Teacher Interaction Scale assessed general and special education teachers' perceptions of special education teachers' current and ideal roles (Cronbach's alpha internal reliability coefficients were .85 and .81). The Team Evolution Questionnaire measured the collaborative teams' developmental stage (Cronbach's alpha was .82). General education teachers were more satisfied with special education teachers' roles than the special education teachers were with themselves (p &lt; .01). General education teachers had higher perceptions about how frequently special education teachers performed their roles than special education teachers themselves (p &lt; .05). Qualitatively, both groups endorsed several collaborative roles as currently performed most frequently by the special education teachers. Compared to previous literature, these results indicate a shift of priority from noncollaborative to collaborative special education teacher roles. Since all 13 teams were categorized in the most highly evolved stage of group development, a direct comparison between teacher satisfaction and the group's stage of evolution was not possible. Implications of these findings are discussed.</description><creator>Litvack, Marla S.</creator><contributor>Karagiannis, Anastassius (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Special education teachers.</subject><subject>Teaching teams.</subject><title>Perceptions of the special education teacher's role in collaborative teams : an evolutionary perspective</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tr023.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m111x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967534b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The colloidal properties of AS diblock copolymers, and the dynamic mechanical properties of ABA triblock copolymers of polystyrene (B) and poly(methacrylic add) or poly(sodium, methacrylate) (A) were investigated. In solvents which are selectively good for the B block, the diblock copolymers form very stable micellelike aggregates which were characterized by size-exclusion chromatography, dynamic light scattering, and viscometry. This micellar system showed no apparent dissociation-associafion equilibrium within the time scale of a few days. The hydrodynamic radii of the micelles increased with the length of both the A and B blocks. The aggregation numbers were determined primarily by the length of the A block and increased with it. For the triblock copolymers, the dynamic mechanical analyses showed the presence of two glass transition temperatures (Tg) associated with microdomains of A and of B. For the neutralised materials, the Tg of the A microdomains increased with the length of the A block. The height of the rubbery plateau located between the T g's increased with the length of the A block.</description><creator>Desjardins, Alain</creator><contributor>Eisenberg, Adi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1991</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>The colloidal and dynamic mechanical properties of styrenemethacrylate based block ionomers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q7990.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967534b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892c57q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cognitive, motivational, and emotional contributors to depressive affect were investigated in dependent and self-critical college students. In the first study, Dependency and Self-Criticism were related to anaclitic and introjective dysfunctional cognitions which explained part of the variance in perceived stress for events involving loss and failure respectively. In the second study, the personality styles were related to different motive dispositions including achievement, affiliation and intimacy. Dependency and Self-Criticism were also related to motivational characteristics which were significant predictors of positive and negative affect. In the third study, Dependency was linked to the occurrence of romantic relationship stressors and Self-Criticism to academic stressors. Both personality styles were related to greater ambivalence over emotional expression, which significantly predicted depression. The variables from the cognitive, motivational, and emotional domains, and stress, were combined in an integrative vulnerability model for depression.</description><creator>Mongrain, Myriam</creator><contributor>Zuroff, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1991</date><subject>Depression, Mental</subject><title>Origins of depressed affect in dependent and self-critical individuals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rw19b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892c57q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429b971</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to describe the physical fitness of middle-aged adults with an intellectual disability and how their state of fitness has changed over time. Thirty-two adults with an intellectual disability served as participants: 14 were female and 18 were male. Participants had an age range from 34 to 57 years. All worked at a readaptation center in Montreal and were participants in a study of physical fitness in 1983. Using the "Canadian Standardized Test of Fitness", the participants were evaluated on tests of Cardiovascular Endurance, Muscular Strength, Muscular Endurance, Flexibility, and Body Composition. All participants were deemed physically capable of performing all the tests after a screening procedure was used. A home visit, previous to the testing session, familiarized the participants with the procedures for each test. The battery of tests took one hour per participant. Three levels of analysis were used to describe the change in physical fitness with age: First, the conversion of raw scores into percentiles highlighted individual differences within the group. Second, to assess the change in fitness over time, a 2 x 2 (group x time) repeated measures design was used. Third, effect sizes were calculated to measure the magnitude of change in fitness over the 13 year period as compared to the general population. Results indicate that, when compared to the general population, the participants had lower levels of fitness and that their fitness had changed significantly over time. Most interesting were results showing that the participants had a significantly greater magnitude of change in VO2max and percent body fat than what is expected in the general population. The findings of this study raise concerns regarding the potential health risks associated with aging and poor fitness for adults with an intellectual disability.</description><creator>Graham, Andrew J., 1964-</creator><contributor>Reid, Greg (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>People with mental disabilities.</subject><subject>Middle aged persons -- Health and hygiene.</subject><subject>Physical fitness.</subject><title>Physical fitness of adults with an intellectual disability : a 13 year follow-up study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj4306483.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429b971</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v7183</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this research was to describe and critically interpret girls' experiences with respect to body image, physical activity and health. The qualitative inquiry included focus group and individual interviews, document analysis and field observations. These methods were used to explore the perceptions of sixty-three girls (grades eight and eleven) and staff from an inner-city high school. Through interpretive data analysis (and constant comparison), the inter-related themes of body image, physical activity and health branched into the sub-themes of societal influences and personal attitudes including: friends, boys, family, school and media. Girls' body images ranged from minor preoccupations to major dissatisfaction with their bodies, while a few girls were happy being themselves. Weak or negative family influences gave way to influences by media, boys and friends. A few girls were very active, whereas others' low levels of participation were attributed to: disinterest in physical activity, intimidation by boys, or perceived lack of opportunity. The girls' perceptions of health incorporated fitness, weight, and eating habits. Girls often used negative qualifiers when describing their weight or body shape. Generally, girls perceived overweight individuals as not taking care of themselves. This research supports the development of gender sensitive physical education programs promoting healthier lifestyles for females.</description><creator>Galloti, Lorraine.</creator><contributor>Dyson, Ben P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Teenage girls -- Health and hygiene.</subject><subject>Self-perception in adolescence.</subject><subject>Physical education for women.</subject><subject>Health behavior in adolescence.</subject><subject>Body image.</subject><subject>Physical fitness.</subject><subject>Teenage girls -- Attitudes.</subject><title>Beyond theory : adolescent girls' perceptions of body image, physical activity and health</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644t29g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v7183</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999842j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The number of women infected with the HIV virus through heterosexual contact is on the rise and expected to increase steadily throughout the 1990's. In order to prevent the further spread of HIV infection and AIDS, behavior change is essential. The focus of this study is on the sexual behaviors, safe sex practices, and the role that self-efficacy and self-assertiveness play in a woman's ability to put into effect preventative behaviors. The study sample consists of 40 heterosexual, English-speaking women from the Montreal area. The results indicate that just under half of this population are using condoms as a safe sex precaution, but they are being used inconsistently. Those participants who reported sometimes using condoms were also the same participants who more frequently reported modifying other aspects of their sexual behavior in order to reduce their risk of infection, as compared to those participants who did not report using condoms. It was also found that the participants' past sexual history, knowledge about HIV transmission, and awareness of risky sexual practices do not predict more cautious sexual behavior. One major factor which did seem to influence modification of risky sexual behaviors was the participants' perception of being at risk for HIV. The majority of the participants did not have difficulty in asserting their desire for safe sex. Their methods, however, in how they would choose to practise safe sex were dependent on the seriousness of the relationship, ability to trust their partner, and their current method of practising safe sex in their own sexual lives.</description><creator>Kornhauzer, C. Monika (Cvetka Monika)</creator><contributor>Talley, William (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Risk-taking (Psychology)</subject><subject>Safe sex in AIDS prevention</subject><title>Sexual risk taking behaviors of women at risk for HIV</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k6833.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999842j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k3569616t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines the concept of art education known as Discipline-based art education, (DBAE), from three vantage points. It begins by tracing the history and development of DBAE theory, and by examining its defining characteristics. It follows with a critical discussion of DBAE theory, specifically from within the context of multicultural education. The discussion then shifts to the realm of practice. The study describes a two week professional development program offered by the Minnesota DBAE Consortium, in Minneapolis, in the summer of 1995, and grounds the discussion in the results of questionnaires and interviews with six secondary school art specialists attending the Summer Institute. Finally, the study examines some of the potential challenges of implementation based on the issues that emerged as the participants translated theory into practice, and focuses specifically on the aspect of the incorporation of the disciplines of art criticism and aesthetics in the classroom.</description><creator>Taran, Caroline.</creator><contributor>Wood, Elizabeth (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Art -- Study and teaching.</subject><title>Discipline-based art education : from theory to practice, challenges of implementation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78td88p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569616t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892c580</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The quality of the strip produced in a near-net-shape casting process is strongly linked to the metal feeding system. An alternative metal delivery system was proposed and a comprehensive mathematical model, including heat transfer, fluid flow and stress studies was used as a tool to perform this task. This model included three-dimensional flows with fully coupled momentum and heat transfer. Turbulence effects as deduced from the standard kappa- 3 equations, macroscopic solidification, as well as flow through porous media were also modeled. A further simple model for stress was employed to calculate the displacements and the stress distribution throughout the forming strip. Besides the mathematical model, an experimental apparatus was developed, reproducing as closely as possible the type of metal-substrate contact occurring in a single-belt caster. Casting of thin strips at high speeds was achieved and a parametric study was carried out. The standard extended nozzle configuration did not provide a smooth flow in the reservoir. Recirculation zones besides a nonuniform delivery of the metal to the belt were observed. Divergences in the solid fractions between the center and the edges of the strips were found to increase with increasing turbulence at the exit gap. The values of the morphology constant C and the overall heat transfer coefficient h were considered the most important inputs of the model. Furthermore, modelling turbulence through a kappa- 3 model proved to be critical for this particular configuration. The adoption of a flow modifier within the extended nozzle eliminated the recirculation zone in the reservoir and yielded a smoother flow to the belt. Such improvements in the flow distribution were decisive to ensure more uniform solidification along the width of the strip. In early solidification, the strip was found to displace inwardly, due to the cooling and contraction of the solid shell. Tensile stresses were calculated at the cooling surface, whereas compressive stresses were found in the middle of the strip. Interfacial heat fluxes and heat transfer coefficients measured on the strip casting simulator were highly dependent on the contact metal-substrate-coating. Values of q and h varied threefold for the various coatings and levels of roughness investigated. Correlations were derived to predict peak heat fluxes and the evolution of q after the peak, for the various coatings. A relationship was observed between the peak heat transfer coefficient and the total solidification time. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Quariguasi Netto, Pedro Gutemberg.</creator><contributor>Guthrie, Roderick I. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Mathematical and physical modelling of a single-belt casting process</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010r885.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892c580</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g732db69m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation focuses on slaves and peasants as self-consciousness actors in northwestern Sierra Leone between 1896 to 1956. During this period, which covers almost the entire duration of British colonial rule in the region, these subaltern groups used covert and violent actions to protest the various demands---labour, tribute and taxation---of the state and the local elite. Covert actions like evasions, escapes and migrations became interwoven into the fabric of colonial rule. Violent actions, which tended to be spasmodic, erupted when social and economic conditions deteriorated sharply. Four major rebellions occurred during colonial rule in region. The first, spearheaded by local rulers, took place within the general context of African resistance to colonialism in 1898. After the rulers were coopted by the colonial state the burden of resistance fell on peasants and slaves. In 1919, after enduring excruciating war-time experiences, peasants, petty-traders, slaves and the urban unemployed rioted against Syrian traders who they believed hoarded and profited from rice. The rural destitution created by the Great Depression and a major locust attack led many ex-slaves and peasants to join the millenarian movement of the itinerant muslim cleric, Idara Konthorfili in 1931. Ware called on his followers not to pay colonial tax and tried to mobilize them to fight against the state. In 1955 and 1956, peasants and other rural groups throughout northwestern Sierra Leone rebelled against high taxation and the despotism of their chiefs. In its timing and virulence the anti-chief rebellion of 1955 and 1956 represented a major paradox in African history. It had occurred during the moment of decolonization; a period when the colonial transfer of power to the new African elite was following formulaic and relatively peaceful lines. The state responded to subaltern protest with repression, paternalism and readjustments in existing social relations. By their actions, slaves and peasants forced the state and elite groups to acknowledge and respond to their concerns. The balance which emerged out of this process of resistance, repression and accommodation became the moral economy of colonialism in Sierra Leone.</description><creator>Rashid, Ismail O. D.</creator><contributor>Echenberg, Myron (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Peasantry -- Sierra Leone.</subject><subject>Sierra Leone -- History.</subject><subject>Sierra Leone -- Politics and government -- 1896-1961.</subject><title>Patterns of rural protest : chiefs, slaves and peasants in northwestern Sierra Leone, 1896-1956</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zq272.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732db69m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr171z94k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Synapse formation involves multiple coordinated events between the presynaptic and the postsynaptic nerve that ultimately results in the expression of the appropriate neurotransmitters at the presynaptic nerve terminal and the matching neurotransmitter receptors on the opposing postsynaptic membrane. For my thesis research, I investigate different aspects of neurotransmitter receptor gene expression, an early step in the process of synaptogenesis. Specifically, I focus on two different neurotransmitter-gated ion channels that are expressed on neonatal rat peripheral neurons: the serotonin 5-HT3 receptor (5-HT3R) and the neuronal nicotinic acetylcholine receptor (nAChR). The 5-HT3R is expressed on both nodose sensory neurons and sympathetic neurons. However, little is known about 5-HT3R expression during neonatal development or about the factors that regulate its expression. To investigate 5-HT3R gene expression, first I examined 5-HT 3R mRNA levels in nodose and sympathetic neurons as they develop in vivo and in culture. My results show that 5-HT 3R gene expression is differentially regulated in these two populations of neurons. In addition, I demonstrate that 5-HT3R gene expression in nodose neurons depends on target innervation and can be modulated by neurotrophins. Neonatal sympathetic neurons express five different neuronal nAChR subunit genes. One unresolved issue is the contribution of these five subunits to nAChR function. To investigate this issue, I altered the expression of one nAChR subunit gene, alpha3, using transient transfection procedures. To do this, first I modified and optimized gene transfer procedures for sympathetic neurons, based on recombinant adenovirus vectors. sing this approach, I overexpressed sense and antisense alpha3 mRNA and investigated how the changes in alpha3 subunit expression affect ACh-evoked currents on cultured sympathetic neurons. I show that changes in alpha3 mRNA levels alter the magnitude of ACh-evoked current densities. My results indicate that alpha3 gene expression is rate-limiting for the assembly and insertion of nAChRs on sympathetic neurons. Together, my results show that multiple mechanisms influence the expression neurotransmitter-gated ion channel genes on peripheral neurons.</description><creator>Rosenberg, Madelaine.</creator><contributor>Cooper, Ellis (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Factors that influence the expression of neurotransmitter-gated ion channels on developing peripheral neurons</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57ns64b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr171z94k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77ft10q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis argues that the interface between human and machine has been an important system of metaphors since the beginning of the twentieth century in North American science fiction (SF) and nonfictional writings. In examining these texts, this study intends to discuss positions and responses regarding technological developments and the social and political experiences underlying it In my parallel analyses of fictional (SF) and nonfictional (philosophical, scientific, theoretical) texts. I wish to signal similarities and differences among the two fields. In different ways, the treatments of cyborgs and cyberspace in both nonfiction and SF have addressed, through these metaphors, notions of mass culture, democracy, as well as individual and collective agency and subjectivity. I also argue that these critical strategies are best understood as the strategies of two social groups---one, of them in a dominant position (that of a professional, mainly technocratic class) and one in an ambivalently marginal position (that of the readers of a mass genre such as SF). In nonfictional writings, the strategy is as a rule one of either uncritical embrace of the present state of affairs, or a specular one of utter rejection, with the only exceptions emerging from contemporary feminism. In SF, attitudes of both consensus and problematization emerge. Thus, my study also calls for a qualification of claims about "postmodernity" as the privileged period in which technology acquires center stage. My first two chapters foreground some theoretical concepts and issues related to both the study of mass culture and of the SF genre. The next three chapters focus on specific texts about the instrumental body and of the virtual frontier, and on the critical responses (by women, and by dissenting male figures) to them. The conclusion stresses the notions of democracy allegorically presented in these texts.</description><creator>Proietti, Salvatore.</creator><date>1998</date><subject>Science fiction -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Cybernetics in literature.</subject><subject>Cybernetics -- Social aspects.</subject><subject>Science fiction, American -- History and criticism.</subject><title>The cyborg, cyberspace, and North American science fiction /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311r08t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77ft10q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3484zj503</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The extracellular matrix (ECM) plays an important role in mammary gland development and function. Osteopontin (OPN), a secreted glycophosphoprotein, with several functional and structural properties of ECM proteins, is expressed at elevated levels during normal and pathologic development of the mammary gland and is present in milk. However, whether it plays any developmental role in the mammary gland is unknown. To investigate this possibility, transgenic AS-OPN mice were generated using a transgene expressing OPN antisense RNA under the control of the MMTV-LTR promoter/enhancer. The mammary glands of AS-OPN mice express low levels of OPN, compared to control littermates, show excessive branching of the ductal epithelium at the virgin stage, impaired proliferation of the mammary epithelium, and abnormal alveolar structure formation during pregnancy, and mild to severe lactation deficiency. To further examine the role of OPN at the cellular level, an established murine mammary epithelial cell line (NMuMG), which is capable of differentiation in culture, was transfected with the same DNA construct used to generate AS-OPN mice. Several antisense OPN cDNA transfected clones, which secrete decreased amounts of OPN compared to mock-transfected cells were obtained. These cells were found to have lost their ability to form branched duct-like structures, as judged by branching morphogenesis assays, by growth in collagen gels and stimulation with hepatocyte growth factor. They also failed to spread on type I collagen, although their binding to type IV collagen was unaffected. The antisense transfectants also assumed a mesenchymal phenotype, characterized by fibroblast-like morphology, an apparent loss of cell-cell contacts and spontaneous cell scattering. Transmigration assays and wounding experiments indicated that these cells also have a higher migratory activity than control cells. Northern blot and immunofluorescence analyses showed that migrating cells downregulate OP</description><creator>Nemir, Mohamed.</creator><contributor>Mukherjee, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Phosphoproteins -- Physiological effect.</subject><subject>Mammary glands -- Growth.</subject><title>Inhibition of osteopontin expression in mammary epithelial cells alters mammary gland morphogenesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053h82n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zj503</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6q182m96r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>My dissertation concentrates on Americans writing at home and abroad in the inter-war period and contextualizes their expatriation with reference to debates between modernist critics over the nature and substance of the American literary tradition. I clarify the definitions of terms like "exile," "emigrant," and "expatriate" central to my analysis but muddied by years of misuse. I do so with reference to coercion, a concept which I develop in accordance with recent work in the philosophy of action. At the same time I make the case for a realist, causalist hermeneutics. Next I explore the aesthetic corollary to my argument with reference to the fiction, autobiography, and literary criticism of Gertrude Stein. I argue that Stein's decision to leave America must be viewed as uncoerced, and as therefore indicative of her emigration to France. Viewed as an emigrant, and not as an exile or expatriate, Stein can be shown to manifest tendencies in her work (towards subjectivity, abstraction, and retrospection) which reflect her dissociation from, rather than ongoing connection to, America. Lastly, I look closely at the work of Van Wyck Brooks and Harold Stearns, two modernist literary and culture critics whose writings on expatriation demonstrably influenced generations of subsequent biographers and intellectual historians. Steams and Brooks can be counted among the most articulate and vociferous proponents of literary change in America, and can be situated at the poles of a vigorous debate within the literary community of their day over whether American letters were better served from within or without the United States. I contrast Brooks' civic humanism with Steams' rugged individualism and identify in the debate over expatriation a powerful analogue to ongoing debates in literary and cultural critical circles referred to as "the culture wars."</description><creator>Muller, Adam Patrick Dooley.</creator><contributor>Livingston, Paisley (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Exiles' writings.</subject><subject>Emigration and immigration in literature.</subject><subject>American literature -- 20th century -- History and criticism.</subject><title>The importance of being elsewhere : modernist expatriation and the American literary tradition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xd433.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182m96r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pr76f527f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Batch soil washing experiments were used to evaluate the feasibility of using biosurfactants for the removal of heavy metals from a contaminated soil and sediments. Surfactin from Bacillus subtilis, rhamnolipids from Pseudomonas aeruginosa and sophorolipid from Torulopsis bombicola were evaluated using a soil contaminated with hydrocarbon and metals (890 mg/kg zinc, 420 mg/kg copper, 12.6% oil and grease) and metal contaminated sediments (110 mg/kg copper, 3300 mg/kg zinc). Although water alone removed insignificant levels of metals, results showed that the biosurfactants could remove 5% of the zinc (with 12% rhamnolipid) and 19.5% of the zinc (with 4% sophorolipid with 0.7% HCl). Copper could also be removed and was most efficiently extracted (greater than 25%) with 12% rhamnolipid or with 2% rhamnolipid with 1% NaOH. 1% NaOH alone removed only 5% of the copper and 2% zinc. After a series of five batch washes, 90% of the copper could be removed by 0.1% surfactin with 1% NaOH while 4% sophorolipid with 0.7% HCl was able to remove 100% of the zinc. From the sediment, a single washing with 0.5% rhamnolipid removed 65% of the copper and 18% of the zinc whereas 4% sophorolipid removed 25% of the copper and 60% of the zinc. Sequential extraction procedures were used on the soil and sediments. For both matrices, the carbonate and the oxide fractions accounted for over 90% of the zinc present in the soil. The organic fraction constituted over 70% of the copper in the soil and sediments. Sequential extraction of the soil and sediments after washing with the various surfactants indicated that the biosurfactants, rhamnolipid or surfactin with NaOH, could remove the organically-bound copper and that the sophorolipid with acid could remove the carbonate and oxide bound zinc and cadmium. Concerning the mechanism for metal removal by the surfactants, the techniques of octanol-water partitioning, ultrafiltration and zeta potential measurements indicated that the surfactants removed the metals first by sorption at the soil interphase, followed by desorption of the metal through interfacial tension lowering and fluid forces and then solubilization of the metal within the micelle.</description><creator>Mulligan, Catherine.</creator><contributor>Yong, Raymond (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>On the capability of biosurfactants for the removal of heavy metals from soil and sediments</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9593tw88n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f527f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn9998443</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation examines the theoretical aspects of communication and coexistence among different and sometimes competing national cultures in contemporary liberal-democratic states. As its primary example, the study focuses on the quest for self-determination of Canada's indigenous peoples, but the theoretical significance of the project extends well beyond the bounds of this particular case. With this end in mind, the dissertation advances and defends a set of normative political principles which could, with certain necessary modifications, serve to guide just, equitable, and stable relations among different national cultures in a broad range of cases and contexts. The discussion opens with the development of a model of cross-cultural understanding and accommodation, which in turn is used to demonstrate the manner in which the theory and practice of liberal democracy often serves to legitimate the assertion of the authority of particular national cultures over their relatively smaller and weaker rivals. In opposition to this more conventional liberal approach, the dissertation proposes a reformulation of the theoretical and institutional bases of liberal conceptions of national sovereignty and self-determination. This alternative approach bypasses any attempt to identify authentic or foundational liberal values which must frame and govern the principle of national self-determination, and which assert their categorical primacy over competing normative ideals and traditions. This approach to self-determination balances, on the one hand, the importance of more localized national ends, ideals, and institutions with a concern, on the other, for universal standards of democratic conduct, responsibility, and governance. What results is not a grand theory of national self-determination, but rather a set of flexible principles which can be attuned to different cultural contexts and circumstances, and which are subject to the democratic consent of the nations or peoples concerned.</description><creator>Murphy, Michael Andrew, 1964-</creator><contributor>Tully, James (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Sovereignty.</subject><subject>Cultural pluralism.</subject><subject>Self-determination, National.</subject><title>Nation, culture, and authority : multinational democracies and the politics of pluralism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579t98j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn9998443</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53jz95s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Several important aspects of ZnO/CdS/CuGaXIn1-X Se2 photovoltaic cells have been examined in this thesis. First of all, CuGaXIn1-XSe2 crystals free from ampoule adhesion and suitable for photovoltaic cell studies were grown using a horizontal Bridgman method. The composition variation for ingots with different starting Ga content was analyzed and the results were interpreted using established pseudobinary phase diagrams. Various optimizations in the cell fabrication, such as crystal polishing, window layer deposition and cell area patterning, were carried out to establish a highly reproducible cell fabrication process for routine studies. The effects of substrate annealing in Ar were investigated for cells with different Ga content. It is believed that Ar substrate annealing is beneficial to CuGaXIn1-XSe2 cells regardless of the Ga content. However, to optimize performance, the same cell fabrication conditions should not be applied to fabricate cells with different Ga content. From illuminated I-V measurements, conversion efficiencies exceeding 10% were achieved in two of the best cells. In particular, a CuGa0.45 In0.55Se2 cell attained a 10.1% efficiency which is the highest among single crystal Cu(Ga,In)Se2 cells with similar Ga content. To establish the energy band diagrams of ZnO/CdS/CuGaXIn 1-XSe2 cells, the band lineup model was examined by considering the variations of electron affinity and energy gap of the absorber. In addition, the built-in potential Vbi as a function of Ga content was calculated based on the relative shift in Fermi level. Then, the lattice mismatch in CuGaXIn1-XSe2 cells was also estimated. Following that, the dark current transport and photo-generated current collection mechanisms were analyzed. It was shown that the effect of shunting was greatly reduced for cells with Ar substrate annealing. Furthermore, the photo-generated current was found to follow a voltage dependent current collection mechanism which was independent of light intensity. Capacitance-voltage measurements were carried out on cells with and without Ar substrate annealing. There is evidence showing the co-existence of both interfacial and bulk states. A substrate annealing in Ar was found to improve the interface properties. Moreover, deep level characteristics of CuGa 0.3In0.7Se2 were analyzed using DLTS technique. Two hole trap levels (0.32 eV and 0.43 eV) and one electron trap level (0.51 eV) were deduced. It is believed that the observed hole trap levels were formed independent of preparation conditions.</description><creator>Lam, Wai Wing Malcolm.</creator><contributor>Shih, I. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Investigation of photovoltaic cells on Bridgman grown CuGaxIn1-xSe2 crystals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kj10h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53jz95s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207tr04n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Three different types of field emission diodes (FEDs)---Si field emitters, metal wedge emitters and Si emitters with an air bridge---have been fabricated. These FE diodes were studied to determine the emission uniformity and stability. Effects of diamond-like carbon (DLC) film on the emission characteristics were specifically studied. The coating of DLC films was carried out by laser ablation and rf sputtering. Significant reduction in turn-on voltage was observed for the first time in the Si microtips with a DLC film coated by laser ablation. Effects of substrate temperature on the quality of the DLC films were also observed. For the Si microtips with DLC films prepared by rf sputtering, the onset voltages of emission were higher. This was found to be due to the high resistivity and the crystalline-like structure of the films. Using the processes developed, arrays of Si microtips were fabricated and tested for emission stability and uniformity. A structure with a built-in pn junction for each tip was adopted to fabricate FE diodes. The measurement results from these FE diodes showed more stable emission than those without the built-in junctions. In the FEDs with pn junctions, the emission current was limited by the reverse junction characteristics. In order to minimize the effect of junction breakdown on the current regulating mechanism, a novel field emission device with a p-i-n junction for current regulation was proposed and implemented. An extremely stable and uniform emission was obtained from these FEDs with p-i-n junctions due to the large breakdown voltages. In addition to the above experimental research, an electric field computation program based on charge density method was developed. The electron emission of FEDs with different tip size, half angle and gate planar levels was simulated. The results showed that the electric field at a given voltage increases when the tip size and half angle are decreased. Moreover, a slightly recessed emitter yields a larger field than the one with a coplanar configuration. In the final part of the thesis, a novel FE triode structure and the required fabrication procedure were proposed. This was done in order to manufacture an operational FE triode without the need of advanced lithography tools, and to overcome the obstacles encountered during the first triode study. FE triodes with submicrometer emitter/gate spacing were successfully fabricated with the procedure developed. In this novel triode, high quality thermal oxide was used as an insulator between the gate electrode and the substrate even without the need of advanced tools for submicrometer lithography. Currents collected by the anode were measured at different gate voltages.</description><creator>Laou, Philips.</creator><contributor>Shih, I. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Field emission devices on silicon</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k437t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tr04n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sm20v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We performed a large (n = 878), multicenter, hospital-based, cross-sectional study to measure the health-related quality of life (HRQOL) of healthy participants treated for dyslipidemia and patients with coronary heart disease (CHD). The HRQOL measures included a nonpreference-based measure (SF-36 Health Survey) and three preference-based measures (Rating Scale (RS), Time Trade-off (TTO) and Standard Gamble (SG)). The adjusted mean HRQOL, of healthy participants undergoing treatment for dyslipidemia was 2.8 (p = 0.02) and 3.3 (p = 0.02) points lower, when compared to a similar group of participants not being treated for dyslipidemia, on the RS and the SF-36 General Health Perception (GHP) subscale, respectively. These differences were unlikely to be due to confounding by comorbidity, age, gender and body mass index. No significant differences were detected on the TTO and SG scales. For each preference-based scaling technique, the adjusted HRQOL mean scores obtained from patients diagnosed with angina, myocardial infarction, or angina and myocardial infarction were similar. Patients with congestive heart failure reported the worst HRQOL on all scales. The test-retest reliability, over a 3 to 6 week period, was acceptable for all scaling techniques and the majority of participants reported consistent scores at the test and the retest assessments. Correlation between the preference-based measures and each of the SF-36 subscales varied from poor to moderate. Compared to the TTO and the SG, the RS was the most highly correlated with the different aspects of the HRQOL measured by the SF-36 Health Survey and had the highest ability to discriminate CHD patients with various physical disabilities and participants reporting specific number of health problems. This study provides a complete set of preference-based measures for use in cost-effectiveness analysis of CHD primary prevention. It suggests that the impact of detecting and treating dyslipidemia on the participant's HRQOL may be small but significant from a public policy point of view. Further research should be done confirming these results and elucidating the causes and the consequences of this negative effect on HRQOL of healthy individuals treated for dyslipidemia.</description><creator>Lalonde, Lyne.</creator><contributor>Grover, Steven A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>Health-related quality of life measures in coronary heart disease prevention and treatment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719n96g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sm20v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zg275</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two clinical studies were conducted to evaluate the effects of recombinant bovine somatotropin in daily, weekly or bi-weekly injected preparations on milk yield, feed efficiency and reproduction. In the first study, a linear dose-response effect of recombinant bST on milk yield with doses of up to 150 mg · 7d-1 was observed. Feed intake was not affected and feed efficiency was increased by bST during lactation. Body condition at the end of lactation was lower in cows supplemented with bST. Feed intake during the dry period following bST supplementation was not affected by bST given during lactation. When differences in body condition were taken into account, efficiency of conversion of dietary energy to milk energy was not affected by bST supplementation. In another study of bST supplementation during lactation, a daily dose of 10.3 mg · d-1 and a sustained release formulation of 350 mg · 14d-1 did not increase milk production or feed efficiency. In the absence of a milk production response, reproductive performance was not affected by bST supplementation. Progesterone production in the second oestrous cycle post partum was higher in cows receiving bST but oestrous activity was not affected. Body condition at calving did not affect milk production, response to rbST or reproductive performance. Cows calving with a body condition less than 3.25 consumed more feed per unit of body weight and resumed ovarian cyclic activity later than cows calving with a body condition greater or equal to 3.25. An epinephrine challenge during the dry period was performed to evaluate whether the effects of bST supplementation during lactation on adipose tissue metabolism persisted during the dry period. Lipid mobilisation by cows having received bST during lactation, as described by the release of non-esterified fatty acids following the epinephrine challenge, did not differ from control cows. Two studies designed to evaluate the effect of bST on oestradiol-induce</description><creator>Lefebvre, Daniel Maurice.</creator><contributor>Block, Elliot (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Dairy cattle.</subject><subject>Bovine somatotropin.</subject><title>Studies on the effects of recombinant bovine somatotropin on nutritional status and reproduction of dairy cows</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87ps150.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zg275</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1831cm71m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The last decade has witnessed substantial changes in organizational structure, inter-organizational relations and the nature of competition. In particular, the realization of interdependencies across firm boundaries has brought forth a range of mechanisms for coordination among firms in vertically related stages of production, or among direct competitors in the same industry. Our objective is to study inter-organizational relations in an oligopolistic setting to explore the interactions between efficiency and strategic incentives for organizations to engage in various forms of coordination, vertically or horizontally. Specifically, we employ a game-theoretic approach to analyze organizational structure and coordination incentives in relation to process innovation, transfer pricing, and degree of competition between products. This study is divided into four parts. In the first part, we look at the impact of manufacturer's investments in process innovation to reduce production costs on distribution channel structure, and vice versa. We show that the optimal channel structure decision depends on interactions between two parameters: degree of product differentiation and the extent of production cost reduction. These parameters represent the two primary 'generic strategies' that most organizations follow in order to gain competitive advantage. Second, we show that decentralized manufacturers invest less in process innovation than integrated manufacturers do. However, manufacturers may prefer decentralized, non-coordinated channels to perfectly coordinated channels when product substitutability is high, contrary to efficiency and transaction-cost based arguments for increased coordination. In the second part, we relax the assumption that a manufacturer has a choice only between integration (or 'hierarchy') and decentralization (or 'market'). Various means of channel coordination are analyzed, and ownership is assumed to be distinct from the particular coordination mechanism employed. It is shown that the consideration of the competitive environment changes incentives for, and benefits to, coordination in various Production, Inventory, and Pricing decisions among members of a supply chain. In the third part, we focus on horizontal cooperation among firms, ignoring the vertical relations. We consider the possibility of technological spillovers in the process innovation efforts of the manufacturers, and their incentives to engage in cooperative R&amp;D agreements with rivals in the same industry. We develop a two-stage game model with manufacturers producing differentiated products, and establish fairly general conditions under which different cooperative arrangements would be beneficial both for manufacturers and consumers. In the fourth part, we merge the above two dimensions, i.e., we investigate the interactions between horizontal cooperative agreements among rival manufacturers and vertical coordination arrangements along the supply chain. The models above are extended to incorporate the triple influence of technological spillovers and research joint ventures, along with demand and cost side parameters, on supply chain coordination incentives. We argue that a better understanding of such interactions is crucial in explicating a more relevant theory of the firm.</description><creator>Gupta, Sudheer.</creator><contributor>Loulou, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Oligopolies</subject><subject>Vertical integration.</subject><subject>Interorganizational relations.</subject><subject>Joint ventures.</subject><title>Strategic aspects of supply chain relations : an interdisciplinary approach to the analysis of inter-firm cooperation and competition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wf52p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cm71m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33950</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>