<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:20:41Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33000" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sf358</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An industrial Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) milk analyser has been adapted for the proximate analysis of fresh or cooked meat and meat products. Stable freeze-dried samples of ground beef and bologna were prepared for the calibration of an FTIR spectrometer equipped with a 37-mum transmission cell maintained at a constant temperature of 65°C and were analysed for fat, protein, moisture, and ash by the official methods of analysis of the Association of Official Analytical Chemists (AOAC) prior to instrumental measurement. The requirement to prepare a "milk-like" emulsion of meat for FTIR analysis led to the development of two prototype high-pressure homogenizers specifically designed to produce analytical volumes of emulsions in which the largest residual colloids present in suspension would have dimensions smaller than 1 mum. Emulsified samples were examined by transmission electron microscopy and laser light scattering spectroscopy to determine the size distribution of fat globules and the dimensions of the residual insoluble fragments of protein. "Milk-like" emulsions of meat passed three times through a high-pressure homogenizer operating at 20,000 psi (138 MPa) had an average fat globule diameter of less than 320 nm. Also, the use of high-pressure homogenization eliminated the need to filter out insoluble proteins from connective tissues prior to the infrared analysis, resulting in a more accurate determination of the protein content in the meat samples. The results of validation studies conducted with both fresh and freeze-dried samples demonstrated that it is possible to analyse meat samples simultaneously for fat, protein, carbohydrates and moisture with good accuracy in approximately 7½; minutes per sample employing existing FTIR instrumentation used for the routine analysis of milk and dairy products.</description><creator>Dion, Bruno J.</creator><contributor>Ismail, Ashraf A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>High pressure (Technology)</subject><subject>Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy.</subject><subject>Meat -- Composition.</subject><title>Application of high-pressure homogenization for the proximate analysis of meat and meat products by Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sh931.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sf358</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354g97n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the goals of current research in medical ultrasound is to develop techniques to quantitatively differentiate between tissue types and tissue states on the basis of the changes in the backscattered signal caused by differences in the elastic properties of the tissues under study. In this dissertation, we proposed to classify white matter and gray matter of adult brain tissues. The first step in this investigation was to develop a linear dichotomizer for the classification of white matter and gray matter using a power spectrum eigenvector approach with Linear Discriminant Analysis (LDA). The LDA classifier is described in Chapter 4. The successful classification rates for pure white matter and pure gray matter tissues were 99% using the LDA. When the LDA was used in transition regions the successful classification rates for both type of tissues dropped to 56%. We concluded that the weakness with this classification scheme was that it did not exploit the information at different scales. In order to overcome this weakness, two multiscale classification methods were developed in Chapter 5, a power spectrum eigenvector approach with Wavelet transform-Linear Discriminant Analysis (WLDA) and a power spectrum eigenvector approach with Wavelet transform-Artificial Neural Network (WANN). Both methods were tested on calibrated media, also known as tissue mimicking phantoms, as well as on synthetically generated media. The data from synthetically generated media were obtained by a three Dimensional Finite Difference Time Domain method (3D FDTD). Both multiscale classification methods performed as well as the LDA method in classifying pure white matter and pure gray matter but they performed better than the LDA in transition regions. The successful classification rates in transition regions were 88% for white matter and 86% for gray matter using WLDA and 89% for white matter and 88% for gray matter using WANN.</description><creator>Diouf, Ibrahima.</creator><contributor>Watkin, Kenneth (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Multiscale analysis of ultrasonic backscattered signals for biological tissues identification : 3D FDTD simulation and in-vitro tests</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97ks08t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354g97n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78td81r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Three new quantitative Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopic methods were developed to measure key lubricant condition monitoring parameters; total acid number (TAN), total base number (TBN), and moisture (H2O). All methods employ a common sample-handling accessory and are based on the addition of specific reagents designed to react stoichiometrically with target species in oils, with quantification being carried out using differential FTIR spectroscopy. The combined use of a stoichiometric reaction and differential spectroscopy overcomes the need for a reference oil, which has traditionally hindered quantitative analysis of lubricants by FTIR spectroscopy. Potassium hydroxide, trifluoroacetic acid (TFA) and 2,2-dimethoxypropane (DMP) were the stoichiometric reagents used to develop the FTIR TAN, TBN and H2 O methods, respectively. Calibrations were developed using either peak height measurements or partial least squares (PLS) regression and the methods were validated using standard addition techniques, as the ASTM (American Society of Testing and Materials) standard methods were not sufficiently reproducible to make valid comparisons. Validation of the methods indicated that the TAN, TBN and H2O methods had accuracies of +/-0.095 mg KOH/g, +/-0.5 mg KOH/g and +/-32ppm respectively and corresponding reproducibilities of +/-0.05 mg KOH/g, +/-0.17 mg KOH/g and +/-22 ppm. The TAN, TBN and H2O methods were implemented on a Continuous Oil Analysis and Treatment (COATRTM) System, integrating instrumentation, software and sample handling so as to provide packaged, user and environmentally friendly analytical methods that are alternatives to conventional ASTM wet chemical methods.</description><creator>Dong, Jun, 1971-</creator><contributor>van de Voort, F. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Lubricating oils -- Analysis.</subject><subject>Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy.</subject><title>Quantitative condition monitoring of lubricating oils by Fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gm53f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78td81r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wh246t69m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A strategy for the total synthesis of palau'amine is disclosed. The bias of a bicyclic framework is used as a key feature for the enantioselective synthesis of the highly functionalized hexasubstituted cyclopentane core of the molecule. A synthetic approach centering on a tin-catalyzed aldol and a Pauson-Khand reaction is presented. This pathway yielded a penta-substituted cyclopentane ring with four stereocenters positioned and the requisite functionalities to allow for further progress. Installation of the last stereocenter was investigated on a model substrate.</description><creator>Dolaine, Regis.</creator><contributor>Gleason, J. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Approaches towards the asymmetric synthesis of the natural alkaloid palau'amine and diastereoselective formation of 5-vinyl cyclopentenes from 1,6-enynes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182m89b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246t69m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fx719n87h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In order to establish the potential of an esterase from Lactobacillus casei for application in the dairy industry, this study was designed with the following objectives: (1) to determine the optimal cultural conditions for growth and enzyme production, (2) to construct a positive selection vector with low copy number for gene cloning, (3) to clone and sequence the gene encoding for esterase, (4) to biochemically characterize the purified recombinant esterase, and (5) to over-express an esterase of L. casei into Escherichia coli as well as into a methylotrophic yeast, Pichia pastoris using strong promoters. Maximal growth and enzyme production in L. casei were obtained after 20 h in basal MRS medium containing 1% (w/v) lactose at pH 7.0, 30°C. Among various substrates (C2--C16) tested, the highest activity was towards C6 and C8. Although the enzyme was produced constitutively, tributyrin induced the enzyme production by a 2.5 fold. A new E. coli and lactic acid bacteria shuttle vector with low copy and positive selection termed pCWL70 was constructed. High transformation efficiency and significant vector stability of pCWL70 were found in L. casei and Lactococcus lactis. An esterase gene (estI) of L. casei CL96 was localized in a 3.3 kb Bam HI DNA fragment that contains an open reading frame of 1,800 bp. The open reading frame estI was isolated by PCR and subcloned into the E. coli expression vector pET29a, and Pichia expression vector pPICZ B, that allows the inducible expression under the control of the T7 promoter and an alcohol oxidase promoter (AOX1), respectively. E. coli BL21(DE3)pLysS containing estI expressed a novel 67.5 kDa protein corresponding to the EstI in N-terminal fusion with the S · tag peptide. An esterase of L. casei CL96 was successfully over-expressed in E. coli up to 500 folds (about 25% of total cellular protein) as well as in the P. pastoris. In high cell density fed-batch fermentation, the recombinant Pichia strain containing linearized pCESTc was grown at pH 6.5 and 30°C, and the cell density peaked at about 180 h with 468 g wet cell weight per liter. The final yield was 3.7 x 106 units/ml, which is 980-folds higher than that of native L. casei cells. The amino acid sequence of EstI indicated that the esterase is a member of a novel GHSMG family of lipolytic enzymes and S-formylglutathione hydrolases (FGH). The putative catalytic triad of EstI consists of residues Ser325, Asp516 and His558 as demonstrated by amino acid sequence alignments. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Choi, Young-Jun, 1967-</creator><contributor>Lee, Byong H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Lactobacillus casei -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Escherichia coli.</subject><subject>Pichia pastoris.</subject><subject>Esterases.</subject><title>Biochemical and molecular aspects of an esterase from Lactobacillus casei CL96</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859h31n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719n87h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vj42x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis investigates the relationship between communication and place, and the informational environment it forms. The thesis takes as its object of analysis signage, and examines signage as an implaced medium of communication. In this work communication, including its practices and technologies, is treated as a dynamic ritual formed by the marking, naming, connecting, and interpreting the environment in the process of wayfinding. Such an approach underscores the inherent duality of communication: its manifestations framed by transmission and ritual; its boundedness by both space and time; and its expression in both mobile and fixed (implaced) media. The thesis thus shifts the disciplinary discourse from the usual text- and language-based focus to a more comprehensive focus that encompasses architectural and infrastructural environments and the grounding action of physical presences. Through its focus on the navigational aspects of communication, and framing by such concepts as wayfinding and signposting, the thesis shows how we can reconfigure the notion of the visual to include the embodied, experiential, and implaced. This in turn can help us gain a new perspective on the changing nature of text, image, representation, information and reality. The thesis argues that as the themes of orientation, navigation, and interface grow alongside the new communication technologies, they make it important to attend to the original mediating role of the built environment and the navigational dimensions of place. It is here, within our foundational spatial orientation and wayfinding, that we turn for the metaphors, conceptual structures, and grounding as we chart our ways through the emerging informational environments. In examining signage as a system of interfaces used in negotiating informational environments, as way-markers in a process of wayfinding, the thesis demonstrates the ways in which the concepts of wayfinding and navigation have become consequential to communication scholarship. It proposes that fruitful cues for the theorising and understanding of emerging informational realms can be drawn from the communicative dimensions of the most familiar immersive environments and their related practices: the physical spaces and built environments that we inhabit and negotiate daily.</description><creator>Chmielewska, Ella.</creator><contributor>Crowley, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Navigation.</subject><subject>Signs and signboards.</subject><subject>Space and time.</subject><title>Implaced communication : wayfinding and informational environments</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dt74q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vj42x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74cs11w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis argues that the popular characterization of high modernist fiction as esoteric, elitist, uncommunicative, and far too difficult for the common reader obscures the democratic principles at the heart of modernist experimentation and its poetics of difficulty. Recent theories of embodied cognition when applied to representative examples of high modernist novels help dispel the myth of inaccessibility and reveal the many ways in which these works actually accommodate the common reader. Once the stigma of inaccessibility is removed from the study of modernist novels, it becomes possible to see how their formal experiments with language as well as the themes and issues they contain operate for readers and writers alike as a means of exploring everyday cognitive activities and responses. To this end, the concept of cognitive dissonance provides a heuristic device for understanding what lies behind the motivations of writers who aestheticise experiences of dissonance in their texts and the responses of readers who confront these texts. This cognitive approach to modern literature challenges assumptions about high modernism's "uncompromising intellectuality" and replaces them with a view of modernism that is more accessible and inclusive without diminishing its radical difficulty. It also paves the way for new readings of highly canonical modernist fiction. For instance, I examine how James Joyce places "inscribed" readers into Ulysses to guide actual readers through some of the difficulties of the novel. I then read William Faulkner's The Sound and the Fury as a novel that both thematises and formally resists the modern threat of behaviouristic human conditioning. Finally, I look at how the theme and form of Virginia Woolf's Mrs. Dalloway reinforce the embodied equation of dissonance with illness and incompletion.</description><creator>Clissold, Bradley.</creator><contributor>Wihl, Gary (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Woolf, Virginia, 1882-1941. Mrs. Dalloway.</subject><subject>Faulkner, William, 1897-1962. Sound and the fury.</subject><subject>Joyce, James, 1882-1941. Ulysses.</subject><subject>Modernism (Literature)</subject><title>Recovering the common sense of high modernism : embodied cognition and the novels of Joyce, Faulkner, and Woolf</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773x37x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cs11w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33rz364</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>While most schooling in the Philippines currently takes place in a coeducational setting, it seems apparent that, although they are attending the same high schools, boys and girls are not getting the same education. In many areas of the Philippines, boys' dropout rates are almost three times that of girls'. As more females graduate from college, women are rapidly replacing men in many fields. However, this does not mean that women are leaving their traditional responsibilities in the home. Quite the opposite, women are now finding themselves faced with double the work while men essentially find themselves without the training or skills to adapt to a changing society. This dissertation looks specifically at the schooling of two communities in the central Philippines. Looking at one school from a very rural village and another in a larger city, I examine the historical and sociological traditions of the Philippines and the island of Panay specifically. I investigate the reasons for girls' success while also looking at some reasons for boys' failure. I look closely at students' relationships with their schools, their teachers, their families, and with each other; I am trying to get a sense of how they perceive themselves and their world. This dissertation uses qualitative research methods including lengthy observation and interview of students, families and teachers. It draws from the traditions of phenomenology and grounded theory, and is constructed in an interpretive anthropological tradition in which the narration is in first person singular and, where possible, the present tense.</description><creator>Clark, Paul, 1965-</creator><contributor>McDonough, Kevin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Women -- Education -- Philippines.</subject><subject>Sex differences in education -- Philippines.</subject><subject>Education, Secondary -- Philippines.</subject><title>A study of two Philippine high schools : a cross-cultural look at the education of girls and boys</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bd368.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33rz364</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214q79b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research program consists of laboratory studies of the corrosion phenomenon and field study of the deterioration due to corrosion of the Dickson Bridge. The laboratory studies examined the influence of increasing levels of corrosion on the progressive deterioration of bond between the steel and concrete and determined the extent to which the various cements and mix proportions influence the corrosion of the reinforcement as well as the chloride ion penetration. The corrosion resistance of the fly ash concrete is examined and compared with that of plain concrete to determine the effects of cement type, w/c ratio, cover thickness, and the use of different classes of fly ash on the durability of the concrete mix. An accelerated electrochemical corrosion procedure was developed with the objective of "completely" corroding the bar in a period of 15--20 weeks. The influence of corrosion on the bond between the reinforcing steel and concrete was studied using two types of tests---the pullout and tension test. Eight levels of corrosion, ranging from no corrosion to complete corrosion, with over 25 percent steel bar weight loss due to corrosion, with wide longitudinal cracks. The phenomena of tension cracking and tension stiffening in tension specimens subjected to corrosion were also examined. The bond behaviour is influenced by the deterioration of the reinforcing bar ribs and by the reduced adhesion and cohesion of the reinforcing bar due to the widening of the longitudinal splitting crack resulting from corrosion. It was noted that low levels of corrosion (about 1--3% mass loss) lead to slight improvement of bond strength. However, bond strength decreases rapidly with an increase in the corrosion level, especially in the case of any severe localized corrosion. Analysis of the test results showed that a 5% mass loss resulted in a 9 percent decrease of the nominal bond stress. While with over 25 percent mass loss due to corrosion, a 90 percent loss of the nominal bond stress was noted. The results indicate that the use of high volume fly ash (three different mixtures) was very effective in delaying the corrosion process as compared to that of the normal portland cement. However, the direct tensile strength of fly ash concrete as calculated from the response of the tension tests was noted to be weaker than that of normal portland cement concrete. Also, the bond performance of the steel bars embedded in the normal portland cement concrete mixtures with a low water-cement ratio of 0.32 was found to be superior than that with a concrete mixture with a larger water-cement ratio. This research program was a part of a detailed strategic program to determine why the Dickson Bridge in Montreal deteriorated so prematurely and to create a data bank from many electrochemical, chemical, physical and mechanical tests on the various bridge components. This thesis includes the results of very detailed tests on four randomly selected 6 m by 5 m segments of the bridge, with some of the basic tests being undertaken on a grid of 0.25 m by 0.25 m. The field test data corroborates the results of six other investigators who undertook similar tests on different parts of the bridge and also repeated some of the tests to ensure reproduction of the results. An evaluation of the steel bar mass loss and the chloride content at the steel-concrete interface in the field showed considerable scatter because of the leaching of the chlorides deeper into the deck. However, an analysis of this data for steel bar mass loss of less then 15% showed good correlation between the field test results and the laboratory data from the tension specimens constructed using the same concrete as the Dickson Bridge. Although more research is needed in this area, presently it is possible to determine the steel bar mass loss from measurement of the chloride contents in its vicinity.</description><creator>Amleh, Lamya.</creator><contributor>Mirza, M. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Bond deterioration of reinforcing steel in concrete due to corrosion</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021g907.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214q79b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806156h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A total of twenty-eight Bacillus spp. isolated from value-added surimi nuggets and their raw ingredients, were tested against each other and selected reference strains of Bacillus and Clostridium for their production of inhibitory substances using the deferred antagonism assay plating method. The isolated Bacillus strains showed inhibitory activity against all Bacillus strains, with the exception of the producer strain, as well as being effective against various strains of C. botulinum (type A, B and E). Subsequent studies showed that the inhibitory activity was detected in the culture supernatant in the late stationary phase of growth prior to sporulation. The inhibitory activity of two Bacillus strains (FN2A and FN33) were selected for further study. The inhibitory substances produced by these two strains were proteinaceous in nature, heat stable (100°C for 15min) and unaffected by organic solvents. A comprehensive study was conducted on the structural characterization of the inhibitor produced by B. subtilis FN2A using FPLC, FTIR, MS and MS/MS. Structural analysis of the inhibitor produced by B. subtilis FN2A showed that it was similar in structure to Surfactin. Preliminary studies have shown that the Surfactin-like-compound from B. subtilis FN2A was produced in significant amounts during growth in bread with maximum production occurring in the late stationary phase (72h), at 30--35°C and at pH 6.5--7.0. Optimization studies on the production of the Surfactin-like-compound by B. subtilis FN2A in bread using a response surface methodology approach showed that temperature (33--36°C); autoclaving time (30 min); inoculum level (4%), alkali pre-treatment (0.16%), water activity (0.995) and pH 6.66 enhanced the production of the Surfactin-like-compound in bread. The compound produced under these optimal conditions also maintained its activity when subjected to various processing treatments (autoclaving, freezing and freeze drying). Initial studies showed that low levels (1% w/w) of the Surfactin-like-compound inhibited the growth of B. cereus and proteolytic and non-proteolytic strains of C. botulinum in a model agar system. However, it had no effect on non-proteolytic strains of C. botulinum when bread, or methanol extracts of bread (1--20%), were added to formulated value-added sterile trout nuggets, with all nuggets being toxic after 28 days at 12°C. Furthermore, inoculation of B. subtilis FN2A directly into nuggets also failed to inhibit growth of non-proteolytic strains of C. botulinum. Omitting certain ingredients in the formulation failed to enhance the anti-botulinal effect of the bread or methanol extracts of the Surfactin-like-compound in the value-added nuggets. However, reducing the pH of the nuggets to ~5.5 enhanced the anti-botulinal effect of the Surfactin-like-compound. Further research is required to improve the dispersibility of the Surfactin-like-compound to inhibit the growth of C. botulinum in food systems.</description><creator>Al-Zenki, Sameer F.</creator><contributor>Smith, James (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Microbial surfactants.</subject><subject>Bacillus subtilis.</subject><subject>Clostridium botulinum.</subject><subject>Bacillus (Bacteria)</subject><subject>Bacteriocins.</subject><subject>Food -- Preservation.</subject><title>Purification, characterization, production and application of biopreservatives from Bacillus species</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hr41r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806156h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jn15c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The susceptibility of steels to transverse cracking during continuous casting depends, in part, on the hot ductility of the steel. In the past, hot ductility has been measured in the laboratory by tensile testing specimens reheated to a high temperature (preferably melted), and then cooled down to the desired test temperature before isothermally testing to fracture. More recently, isothermal tensile testing has been performed after imposing different thermal histories prior to reaching the test temperature. The most relevant thermal history is that of the solidifying strand surface. Such thermal histories have been found to be quite complex, and invariably involve rapid cooling and heating cycles. This will therefore lead to high thermal gradients, which, in turn, can generate strains in the surface of the solidifying strand. Thus, the purpose of this thesis was to consider the effect of the thermomechanical history on the hot ductility of steel. A Nb-Ti microalloyed steel was chosen to be studied, since microalloying often increases susceptibility to transverse cracking. After in-situ melting and solidification, tensile test specimens were subjected to the thermal history typical of a continuously cast billet. Different amounts of prior deformations in various schedules were imposed on the specimens at selected stages during the thermal history, before tensile testing to fracture at the time and temperature corresponding to the unbending stage of the billet casting. It was found that the hot ductility varied from 1% to 98%, depending on the stage in the thermal history at which prior deformation was executed. Microstructural studies showed remarkable changes in the precipitation pattern occurred due to the employed prior deformation. Similar hot ductility measurements executed on a low carbon steel, that was free from microalloy elements, exhibited an effect of prior hot deformation which was quite different to the Nb-Ti microalloyed steel. In particular, the effect on the hot ductility was not as dramatic. The effects were also postulated to be due to precipitation.</description><creator>Akhlaghi-Esfahani, Siamak.</creator><contributor>Yue, Steve (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Effect of a thermomechanical history on the hot ductility of a Nb-Ti microalloyed steel and a low carbon steel</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gv319.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jn15c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603r0181</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study is an exploration of the relationship between spirituality and the career-transition process in middle-aged women's lives. The sample of this study consisted of 20 women who were in or went through a career-transition process. The research data were collected through in-depth interviews. Grounded theory methodology (Strauss &amp; Corbin, 1990) was used to analyse the data and to generate frameworks for the interaction between the career-transition process and spirituality. The results indicated three different frameworks to explain the interaction between the two research variables for three different patterns of career-transition process. These frameworks included five major themes related to spirituality and the career-transition process: (a) reflection, (b) belief in a transcendent dimension of reality, (c) principles and morals to live by, (d) reciprocity, and (e) life outside work.</description><creator>Akçali, F. Özge.</creator><contributor>Sinacore, Ada L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Career changes.</subject><subject>Women -- Employment.</subject><subject>Women -- Religious life.</subject><title>An exploration of the relationship between spirituality and the career-transition process in middle-aged women's lives /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mx07d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r0181</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859h32x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Neuropeptide Y (NPY) and NPY receptors are concentrated in the hippocampal formation where they modulate cognitive functions and seizures. The cellular mechanisms underlying the physiological roles of NPY in the hippocampus are still rather elusive. Cultured hippocampal cells offer a simple model to study the expression of hippocampal NPY receptor subtypes and their respective cellular distribution. The present thesis examines the presence of NPY receptors in primary dissociated hippocampal cells in culture using a combination of molecular, pharmacological and immunocytochemical approaches. Receptor binding experiments revealed the preferential expression of Y1-like receptors over the Y2, Y4 and Y5 subtypes in rat hippocampal cultures. Cultured hippocampal cells expressed high level of Y1 receptors and very low amounts (below detection) of the Y2, Y 4 and Y5 receptor binding sites. The genuine nature of the Y1-like receptor expressed in these cells was confirmed using amplification (RT-PCR) of Y1 receptor mRNAs. The cellular phenotype expressing Y1 receptor was investigated using double labeling methods. Specific autoradiographic and immunolabeling signals of Y1-like receptors were observed on neurons (70% of the total population of neurons) and astrocytes (20% of the total population of glia cells) as revealed respectively by neuron specific enolase (NSE) and glial fibrillary acidic protein (GFAP) immunostaining. The Y1 receptor labeling is distributed uniformly over neuronal cell bodies and processes compared to a non-uniform and clustered distribution on type I astrocytes. Neurons labeled by the various Y1 receptor markers were mostly glutamate-positive as revealed by double labeling. Interestingly, a small proportion (2--5%) of NPY-positive hippocampal neurons (NPY-positive cells represent around 10% of the total population of neurons) were also enriched with Y1 receptor labeling. These results suggest the possible autoregulatory role for the Y1 receptor on NPY release. Taken together, these anatomical and pharmacological results suggest that Y1 receptor may play an important role in the hippocampus via the regulation of astrocytic and/or neuronal functions and the modulation of the release of glutamate and/or NPY.</description><creator>St-Pierre, Jacques-André.</creator><contributor>Quirion, Remi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Cellular and pharmacological characterization of NPY YI receptor expression in cultured rat hippocampal neurons and astrocytes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj2363811.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859h32x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cn69m572x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present research included gender in Person-by-Situation interaction models in the study of interpersonal behavior and affect. An event-contingent recording methodology was used to measure behavior and affect across situations and over time in natural settings for a 20-day period with adult community samples. Three dyadic situations of personal relationships that varied in gender composition and emotional closeness were examined: same-sex friendships, opposite-sex friendships, and romantic relationships. Traditional investigations of gender, disregarding situational factors, have determined that women are generally less agentic, more communal, and more emotional than men. The present research demonstrated that the interpersonal behavior of agency and communion were influenced by both situation and gender. In same-sex friendships, women and men behaved consistently with their gender-stereotypes: pairs of women were more communal than pairs of men and pairs of men were more agentic than pairs of women. In mixed-sex dyads, individuals did not behave consistently with gender-stereotypes. Women and men behaved similarly on agency and communion with opposite-sex friends. In interactions with a romantic partner, women behaved less communally than men. Personal relationship situations were found to moderate agentic and communal behaviors, demonstrating the plasticity and variability of gender role behaviors. Pleasant and unpleasant affect intensity was influenced by situation but not gender. The present research demonstrated that women and men reported experiencing similar levels of affect across the relationship situations. As predicted, individuals experienced both greater pleasant and unpleasant affect in romantic relationships than friendships. The current research confirmed that there is a need to move beyond the conception that the stereotypic characteristics of men and women reside within individuals. Gender should be included in Person-by-Situation interaction models, taking into consideration psychological and social factors that shape the expression of sex-differentiated behaviors and the experience of emotions.</description><creator>Suh, Eun Jung, 1968-</creator><contributor>Moskowitz, D. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Male friendship.</subject><subject>Man-woman relationships.</subject><subject>Social interaction.</subject><subject>Female friendship.</subject><title>Gender-by-situation interaction models of agency, communion, and affect</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sf36j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m572x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:79407z86v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Human carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA) is a heavily glycosylated cell surface protein that belongs to the immunoglobulin superfamily (IgSF). It is overexpressed in a wide variety of human cancers. CEA functions in vitro, at least, as an intercellular adhesion molecule. It has also been shown that ectopic expression of CEA can block myogenic differentiation of rat L6 and mouse C2C12 myoblasts. Both the intercellular adhesion function of CEA as well as the inhibition of myogenic differentiation are dependent on homophilic binding of its extracellular domains. Previous studies have demonstrated that homophilic binding of CEA is mediated by double reciprocal bonds between the N and A3B3 domains of anti-parallel CEA molecules on apposed cell surfaces. Treatment of nonfusing L6 (CEA) with four fusion polypeptides representing the different domains of CEA showed that only N and A3B3 peptides were able to release the myogenic differentiation block. This information provoked studies designed to identify the precise subdomain (s) within the N domain that could be used to develop inhibitory agents to both disrupt the intercellular adhesion function and to release the myogenic differentiation block. Moreover, we show here that in addition to anti-parallel CEA-CEA interactions, parallel CEA-CEA interactions on the same cell surface are involved in the myogenic differentiation block. In this study, it is demonstrated by site directed mutagenesis, that at least three different subdomains, G30YSWYK, N42RQII, and Q 80NDTG, in the N-terminal domain are required for homophilic binding of CEA. Two cyclized peptides representing subdomains, N42RQII and Q80NDTG, were effective in blocking intercellular adhesion mediated by CEA. We also identified the binding epitope of an anti-CEA monoclonal antibody (A20), known to block homophilic binding of CEA, and showed that it bridges N42RQII and G30YSWYK. Furthermore, it was shown that G30YSWYK, N42RQII, and Q80NDTG are all involved in the diffe</description><creator>Taheri, Maryam.</creator><contributor>Stanners, C. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Characterization of the structural determinants of two functions of human carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA) : intercellular adhesion and differentiation inhibition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732db66s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/79407z86v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r7236</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>DNA vaccination is based on in vivo delivery of plasmids encoding an antigen, leading to antigen synthesis and specific immunity. This technology is still in its infancy but has advantages over conventional vaccination, such as the stimulation of all arms of the immune response, i.e., humoral immunity, T-helper (17h) cells and cytotoxic T lymphocytes (CTLs). We studied DNA vaccination against human carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA) in mice. Our hypothesis was that codelivery of cytokine- and CEA-encoding plasmids could regulate responses, and allow polarization of Th responses to either type 1 (Th1) or type 2 (Th2). We found that intramuscular injection of the CEA plasmid alone induced antibodies, Th1 cells and CTLs reactive to CEA. These mice had increased immunity against transplanted syngeneic CEA+ stably transfected tumor cell lines, but always developed lethal tumors. Coinjection of the CEA plasmid with a vector encoding either IL-12 or interferon gamma (IFNgamma) markedly enhanced IgG2a production (IFNgamma-dependent), IFNgamma secretion by spleen cells (a Th1 cytokine) and CTL-mediated tumor cell lysis, in a CEA-specific way. Moreover, resistance to a tumor challenge was greatly improved, such that up to 80% of mice survived tumor free. In contrast, coinjection of CEA and IL-4 genes increased CEA-specific IgG1 levels (IL-4-dependent) and IL-4 secretion by lymphocytes (a Th2 cytokine), but decreased both CTL activity and tumor resistance. Thus, we could readily enhance or polarize immunity. The IL-12 cDNA had the strongest adjuvant effect, which was only observed when it was injected at the same site as the CEA gene. To analyze effector components, we studied IL-12-plasmid-enhanced DNA vaccination in gene knockout mice, lacking either CD3, CD4, CD8. IFNgamma, perforin or Fas ligand (FasL). Only mice expressing all of CD3, CD4, IFNgamma, CD8 and perforin, and inoculated with both the CEA and IL-12 genes, could fully resist a tumor challenge. The Fas/FasL lytic</description><creator>Song, Keli, 1955-</creator><contributor>Prud'homme, Gerald J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>DNA-based vaccination against carcinoembryonic antigen</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n031t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r7236</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53wx457</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Traditionally, the vestibulo-ocular reflex (VOR) has been considered a stereotyped ocular counterrotation response to head movement that stabilizes a visual image on the retinae. However, during natural head movements, the appropriate magnitudes and directions of compensatory ocular deviations depend on viewing context. Moment-to-moment adjustments in VOR performance are required as gaze is redirected towards different viewing locations. This thesis presents an investigation of viewing-context-dependent VOR performance through the development of a physiologically and anatomically based bilateral model structure. Previous theoretical studies of visual-vestibular interactions during head-centered rotation are extended by simulating both ocular responses and those of individual premotor brainstem neuron types in an integrated binocular controller for slow eye movements. Central sensitivities to vestibular canal signals are modulated as a function of instantaneous binocular fixation state to simulate appropriate viewing-location-dependent changes in monocular rotational VOR performance and distinct premotor cell behaviors. A new hypothesis for the central dynamic processing of sensory otolith signals in the translational VOR is presented. Previous proposals suggested that the unique dynamic characteristics of otolith and canal afferent signals imply additional central processing in the translational as compared to the rotational VOR pathways. The strategy presented here demonstrates that projecting canal and otolith signals onto a shared premotor circuit at unique sites is sufficient to reproduce observed ocular and central behaviors without introducing additional central filters. By implementing this simple strategy in the bilateral model structure the ability to achieve appropriate compensatory responses for different translation directions and viewing locations in the horizontal plane is demonstrated. Finally, the model is extended to incorporate brainstem-cerebellar interactions. Current conclusions surrounding potential central sites for plasticity underlying long-term VOR gain adaptation are evaluated. The work makes new suggestions for vestibulo-ocular system organization and proposes directions for experimental work in addressing the following general themes: (1) Sensory convergence onto a shared premotor controller; (2) The role of a bilateral topology in motor pattern selection and binocular coordination; (3) The role of central connectivity in the appearance of distinct premotor cell types; (4) The ability to localize central sites for modifications underlying viewing-location-dependent and long-term adaptive changes in reflex performance.</description><creator>Green, Andrea Michelle.</creator><contributor>Galiana, H. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Visual-vestibular interaction in a bilateral model of the rotational and translational vestibulo-ocular reflexes : an investigation of viewing-context-dependent reflex performance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892c50s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wx457</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848s23x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The eukaryotic initiation factor (eIF) 4F complex is composed of three polypeptides: eIF4A, eIF4E and eIF4G. eIF4E is the cap-binding subunit; eIF4A is the component which exhibits RNA helicase activity and is thought to unwind the secondary structure present at the 5' leader sequences of mRNAs; eIF4G serves as a scaffold to bring together eIF4E, eIF4A, with eIF3, thus recruiting the mRNA to the 40S small ribosomal subunit. Here, I describe the identification and characterization of a novel homologue of eIF4G that we have termed eIF4GII. We renamed the previously discovered polypeptide, eIF4GI. eIF4GI and eIF4GII are 46% identical at the amino acid level. eIF4GII interacts directly with eIF4E, eIF4A, eIF3 and the poly(A) binding protein. eIF4GII restores cap-dependent translation in a reticulocyte lysate which had been pretreated with rhinovirus 2A protease to cleave endogenous eIF4G. Our findings indicate that eIF4GII is a functional homologue of eIF4GI. In contrast to cellular mRNAs, entero- and rhinovirus RNAs do not possess a cap structure, and their translation is mediated by ribosome binding to an internal ribosome entry site present within the 5' untranslated region. The cleavage of eIF4G induced by the viral protease 2A is thought to be responsible for the shutoff of host protein synthesis in entero- and rhinovirus-infected cells. Nonetheless, in virus-infected cells, a lack of correlation between eIF4GI cleavage and inhibition of host translation is observed. eIF4GII, like eIF4GI, is also cleaved upon viral infection. Here, I present data showing that the kinetics of cleavage of eIF4GII perfectly coincide with the inhibition of cellular protein synthesis observed after entero- and rhinovirus infection. Thus, proteolysis of both eIF4GI and eIF4GII appears to be required for the shutoff of host protein synthesis after entero- and rhinovirus infections.</description><creator>Gradi, Alessandra.</creator><contributor>Sonenberg, Nahum (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Translational control in eukaryotes : discovery of a novel human eukaryotic translation initiation factor and its role in the shutoff of host cell protein synthesis following entero- and rhinovirus infections</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440v282.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848s23x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z708z43m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Bcg/Ity/Lsh locus confers natural host resistance to mice infected with several unrelated species of intracellular pathogens. The Nramp1 gene was identified by Vidal and colleagues by positional cloning of candidate genes for the Bcg/Ity/Lsh locus. A single glycine-to-aspartate substitution at position 169 (G169D) in the predicted TM4 domain of the Nramp1 protein was found to be associated with susceptibility to infection. To initiate characterization of the Nramp1 gene and its role in infection, the Nramp1 genomic structure was analyzed including its exon-intron boundaries. Analysis of the 5' upstream region revealed the use of multiple transcription initiation sites mapping near possible initiator sequences and identified consensus DNA sequence motifs previously implicated in regulating cell-specific and inducible gene expression in macrophages. Transgenic mice were generated in which a genomic clone of the Nramp1 G169 allele was transferred onto a homozygous Nramp1 D169 allele genetic background. Expression of the Nramp1 (G169) protein in transgenic macrophages was concommitant with the emergence of resistance to infection with Mycobacterium bovis and Salmonella typhimurium. The gain of function detected in transgenic mice helped to establish that (1) Nramp1 and Bcg/Ity/Lsh are allelic, and (2) the Nramp1(D169) allele is the molecular basis for susceptibility to infection. Nramp1 gene expression was examined to help understand the role of Nramp1 during infection. Analysis of bone marrow-derived cell colonies found Nramp1 mRNA to be limited to mature professional phagocytes of myeloid lineage. Nramp1 mRNA expression was found to be upregulated by inflammatory and cytokine stimuli in a macrophage cell line and in vivo. To assay for Nramp1 function, an in vitro system was created where the Nramp1(D169) cDNA was transfected into the RAW264.7 macrophage cell line. Transfected Nramp1 protein was found to be in a membranous compartment, recruited to the membrane</description><creator>Govoni, Gregory R.</creator><contributor>Gros, Philippe (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Characterization of the Nramp1 gene and its role in natural host resistance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021g92s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708z43m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558f893</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis provides the first unconditional proof that the ring Z[square root of 14]; is a Euclidean domain. The proof is generalized to other real quadratic fields and to cyclotomic extensions of Q . It is proved that when K is a real quadratic field (modulo the existence of two special primes of K) and when K is a cyclotomic extension of Q that OK satisfies: OK is a Euclidean domain if and only if it is a principal ideal domain. The final chapter discusses the good possibility of finding similar results when K is an arbitrary Galois extension of Q . The proof is a modification of the proof of a theorem of Clark and Murty giving a similar result when K is a totally real extension of degree at least three. The main changes are a new Motzkin-type lemma and the addition of the large sieve to the argument. These changes allow application of a powerful theorem due to Bombieri, Friedlander and Iwaniec in order to obtain the result in the real quadratic case. The modification also allows the completion of the classification of cyclotomic extensions in terms of the Euclidean property and is expected to yield an advance in the general case.</description><creator>Harper, Malcolm, 1958-</creator><contributor>Murty, M. Ram (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>A proof that Z[square root 14] is a Euclidean domain /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zj44z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558f893</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ff3656929</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis of this dissertation can be summed up in a nutshell: Death forces language into being. When faced with the possibility of non-existence, humans are confronted with the reality of nothingness and respond (with speech) by filling the fathomless emptiness of the abyss with permanent meaning. Chapter I outlines this thesis in detail as grounded in Heidegger's existential analytic and provides examples of some of its manifold applications in both everyday life and literary experience. The thesis is supported in three main steps. In Part A I explore the problem of human subjectivity in terms of Heidegger's existential ontology in particular with respect to the question of language and death. I show that the process of language evolution can be understood as an ongoing conflict resolution between the two fundamental modes of human selfhood. The gap between authenticity and inauthenticity is resolved in the dialogue of language. Death, which is nothing other than the nothingness of this yawning gap where one can easily lose oneself, thus appears to be a main factor of language origination, and, paradoxically, at the same time it finds its supersession in language. In Part B I demonstrate that Heidegger has an answer to the question of language origins, and what his answer is. Both the "That" and the "What" lead to the further question of why language "exists" at all. The answer is simple. If Heidegger's phenomenological ontology can be understood as a linguistic ontology, as argued in Chapter I, the relationship between death and language follows. Death motivates the emergence of language, because it is the "existence" of language that can counteract the facticity of death. In Part C I derive support for such a position from Hegel and Benjamin in order to demonstrate that the position is tenable also for other thinkers. In the concluding chapter on Parmenides I show that, with Heidegger, it is possible to see in Parmenides the originator of the thought that the "divine" ontological status of language constitutes, in its persistent thinking of being, a continued existence that defies the facticity of death.</description><creator>Oberst, Achim.</creator><contributor>Buckley, R. Philip (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>di Giovanni, George (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Heidegger, Martin, 1889-1976</subject><subject>Language and languages -- Philosophy.</subject><subject>Ontology.</subject><subject>Death.</subject><title>The bounds of being : existence - death - language : the existential-ontological connection of language and death in Heidegger's being and time : an exegetical approach to Heidegger's linguistic ontology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jw314.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff3656929</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60cz199</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Elections---often to a considerable degree---influence the fiscal policies pursued by governments installed on the basis of their results. Nonetheless, government behaviour is typically modelled exogenously, usually by means of a benevolent, permanently installed "social planner." However, since fiscal policies, devised by democratically elected governments, complement the decentralised pricing system, which---as shown by Samuelson (1954)---is incapable of optimally allocating both private and public goods, the social-planner approach is viewed as being an unsatisfactory tool for the purpose of describing the political aspects of economic decisions. In the absence of a "first-best," Pareto-optimal tax system, fiscal policies are implemented as a result of inter-household "conflicts" over tax rates and public spending. In order to be able to overcome the theoretical difficulties encountered in previous contributions to the Economic Theory of Politics, this text will propose a model that explicitly depicts---"democratically aggregated"---political decisions made on the level of every individual. In this thesis, it will be shown that (i) a country's overall budget can be derived endogenously without relying on the theoretical shortcut of interpersonal preference aggregation, (ii) electoral fluctuations be explained on the basis of the changes to the individuals' particular income and wealth situations, (iii) political behaviour be described in terms of votes and abstentions as well as party membership and ideology, and (iv) the crucial importance of a country's wealth distribution be discussed in the context of economic stability and the role of government.</description><creator>Olters, Jan-Peter.</creator><contributor>Bala, Venkatesh (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Economics -- Political aspects.</subject><subject>Politics, Practical -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Endogenous ballot decisions and "optimal" fluctuations : an economic model of politics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bj86s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz199</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:th83m101p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In international economics literature, different variants of the Nash equilibrium have been used to formulate strategic and retaliative behavior. However, the negotiation process underlying the Nash equilibrium does not capture the notion of retaliation properly. We use the "contingent threat situation" (Greenberg, 1990) to reformulate three different international economic environments. First, a two-country, two-commodity model of trade is considered to reformulate the tariff retaliations. It is known that tariff retaliations lead to a Nash equilibrium outcome, a non-free trade outcome. We show, in the framework of the "theory of social situations", that the free trade equilibrium is supported by a "stable standard of behavior". Second, the basic two-country, single commodity model is employed to formulate the interactive and retaliatory policies regarding the choice between foreign investment and immigration. Considering three different strategic environments, we investigate the outcomes supported by "stable standards of behavior" under these strategic scenarios. We also provide a critical examination of Jones-Coelho-Easton's proposition (Jones, Coelho, and Easton, 1986). Third, a simple model of international debt is formulated using a strategic form game. In the game, a country in financial crisis and on the verge of default is requesting a new loan, and a bank, with exposure to the foreign country's debt, contemplates whether it should issue the new loan. We show that "issue a new loan" and "not default", a Pareto optimum pair of strategies, is stable. Interestingly, we get this result by using a non-cooperative negotiation process, offered by the "individual contingent threat situation".</description><creator>Oladi, Gholamreza.</creator><contributor>Greenberg, Joseph (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Game theory.</subject><subject>International economic relations -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>International trade -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Three essays in international economics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wp49q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m101p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gm550</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study explores the notion of autonomy in the dynamics of private higher education in China. Focusing on the role and function of autonomy in the operation of private institutions of higher education, it examines the evolution of government policy, documents the recent rapid development of private post-secondary institutions, and investigates the quality of the relationships between private institutions, their communities, society and government. Data were collected from government sources and from fifty-six private institutions through various methods, including interviews, questionnaires and case studies. Qualitative analysis of the data revealed different dimensions, perceptions, and patterns of autonomy in these institutions. The study found that institutional autonomy has generally promoted efficiency and flexibility in the operation of these institutions and allowed adaptability and responsiveness to changing social and economic conditions which in turn, have enabled private higher education to contribute significantly to the on-going transformation of Chinese society. However, such autonomy is subject to both external internal constraints and problems, including some restrictive government policies, the lack of financial resources and inexperience in private school operation.</description><creator>Pei, Chao, 1957-</creator><contributor>Smith, David C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Higher education and state -- China.</subject><subject>Private universities and colleges -- China.</subject><subject>School autonomy -- China.</subject><title>Autonomy and private higher education in China</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75df25v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gm550</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65v9586</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:36:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>I am writing a feminist theology of music. Feminist musicologists, by studying music's relation to human sexuality (a connection which theologians have neglected, suppressed, or simply ignored), contend that music has always functioned as a metaphor for sexual relations. As such, music constitutes a site where personal and social formation is negotiated and contested. Via repertoires of musical conventions, much like those in film and literature, composers arouse, manipulate, and channel our desires, thereby reinforcing (and sometimes transgressing) cultural norms of sexuality and gender construction. Their compositions become "fabrications of sexuality." (McClary) Historically, theologians and church authorities vilified music's preeminent worth as an erotic medium, promoting instead its exemplary embodiment of ontic harmony and order. To do so, they clothed their polemic against "illicit" musical practices with the rhetoric of effeminacy, thus veiling male ambivalence toward women and the body in a politics of transcendence. After a critique of these masculinist models, and an exposition of music as a gendered, en-gendering discourse, I will redefine music theologically as abject, fleshly imitatio. To construct a feminist musico-theological model, I shall synthesise a lost trope from the tradition with insights which I have gained from the musical activities of four women musician-composers: Hildegard of Bingen, Bolognese nun Lucrezia Vizzani (and her consoeurs), Sister Rosetta Tharpe, and Diamanda Galas. Through this recuperative synthesis, music's theological significance will shift from its incarnation of harmony and order---divine, cosmic, or human to its ineradicable promiscuity, its dis-integrative powers. My original contribution to the field is fourfold: (1) I document the rhetoric of effeminacy and virility which has influenced and shaped traditional theologies of music, and thereby undermine the latter's privileged status as musico-theological resources; (2) I portray the music of the above women composers as musical imitations of Christ; (3) I enrich revisionist accounts of women in the Christian tradition by giving greater prominence to women's musical activity, the latter previously neglected in, for example, theological studies of mediaeval women, this despite music's centrality to their daily lives; (4) I initiate mutually enriching dialogue between feminist musicology and theology. To date, a feminist theology of music has not been written.</description><creator>Epstein, Heidi.</creator><contributor>Morris, Mitchell B. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Henderson, Ian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Feminism -- Religious aspects.</subject><subject>Theology.</subject><subject>Feminism and music.</subject><subject>Music -- Religious aspects.</subject><title>Melting the Venusberg : a feminist theology of music</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vs62r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65v9586</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33025</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>