<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:54:31Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):26350" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qf85nb54s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Collinear fast-beam laser spectroscopy is a method of studying atomic and ionic hyperfine structure where a particle beam and a laser beam are superposed along the same line. Such a facility exists at ISAC, TRIUMF, Vancouver, BC, and was designed especially for polarising radioactive beams of alkali metals. In order to produce polarised fluorine for the use in NMR, the hyperfine structure of the 3s 4P 5/2 and 3p 4D 7/2 states has to be known. The hyperfine coefficients for those two levels are measured for the first time to be A = 2645.6(6) MHz and A = 1565.6(4)MHz respectively. The 3p 4D5/2 state is also studied to measure the metastable atom fraction and its hyperfine constant is measured to be A = 1148(5)MHz. A study of lanthanum ions is also carried out. Spectra for the 6 s2 1S0 to 5 d6p Do13 transition are measured with stable 139La to evaluate the sensitivity of the equipment and with radioactive 139La for preliminary commissioning of the isotope shift study.</description><creator>Cocolios, Thomas Elias</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Physics, Atomic.</subject><subject>Physics, Radiation.</subject><title>Collinear fast-beam laser spectroscopy at ISAC</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Thomas Elias Cocolios, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d454k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nb54s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:707958028</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, we present many facts pertaining to the Poincare sphere, also called the Bloch sphere. We demonstrate how to compute the R3 rotation matrix that corresponds to a given unitary matrix and, inversely, the unitary matrix corresponding to each rotation matrix. We show that any set of quantum states that is contained in a plane through the Bloch sphere can be encrypted perfectly using only one bit of key, while two bits are required to encrypt any other set. We also try to find equivalent statements for spaces of dimension higher than two. Last, we study the generality of our encryption model, the private quantum channel, or PQC. We introduce the notion of unitary PQC with variable ancilla, and show that any model for a perfect quantum cypher reduces to this new model. We also show that, using any model, 2n bits of key are always required to encrypt n qubits.</description><creator>Courchesne, Martin.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>De la sphère de Poincaré au chiffrement d'information quantique</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Martin Courchesne, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pg54d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/707958028</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d56zw822</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mycobaterium bovis Bacille Calmete-Guerin (BCG) strains are live attenuated vaccines given to prevent tuberculosis. The nature of their attenuation has long been obscure. Recent studies suggest that BCG vaccines are metabolic mutants and antigen mutants, proposed to result in bacteria with decreased persistence and immunogenicity in the host. One specific metabolic defect is that BCG strains are unable to use certain amino acids as nitrogen sources, and paradoxically, that adding L-serine to the culture medium inhibits growth. To explore this further, we studied the growth of BCG strains in different concentrations of serine (both in vivo and in vitro ), screened several candidate genes for mutations and studied the transcription of sdaA and glnA1 genes (encoding for serine deaminase and glutamine synthetase respectively) in the presence or absence of serine. We found that growth inhibition caused by serine could be reversed by over-expressing sdaA or glnA1 via plasmid complementation and by supplementing growth media with glutamine or alpha-ketoglutarate. However, we were unable to detect any genetic mutations that might explain these findings. Consequently, we postulated that BCG strains fail to adequately induce transcription of otherwise genetically-intact sdaA and glnA1 genes in response to serine-induced blockade of glutamine synthetase. To explore the cause of this deficient response, we turned to Rv3676, predicted to encode the cyclic AMP receptor protein, for which a number of mutations have been described in BCG strains. We noted that M. tuberculosis can utilize glucose, unlike BCG strains, but that BCG strains complemented with wild-type Rv3676 are able to consume glucose in vitro. Additionally, plasmid complementation of BCG strains with Rv3676 reversed the growth inhibition caused by serine. Together, these results suggest that mutations in the Rv3676 global regulator gene in BCG strains have resulted in impaired glucose utilization by BCG strains, indirectly impairing sensing of nitrogen status, as measured by serine-associated growth inhibition. The potential implications of this series of metabolic defects for virulence and persistence of the organism in the vaccinated host are discussed. Concretely, we hypothesized that BCG's growth defect in high serine is related to flaws in nitrogen metabolism, or its regulation.</description><creator>Carranza, Laura.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><title>Studies in metabolic defects of BCG strains</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Laura Carranza, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322d55t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zw822</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20ss76x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background. Studies of recognition of depression in elderly (aged 65 or more) medical inpatients showed low recognition of depression by attending physicians. However, few studies have compared different measures of recognition of depression. Objectives. To evaluate the validity of four recognition indicators and a global measure of recognition against a diagnosis of depression and the effect of patient characteristics on recognition of depression. Methods. In a cohort of 264 medical inpatients 65 years and over (115 with major or minor depression, 78 with no depression), using data from two previous studies, sensitivities, specificities, and diagnostic odds ratios (DOR) of four indicators of recognition (Diagnosis, Symptoms, Treatment and Referral) and a global measure of recognition (any of the four indicators) were calculated. Stratified analysis was conducted to assess recognition by age, gender, history of depression, antidepressant use before admission, severity of depression, comorbidity, duration of hospitalization, disability and hospital of admission. The associations of patient characteristics with recognition were described among patients with major or minor depression using multiple logistic regression. Results. Less than half of the patients were recognized according to the global measure of recognition. The indicator with the highest sensitivity was Treatment (27.8%, 95% CI: 20.0-37.0), while the indicator with the best specificity was Diagnosis (96.6%, 95% CI:91.9-98.7). The unadjusted DOR of global recognition was 2.6 (95% CI: 1.5, 4.4). Comorbidity, severity of depression, history of depression, duration of hospitalization, antidepressant use before admission and hospital of admission were significantly associated with global recognition. Conclusion. Recognition of depression in elderly medical inpatients is low. Identifying factors that hinder recognition may guide interventions aimed at improving diagnosis and treatment of depression in elderly medical inpatients.</description><creator>Cepoiu, Monica Elena.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Psychology, Clinical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Gerontology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Epidemiology.</subject><title>Recognition of depression in elderly medical inpatients</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Monica Elena Cepoiu, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059c773j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20ss76x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hc50j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Research suggests that athletes are at greater risk of disordered eating than their non-athletic counterparts. However this literature is limited primarily to female, college-aged populations. The objectives of this study were to develop and validate a screening tool (the Questionnaire of Eating Attitudes and Behaviors, Q-EAB) designed to assess disordered eating attitudes and behaviors in male and female athletes and to estimate the prevalence of disordered eating in a sample of Masters Athletes. A sample of 63 females and 48 males (mean age = 45.4+/-6.6 years, range = 35-65) completed a series of 6 eating questionnaires online as well as three 24 hour dietary and activity recalls. Female and non-elite athletes showed significantly greater disordered eating attitudes and behaviors than male and elite athletes respectively. Results indicated that the Q-EAB correlated to the five standard questionnaires. We conclude that the QEAB may be an effective screening tool for disordered eating in athletes.</description><creator>Caldwell, Tristaca K.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Athletes -- Nutrition.</subject><title>Development and validation of a screening tool for disordered eating in athletes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Tristaca K. Caldwell, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d455v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hc50j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67jr47q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The folding and assembly of proteins in the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) lumen and membrane are monitored by ER quality control (ERQC) mechanisms. This thesis focuses on two elements of ERQC: the unfolded protein response (UPR) and ER-associated degradation (ERAD), essential processes that prevent the accumulation of misfolded proteins in the cell. The mechanisms of both are well studied but only partially characterized and additional pathways are conjectured to exist. We have created the ERQC database that contains protein interactions, gene expression data, sub-cellular localization and orthologies for all genes involved in the UPR and ERAD. Using this highly curated database, we have built a probabilistic protein interaction model that integrates this data in a statistically coherent fashion. The model allows us to both predict a set of proteins likely to be involved in these processes and to describe their likely roles therein.</description><creator>Calafell, Sara J.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>A curated database and probabilistic model of endoplasmic reticulum quality control /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Sara J. Calafell, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v341m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jr47q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qs215</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The importance of developing relevant ovarian cancer models led us to test the applicability of a system comprised of epithelial ovarian cancer cell lines. The high frequency of loss of heterozygosity (LOH) and rearrangements of chromosome 17 in ovarian tumors provide evidence of a role of chromosome 17 genes in ovarian tumorigenesis. Oligonucleotide microarray expression analysis was applied to assess the expression profiles of 864 probe sets that map to chromosome 17. The TOV112D ovarian cancer cell line, a spontaneously immortalized and tumorigenic ovarian cancer cell line derived from an endometrioid histopathological subtype, which has been shown to exhibit LOH of chromosome 17, was used as a model to identify candidate genes based on Affymetrix expression microarray analyses in comparative analysis with three primary cultures derived from normal ovarian surface epithelium (NOSE). Two-way comparative analyses identified 81 probe sets, representing 64 differentially expressed genes, which exhibited at least a three-fold difference in expression relative to the mean of NOSE samples. The expression of these 64 candidate genes was investigated by microarray analysis in 31 fresh solid malignant ovarian tumors of different histopathologies, six ovarian tumors of borderline pathology, 32 primary cultures of ovarian tumors, 28 primary cultures of malignant ovarian ascites, and 16 NOSE samples. The chromosome 17 expression profile of TOV112D monolayer was compared with this cell line grown as a three-dimensional spheroid, solid tumors and monolayer cultures of these tumors from intraperitoneal and subcutaneous injection into nude mice. The expression profiles of selected candidates were validated by RT-PCR. About 63% of the candidates overexpressed at least three-fold relative to TOV112D were also overexpressed in some of the solid malignant ovarian tumors, and about 91% of the candidates that were underexpressed at least three-fold in TOV112D were also underexpressed in some of these tumors. The same differential pattern of gene expression of candidates was also observed in primary cultures of ovarian tumors and ovarian ascites, however, the effect in primary cultures was reduced. These results indicate that TOV112D, representing a spontaneously immortalized long-term passage, was more representative of solid ovarian tumors compared with the primary cultures. Growth conditions showed little impact on the expression profile of candidates when TOV112D was grown in different culture environments such as in vitro monolayer or mouse tumor xenograft. The finding that TOV112D identified differentially expressed genes in ovarian tumor samples regardless of histopathological subtype indicates that it is a useful model, not only to study the endometrioid subtype, but also serous and clear cell subtypes of epithelial ovarian cancer. Comparison of the expression profiles of our candidate genes identified by microarray analysis with published reports revealed that eight genes (ACACA, SFRS2, CCL2, CSF3, IGFBP4, KRT19, ITGA3, and TIMP2) were previously implicated in ovarian cancer, and 23 including MAC30 and TBX2 were implicated in tumorigenesis of other types of cancers. The use of long-term ovarian cancer cultures provides scientists with a model to study candidate genes, some of which may prove important for early detection or represent targets for the development of new ovarian cancer treatments.</description><creator>Breznan, Anna Devorah.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Oligonucleotide microarray analysis of chromosome 17 gene expression in a model human epithelial ovarian cancer cell line, TOV112D, and in epithelial ovarian tumors and ovarian malignant ascites</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Anna Devorah Breznan, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dc776.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qs215</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qs22f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The courtship behavior of the brown garden snail, Cantareus aspersus , includes a bizarre component where one snail attempts to pierce its mating partner with a sharp, calcareous dart that is covered with mucus. In vitro, the mucus causes conformational changes to the reproductive tract causing sperm to be stored rather than digested. In addition, successful dart shooters have an increased relative paternity compared to unsuccessful shooters. I have tested whether this increased paternity is caused by the mucus delivered on the dart or by the mechanical action of the dart. Mating trials were conducted using dartless and glandless snails, where a future mother was mated to two different potential fathers, receiving an injection of mucus with one mating, and an injection of saline with the second mating. The fathers accompanied by the mucus injection sired significantly more offspring than the fathers accompanied by the saline injection. I conclude that the mucus carried on the dart is responsible for increased paternity levels in Cantareus aspersus.</description><creator>Blanchard, Katrina C.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Brown garden snail -- Reproduction.</subject><subject>Brown garden snail -- Sexual behavior.</subject><title>The mechanism of the dart's influence on paternity in the snail, Cantareus aspersus /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Katrina C. Blanchard, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881m26g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qs22f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t214x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study examined the peak pressures and pressure patterns in the skate boot of hockey players during the backward cross-over stride. Fifteen flexible piezo-resistive pressure sensors (1.2 x 1.1 x 0.2cm thick) were placed on the plantar, dorsal, medial, and lateral surfaces of each foot for eight varsity level hockey players (mean +/- SD: height (m) = 1.80 +/- 0.07, weight (kg) = 87 +/- 0.06) and eight recreational hockey players (mean +/- SD: height = 1.76 (m) +/- 0.06, weight (kg) = 82 +/- 0.07). The strides were cut and the data was processed according to ability group and cross-over direction. The results demonstrated significant differences between groups in average speed, and in peak pressures on the medial and lateral surfaces of the foot (p≤0.05). The results also indicated a significant difference on the plantar surface of the foot when comparing cross-over directions (p≤0.05).</description><creator>Broad, Nicholas R.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Skating -- Physiological aspects.</subject><subject>Hockey players.</subject><title>A comparison between elite and recreational skaters' foot pressure patterns during backward cross-overs /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Nicholas R. Broad, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042t434.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t214x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tm24j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main goal of this research was to explore the use of benchmarking in the dairy industry. This includes descriptions of the various sectors in North America where benchmarking has been used successfully on a continuous basis or in research. Benchmarking methods that are currently used in the Quebec dairy industry are examined. An improvement to such methods is proposed through the use of visualization, coupled with interactivity, and with a focus on adaptability and usage. The advantages of such an interactive tool are discussed in light of on-farm decision-making, and a further use of visual slider applications is described to help with parameters of known economic importance.</description><creator>Boda, Gayatri.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Dairy farming -- Decision making.</subject><subject>Information storage and retrieval systems -- Dairy farming.</subject><subject>Benchmarking (Management)</subject><title>Benchmarking dairy information using interactive visualization for dairy farm decision making</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Gayatri Boda, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h229k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tm24j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k35694774</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Lipase was partially purified from the viscera of grey mullet ( Mugil cephalus) by ammonium sulfate fractionation, simultaneous desalting, and concentration via ultrafiltration and then affinity chromatography on EAH-Sepharose 4B. The partially purified extract was characterized using p-nitrophenyl palmitate (rho-NPP) as substrate. Grey mullet lipase was active within the pH range of 7-10, with an optimum pH of 8.0, and was stable from pH 4-10. The enzyme was active within the temperature range of 20°C and 60°C, and exhibited an optimum for the hydrolysis of rho-NPP at 50°C. The enzyme was stable between 10-50°C, beyond which it lost activity progressively. At 50°C there was ca. 50% residual activity after 60 min incubation. However at 60°C, there was 22%, 20% and 0% remaining activity after 10, 30 and 60 min incubation respectively. Based on the temperature activity data, the activation energy for the hydrolysis of rho-NPP was calculated as 1.94 kcal/mol (8.15 kJ/mol). The rho-nitrophenyl esters of medium to long chain fatty acid (C10-C16) served as good substrates with the order of ease of hydrolysis as; rho-NP-palmitate &gt; rho-NP-myristate &gt; rho-NP-caprate &gt; rho-NP-caproate &gt; rho-NP-butyrate &gt; rho-NP-acetate. The Km' and Vmax for the hydrolysis of rho-NPP were 0.22 mM and 20 mumol min-1 mg-1 , respectively. The hydrolytic activity of the lipase was enhanced by Mg2+, Mn2+, NaN3, and EDTA, but strongly inhibited by Hg2+, and Cu2+. PMSF (1 mM), Ca2+ (1 mM and 10 mM) had no effect on grey mullet lipase activity. Lower concentrations (25-10% v/v) of water-miscible organic solvents (dimethyl sulfoxide, dimethyl formamide, iso-propanol, and methanol) had negligible effect on the activity of the lipase while higher concentrations (&gt;50% v/v) completely inhibited the enzyme. The grey mullet lipase was remarkably stable in water-immiscible organic solvents (benzene, toluene, hexane, heptane, and isooctane). The water-immiscible solvents also activated the enzyme with hexane giving the most activation. Lower concentrations of trihydroxylated bile salts (sodium taurocholate, and sodium cholate) were more potent activators than the dihydroxylated bile salt (sodium deoxycholate). Sodium dodecyl sulfate at 1 mM, and Tween 80RTM at 1% had 6% and 12% stimulatory effect on the activity of the enzyme respectively, while 1% and 0.5% Triton RTM X-100 caused 67% and 40% inhibition, respectively.</description><creator>Aryee, Alberta Naa Ayeley.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Lipase -- Separation.</subject><subject>Gray mullets.</subject><title>Extraction, partial purification and characterization of the lipase fraction from the viscera of grey mullet (Mugil cephalus)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Alberta Naa Ayeley Aryee, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r9674009.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k35694774</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m1978</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although an extensive body of literature exists describing the properties of cells found in the primate vestibular nuclei (VN), the rat vestibular nuclei have not been explored in a comparable manner in order to allow for meaningful comparisons. Previous single-unit experiments in rat VN did not track eye movements and were performed in anesthetized or paralyzed preparations. This study characterizes the properties of vestibular-related cells in awake, behaving rats, using standard single-unit methodology, and video oculography to monitor eye movements, thus providing the first description that is comparable to the primate literature. Male, Long-Evans rats were head restrained and sinusoidally rotated at frequencies ranging from 0.1-1.0Hz, reaching a maximum velocity of 100 deg/sec. Eye position sensitivity was assessed by recording cell activity as the rat fixated at different locations. We show the presence of cells that are sensitive only to vestibular stimulation, equivalent to vestibular-only cells in primates. These cells have no eye sensitivity, and show a moderate increase in head velocity sensitivity with increasing stimulus frequency. Additionally, we show the presence of cells with eye movement-related sensitivities that bear a close resemblance to primate eye-head neurons. These results suggest that the rat vestibular nuclei may contain a similar cross section of cells as those found in the primate vestibular nuclei. These results shed light on the type of information in the vestibular nuclei that is available for other upstream systems, and is particularly relevant to spatial orientation, which has been shown to depend on vestibular input.</description><creator>Andrei, Ariana R.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Firing characteristics of central vestibular neurons in response to angular rotation in the head-restrained rat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Ariana R. Andrei, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gd310.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m1978</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s4655h00b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background. The Response Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumours (RECIST) assess the efficacy of new therapies in clinical trials of solid tumours but not of lymphoma. These criteria, with some modifications, could replace the International Workshop Classification (IWC) for assessing efficacy in lymphoma. A lymphoma-adapted version of RECIST (LAR) would be simpler to apply than the IWC criteria and allow efficacy assessment to be standardized across clinical trials. Methods. RECIST was modified to apply to the unique features of lymphoma. Using data from three phase II lymphoma trials (n=115), the clinical qualities of this modified scale were studied. Face, content and construct validity, and responsiveness were considered. Content validity was measured qualitatively using a pre-existing tool. Construct validity was measured using conventional agreement statistics. Responsiveness was evaluated using several responsiveness statistics. Results. Face and content validity demonstrated that the LAR has some advantages over the IWC. Measures of construct validity between the LAR and IWC indicated high agreement. There is a moderate to high responsiveness for both the LAR and IWC. Conclusion. Since the LAR is simpler to apply and yields near identical tumour response measures as the IWC, as well as similar responsiveness, it should be studied further as a tool to assess treatment response in lymphoma.</description><creator>Assouline, Sarit.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Epidemiology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Validity and responsiveness of an adapted version of RECIST (Response-Evaluation Criteria in Solid Tumours) to assess response in non-Hodgkin's lymphoma and Hodgkin's disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Sarit Assouline, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b3855.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655h00b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:th83kz59h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Despite significant progress in the field of organic chemistry, the asymmetric formation of all-carbon quaternary centers still represents a considerable challenge. Our group previously reported the stereocontrolled generation and alkylation of alpha,alpha-disubstituted amide enolates to form quaternary centers. This reaction takes place via the reduction of bicyclic alpha,alpha-dialkylated alpha-thioglycolate lactams using one-electron transfer reagents. This method suffered from several limitations to practicality, thus this research project has focused on the development of a second-generation chiral auxiliary system which would overcome the first generation auxiliary shortcomings. The design and synthesis of a new chiral auxiliary system is described. The design is modular and allows the auxiliary to be synthesized in a few shorts steps from commercially available materials. Alkylation of the new auxiliary, reductive enolization and the subsequent final alkylation to form quaternary centers is achieved with high levels of stereocontrol for both enolate intermediates. Two sets of conditions are described to cleave the auxiliary and liberate the products containing the quaternary centers. The methodology that has been developed is versatile and represents a practical solution to the enantioselective formation of quaternary carbon centers. It also overcomes all the shortcomings of the first generation.</description><creator>Arpin, Azélie.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Development of a practical method for the asymmetric synthesis of quaternary carbon centers : a second generation auxiliary</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Azélie Arpin, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311p67k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83kz59h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892b125</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, a study was undertaken on the premise that the world population living in urban centers is expected to increase from 3.8 billion to 5.2 billion, from 2005 to 2025, representing 54% and 65% of total world population, respectively. The urban population (UP) growth will produce remarkable amounts of urban food waste (UFW) that will add more pressure on already overloaded municipal solid waste (MSW) management systems of cities. This problem is more serious in countries experiencing major economic growth such as China where UP is expected to increase from 44% to 66% of the total country population, from 1995 to 2025. Asia produces the largest amount of UFW, which is expected to increase from 251 million ton to 418 million ton (45% to 53% of total world UFW) from 1995 to 2025. On site treatment of UFW along with a limited movement of world population from rural to urban areas are suggested to reduce pressure on MS W management system for the upcoming decades. In this thesis, a project was also undertaken to develop compost recipes for urban center such as downtown Montreal. Monthly (June to August) average residential FW production was found to 0.61 (+/-0.13) kg capita-1 day-1 and that of a restaurant was found to be 0.56 (+/-0.23) kg customer-1 day-1. From trial tests, the best compost recipes mixed 8.9 kg, 8.6 kg and 7.8 kg of UFW for every kg of wheat straw, hay and wood shaving, on a wet mass basis. However, quantity and characteristics of FW vary from one month to another; therefore, regular adjustment of compost recipe is recommended. When using wood shavings as bulking agent, it is strongly recommended to correct the acid pH.</description><creator>Adhikari, Bijaya K.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Compost -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Metropolitan Area.</subject><title>Urban food waste composting</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Bijaya K. Adhikari, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n143h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892b125</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074v373</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Despite being abundant in the earth's crust, the concentration of Fe in many oceanic regions is so low that it is limiting to the growth of photosynthetic plankton. Heterotrophic bacteria play key roles in the oceanic cycling of carbon and nutrients, but it is unclear whether they can be Fe-deficient in nature, or what possible effects Fe-deficiency might have on their ecology and physiology. In chapter 1, I investigated the response of a natural bacterial community to a mesoscale Fe-enrichment experiment in the northeast subarctic Pacific. The addition of Fe to surface waters caused a rapid stimulation of bacterial growth and production, and induced the organic Fe uptake systems of bacteria. These findings suggest that bacteria responded directly to increased Fe availability, and may be Fe-deficient in situ. In chapter 2, I examined the effects of Fe-deficiency on the coupled processes of carbon catabolism and adenosine triphosphate (ATP) production in cultures of the marine bacterium Pseudoalteromonas haloplanktis. In Fe-limited cells, Fe-dependent oxidative pathways of ATP production were downregulated, leading to an intracellular energy deficit. Thus, by altering carbon metabolism and energy acquisition of heterotrophic bacteria, Fe may affect the cycling of carbon in parts of the sea.</description><creator>Adly, Carol.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Iron -- Physiological transport.</subject><subject>Heterotrophic bacteria.</subject><subject>Marine bacteria.</subject><subject>Iron -- Metabolism.</subject><title>The role of iron in the ecology and physiology of marine bacteria /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Carol Adly, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79407x55n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074v373</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97kq740</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Biomarkers of Cervical Cancer Risk (BCCR) case-control study was designed to address the role of human leukocyte antigen (HLA) alleles as cofactors in the development of high-grade cervical intraepithelial neoplasia (HG-CIN). Cases were women with histologically-confirmed HG-CIN attending colposcopy clinics and controls were women from outpatient clinics with normal cytological screening smears. Cervical specimens were submitted for both human papilloma virus (HPV) testing and HLA genotyping. Risk ratios were generated using logistic regression modelling. This analysis includes 381 case and 884 control subjects, mainly of French-Canadian descent. The B7-DRB1*1501-DQB1*0602 haplotype was associated with a 41 % reduction in risk of HG-CIN [relative risk = 0.59; 95 % confidence interval = 0.36-0.96], and an 83 % reduction in risk for HPV 16 or HPV 18-positive subjects. Possession of the B7-DRB1*1501-DQB1*0602 haplotype was moderately protective, and may be associated with slowing of disease progression to HG-CIN in women who are carriers of common oncogenic HPV types.</description><creator>Ades, Steven.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Epidemiology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Human leukocyte antigen polymorphisms and risk of cervical neoplasia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Steven Ades, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666480p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kq740</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30pt02k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The generalized least squares (GLS) method for phylogenetic inference assumes that errors in observed distances have an approximately Gaussian distribution. GLS has not been widely used nor properly evaluated because of computational difficulties. We examine issues relating to the implementation of GLS. Different estimates for the covariance matrix are examined. We found that the matrix is often ill-conditioned. Methods for solving the ill-conditioned unconstrained least squares problem are compared in terms of stability and efficiency. We conclude that the normal equations method, with a modified covariance matrix, performs best. Versions of the nonnegative constrained GLS method are discussed, implemented, and evaluated. Curiously, the GLS method was less accurate than the simpler weighted least squares method. We compare Maximum Likelihood (ML) with least squares methods for selecting trees and we notice that GLS correlates well with ML on trees close to the true tree.</description><creator>Abu Safia, Ahmed.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Phylogenetic inference by generalized least squares : computational aspects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Ahmed Abu Safia, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fp29x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pt02k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945r12f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Quebec unions negotiating with federal, provincial, or municipal governments were studied for two outcomes relevant to women’s social welfare: women’s elective status, and collective agreement provisions favourable to women workers. Multiple analytic methods explored two aims: to develop a model of unions’ interaction with women members, and to derive typologies of unions. Union typologies derived from cluster analysis show that unions ranking high on those measures relevant to women’s welfare show greatest similarity on the following indices: union democracy, educational programs, organizational responsiveness to women members, policy toward political and social change, internal union women’s committees, and percentage of women. Path analytic results reveal that women’s committees are a more effective intra-union strategy than is an electoral strategy; and that progressive union policy is necessary but not sufficient for women to achieve greater equality in collective barganing outcomes. The path model explained 55% of variance in collective agreement outcomes.</description><description>Cette etude porte sur deux questions relatives a la condition de la femme dans les syndicats qui, au Quebec, negocient avec les gouvernements federal, provincial et municipal: la representation de la femme dans les postes elus et les dispositions des conventions collectives favorables aux travailleuses. Differentes methodes d’analyses statistiques ont utilisees afin d’etablir un modele d’interaction entre les syndicats et leurs syndiquees ainsi que differentes typologies de syndicats. Ces typologies, derivees des analyses en grappes (cluster analysis), demontrent que les syndicats qui ont obtenu des resultats eleves dans les questions reliees a la la condition feminine ont Ie plus haut degre de similitude dans les indices suivants: democratie syndicale, programmes de formation, ouverture du syndicat face au femmes membres, position syndicale en regard des changements sociaux et politiques, comites internes sur la condition feminine, et proportion de femmes membres. Une illustration graphique selon Ie path analysis revele que les comites intrasyndicaux sur la condition feminine donnent de meilleurs resultats qU’une strategie electorale. Ces analyses indiquent egalement qu’une ideologie syndicale progressiste est necessaire mais non suffisante pour permettre aux femmes d’atteindre une plus grande egalite dans les conventions collectives. Ce modele d’analyse (path model) explique 55% des variances dans les dispositions des conventions collectives.</description><creator>Heppner, Barbara</creator><contributor>Neysmith, Sheila (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1984</date><subject>Women labor union members -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Sociology, Industrial and Labor Relations.</subject><title>Women in public sector unions in Québec : organizing for equality</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pt03v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945r12f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773w002</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>As epic was considered a culturally comprehensive genre, so Spenser's Faerie Queene and Milton's Paradise Lost provide an effective locus for inquiry into literary representations of body marks in the Renaissance, and hence of the body itself. While grounded on central principles of Renaissance poetics such as delightful teaching, utpictura poesis, and catharsis, Spenser's and Milton's graphic accounts of wounds and diverse other types of body marks show corporeality can have positive import for the soul and heroic identity, just as they are shaped in part by bodily experienees. This dissertation thus reconsiders the widespread assumption that early moderns primarily viewed the body as a subservient yet sometimes threatening container for the soul....</description><description>Une épopée fut culturellement considérée comme un vaste genre: The FaerieQueene, et Paradise Lost, de Spenser et Milton, sont pertinents pour l'étude desreprésentations littéraires des marques corporelles durant la Renaissance, et du corps.Basées sur les principes de la poésie de l'époque, comme l'enseignement délicieux, utpictura poesis, et la catharsis, les explications graphiques de blessures et autres cicatricesde Spenser et Milton montrent que la matérialité peut avoir une portée positive sur l'âmeet l'identité héroïque: elles sont formées par des expériences corporelles.</description><creator>Frey, Christopher Lorne</creator><contributor>Borris, Kenneth (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2006</date><subject>Milton, John, 1608-1674. Paradise lost.</subject><subject>Spenser, Edmund, 1552?-1599. Faerie queene.</subject><subject>Human body in literature.</subject><title>Body marks in early modern English epic : Spenser's Faerie Queene and Milton's Paradise Lost</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s5109.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773w002</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj430497m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Saartje BaartJnan was a South African woman who signed a contract in 1810 that effectively made her the property of two white men wishing to exhibit her in Europe because of the shape and color of her body. In this text 1 examine two very different categories of representations of Baartman. First, I discuss images that were produced during Baartman's lifetime that discursively transformed her from a black woman with an identity into a pathologized body known as the Hottentot Venus, and second, I discuss the contemporary black female artists who are producing art inspired by Baartman in order to problematize the racist and sexist assumptions that have been inscribed on the black female body. My research encompasses important scholarship done by white feminist art historians, as well as that by black feminist theorists, and my thoughts on this subject have also been informed tremendously by work that has been done on the visual culture of slavery and on racist stereotypes by post-colonial scholars.</description><creator>Skelly, Julia</creator><contributor>Nelson, Charmaine  (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2006</date><subject>Women artists, Black.</subject><subject>Baartman, Sarah.</subject><subject>Women, Black, in art.</subject><title>No strangers to beauty : contemporary black female artists, Saartje Baartman and the Hottentot Venus body</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g306w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430497m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52j839s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this study we shall deal with the great affirmation of the Bible that the purpose of God which is manifested in the history of Israel is the same purpose on which the entire creation is founded. Being a redemptive purpose, it is conceived not as an abstract, immovable design, but as effective in itself, identical with the creator’s word striving for fulfillmnt in the world. Jesus fulfills this all-inclusive purpose as the Messiah at Israel, bringing the chosen people of God, and in principle the entire cosmos, to a final crisis wherein divine judgment is enacted. on human sin and the new humanity is brought into being. The new hu:aanity, inaugurated in Christ’s fulfillment of the creator’s purpose, is an eschatological concept and otters man the possibility of becoming a complete man in Jesus Christ. Man’s response to this offer involves the recognition of human solidarity, even cosmic solidarity, for, by divine intent, he lives not in isolation, but in a network of relationships to the rest of creation.</description><creator>Suld, Henry</creator><contributor>Caird, George B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1961</date><subject>Religion, General.</subject><subject>Jesus Christ.</subject><title>The relation of the doctrine of creation to the person of Jesus Christ in New Testament theology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dc79r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j839s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn3011720</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis I argue against the contemporary scholars of Thomas Hobbes who claim that Hobbes's theory of language was an anticipation of modern semantic theories of truth.  I claim that a more valuable comparison is to the logical positivism of A.J. Ayer. In seeing Hobbes's theory of language as an anticipation of twentieth-century logical positivism, it becomes evident that the emphasis should be not on Hobbes's theory of language only, but on the idea that Ayer and Hobbes share in a philosophy, or science, consisting of both empirical observation and knowledge that is made necessary and true (and thereby made useful) by propositional language and deductive science.  The elements of logical positivism in Hobbes's work also have much bearing on his political theory.  I argue that the state of nature is a condition in which there can be no certain, deductive reasoning, and that science and certain knowledge is therefore possible only in the commonwealth once the covenant has taken place and a sovereign has been erected.  In response to the objection that reason does operate in the state of nature through the laws of nature (which Hobbes claims are precepts of reason), I argue that the laws of nature should be reconceived as the hypotheses, or hypothetical propositions, of nature because the certainty of the laws requires that some conditions be fulfilled and needs the consensus of all men involved in the covenant. Thus, Hobbes's political theory consists of both the empirical knowledge of man in the state of nature, expressed as hypotheses, and man's capacity to turn his hypotheses into certain and necessary propositions through the willing of the covenant and the creation of a sovereign who maintains objective control over the definitions and laws of the state.  In this interpretation of Hobbes's theory of language and politics, the commonwealth is the first necessity for the generation of any scientific knowledge; however, it is not a permanently guaranteed condition.   Therefore, the artifice of politics and necessary, certain reasoning must be acknowledged insofar as the commonwealth exists only for our own preservation and to the end of eradicating the uncertainty of the natural condition. </description><description>Dans cette thèse, je soutiens contre les savants contemporains de Thomas Hobbes qui prétendent que la théorie de Hobbes de la langue était une anticipation des théories modernes sémantique de la vérité. J'alléges qu'une comparaison avec le positivisme logique de AJ Ayer est plus utile.  En voyant la théorie de Hobbes de la langue comme une anticipation du positivisme logique du XXe siècle, il devient évident que l'accent devrait être mis non pas seulement sur la théorie de langue de Hobbes, mais sur l'idée que Ayer et Hobbes part de la philosophie, ou de la science, comprenant à la fois l'observation empirique et les connaissances qui est rendue nécessaire et vrai (et donc fait utile)  selon la langue propositionnelle et de la science déductive. Les éléments du positivisme logique dans le travail de Hobbes ont également beaucoup d'influence sur sa théorie politique. Je soutiens que l'état de nature est un état dans lequel il ne peut être certains raisonnement déductif, et que la science et certains connaissances sont donc possible que dans la république une fois l'alliance a eu lieu et un souverain a été érigé. En réponse à l'objection que la raison ne fonctionner pas dans l'état de nature par les lois de la nature (ce que Hobbes revendique sont les préceptes de la raison), je soutiens que les lois de la nature doit être repensée pour les hypothèses, ou des propositions hypothétiques, de la nature parce que la certitude des lois exige que certaines conditions soient remplies et les besoins du consensus de tous les hommes impliqués dans l'alliance.  Ainsi, la théorie politique de Hobbes consiste à la fois des connaissances empiriques de l'homme dans l'état de nature, exprimées sous forme d'hypothèses, et la capacité de l'homme de transfomer ces hypotheses en certaines propositions nécessaire par la volonté de l'alliance et la création d'un souverain qui maintient le contrôle l'objectif sur les définitions et les lois de l'Etat. Dans cette interprétation de la théorie de Hobbes de la langue et de la politique, la république est la première nécessité pour la génération des connaissances scientifiques, mais ce n'est pas une garantie d'un condition permanente. Par conséquent, l'artifice politique et nécessaire, le raisonnement de certains doit être reconnu dans la mesure où la république n'existe que pour notre propre préservation et à la fin de l'éradication de l'incertitude de la condition naturelle. </description><creator>Planinc, Emma</creator><contributor>Arash Abizadeh (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Political Science - General</subject><title>Let us make man: politics and logical positivism in the work of Thomas Hobbes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289j31m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn3011720</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ff365551v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette  thèse  aborde le problème de la conversion de données dans le système  numérique de résidus (Residue Number System - RNS). Le système RNS a été considéré comme un sujet intéressant par de nombreux chercheurs ces dernières années. Son importance découle de l'absence de la propagation de retenue entre ses unités de calcul. Ceci facilite la réalisation de circuits arithmétiques à grande vitesse et de faible puissance. Cet avantage est d'une importance primordiale dans les processeurs embarqués, en particulier ceux qu'on retrouve dans les appareils portables, pour lesquels la consummation d'énergie est l'aspect le plus critique de la conception. Cependant, le traitement supplémentaire introduit par les circuits de conversion de données décourage l'utilisation du RNS au niveau des applications. Dans cette thèse, nous cherchons des schémes efficaces pour la conversion de la représentation conventionnelle à la représentation RNS et vice-versa. La représentation conventionnelle peut être sous la forme d'un signal analogique en temps continu où d'un signal échantillonné numérique représenté en format binaire. Nous présentons quelques algorithmes actuellement disponibles et les systèmes de conversion associés lorsque le signal est sous unereprésentation binaire. Dans notre contribution à ce domaine de recherche, nous proposons trois astuces différentes pour la conversion lorsqu'une interaction avec le monde analogique réel est nécessaire. Nous dévelopons deux systèmes efficaces pour la conversion directe du domaine analogique à RNS. Un autre système efficace pour la conversion directe de RNS à analogique est également proposé. La performance et l'efficacité de ces convertisseurs sont mises en évidence et analysées. Les schémas proposés sont destinés à encourager l'utilisation du RNS dans diverses applications dans l'avenir.</description><description>This thesis tackles the problem of data conversion in the Residue Number System (RNS). The RNS has been considered as an interesting theoretical topic for researchers in recent years. Its importance stems from the absence of carry propagation between its arithmetic units. This facilitates the realization of high-speed, low-power arithmetic. This advantage is of paramount importance in embedded processors, especially those found in portable devices, for which power consumption is the most critical aspect of the design. However, the overhead introduced by the data conversion circuits discourages the use of RNS at the applications. In this thesis, we aim at developing efficient schemes for the conversion from the conventional representation to the RNS representation and vice versa. The conventional representation can be in the form of an analog continuous-time signal or a digital signal represented in binary format. We present some of the currently available algorithms and schemes of conversion when the signal is in binary representation. As a contribution to this field of research, we propose three different schemes for direct conversion when interaction with the real analog world is required. We first develop two efficient schemes for direct analog-to-residue conversion. Another efficient scheme for direct residue-to-analog conversion is also proposed. The performance and the efficiency of theses converters are demonstrated and analyzed. The proposed schemes are aimed to encourage the utilization of RNS in various real-time and practical applications in the future.</description><creator>Abdelfattah, Omar</creator><contributor>Andraws Swidan (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Zeljko Zilic (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Data conversion in residue number system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859f962.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff365551v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311p68v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:21:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse explore les questions applicables à la navigation et au survol de la mer territoriale par les aéronefs militaires embarqués sur les navires de guerre, désignés sous le vocable « organic aircraft », librement traduit par l'expression « aéronefs intégrés ».  Un survol des zones maritimes promulguées par le droit de la mer, telles que mises en œuvre en droit canadien révèle une préférence marquée pour l'imposition de l'autorité de l'État côtier sur de vastes étendues maritimes, au détriment possible de la liberté de navigation défendue par les puissances maritimes. L'utilisation des aéronefs intégrés est menacée par un cadre juridique ne tenant pas compte de la relation symbiotique entre le navire et l'aéronef qu'il transporte. Les régimes de passage ne permettent pas le survol là où on en aurait le plus besoin. Les faiblesses dans l'interprétation généreuse de la liberté de navigation par les commentateurs associés à la Marine des États-Unis et une préoccupation accrue quant à la sécurité des côtes ne sont pas susceptibles de mener à une évolution du cadre juridique qui pourrait garantir une liberté de survol adéquate pour les aéronefs intégrés.  </description><description>This thesis explores the issues of navigation and overflight of the territorial sea by military aircraft operating from warships, known as organic aircraft.  A review of maritime zones in the Law of the Sea from a Canadian perspective reveals a preference for the exercise of coastal State jurisdiction on significant ocean space, to the potential detriment of freedom of navigation advocated by maritime powers. Current uses of organic air are challenged by a legal framework which does not take into account the unique relationship between ships and the aircraft they carry. The regimes of passage do not allow overflight when it would be most needed. The weaknesses in the generous interpretation of navigational rights advocated by commentators associated with the US Navy and a climate of significant preoccupation towards security of the coasts are not conductive to any changes in the legal framework that would secure special freedoms of overflight for organic aircraft. </description><creator>Pelletier, Martin</creator><contributor>Armand De Mestral (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>Overflight of organic aircraft and the territorial sea</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xc178.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311p68v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):26375</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>