<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:22:54Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):21025" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82k832f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the last two decades international terrorism has made international civil aviation one of its prime targets. While the aviation security conventions cover a variety of acts of terrorism against civil air transport they failed to adequately deal with terrorism at international airports. In direct response to the terrorist attacks that took place at Rome and Vienna international airports in December 1985, the international civil aviation community adopted under ICAO auspices the Montreal Protocol of 1988, a new legal instrument aimed at the control of terrorism at airports serving international civil aviation. The purpose of this thesis is to critically examine the Protocol in order to provide an answer to the question whether or not this legal instrument can be considered as an effective tool for the achievement of its main goal, the suppression of terrorism at international airports.</description><creator>Shavit, Uri</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Transportation.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>The Montreal protocol of February 24th, 1988 - a critical evaluation /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nc39w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k832f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vh82p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The fish processing industry is actively seeking for alternative methods of shelf life preservation and marketability of fresh fish, while at the same time economizing on energy costs. Two methods which fulfill both objectives are modified atmosphere packaging (MAP) and glucose oxidase (GOX)/Glucose dipping solutions. MAP is the packaging of perishable products in an atmosphere other than that of air and is used for the shelf life extension of beef, pork, fruits, vegetables and bakery products. GOX, either alone or in conjunction with MAP has the potential for shelf life extension of fresh fish. The objectives of this study were to determine the combined effect of glucose oxidase/glucose or gluconic acid dipping solutions and modified atmosphere packaging in conjunction with refrigeration on the shelf life extension of mackerel and cod. This study has shown that the shelf life of fresh fish can be extended through the combined use of MAP/dipping solutions and refrigeration. This novel process of "dipping" in GOX solution in conjunction with modified atmosphere packaging (MAP) will have a significant effect in the area of fish hygiene and will minimize fish losses incurred through spoilage.</description><creator>Lee, Yun-ae</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Fish as food -- Packaging.</subject><subject>Protective atmospheres.</subject><subject>Fish as food -- Preservation.</subject><title>Combined use of modified atmosphere packaging (MAP) and glucose (GOX) for shelf-life extension of fresh fish</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085m35s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vh82p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj236322v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis describes a stand-alone, unity power factor, current-regulated SPWM rectifier. The topology is based on the series connection of 3 single-phase, 4-valve rectifier bridges, which allows 2-state logic SPWM strategy to be used without interphase interference. The issues and problems of LdI$ sb{ rm dc}$/dt voltage and low harmonic waveform distortion are identified. Solutions are found by using a dc snubber circuit and a simple local notch filter feedback circuit which performs the dual function of stabilizing and active filtering. From the clarification given by this more expensive but less constrained topology, the stage is set for the next step in incorporating the lessons learnt here to the more economical topology based on the 6-valve, 3-phase parallel bridge, which requires a tri-state logic for PWM control when operating in the current-source configuration.</description><creator>Lujara, Nelson Kakuru</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Construction and test of a SPWM current source converter</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g1355.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236322v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jd472x540</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis deals with the non-linear dynamic time history analysis of a certain type of medium- and high-rise concentric braced frame designed according to the new National Building Code of Canada (1990) and CAN/CSA-S16.1-M89. The program DRAIN-2D was used to carry out the earthquake simulations of this structure. A number of recorded earthquakes was selected as the input of ground motions. A preliminary statistical study is attempted on the structural response to the ground motions. The design procedures proposed by the new design codes are evaluated. Some provisions of Clause 27 of the CAN/CSA-S16.1-M89 have been found inadequate in the light of the analysis described. Some revised procedures are proposed and then evaluated against those currently in use. The results are shown to provide improved designs.</description><creator>Lu, Feng</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Seismic response of concentrically braced frames meeting Canadian design criteria</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bm797.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd472x540</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65v9098</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study deals with Allied policy for postwar Germany during the Second World War (1941-1945) and the Allied occupation (1945-1949). It is shown that the ideological division and the conflicting objectives of the occupation powers led to a disintegration of cooperation between the occupation powers, and resulted in the division of Germany as an alternative settlement to the "German Problem". The evidence is based on the available government documents, eye-witness accounts, and secondary sources.</description><creator>Szanajda, Andrij</creator><date>1991</date><subject>German reunification question (1949-1990)</subject><subject>Germany -- History -- 1945-1955</subject><title>From cooperation to alternative settlement : the Allies and the "German problem", 1941-1949</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p5792.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65v9098</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x015t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examined the knowledge and processes that adults use to reason about moral dilemmas. Two contrasting analyses of moral reasons, Kohlberg's justice orientation and Gilligan's response orientation, were reviewed and criticized. From this a Moral Reasoning Grammar which formally characterizes the semantics of the justice and response moral orientations was developed. Specifically, the Moral Reasoning Grammar distinguished reasoning based on principles and their defense from reasoning based on narrative and social-interactive knowledge. The Moral Reasoning Grammar was applied to subjects' protocols to determine the extent to which these two orientations characterized subjects' verbal responses to moral problems. Application of the Moral Reasoning Grammar resulted in good coverage of subjects' verbalizations which reliably differentiated knowledge and processes used by subjects resolving moral problems from either a justice or response orientation. The justice orientation characterized the four male subjects' protocols and the response orientation characterized the four female protocols. The small sample precludes any generalization of this finding. The Moral Reasoning Grammar and results were discussed in terms of further psychological research, an expanded and more comprehensive philosophical approach to moral reasoning, and the potential educational implications.</description><creator>Keefer, Matthew Wilks</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Judgment (Ethics)</subject><subject>Reasoning</subject><title>Analysing justice and response orientations in moral reasoning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hq89q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x015t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:02870x022</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Basic education is a crucial, often underfunded component of national development. Theories based on basic needs both illustrate the links between education and other goals associated with the elimination of poverty and define the types of education needed to maximise these links and advance these goals. Third World progress towards basic educational goals, as measured by first level enrollment, literacy and resources available to education, has been slowed particularly as a result of economic pressures. Measures taken by international organisations to relieve these pressures have not adequately protected the poor; and in some cases have adversely affected the maintenance of systems of basic education. The World Bank, as the world's largest development organisation and as one concerned with economic adjustment, is changing its policies to adapt to this situation. (These changes are taking place in an institution noted for being more oriented to economic growth than to human needs.) There is, however, room for cautious optimism that trends within and without the Bank may converge to bring basic education to a higher place on the development agenda.</description><creator>Kaler, Amy</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Economic development -- Effect of education on</subject><subject>World Bank</subject><subject>Education -- Developing countries</subject><title>Basic education and the World Bank : crisis and response in the 1980s</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m528c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870x022</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d1016</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Electroosmotic dewatering of Bentonite suspensions under conditions of constant DC voltage and constant DC current was investigated experimentally in a column 5 cm in diameter. The suspensions were prepared with CaCl$ sb2$ in distilled water with concentrations up to 1 M. The initial solid content was between 9.1 wt% and 26 wt% and the initial bed height ranged from 1.0 cm to 5.2 cm. Constant voltages from 4.0 V to 8.0 V and constant currents from 90 mA to 110 mA were used. Electroosmosis removed 20-60% of the water with energy expenditures well below the energy required to vaporize the water. Higher voltages or currents removed more water. Removal rates were increased by the addition of CaCl$ sb2$. The lowest bed height (1 cm) gave the lowest energy of dewatering, but the final water removal was low. For constant voltage experiments with an initial field strength of 2.8 V/cm, bed heights around 2 cm gave the highest water removal. The initial solid content had little effect on the final solid content. The Helmholtz/Smoluchowski theory did not predict correctly the effects of electrolyte concentration, solid content and bed height on the rate of electroosmotic dewatering.</description><creator>Ju, Shuohui</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Electroosmotic dewatering of bentonite suspensions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g405t.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d1016</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21tg53f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Aedes aegypti pupae were exposed to cercariae of the digenean Plagiorchis noblei in order to assess the effects of infection on the spontaneous flying activity and reproductive success of surviving adults. Infections established primarily in the thorax and abdomen of the insects (mixed infections) or in the abdomen alone. In mixed infections, as few as one or two metacercariae in the thorax reduced the spontaneous flying time of females by almost half. Such infections also reduced total egg production, the number of ovarian cycles, fecundity per cycle, as well as fertility and life span of female hosts. The fertility and life span of males was similarly affected. Purely abdominal infections reduced the life span of males and females as well as the fertility of males, but only at high intensities. Such effects on adult behaviour, reproductive success and life span may augment the known lethal effects of the parasite.</description><creator>Kimoro, Charles Omuoyo</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Plagiorchiidae.</subject><subject>Aedes aegypti -- Reproduction.</subject><subject>Aedes aegypti -- Parasites.</subject><title>The effects of Plagiorchis noblei, Park, 1936 on the reproductive success and behaviour of adult Aedes aegypti /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268635f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21tg53f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451j715</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tissue-cultured shoots and plantlets usually have leaves with non-functional, open stomata and little epicuticular and cuticular wax, resulting in excess evapotranspiration after transplantation. Various strategies were evaluated to decrease ex vitro acclimatization difficulties for 'Silvan' blackberry, including transplanting unrooted shoots, increasing the medium agar concentration from 6 to 9 or 12 g/l and diluting the basal medium. Increased medium agar concentrations and medium dilution did not improve survival or growth. Stomatal function resumed sooner in new leaves of plantlets than shoots. High relative humidity ($&gt;$95%) and low light intensity (90 $ mu$mol s$ sp{-1}$ m$ sp{-2}$) negatively affected stomatal closure both on acclimatizing transplants and greenhouse-grown plants. Guard cells developed on leaves in vitro were physiologically active but had apparent anatomical abnormalities that inhibited closure. A rapid clearing and staining method was developed for examination of foliar morphology using intact in vitro blackberry (Rubus sp. 'Silvan') and strawberry (Fragaria x ananassa Duch. 'Totem') plantlets and sections of greenhouse-grown 'Silvan' and 'Totem' leaves. This method involved three steps: (1) removing the chlorophyll by autoclaving in 80% ethanol; (2) dissolution of the protoplasm using 5% NaOH at 80$ sp circ$C; (3) post-alkali treatment with 75% bleach (4.5% NaClO) at room temperature for tissue-cultured plantlets and at 55$ sp circ$C for greenhouse-grown leaves. Aqueous safranin (10 mg/l) was used for staining.</description><creator>Tisdall, Laurence</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Acclimatization (Plants)</subject><subject>Plant micropropagation.</subject><subject>Blackberries -- Propagation -- In vitro.</subject><title>Acclimatization of micropropagated 'Silvan' blackberry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88ch821.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451j715</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h702q754n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In order to determine the role of nutritional status as a predictor of mortality in patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD), 348 patients with severe airway obstruction were followed for 1 to 3 years. Baseline measurements were done on patients recruited for a clinical trial of negative pressure ventilation in severe COPD. When adjusted for the severity of disease, as assessed by the forced expiratory volume in one second (FEV$ sb1$) and the use of oxygen therapy, body mass index (BMI) was a significant predictor of mortality in the recruited group. The relative risk (RR) for BMI comparing the 25$ sp{ rm th}$ to the 75$ sp{ rm th}$ percentile was 1.86 (1.76, 1.97). Both BMI and triceps skinfold thickness (TSF) were the nutritional parameters which significantly predicted mortality in the subgroup of randomized patients when adjusted for the partial pressure of carbon dioxide in arterial blood (PaCO$ sb2$) and use of oxygen therapy. The RR's comparing the 25$ sp{ rm th}$ to the 75$ sp{ rm th}$ percentile for BMI and TSF respectively, were 2.09 (1.92, 2.27) and 1.80 (1.66, 1.96).</description><creator>Gibbons, Laurie</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Nutrition.</subject><title>Nutritional status as a predictor of mortality in severe chronic obstructive pulmonary disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cf437.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q754n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78td32t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Some recent work of Suvin (indebted to Merleau-Ponty's Phenomenologie de la perception) asserts that two fundamental aspects of the praxis of theatre spectatorship--the non-tactile, inactive physicality of the spectator, and her/his imaginative cognitive participation in the apperception of the performance text--might better be understood when examined with regard to the "apraxias," neurological disorders of purposive physical movement. This thesis follows up this line of thought in examining clinical material on apraxia, both temporally previous and subsequent to Merleau-Ponty's discussion. Additionally, it is contended that various paradigms in Bergson and within modern cognitive science (Edelman, Schacter) may be applied with some utility to the praxis of theatre spectatorship. This may lead to a better understanding of the mental participation of the spectator in the performance text as a modulation of present perception and past subjective experience. Such an understanding is compatible with a semiotic "encyclopedia" (Eco), possibly buttressing it with arguments extrapolated from neurology.</description><creator>Wood, Andrew</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Theater audiences</subject><subject>Apraxia</subject><subject>Theater -- Psychological aspects</subject><title>Theatre spectatorship and the "apraxia" problem</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930bz397.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78td32t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Languages, Literatures, and Cultures</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v692t755n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A model is presented to describe pp and pp scattering in the c.m.s. energy range from 5 Gev to 1.8 Tev. Although some attention is paid to properties of the differential cross section, the primary focus is on parametrizing the forward amplitude in a manner consistent with experimental measurements of the total cross section, the rho parameter, and the forward slope. The model is a hybrid, employing Regge Theory for energy dependence, dipole form factors for momentum transfer distributions, and impact parameter eikonalization is used to unitarize the amplitude. The model is first motivated, then the results of fits to data are presented, and finally it is compared to a model based on hard scattering of partons.</description><creator>Wall, Wolfe</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>A hybrid model of proton scattering /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687j683.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t755n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603qz68v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis, from a "locality studies" perspective, examines the impact of industrial restructuring and employment decline on the relationship between locality, gender and patriarchy at the household level in Windsor, a pulp and paper mill town in South-Eastern Quebec. A detailed questionnaire/survey was deployed in May and June 1987, during a period of massive reorganization and automation of production by Domtar Fine Paper Mill, the dominant local employer. The primary empirical focus of this work is on the household impacts of job losses, incurred directly or indirectly by this restructuring. Particular attention is paid to the relationship between gender, employment and income and how this relationship is manifested among the differing material circumstances of Windsor households, and to attempts to adapt to the socio-economic impacts of restructuring via self-conscious "coping strategies". A secondary focus is communal coping strategies aimed at combatting declining industrial employment. Findings indicate an exacerbation of economic polarization between economically stable households of the remaining Domtar employees and households enmeshed in unstable economic and employment conditions.</description><creator>Critchley, Jacques R. (Jacques Rigby)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Households -- Québec (Province) -- Economic aspects</subject><subject>Women -- Employment -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Paper industry workers -- Québec (Province)</subject><title>Employment, gender and household polarization in a single industry town : the social impacts of economic restructuring in Windsor, Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397946q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603qz68v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d56zx75v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This Master's thesis in creative writing consists of two parts: a novel and a critical study. The creative writing part is entitled La Cosworth. Carlos da Silva, the main character, seeks material goods to the detriment of his friends, family and happiness. He begins to decay simultaneously with his car and dies after it is completely destroyed in an accident. Product of his environment, he ceases to exist after he loses his car, which symbolizes his way of life and his existence. La genese de Carlos et de sa Cosworth precedes the creative writing part and shows the evolution of the novel. Todorov recognizes two kinds of stories: based on plot or on the character. The critical study explains why La Cosworth is a character novel. It covers the genesis and changes of the characters. It explains the importance of the automobile in the story and the use of music as a means of framing and animating the narration. We will analyse the development of the chapters and the overall construction which are dependent on the evolution of the characters. And to conclude, we will discuss problems encountered while writing and the way they were resolved.</description><creator>Da Conceicao, José Carlos</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Da Conceicao, José Carlos. Cosworth</subject><title>La genèse de Carlos et de sa Cosworth suivi de La Cosworth /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720d99q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zx75v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tw34b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Planar optical waveguides fabricated by proton-exchange and annealed proton-exchange in LiNbO$ sb3$ are investigated. The use of a Fermi function was found to accurately model the proton-exchange refractive index profile resulting in a better agreement between the measured effective mode indices and the computed dispersion curves compared to the conventional step-index profile. Numerical simulations of the nonlinear diffusion equation have shown that the proton-exchange process cannot be adequately described by the well established ion-exchange equations. A generalized Gaussian function was used to accurately model the refractive index profile in annealed proton-exchanged waveguides resulting in considerable improvements over previous work. Annealing was found to allow for flexibility in the tailoring of the waveguide parameters. In addition to establishing single mode propagation criteria, changes in these parameters were correlated with the fabrication conditions using a general power law thus showing that the anneal process is not characterized by simple diffusion mechanisms.</description><creator>Nikolopoulos, John</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Characterization of proton-exchanged planar optical waveguides in LiNbO3</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kt98n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tw34b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8623j002m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis analyzes the corporeal origin of theoretical works in XVI$ sp{ rm th}$ century French architecture. A comparison of Philibert de l'Orme's treatises and Francois Rabelais' work allows for a dynamic awareness of materiality to emerge. During the Renaissance, this awareness was based on analogical relationships and Hermetic texts. However, whether one looks at the theory of the Elements, the concept of Proportion, the microcosm-macrocosm interplay, or even the Cardinal Virtues, it appears that the references were always traced back to the everyday experience of the body. Confronted with the mechanistic and objectifying conceptualizations that dominate today, this thesis supports the crucial role the architect must play in the bringing forth of places that allow for a perception of the body closer to apprenticeship than to domination.</description><creator>Chupin, Jean-Pierre</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Architecture, Renaissance -- France</subject><subject>Rabelais, François, ca. 1490-1553?</subject><subject>L'Orme, Philibert de, 1515?-1570</subject><title>De Philibert De l'Orme et De Rabelais : analogous treatises: a companion</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j6763.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j002m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tq57nr75n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We have studied the radiation decays of non strange mesons into (pi)('+),(pi)('-) and one or three gamma rays observed in the reaction (pi)('-) + p (---&gt;) Meson + n at beam momentum 8.45 Gev/c in a Counter-Spark chamber experiment conducted at Argonne National Laboratory Zero Gradient Synchrotron. We set a new apper limit on the branching ratio (omega) (---&gt;) (pi)('+)(pi)('-)(gamma) which is almost an order of magnitude smaller than the previously set upper limit. We present a high statistics independent measurement of the branching ration (eta)' (---&gt;) (rho)(gamma). We observed the decays (rho) ((omega)) (---&gt;) (eta)(gamma) for the first time in the reaction (pi)('-)p (---&gt;) (rho) ((omega))n and measured the decay rates (GAMMA)(,(rho)((omega)) (---&gt;) (eta)(gamma)).</description><creator>Shahbazian, Elisa.</creator><date>1982</date><subject>Mesons -- Decay.</subject><subject>Radioactive decay.</subject><title>Radiative decays of [eta, rho, omega, eta'] mesons produced in the reaction [pi-]+p [yields] meson + n at 8.45 Gevc</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jm16f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57nr75n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn009z658</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study evaluates the efficacy of self-hypnosis and its components--relaxation instructions and waking analgesia suggestions--for pain reduction in patients recovering from gallbladder surgery. Forty elective surgery patients were randomly assigned to one of the three experimental pain control procedures or to a standard treatment control group--preoperative teaching. The treatments were found to be equally credible and generated equivalent expectancies for success. Pain was assessed using multiple subjective and objective measures sampled across the postoperative period. Multivariate analysis of these data indicated that the experimental treatments were no more effective in diminishing postoperative pain than the control procedure. However, the analysis revealed several significant correlates and predictors of postoperative pain. These included trait anxiety, depression, stress coping style as well as interview and rating scale reports of cognitive coping strategies. Significant predictors of credibility--expectancy, treatment utilization and cognitive coping classifications were also found. Analysis of the pain measurement strategy indicated consistency among the subjective measures--the McGill Pain Questionnaire and visual analogue scales--which were relatively independent from the objective measures, which comprised electronically monitored gross motor activity and analgesic medication requirements. Possible interpretations and implications of these results as well as suggestions for future research are discussed.</description><creator>Taenzer, Paul.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Gallbladder -- Surgery.</subject><subject>Postoperative pain.</subject><subject>Autogenic training.</subject><subject>Analgesia.</subject><subject>Mental suggestion.</subject><title>Self-control of postoperative pain : effects of hypnosis and waking suggestion</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526d13n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn009z658</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z159d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Using the new Picker flow calorimeter, the excess heat capacity (C(,p)('E)) has been measured for systems containing normal, branched and cyclic alkanes. The results indicate two unusual effects: (1) a large negative contribution due to the destruction of orientational order in a pure n-alkane component, and (2) a positive contribution attributed to the "condensation" of a more freely-moving molecule or segment on a sterically-hindered branched alkane, resulting in a restriction of rotational movement, i.e. creation of order in the solution. Mixtures of cycloalkanes and their methyl derivatives also show unexpected positive effects in the excess heat capacity. Thus the plate-like cyclopentane molecule gives positive C(,p)('E) values when mixed with other plate-like methyl derivatives of cyclohexane suggesting a hindering of its molecular rotation. Cyclohexane mixed with globular branched and cyclic alkanes shows S-shaped C(,p)('E) curves, negative at low concentration of cyclohexane but positive at high, indicating the possibility of a restriction of cyclohexane motion. Effects of order are also apparent in the equation of state of a liquid. The thermal pressure coefficient for systems containing n-hexadecane has been found to be anomalous and is explained by a lowering of the internal energy of n-hexadecane by orientational order. Excess volume (V('E)) has been studied for systems of branched and normal alkanes by investigating different effects contributing to the total V('E), particularly an important effect of a difference in thermal pressure coefficients of the two components.</description><creator>Tra, Van-Huu.</creator><date>1982</date><subject>Alkanes.</subject><subject>Heat of mixing.</subject><subject>Molecular structure.</subject><subject>Order-disorder in alloys.</subject><title>Effects of molecular shape on the structure of alkane mixtures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sk33q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z159d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn301205b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Phosphorus and phytoplankton dynamics in freshwater are usually thought to be tightly coupled and interdependent, yet orthophosphate uptake in situ has been observed to be mediated largely by particles of bacterial size. The purpose of this thesis is to examine the general hypothesis that freshwater bacterioplankton are markedly superior competitors for phosphorus, relative to the phytoplankton. Using isolates of three species of pelagic bacteria, and two of algae, it was shown that the bacteria possess much higher affinity orthophosphate uptake kinetics than the algae. In a Monte Carlo simulation study, the accuracy and precision of these Michaelis-Menten parameter estimates were found to depend strongly upon the experimental design matrix. Bacterial superiority in uptake was also reflected in terms of growth, in chemostat competition experiments, which also showed algal and bacterial uptake of orthophosphate to be well correlated with their relative long-term phosphorus assimilation. In parallel experiments in situ, bacterioplankton were found invariably to be responsible for more than 97% of the orthophosphate uptake. In contrast, excreted organic phosphorus was utilised almost exclusively by the phytoplankton. There is little evidence as yet that excretion and reuptake of phosphorus is important in redistributing phosphorus among the plankton.</description><creator>Currie, David J. (David John)</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Water -- Phosphorus content.</subject><subject>Freshwater microbiology.</subject><subject>Phosphorus -- Metabolism.</subject><subject>Freshwater phytoplankton.</subject><title>Phosphorus competition and partitioning between freshwater phytoplankton and bacterioplankton</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np1939827.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301205b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:41687j259</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Some new inorganic and organometallic derivatives of methylcyclosiloxanes have been prepared and characterized by IR, MS and ('1)H NMR. Compounds, {CH(,3)(Br)SiO}(,3) and {CH(,3)(Br)SiO}(,4) were prepared by cleavage of silicon-phenyl bond with bromine at low temperature. The reaction of {CH(,3)(Br)SiO}(,3) with Na(sec-butyl)(,3)BH at low temperature produced the highly reactive trimer, {CH(,3)(H)SiO}(,3). Compounds {CH(,3)(Co(CO)(,4))SiO}(,4), {CH(,3)(Fe(CO)(,2)(eta)('5)-C(,5)H(,5))SiO}(,4), and {CH(,3)(Co(CO)(,4)SiO}(,5) were prepared by the hydrogen elimination reaction of {CH(,3)(H)SiO}(,n), n = 4 and 5 with Co(,2)(CO)(,8) and {Fe(CO)(,2)(eta)('5)-C(,5)H(,5)}(,2). It was also possible to isolate the compound {CH(,3)(Co(CO)(,4))SiO}(,1){CH(,3)(Fe(CO)(,2)(eta)('5)-C(,5)H(,5))SiO}(,3) by reacting {CH(,3)(H)SiO}(,1){CH(,3)(Fe(CO)(,2)(eta)('5)-C(,5)H(,5))SiO}(,3) with a stoichiometric amount of Co(,2)(CO)(,8). A detailed study of mass spectra of {CH(,3)(R)SiO}(,n), where R = H, (n = 4, 5, and 6), R = C(,6)H(,5), (n = 3 and 4), R = Br, (n = 3 and 4), R = Co(CO)(,4), (n = 4 and 5) and R = Fe(CO)(,2)(eta)('5)-C(,5)H(,5), (n = 4) was achieved. Compounds R = Co(CO)(,4) show stepwise loss of all CO groups from ions {M}('+(.)), {M-Co(CO)(,4)}('+), and also {M}('++). A simple empirical approach based on the chemical environment of methyl protons was used to assign ('1)H NMR spectra of geometric isomers of substituted methylcyclosiloxanes. The total assignment of ('1)H NMR spectra allowed the determination of the isomeric composition of most new compounds mentioned above.</description><creator>Pelletier, Emilien.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Silicon compounds.</subject><subject>Siloxanes.</subject><title>Synthesis and characterization of a new class of silyl-transition metal compounds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v386z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687j259</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gk651</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Multiphase flow in porous media is a wide-ranging phenomenon, covering such topics as the motion of immiscible fluids, where the interaction with the medium is by exchange of heat and/or mass between phases, to fluid-solid phase flow accompanied by clogging and leaching. The present study is limited to the flow of immiscible fluids (oil and surfactant), where fine solids (clay) migration occurs during the motion. It is divided into two parts: (a) experimental and (b) theoretical. The experimental investigations have been performed in order to evaluate: (a) the factors (e.g., porosity, temperature and injection pressure) that affect the injected surfactant flow rate through oil/soil mixtures, (b) the role of clay mineral concentration on the uptake and displacement of oil by the injected surfactant, (c) the portion of the oil displaced by the injected surfactant in the medium, under the testing conditions, (d) the effect of injection head on the rate of oil uptake during the injection process. The theoretical analysis leads to a new diffusion model which accounts for the simultaneous movement of oil, fines and surfactant. The conclusion to be drawn from this part is that the new simplified model, together with further refinement, lead to a better understanding of the behaviour and prediction of the multiphase flow through a porous medium.</description><creator>Elmonayeri, Diaa S. (Diaa Salah), 1950-</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Porosity.</subject><subject>Multiphase flow.</subject><title>Mechanism and analysis of multiphase flow through soil</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mn026.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gk651</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74cr18m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A variety of iron precipitates formed in the electrolytic zinc industry were studied to estimate the possibility of magnetic filtration to augment conventional thickening/filtering systems. The precipitates included K,NH(,4),Na jarosites, (alpha) and (beta) goethite, (alpha) hematite and an industrially produced NH(,4) jarosite. The wet Frantz Isodynamic Separator was used to generate magnetic susceptibility data. Susceptibilities ranged from (kappa) = 6.9 x 10('-5) (---&gt;) 15.5 x 10('-5) emu/cm('3)0e. Particle size of the precipitates ranged from 25 (mu)m to &lt; 1 (mu)m. Magnetic filtration breakthrough curves were produced using a high gradient magnetic filtration technique. The role of fluid viscosity and velocity as well as magnetic field was studied. All the precipitates proved filterable. A comparison was made of a physical and an empirical model of the breakthrough curves in the sizing of the magnetic filters required to treat thickener overflow at the CEZ Valleyfield plant. For a volumetric flow of 100m('3)/hr electrolyte, containing 15g/L NH(,4) jarosite, 2 magnets of 2.6m diameter and 0.35m bed depth are required to lower solids contents to the present operating level of 3g/L.</description><creator>Todd, Iain A.</creator><date>1982</date><subject>Iron -- Metallurgy.</subject><subject>Magnetic separation of ores.</subject><subject>Zinc -- Metallurgy.</subject><title>Magnetic filtration of iron precipitates</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xm57k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cr18m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xs55mc70s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Lower critical solubility temperatures (LCST) have been measured for polyethylene (PE), polypropylene, ethylene-propylene copolymers, polybutene-1, polypentene-1 and poly 4-methylpentene-1 (P4MP1) in twenty-five isomeric alkanes. The LCST for PE are much lower than for branched polyolefins, especially in branched alkanes. The results are not predicted by the Prigogine-Flory-Patterson theory but are understood in terms of correlations of molecular orientations in the PE melt. Fusion thermodynamics of P4MP1 confirm the existence of ordered conformations in the melt. The thermoreversible gelation of P4MP1 solutions depends on solvent and thermal history. It is studied by calorimetry, viscosimetry and wide angle X-ray diffraction. The gel crosslinks are presumably of a fringed-micellar nature and their formation is tentatively associated with the existence of helical conformations of P4MP1 in solution. The latter is also responsible for the obtaining of four different crystalline structures of P4MP1 from solutions and gels. Preliminary measurements of dynamic mechanical properties of P4MP1 gels are reported.</description><creator>Charlet, Gérard.</creator><date>1982</date><subject>Gelation.</subject><subject>Polymers.</subject><subject>Heat of solution.</subject><subject>Polyolefins.</subject><title>Effect of order on LCST and gelation of polyolefin solutions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qc98z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mc70s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):21050</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>