<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:09:43Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):17600" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dq811</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores the Ottoman guilds during the sixteenth and eighteenth centuries as they are depicted in the miniature paintings contained within two well-known and well-preserved festival albums: the Surname-i Humayun (1582) and the Surname-i Vehbi (1720). These manuscripts describe the events occurring during the festival celebrations for the circumcisions of the sons of Sultan Murad III (r. 1574-95) and Sultan Ahmed III (r. 1703-30) and while they offer an excellent portrait of Ottoman society in general, they are particularly noteworthy for their portrayals of guild processions. Based on analysis of the festival paintings as well as on existing literature, the guilds are examined in the greater context of the Ottoman Empire and aspects such as guild function, structure, hierarchy, membership, and origins and evolution of the guilds are considered.</description><creator>Serban, Carrie.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Guilds -- Turkey -- History.</subject><subject>Miniature painting, Turkish.</subject><title>A study of the Ottoman guilds as they are depicted in Turkish miniature paintings /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c6224.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dq811</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xw69g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores two factors that have been instrumental in the evolution of society and ethnic and national identities in southern Central Asia. It is argued that the development of these identities (and the obstacles encountered in the process) are closely linked to the place of Islam in central Asian society, and the delicate ethnic balance between the Turkic and the Iranian cultural spheres -- which also manifested itself as the symbiosis between sedentary-agrarian and nomadic populations. It was the disruption of these two factors under Soviet rule which led to lasting problems that continue to bedevil the region to this day.</description><creator>Majoka, Hashir.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Uzbekistan -- Civilization.</subject><subject>Islam -- Asia, Central.</subject><subject>Asia, Central -- Civilization.</subject><subject>Tajikistan -- Civilization.</subject><title>Islam and the Turkic Tajik symbiosis in Central Asia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/44558h86p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xw69g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g384h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Using second trimester amniotic fluid (AF), the objectives of this study were two-fold: 1) to investigate the relationship between AF glucose and insulin levels as a predictor of macrosomia and 2) to create a risk profile for macrosomia (LGA&gt; 90th percentile) using a combination of AF glucose and insulin concentrations. Amniotic fluid samples were obtained from non-diabetic women (n = 542) undergoing age-related amniocentesis (12th to 22nd week). AF glucose was quantified using a standard hexokinase assay and AF insulin was quantified using the Beckman Access ultrasensitive assay system. Although LGA infants were found to have significantly higher concentrations of insulin and glucose in their 2nd trimester AF, logistic regressions showed that neither alone predicted the outcome of macrosomia. However, a Bayesian two-dimensional contour map plotted the risk for LGA using both AF glucose and insulin. The two-dimensional contour map illustrated the value in considering AF glucose and insulin together to predict LGA in newborns.</description><creator>Rubino, Maria.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Amniotic liquid -- Analysis.</subject><subject>Fetus -- Growth.</subject><subject>Birth weight.</subject><title>Second trimester amniotic fluid insulin and glucose as predictors of macrosomia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gx43h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g384h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1c18dk270</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Outer Space Treaty established the obligation to provide continuing supervision of its national space activities by the appropriate state. The implementation of this obligation remains a matter of state discretion. Since this Treaty came into force the world has evolved to become reliant on space based utilities to enable the global economy and state governance. Today, space faring states are increasingly dependent upon the supervision practices of other states to assure its space interests as the attribution of state responsibility becomes more difficult to ascribe. Therefore, the absence of binding supervision standards may become an impediment to future space applications due to three identified trends. First, the trend towards space commercialization requires active state supervision. Second, the rise in environmental hazards requires minimal safety standards to decrease the harmful effects on space applications. Third, space security requires identification of intentional acts and prudent measures to safeguard vital space applications.</description><creator>Spencer, Ronald L.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Astronautics and state.</subject><subject>Outer space -- Exploration -- Environmental aspects.</subject><subject>Space security.</subject><subject>Space industrialization -- Government policy.</subject><subject>Astronautics and state -- United States.</subject><subject>Space environment.</subject><title>Implementing international standards for &amp;quot;continuing supervision&amp;quot;</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33s1213.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dk270</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827g511</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the early 21st century, the private commercial space transportation industry demonstrated that commercial human space flight is both technologically and economically feasible. In 2004, the United States Congress responded by passing legislation authorizing the Department of Transportation to license and regulates commercial human space flight. This thesis examines and assesses the U.S. commercial human space flight vehicle licensing and regulatory law. Tort liability is inextricably linked to the success of the commercial human space flight industry and to that end this thesis provides an analysis of U.S. tort liability law in the event of a commercial human space flight vehicle accident.</description><creator>Mineiro, Michael C.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Liability for space vehicle accidents -- United States.</subject><subject>Space law -- United States.</subject><subject>Manned space flight.</subject><title>Commercial human space flight in the United States : federal licensing and tort liability</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mn56s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827g511</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343w612</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ectogenesis -- literally creation outside the womb -- is a word coined by British geneticist J.B.S. Haldane in 1923 as he provocatively predicted future scientific frontiers. Fast-moving assisted reproductive technologies assure us that ectogenesis is no longer the fantastical creation of futuristic writers. Instead, it is likely to manifest in one of three ways. It may be a quiet byproduct of the lessening gap between in vitro procedures and the use of sophisticated neonatal environments. It may arise from endometrial tissue ladders grown into artificial wombs. Or, it may be as bizarre as that envisioned in Brave New World where there is an intentional effort to create an artificial womb from which the development of a human being may be scrutinized and monitored from start to finish. The morass of hasty and reckless legislation passed in various countries to deal with the creation and termination of embryonic life shows that few are prepared to deal with exigencies of ectogenesis when it arrives insidiously or abruptly. Moreover, Eastern thought and traditions will conflict with Western ideology with respect to the beginning and maintenance of human life. This thesis suggests that the language, structure and philosophy of the United Kingdom's Human Fertilisation and Embryology Act is well crafted and should be considered as a world-wide paradigm. This thesis also suggests that ectogenesis will mandate that the interests of the developing fetus override notions of reproductive autonomy.</description><creator>Tomsick, Terry.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Ectogenesis -- Moral and ethical aspects.</subject><subject>United Kingdom. Human Fertilisation and Embryology Act 1990.</subject><subject>Ectogenesis.</subject><title>Ectogenesis : the next generation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g869x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343w612</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207ts79x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Perturbations of the Laplacian are known as Schrodinger operators. We pose a question about perturbations of eigenfunctions from multiple eigenspaces and answer the question in the case of the two-sphere. This is used to extend a previously known result about nodal sets of spherical harmonics to eigenfunctions of Schrodinger operators on the two-sphere. We also review some of the classical and recent results about nodal sets and domains for eigenfunctions of the Laplacian.</description><creator>Haldane, Evan.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>SchrÜdinger operator.</subject><subject>Eigenfunctions.</subject><title>Geometry of nodal sets and domains for eigenfunctions of SchrÜdinger operators</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806378z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207ts79x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dj52w8348</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The application of Nuclear Magnetic Resonance (NMR) spectroscopy in the determination of nutrition labeling component data (NLCD) was investigated, with the intent of using this methodology as a primary method to calibrate FTIR instrumentation for NLCD confirmation or screening on a routine basis. Unlike previous NMR studies, this work used three strategies to attain accuracy and reproducibility of NLCD through: (i) appropriate setting of operational parameters for spectral acquisition; (ii) resonance selection by optimizing the signal in proportion to the nuclei population and (iii) integration of resonances by pre-defined fixed chemical shift ranges. Both of 13C NMR spectra and 1H NMR spectra were shown to provide robust and acceptable results on the condition of appropriate acquisition of spectra for quantization purposes and the adoption of standard procedures for spectral processing, integration and calculation purposes. A quantitative approach of NLCD including trans content was determined by the interpretation resonance signals of 13C's and 1H's from methylene groups presented in triglyceride complex of fats and oils. An alternative method based on partial-least-squares (PLS) calibrations was provided as well, the latter proved to be especially useful in dealing with overlapping bands frequently found in 1H spectra. With the diagnostic provided by PLS, the trans and cis signals were shown to be separated in 1H spectra. It is the premise for the trans fat determination based on 1H spectra. Unit conversion from mole to weight % was addressed and a solution was developed based on NMR data per se, without significant assumptions. Validation involving the analysis of three different lipid types (model triacylglycerols, refined and hydrogenated oils) demonstrated that NMR predictions of NLCD were in good agreement with those results either from samples' actual values as well as those obtained using GC and FTIR predictions. Thus with appropriate integration of instrumentation, software and spectral processing accessories, both 13C and 1H NMR can determine NLCD, but with the capability to determine trans, 1H NMR is more practical than 13C NMR due to its much shorter spectral acquisition time. Thus NMR can serve as a primary method for the calibration of FTIR instrumentation, a practical instrumental method for routine NLCD determination and screening.</description><creator>Gao, Lei.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Trans fatty acids -- Analysis.</subject><subject>Food -- Labeling.</subject><subject>Food -- Fat content.</subject><subject>Nuclear magnetic resonance.</subject><title>Determination of quantitative nutritional labeling compositional data of lipids by Nuclear Magnetic Resonance (NMR) spectroscopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wv15c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w8348</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m613n219z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Learning agents often find themselves in environments in which rare significant events occur independently of their current choice of action. Traditional reinforcement learning algorithms sample events according to their natural probability of occurring, and therefore tend to exhibit slow convergence and high variance in such environments. In this thesis, we assume that learning is done in a simulated environment in which the probability of these rare events can be artificially altered. We present novel algorithms for both policy evaluation and control, using both tabular and function approximation representations of the value function. These algorithms automatically tune the rare event probabilities to minimize the variance and use importance sampling to correct for changes in the dynamics. We prove that these algorithms converge, provide an analysis of their bias and variance, and demonstrate their utility in a number of domains, including a large network planning task.</description><creator>Frank, Jordan William, 1980-</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Reinforcement learning.</subject><subject>Markov processes.</subject><subject>Computer algorithms.</subject><title>Reinforcement learning in the presence of rare events</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698c32c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n219z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5999n7027</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An efficient and expedient synthetic method was developed for the preparation of chiral poly-substituted morpholine and oxazepine derivatives. The method was designed in the objective of applying the synthesis to the preparation of Cyclophilin A inhibitors. The stereo- and regioselective method involves the reaction of enantiopure beta-amino alcohols with alpha,beta-unsaturated aldehydes. The synthesis proceeds through three steps; i) Reductive amination, ii) N-alkylation/ N-tosylation and iii) intramolecular-haloetherification. Stereoselectivity of this last step was controlled by N-alkyl/ N-tosyl groups and substitution across the double bond, and was enhanced by the addition of Bronsted acids. Substitution across the double bond of the starting material controlled the regioselectivity of the method. Morpholines were obtained through 6- exo cyclization and oxazepines were obtained through 7-endo cyclization. A small library of morpholine-based derivatives was designed in-silico. Affinity and binding modes to the Cyclophilin A were investigated through a docking-based virtual screening study.</description><creator>Bilbeisi, Rana A., 1983-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Morpholine -- Synthesis.</subject><subject>Oxazepines -- chemical synthesis.</subject><subject>Azepines -- Synthesis.</subject><subject>Peptidylprolyl isomerase -- Inhibitors.</subject><subject>Cyclophilin A -- antagonists &amp; inhibitors.</subject><subject>Morpholines -- chemical synthesis.</subject><title>Expedient synthesis of chiral poly-substituted morpholine and oxazepine derivatives for the preparation of cyclophilin A inhibitors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p845v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n7027</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547w16k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Reactive airways dysfunction syndrome (RADS), a form of irritant-induced asthma (IIA) has been observed in humans following acute chlorine (Cl 2) gas exposure in occupational and domestic settings. Following Cl 2 injury, subepithelial fibrosis, mucous hyperplasia, and non-specific airway hyperresponsiveness have been reported. Based on the disease profile, we hypothesized that pulmonary damage may be oxidative in nature. The aim of this work was to develop a murine model of irritant-induced asthma in order to investigate the pathogenic processes and potential oxidative mechanisms involved in response to Cl2 exposure, with a secondary aim of examining the role of iNOS in response to Cl2 inhalation. A/J, C57BI/6J (wild type) and iNOS-1- mice exposed to various concentrations of Cl2 were mechanically ventilated for measurement of lung mechanics and responses to i.v. methacholine (MCh). Bronchoalveolar lavage was performed to examine total protein, cell populations and nitrate/nitrates. Tissues were harvested for histology and immunocytochemistry for iNOS, 3NT and carbonyl residues. To examine the role of iNOS, a subset of animals were treated with a selective iNOS inhibitor (1400W) and non-selective NOS inhibitor LNAME. Chlorine exposure caused airway hyperresponsiveness, which appeared to be mitigated by iNOS blockade with 1400W, however this was not the case in iNOS-1- mice. Cl2 exposure also caused increases in total BAL protein, total cells, NOx, neutrophils, iNOS, 3NT and carbonyl residues. In conclusion, chlorine exposure causes lung injury, similar to reactive airways dysfunction syndrome, characterized by airway hyperresponsiveness, epithelial sloughing, inflammatory cell influx, oxidative injury and increases in both the activity and expression of iNOS. Chlorine-induced airway hyperresponsiveness is mitigated, in part, by selective blockade of iNOS with the use of pharmacological intervention.</description><creator>Campbell, Holly R., 1976-</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Asthma -- enzymology.</subject><subject>Lung Diseases -- chemically induced.</subject><subject>Mice, Inbred C57BL.</subject><subject>Nitric Oxide Synthase Type II -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Chlorine -- toxicity.</subject><subject>Mice.</subject><title>Chlorine-induced lung injury and the role of iNOS</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n204275s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547w16k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pk99c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Despite the overwhelming evidence for atrophy of the NGF-dependant Basal Forebrain Cholinergic neurons during aging, there is no persuasive evidence towards a decrease in NGF and/or NGF mRNA content in the brain of aged animals. Previous experiments from our laboratory have shown that NGF is released as a precursor protein and cleaved into the mature form in the extracellular space under the influence of a complex protease cascade. These recent findings have lead us to propose that any alterations in levels and/or activity of this maturation/degradation cascade might affect NGF's biological activity and perhaps lead to cognitive impairments in a subset of aged rats. To investigate this possibility, we measured protein and mRNA levels of the protease cascade players (NGF, pro-NGF, tPA, plasminogen, plasmin, MMP-9, neuroserpin). We found significantly decreased levels of both pro-NGF protein and NGF mRNA, but no difference in the remaining elements of the protease cascade, when comparing aged impaired (Al) to the aged unimpaired (AU) animals. Our second objective was to investigate whether animals trained in the Morris Water Maze would preserve their cognitive status in two additional behavioral paradigms, the Novel Object Location (NOL, spatial memory) and Novel Object Recognition (NOR, nonspatial memory) tasks. We found that both AU and AI animals in the MWM were impaired in the NOL when compared to the young controls, with the AI animals performing significantly worse than the AU in this particular task. In the NOR tasks, AI animals performed significantly worse compared to both young and AU animals. In conclusion, further experiments are required to better understand the implication of the complex protease cascade involved in NGF's maturation and degradation as well as its effect on memory of aged animals. In addition, because the segregation of animals (aged impaired/unimpaired) is a crucial step in aging research, we now have additional behavioral paradigms (NOL/NOR) that confirm the cognitive status of these animals.</description><creator>Bossy, Tanya.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Cognition Disorders -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Memory Disorders -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Rats.</subject><subject>Rats, Inbred F344.</subject><subject>Aging -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Nerve Growth Factors -- metabolism.</subject><title>Implication of a novel nerve growth factor (NGF) maturation and degradation cascade in the Fischer-344 rat model of age-associated memory deficits</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r906z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pk99c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150n64s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Focal adhesion kinase (FAK), a non-receptor kinase, is a key regulator of integrin and focal adhesion signaling required for cancer cell survival, cell migration, and cell invasion. Amplification/Overexpression of FAK occurs in a wide variety of human cancers, supporting a role in carcinogenesis. Moreover, preclinical studies using cancer models where FAK is genetically inhibited indicate that this kinase is a potential therapeutic target to interfere with cancer progression. However, very little progress has been made in the identification of chemical inhibitors for potential therapeutic applications, in contrast to other kinases. Herein, I report optimization of the high-throughput in vitro Glo kinase assay for screening inhibitors of FAK kinase activity. Screening a large library of small molecule chemicals using these assays identified at least twenty FAK inhibitors, including a new FAK inhibitor developed by Pfizer and undergoing human clinical trials, and the non-specific kinase inhibitor staurosporine. Molecular studies of selective FAK inhibitors are undergoing in my host laboratory. In addition to this in vitro assay, I established similar assays to examine FAK kinase and adapter function in intact cells. The latter consists of ErbB-transformed cells deficient in FAK, and their matched cells where wild-type or kinase-dead FAK was restored. Biological characterization of these models revealed that both FAK kinase and adaptor activities cooperate for the regulation of cell migration, cell invasion, and tumor formation.</description><creator>Cao, Yangxiezi.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Breast Neoplasms -- drug therapy.</subject><subject>Focal Adhesion Protein-Tyrosine Kinases -- antagonists &amp; inhibitors.</subject><title>A chemical-biology approach for screening novel inhibitors of focal adhesion signaling in relation to breast cancer /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/794081723.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150n64s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4x51hp150</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nuclear receptors play crucial roles in the transcriptional regulation of many biological processes such as development and cellular differentiation. ERRalpha is known, along with coactivator PGC-1alpha, to playa central role in the control of energy metabolism in cardiac and skeletal muscle. They activate the expression of many genes involved in mitochondrial oxidative metabolism. Here we identified PROX1, a factor that was previously shown to broadly influence metabolism, as a regulator of this pathway. Indeed, PROX1 interacts in vitro and in vivo with both ERRalpha and PGC-1alpha. To provide more insight on the hepatic functions of ERRalpha and PROX1, we performed ChIP-on-chip using mouse liver, identifying a large number of ERRalpha and PROX1 genomic targets and reinforcing their role in energy metabolism. Over 40% of the target genes were found to be common to both factors and we observed that PROX1 could be recruited to ERRalpha binding sites and act as a negative regulator o fthe ERRalpha/POC-1alpha pathway.</description><creator>Charest-Marcotte, Alexis, 1984-</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Liver -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Heat-Shock Proteins -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Receptors, Estrogen -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Homeodomain Proteins -- metabolism.</subject><title>Functional interaction between PROX1, ERR[alpha] and PGC-1[alpha] in the control of energy metabolism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60d1269.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hp150</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8s45qd43v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction: Stroke is associated with a high prevalence of dysphagia in the elderly population. Hence, dysphagia evaluation and management are key issues in stroke rehabilitation. The McGill Ingestive Skills Assessment (MISA) is a recently developed mealtime observational tool aimed at evaluating the functional aspects of the oral phase of ingestion. Objective: To determine the discriminative validity of the MISA by assessing known/extreme groups of elderly individuals presenting with stroke, who have been admitted to an acute-care-hospital or a rehabilitation center. Participants were allocated to one of two groups: 1) individuals with stroke and no dysphagia, who are on a regular diet and 2) individuals with stroke and dysphagia, who are permitted only purees. Methods: Participants were evaluated with the MISA and a comprehensive chart review was conducted. Analysis: Groups were compared on socio-demographic and clinical characteristics. Univariate tests were performed to test the significance of between-group differences. Conclusion and significance: The results of the study are satisfactory, and enhance the clinical usefulness of the tool for dysphagia management. These results also support future studies addressing the responsiveness of the MISA.</description><creator>Francis, Charmine, 1978-</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Deglutition Disorders -- diagnosis.</subject><subject>Deglutition Disorders -- physiopathology.</subject><subject>Aged.</subject><subject>Aged, 80 and over.</subject><subject>Geriatric Assessment -- methods.</subject><title>The discriminative validity of the McGill Ingestive Skills Assessment (MISA) /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82kc07q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qd43v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33s122c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) affects up to 10% of school-aged children and half as many adults. The core features of impulsivity, hyperactivity, and inattentiveness commonly give rise to academic underachievement, poor social relationships, and increased risk for mood and anxiety disorders. Although the relevant neurobiological mechanisms remain poorly understood, altered mesocorticolimbic dopamine (DA) transmission has been proposed. The aim of the present study was to compare striatal DA function in treatment-naive adults with ADHD vs. age- and IQ-matched controls. Two PET/[11C]raclopride scans, one with placebo and one with d-amphetamine (d-AMP; 0.3 mg/kg, p.o.), were administered to five men with ADHD and five healthy male volunteers. The ADHD group differed from controls in demonstrating significant d-AMP-induced reductions in posterior caudate (p&lt;0.05). These results may support a proposed model of reduced DA tone leading to increased phasic signaling in ADHD.</description><creator>Faridi, Nazlie.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Amphetamine -- pharmacology.</subject><subject>Amphetamine -- therapeutic use.</subject><subject>Receptors, Dopamine D2 -- drug effects.</subject><subject>Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity -- drug therapy.</subject><subject>Dopamine Uptake Inhibitors -- pharmacology.</subject><subject>Dopamine Uptake Inhibitors -- therapeutic use.</subject><title>Amphetamine-induced dopamine release in treatment-naïve men with ADHD : a PET[¹¹C]raclopride study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m549f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33s122c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128nj44j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background. Carotid stenosis is an important cause of stroke. Carotid endarterectomy is a means of reducing the burden of stroke but is of marginal benefit in individuals with asymptomatic carotid stenosis. The identification of factors associated with increased risk of cerebral ischemic events would help select individuals who may obtain a greater benefit. Methods. A comprehensive search was performed to identify studies examining risk factors for cerebral ischemic events in patients with asymptomatic carotid stenosis. Inclusion criteria were defined a priori. Relevant studies were reviewed, assessed for quality, and data were extracted. Results. Thirty-four studies met the inclusion criteria. There was a suggestion of increasing neurological events with increasing severity and progression of carotid stenosis. There was some evidence for an association with carotid plaque morphology. No consistent association was found with clinical factors, impaired cerebral vasoreactivity, or cerebral embolic signals. Conclusions. The evidence is insufficient to reliably identify individuals with asymptomatic carotid stenosis who are at a higher risk of cerebral ischemic events.</description><creator>Ehrensperger, Eric, 1966-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Cerebrovascular Accident -- prevention &amp; control -- Review.</subject><subject>Cerebrovascular Accident -- etiology -- Review.</subject><subject>Brain Ischemia -- etiology -- Review.</subject><subject>Endarterectomy, Carotid -- Review.</subject><subject>Brain Ischemia -- prevention &amp; control -- Review.</subject><subject>Carotid Stenosis -- Review.</subject><title>Predictors of cerebral ischemic events in patients with asymptomatic carotid artery stenosis : systematic review</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qn426.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nj44j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5138jj185</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents the results of a spectroscopic survey of the RCS2319+00 supercluster field using the VIMOS instrument on the 8-meter Very Large Telescope. This system is a rare and massive high-redshift structure, comprising at least three galaxy clusters at z = 0.9, separated by less than 3 Mpc, and is one of the few examples of the progenitors of present-day massive galaxy clusters. We measure 638 new redshifts from a sample of 1134 target sources, 49 of which are consistent with the supercluster redshift. Redshifts are also obtained for 24 radio galaxies within the field, with 6 of these identified as cluster members. We combine the VIMOS redshift catalogue with the data analyzed by Gilbank et al. (2008) from the IMACS spectrograph on the 6-meter Magellan telescope for a total of 1051 redshifts over an area of ~ 30 x 30 square arcminutes, with 94 spectroscopically confirmed supercluster members. From this combined data set the mean spectroscopic redshifts of the three galaxy clusters were refined and found to be zspec = 0.9056, 0.9041, and 0.9047 for clusters A, B, and C respectively. A new velocity dispersion of sigmav = (1300 +/- 410) km S-1 was calculated for the largest component cluster, A, and was used to estimate a new cluster membership redshift range of 0.8857 ≤ z ≤ 0.9239. These data will facilitate further scientific study of RCS2319+00 and will shed light on the evolution of massive clusters, hierarchical structure formation, and galaxy evolution. In combination with other spectroscopy this data will allow: the full extent of the supercluster and its substructure in redshift space to be traced; a determination of the dynamical masses of the individual sub-clusters; and a study of the galaxy population within the structure, in particular the star-forming galaxies and active galactic nuclei as traced by radio and infrared emission.</description><creator>Faloon, Ashley J., 1983-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Red shift.</subject><subject>Astronomical spectroscopy.</subject><subject>Superclusters.</subject><title>A spectroscopic survey of the supercluster RCS2319+00 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053k90r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5138jj185</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z9033697</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Centrosomes are major microtubule organizing centres that set up an internal microtubule (MT) network contributing to cell shape and to the formation of the mitotic spindle during cell division. Rearrangement of this MT array can be dictated by the centrosome and occurs during cell adhesion, polarization and migration. However, little is known about what regulates centrosome assembly and maintenance. beta1-integrins are common cell surface receptors and we show that beta1-integrin signalling is necessary for modulation of centrosome dynamics. In an attempt to identify the downstream components of beta1-integrin signalling involved, we also discovered that the activation of focal adhesion kinase or integrin linked kinase are not required in maintaining centrosome integrity. This would indicate that a non-canonical signalling beta1-integrin pathway might be involved in controlling centrosomal dynamics. This gives us greater insight into the mechanisms that control centrosomal stability and may lead to the better understanding of diseases like cancer and diseases, i.e. lissencephaly, which involve defects in cell polarization and asymmetric cell division, where the centrosome seems to have an important role.</description><creator>Ong, Yen May.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>CD antigens.</subject><subject>Microtubules -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Antigens, CD29 -- physiology.</subject><subject>Centrosome -- physiology.</subject><subject>Centrosomes.</subject><subject>Microtubules.</subject><title>The role of [Beta]1-integrins in centrosomal stability /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xg541.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z9033697</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zw12z8866</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>On June 8, 2007, the Supreme Court of Canada [SCC] overruled its jurisprudence of the past twenty years on freedom of association. The majority of the judges agreed that section 2d) of the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms protects the right to the process to collective bargaining. In doing so, the SCC rejected the ratio of the majority enunciated in the 1987 trilogy and, at last, gave place to international labour law, in particular to freedom of association principles elaborated by the International Labour Organization's supervisory bodies. The analysis of these principles, focused on three related rights, i.e. the right to collective bargaining, the right to strike and the right not to associate, allows the author to conclude that for the first time, Canada is showing greater respect for its international obligations. What the SCC will decide for the right to strike remains to be seen.</description><creator>Choko, Maude.</creator><date>2008</date><subject>International Labour Organization.</subject><subject>Freedom of association -- Canada.</subject><subject>Labor laws and legislation -- Canada.</subject><title>La liberté d'association au Canada et la liberté syndicale à l'OIT : synonymes?</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430833w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z8866</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9c67wr50w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We present the observations, reduction and preliminary analysis of a sample of 45 mid-to-high redshift galaxy clusters imaged with the Spitzer Space Telescope's MIPS camera at 24 ~m and selected from the Red Sequence Cluster Survey. The purpose of the data set is motivated by a broad review of studies into the evolutionary trends of galaxy clusters and their constituent galaxy populations, focusing specifically on recent results that indicate clusters are environmental drivers of dusty starburst and active galactic nuclei activity. To accommodate the large amount of data in hand, we have constructed an extensive data reduction pipeline for the MIPS data and describe its development and output in detail. Using the resulting catalogues for introductory analysis, we find strong evidence for an excess luminous infrared galaxy population in galaxy clusters at high redshift and discuss the implications of this discovery in terms of cluster evolution and motivate future work.</description><creator>O'Donnell, D. V. (Daniel V.), 1983-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Red shift.</subject><subject>Infrared spectroscopy.</subject><subject>Astronomical spectroscopy.</subject><subject>Galaxies -- Clusters.</subject><title>An infrared survey of galaxy clusters with the Spitzer Space Telescope /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913t51n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wr50w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20sx550</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The fast-skeletal-muscle-fiber-specific expression of the troponin I(fast) (TnIfast) gene is driven by an Intronic Regulatory Element (IRE) located within the first intron of the gene. The IRE is a 148 bp transcriptional enhancer that contains several known and suspected cis-regulatory elements. These include the E-box, the closely-spaced MEF2 site and CACT box, the CACC site, and the CAGG element. Previous loss-of-function studies performed using the quail TnIfast IRE suggest that its activity depended on the MEF2 and CACT elements. The goal of my thesis research was to determine whether the MEF2 and CACT sites were not only necessary, but also sufficient, to support IRE activity. I prepared head-to-tail multimers of a 27-bp IRE segment that consisted largely of the near-adjacent MEF2 and CACT elements and did not contain any other known/suspected elements. These multimers were cloned upstream of a reporter gene consisting of the minimal promoter of the quail TnIfast gene linked to sequences encoding human placental alkaline phosphatase. The transcriptional capabilities of the constructs were assessed by gene transfer into the mouse soleus muscle in vivo by intramuscular injection/electroporation, and histochemical analysis of reporter enzyme plap expression including quantitative microdensitometry. I found that expression of these constructs was readily detectable and that it was markedly reduced by prior mutation of the CACT and, especially, of the MEF2 sites. These data indicate that the short DNA segment containing MEF2 and CACT elements is sufficient to drive expression in skeletal muscle and confirms the functional importance of these specific elements. Although constructs containing the wild-type IRE 27-bp region were expressed, there was little preferential expression in fast fibers, in contrast to expression driven by the complete 148-bp IRE. Thus my results indicate that the MEF2 and CACT elements are not sufficient to drive fast fiber-type-specific expression, and suggest that additional elements outside of the 27-bp region tested are also necessary for fiber-type-specificity.</description><creator>Nowacka, Lidia.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Striated muscle.</subject><subject>Genetic transcription -- Regulation.</subject><subject>Muscle Fibers, Fast-Twitch -- physiology.</subject><subject>Troponin I -- genetics.</subject><subject>Enhancer Elements, Genetic.</subject><subject>Muscle proteins.</subject><subject>Mice.</subject><subject>Muscle Development.</subject><subject>Muscle, Skeletal -- embryology.</subject><title>Muscle gene transfer studies of a 27-BP segment of the troponin I fast gene IRE enhancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cf559.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20sx550</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591c80x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pup directed maternal licking and grooming (LG) increases with corticosterone (CORT) supplimentation (Rees et al 2004). Increases in LG lead to an attenuation of the adult offspring's HPA response to stress (Liu et aI1997). Similarly, Neonatal increases in glucocorticoids lead, in adulthood, to the same attenuation of the HPA stress response (Catalani et aI1993). We hypothesize that dams exhibiting increased LG will have increased circulating CORT, and this increase will be reflected in their offspring. This thesis characterizes the HPA hormone profile adrenocorticotropic hormone (ACTH), CORT &amp; Corticosterone Binding Globulin (CBG) in High LG (H) and Low LG (L) litters, 5 days postpartum (P4). Furthermore pup plasma CORT levels are determined at (P) 3,4,6,10 &amp; 14. Finally P10 Hand L LG ACTH, CORT &amp; CBG will be assessed after stress. RESULTS: H compared to L LG dams have significantly increased plasma CORT (p=0.03). At P4, H LG offspring have significantly increased plasma CORT (p=0.03) and significantly decreased plasma ACTH (p=0.04) as compared to L LG offspring. Plasma CBG levels are significantly lower in H compared to L LG offspring (p=0.01) at the same age. Across the Stress Hyporesponsive Period (SHRP) H LG offspring had significantly increased plasma CORT (p= 0.00) compared to L LG offspring at P3. Challenged with a stressor at P10, H LG offspring have an exaggerated plasma CORT response (p=0.00). This data suggests increases in plasma CORT in the dams leads to increased CORT in the high offspring, contributing perhaps to a more mature stress response at P10. Key word abbreviation: (1) CORT - CORTicosterone, (2) ACTH - AdrenoCorticoTropin releasing Hormone, (3) CBG - Corticosteroid Binding Globulin, (4) SHRP - Stress Hypo-Responsive Period, (5) P - Post-natal day, (6) HPA - Hypothalamic-Pituitary-Adrenal, (7) LG - Licking/Grooming, (8) ADX/OVX - ADrenalectomized/OVarectomized.</description><creator>Nesbitt, Catherine.</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Pituitary-Adrenal System -- physiopathology.</subject><subject>Corticosterone -- blood.</subject><subject>Rats, Long-Evans.</subject><subject>Stress, Physiological -- physiopathology.</subject><subject>Rats.</subject><subject>Adrenocorticotropic Hormone -- blood.</subject><subject>Maternal Behavior -- physiology.</subject><subject>Hypothalamo-Hypophyseal System -- physiopathology.</subject><title>Variations in maternal lickinggrooming influences both dam and offspring's hypothalamic-pituitary-adrenal hormone profile</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sh309.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591c80x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dz010t658</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The impact of a primary infection with the incompatible digenean Plagiorchis elegans to groups composed of young, juvenile and adult Biomphalaria glabrata and a challenge infection with the compatible parasite Schistosoma mansoni was examined. Egg production of young B. glabrata was significantly reduced by P. elegans at the higher exposures of 16 eggs per snail, while egg production of adult B. glabrata was reduced at exposures of 8 and 16 eggs per snail. Egg production of juvenile B. glabrata snails was not significantly affected by any of the levels of P. elegans exposures. The survivorship of juvenile B. glabrata snails was significantly lowered by an exposure to 16 P. elegans eggs per snail. The survivorship of adult snails was significantly reduced by exposures to both 8 and 16 P. elegans eggs per snail. Interestingly enough, the survivorship of young B. glabrata snails was not significantly affected by P. elegans exposure. Snails harboring small P. elegans infections acquired a resistance to Schistosoma mansoni infection. Infection with P. elegans did not have any significant effect on the egg production of the young and adult sympatric snails, Helisoma trivolvis trivolvis. The survivorship of adult H. trivolvis trivolvis was not significantly affected by exposure to P. elegans. This being said, young H. t. trivolvis that were exposed to P. elegans had a higher survivorship than did control snails. Exposed Bulinus truncatus snails laid up to 50% fewer eggs for the first five weeks due to P. elegans infection. There was however no effect on the survivorship of the snails.</description><creator>Daoust, Simon, 1983-</creator><date>2008</date><subject>Biomphalaria glabrata -- Parasites.</subject><subject>Schistosoma mansoni -- Parasites.</subject><subject>Schistosoma mansoni -- Biological control.</subject><subject>Plagiorchiidae.</subject><subject>Biomphalaria glabrata -- Biological control.</subject><title>Potential use of the digenean parasite, Plagiorchis elegans, as a biological control agent of Biomphalaria glabrata (Pulmonata:Planorbidae) and Schistosoma mansoni (Digenea:Schistosomatidae)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p8464.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010t658</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5999n703h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:20:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Airway remodeling in asthma includes alterations in extracellular matrix and airway smooth muscle (ASM) mass. For this study, ASM cells were obtained from rats that were challenged with ovalbumin (OVA) or saline (SAL) as control. OVA and SAL cells were seeded on plastic control (PC) or on plates coated with decorin or biglycan. OVA cell number was significantly increased versus SAL cells, for cells seeded on PC (48 h). A significant decrease in cell number was observed for both OVA and SAL cells seeded on decorin compared to PC cells (48 h). OVA cells, however, showed a more modest reduction in cell number. Furthermore, biglycan decreased SAL cell number only. Compared to no strain (NS), mechanical strain (S) reduced cell number for OVA and SAL cells on all matrices. In addition, S up-regulated expression of beta 1-integrin relative to NS controls. Results suggest an ability of ASM cells to be modulated by matrix and mechanical stimulation.</description><creator>Pasternyk, Stephanie Marika, 1983-</creator><date>2009</date><subject>Respiratory System -- cytology.</subject><subject>Airway Remodeling -- physiology.</subject><subject>Stress, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Extracellular Matrix -- physiology.</subject><subject>Asthma -- physiopathology.</subject><subject>Myocytes, Smooth Muscle -- physiology.</subject><title>Effect of extracellular matrix and mechanical strain on airway smooth muscle</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150n652.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n703h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):17625</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>