<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:09:42Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):5050" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sm81k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The biosynthesis of the trans-11-tetradecenal sex attractant pheromone of the eastern spruce budworm, Choristoneura fumiferana (Lepidoptera:Tortricidae} was examined both in vivo and in vitro, and shown to involve a trans-11-tetradecenyl acetate intermediate. In vivo labelling with (1-14C]-acetate showed that tetradecenyl acetate was made de novo with synthesis occurring only in the pheromone gland, and that the acetate ester was specifically degraded during the nightly period of pheromone release by the budworm moth. […]</description><description>La biosynthèse de l'aldéhyde trans-11-tétradécenal, utilise comme phéromone par la tordeuse des bourgeons d'epinettes, Choristoneura fumiferana Lepidoptera:Tortricidae), fut étudiée in vivo ainsi qu'in vitro. L'acétate de trans-11-tetradecenyle fut identifié comme intermédiaire dans la biosynthèse de la phéromone. Par une technique d'incorporation de [1-14C]-acetate in vivo, il a été démontre que l'acetate de tétradécenyle peut être synthétisé à partir de l'acétate, et que cette synthèse se trouve uniquement chez la glande de l'insecte productrice de la phéromone. L'acétate de tétradécenyle est également dégradé pendant la période nocturne ou la phéromone est relachée. […]</description><creator>Morse, David</creator><contributor>Meighen, Edward A.</contributor><date>1984-04</date><subject>Pheromone biosynthesis</subject><title>Pheromone Biosynthesis in the Spruce Budworm</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386m849.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sm81k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gq673</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'utilisation de traceurs injectés dans la lumière des tubes séminifères nous a permis de démontrer que les cellules de Sertoli sont, en plus d'être des phagocytes, des cellules pinocytiques actives. Les traceurs d'abord incorporés dans de larges corps multivésiculaires pâles et de formes irrégulières, passent dans les corps multivésiculaires sphériques denses et enfin dans les lysosomes secondaires. La phagocytose des corps résiduels de spermatides est un processus qui résulte d'une interaction spécifique des membranes des corps résiduels et de la membrane des cellules de Sertoli. Alors que cette phagocytose dépend de l'intégrité des microtubules de la cellule de Sertoli la pinocytose est indépendante de l'état des microtubules ou des filaments cytoplasmiques de ces cellules. Une étude morphométrique des cellules de Sertoli au cours du cycle de l'épithélium séminifère a révélé une faible activité pinocytique du stade II au stade VIII du cycle tandis que l'activité pinocytique est élevée du stade IX au stade XIV du cycle ce qui démontre une évolution cyclique marquée du phénomène. Par ailleurs la phagocytose des corps résiduels se situe lors du stade IX du cycle au cours duquel on observe une réduction marquée du nombre des lysosomes secondaires qui paraissent se fusionner avec les phagosomes. Ces observations démontrent une relation étroite entre la pinocytose et la phagocytoses dans la cellule de Sertoli.</description><description>The present study revealed that Sertoli cells were not only phagocytic cells but also active pinocytic elements which internalized by fluid-phase endocytosis tracers infused in the lumen of the seminiferous epithelium. The endocytosed tracers first reached large irregularly shaped, pale multivesicular bodies considered as endosomes, and later the tracers were seen in smaller, denser, spherical multivesicular bodies and in dense secondary lysosomes. Phagocytosis of the spermatid's cytoplasmic residual bodies appeared to be a specific process mediated by membrane-to-membrane interaction between the plasma membrane of the residual bodies and certain segments of the apical plasma membrane of the Sertoli cell. Fluid-phase pinocytosis seemed to be a constitutive process independent of microtubule polymerization and microfilament gelation, whereas phagocytosis of the residual bodies was dependent on microtubule integrity. The morphometric analysis revealed a low level of endocytic activity of Sertoli cells from stage II to stage VIII and a high level from stage IX to stage XIV, emphasizing . the cyclic nature of this process. At stage IX of the cycle the secondary 1ysosomes fuse with phagosomes containing the cytop1asmic residual bodies. These observations clearly demonstrated a close relation of pinocytosis with phagocytosis in Sertoli cells.</description><creator>Morales, Carlos Ramon</creator><contributor>Clermont, Y.</contributor><date>1984-03</date><subject>Sertoli cells</subject><subject>Endocytosis</subject><title>Endocytic Activity in Sertoli Cells of the Rat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kq56b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gq673</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sj759</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nous examinons les hypothèses géométriques d'une grande gamme de modèles pour les Collisions Relativistes d'Ions Lourds (CRIL). La plupart de ceux-ci font des prédictionserronées. Nous proposons un modèle hybride qui tient compte de l'effet de transparence nucléaire et nous l'employons pour calculer la section efficace inclusive du proton. La partiethermodynamique de ce calcul est effectuée en modifiant les fonctions de production du modèle firestreak. La contribution des collisions directes est évaluée dans le cadre du modèle de diffusion aux grandes impulsions. Les résultats sent en bon accord avec !'experience. […]</description><description>Geometrical assumptions of a large class of models for Relativistic Heavy Ion Collisions (RHIC) are examined. Frequently used models fail quantitatively. A two-component model which incorporates nuclear transparency is proposed. The model is employed to calculate the proton inclusive spectrum. The first component (thermal) is calculated within the framework of the thermodynamic model by recasting the yield functions of the firestreak model. The second component (knock-out) is described by the hard-scattering model. The results are in close agreement with data. […]</description><creator>Mobed, Nader</creator><contributor>Gupta. S. Das</contributor><date>1984-05</date><subject>Heavy ion collisions.</subject><subject>Heavy ion collisions -- Spectra.</subject><title>Geometrical and thermodynamic Aspects of Relativistic Heavy Ion Collisions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qf46m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sj759</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848s912</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Afin de déterminer si l'antigène moyen et/ou petit T du virus de polyome est nécessaire pour la transformation, des mutants de plasmides contenant le ou les oncogène viraux ont été construite et testés en ce qui concerne leur capacité de transformation des cellules Rat-1 in vitro. Des mutations causant des insertions ou des délétions dans les séquences qui codent pourles antigènes petit et moyen T, ont entrainé l'incapacité de l'ADN de transformer les cellules Rat-1. Des mutations similaires dans les séquences qui codent pour l'antigène moyen T, mais non pas pour l'antigène petit T, ont eu pour effet d'abolir l'activité de transformation de l'ADN. Par contre, deux mutants (pPdll-4 et pPdl2-7) ont conservé cette capacité de transformation des cellules. Il en ressort que l'antigène petit T seul n'est pas suffisant pour causer la transformation, tandis que l'antigène moyen Test nécessaire pour assurer la transformation, soit seul, soit en association avec l'antigène petit T. […]</description><description>To determine whether small and/or middle T antigen of polyomavirus are required for transformation, mutants of recombinant plasmids which bear the viral oncogene(s) were constructed and tested for their capacity to transform Rat-1 cells in culture. Insertion and deletion mutations in sequences encoding small and middle T antigens rendered the DNA incapable of transforming Rat-1 cells as measured by the focus assay. Similar mutations in sequences which encode middle but not small T antigen generally abolished the transforming activity of the DNA. However, two mutants (pPdll-4 and pPdl2-7) retained the capacity to transform cells. From these studies, I concluded that small T antigen alone is insufficient to cause transformation and that middle T antigen is required for transformation either by itself or in combination with small T antigen. […]</description><creator>Mes-Masson, Anne-Marie</creator><contributor>Hassell, John</contributor><date>1984-08</date><subject>Polyomavirus</subject><title>A Genetic Analysis of Cellular Transformation by Polyomavirus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p272r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848s912</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bk128d410</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The synthesis and regulation of the capsular polysaccharide (CP) of N. meningitidis and its relationship to the virulence of this organism for mice were examined. Two spontaneous, isogenic mutants (PRM101 and PRM102) of the wildtype (Wt) strain M986, unable to synthesize and release CP, were isolated; both exhibiting a dramatic loss of virulence and a change of colony phenotype from iridescent to opaque. Wt virulence was regained upon reversion to the Wt phenotype. Strain PRM102 possessed only 25% of Wt sialyltransferase activity but had Wt levels of the N-acetylneuraminic acid (NANA) condensing enzyme and a cytidine 5'- monophospho-N-acetylneuraminic acid (CMP-NANA) synthetase. […]</description><description>Tenant cornpte de la synthèse et de la régulation du polysaccharide capsulaire (PC) de N. meningitidis, la virulence de cet organisme chez la souris a été examinée. Deux mutants isogonique (PRM101 et PRM102), provenant de mutations spontanées de la souche de type sauvage M986, mais incapables de synthétiser et de libérer le PC, ont été isolés. Ces deux mutants accusèrent une diminution considérable de leur virulence et une modification de la morphologie phénotypique des colonies, passent d'un aspect iridescent à un aspect opaque. Une réversion au phénotype sauvage a entrainé la réapparition de la virulence. La souche PRM102 présentait seulement 25% de l'activité de l'enzyme sialyltransférase de type sauvage, mais possédait la même activité que la souche sauvage en ce qui concerne l'enzyme responsable de la condensation de 1 'acide N-acétyl-neuraminique (‘’NANA’’) et la synthétase de la cytidine 5'-mono-phosphate et de l'acide N-acétyl-neuraminique ("CMP-NANA"). […]</description><creator>Masson, Luke</creator><contributor>Holbein, B. E.</contributor><date>1984-08</date><subject>Capsular Polysaccharide</subject><title>Physiology of Sialic Acid Capsular Polysaccharide Synthesis in Serogroup B Neisseria Meningitidis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827d977.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128d410</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150m400</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les gènes de la leghémoglobine (Lb) sont induits seulement après 1' infection de la légumineuse par le Rhizobium. Il y a quatre leghémoglobines majeures chez la fève soya qui sont codées par quatre gènes séparés. En parcourant le chromosome par hybridations successives dans des librairies génomiques Alui-Haeiii et EcoRI l’arrangement des genes de la leghémoglobine sur le chromosome de la fève soya a été analysé. Un groupe de quatre différents gènes de Lb ont été isolé des librairies dans un ensemble de clônes se chevauchant lesquels totalisent 45 kilobases (kb) d'ADN contigu.[…] </description><description>Leghemoglobin (Lb) genes are induced only following infection of the legume plant by Rhizobium. In soybean, there are four major leghemoglobins which are encoded by four separate genes. A chromosomal walk has been carried out to investigate the arrangement of these Lb genes on the soybean chromosome by screening Alui-Haeiii and EcoRI genomic libraries. A cluster of four different Lb genes was isolated from the libraries in a set of overlapping clones which together include 45 kilobases (kb) of contiguous OOA. […]</description><creator>Lee, Jong Seob</creator><contributor>Verma, Desh Pal S.</contributor><date>1984-07</date><subject>Soybean.</subject><subject>Gene mapping.</subject><subject>Kidney bean.</subject><title>Chromosomal Arrangement of Leghemoglobin Genes in Soybean and Kidney Bean</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hj004.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150m400</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:41687k59b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The characteristics and specificity of receptors for insulin, epidermal growth factor (EGF), and the insulin-like growth factors (IGFs), IGF-I and IGF-II, were studied in human early gestation and term placental cell cultures of syncytiotrophoblast origin. [125r]-1abeled peptides bound rapidly and reversibly to their cell surface receptors and exhibited a high degree of specificity. Maximal binding occurred at pH 7.5 and binding was proportional to cell protein and ligand concentrations. The placenta was found to be extremely rich in degrading activity for insulin and IGFs, but not for EGF. Bacitracin decreased the degradation of insulin and IGF peptides and was essential for the study of these peptides. […]</description><description>Les caractéristiques et spécificités des récepteurs à l'insuline au facteur de croissance épidermique (EGF), et aux facteurs de croissance insuliniques IGF-I et IGF-II, furent étudiés sur des cultures de cellules du syncytiotrophoblaste provenant de placentae de début de gestation et de placentae à terme. Les peptides marqués à l'iode 125 [125I] se liaient rapidement et réversiblement à leurs récepteurs membranaires et montraient un haut degré de spécificité. Le taux de liaison était maximal à pH 7.5 et était proportionnel à la concentration de proteine cellulaire et de chacun des peptides marqués. Il fut noté que le placenta possédait un pouvoir de dégradation de l'insuline et des IGFs extrêmement important, mais très faible dans le cas de l'EGF. La bacitracine diminuait la dégradation de l'insuline et des IGFs et était indispensable a l'étude de ces peptides. […]</description><creator>Lai, Wei H.</creator><contributor>Guyda, H. J.</contributor><date>1984-01</date><subject>Insulin</subject><title>Characterization of growth Factor Receptors in Human Placental Cells in Culture</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zw87q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687k59b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289m38z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>J'introduis une classe de théories totalement transcendantes (tt) dites « basic" et je demontre une théorème concernant la structure des modèles de ces théories. Tout module tt est "basic". Les théories modèle-complètes des modules introduites par Eklof et Sabbagh produisent des analogies puissantes entre la théorie des idéaux d1un anneau Noetherien et le traitement des types par stabilité. Je donne des démonstrations purement modèle théoriques du théorème de Matlis sur les modules injectifs et de Lasker-Noether sur la décomposition des idéaux. Je généralise ces resultats pour les théories tt de modules quelconque et donne une demonstration purement modele-théorique du théorème de Garavaglia sur la decomposition des modules tt. J'étends ces méthods aux modules topologique dans la logique topologique Lt. Je généralise le rang de Deissler pour les modèles minimaux afin d'analyser la complexité de l’enveloppe injective d'un module sur un anneau commutative Noetherien en fonction de la dimension de Krull. </description><description>I introduce a class of totally transcendental (tt) theories called basic and prove a structure theorem for the models of such a theory. Every tt module is basic. The model-complete theories of modules introduced by Eklof and Sabbagh provide some strong analogiés between the ideal theory of a Noetherian ring and the stability-theoretic treatment of types. I give purely model-theoretic proofs of Matlis• theorem on injective modules and the Lasker-Noether decomposition of ideals. I generalize these results to arbitrary tt theories of modules and give a purely model-theoretic proof of Garavaglia•s theorem on the decomposition of tt modules. I extend these methods to topological modules in the topological logic Lt • I generalize Deissler•s rank for minimal models in order to analyze the complexity of the injective envelope of a module over a commutative Noetherian ring in terms of Krull dimension.</description><creator>Kucera, Thomas Glen</creator><date>1984-08</date><subject>Model theory.</subject><subject>Modules (Algebra)</subject><title>Applications of Stability-Theoretical Methods to Theories of Modules</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343v39b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289m38z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:41687k603</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La présente thèse porte sur le droit et les institutions juridiques relies à l'industrie pétrolière de Trinidad et Tobago. Elle cherche à évaluer si ce droit et ces institutions permettent à l'État d'atteindre les objectifs qu'il a énonces et dans quelle mesure ils créent une structure juridique et administrative efficace pour la réglementation de l’industrie. […]</description><description>This work has, through an in-depth assessment of the law and institutions employed in the petroleum industry in Trinidad and Tobago, evaluated their viability in achieving declared state objectives and in providing a legal and administrative framework for regulating this industry. […]</description><creator>Khan, Kameel I.F.</creator><contributor>Groffier-Atala, Ethel</contributor><date>1984-03</date><subject>Petroleum</subject><title>The Legal and Administrative Regulation of the Petroleum Industry in Trinidad and Tobago: A Study of Law and Policy in Petroleum Development</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526f66w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687k603</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z7090227</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>De nos jours, la construction des modèles macroéconomiques pour économies ouvertes dans la tradition monétaire a été enterprise suivant l’approche monétaire de la balance des paiements. Même si la structure générale de cette approche réprésente un cadre souple a partir duquel on peut développer un modèle macroéconomique complète, sa version populaire constitue une version polaire, dont l’utilité pour une économie ouverte et sous-développée comme le Bangladesh est limitée. En prenant l'approche générale monétaire comme point de départ et en tenant compte des réalités des économies sous-développé, cette thèse tente de construire et d’estimer un modèle macroéconomique trimestriel du Bangladesh pour la période allant du troisième trimestre de 1972 au deuxième trimestre de 1981. Considérant la répartition sectorielle ainsi que les relations comportementales et non-comportementales, le modèle contient des caractéristiques distinctives. En effect, la thèse a donné un cadre analytique pour l’étude des comportements des principaux variables microéconomiques du Bangladesh et aussi pour les prescriptions des politiques bien définies. Elle offre aussi la base pour des recherches semblables dans d'autres économies sous- développés.</description><description>Recently, the building of open-economy macroeconomic models in the monetary tradition has largely proceeded along the lines of the modern monetary approach to the balance of payments. Even though the basic general structure of this approach represents a versatile framework from which a complete macroeconomic model can be built, its common version is a polar one and is of limited value for an open, underdeveloped economy like Bangladesh. Taking the general monetary approach as its starting point and considering the realities of underdeveloped economies, this dissertation builds and estimates a quarterly macroeconomic model for Bangladesh for the period 1972 QIII - 1981 QII. The model has several distinctive features in terms of sectoral division and behavioural and non-behavioural relations. The present dissertation provides an analytical framework for studying the behaviours of the major macroeconomic variables of Bangladesh and for making some definite policy prescriptions. It also provides scope for similar research for other underdeveloped economies.</description><creator>Jahan, Selima</creator><contributor>Handa, J.</contributor><date>1984-07</date><subject>Balance of payments -- Bangladesh.</subject><subject>Macroeconomics.</subject><subject>Bangladesh -- Economic conditions.</subject><title>Money, Income and the Balance of Payments of Bangladesh : A Macroeconomic Model</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kd100.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z7090227</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q811kn193</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of this thesis is to present coherently the theory of ringoids from a purely ring theoretical point of view. Chapter 1, 2 and 3 are devoted to extend the results in theory of non-commutative rings to ringoids. In Chapter 4 we characterize torsion theories in abelian categories by using techniques in topos theory. In Chapter 5 and 6 we apply the results in previous chapters to characterize torsion theories in ringoids and prove the additive Giraud's theorem.</description><description>Le but de cette thèse est de présenter de façon cohérente la théorie des annoides vue A travers la théorie des anneaux. Dans les trois premiers chapitres nous prolongeons des résultats de la théorie des anneaux non-commutatifs à la théorie des annoides. Dans le quatrième chapitre, nous donnons une caractérisation des théories de torsion en utilisant des méthodes de la théorie des topos. Dans les chapitres 5 et 6, nous appliquons les résultats des chapitres antérieurs au problème de la caractérisation des théories de torsion et démontrons une version additive du théorème de Giraud.</description><creator>Chu, Po Hsiang</creator><date>1984-06</date><subject>Categories (Mathematics)</subject><subject>Abelian categories.</subject><subject>Rings (Algebra)</subject><title>Theory of Ringoids</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sw28w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811kn193</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j792p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le dosage biochimique des récepteurs ostrogéniques dans les adénocarcinomes mammaires humains a un intérêt clinique bien établi, cependant la localisation cellulaire des sites de liaison aux œstrogènes dans ces tumeurs demeure incertaine. Les travaux décrits dans cette thèse ont permis d'identifier les sites de liaison de l'oestradiol au moyen de l'autoradiographie après incubation in vitro dans une série de 57 cas de lésions mammaires dont 17 étaient bénignes et 40 étaient des adénocarcinomes. Les résultats obtenus avec la méthode d'incubation in vitro se comparent favorablement avec ceux obtenus dans des études in vivo portant sur l'utérus de souris, un organe cible des œstrogènes bien caractérise. Dans les lésions mammaires bénignes une proportion variable des cellules épithéliales contenaient des sites spécifiques de liaison ostrogénique. Les cellules myoépithéliales lorsqu'elles pouvaient être identifiées et les cellules stromales étaient en général négatives. Les adénocarcinomes mammaires avec un dosage de récepteur ostrogénique positif contenaient à la fois des cellules épithéliales marquées et des cellules négatives. Les résultats quantitatifs obtenus avec la méthode autoradiographique se comparent favorablement avec ceux obtenus avec les méthodes biochimiques.</description><description>The biochemical assay of human mammary carcinomas for estrogen receptors is of proven clinical utility, but the cellular localization of estrogen binding siteswithin these lesions is less certain. This thesis describes the identification of estrogen binding sites as visualized by thaw-mount autoradiography after in vitro incubation in a series of 17 benign and 40 malignant human female mammary lesions. The results of the in vitro incubation method compared favorably with data from in vivo studies in mouse uterus, a well-characterized estrogen target organ. In noncancerous breast biopsies a variable proportion of epithelial cells contained specific estrogen binding sites. Histologically identifiable myoepithelial and stromal cells were, in general, unlabeled. In human mammary carcinomas, biochemically estrogen receptor-positive, labeled and unlabeled neoplastic epithelial cells were identified by autoradiography. Quantitative results from the autoradiographic method compared favorably with biochemical data.</description><creator>Buell, Richard H.</creator><contributor>Tremblay, Gilles</contributor><date>1984</date><subject>Estrogen receptors</subject><title>The Autoradiographic Localization of Estrogen Binding Sites in Human Mammary Lesions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494b707.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j792p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f842x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>On a observé les enregistrements extra-cellulaires venant des neurones de l’hypothalamus médian pour démontrer les connexions avec l’éminence médiane, la tige pituitaire, le septum latéral, l’amygdale, la région pré-optique hypothalamique antérieure et “PAG”. Des programmes d’ordinateur interactifs et des programmes et données de base out été utilisés pour l’analyse des résultats. On a démontré que certain certains neurones tubéro-infundibulaires identifies par la projection de leur axone ver l’éminence médiane se divisent en plusieurs branches vers la tige pituitaire. […]</description><description>Extracellular recordings from medial hypothalamic neurons were examined for ecidence of connections with the median eminence, pituitary stalk, lateral septum, amygdala, pre-optic-anterior hypothalamic area and PAG. On-line computer programs and data base management programs assisted in data analysis. Certain tuberoinfundibular neurons, identified be evidence of axonal projection to the median eminence, demonstrated axon branching to the pituitary stalk. Some paraventricular nucleus neurons, including putative vasopressinergic neurosecretory cells, demonstrated axon branching to the median eminence and the pituitary stalk. […]</description><creator>Blume, Howard W.</creator><contributor>Renaud, Leo P.</contributor><date>1984-03</date><subject>Medial hypothalamic neurons</subject><title>An Electrophysiological Study of the Connections and Neuropharmacology of Medial Hypothalamic Neurons of the Rat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m652n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f842x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04ds02j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis critical reflection is exposed to the epistemological critique directed by Michel Foucault against the human sciences in order to determine what grounds remain for a notion of the subject in communications theory. The Western heretical tradition of gnosis known asthe Hermetic tradition is discussed on the basis of the etymological relation of Hermes to hermeneutics. This relationship is examined in the context of a reflection on the political significance of heresy. The structure of the hermetic sign is discussed from the point of view of Neoplatonism which is taken to form part of the hermetic tradition. […]</description><description>Dans cette thèse la pensée critique est mise dans le champ épistemologique délimité par Michel Foucault afin de déterminer a quel titre on pourrait se former une notionexacte du sujet dans les sciences humaines. La tradition hérétique de la gnose qui porte le titre hermetisme est examiné au point de vue de la relation étymologique du nom Hermes à hermeneutique. Cette question est débattue dans le contexte d'une consideration de la signification politique de la hérésie. Aussi, la structure du signe dans le Néoplatonisme est examinée en raison de son affinité avec l'hermétisme. […]</description><creator>Biel, Kent</creator><date>1984-05</date><subject>Gnosticism.</subject><subject>Hermeneutics.</subject><subject>Foucault, Michel, 1926-1984.</subject><title>Critical Reflection and the Hermetic Tradition : A Study of Michel Foucault’s Politics of the Imagination and Subjectivity in Relation to the Western Counter-Tradition of Gnosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149s08f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04ds02j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Communications</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bk128d428</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette étude porte sur les propriétés physiques d'un nouvel ionomère, un aromatique carboxylé, ainsi que son précurseur. Seul le système ayant un poids équivalent de 600 fut étudié en profondeur, sous forme de membranes d'une épaisseur de ca. 150 um. […]</description><description>This thesis describes the investigation of the physical properties of an aromatic carboxylate ionomer system and its non-ionic precursor. The study is focused onmicroporous films (ca. 150 um in thickness) of 600 equivalent weight. These materials were studied with the dual objectives of investigating the structure-property relationsin a novel ionomer system and of exploring its viability as a separator in alkaline water electrolysis. […]</description><creator>Besso, Erica</creator><contributor>Eisenberg, A.</contributor><date>1984-05</date><subject>Polymers.</subject><subject>Aromatic compounds.</subject><subject>Ionomers.</subject><title>Mechanical Properties and Supermolecular Structure of Aromatic Carboxylate Ionomers and Their Non-Ionic Precursors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kw230.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128d428</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cn69m653x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is concerned with problems of current interest in the computer-aided simulation of synchronous machines. It deals with the application of the finite element method in the computation of generator terminal parameters and the simulation of steady-state operation. A linear transformation is described which is shown to be very useful in the modeling of electric machines as well as post processing the data obtained from a finite element program. Using this transformation, the space and time harmonic content of the waveforms are considered in the computations. […]</description><description>Cette thèse traite de problèmes d’interêt actuel dans le domaine de la conception assistée par ordinateur de machines synchrones. De façon plus spécifique, la méthode des éléments finis a été appliquée au calcul des impédances du circuit équivalent et à la simulation du fonctionnement en régime permanent de ces machines. Une transformation linéaire particulièrement utile est décrite on démontre son utilité pour la modélisation des machines aussi bien que pour le traitement des données issues d'un programme d'éléments finis. En utilisant cette transformation, On arrive à tenir compte à la fois des harmoniques spatiales et temporelles dans les calculs. […]</description><creator>Bélanger-Grou, Hélène</creator><contributor>Stern, Muriel</contributor><date>1984-03</date><subject>Rats -- Behavior.</subject><subject>Aldehydes -- Physiological effect.</subject><subject>Alcohol -- Physiological effect.</subject><title>Preference For and Tolerance to Ethanol : Acetaldehyde Involvement</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cs93c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m653x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g732dc29v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The relationship between organic and mineral components was studied in rat incisor enamel using transmission electron microscopy, freeze-fracture replicas and radioautography. The two categories of matrix proteins were separately visualized. Amelogenins constituted non-structural, heterodispersed material in the intercrystallite space. They contributed significantly to the randomized behavior of labeled proteins seen with radioautography. […]</description><description>La relation entre les composantes organiques et minérales de l’email de l’incisive du rat à été étudié à l’aide de la microscopie électronique, du cryodécapage et de la radioautographie. Les deux catégories de protéines de la matrice ont été visualisées séparément. Les amélogénines constituent un matériel non-structural et sont dispersées de manière hétérogène dans l’espace entre les cristaux. Ces protéines marquées tel que visualisé par radioautographie. […]</description><creator>Bai, Paul Shin Woo</creator><contributor>Warshawsky, Hershey</contributor><date>1984-08</date><subject>Transmission electron microscopy</subject><subject>Organic matrix</subject><title>The Structure and Relationship Between the Organic Matrix and the Crystallites in Rat Incisor Enamel</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vt30p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732dc29v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z316q3922</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is concerned with problems of current interest in the computer-aided simulation of synchronous machines. It deals with the application of the finite element method in the computation of generator terminal parameters and the simulation of steady-state operation. A linear transformation is described which is shown to be very useful in the modeling of electric machines as well as post processing the data obtained from a finite element program. Using this transformation, the space and time harmonic content of the waveforms are considered in the computations. […]</description><description>Cette thèse traite de problèmes d’interêt actuel dans le domaine de la conception assistée par ordinateur de machines synchrones. De façon plus spécifique, la méthode des éléments finis a été appliquée au calcul des impédances du circuit équivalent et à la simulation du fonctionnement en régime permanent de ces machines. Une transformation linéaire particulièrement utile est décrite on démontre son utilité pour la modélisation des machines aussi bien que pour le traitement des données issues d'un programme d'éléments finis. En utilisant cette transformation, On arrive à tenir compte à la fois des harmoniques spatiales et temporelles dans les calculs. […]</description><creator>Ashtiani, Cyrus N.</creator><contributor>Lowther, D. A.</contributor><date>1984-03</date><subject>Computer simulation.</subject><subject>Electric machinery, Synchronous.</subject><subject>Finite element method.</subject><title>Computer-Aided Simulation of Synchronous Machines by Finite Elements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn1071432.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q3922</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hh63sz388</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Three apple genotypes, Ottawa 3, Malus robusta No. 5, and Macspur (juvenile and adult phases) were successfully propagated in vitro. Normal shoot cultures of Ottawa 3 were obtained only on sucrose medium containing combinations of benzyladenine, naphthaleneacetic acid or indolebutyric acid (IBA), and gibberellic acid. Sorbitol was aprerequisite for growth of meristem tip explants and was most beneficial for shoot proliferation of M.robusta. Juvenile phase Macspur cultures maintained on sucrose medium grew equally well when subcultured on sorbitol and sucrose media, and showed a significantly higher shoot number than corresponding adult phase cultures; shoot proliferation of adult phase cultures was best on sorbitol medium. […]</description><description>La culture in vitro de trois génotypes de pommiers, Ottawa 3, Malus robusta No. 5, et Macspur (phase juvénile et adulte) a été réalisée. La croissance normale de la tige d'Ottawa 3 n'est obtenue que sur milieu au sucrose contenant un mélange de benzyladénine, d'acide naphthalèneacétique ou d'acide indolebutyrique (AIB) et d'acide gibbérellique. Le sorbitol est essentiel à la croissance des explantats de points végétatifs et stimule à un niveau significatif la prolifération des tiges de M. robusta. Les tissus de Macspur en phase juvénile entretenus sur milieu au sucrose, lorsque repiques, se développent aussi bien sur milieu au sucrose que sur milieu au sorbitol, et produisent un plus grand nombre de tiges que les tissus en phase adulte. La prolifération des tiges dans les cultures des tissus en phase adulte est la plus forte sur milieu au sorbitol. […]</description><creator>Pua, Eng-Chong</creator><contributor>Chong, C.</contributor><date>1983</date><subject>Apples.</subject><subject>Plant growing media, Artificial.</subject><subject>Plant propagation.</subject><title>Morphogenesis and Physiology of Malus Tissues and Cells in Vitro</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547t91q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sz388</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rb68xf13k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the present work, we characterized T-cell populations induced by thymic microenvironmental fractions. We show that three populations of Thy-1 positive cells belonging to two different T cell lineages can be distinguished. In the first lineage, E-Thy-l cells {population I) are induced by ITF from bone marrow Thy-1 negative precursors. These E-Thy-l cells, in turn, after incubation with STF become F-Thy-1 cells (population II). In the second lineage, E-Thy-l cells {population III) are also derived from the bone marrow but they are induced by STF and cannot be further differentiated as in the case of population II. In the GvH reaction, populations I and II are probably amplifier cells, while population Ill are the effectors. Finally, in the present work, we have solubilized a biologically active thymic microenvironmental factor (ITF) by peritoneal macrophages acting on the migration of bone arrow cells to the thymus.</description><description>Dans le présent travail, nous avons caractérisé les sous populations de cellules T induites par le stroma thymique. Nous démontrons que trois sous-populations de cellules Thy-1 positives appartenant à deux lignées de différenciation sont induites par l’ITF et/ou le STF. Dans la première lignée, des cellules E-Thy-l (sous population I) sont induites par 1 'ITF à partir de précurseurs Thy-1 négatifs venant de la moelle osseuse. Ces cellules sont ensuite différentiées en cellules F-Thy-1 (sous-population II) par le STF. Dans la deuxième lignée, des cellules E-Thy-l (sous-population III) proviennent aussi de précurseurs Thy-1 négatifs, mais elles sont induites par le STF et ne peuvent être différentiées ultérieurement en cellules F-Thy-1. L1etude des fonctions de ces sous-populations dans la réaction GvH montre que les sous-populations I et II sont probablement amplificatrices tandis que la sous-population Ill représente les effectrices. Puis, finalement, dans ce travail, nous avons solubilise l'élément actif de 11 ITF membranaire par les macrophages péritonéaux agissant sur la migration des précurseurs de cellules T au thymus.</description><creator>Paquette, Manon</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Stroma thymique</subject><title>Participation du Stroma Thymique Dans la Differenciation de Sous-Populations de Cellules T</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bw909.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xf13k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440w13n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La Cartographie Dynamique est définie, revue et examinée du point de vue de son défaut de répondre aux changements technologiques qui influencent la plus grande partie de la cartographie générale. Une paradigme du mouvement cartographique qui décrive tous les mouvements sur une carte à l'égard de la direction, du volume et de l'étalage s'est créé. Le modèle du mouvement cartographique est développé pour donner les mouvements sur une carte en dimensions quantitatives. La technique de créer la cartographie dynamique est appliquée aux éléments du mouvement du sol et aux éléments du vent pour éprouver l'utilité et la sécurité de telles cartes geographiques. Des programmes d'ordinateur sont introduits pour automatiser le procès de créer des cartes de mouvement qui sont évoluées des étalages graphique et qualitatives aux instruments quantitatifs et analytiques. En somme, le chercheur croit que pour que la cartographie dynamique se développé au-delà de sa stagnation actuelle, on doit faire des tentatives pour la rendre quantitative plutôt que qualitative la ou les produits doivent être dessinés pour l'analyse plutôt que limites à l'étalage. Cette thèse pourvoie une telle tentative. </description><description>Dynamic Cartography is defined, reviewed and examined in light of its failure to respond to the technological changes presently affecting the major part of general cartography. A paradigm of cartographic movement is created which describes all mappable movements in terms of direction, volume and velocity. The Cartographic Movement Model is developed to give mappable movements quantitative dimensions. The technique of creating movement maps is applied to solifluction data and wind data in order to test the usefullness and reliability of such maps. Computer programs are introduced to automate the process of creating movement maps which have evolved from qualitative graphic displays to quantitative analytical tools. In summary, the researcher believes that in order for Dynamic Cartography to develop beyond its present stagnation, attempts must be made to make it quantitative rather than qualitative, where the products should be designed for analysis rather than limited to display. This thesis provides one such attempt.</description><creator>Millette, Thomas L.</creator><date>1983-04</date><subject>Solifluction -- Maps.</subject><subject>Geomorphological mapping -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Cartography -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Dynamic Cartography: The Mapping of Movement and Change, A Cartographic Treatment of Some Geomorphological Processes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r0890.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440w13n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8p58pg360</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nous calculons les fonctions du groupe de renormalisation y(n) et y ns (n) nécessaires a l'évaluation perturbative de la fonction de structure G1(q2) pour la diffusion polarisée d'électrons par des protons, jusqu'à l'ordre g4 de chromodynamique quantique (QCD). Nous utilisons pour ces calculs la méthode de régularisation dimensionnelle et le système de soustraction minimale. Nous présentons les résultats obtenus pour y(n) et yn (n) sous forme analytique et calculons aussi leur valeur numérique pour n = 2, 4, 6, ... , 20. Finalement nous évaluons le deuxièmes moment de G1(q 2) en QCD avec 4 et 6 saveurs de quarks en considérant les coefficients de Wilson comme des inconnues. </description><description>We compute the anomalous dimension y(n) and Yns (n) needed in the evaluation of the polarized structure function G1 ( q2 ) in electron-proton scattering, up to and including the order g4 contributions in the minimal subtraction scheme in perturbative QCD. Both the analytic expression and the numerical result for y(n) and Yns (n) with n = 2, 4, 6, …, 20 are obtained. We also evaluate the second moment of flavor singlet and the flavor non-singlet part of G1 ( q2 ) in QCD, with 4 and 6 flavors with the Wilson coefficients left as unknowns.</description><creator>Marleau, Guy</creator><contributor>Lam, C. S.</contributor><date>1983-01</date><subject>Electrons.</subject><subject>Polarization (Nuclear physics)</subject><subject>Protons -- Scattering.</subject><title>Deep Inelastic Polarized Electron-Proton Scattering in QCD</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tv067.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pg360</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn301383x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les différences entre les processus de résolution de problèmes appliques par des enfants doués et des enfants normaux ont été analysées, selon le langage de programmation Logo. Repartis en paires, seize enfants de 9 à 11 ans ont suivi un cours de géométrie "Turtle" d'une durée de dix semaines. Un système de classification des protocoles d'analyse, conçu en 1978 et augmenté aux fins de la présente étude, a été utilise pour l'examen des différences entre les processus de résolution de problèmes pour ce qui est du style de programmation (réseaux de traitement), du type et de la fréquence des erreurs (erreurs), des stratégies d'adaptation concomitantes (mesures de mise au point) et de la relation existant entre les erreurs et les stratégies commises et utilisées par les enfants doués et les enfants normaux. L'étude se complète d'un modèle de résolution de problèmes s'adressant à des débutants en programmation et s'inscrivant dans un contexte de projets axes sur un objectif.</description><description>The differences in the process of problem-solving by gifted and non-gifted chi!dren using the Logo programming language are analyzed. Working in pairs, sixteen 9-11 year old children were taught Turtle geometry for a ten-week period. A classification system of protocol analysis, developed in 1978 and extended for the present study, was employed to examine differences in problem-solving in terms of programming style (procedural nets), types and frequencies of errors {bugs), concomitant coping strategies (debugging actions), and the relationship between errors and strategies for the gifted and non-gifted children. A model of problem-solving for beginners in programming in the context of goal-directed projects is proposed.</description><creator>Maniatis, Eustathia Georgiou</creator><contributor>Cartwright, Glenn F.</contributor><date>1983-06</date><subject>Child psychology.</subject><subject>Problem solving in children.</subject><subject>LOGO (Computer program language)</subject><title>An Analysis of the Differences in Problem-Solving of Gifted and Non-Gifted Children Using the Logo Programming Language</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816p87z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301383x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wj46m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Afin d'élucider le rôle du tronc cérébral clans le contrôle des états de veille-sommeil, du sommeil paradoxal en particulier, une nouvelle méthode informatisée de quantification, représentation graphique et classification automatique des données électrographiques a été developpée. La concordance entre les classifications automatique et traditionelle s'est prouvée satisfaisante. L'application de cette méthode a permis une analyse quantitative et objective des effets de diverses lésions sur les états de veille-sommeil. Une comparaison entre les effets de lésions à l'intérieur du tegmentum pontique a demontré que les structures du tegmentum latéral sont essentielles à la génération de l'état de sommeil paradoxal, tandis que le champ du tegmentum gigantocellulaire ne joue qu'un rôle mineur. Des considérations anatomiques suggèrent que les cellules du tegmentum latéral contribuent d'une façon significative à un système réticulaire ponto-bulbaire qui pourrait être le substrat anatomique essentiel à la génération du sommeil paradoxal.</description><description>To further elucidate the role of the brain stem in the control of sleep-wakefulness states, and paradoxical sleep in particular, a new computer method for the quantification, graphic representation and classification of sleep-wakefulness electrographic data has been developed for cats, using computer graphics and cluster analysis. Correspondence between the present method and traditional classification was satisfactory. Application of the method has allowed for a graphic and objective assessment of the effects of lesions on sleep-wakefulness states. Comparison of effects of lesions within the pontine tegmentum has suggested that structures within the lateral tegmentum are essential for the generation of the state of paradoxical sleep, whereas the gigantocellular tegmental field appears to play a minor role. Anatomical considerations have suggested that cells in the lateral tegmentum contribute significantly to a longitudinal reticular fiber projection system which may be the critical anatomical substrate for the generation of paradoxical sleep. </description><creator>Friedman, Lee</creator><contributor>Jones, Barbara E.</contributor><date>1983-05</date><subject>Sleep-wakefulness</subject><title>Application of Computer Graphics and Cluster Analysis to the Study of Sleep-Wakefulness States Before and After Pontine Tegmental Lesions in the Cat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322g83d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wj46m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5138jh03b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:38:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse propose une exploration et une contexualisation du projet monumental d'Elizabeth Barrett Browning dans son poème narratif Aurora Leigh (1856), qui est celui de construire une poétique du sujet féminin.  Notre point de vue méthodologique s'appuie sur deux appareils théoriques: la sémiotique intertextuelle et la critique littéraire féministe. Les Chapitres Deux et Trois abordent une problématique de contexte à l'égard d'Aurora Leigh à travers l'examen d'une tradition d'auto-réflexivité dans les écrits féminins de la fin du XVIIe siècle au début du XIXe, et une analyse du discours hégémonique sur la "femme" du début de l'époque Victorienne. Dans les Chapitres Quatre et Cinque nous examinons l'évolution d'une poétique du sujet féminin chez Elizabeth Barrett Browning. Enfin, le Chapitre Six consiste en l'analyse de la littérature critique sur Aurora Leigh depuis la date de sa publication jusqu'aujourd'hui, ceci dans l'optique des deux préoccupations majeures de notre travail: (1) la construction d'un sujet poétique  féminin dans Aurora Leigh, et (2) la position relative de ce projet a l'intérieur du contexte hégémonique et du contexte d'une tradition d'autoréflexivité féminine.</description><description>The dissertation explores and contextualizes Elizabeth Barrett Browning's monumental endeavor, in Aurora Leigh (1856), of constructing a poetics of the female subject. Methodologically, the thesis draws on two theoretical frameworks: intertextual semiotics and feminist literary criticism; these frameworks are delineated in the Introductory Chapter. Chapters Two and Three propose a problem-context for Aurora Leigh by examining a tradition of self-reflexivity in women's writing from the late seventeenth century to the early nineteenth century, and by analysing the early Victorian hegemonic discourse on femininity. The evolution of a poetics of the female subject in Elizabeth Barrett Browning's canon is then explored in Chapters Four and Five. This poetics is seen to evolve out of the paradigm of the "poet's life" and to involve three sets of relationships: between the poet and the world; between the poet and the predecessors; within the poet: between female identity and poetic self. Finally, Chapter Six surveys the critical literature on Aurora Leigh from the date of its publication to the present day, with particular emphasis on the two major concerns of the present work, namely, (1) the poem's exploration of the problematics of a female poetic subject, and (2) the relative position of this endeavor both within the hegemonic context and within the context of a tradition of self-reflexivity in women's writing. […]</description><creator>Freiwald, Bina</creator><contributor>Gopnick, Irwin</contributor><date>1983-04</date><subject>Women poets.</subject><subject>Browning, Elizabeth Barrett, 1806-1861. Aurora Leigh.</subject><subject>Women in literature.</subject><title>The Printing Woman’s Proper Sphere: The Discursive Moment of Elizabeth Barret Browning’s</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bw91k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5138jh03b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):5075</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>