<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:59:14Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2350" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225d18f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this study was to determine if teaching the new sugar guidelines, which now permit up to 10% of energy from added sugars, would modify dietary habits, metabolic control and perceived quality of life in free-living subjects with type 2 diabetes. In an eight month randomized controlled trial, 48 subjects with type 2 diabetes were taught, by a trained dietitian, either a conventional diabetic meal plan: conventional group (C) or one in which they could integrate the new sugar guidelines: sugar group (S). Patients were seen at the clinic every 2 months (total of 5 visits) by the dietitian and the endocrinologist. During the pre-randomization period (0 to 4 months) all subjects were taught the conventional diabetic diet and advised to avoid concentrated sugars. Randomization to the C or the S group took place at the 4 month visit (4 to 8 month period = post-randomization). The S group were taught how to use and integrate the Canadian Diabetes Association's new sugar choices (e.g. added sugar: honey, regular jam, white sugar, etc) into their daily diabetic meal plan. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Nadeau, Julie.</creator><date>1998</date><subject>Non-insulin-dependent diabetes -- Nutritional aspects.</subject><subject>Sugar.</subject><title>The impact of introducing dietary sugar in the meal plan of free-living subjects with type 2 diabetes /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f5728.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225d18f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tp08k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Glutathione S-transferases (GSTS), a family of isozymes that catalyzes the conjugation of glutathione to a variety of electrophiles, protect cellular constituents from electrophilic and oxidative attack. Aging is associated with an overall increase in oxidative stress and thus free radical production. The present study examines the immunocytochemical localization of Ya, Yc, Yb1, Yb2, Yo, and Yf GST subunits in the testis and epididymis of Brown Norway rats aged 3, 12, 18, and 24 months. In the testis, neither Sertoli nor germ cells showed changes in GST staining pattern during aging. At 24 months, two types of Leydig cells were noted. Some (peritubular) formed a distinct band at the periphery of the tubule while others were seen in the interstitial space. The peritubular cells were identified as Leydig calls by specific staining for 3beta-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase (3beta-HSD), a Leydig cell specific marker. Both types of Leydig cells were intensely reactive for all GST subunits at all ages. In the epididymis, principal cells of all epididymal regions, except the proximal cauda region, showed no changes in GST expression at all ages examined. At 24 months, some principal cells of this region became greatly enlarged and vacuolated. These cells were unreactive for Yo, Yb1, Yb2 and Yc, while adjacent normally appearing principal cells maintained the same intensity of expression as seen in 3 month controls. In contrast, vacuolated principal cells were reactive for the Ya subunit, while adjacent normal principal cells were unreactive. These data indicate that selective changes occur in the expression of GM at 24 months in principal cells having both a normal and a vacuolated appearance. Taken together, these data show that aging affects region-specific changes in GST expression in the epididymis and Leydig cell distribution in the testis. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Mueller, Andréa.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Biology, Anatomy.</subject><title>The effects of aging on the expression of glutathione s- transferases in the testis and epididymis of the brown Norway rat /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh750.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tp08k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sj406</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Boltzmann equation for the diffusion of Hawking radiation from microscopic black holes is solved using the test particle method. Formation of a dense cloud of interacting particles analogous to the photosphere of the Sun is confirmed. We find that at least two kinds of photospheres may form: a quark-gluon plasma for black holes of mass MBH &amp;sime; 5 x 1014 g and an electron-positron-photon plasma for MBH &amp;sime; 2 x 1012 g. The QCD photosphere extends from the black hole horizon for a distance of 0.2--4.0 fm for 109 g &amp;sime; MBH &amp;sime;5 x 1014 g, at which point quarks and gluons with average energy of order ΛQCD hadronize. The QED photosphere starts at a distance of approximately 700 black hole radii and dissipates at about 400 fin, where the average energy of the emitted electrons, positrons and photons is inversely proportional to the black hole temperature. Possible consequences of these photospheres are discussed.</description><creator>Mostoslavsky, Michael.</creator><date>1998</date><subject>Physics, Astronomy and Astrophysics.</subject><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>Hawking radiation photosphere around microscopic black holes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k9371.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sj406</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26z056n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The fibrous sheath (FS) is a cytoskeletal structure that encases the axoneme in the principal piece of the spermatozoon tail. In the rat, it is composed of several proteins of which a 75 kDa polypeptide (FS 75) is the most prominent. The objectives of this study were to clone and sequence this protein and to characterize its transcriptional and translational origins during spermatogenesis. We succeeded in isolating two overlapping cDNAs encoding half of the downstream segment of the FS 75 protein. Both clones were obtained by screening a rat testicular phagemid cDNA library with an anti-FS 75 polyclonal antibody. The upstream portion of the FS 75 mRNA containing the initiation codon for translation was obtained by using the Polymerase Chain Reaction (PCR) technique, a pair of specific primers and a lambdagt11 cDNA rat library. The amino acid sequence of the longest possible open reading frame of the rat FS 75 was found to be almost identical to two previously cloned major FS polypeptides of mouse spermatozoa. Sequence analysis of the rat FS 75 cDNA revealed two A&amp;barbelow;-K&amp;barbelow;inase A&amp;barbelow;nchoring P&amp;barbelow;rotein (AKAP) domains and several kinase phosphorylation sites supporting the idea that this protein plays a crucial role in the motility of spermatozoa. The presence of a potential N-mistoylation site suggests that this protein may bind covalently to the inner leaflet of the plasma membrane (PM) which may explain the close relationship between the FS and PM from early development in round spermatids (step 2 of spermiogenesis) to maturation in spermatozoa. Developmental Northern Blot analysis and in situ hybridization revealed that the FS 75 mRNA is mainly haploid expressed with an abundant level of mRNA in round spermatids. Maximum levels of the FS 75 polypeptide, determined by immunocytochemistry, correlated with a rapid decline in corresponding mRNA levels in step 14--16 spermatids. Since transcriptional termination occurs several steps earlier</description><creator>Moshonas, Demetra.</creator><date>1998</date><subject>Health Sciences, Human Development.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Molecular cloning and developmental expression of the 75 kDa protein of the rat fibrous sheath</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483m31h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z056n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h665z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Following fertilization, the embryo undergoes a sequence of precisely timed cleavage cycles to produce a blastocyst. The timing of these cycles likely depends in part on appropriate levels of gene activity. I have investigated whether high mobility group (HMG) proteins 14 and 17, which are associated with chromatin containing transcribed genes, are expressed in mouse embryos and are required to maintain normal early developmental timing. As assayed using RT-PCR, mRNAs encoding both HMG-14 and HMG-17 were present throughout preimplantation development to the blastocyst stage. By immunofluorescence, both proteins were detected in the nuclei of prophase I-arrested oocytes and embryos beginning at the 2-cell stage. To investigate their function, antisense oligonucleotides targeting the 5' end of each mRNA species were injected into 1-cell stage embryos which were then cultured to develop to the blastocyst stage. At the 2- and 4-cell stages, only weak nuclear immunofluorescence was observed; however, by the 8-cell stage, the staining pattern of injected embryos was indistinguishable from controls. Thus, the injected antisense oligonucleotides transiently depleted the cellular supply of HMG-14 and HMG-17. Furthermore, the embryos in which both HMG-14 and MAG-17 had been depleted progressed significantly more slowly through successive stages of preimplantation development, as compared with embryos in which the proteins were individually depleted or injected with nonsense oligonucleotides. Therefore, it can be concluded that depletion of HMG-14 and HMG-17 from embryonic chromatin transiently delays preimplantation development, demonstrating a crucial role for these proteins in maintaining the normal temporal coordination of development.</description><creator>Mohamed, Othman A.</creator><date>1998</date><subject>Chromatin.</subject><subject>Mice -- Development.</subject><title>Functional role of high mobility group proteins 14 and 17 during early mouse development</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d638m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h665z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c534fr061</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis discusses the measurement of the dE/ dx resolution of the BaBar drift chamber. The study was performed on the data obtained with a small scale prototype drift chamber (built at LAPP, Annecy, France) during test beam runs at CERN (PS) and Zurich (PSI). Drift chamber simulations were performed in order to study the expected performance. Good tracking, necessary in the analysis of the PS runs but unnecessary in the PSI runs, was obtained by performing a chi2 minimization of the space residuals, yielding a time to distance function. An average tracking resolution of ≈350mum was achieved. The resolution result for seven energy loss samplings per event was scaled up to 40 samples per event which will be available in the BaBar chamber. The expected dE/ dx resolution of the BaBar chamber, as obtained from the PS runs, is: (7.3 +/- 0.1 +/- 0.5)%. The result from the PSI runs is: (6.9 +/- 0.4 +/- 0.5)%.</description><creator>Milek, Marko.</creator><date>1998</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>Specific ionization in a drift chamber filled with helium-isobutane</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gg169.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fr061</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cn69m622x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A mesoscale model with a horizontal resolution of 20 km was used to perform a simulation of the rapidly deepening continental cyclone of 19--21 July 1996 that produced heavy precipitation and severe flooding in the Saguenay region of Quebec, Canada. Sensitivity experiments were conducted and diagnostics performed to investigate the interactions and relative importance of the forcing mechanisms that led to the explosive cyclogenesis and heavy precipitation. It is found that condensational heating is integral for the establishment of a phase lock between the surface cyclone and a strong, upper-level short wave trough which steers the cyclone. A weaker trough acts to retard the progression of the stronger trough, ultimately causing the cyclone to be located in a favorable position to interact with orography. Using potential vorticity (PV) inversion diagnostics, the relative contributions to cyclogenesis from the positive anomalies from upper-level PV, condensation-generated PV and surface potential temperature are quantified. The contribution to the precipitation from orographic forcing due to upslope flow is also quantified through sensitivity experiments.</description><creator>Milbrandt, Jason.</creator><date>1998</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>A modeling study of an extreme precipitation event : the Saguenay flood</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j333x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m622x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4x51hm34s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the numerical solution of nonlinear integral equations, classic finite difference and series methods lead to systems of nonlinear algebraic or transcendental equations which are solved by iterative schemes such as the Newton method. The present work develops a sequential eigenfunction expansion for the numerical solution of certain nonlinear integral equations. The nonlinear term provides constraints for the amplitudes of the eigenfunctions and a subsequent iteration is used to refine these coefficients. A comparative study of the present method with the Broyden method is conducted. It is shown that the expansion procedure provides an early indication about the multiplicity of solutions which is not present when using the classic methods of solution. Numerical examples are presented which demonstrate the robustness of the expansion method in determining multiple solutions.</description><creator>Michelis, Katina.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>A sequential eigenfunction expansion approach for certain nonlinear integral equations /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75df74s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hm34s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v692t846w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A two year study was conducted on the Macdonald Campus Farm on a 2.4 ha site of shallow St. Amble loamy sand cropped to corn (Zea mays L.). Three types of tillage practice (conventional tillage, reduced tillage, and no-till) were combined with 2 residue levels (with and without) in a randomized complete block design. The effect of these practices on NO 3--N distribution at 0--50 cm in the soil profile, and on plant N uptake were studied. Organic matter, pH, bulk density, and soil moisture contents were also monitored. Residues were found to have a greater influence on soil NO3--N transformations (mineralization and immobilization), than tillage. In July 1996 residues suppressed NO3--N levels in reduced tillage (RT), but increased NO3--N levels in conventional tillage (CT). Residues initially increased N03--N levels in no-till (NT), but a few weeks later caused a sharp decline in NO 3--N levels in NT. In August 1996, RT and NT treatments without residue were found to have much greater concentrations of NO 3--N than those with residue. The effect of N suppression caused by residues was observed in Spring 1996, July 1996, August 1996, and August 1997. Reduced tillage demonstrated less NO 3--N fluctuation than the other tillage treatments. Wheel tracked rows had up to 20 times more NO3--N at 0--15 cm than the non wheel tracked rows, caused by the uneven distribution of N fertilizer. However, high NO3--N levels in the wheel tracked rows decreased to levels comparable with those in non fertilized (non wheel track) rows at 50 cm. Corn yields were not affected by tillage or residue treatments, neither were they influenced by the percentage of tissue N content. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Mehdi, Bano B.</creator><date>1998</date><subject>Soils -- Nitrogen content.</subject><subject>Tillage.</subject><subject>Corn -- Residues.</subject><subject>Soils -- Nitrate content.</subject><title>Soil nitrate-N and plant nitrogen distributions under different tillage practices</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773x79f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t846w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773x806</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nitric oxide (NO) and endothelin-1 (ET-1) are ubiquitous molecules whose actions have been implicated in several airway and vascular pathologies. NO is a free radical produced by the action of inducible and constitutive nitric oxide syntheses (NOS II and NOS III, respectively). NO possesses a wide range of actions including cellular damage which is mediated in part by peroxynitrite (ONOO-), an oxidant formed by the rapid reaction of NO with superoxide. ET-1 is a vasoconstrictor with well known mitogenic properties. In view of the physiologic properties of NO and ET-1, as well as the implication of these molecules in several pulmonary pathologies, we hypothesized that fibroproliferative lung disorders are associated with the cellular induction of NOS, ONOO-, and ET-1. Localization of these agents were qualitatively and quantitatively analyzed using immunohistochemistry and in situ hybridization in several proliferative lung disorders. These findings are essential for our understanding of the pathogenesis of lung disease and the biology of vasoactive substances. They also suggest a possible role for both the NO and ET pathways in the functional and morphological abnormalities in proliferative disorders of the lung. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>McDermott, Colleen D.</creator><date>1998</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Nitric oxide and endothelin-1 in proliferative diseases of the lung</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g950t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773x806</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hr838</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main objective of this thesis is to present a quantitative method for modeling data collected from different studies on a same research topic. This quantitative method is called meta-analysis. The first step of a meta-analysis is the literature search, conducted using computerized and manual search strategies to identify relevant studies. The second step is the data abstraction from different relevant papers. In general, at least two independent raters systematically abstract the information, and interrater reliability check is performed. The next step is the quantitative analysis of the abstracted data. For this purpose, it is possible to use either fixed or mixed effects linear model. Under the fixed effects model, only the variability due to sampling error is considered. In contrast, under the mixed effects model, an additional random effects variance is being considered. Both, the method of moments and the method of maximum likelihood can be used to estimate the parameters of the model. Finally, the use of the above mentioned models and methods of estimation is illustrated with a data set on the prognosis of depression in the elderly, made available by Dr. Martin Cole from the Department of Psychiatry at St. Mary's Hospital Center in Montreal.</description><creator>Mansour, Asmaâ.</creator><date>1998</date><subject>Statistics.</subject><title>Modeling outcome estimates in meta-analysis using fixed and mixed effects linear models</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj2364222.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hr838</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vd66w195c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Receptor tyrosine kinases (RTKs) mediate transduction of extracellular signals to the interior of the cell. The oncogenic variant of the Met RTK (Tpr-Met) transforms fibroblast cells. Multiple proteins involved in activating signal transduction pathways bind the Tpr-Met protein at a single highly phosphorylated tyrosine, tyrosine 489. This tyrosine residue is essential for Tpr-Met mediated transformation, implicating one or more of these substrates in this event. The specificity of the interaction between RTKs and their substrates is determined by amino acids surrounding the phosphotyrosine residue. To determine the role of each Tpr-Met substrate in cellular transformation, I have designed Tpr-Met mutants predicted to have a unique substrate binding specificity, by altering the three amino acids immediately downstream of tyrosine 489. My results show that the in vitro optimal binding motifs predicted for various substrates may not apply in vivo to Tpr-Met.</description><creator>Mahendran, Mahishini.</creator><date>1998</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Generation of mutants of the Met tyrosine kinase oncoprotein with substrate binding specificity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451k75g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w195c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72p9314</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We investigated the relationship between rhythms occurring at different time-scales, namely circadian and ultradian rhythms. Furthermore, we examined the potential role of the period (per) gene, a known clock gene initially isolated in Drosophila, for regulating these rhythms in the wild-type cricket, Teleogryllus oceanicus . Here we report a positive correlation between circadian and ultradian rhythms in crickets. Thus, crickets with a slow endogenous circadian rhythm also have a slow ultradian rhythm, and conversely, animals with a fast endogenous circadian rhythm have a fast ultradian rhythm. In addition to this correlation, we observed PER-like immunoreactivity in the regions of the cricket nervous system involved in regulating these rhythms, namely the brain, in particular the optic lobes, and the meso- and metathoracic ganglia. We thus conclude that different time-scale rhythms may be regulated by a common setting element, a role potentially played by the per gene.</description><creator>Lupien, Mathieu.</creator><date>1998</date><subject>Oceanic field cricket -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Circadian rhythms.</subject><subject>Ultradian rhythms.</subject><title>Correlation between ultradian and circadian rhythms in the cricket, Teleogryllus oceanicus : potential role for the period gene</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720g08p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p9314</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150m20h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Strategic planning is not only necessary in today's global economy where markets are becoming more susceptible to international competition, it is vital. The foresight of market reactions can lead to a competitive advantage. Market share losses can be minimized (and market share gains maximized) with the knowledge obtained from primary marketing research involving a stated preference study to examine consumer behaviour. Before launching a new product or providing a service, discrete choice analysis can empower strategic planners, managers and marketers with a tool which aids in optimizing products and services for a potential market with the end of maximizing sales and services. Discrete choice analysis is a tool to understand human choice behaviour. It is employed for statistical inference on a model of choice behaviour from data obtained by sampling from a population of decision makers. This thesis gives an overview of the basic concepts of conjoint analysis which addresses discrete choice analysis for strategic product and service planning. The statistical model specification, the multinomial logit, is derived assuming that decision makers follow a choice rule called utility maximization, where these random utilities are Gumbel distributed. The model is applied to a stated preference study in which environmentally friendly vehicles are presented as possible vehicle choices.</description><creator>Lukban, Albert.</creator><date>1997</date><subject>Statistics.</subject><title>Discrete choice modelling in conjoint analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j3346.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150m20h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892d12k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Thylakoid organization and the distribution of photosystem (PS) I and II proteins in the green alga Coleochaete scutata were analyzed by electron microscopy. Thylakoids were observed to associate in varied conformations. Extended bands of thylakoids were present, as in other algae, but numerous grana, characteristic of higher plants, were also detected. Immunolabelling experiments were conducted with two heterologous antisera raised against PS proteins in the cyanobacterium Synechococcus elongatus: one antiserurn against the 60 and 62 kDa PSI reaction centre proteins, the other against the 47 kDa PSII core antenna protein. PSI was 2.6 times more concentrated in the nonappressed membranes (NAM) than in the appressed (AM), with 62% of labelling on NAM. The concentration of PSII in AM was 1.6 times that of the NAM, accounting for 75% of PSII. Thus, in C scutata, PSI and PSII are located in both appressed and nonappressed thylakoid membranes, but with a trend towards the lateral heterogeneity of PS proteins observed in higher plants. These results support the body of ultrastructural and molecular data linking charophytes with the ancestry of higher plants.</description><creator>Kerr, Ellyn.</creator><contributor>Gibbs, Sarah P. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Coleochaete.</subject><subject>Photosynthesis -- Molecular aspects.</subject><subject>Thylakoids.</subject><title>Thylakoid organization and photosystem distribution in Coleochaete scutata : further homologies between charophytes and higher plants</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55mf03b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892d12k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vd68t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study was designed to investigate the neuropsychological functioning of two groups of children: one evaluated as having borderline psychopathology, and a second with psychiatric disorders such as conduct disorder and/or attention deficit hyperactivity disorder, but not BPD. The total sample included 83 subjects, 71 boys and 12 girls, ranging in age from seven-12 years. Borderline psychopathology was assessed using the Child Diagnostic Interview for Borderlines (C-DIB-R). Frontal-system functioning was assessed with the Continuous Performance Test, the Wisconsin Card Sorting Test, and the Rey Complex Figure Test. IQ was evaluated with the Wechsler Intelligence Scale for Children - Third Edition, and the Quick Neurological Screening Test was given to identify any soft sign neurological impairments. It was found that there were specific neuropsychological deficits associated with borderline pathology, including poor attentiveness, marked impulsivity, risk taking behaviour and poor conceptual learning.</description><creator>Joseph, Shari.</creator><contributor>Paris, Joel (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Psychology, Clinical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health.</subject><title>The neuropsychological risk factors associated with borderline pathology in children /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bd83n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vd68t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hh63sz08j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dinoflagellates are a diverse group of protists, some of which are photosynthetic. The typical dinoflagellate chloroplast contains two proteins not found in any other photosynthetic eukaryote: peridinin-chlorophyll a-protein (PCP) and Form II ribulose-1,5-bisphosphate carboxylase/oxygenase (Rubisco). Immunoelectron microscopic observations on the dinoflagellate Amphidinium carterae show that PCP is localized in the chloroplast stroma, not in the thylakoid lumen as previously postulated due to the presence of a putative lumen-targeting sequence. Antisera against Form II Rubisco from bacterial (Rhodospirillum rubrum) and dinoflagellate (Symbiodinium sp.) sources were both shown to label the chloroplast and pyrenoid of A. carterae . Antiserum to Form I Rubisco from the haptophyte, alga Isochrysis galbana resulted in no labelling. Parallel experiments on the dinoflagellate Peridinium foliaceum, whose chloroplasts are all attributed to its diatom endosyrnbiont and on the diatom Phaeodactylum tricornutum revealed plastid pyrenoid labelling only with antiserum to Form I Rubisco.</description><creator>Jenks, Andrée.</creator><contributor>Gibbs, S. P. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Chloroplasts.</subject><subject>Dinoflagellates.</subject><title>The dinoflagellate chloroplast : immunolocalization of two unique plastid proteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zg64tp09v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sz08j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:76537327t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The semi and climate at the Fordwah Eastern Sadiqia (South) Project, Pakistan, comprised of 105,000 ha of culturable command area, is characterized by large seasonal temperature fluctuations and a monsoon season. The canal system behaves as a recharge source to the regional groundwater and has caused waterlogging and salinity problems. The aquifer of the project area is unconfined and underlain by sediments deposited by the Sutleg-Hakra river system. To quantify the rate of groundwater recharge in the project area, a numerical groundwater model was developed. A network of 125 observation wells was installed and watertable depth data were collected for the period of June 1994 to June 1997. Within this network, a distinction was made between internal and external nodes representing nodal areas and boundary conditions, respectively. Other data used in the model were aquifer characteristics obtained from seven historical and five newly performed pumped well tests. The aquifer analysis showed a regional decrease in aquifer transmissivity from the eastern region to the western. The hydraulic conductivity values obtained from these analyses were assigned to each side of each nodal area. The aim of the present study was to develop a more reliable and time consuming methodology to determine the yearly, seasonal and monthly net-recharge occurring in the study area. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Javed, Ijaz.</creator><contributor>Bonnell, Robert (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Groundwater -- Pakistan -- Bahawalnager Region.</subject><subject>Groundwater -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Groundwater development and management at Fordwah Eastern Sadiqia (South) Project, Bahawalnager, Punjab, Pakistan</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623f74t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537327t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644t706</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Differences in the activity of various components of the endogenous opioid system under basal conditions and following ethanol exposure have been reported between strains and lines of animals showing either a high or low ethanol consumption. The objective of the present studies was to investigate the presence of differences in (a) the density of kappa opioid binding sites, (b) the content of prodynorphin mRNA and (c) the content of dynorphin peptides in distinct brain regions between C57BL/6 (ethanol-preferring) and DBA/2 (ethanol avoiding) mice. Results indicated that the C57BL/6 mice have a higher content of kappa opioid binding sites and of dynorphin A 1--13 in the amygdala, and of dynorphin A 1--8 in the ventral tegmental area, while the DBA/2 mice presented a significantly hew content of kappa opioid binding sotes, prodynorphin mRNA as well as dynorphin A 1--13 and dynorphin A 1--8 peptides in the nucleus accumbens and septum. In addition, the DBA/2 mice presented a higher content of kappa opioid receptors in the periaqueductal grey and of dynorphin A 1--13 and dynorphin A 1--8 in the caudate putamen. Since the enhanced stimulation of kappa opioid receptors at the level of the nucleus accumbens has been associated with decreased dopamine release and aversive states, the higher content of kappa opioid receptors, prodynorphin mRNA and dynorphin peptides (the endogenous ligand of kappa binding sites), in regions of the limbic system of the DBA/2 mice may play an important role in determining their low alcohol consumption.</description><creator>Jamensky, Neil Thomas.</creator><contributor>Gianoulakis, Christina (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Psychology, Psychobiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Content of dynorphins and kappa opioid receptors in the brains of alcohol-preferring C57BL6 and alcohol-avoiding DBA2 mice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698962p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644t706</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:td96k4782</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Protein deficiency may increase susceptibility to gastrointestinal (GI) parasitic infections, possibly as a result of impaired systemic and/or intestinal effector responses induced by downregulation of Th2 cytokines and/or upregulation of Th1 cytokines. To test this hypothesis, female BALB/c mice (n = 18/diet) were fed a control (24%), marginal (7%), or deficient (3%) protein diet and given a challenge infection with the GI nematode, Heligmosomoides polygyrus. The 3% mice had higher worm burdens at 1, 2 and 4 weeks post-challenge infection (pci), lower increases in serum IgE, reduced intestinal eosinophilia, and depressed mucosal mast cell proliferation and activation at 1 to 2 weeks pci. To determine whether these suppressed effector responses in the 3% mice were associated with altered spleen and mesenteric lymph node (MLN) cytokine profiles, cells were restimulated in vitro with parasite antigen and cytokine concentrations were measured. Deficient MLN cells secreted significantly less IL-4 and more IFN-gamma at 1--2 weeks pci than did control MLN cells. Deficient spleen cells also secreted more IFN-gamma at 2 weeks pci compared with control spleen cells. From RT-PCR analyses, the 3% mice also had lower IL-4 mRNA expression in spleen and MLN at 1--2 weeks pci. Our study supports the hypothesis that protein deficiency exacerbates the survival of a GI nematode parasite by decreasing IL-4 (Th2) and increasing IFN-gamma (Th1) early in the infection, leading to reduced gut and systemic Th2 effector responses.</description><creator>Ing, Rebecca Yat Loo, 1971-</creator><contributor>Koski, Kristine G. (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Scott, Marilyn E. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Mice -- Parasites.</subject><subject>Helminthiasis -- Nutritional aspects.</subject><subject>Heligmosomatidae.</subject><subject>Protein deficiency.</subject><title>Dietary protein deficiency modifies systemic and gut-associated immune responses in mice infected with Heligmosomoides polygyrus (Nematoda)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dc11d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k4782</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gh93h170b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The distinct structural properties of heterochromatin accommodate a diverse group of vital chromosome functions, yet we have only rudimentary knowledge about its protein composition. One powerful tool for Drosophila biologists has been a group of genes that reverse the repressive effect of heterochromatin on the expression of a gene placed next to it ectopically. Several of these genes are known to encode proteins enriched in heterochromatin. The best characterized of these is the heterochromatin associated protein, HP1. HP1 has no known DNA-binding activity, hence its incorporation into heterochromatin is likely to be dependent upon other proteins. To examine HP1 interacting proteins, we isolated three distinct oligomeric species of HP1 from the cytoplasm of early Drosophila embryos and analyzed their compositions. The two larger oligomers resemble a fraction of that is tightly associated with the chromatin of interphase nuclei. Like the HP1 in these two cytoplasmic oligomers, this tightly bound nuclear fraction of HP1 is underphosphorylated and is associated with subunits of the origin recognition complex (ORC). We also found the localization of HP1 into heterochromatin to be disrupted in mutants for the ORC2 subunit. This phenotype supports a role for ORC in HP1 targeting and heterochromatin assembly. This proposed role for Drosophila ORC suggests striking similarities to the ability of ORC to recruit the Sir1 protein to silencing nucleation sites at the silent mating type loci in S. cerevisiae.</description><creator>Huang, Da Wei.</creator><contributor>Kellum, Rebecca (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Oligomers.</subject><subject>Drosophila -- Molecular genetics.</subject><subject>Heterochromatin.</subject><title>Purification and characterization of HP1 oligomers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h395c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h170b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xd07gv84b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The work presented here addresses the problem of the development of a conformance test suite and an interoperability test suite for the ATM Signaling protocol based on the finite state machine model (FSM). The experimental tools developed at the University of Montreal are used to partially automate the process of test development. Tools use the underlying FSM model. Development of a conformance test suite starts from a complete SDL specification of the Signaling protocol. The specification is developed from the standard document prior to test development. Using the tool chain, the FSM model from the SDL specification is extracted, and, based on an FSM test generation method, a test suite from the FSM model is produced. Test cases for the data part of the protocol are derived directly from the text in the standard. The obtained test suite is validated in the SDL environment against the SDL specification. The interoperability testing assumes a system of two implementations of the Signaling protocol connected via a network. Tests are represented in terms of protocol services. Test development process is also based on the FSM testing. The behavior of the complete system is represented by a global FSM, and a test suite is developed form the obtained FSM.</description><creator>Hristov, Dionis.</creator><contributor>Gao, Guang (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Development of tests for the ATM signaling protocol</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cg582.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gv84b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62fb55t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this study was to derive new selection indices for swine production in Quebec. First economic values were derived as change in profit per market pig for a one unit change in a trait while all other traits remain unchanged. Production figures and prices used were taken from Quebec figures. Comparing with the currently used economic values, the responses showed the same range for the sire line with a higher emphasis on age to 100 kg for the new values. The same trait, response in age to 100 kg was much smaller in the maternal line for the newly derived economic values but showed higher responses for backfat and litter size. Lean yield was found to have higher responses if used directly as a selection criterion for carcass composition instead of backfat. Feed intake was found to have unfavourable responses in the maternal line but did not change the responses for the paternal line. Including farrowing interval in the maternal line resulted in favourable responses for lean yield and litter size. Regulating the backfat level using a restricted index in the dam line had no effect on the other traits in the index.</description><creator>Holzbauer, Regina.</creator><contributor>Cue, Roger I. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Swine -- Breeding -- Economic aspects -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Swine -- Breeding -- Selection indexes.</subject><title>Economic values and responses to selection using selection indices in swine</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t8475.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fb55t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gf06g4772</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Randomly constructed networks of N elements governed by piecewise linear differential equations have been proposed as models for neural and genetic networks. In this model an element is labelled "on" if it is above a threshold, and "off" otherwise. The logical state of the network at any time is thus a Boolean vector. For each element, there is a rule (truth table) specified by the values of K input elements that determines whether it will switch its state (from 1 to 0 or from 0 to 1) at some future time. Parameter p biases the output state of each automata and influences the global dynamics of the system. Discrete switching network analogues of the piecewise linear differential equations show a transition from ordered to disordered dynamics as p and K are varied. The transition is analyzed in continuous switching networks. Previous studies of these networks have demonstrated the existence of steady state, periodic, and chaotic attractors. Numerical studies analyze the dynamics of a randomly chosen ensemble of networks as a function of N, K, and p. Theoretical insight into the change in dynamics is gained through the derivation of a Markov process for the number of elements at time t that are approaching their threshold. Analysis of this Markov model yields a critical relation between p and K that separates ordered dynamics from deterministic chaos.</description><creator>Hill, Colin C.</creator><contributor>Glass, Leon (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Physics, General.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Transition to chaos in models of genetic networks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698963z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g4772</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806203p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:20:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Japanese vegetable market is characterized by a general tendency towards the concentration of production by region. Amongst all vegetables, potato production has the highest level of concentration. Eighty-six percent of the total market quantity is accounted for by Hokkaido, the largest production prefecture amongst the 47 prefectures in Japan. The Herfindahl Index for prefectures in the Japanese potato market was 0.74 in 1994, indicating that the fewness of producers was equivalent to a market where total output was shared equally by only 1.35 producers. Under this highly concentrated situation, existence of monopolistic power, or more generally, oligopolistic power, of the large scale producers can be suspected. In this thesis, the level of competition in the Japanese Potato market was evaluated employing conjectural variations analysis based on a monthly data for 1989 to 1995 to reveal the nature of the market. Four wholesale markets, in four large consumption areas, and eight production areas in differ ent geographical locations in were analyzed. The conclusion from the results of the empirical analysis is that, despite the high level of concentration in production, all producing regions including the dominant producer, Hokkaido, seem to have behaved competitively. One implication for the competitive behavior of these large producers is the imperative to maintain their share in the market against potential competitors, resulting in price setting close to the marginal cost.</description><creator>Higaki, Yusuke.</creator><contributor>Coffin, Garth (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Potato industry -- Japan.</subject><subject>Competition -- Japan.</subject><title>Competition in the Japanese potato market</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816p64n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806203p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2375</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>