<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:09:55Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):17650" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vg13n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The condition which is now known as lead poisoning was familiar even in ancient times. Hippocrates (370 B.C.) was probably the first to associate lead with certain symptoms, such as severe attack of colic in a man who extracted metals. The symptoms of lead poisoning were more clearly defined in the first century A.D. by Dioscorides, “the drinking of litharge (red lead) causes oppression to the stomach, belly, and intestines, by its severe pressure; it suppresses the urine, while the body swells and acquires an unsightly leaden line”. He also speaks of paralysis and delirium as consequences of the ingestion of lead.</description><creator>Vardanis, Alexandre.</creator><contributor>Quastel, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1958</date><subject>Genetics.</subject><title>The effect of lead compounds on the metabolism of the central nervous system.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h128nj45t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vg13n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5138jj19f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In oviparous vertebrates each period of egg production is associated with profound changes in blood chemistry, in physiology and in morphology of the female. The plasma changes include increased concentrations of certain proteins, lipids, vitamins and minerals and these changes are considered to be related to the mobilization of these compounds for egg formation. In addition to the normal puberal changes, which, as in the mammal, are related to endocrine activity, similar and even greater increases in these plasma constituents result from estrogen treatment of birds of either sex or of castrates.</description><creator>Vanstone, William. E.</creator><contributor>Common, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1957</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>Studies on the formation of serum proteins in the fowl.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kk88m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5138jj19f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agriculture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924g390</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the earliest contributions to the theory of electrolytic conductance was made by Kohlrausch (1), who observed that the equivalent conductance of an electrolyte at infinite dilution is the sum of two independent factors characteristic of the anion and cation respectively. This is known as Kohlrausch's "Law of Independent Migration of Ions". The classical theory of Arrhenius (2) published in 1885 was the next significant advance. He postulated that when an electrolyte is dissolved in a solvent, it partially dissociated into charged particles (now called ions). Another postulate of his theory was that the degree of dissociation of the electrolyte depends on the concentration of the solution, increases with dilution, and becomes complete in an infinitely dilute solution.</description><creator>Unni, Ayalur. K.</creator><contributor>Schiff, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1958</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Precision conductance measurements of some quaternary ammonium halides in nitromethane.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kx52n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924g390</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rb68xg56k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Supersonic inlet starting by mass spillage is studied theoretically and numerically in the present thesis. A quasi-one-dimensional, quasi-steady theory is developed for the analysis of flow inside a perforated inlet. The theory results in closed-form relations applicable to flow starting by the mass spillage technique in supersonic and hypersonic inlets. The theory involves three parameters to incorporate the multi-dimensional nature of mass spillage through a wall perforation. Mass spillage through an individual slot is studied to determine these parameters; analytical expressions for these parameters are derived for both subsonic and supersonic flow conditions. In the case of mass spillage from supersonic flows, the relations are exact. However, due to the complexity of flow field, the theory is an approximation for subsonic flows. Therefore, a correction factor is introduced which is determined from an empirical relation obtained from numerical simulations. A methodology is also proposed to determine perforation size and distribution to achieve flow starting for a given inlet at a desired free-stream Mach number. The problem of shock stability inside a perforated inlet designed with the proposed method is also discussed. The method is demonstrated for some test cases. Time-realistic CFD simulations and experimental results in the literature confirm the accuracy of the theory and the reliability of the proposed design methodology.</description><creator>Najafiyazdi, Alireza.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Airplanes -- Scramjet engines.</subject><subject>Supersonic planes.</subject><subject>Airplanes -- Ramjet engines -- Air intakes.</subject><title>Theoretical and numerical analysis of supersonic inlet starting by mass spillage</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b7116.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xg56k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924g40r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The continuum design sensitivity analysis (CDSA) has been applied to the magnetostatic and electrostatic force calculation. This method allows the computation of the net loading force on a body as well as the force distribution on the surface of the body. An algorithm for force calculation combined with a standard field analysis software package is presented. The efficiency and accuracy of the method is proved through the numerical implementation applied to a set of test examples. In addition, the new approach has several advantages over the traditional methods based on the Maxwell Stress Tensor, such as no air gap or artificial interference with the original model is required. Particularly, the performance analysis of a MEMS micro-mirror using CDSA torque calculation is conducted for the first time.</description><creator>Li, Min, 1977 Apr. 2-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Microelectromechanical systems -- Design and construction.</subject><title>Continuum design sensitivity analysis based force calculation in EM devices</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kk89w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924g40r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cx92p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Various surgical options exist to correct pathologies of the aortic valve, including mechanical or biological valve implantation, reconstruction of the native vessels, and a combination of the two. Additionally, finite-element analysis and, to some extent, fluid-structure interaction (FSI) analyses have been used in the past to analyze how these procedures may affect various engineering metrics such as tissue stresses and opening and closing dynamics of the valves. In this work, a similar type of model and analysis is performed, however, in addition to modeling the actions of the aortic valve, coronary flows are also considered. By incorporating these vessels, it is possible to examine coronary flow perturbations to mechanical and geometric model variations and to assess certain surgical procedures in regards to a new clinically relevant metric.</description><creator>Campbell, Ian, 1982-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Aortic valve -- Abnormalities.</subject><subject>Fluid-structure interaction.</subject><subject>Finite element method.</subject><subject>Coronary circulation.</subject><subject>Aortic valve.</subject><title>A study of coronary flow in the presence of geometric and mechanical abnormalities in a fluid-structure interaction model of the aortic valve /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zv27b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cx92p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zx94b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Skeletal satellite cells are adult stem cells located among muscle fibers. Proliferation, migration and subsequent differentiation of these cells are critical steps in the repair of muscle injury. We document in this study the roles and mechanisms through which the NAPDH oxidase complex regulates skeletal satellite cell proliferation. The NADPH oxidase subunits Nox2, Nox4, p22phox, p47phox and p67 phox were detected in primary human and murine skeletal muscle satellite cells. In human satellite cells, NADPH oxidase-fusion proteins were localized in the cytosolic and membrane compartments of the cell, except for p47 phox, which was detected in the nucleus. In proliferating subconfluent satellite cells, both Nox2 and Nox4 contributed to O2- production. However, Nox4 expression was significantly attenuated in confluent cells and in differentiated myotubes. Proliferation of satellite cells was significantly reduced by antioxidants (N-acetylcysteine and apocynin), inhibition of p22phox expression using siRNA oligonucleotides, and reduction of Nox4 and p47phox activities with dominant-negative vectors resulted in attenuation of activities of the Erk1/2, PI-3 kinase/AKT and NFkappaB pathways and significant reduction in cyclin D1 levels. We conclude that NADPH oxidase is expressed in skeletal satellite cells and that its activity plays an important role in promoting proliferation of these cells.</description><creator>Mofarrahi, Mahroo.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Muscle Fibers -- cytology.</subject><subject>Reactive Oxygen Species -- metabolism.</subject><subject>NADPH Oxidase -- metabolism.</subject><subject>Satellite Cells, Skeletal Muscle -- cytology.</subject><title>Regulation of skeletal muscle satellite cell proliferation by NADPH oxidase</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920g1478.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zx94b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21tk16x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Objective. To examine the profile of executive function (EF) performance in children diagnosed with Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) as function of their subtypes and comorbid disorders. Methods. Two hundred and eighteen, 6-12 year old children clinically diagnosed with ADHD were characterised according to their clinical profile. Various EF domains were assessed while children were not on medication. General cognitive performance was assessed using Wechsler Intelligence Scale for Children. Results. 54.1% of children were diagnosed with combined subtype, 34.9% with inattentive subtype and 11% with hyperactive subtype. Significant age difference was found in ADHD subtype distribution and significant age and IQ difference was found in EF performance. After controlling for age and IQ no association was found between EF and ADHD subtypes or EF and comorbid disorders. Conclusion. These results indicate that age and IQ play an important role in cognitive task performance.</description><creator>Ter-Stepanian, Mariam.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Attention-deficit hyperactivity disorder.</subject><subject>Cognition in children.</subject><title>Executive functioning in children diagnosed with ADHD : examining DSM-IV subtypes and comorbid disorders</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qw45c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21tk16x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4f16c623d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study examined the benefits of implementing multicultural music education into an elementary school's music curriculum. Conducted in a region with a culturally diverse student population, the study surveyed in-service music teachers and elementary students' parents on their perceptions of multicultural music education. Meanwhile, a set of experimental classes focused on Chinese music was taught to a diverse class of Grade 5 students to study their reactions and learning outcomes when studying non-Western music. Results indicate that (a) multicultural music needs to be better implemented in Ontario's music curriculum, (b) students receive non-Western music with enthusiasm, and (c) if taught responsibly, learning music from non-Western cultures can expand individual students' musical and cultural horizons, help eliminate stereotypes and discrimination in society, and possibly elevate the status of music education in schools.</description><creator>Schaus, Lam E.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Music -- Cross-cultural studies.</subject><subject>Multicultural education.</subject><title>Implementing multicultural music education in the elementary schools' music curriculum</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dh20w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c623d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1831cp55n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>As gambling becomes more accessible, problems associated with gambling have begun to affect ever increasing numbers of youth. Despite legal restrictions in some jurisdictions, Internet gambling is undergoing a massive worldwide expansion. The relationship between the convenience, anonymity, and the 24-hour availability of Internet gambling and problem gambling in young people presents a serious concern. This study explored Internet gambling in a sample of university students aged 18 to 20 years. Students reported on their involvement in gambling activities both on and off the Internet. In the past 12 months, 6.7% of participants had gambled for money on the Internet, with higher rates among males (11.0%) than females (.8%). As well, 39.4% of students reported that in the past 12 months they had played gambling-type games on Internet 'practice' sites, where no money was required to play. Concerns about the possible effects of Internet gambling are raised and possible future directions for research are presented.</description><creator>McBride, Jessica I.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Internet gambling.</subject><subject>Teenage gamblers.</subject><subject>Gamblers.</subject><subject>College students.</subject><title>An exploratory analysis of Internet gambling among university students /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386p34h.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cp55n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z9033700</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Access to markets is increasingly regarded in development circles as a critical factor in determining livelihood choices in peasant economies. In the northeastern Peruvian Amazon, a multitude of river transporters and market intermediaries based in the central city of Iquitos provide essential services and market opportunities for remote peasant producers across the region. Using a multi-scalar, multi-method approach involving extensive fieldwork in the Peruvian Amazon, this research (re)assesses the meanings and implications of "remoteness" and "connectedness" for rural peasants. At the regional scale, I examine the functional heterogeneity of river trading networks and marketing agents. Given the high-risk/high-transaction-cost environment, river trading is found to be expensive for producers and traders alike. High costs are exacerbated by the low gross returns of rural production (mainly food and natural building materials). Thin or missing markets for credit, labour, land and insurance increase the hardships associated with limited access to product markets. Regional findings are complemented with a comparative livelihoods analysis in two remote communities of the Alto Tigre River that benefit from differential access to oil-labour. My study reveals that differential access to labour has significant impacts on the livelihood strategies of working households. However, given limited access to external markets, cash-income from oil-labour is found to offer limited opportunities for growth. In sum, the research proposes insights for advancing the debate on livelihoods and poverty in the Peruvian Amazon.</description><creator>Cohalan, Jean-Michel.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Amazon River Region -- Economic conditions.</subject><subject>Indians of South America -- Amazon River Region -- Economic conditions.</subject><subject>Peasants -- Amazon River Region -- Economic conditions.</subject><subject>Land use, Rural -- Amazon River Region.</subject><title>River trading in the Peruvian Amazon : market access and rural livelihoods among rainforest peoples</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qt64r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z9033700</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278z01p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A complex physiological system, composed of central and peripheral signals, balances energy intake and expenditure. Among these signals, the enteric and orexigenic hormone ghrelin is a regulator of energy balance with several uncharacterized functions. Although much research has accumulated regarding ghrelin's effects on metabolic parameters, little is known about its other behavioural and cognitive effects. Consequently, this study, using functional magnetic resonance imaging, showed that ghrelin administered intravenously to healthy volunteers increased the neural response to food pictures, as well as faces of fear and disgust, in brain areas regulating the hedonic and incentive evaluation of visual stimuli, such as the amygdala. Moreover, ghrelin exhibited memory enhancing effects for both food pictures and faces of fear and disgust. These findings suggest that ghrelin's activation of the amygdala may serve as a magnitude signal for value judgments of visually-presented food and non-food stimuli, thus engaging critical feeding, emotional and cognitive responses.</description><creator>Bedrossian, Diane.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Magnetic Resonance Imaging.</subject><subject>Peptide Hormones.</subject><subject>Food.</subject><subject>Amygdala -- physiology.</subject><title>The effects of ghrelin on the amygdala response to visual food and non-food stimuli : an fMRI study in humans</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429f13m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278z01p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sp00s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Balbuzard is a musical composition of approximately twelve minutes in length, scored for solo clarinet, wind symphony and electronics. It focuses on cluster-like sound masses and explores ways of using these to give the music a clear sense of direction. To this end, tools were developed using a variety of computer applications or programming languages, such as Lisp, OpenMusic and Cubase. These tools made possible a kind of graphic composition where diagrams of different shapes were entered into a computer interface and converted into source material. The generated source material consisted of several rhythmic strata whose pitches, mainly part of diatonic, octatonic or chromatic collections, followed the contour of the entered shape. With this visual process, it was also possible to explore the creation of contrapuntal textures by entering diagrams of lines representing the path of each contrapuntal voice.* *This dissertation is a compound document (contains both a paper copy and a CD as part of the dissertation). The CD requires the following system requirements: Windows MediaPlayer or RealPlayer.</description><creator>Adamcyk, David.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Band music -- Analysis, appreciation.</subject><subject>Band music -- Scores.</subject><subject>Electronic music.</subject><title>Balbuzard : for solo clarinet, wind symphony and electronics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj2365962.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sp00s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q524js591</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A fractional iterative channel estimation and data detection algorithm is proposed for frequency selective, quasi-static MIMO channels. It is shown that due to the correlation of the noise samples after pulse matched filtering and sampling, the complexity of the derived receiver, based on the Expectation-Maximization (EM) algorithm with fractional sampling, is the same as that of the ML receiver, which requires an exhaustive search. It is shown that by using a noise whitening filter to whiten the noise samples, the algorithm can be efficiently implemented using the Viterbi algorithm instead of using an exhaustive search technique. Due to spectral zeros of the autocorrelation function of the noise sequence, noise whitening filter designed by spectral factorization are not practical for the square-root raised cosine pulses and similar shapes. An alternative prediction-error whitening filter is proposed solving the Yule-Walker equations. We analyze the performance of the proposed receiver via numerical simulations. It is observed that when the channel is perfectly known, the performance of the fractional ML receiver, with five-tap whitening filter, is only 0.5 dB worse than that of the optimal ML receiver at a BER of 10-4. When the path delays are fixed and the channel is unknown, the fractional iterative scheme outperforms the symbol rate iterative scheme between 0 and 16 dB, and between BERs of 2 x 10-1 and 2 x 10 -4. With varying path delays, the fractional scheme is better for all simulated SNR values. However, both schemes experience a severe error flooring. Application of the EM algorithm to iteratively estimate frequency selective channels and detect the transmitted information sequence improves the efficiency of pilot symbols. By using additional iterations, the BER is lowered with the same number of pilot symbols. We also compare the performance of the iterative receiver that uses the correct tap covariance matrix with the one that assumes a diagonal covariance matrix. It is observed that with fixed path delays the performance is identical with both models. With varying path delays and fractional sampling the diagonal assumption results in a performance loss of 0.5 dB.* *This dissertation is a compound document (contains both a paper copy and a CD as part of the dissertation).</description><creator>Szubbocsev, Zoltan.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>The EM algorithm for frequency selective, quasi-static fading channels /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tw19h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524js591</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74cv38q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Personal computers (PC) and high level programming techniques have been developing so rapidly during last decade leading to new and exciting opportunities in the field of education. The purpose of this research was to develop food processing virtual labs as efficient teaching and study tools for food processing courses using user-friendly computer languages (VC++, MFC and OpenGL). A 3D graphic technique was employed in this study as a specific objective to generate 3D graphics in the visualization mode. According to functionalities, virtual labs were designed for three basic simulations: (1) Calculation simulations, which perform various calculations related to food processing. These simulations help users to remember and understand the formula used in process calculations. Several simple concept calculations were included: conduction heat transfer in steady state through individual and composite slabs; two-component mass balance systems, Pearson rule applications; freezing and thawing time calculations; (2) Animation simulations, which are aimed to visualize processing scenarios for different physical phenomena or working principles. Included in these simulations were: conduction heat transfer through single and multiple walls under steady state; mixing processes involving two and three component systems and Pearson rule concept; freezing and thawing processes through slab, cylinder, and sphere, the three regular shapes, agitation thermal processing modes which include axial agitation and end-over-end agitation in rotational retort; (3) Virtual equipment simulations, which are aimed to dynamically simulate a real operating environment and to demonstrate equipment working principle, internal structure, and operating procedures. The simulated equipment include a horizontal retort used in thermal processing and a high pressure processing equipment used in non-thermal processing. The food processing virtual labs provide a new way in teaching and learning, with no risk, time or place limitations, and are cost effective. The simulated scenarios and equipment can be used as teaching tools in food processing courses, which provide an efficient way to the instructor/assistant. Instructor/assistant can dynamically and repeatedly demonstrate the operating process for the simulated equipment in a vivid and interested manner. Also students can get intuitive understanding by viewing these simulations. Computers are the waves of the future; however, traditional learning techniques should not be forgotten.* *This dissertation is a compound document (contains both a paper copy and a CD as part of the dissertation). The CD requires the following system requirements: Windows 95 or higher.</description><creator>Chi, Minli, 1965-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Food industry and trade -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Simulation methods.</subject><subject>Food industry and trade -- Research.</subject><title>Development of virtual laboratory as an educationalresearch tool in food processing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m3099.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cv38q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z460s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Disease resistance in a plant is a manifestation of a complex phenomenon which involves among other things, the inherent and acquired physiologic properties of not only the host but also those of the pathogen influenced by ever-changing conditions of both the macro- and micro-environment.</description><creator>Udeaja, Arubaluezeama Philip.</creator><contributor>Pelletier, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1958</date><subject></subject><subject>Plant Pathology.</subject><title>Studies on the Nature of Resistance of Plants to Disease: the Effect of Growth Substances on the Resistance of Beets to Beet Leaf-Spot (Cercospora Beticola Sacc.) and of Phaseolus Beans to Bean Rust (Uromyces Phasecli Var. Typica Arth.)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pr53g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z460s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn00b2449</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The rapidly growing field of teratology has recorded an amazing variety of developmental aberrations, either "spontaneous", or with some more or less clear-cut genetic or environmental cause. This preliminary descriptive stage is certainly necessary as a guide to the further, more detailed, study of the pathogenesis of individual abnormalities. However no matter how many more abnormalities are added to the list this method will add very little to knowledge of the basic causes of developmental defects. [...]</description><creator>Trasler, Daphne G.</creator><contributor>Fraser, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1958</date><subject></subject><subject>Genetics.</subject><title>Genetic and Other Factors Influencing the Pathogenesis of Cleft Palate in Mice.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580r334.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b2449</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78tg74r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tests were conducted to investigate the change in the turbine performance characteristics of a single stage, axial flow gas turbine resulting from changes in the thermodynamic properties of the working fluid. These properties are determined by the values of Cp and y and the method of varying these values was to inject water into the turbine inlet gas stream.</description><creator>Taylor, G.</creator><contributor>Mordell, D.L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1958</date><subject></subject><subject>Mechanical Engineering.</subject><title>Turbine Performance with Varying Thermodynamic Properties of the Working Fluid.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451n35x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tg74r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gh93h330s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The problem of mixing of subsonic circular jets with stationary fluid and with a stream at right angle has been studied. The present knowledge and conventional methods of approach to this problem are described. Applying Elrod's momentum diffusion theory of heat conduction to the mixing of a circular jet issued to a stationary fluid, the velocity distribution in the mixing region has been calculated and compared to Corrsin's experiment, and proved to be not quite satisfactory, especially at distance near the jet orifice. [...]</description><creator>Tao, Chia-Hwa.</creator><contributor>Wu, J.H.T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1958</date><subject></subject><subject>Mechanical Engineering.</subject><title>the Mixing of Circular Jets.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bj60x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h330s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1831cp56x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Studies of population trends in the Western world over the past fifty years indicate that the aged, that is, those persons over 65 years, have increased, as a group, both relatively and absolutely. This, in turn, has created a shift in the balance between dependants, i.e., those under 20 and those over 65, to the bread-winners, throwing a heavier burden on the earning population. These trends have had wide ramifications in our economic and social institutions, and have made research and planning imperative in the field of geriatrics.</description><creator>Tannenbaum, Ruth.</creator><date>1958</date><subject></subject><subject>Social Work.</subject><title>Two Patterns of Living Arrangements for Aging Windows.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h813m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831cp56x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418r958</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ce sage conseil de Sainte-Beuve inspirera notre travail d'apprenti-critique. Considérons notre homme comme un prisme taillé par la vie, les évenements qui, au cours des années, ont façonné son esprit et sa personnalité. A travers les facettes erre la pensée secrète, le génie intime de l'individu. Notre cristal sera Voltaire ciselé par les événements d'une année de sa vie. En tournant et en retournant ces 365 jours, et en examinant de près le spectre lumineux, nous espérons trouver au bout de l'arc-en-ciel la flamme qui est l'essence de l'homme.</description><creator>Szablowski, Julie.</creator><contributor>Launay, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1958</date><subject></subject><subject>French.</subject><title>L'Annee 1745 dans la Vie et l'Oeuvre de Voltaire.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524js60s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418r958</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:08612s26j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this investigation is to study correlates of decisions made in personnel selection interviews. The identification of such correlates serves to demonstrate factors which may account for the unreliability of interview decisions. </description><creator>Sydiaha, Daniel.</creator><contributor>Webster, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1958</date><subject></subject><subject>Psychology.</subject><title>the Relation between Actuarial and Descriptive Methods in Personnel Appraisal.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30px468.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612s26j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3n204277b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Systematic studies on the metabolic activities of nervous tissue began with the classical studies of Warburg, Posener and Negelein. They measured oxygen consumption, aerobic and anaerobic glycolysis of several tissues of the rat in an attempt to investigate the differences between the metabolism of neoplastic and normal tissues. Among their normal tissues they included brain cortex slices and retina. [...]</description><creator>Sved, Stephen.</creator><contributor>Quastel, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1958</date><subject></subject><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>the Metabolism of Amino Acids in the Central Nervous System.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jf90h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n204277b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz8063797</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>At the end of the proof of lemma 4 of section 4 it is shown that if (x, y) is a generic point of a connected one-dimensional algebraic subgroup G of D2, and x=1, then (x,y) satisfies an irreducible equation [...]</description><creator>Sussman, David.</creator><date>1958</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><subject></subject><title>on Certain Subgroups of Algebraic Matrix Groups at Prime Characteristic.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d5701231.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz8063797</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2v23vx68z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:21:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This paper reviews the work done by early investigators, and discusses the theories proposed to explain the presence of microwave signals well beyond the horizon. The experimental work carried out to investigate the effect of meteorological phenomena on the signal received over a microwave link between Ottawa and Dorval Airport is described. Further experiments which suggested themselves as a result of this work are outlined.</description><creator>Stone, Samuel Alexander.</creator><contributor>Pavlasek, T.J.F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1958</date><subject></subject><subject>Electrical Engineering.</subject><title>Beyond the Horizon Propagation at Microwave Frequencies.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns064947h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vx68z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):17675</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>