<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:58:44Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2175" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr172038m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Functional consequences of the combination of an N-terminal deletion of the rat Na, K-ATPase alpha1 subunit (alpha1M32) and a Glu233 → Lys substitution (E233K) in the M2-M3 loop provide evidence for mutual interactions of these cytoplasmic regions. The steady-state conformational equilibrium of the double mutant (alpha1M32E233K) is shifted towards E 1, which was evidenced by kinetic changes including (1) a 15-fold reduction in catalytic turnover (Vmax/EPmax), (2) an increase in apparent affinity for ATP, (3) a decrease in vanadate sensitivity, (4) a marked (≈10-fold) K+-activation of Na-ATPase activity, and (5) altered cation affinities. The decrease in catalytic turnover effected by the double mutation was associated with a 5-fold decrease in Vmax and a compensatory ≈3-fold increase in expressed alpha1M32E233K protein. The importance of charge at residue 233 is underscored by the consequences of single and double mutations comprising either a conservative (E233D), a neutral (E233Q), or a positive (E233K) substitution.</description><creator>Boxenbaum, Nanna.</creator><contributor>Blostein, R. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Functional consequences of mutations in cytoplasmic domains of the sodium pump alpha subunit</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bh229.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr172038m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p248p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This observational study compared the value of physician-administered Advanced Life Support (MD-ALS) to Basic Life Support (BLS) in the treatment of penetra1mg trauma in an urban setting. Patients were identified in Montreal and Quebec City between 1993 to 1997 Prehospital care is provided exclusively by Urgences Sante in Montreal. Patients in Montreal are randomly allocated to either ALS or BLS due to an insufficient number of MD-ALS units. The south shore of Montreal and Quebec City are serviced by a separate emergency medical system (EMS) which provides only BLS. Differences were not statistically significant in terms of age and ISS between treatment groups. Mortality, when examined using both the Intent to Treat and Efficacy approaches, did not differ between ALS and BLS patients. Prehospital treatment type was not a significant predictor of mortality, or length of hospital stay. Patients treated by MD-ALS required home-care services more often than BLS patients once discharged, and spent significantly more time at the injury scene.</description><creator>Benoit, Paul Daniel.</creator><contributor>Sampalis, John (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Impact of on-site physician care in penetrating trauma</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zz67c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p248p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d219v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The E1B-55 kDa protein of human adenovirus type 5 is known to function early in lytic infection by reversing growth arrest and apoptosis that result from E1A-induced accumulation and activation of the p53 cellular tumor suppressor. This function allows infected cells to survive long enough to produce high levels of progeny virions, and in the case of rodent cells it permits the formation of stable E1A transformants. The E1B-55 kDa protein binds to p53 and inhibits its ability to activate transcription. Inhibition of p53 appears to result from transcriptional repression activity associated with the E1B-55 kDa polypeptide. In the present studies using fusion products containing the DNA binding domain of Gal4 linked to a series of mutant E1B-55 kDa proteins, we have identified a domain towards its carboxy terminus that is responsible for repression. It may function directly as a repressor or it may bind to a cellular repressor that is targeted to p53-dependent promoters through interactions of the E1B-55 kDa protein with p53. This domain is also present in the 156-residue (156R) product of E1B, which is composed of the amino terminus 79 and carboxy terminus 77 amino acids of the E1B-55 kDa protein. Although 156R does not appear to bind to p53 in the in vivo experiments conducted here, its repression activity could be directed against other targets through a separate mechanism.</description><creator>Assefi, Laila.</creator><contributor>Branton, P. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Identification of the transcriptional repression domain of the adenovirus type 5 E1B-55 kDa protein</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gv832.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d219v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418q31h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main objectives of this prospective cohort study were to examine the construct and predictive validity of the STREAM, and estimating its responsiveness. Sixty three acute stroke patients were evaluated on the STREAM and other measures of impairment and disability during the first week post-stroke, four weeks later, and three months post-stroke. The results of the study showed that STREAM scores were associated with measures of impairment and disability, and could discriminate subjects based on Balance Scale and Barthel Index scores. Moreover, the STREAM during the first week post-stroke was found to be an independent predictor of discharge destination after the acute care hospital, and of gait speed and the Barthel Index at three months post stroke. In addition, the total and subscale STREAM scores were able to mirror changes in motor performance between each evaluation. The utility and measurement properties of STREAM warrant its use in clinical practice and research.</description><creator>Ahmed, Sara, 1974-</creator><contributor>Mayo, Nancy (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><title>The Stroke Rehabilitation Assessment of Movement (STREAM) : validity and responsiveness</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cg56h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418q31h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591b57x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Substantial numbers of adolescents suffer from the detrimental effects of internalized shame, however no assessment scale existed specifically for use with youth. Consequently, this study utilized multidimensional scaling, focus groups and questionnaires to develop the Adolescent Internalized Shame Scale. Analyzes revealed some clinicians do not adequately differentiate shame and guilt, adolescents unquestionably comprehend the feelings and ramifications of shame and there are significant gender differences in how youth experience shame. Statements generated by youth during focus groups and on the questionnaires raise considerable concerns regarding the painful experience of shame, and the resultant feelings of self-harm and suicide. In addition, the youth generated statements confirmed the desire of some youth to respond to shame with anger or rage, thus highlighting the gravity of the situation and necessity for effective intervention by clinicians.</description><creator>Johnston, Cindy M.</creator><contributor>Werk, Annette (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Shame -- Testing</subject><subject>Shame in adolescence</subject><title>Development of the adolescent internalized shame scale</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dv293.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591b57x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nw70k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Battery is a major health care issue that, despite increased recognition, fails to be detected in health care institutions. Without adequate detection, referral to social and community services are less likely to occur, rendering women victims vulnerable to continued risk physically, psychologically and medically. This study seeks to describe actual detection and referral practices in an emergency department at a large teaching hospital in Quebec, as well as explore health care professionals' knowledge about and practices regarding the detection and referral of battered women. Its aim is to better understand the pathways and barriers to detection and referral of abused women in order to enhance current practice responses in emergency departments. To examine detection and referral rates and predictors of battery, 200 medical charts from the emergency department were reviewed. Supplementing analyses of the charts were in depth interviews with ten health care professionals working in the emergency department. From these sources of data, it became apparent that neither detection nor referral occur in any systematic fashion. Whereas health care professionals seem to know a great deal about battery, their actual practice appears to be contradictory. Gynecological problems and woman's age were not found to be related to detail in charts but physical injuries were. Whereas a positive relationship was found between detection and referral in the chart reviews, everyday practice showed inadequacy in both areas. Implications for social work contributions to health care practice related to battery are offered.</description><creator>Iorio, Cristina.</creator><contributor>Krane, Julia (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Medical social work.</subject><subject>Hospitals -- Emergency services.</subject><subject>Abused women -- Medical care.</subject><title>Detecting and referring battered women : an emergency department case study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v7689.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nw70k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tp079</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Increasing numbers of older persons, service provision within the home and shrinking resources have resulted in the need to evaluate service provision. This study examined agency process and client-perceived health in a single point of entry case managed program in a community health centre. The participatory evaluative model involved a dossier review, interviews with workers, and a description of client functioning using the SF-12(TM). Examination of files (N = 100) revealed that objectives were not being obtained: client involvement was low, services were late, and files were poorly completed. Only 14 (9%) of clients were referred for the SF-12(TM); further investigation revealed systemic difficulties such as lost clients (N = 4). Worker interviews (N = 12) explained that heavy caseloads result in reactive services, poor completion of case management functions, and service implications for clients. Strengths included the multi-disciplinary approach and single point of entry. Recommendations include a cost benefit analysis, an outcome measure, a caseload standard and a quality assurance model that assures accountability and monitoring.</description><creator>Grenier, Amanda.</creator><contributor>Duder, Sydney (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Older people -- Home care -- Québec (Province) -- Evaluation.</subject><subject>Home care services -- Québec (Province) -- Evaluation.</subject><title>Home care : evaluation of a case management model</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj4306857.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tp079</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712m896m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Objectives. Explore and describe the impact of premature life-threatening illness, stigma, multiple loss of significant others, decreased vocational choice and mobility and decreased financial security among young gay men living with AIDS. It was hypothesized that young gay men with AIDS and the elderly experience similar physical, social, and psychological changes, but the cognitive adaptation to these changes are hindered by the non-normative timing of these events. Methods. Thirty-two self-identified gay men with AIDS between the ages of 22 to 44 years were recruited from an out-patient clinic in Montreal. These participants were asked to complete a comprehensive questionnaire, which assessed the respondent's daily stress, impact of HIV, health-related quality of life, ways of coping, multiple loss, dependency on informal and formal supports, and preparation for death. Quantitative methods were used to analyse the data. Results. The hypothesis was confirmed. Respondents reported relatively low levels of health-related quality of life, significant concern over health and financial security, considerable multiple loss, increased dependency on informal and formal supports, proportionally greater use of active coping strategies, and significant concern about discrimination. Conclusions. A comprehensive method of intervention which addresses all of the biopsychosocial aspects to care is proposed. It is suggested that a coordinated multidisiciplinary approach to clinical and research endeavors should be adopted to address the multidimensional obstacles facing young gay men with AIDS.</description><creator>Bourgeois, Chantal G.</creator><contributor>Rowe, William (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>AIDS (Disease) -- Patients -- Mental health</subject><subject>AIDS (Disease) -- Psychological aspects</subject><title>The impact of AIDS on the life cycle of young gay men /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cs66g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m896m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xs55mf00h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>As the rate of divorce is increasing, the number of children who have to cope with these stressful situations is also growing. Since these divorces come with many problems for the children involved, they are getting more and more attention. The professionnals who are required by the court to give their opinion on who should get the custody or what will be the right of access, have pointed out a particular phenomenon: parental alienation syndrome. The first person who described this syndrome was Gardner (1989, 1992a). He blamed the court system for the syndrome, where, in its adversarial perspective, one side tries to win over the other using alienation as one of their strategies. In our opinion, this view does not account for all the aspects of the parental alienation syndrome and for the emotional turmoil created by the divorce. When, after a divorce, one is trapped in one's emotions, the result is an impass, where parental alienation is but one aspect of this impass. This paper shows how an impass, grows and which form the parental alienation syndrome takes. Cases from our practice will illustrate some situations of parental alienation resulting from a psychological impass and where the children are the victims.</description><creator>Bellerose, Jean-Guy.</creator><contributor>John, Lindsay (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Divorced parents -- Psychology</subject><subject>Divorced parents -- Family relationships.</subject><subject>Children of divorced parents</subject><title>De l'impasse du divorce à l'aliénation parentale</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75df70p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55mf00h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053j257</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Antonio Averlino, known as Filarete (1400--1469), wrote that architecture is a gestational process, likening the architect to the mother and the father as the client. The process requires the architect-mother to " fantasticare e pensare e rivoltarselo per la memoria," fermenting ideas and incubating them in conjunction with one's memory. The intent is to understand mnemonics as a creative operation in Filarete's Trattato di Architettura. A key to this lies with Filarete's personal symbol, the bee. The bee's process of mellification acts as a metaphor of the architect's gestational design. The bee, long utilized as a memorative trope, points towards other memory models created throughout the treatise, culminating with the design for the House of Vice and Virtue. Directing the reader and inhabitants of the city in a social narrative, Filarete's architecture reveals the dependence upon remembrance and virtue for the city's creation and public rituals to sustain its life.</description><creator>Yocum, Carole.</creator><contributor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Filarete, ca. 1400-ca. 1469. Trattato di architettura.</subject><title>Architecture and the bee : virtue and memory in Filarete's Trattato di architettura</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n327j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053j257</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752j942</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Traditional communities in most Third World countries today are facing the influx of all industrialized economy which is leading to the introduction of new building technologies, infrastructure and modern communications. This has resulted in a change in the built environment of traditional settlements. There are many dynamic factors which help to shape the decisions people make about the physical nature of their built environment. The linking of these decision-making factors to the external forces influencing society is very important to arrive at a clear understanding of how traditional forms give way to new ones. This thesis links global and local forces in interaction in the small mountain community of Karimabad, Hunza in Northern Pakistan, which is experiencing the effects of a capital economy and the new social and cultural milieu which accompanies it. Added to that the community has also been subjected to the effects of international tourism and development projects. The thesis shows, how, under the influences of these factors, the local traditional house form has transformed in terms of change in building materials and housing layouts. This study was also carried out with the view of linking local perceptions of change, with the actual physical changes in housing. The thesis attempts to show how the ordinary household in Karimabad makes its decisions for change, and views the outside world and their place in it, and how this change is reflected in the changed house forms and building materials. This research also draws on the theoretical framework and references of how globalization is affecting traditional settlements on the periphery. The findings of the study point to a strong link between external influences, especially of media, tourism, and international development institutions, and the changed house forms and materials. It also shows that it is not possible to isolate individual decision-making from external influences, especially where material culture is concerned.</description><creator>Viquar, Sarwat.</creator><contributor>Bhatt, Vikram (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Architecture, Domestic -- Pakistan -- Karimabad.</subject><subject>Hunza (Pakistan) -- Social conditions.</subject><title>Modernization and cultural transformation : change in building materials and house forms, Karimabad, Pakistan</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227ms032.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752j942</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75df71z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>At the close of the sixteenth century, the Roman architect Domenico Fontana choreographed the transformation of the Vatican Obelisk from its antique position on the circus of Nero, to its present location facing St. Peter's. Fontana's treatise Della trasportatione dell'obelisco Vaticano (1590), records this event in a detailed narrative, and a series of remarkable etchings. Architect to Pope Sixtus V, Fontana is often cited as a founder of city planning due to his seminal reorganization of Rome's topography, and as an early proponent of civil engineering owing to his calculated mechanics. Yet neither of these appellations do justice to Fontana's complex practice, one in which architecture is composed in time, characterized by the intensity and profundity of the festival, and the divine power of Man to operate within a world of sympathies. The scaffold which translates the obelisk---and the occulted knowledge of these cosmographic relations---into the space of the city, also invokes an alternate tradition for architecture. Opposite classical solidity and eternal being, Fontana's castello proposes the immaterial, and the ephemeral. An inquiry into this scene of emerging order is particularly relevant for our contemporary world, with our idols fallen and our foundations in rain. Appended to this thesis is an abridged English translation of Della trasportatione, chapter 1.</description><creator>Toker, Eric Solomon.</creator><contributor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Obelisks -- Vatican City.</subject><subject>Vatican City -- Buildings, structures, etc.</subject><subject>Fontana, Domenico, 1543-1607. Della trasportatione dell'obelisco Vaticano.</subject><title>An architectural excursus into the site of becoming : Domenico Fontana's Della trasportatione dell'obelisco Vaticano</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848s645.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75df71z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f8126</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis analyses the architecture of the Royal Victoria College (Bruce Price, 1896--1899), a purpose-built women's residential college of McGill University, Montreal, and its first extension (Percy Nobbs, 1930--193 1), as material evidence of the rhetorical construction and negotiation of gender. A contextual analysis of the original RVC reveals the gender significance of the building's relationship to its affiliate institution (McGill), to an urban geography (Phillips Square), and to a commercial typology (the railway hotel), while a spatial analysis examines the significance of its women occupants as 'architects', and of changes to the building over time. The thesis concludes that the building served as an important site in turn-of-the-century gender negotiations---one that helped to contest "separate spheres" rhetoric and that stands as evidence of women's active participation in the shaping of spatial relations and social identities.</description><creator>Miller, Deborah L., 1960-</creator><contributor>Adams, Annmarie (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Dormitories -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Architecture and women -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History</subject><subject>Royal Victoria College (Montréal, Québec) -- Buildings.</subject><subject>Women college students -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History.</subject><title>"The big ladies' hotel" : gender, residence, and middle-class Montreal : a contextual analysis of the Royal Victoria College, 1899-1931</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v987n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f8126</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53wx970</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Among the few matrilineal communities from around the world were the Nairs of the south-western coast, also known as the Malabar coast, of India. The system of matrilineal consanguinity and descent practiced by the Nairs was remarkable for its complex kinship organization and joint family set up, and the unique status---social and economic---it afforded to the women of the community. These factors were reflected in the spatial morphology of the traditional Nair house, an assemblage of four blocks, called the nalukettu. The different structural identities of the tarawad institution; the comparative latitude and the bias of inheritance that women enjoyed; the codes of marriage, interaction and avoidance; and the observation of rituals, an integral part of the cosmology and temporal cycle of the system, all find expression in the layout and spatial organization. On the whole, the geometry of the Nair nalukettu was a graphic metaphor of the social and behavioral patterns of the Nair community overlaid on the Hindu way of life, as interpreted by the community. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Menon P., Balakrishna.</creator><contributor>Bhat, Vikram (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Adams, Annmarie (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Nairs -- Social life and customs.</subject><subject>Matrilineal kinship -- India -- Kerala.</subject><subject>Architecture and society -- India -- Kerala.</subject><subject>Architecture, Domestic -- India -- Kerala.</subject><title>Matriliny and domestic morphology : a study of the Nair tarawads of Malabar</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053j26h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wx970</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913r984</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this thesis is to identify alternative building systems for low rise housing, that can be applied to the market of countries of the former Yugoslavia. Six building systems, developed and produced in Canada, have been selected for this purpose. In order to compare them to existing system, the set of criteria for evaluation is developed, based on three major aspects: the technical aspect deals with codes and regulations, implementation, durability and other physical characteristics of building systems; the economic aspect compares costs; and the psychological aspect investigates the level of acceptance from both the builders' and homeowners' point of view. The results of this research prove the complexity of the issue of technology transfer. Even though all evaluated building systems showed technical and, particularly economical improvements over the existing masonry, it is the issue of cultural acceptance that is the determining factor in the success of a new product. That is the main reason why building systems based on concrete would more likely be accepted over "light" frame systems. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Horvat, Miljana.</creator><contributor>Friedman, Avi (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Housing -- Slovenia.</subject><subject>Housing -- Croatia.</subject><subject>Housing -- Yugoslavia.</subject><subject>Housing -- Macedonia.</subject><subject>Housing -- Bosnia and Hercegovina.</subject><title>Technology transfer : can Canadian affordable homes be built in the countries of former Yugoslavia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21th61b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913r984</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930c042x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research documents the use of a 7.6 cm laboratory Knelson Concentrator (LKC) to determine the amount of gravity recoverable gold (GRG) content in ores and evaluate the performance of gravity circuits, with an emphasis on high gangue density. Two approaches were used to minimize the effect of the high gangue density in estimating the GRG content, oversize removal and 2:1 ratio dilution with silica flour. The amount of GRG was determined in four ore samples with an established protocol, yielding values of 35% to 78% of total gold. Results from the Angnico-Eagle La Ronde Division (AELRD), Louvicourt and East Malartic mills suggest that the typical Knelson-based gravity circuit which can recover one half to two thirds of GRG from low density gangues will only recover one third to two fifths of the GRG from high density gangues. Simulation of gold recovery at AELRD showed that the high circulating loads, 700--1100%, were a significant factor in reducing gold recovery by gravity. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Zhang, Bo, 1963-</creator><contributor>Laplante, Andre (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><subject>Mineralogy.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Recovering gold from high density gangues with Knelson concentrators</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930c0436.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c042x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b819c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>For centuries human society has relied on coal as a principal source of fuel for heat and power. Extraction of this valuable fuel has always been influenced by control over hazards such as water inflows and potentially explosive dust and methane gas. A major focus of the research has been on methane including: methane properties of seams, insitu and laboratory testing; methane emissions; investigation of operational issues (e. g. Phalen 7 East); and refinement of prediction models. This thesis gives an overview of methane and ventilation research covering the following aspects: Defining coal seam characteristics: specific emissions---the relationship between methane content, coal 'rank' and depth; the geothermal gradient; insitu gas pressure; and associated hydrocarbon content of mine air samples analyzed. Defining the performance of Sewergate ventilation, particularly on Phalen 7 East. Sewergate ventilation is a marriage between a typical 'U' and a bleeder ventilation system. Underground measurements including a novel use of 'tubebundles', have provided a clearer understanding of factors affecting Sewergate performance. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Young, David A., 1960-</creator><contributor>Hassani, F. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Methane and ventilation studies in coal mining in the Sydney Coalfield, Nova Scotia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257h090.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b819c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x601w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new gold centrifugal concentrator, the Falcon SuperBowl, was tested both at plant and laboratory scales to assess its ability to recover gold from grinding circuits. The performances of a 21-in SuperBowl (SB21) at Mineral Hill and New Britannia Mines showed that it could recover gravity recoverable gold (GRG) of all sizes, especially below 25 mum at Mineral Hill Mine. Three types (to test the effect of gangue density and size distribution) of synthetic feeds were used to characterize a laboratory 4-in SuperBowl (SB4) as a function of feed rate and fluidization water flow rate. A 20-in Knelson Concentrator and a shaking table were further tested in this program with the samples extracted from Casa Berardi and Mineral Hill Mine, respectively. The 30-in Knelson was tested at two different conditions to assess the impact of fluidization water flow rate and explore the importance of cycle time. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Xiao, Jie, 1964-</creator><contributor>Laplante, A. R. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Testing a new gold centrifugal concentrator</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237ht87j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x601w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j6731616d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Quick-return mechanisms are quite common in manufacturing processes. e.g in pick-and-place operations, metal-cutting, and metal-forming, where dwell is usually required. Dwell is the period where a driven link remains stationary and the tool can be replaced or the workpiece can undergo a machining operation. Unlike lower-pair mechanisms, cam mechanisms can produce dwell exactly. In this thesis, cam-follower systems are used as building modules in the design of quick-return mechanisms. The underlying cam mechanisms are optimized to obtain a compact, quick-return mechanism. A unified method for the optimization of cam mechanisms is proposed. The optimum parameters of the cam mechanism are obtained by cam-area minimization subject to performance and geometric constraints. In addition, the power required from the motor is reduced by adding an elastic torque-compensation mechanism to the system. A Graphical User Interface is developed to aid the designer during the design process. The modular method is applied to the synthesis and optimization of long-stroke, quick-return mechanisms. In addition, the design of a simple cam mechanism to replace the transmission mechanism of a textile machine composed of an elliptic-gear train and a four-bar linkage is also included as an application example.</description><creator>Wu, Chu-Jen.</creator><contributor>Angeles, Jorge (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>A modular approach to the synthesis of quick-return mechanisms /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pg114.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j6731616d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nc580p73p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A two-part system for the semi-automatic collection, correction, and analysis of blood data collected during positron emission tomography (PET) studies is presented. The blood data collection system may be used for either manual or automatic sampling of blood, from either arterial or venous source. It performs all corrections required on the blood for confounds external to the body. In addition, this blood collection system allows the integration of an automatic blood sampler with a PET scanner that does not otherwise support one. Finally, it writes a data file in a new, portable, and extensible file format for the storage of blood data. The blood analysis system reads this blood data file and allows the rapid implementation of compartmental kinetic models of tracer behaviour. The tools that comprise this system are also extensible and allow the development of analysis tools for other brain imaging modalities.</description><creator>Wolforth, Mark.</creator><contributor>Evans, Alan C. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>A system for the acquisition and analysis of blood data for positron emission tomography /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w6634583t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580p73p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2v23vw15q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Thickening is the separation of suspended solid particles from a liquid by gravity settling. As a feed stream enters the thickener, the solids settle to the bottom. Clarified liquid overflows the top and the settled solids (underflow) is removed. Thickeners are widely used in the minerals and metal processing industry. To assist in the monitoring and control of thickeners a conductivity probe has been developed. Test work was carried out on a concentrate thickener at the Copper Cliff, Ontario Division of Inco Limited in Sudbury. The conductivity probe is a multicell arrangement. It exploits the difference in conductivity between liquid, slurry and settled solids. A conductivity profile is collected which locates the interfaces (liquid/slurry, slurry/settled solids) by detecting the change in conductivity, The conductivity profile can be readily converted to a solids concentration profile using a model due to Maxwell. From the solids profile, a solids inventory are obtained along with an estimation of underflow density. The main tasks in this thesis were to (a) develop a method of on-line calibration and (b) develop a level estimation procedure. The former was achieved by designing a portable probe and lowering it in to predetermined positions corresponding to rings on the probe. The time between re-calibration was also established (ca. 10 days). In the case of the level a previous method using a 0--1 scale has been converted to a true bed height using the bed height estimated by the operators using a weighted rope.</description><creator>Vergouw, Ir. Jolanda.</creator><contributor>Finch, J. A. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>A conductivity probe for thickeners : calibration and level estimation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kj432.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vw15q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rk25q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The influence of microstructure on the mechanical and tribological properties of an ASTM F1537-94 Co-Cr-Mo alloy was studied in this work. The microstructure was manipulated through room temperature deformation, heat treatment and varying the C content of the material. Deformation of the material resulted in a strain-induced transformation (SIT) of the metastable face-centered cubic crystal structure to the stable hexagonal close-packed (HCP) structure. The volume fraction of the HCP phase was found to be proportional to the applied strain and was also found to decrease with an increase in the C content. Nor deformation of the material improved the mechanical properties by increasing the yield strength and ultimate tensile strength of the material without any significant losses to the elongation to fracture. A heat treatment was performed prior to room temperature deformation in order to homogenize the microstructure. This lowered the amount of SIT and the strength of the material, due to the coarser grain structure. The coefficient of friction of the material decreased when the C content in the alloy was low. There were no significant changes to the coefficient of friction with increasing amounts of the HCP phase in the bulk microstructure.</description><creator>Varano, Rocco.</creator><contributor>Yue, Steve (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Bobyn, J. Dennis (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><title>Structure-property investigation of Co-Cr-Mo alloys used in metal-metal total hip replacements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881p207.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rk25q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nc580p74z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Canadian Institute for Telecommunications Research (CITR) has undertaken a five year "Major Project" in Photonic Systems and Devices to develop a backplane based on free-space optical technology. One of the main goals of the "Major Project" is to develop an optical backplane architecture capable of interconnecting several electronic printed circuit boards (PCBs) with an aggregate bandwidth on the order of 1 Terabit per second (Tb/s). In this thesis, we will consider the design of an electrical-optical interface for a free-space optical backplane that can support 307.2 Gigabits per second (Gb/s) of aggregate data traffic. The electrical-optical interface is also known as a "Smart Pixel Array" (SPA) since it is an integrated two-dimensional array of opto-electronic devices with optical and electronic I/O, and with electronic processing capabilities. To take advantage of the very high bandwidth of optics, the on-chip electronics must be carefully designed to support the necessary functions required, while minimizing critical paths to support very high optical clock rates. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Tyan, Victor.</creator><contributor>Szymenski, Ted (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Design of an electrical-optical interface for a 307.2 GBS free-space optical backplane</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w0325147.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580p74z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sc45d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Damping of steel beams with constrained viscoelastic layers is studied in both the frequency and time domains. Cantilevered steel beam specimens with various configurations of constrained viscoelastic layers are experimentally and analytical subjected to random frequency vibrations, spike inputs, and large finite rotations A frequency dependent shear modulus is used to express the viscoelastic material behavior in the frequency domain, and a Prony series representation of the shear relaxation modulus is used for time domain simulations. The simulated response converges using approximately five Prony terms in the series. Increase in damping from one to two layers of constrained viscoelastic treatment and the detrimental effect of a discontinuous constrained viscoelastic treatment is observed experimentally. Predicted responses obtained using the proposed finite element model exhibit similar trends. Natural frequencies and damping factors obtained from linear and nonlinear time domain finite element analyses are found to be in good agreement with experimental results.</description><creator>Slanik, Marta.</creator><contributor>Nemes, James A. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><title>A numerical and experimental investigation of steel beams damped with constrained viscoelastic layers /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f570q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sc45d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67jt39f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:18:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Laminar morphology of high density polyethylene (HDPE)/polyamide-6 (PA-6) blends was obtained, for the first time, in a co-rotating twin screw extruder. The morphology analysis in the interior of the adapter, which connects the extruder with a slit die, revealed that, under specific processing conditions, it is possible to produce layers of PA-6 in the end of the screw zone of the extruder. These layers were visible at very low magnification (6.7X). It was also observed that a high adapter converging angle (70°) produced breakup of the layers, due to the high elongational and shear flow. The micrographs of the extruded final products showed distributed layers across the sample thickness are along the flow direction. The effect of design variables such as adapter angle and die gap on the final product morphology was studied. The effect of processing variables, including temperature profile, feed rate, and screw speed, were evaluated. speed, were evaluated. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Rodriguez Veloz, Oscar Alberto.</creator><contributor>Kamal, M. R. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Plastics Technology.</subject><title>The development of laminar morphology in a co-rotating twin screw extruder /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021h343.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67jt39f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2200</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>