<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:05:23Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):16400" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pr76f718w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A number of nematode species can be found in almost any sample of agricultural soil taken at random. Some of these have long been recognized as the causative organisms of certain diseases in plants and as causing crop losses of economic significance. Recently there has been increased recognition of the importance of this group of parasites. Farmers as well as research workers are coming to realize that reduced yield and diseased conditions may often be laid at the door of the “eelworm”. Intensive and extensive study of phytonematology is therefore in order. Visible evidence can be found in the numerous publications in these fields.</description><creator>Preiser, Franz. A.</creator><contributor>Morrison, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Entomology.</subject><title>Study and development of comparative laboratory testing methods of nematicides.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053k83b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f718w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2774022w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>All contracts of air carriage nowadays contain provisions limiting or excluding the liability of the carrier in the event of the negligence or otherwise of himself or his servants and agents. Since, in the vast majority of cases, the carrier employs servants and agents for the purpose of carrying out his obligations under his contracts to carry, the injury or damage complained of will invariably be the result of the acts of these servants or agents. The injured party will then have a choice of actions. He may sue the carrier whose vicarious liability is limited by the contract or he may sue the servant or agent who actually caused the damage.</description><creator>Pratt, Geoffrey. N.</creator><contributor>Rosevear, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Air and Space Law.</subject><title>Contractual limitation of servants’ liability in air carriage.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zj048.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2774022w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj139567c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The composition and structural features of feldspars from the rocks of Mounts Royal, Bruno, Johnson, St. Hilaire, Rougemont, Yamaska, Shefford and Brome have been studied by optical and x-ray diffraction methods. Extensive diffraction work did not disclose the presence of highly disordered feldspars (high comparative forms). However, the plagioclases of these rocks belong to a distinct series whose order-disorder relations are in agreement with the geological setting of the intrusives and would classify the rocks as hypabyssal rocks (shallow seated rocks). The alkali feldspars of the Monteregian rocks belong to the low-albite--orthoclase series. The presence of this series of alkali feldspars and the absence of feldspars of the low-albite--microcline series is a characteristic of these rocks that is regarded to be a consequence of their cooling history. The rate of cooling of the igneous masses and the annealing of the rocks under predominantly dry conditions are thought to have been the principal factors responsible for the incomplete ordering of the feldspars. The trends of crystallization and the interrelations between the rock types are discussed on the basis of the compositional data obtained on the feldspars. A qualitative diagram for pressures of approximately 1000 bars has been presented to explain the paragenesis of the feldspar associations encountered in the Monteregian Rocks.</description><creator>Pouliot, Gaston.</creator><contributor>Stevenson, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>The thermal history of the Monteregian intrusive based on a study of the feldspars.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h318h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139567c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s6082</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The work of Wearn (1933) describing the myocardial circulation, with its myocardial sinusoids and arterio-luminal vessels, was confirmed by Vineberg in 1945. He reported implanting the left internal mammary artery into the wall of the left ventricle. The intercostal branches were open and bled freely into the myocardial tunnel through which the internal mammary artery had been drawn. In no single instance, in either animal or human heart, was there a myocardial hematoma. The implanted arteries not only remained open, but sent out branches which anastomosed with those of the surrounding coronary vessels.</description><creator>Pifarre, Roque.</creator><contributor>Vineberg, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>An experimental evaluation of different procedures to induce ventricular-luminal-myocardial circulation.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tw13v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s6082</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Health Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xw597</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:01:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this discussion of the Ukraino-Polish border problem, we have to take into consideration two distinct aspects of the problem. On the one hand, we have to analyse the problem as a problem of development and growth of the constitution; on the other band, the problem is seen as an aspect of diplomacy. The border problem cannot be separated from the general constitutional questions. The border, in fact, becomes delineated in the process of formation of a state. The border is the limit of claim of sovereignty, and of its effective exercise by a state. Hence, in our discussion of the Ukraino-Polish border problem we will have to trace the development of the corresponding states, and see how their borders, or claims for borders clashed.</description><creator>Pidhaini, Oleg.</creator><contributor>Mladenovic, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>History.</subject><title>The question of the Ukraino-Polish border during the First World War.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v211z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xw597</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r6784</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:02:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Investigations into the effects of aerobic bacteria, belonging to the cereus group, on insects are very numerous and important advances in this field have been made during the last decade. Workers have shown that strains of crystalliferous bacteria, known under the names of Bacillus thuringiensis Berliner and Bacillus entomocidus Heimpel and Angus, are highly virulent and specific to Lepidopterous larvae. Several workers have reported that Galleria mellonella L. has a variable susceptibility to Bacillus thuringiensis Berliner.</description><creator>Perron, Jean-Marie.</creator><contributor>Morrison, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Entomology.</subject><title>The effects of commercial Bacillus thuringiensis Berliner spore preparations on Galleria mellonella L. (Lepidoptera, pyralidae) in the Laboratory.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sf07d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r6784</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xw600</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:02:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The introduction into an animal of a foreign substance, usually a natural macromolecule such as a protein, a polysaccharide or a conjugated lipid induces the production of globular serum proteins which possess the unique property of combining specifically with the foreign substance (1). These serum proteins are known as antibodies and the foreign substances responsible for their production are known as antigens. An animal or individual in whom antibodies have been formed is said to be immunized. These antibodies are produced either by natural exposure or injection of the antigen.</description><creator>Perelmutter, Lewis. L.</creator><contributor>Sehon, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Characterization of antibodies in sera of allergic individuals.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jv73z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xw600</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jd473098n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:02:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The results of model footing tests on a remoulded clay are described. For the clay used in these tests, the observed deformations and bearing capacities were not in agreement with those expected from the conventional bearing theories. The observed bearing capacity was about 25 percent less than that given by the latter theories, due to a punching or local shear failure. An approximate theory developed by Bishop et al (1945), to determine the load required to force a punch into a semi-infinite cohesive mass, was examined. The bearing capacity determined from this theory was in reasonable agreement with the results of the model tests, and also a limited amount of other data which could be examined. On the basis of these limited results, a relation is suggested for the bearing capacity of surface footings on saturated clay which includes, and predicts from the stress-strain properties of the clay, the case where a local shear failure occurs.</description><creator>Peck, Graeme. M.</creator><contributor>Yong, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics.</subject><title>Bearing theories related to model tests on remoulded clay.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655m106.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd473098n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278x92x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:02:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The substantial increase in chicken broiler production in recent years has created a demand for a steady supply of broiler chicks in order to keep pace with consumer demand for poultry meats of this kind. Meat-type pullets therefore constitute a significant part of pullet replacement programs each year as these pullets eventually become the breeding hens that provide hatching eggs for the broiler industry. Methods of feeding have been given serious attention for many years and considerable variation in feeding systems is encountered in recommendations for the feeding of poultry.</description><creator>Parkin, Herbert. J.</creator><contributor>Nikolaiczuk, N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Nutrition.</subject><title>The effect of feed restriction upon the growth and initial performance of meat-type replacement pullets.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qt52z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278x92x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agriculture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547w07m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:02:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Basic assumptions throughout the linear baroclinic model proposed by Fleagle (1957) for atmospheric motions are re-evaluated to assess applicability of the model for vertical motion computations in connection with potential-kinetic energy conversions in the stratosphere. It is found that some revisions are necessary to adequately describe very long wave activity, dominant at these levels, under the high stability conditions present. The source of the difficulties is found in the scaling of parameters of the zonal flow. Simple, but computationally awkward, corrections are suggested, and their affect partially traced through the model.</description><creator>O’Reilly, Brian. E.</creator><contributor>Boville, B. W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Meteorology.</subject><title>Atmospheric energy conversions by the Fleagle model.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rp830.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547w07m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fm788</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:02:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents a new method of analyzing Gaussian distributions as found in photopeaks in scintillation spectrometry. The technique provides an improvement in accuracy and convenience for obtaining line widths and positions over previously available methods. Some aspects of energy resolution of scintillation counters are investigated, and a semi-graphical method is described for resolving lines that overlap too much to be easily analyzed by other techniques.</description><creator>Onno, Peter.</creator><contributor>Bell, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>The energy resolution of scintillation counters.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qt537.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fm788</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2j62s8469</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:02:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>From 1834 to 1836 the Colony of the Cape of Good Hope was in a state of fermentation that was to bring about, in the whole of South Africa, changes which were as great as they were unforescen - The emancipation of slaves and the compensation of their owners. The English Parliament voted for the latter purpose, a sum of 20,000 pounds but unfortunately, that amount proved insufficient to pay the compensation in full, with the result that grave disatisfaction was caused everywhere, espacially in South Africa where the slaves numbered 35,000.</description><creator>Ntsinyi, Claude. T.</creator><contributor>Reid, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>History.</subject><title>The British attitude towards the Basuto.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k1722.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s8469</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vm587</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:02:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Spalanzani (1768) was the first to study regeneration in vertebrates. He discovered this phenomenon in the limbs and tails of newts and frog tadpoles. Since then and particularly during the last seventy odd years, regeneration in vertebrates has been an attractive field of research. The studies have been directed both towards discovering the presence, absence or extent of regenerative capacities in different animals as well as towards reaching an understanding of the actual processes involved.</description><creator>Niazi, Iqbal. A.</creator><contributor>Berrill, N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Zoology.</subject><title>Histological studies in regeneration of tails in anuran tadpoles and ammocoetes.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j3860b39p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vm587</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sk85r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:02:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Management of public enterprise in Canada has been generally entrusted to a public corporation which, it is argued, provides the necessary managerial freedom from undesirable political control. It is also considered to encourage both productive competitiveness, and a sufficient degree of public control in accordance with the principle of responsible government. The Canadian Broadcasting Corporation and the Canadian National Railways are under considerable public control through the media of regulatory and investigative agencies, both parliamentary and governmental. Parliament, which constitutes the apex of the administrative pyramid, possesses sufficient opportunities and methods to exercise its control on these corporations. It is however, suggested that Parliament has not utilized these opportunities to the full extent.</description><creator>Naseer, Syed. M.</creator><contributor>Mallory, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Economics and Political Science.</subject><title>Parliament and the public corporations in Canada: a study in public ownership and accountability.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mk03w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sk85r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics and Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w9505404t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:02:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Data presenting two or more sets or related observations may arise in many fields of activity. It is often desirable to measure the relationship which occurs between these two or more statistical series. This relationship may be established and measured by means of correlation techniques. In many statistical problems the relationships among the variables are so complex that simple correlation gives a very incomplete and inadequate answer to the question. In some problems the variables are studied simultaneously in order to find out their interrelations; in others there is one particular variable of interest and the remaining variables are studied for their possible aid in throwing light on this particular one.</description><creator>Namini, Hassan.</creator><contributor>Guttman, I. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>The distribution of correlation coefficients of samples of size n taken from a k-dimensional normal population.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z709129c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w9505404t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2v23vx58q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:02:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The steroids are a widely occuring group of natural products. They are colourless, crystalline solids and structurally related to the tetracyclic cyclopentanoperhydrophenanthrene. This important class of compounds has been the subject of extensive reviews and those by Fieser and Fieser, Shoppee and Klyne are some of the recent ones. The interest in the chemistry of steroids has remained undiminished since the discovery of cholesterol by Michel Eugène Chevreul in 1815. Early interest in this field was largely confined to elucidation of skeletal structure and the interrelationship of various steroids.</description><creator>Nagarajan, R.</creator><contributor>Just, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The synthesis and reactions of 12-methylsteroids.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p8421.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vx58q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x280j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:02:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A Precambrian layered gabbroic intrusion about 560 km^2 in area, of the Skaergaard type, crops out on the middle north coast of Labrador. Border zones and a Layered series are recognized, and have the following characteristics and approximate mean thicknesses. The intrusion displays extreme fractionation resulting in larvikite consisting of mesoperthite, fayalite, ferroaugite, and ore as the uppermost differentiate. Mineral variation and differentiation are described by means of quantitative mineralogy.</description><creator>Morse, Stearns. A.</creator><contributor>Kranck, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>Geology of the Kiglapait layered intrusion, coast of Labrador, Canada.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289n55t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x280j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qt54h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:02:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In George Eliot's first full-length novel, Adam Bede, she planned to write "a simple story." She wished to paint "faithful pictures of a monotonous homely existence," that would be "the faithful representing of common-place things." (p.183) This determination to write of ordinary people, and more specifically of the working class, was part of the reaction of Victorian writers against the romantic hero; George Eliot takes great pains to remind the reader that she is writing of common-place people, not of "the loftier sorrows of heroines in satin boots and crinoline, and of heroes riding fiery horses, themselves ridden by still more fiery passions."</description><creator>Morris, Margaret. D.</creator><contributor>Lucas, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>English.</subject><title>The role of the protagonist in the novels of George Eliot.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cx87t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qt54h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:73666832v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:02:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis describes the successful extraction of the full energy proton beam from the McGill synchrocyclotron. Extraction was achieved by increasing the radial separation for the last few orbits by the process of non-linear regenerative magnetic deflection, and then leading the last orbit into a magnetic channel. Design and installation of the magnetic regenerator and the magnetic channel are described in the main body of this thesis, and theoretical development of the design criteria is given in the appendix. The extracted beam has been focused to a spot 1.3 x 4.8 mm with a divergence of 1° at a position 15 feet from the channel exit. It has a pulsed time structure consisting of 15 x 10-^6 sec. bursts repeated 400 times per second, and an average intensity of 4 x 10^-9 amperes.</description><creator>Moore, Robert. B.</creator><contributor>Frisken, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>Magnetic extraction of the proton beam from the McGill Synchrocyclotron.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x281t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666832v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h415pf21g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:02:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A synoptic and dynamic investigation of the jet stream reveals that in a transverse profile the maximum wind tends to lie along a pseudo-parabolic rather than a horizontal surface. The upwardfacing parabola is identified by a band of warm temperatures on the cyclonic side of the jet core and a band of cold temperatures on the anticyclonic side. The model is shown to be compatible with the thermal wind relationship.</description><creator>Million, Herbert. A.</creator><contributor>Boville, B. W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Meteorology.</subject><title>A study of the thermal structure of jet stream wind maxima.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sh23w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pf21g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6q182p73v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:02:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dans la croissance et le développement de notre pays bilingue il n'y a probablement aucune question qui ait suscité plus de discussion et oui ait provoqué plus d'articles et de déclarations diverses et contradictoires que la question de la langue française au Canada. Nous avons parmi les critiques d'opinion opposée ceux qui louent le parler des Canadiens-français pour sa pureté et son élégance. Au début du dix-huitième siècle, à l'époque oh le français des premiers colons venus de nombreuses provinces de la France était devenu à peu près uniforme, un visiteur de la France, le père Charlevoix, écrivit que "nulle part on ne parle plus purement le français qu'en Nouvelle- France." </description><creator>Miller, Willard. M.</creator><contributor>Rigault, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>French.</subject><title>Les canadianismes dans le roman canadien-français contemporain.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mr033.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182p73v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zf70s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:02:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The properties of metallic materials are largely determined by their microstructure, i.e. by the relative amounts and by the arrangement of the phases that make up the microstructure. This fact has not been given the full attention which might seem due to it because, in the development of alloys, metallurgists have concentrated most on the properties of the separate constituents, less on the amount of these constituents and least of all on the disposition of the alloying elements in the final structure A simple illustration of the above remarks can be found in the case of cast iron, an alloy of iron and graphite.</description><creator>Miller, William. A.</creator><contributor>Williams, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Metallurgical Engineering.</subject><title>A study of microstructure in zinc-tin alloys.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000363w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zf70s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn3014991</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:02:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis the Feshbach-Lomon Boundary Condition Model for nucleon-nucleon interactions is applied to the Independent Pair Model (or Brueckner theory) of infinite nuclear matter, and to the modified Brueckner theory which includes also the hole-hole interactions. This is accomplished by the construction of a pseudopotential which is equivalent to the Boundary Condition Model in the two-nucleon problem. The pseudopotential is then used in the many-body problem in place of the complicated phenomenological nucleon-nucleon potentials used in more standard treatments. Because of the very simple form of the pseudopotential, the integral equation for the nuclear matter K matrix can be handled relatively easily and without resorting to perturbative approaches. Further, the dependence of the K matrix on the centre of mass momentum of the interacting pair is treated more fully than in previous treatments. Numerical calculations are performed for the case when the nucleon-nucleon interaction vanishes in all but 1s0 states, and in particular the effects arising from the hole-hole interactions and from the centre of mass momentum dependence of the K matrix are discussed. The singularity of the K matrix, the presence of which has been associated with a superconducting state of the system, is investigated for the case when the interaction potential vanishes in all but 1s0 states. The question of whether a singularity exists when the interacting particles have a non-zero centre of mass momentum is also discussed. Finally a value for the size of the energy gap is found.</description><creator>McMillan, James. M.</creator><contributor>Kahana, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>The nuclear many-body problem using the boundary condition model.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75rc57k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn3014991</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j333594r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:02:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An investigation is made of the usefulness of a variational method for the calculation of the neutron flux distribution in a cylinder. In particular the method is applied to a long homogeneous cylinder which captures and isotropically scatters neutrons and which is subject to an incurrent of neutrons with an angular distribution proportional to the cosine of the angle between the normal to the surface and the direction of neutron travel. Tables and figures are given to illustrate the accuracy of the “method for cylinders with radii up to four mean free paths and which range from almost purely capturing to nearly purely scattering. The calculations are done with trial functions that are polynomials in the square of the distance from the cylinder axis with various number of terms, up to nine, included.</description><creator>McKay, Carlyle. D.</creator><contributor>Wallace, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>A variational solution of the one group neutron transport equation with isotropic scattering in long, homogeneous, circular cylinders.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311t044.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j333594r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82kc012</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T20:02:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It has been realized for many years that egg yolk is remarkable for its high content of phosphoprotein. However, considerable uncertainty has existed as to the number and nature of the proteins present in egg yolk. Most of the more recent studies have distinguished two lipoprotein fractions, which have been designated as 'lipovitellin' and 'lipovitellenin'; at one time lipovitellin was regarded as a phospholipophosphoprotein, but more recently it has been realized that the older lipovitellin preparations included a phosphoprotein of relatively very high (about 10%) phosphorus content.</description><creator>McCully, Keith. A.</creator><contributor>Common, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1962</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>Zone electrophoretic studies of the proteins of avian serum and egg yolk.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89db049.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82kc012</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agriculture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):16425</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>