<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:56:29Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43000" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x442q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>En raisonnement sur les systemes multi-agents, il est important de regarder  au-dela du domaine de la logique propositionnelle et de raisonner sur les con-  naissances des agents au sein du syst`eme, parce que ce qu'ils savent au sujet de  l'environnement influe sur la mani`ere dont ils se comportent. Un outil utile pour  l'analyse et la formalisation de ce que les agents savent, est la logique  epistemique,  une logique modale developpee par les philosophes du debut des annees 1960.  La logique  epistemique est la cle de la comprehension des connaissances dans les  systemes multi-agents, mais elle est insuffisante si l'on veut  etudier la facon dont  la connaissance des agents  evolue a travers le temps. Pour ce faire, il est necessaire  de recourir a une logique qui allie des modalites dynamiques et  epistemiques,  appele la logique  epistemique dynamique. Certaines formalisations de la logique  epistemique dynamique utilisent la semantique de Kripke pour les etats et les  actions, tandis que d'autres prennent une approche algebrique, et utilisent les  structures ordonne dans leur semantique. Nous discutons plusieurs de ces logiques,  mais nous nous concentrons principalement sur le cadre algebrique pour la logique  epistemique dynamique. Les approches adoptees dans le passe a la logique epistemique dynamique ont  generalement  ete axe sur les actions dont l'objectif principal est de communiquer  des informations d'un agent a un autre. Ces actions sont dans l'impossibilite de  modifier l' evaluation de toute proposition au sein du systeme. Dans des domaines  tels que la securite et l' economie, il est facile d'imaginer des situations dans  lesquelles ce type d'action serait insuffisante. Au lieu de cela, nous etendons le  cadre algebrique pour inclure a la fois des actions de communication et des actions  qui changent l' etat du systeme. En outre, nous proposons une nouvelle modalite  qui permet de capturer a la fois les changements  epistemiques et les changements  propositionels qui resultent de l'action des agents.</description><description>In reasoning about multi-agent systems, it is important to look beyond the  realm of propositional logic and to reason about the knowledge of agents within  the system, as what they know about the environment will affect how they behave.  A useful tool for formalizing and analyzing what agents know is epistemic logic,  a modal logic developed by philosophers in the early 1960s. Epistemic logic is  key to understanding knowledge in multi-agent systems, but insufficient if one  wishes to study how the agents' knowledge changes over time. To do this, it is  necessary to use a logic that combines dynamic and epistemic modalities, called  dynamic epistemic logic. Some formalizations of dynamic epistemic logic use  Kripke semantics for the states and actions, while others take a more algebraic  approach, and use order-theoretic structures in their semantics. We discuss several  of these logics, but focus predominantly on the algebraic framework for dynamic  epistemic logic. Past approaches to dynamic epistemic logic have typically been focused on  actions whose primary purpose is to communicate information from one agent  to another. These actions are unable to alter the valuation of any proposition  within the system. In fields such as security and economics, it is easy to imagine  situations in which this sort of action would be insufficient. Instead, we expand  the framework to include both communication actions and actions that change the  state of the system. Furthermore, we propose a new modality which captures both  epistemic and propositional changes that result from the agents' actions.</description><creator>Phillips, Caitlin</creator><contributor>Doina Precup (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Prakash Panangaden (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>An algebraic approach to dynamic epistemic logic</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pt21s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x442q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj236247h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dans ce mémoire, la conception de filtres de données-échantillonnées ayant une réponse impulsionnelle infinie basée sur le traitement de signal en mode temporel est présentée. Le traitement de signal dans le domaine temporel (TSDT), définie comme étant le traitement d'information analogique échantillonnée en utilisant des différences de temps comme variables, est devenu une des techniques émergentes de conception de circuits des plus populaires. Puisque le TSDT est toujours relativement récent, il y a encore beaucoup de développements requis pour étendre cette technologie comme un outil de traitement de signal général. Dans cette recherche, un ensemble de blocs d'assemblage capable de réaliser la plupart des opérations mathématiques dans le domaine temporel sera introduit. En arrangeant ces structures élémentaires, des systèmes en mode temporel d'ordre élevé, plus spécifiquement des filtres en mode temporel, seront réalisés. Trois filtres de deuxième ordre dans le domaine temporel (passe-bas, passe-bande et passe-haut) sont modélisés sur MATLAB et simulé sur Spectre afin de vérifier la méthodologie de conception. Finalement, un intégrateur amorti et un filtre passe-bas IIR de deuxième ordre en mode temporel sont implémentés avec des composantes discrètes.</description><description>In this work, the design of sampled-data infinite impulse response filters based on time-mode signal processing circuits is presented. Time-mode signal processing (TMSP), defined as the processing of sampled analog information using time-difference variables, has become one of the more popular emerging technologies in circuit design. As TMSP is still relatively new, there is still much development needed to extend the technology into a general signal-processing tool. In this work, a set of general building block will be introduced that perform the most basic mathematical operations in the time-mode. By arranging these basic structures, higher-order time-mode systems, specifically, time-mode filters, will be realized. Three second-order time-mode filters (low-pass, band-reject, high-pass) are modeled using MATLAB, and simulated in Spectre to verify the design methodology. Finally, a damped integrator and a second-order low-pass time-mode IIR filter are both implemented using discrete components.</description><creator>Guttman, Michael</creator><contributor>Gordon W Roberts (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Sampled-data IIR filtering via time-mode signal processing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bm11k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236247h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773w14d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ce document en deux volumes comprend une analyse (volume 1) de l'intégralité de la partition (volume 2) de Catching Air and the Superman, une composition pour seize musiciens, en un mouvement, d'environ quinze minutes. L'oeuvre fait intervenir à la fois des éléments électroniques, contrôlés par deux interfaces gestuelles, appelés t-sticks, et des instruments acoustiques. Au total, trois instruments électroniques peuvent être entendus dans cette pièce : un clavier MIDI et deux t-sticks sopranos. Les instruments acoustiques constituent un orchestre de chambre comprenant : une flûte (piccolo), un hautbois, une clarinette, deux saxophones, un ténor et un baryton, une trompette, un trombone, deux jeux de percussions, deux violons, un alto ainsi qu'un violoncelle. L'analyse qui suit débute par un historique de l'évolution de l'usage des technologies électroniques en composition pour arriver au contexte de ce projet spécifique. Les concepts et modèles intervenant dans Catching Air and the Superman sont présentés à la suite de cet historique. Le restant du volume 1 comprend une discussion détaillée des aspects suivants : structure et forme de la composition, espace spectrale et champ des hauteurs, traitement des objets sonores et travail motivique, rythmes, minutage et tempo.</description><description>This two-volume dissertation contains an analysis text (Volume 1) of the complete musical score for Catching Air and the Superman (Volume 2), which is an approximately fifteen-minute, one-movement composition for sixteen musicians. It features interactive electronics through an integration of gestural controllers, known as t-sticks, and acoustic instruments. In total, three digital instruments are heard in the work: MIDI keyboard and two soprano t-sticks. The acoustic instruments constitute a chamber orchestra: flute (piccolo), oboe, clarinet, tenor saxophone, baritone saxophone, trumpet, trombone, two percussion, two violins, viola and violoncello. The following analysis begins with a contextual examination of electronic music technology in relation to the compositional project. Next, the concepts and models of Catching Air and the Superman are outlined. The remainder of Volume 1 contains a detailed discussion pertaining to: compositional structure and form, spectral and pitch space, object and motif, rhythm, timing and tempo.</description><creator>Stewart, David</creator><contributor>John Rea (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Sean Alastair Ferguson (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Music</subject><title>Catching air and the Superman</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h239t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773w14d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w95050970</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A guinea pig model of dextran sulphate-induced colitis was developed to investigate nutritional strategies in improving gastrointestinal inflammation.  The present study aimed to determine if a diet rich in docosahexaenoic acid (DHA) improves clinical and physical symptoms of inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) and whether DHA alters inflammatory lipid mediator production, and subsequent systemic effects on the acute phase response (APR).  DHA improved symptoms of IBD, including; fecal blood, diarrhea, lethargy, survival, and dietary intake.  Feeding of DHA increased the percent of DHA in livers (1.2% vs 0.3%), tended to decrease inflammatory mediator production, but did not decrease intestinal damage or alter protein kinetics.  These results demonstrate that DHA improves clinical and physical symptoms associated with IBD, possibly involving decreased lipid mediator production.  The mechanism of action does not appear to involve a blunting of the APR nor decreases in intestinal damage.</description><description>Un modèle de cochon-dinde injecté de dextran sulfate colite a été développé pour investiguer les stratégies nutritionnelles afin d'amenuiser les symptômes d'inflammation gastro-intestinale (IBD). La présente étude visait à déterminer si une diète riche en acide docosahexaenoic (DHA) améliore les symptômes cliniques ainsi que physiques de la maladie inflammatoire de l'intestin, si le DHA altère la production de lipides inflammatoires médiateurs et, les effets systémiques subséquents sur la phase de réponse aigue (APR). Le DHA à amélioré les symptômes de l'IBD, incluant; sang fécal, diarrhée, léthargie, survie et l'apport diététique. L'apport de DHA à augmenté le pourcentage de DHA dans le foie (1.2% vs 0.3%), à tendu à diminuer la production de médiateur d'inflammation mais n'a pas diminué le dommage intestinal ou altéré la cinétique des protéines. Ces résultats démontrent que le DHA améliore les symptômes cliniques et physiques associés avec l'IBD, possiblement à travers la diminution la production de lipides médiateurs. La mécanique ne semble pas provoquer un émoussement de l'APR ou diminuer le dommage intestinal.</description><creator>Bradley, Tanya</creator><contributor>Linda J Wykes (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Nutrition</subject><title>The effect of docosahexaenoic acid on disease progression, inflammatory mediator production, and protein synthesis in guinea pigs with dextran sulphate-induced colitis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hc63m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95050970</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50gw661</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation examines two controversies involving paintings  of the female nude by artists Debora Arango and Carlos Correa during a period of  political crisis in Bogota (Colombia) in order to open the political to cultural  analysis and thus shed light on scenarios of change in the 1930s and 1940s.  Unpacking the controversies lends insight into the unique ways in which modernity,  the body, its representations, sexuality, gender and politics came together in  Colombia during this period. Such an approach also shows that modernity in Colombia  involved shifts in religious and secular frames of sense-making and morality. This  dissertation argues that the controversies and the female nudes provide a window  into the Liberal regime's creation of culture as an autonomous sphere as part of its  cultural program, which bridged high and popular culture, as well as on aspects of  private life concerned with sexuality and gender. It shows how such changes  registered in the lives of the artists and how the artists translated the changes  they experienced into modes of pictorial expression. This dissertation argues that  the demands of the aesthetic and the demands of politics during this period pressed  on each other, resulting in the wide-spread perception of moral breach that came to  a head in the "scandals of the female nudes." This dissertation thus sheds  light on dimensions of both the political and the private during this  period. Because art and politics were thus entangled, this dissertation  shows that, in this particular Colombian modernity, society was not polarized, that  the private and the private overlapped, that issues of intimacy surfaced in the  public realm, and that Catholicism was the idiom shared by men and women who were  grappling with change. It shows that the cultural program of the Liberal regime was  the immediate referent for criticism in these events and, through it, of the Liberal  regime's reforms of education of 1934 and 1936. Finally, it shows that this  modernity and its attendant anxieties were played out through the body in the public  and the private realms, within, not against, the Catholic tradition, in  unprecedented ways. This thesis demonstrates that politics and issues of sexuality  and gender were entangled in the public sphere and converged in the female nudes,  turning them into a major threat to morality within both religious and secular  frameworks. By unpacking the controversies, this dissertation marks a seminal break  with historical accounts that describe Colombia's as a failed modernity, its society  as polarized, and debates over sexuality and gender as the product of politics. This  dissertation also contradicts art historical writings that account for the  production of images and the reception of art in this period solely in political  terms.</description><creator>Suescun Pozas, María del Carmen</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Female nude in art -- Public opinion</subject><subject>Art, Colombian -- 20th century</subject><subject>Art and society -- Colombia -- 20th century</subject><subject>Arango Pérez, Débora</subject><subject>Christianity and art -- Colombia -- Catholic Church</subject><subject>Correa Carlos, 1910-1985</subject><title>Modern femininity, shattered masculinity : the scandal of the female nude during political crisis in Colombia, 1930-1948</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w6634412n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gw661</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20ss97p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Throughout history, two conceptions of happiness have been  advocated. The hedonic ideal, which often predominates in modern Western societies,  advocates enjoyment and avoidance of pain. The eudaimonic view argues that  fulfillment comes from personal growth and excellence. This research was among the  first empirical comparisons of eudaimonic and hedonic pursuits in terms of their  actual relationships with happiness. One study was conducted with a single questionnaire (117  participants) and a second used detailed experience-sampling (100 participants). In  the majority of analyses, hedonic activity was linked with greater positive affect  and lower negative affect than eudaimonic activity was, while eudaimonic activity  was associated with greater meaning in life and higher personal expressiveness  (i.e., authenticity, involvement, fulfillment, and feeling alive). These results  suggest that positive and negative affect (more emotional and visceral) could be  called hedonic well-being, while meaning and personal expressiveness (subtler,  require thought, and involve feeling more integrated and right than good) might be  called eudaimonic well-being. The findings also underline the limitations of  assessing only hedonic happiness, as is usually done---it can lead to inaccurate  conclusions about the benefits of eudaimonic pursuits. The results also suggested a trade-off in time between the  benefits of hedonic and eudaimonic activities. The links between hedonic activity  and well-being were strongest during the activity but often weakened with time. In  contrast, the links between eudaimonic activity and happiness were weakest during  the activity but became stronger with repeated eudaimonic efforts. People with  frequent eudaimonic interests were also happier during many activities, even hedonic  ones, than those with few eudaimonic projects; such increased enjoyment was not  experienced by people with frequent hedonic pursuits. These results are consistent  with theories that hedonic activities produce immediate satisfaction but that it  fades with time, whereas eudaimonic strivings are challenging but increase  well-being in the long run. Eudaimonic activities may promote well-being by building  personal capital, e.g., coping skills, improved life circumstances, and deeper  appreciation of life experiences. These findings suggest that the modern preoccupation with  enjoyment and comfort is an incomplete ideal. People probably need significant  eudaimonic pursuits to experience meaningful and lasting  fulfillment.</description><creator>Huta, Veronika</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Self-actualization (Psychology)</subject><subject>Hedonism.</subject><subject>Well-being</subject><title>Pursuing pleasure versus growth and excellence : links with different aspects of well-being</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fr800.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20ss97p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jk86x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation sets out to determine the social function of  paraenesis ("moral exhortation") within Valentinian Christianity. In order  to explicate this social function, this study places the discussion within the  context of ancient rhetorical practices of ethical admonition; i.e., how did  paraenetic discursive practices act as rhetorical devices for affecting social  formation? In order to establish the function of paraenesis, it is necessary to  engage both literary and social aspects of the paraenetic genre. The latter is most  challenging, given the methodological difficulties inherent in moving from textual  context to socio-historical reconstruction of the situation behind a text. To  address this problem, a method is adapted from sociology (interactionism) and social  psychology (positioning theory) in order to critically gauge the social idealization  of the sources. Special attention is given to the paraenetic contours of the Gospel  of Truth (NHC I,3) and the Interpretation of Knowledge (NHC XI,1). This dissertation is structured into five chapters. The first  chapter will frame the discussion within current developments in the study of  Gnosticism, where there has been a growing appreciation for social and ethical  aspects of the Nag Hammadi tractates. A delimitation of the source base for this  study will also be offered. Chapter 2 will offer a comprehensive overview of  scholarly discussions of paraenesis over the past century. A functional definition,  with an attendant typology of paraenetic material will be offered in closing.  Chapter 3 directly engages the literary aspects of paraenesis within Valentinianism,  placing the discussion within the context of moral exhortation in the Greco-Roman  world, and, more specifically, early Christianity. This chapter will establish the  presence of paraenesis within the Valentinian sources. Chapter 4 will then address  the social function of paraenesis in two examples of Valentinian paraenesis,  highlighting the rhetorical and discursive voice of each text. The final chapter  will summarize the findings of the dissertation and raise implications of this study  for the field of early Christian studies.</description><creator>Tite, Philip L., 1969-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Persuasion (Rhetoric) -- Moral and ethical aspects -- History.</subject><subject>Rhetoric, Ancient.</subject><subject>Valentinus, 2nd cent.</subject><subject>Christian ethics -- History -- Early church, ca. 30-600.</subject><subject>Valentinians.</subject><subject>Gnosticism.</subject><title>Valentinian ethics and paraenetic discourse : determining the social function of moral exhortation in Valentinian Christianity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s0634.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jk86x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x4430</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The misorientations between FCC and BCC crystals are  characterized according to the common lattice correspondence relationships in terms  of their parallelism conditions. Individual variants of the six models, namely the  Bain, Kurdjumov-Sachs, Nishiyama-Wassermann, Pitsch, Greninger-Troiano and inverse  Greninger-Troiano relations, are identified and represented in both pole figure form  and in Rodrigues-Frank space with respect to various coordinate frames. In this way,  the relations between the variants of these models are clarified. The orientations of the kamacite (BCC) lamellae transformed from  a single prior-taenite (FCC) grain in the Gibeon meteorite were measured by  analyzing the electron backscatter diffraction patterns. The local misorientations  between individual FCC and BCC crystals along their common interfaces were computed  and are compared with the common lattice correspondence relationships. The  orientation relations between the alpha and gamma phases in the plessite regions are  also characterized. The Neumann bands (mechanical twins) and their orientation  variations within individual kamacite lamellae were studied and  analyzed. A Nb-bearing TRIP steel was control rolled and a certain amount  of austenite was retained through appropriate heat treatment. EBSD measurements were  conducted on specimens deformed to various reductions and the textures (ODF's) of  both the gamma and alpha phases were obtained from the measured data points. The  orientations of the bainite formed within individual prior-austenite grains are  compared to those expected from the common correspondence relationships and the  average orientation of the prior-austenite grain. The crystallography of the bainite  laths within a single packet is also characterized. The orientations of the bainite formed from individual  prior-austenite grains are analyzed with respect to their parent orientations. The  occurrence of variant selection at the grain scale was examined using a  dislocation-based model. The model considers the role of the slip systems that were  active during prior deformation, as well as those of in-plane reaction, cross-slip  and the partial dislocations that are linked to specific variants. In this model,  the K-S and N-W correspondence relations are united through the dissociation of  perfect dislocations. The variants in more than 70% of the grains examined are  reasonably well predicted by this model.</description><creator>He, Youliang,</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><title>Grain-scale characterization of FCCBCC correspondence relations and variant selection</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vt81w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x4430</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8p58pd45j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines the birth of television and the modern media  corporation that launched it, through the archives of the designer of the  "first" set, John Vassos, a Greek-born American industrial designer,  interior decorator, and illustrator (1898-1985). Vassos's early career is used as a  case study to analyze the historical and cultural forces that shaped the emergence  of this new media and the new profession of industrial design, through archival  materials housed in the Archives of American Art at the Smithsonian Institution in  Washington D.C. and at Syracuse University. Specifically, this thesis unites various  parts of Vassos's early career, from his modernist illustrations to industrial  design, through the aesthetics and practices of modernism. As RCA's lead industrial  designer for over 40 years, Vassos was involved in the design and promotion of RCA's  electronic products, including radios and televisions and studio equipment. Vassos  also designed the new spaces carved out for their use in the home including the  "living room of the future" featured at the 1939 World's Fair. Drawing  from his skills as an illustrator, designer and display expert, Vassos helped  develop RCA's public image at a time of its greatest expansion in radio and  television manufacturing and broadcasting. This reading of Vassos's work is both  diachronic, taking into account his work over the early part of his career to  analyze his specific contribution and synchronic, in relationship to other designers  working contemporaneously. Thus, this thesis explores Vassos's double role as a  participant, with active agency within the emergence of the new field and as a  subject, constrained by social roles and forces. Ranging from turnstile to the  transmitter, Vassos along with other industrial designers used the streamlined  aesthetic to create visual unity among mechanical and electronic products, from home  to office, from subway to skyline.</description><creator>Schwartz, Danielle</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Vassos, John, 1898-1985</subject><subject>Design, Industrial -- United States -- History -- 20th century.</subject><subject>Radio Corporation of America -- History</subject><subject>Television -- Receivers and reception -- History.</subject><title>From turnstile to transmitter : John Vassos, industrial designer, 1927-1941</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zb527.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pd45j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354f719</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This doctoral dissertation, as part of a large and ongoing  CIHR-funded study, used a subset of the total sample to evaluate the contribution of  interactive health communication (IHC) as a complement to more traditional means of  informational support (Care-as-usual) to optimal adjustment of women newly diagnosed  with breast cancer (N = 135). According to the study protocol, participants in the  experimental group received an IHC educational intervention for an eight-week  period. Measures of psychosocial adjustment and information-related variables were  administered in interviews at Time 1 (pre-intervention) within 8 weeks of initial  diagnosis, and again 8 weeks post-intervention (Time 2). Psychosocial adjustment  variables included: depressive symptoms (CESD), anxiety (STAI-Y), well-being (IWB),  and quality of life (SF-36)-mental and physical health components.  Information-related variables included: the need for information related to cancer,  cancer-specialist, and family or friend's informational support, and overall  satisfaction with information. Optimism and Constructed meaning were evaluated at  Time 1 and 2, respectively. A GLM MANCOVA model tested overall F-ratios and  regression coefficients using difference scores. Predictors in the model were: group  (experimental versus control), constructed meaning, and optimism. The overall model  (df = 8, 121) was significant for Group, F = 3.66, p &lt; .001, effect size eta2  = .20, Constructed Meaning, F = 3.04, p &lt; .004, effect size eta2 = .17, and  Optimism, F = 2.95, p &lt; .005, effect size eta2 = .16. Participants in the  dissertation experimental group had significant improvements in QOL-physical health  and overall satisfaction with information when compared with the control group.  Constructed meaning was significantly associated with beneficial changes in all of  the adjustment-related variables. The results of this dissertation clarify the  potentially significant roles IHC and constructed meaning pl</description><creator>Radcliffe-Branch, Deborah S.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Cancer -- Patients -- Counseling of.</subject><subject>Breast -- Cancer -- Psychological aspects.</subject><title>The contribution of interactive health communication (IHC) and constructed meaning to psychosocial adjustment among women newly diagnosed with breast cancer /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042t566.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354f719</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cr56n1605</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The epididymis functions in the transport, maturation, storage  and protection of spermatozoa. The structure and functions of the epididymis are  dependent on androgens, primarily dihydrotestosterone (DHT). 5a-Reductases (types 1  and 2) are thus key enzymes in this tissue because of their role in converting  testosterone to DHT. The goal of this thesis was to examine the consequences on the  rat epididymis and epididymal sperm of inhibiting DHT formation using novel dual  5alpha-reductase inhibitors (i.e. inhibitors specific to both isoforms of  5alpha-reductase). The first objective was to analyze the effects of  5alpha-reductase inhibitor treatment on gene expression in the four epididymal  segments (initial segment, caput, corpus and cauda epididymidis) using cDNA arrays.  Treatment had highly segment specific effects on epididymal gene expression.  Affected genes included those involved in fatty acid and lipid metabolism,  regulation of ion and fluid transport, luminal acidification, oxidative defense and  protein processing and degradation; these are essential processes contributing to  the formation of an optimal luminal microenvironment required for proper sperm  maturation. The next objective was to determine whether the observed changes in gene  expression actually translated into effects on epididymal sperm functions. Fertility  and several key facets of epididymal sperm maturation were analyzed. The percentages  of motile and progressively motile sperm from the cauda epididymidis decreased and  characteristic sperm motion parameters were altered. An elevated proportion of sperm  from this region also retained their cytoplasmic droplet. Matings with treated males  resulted in fewer successful pregnancies and a higher rate of preimplantation loss.  Lastly, cDNA arrays and quantitative real-time RT-PCR were used to elucidate  potential signaling mechanisms via which DHT mediates and/or regulates its  differential effects on epididymal gene expression and</description><creator>Henderson, Natali Anne</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>The consequences on the rat epididymis of inhibiting 5-alpha-reductase /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jv09d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n1605</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fk98z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The neurotrophin family of proteins regulates a wide variety of  functions in neurons, including regulation of neuronal survival, axonal and  dendritic growth and synaptic plasticity. The regulation of neurotrophin trafficking  is believed to be important in many aspects of their function, as exemplified by the  role of BDNF, which is released in response to activity, in long-term potentiation  in the hippocampus and the ability of neurotrophins to initiate a retrograde  pro-survival signal along peripheral axons. In this thesis I describe three  mechanisms by which neurotrophin trafficking occurs differently for different  members, or forms, of the neurotrophin family. Firstly, I show that two  neurotrophins, BDNF and NT-4, which signal through the same receptors, can be  released from cells containing both constitutive and regulated secretory pathways  through different mechanisms. NT-4 is released continuously, soon after its  synthesis, from AtT-20 cells, while BDNF is stored within the cells and released in  response to depolarisation. Secondly, I show that, in primary sympathetic neurons,  the functionally antagonistic Trk and p75NTR receptors, in complexes with their  respective neurotrophin ligands, are differently localized on the cell surface and  are internalized with different characteristics. This contradicts a model in which  the antagonism between these receptors is mediated directly and instead suggests an  indirect mechanism of antagonism. In addition, I show that the p75NTR-ligand complex  can be retrogradely transported at a similar rate to that reported for Trk, but that  the initiation of this transport occurs through a different mechanism. Finally, I  show that the neurotrophin precursor, pro-BDNF, can be released endogenously from  glial cells, consistent with its postulated role as a high affinity ligand for a  p75NTR-containing signalling complex. When over-expressed in cell lines, pro-BDNF  release is activity-independent, in contrast to</description><creator>Hibbert, Andrew Paul</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Spatial and temporal differences between the trafficking of members of the neurotrophin family of proteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w5209.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fk98z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483j819</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is concerned with asynchronous circuit design and  verification. Specifically, we will focus on new methods of modeling the control of  data transmission between submodules in asynchronous systems. Our methods of modeling will be applied to asynchronous circuit  synthesis; the methods will also be applied to interface recasting, by which we mean  transforming the communication protocol of a module interface while preserving its  functional behavior. Therefore, a circuit that uses one protocol for communication  at its interface can be recast to another circuit that uses a different protocol at  its interface while preserving the functional behavior of the original circuit.  Furthermore, our methods would permit a single module to use several different  protocols at its interfaces. By applying our methods, an additional degree of  flexibility will be offered to designers in asynchronous data transmission design:  namely, the choice of protocols for synchronizing circuit components without  affecting the functional behavior of such components. This thesis introduces the formal definitions of semi-hiding and  converse semi-hiding operators, along with a study of the algebraic properties of  these operators. First-cut algorithms for semihiding and converse semi-hiding  operations have been implemented in FIREMAPS. Using these operators, specifications  of circuit modules could be analyzed in the active-edge domain with less complexity  and mapped to transition-level specifications if necessary.</description><creator>Kong, Xiaohua, 1974-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Protocol modeling and recasting for handshaking circuits</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w038j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483j819</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w9505102n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this dissertation I explain the transition from modernism to  postmodernism through the study of the French existentialist novel. I follow  theories that demonstrate that the latter owes its success to historiographic  metafiction. By setting off the aporias that deeply penetrate modern novels, I  demonstrate the obsolescence of the prototype of the realist novel and I explain the  impasses towards which the project of a committed literature lead, inscribed in the  line of realism and aimed at an almost direct relation with society and history  through the mediation of art between 1945 and 1955 in France. On one hand I consider literature as an object which can be  described by the methodologies of history. On the other hand I suggest an analysis  of the historicity of the text that is constituted by the dynamic system generated  by the interaction, the interdependence, and the correlation of the poetic and  aesthetic parameters and the factors of the historical context. My aim is to set off  the poetic and aesthetic mecanism of stability and of transformation of literary  creation according to the dynamic relation between the vector of the project  associated to realism and the one of the prototype associated to the novel. I think  that late modernism produces paradoxical configurations of the novel because it is  the period in which the project of realism becomes lapsed and the prototype of the  realist novel becomes dilapidated. Among the works that are exemplary of the tension between  fiction and history and between project and prototype in the framework of the  representation of reality and of the inscription of history in novels, I identified  Albert Camus' La Peste, Simone de Beauvoir's Les Mandarins and Jean-Paul Sartre's  Les Chemins de la liberte . I conclude that the enterprise of committed literature  was an aporias because it was generated from the impoverishment of the project of  realism and the obsolescence of the prototype of the novel. Later literature was  extricated, firstly, by the radically and extremely metafictional writing of the  Nouveau Roman and, secondly, it was changed by postmodern historiographic  metafiction. The crisis of history and of the writing of history was solved by works  in which there is the acknowledgement and the use of sophisticated mediations to  evoke and inscribe history in different ways.</description><creator>Calderón, Jorge</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Literature and history.</subject><subject>Existentialism in literature.</subject><subject>Beauvoir, Simone de, 1908-1986 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Sartre, Jean-Paul, 1905-1980 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>Camus, Albert, 1913-1960 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>French literature -- 20th century -- History and criticism.</subject><title>Configurations aporétiques, fiction de l'histoire et historicité de la fiction : Simone de Beauvoir, Albert Camus et Jean-Paul Sartre</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53ww31p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w9505102n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bc01z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The impact of agricultural practices on wood turtle (Glyptemys  insculpta) movements and survivorship was investigated in a fragmented agri-forest  landscape over two years. Agricultural activities and machinery contributed to the  death of 20% of radio-tracked turtles. Annual survivorship of adults was 0.904 and  0.868 and for juveniles it was 0.815 and 0.831 for 1998 and 1999, respectively.  Mutilation rates in adults were 90% +/- 3% in both years; in contrast, the maximum  rate in juveniles was 57%. Setting the cutting height of disc mowers to 100 mm would  increase harvest yields, reduce wear on machinery, decrease soil erosion, and reduce  turtle mortality and mutilation rates. The concepts of integral, statistical, and  linear range are introduced as distinct estimators of turtle movements. Since  integral ranges include all habitats critical to survival, they provide an important  contribution to our knowledge of imperiled species. Statistical ranges are stable  and easily promote within and between study comparisons. Linear ranges quantify  migratory and ranging movements. Thread-trailing techniques were used to record the  fine-scale movements of six adult male G. insculpta translocated to an experimental  hayfield patch-matrix. Although patch size had no effect on move length or path  sinuosity, habitat structure did. Paths were generally straighter and move length  longer in the harvested portion of a hayfield. Apparent habitat boundaries were  shown to be permeable. Subjects exhibit three movement phases: agitation dispersal,  local search, and ranging. Thus, G. insculpta exhibit predetermined movement  patterns and move to maximize the likelihood of locating resources, while minimizing  the probability of revisiting previously searched areas. Recent changes in  agricultural practices and machinery are having a decidedly negative impact on G.  insculpta. This study provides new insights into the movements of G. insculpta. Such  knowledge will be an es</description><creator>Saumure, Raymond A.</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Wood turtle -- Ecology -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Wood turtle -- Dispersal -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Wood turtle -- Conservation -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>Spatial ecology and conservation of the North American wood turtle (Glyptemys insculpta) in a fragmented agri-forest landscape</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n386f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bc01z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343s68c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Many complex systems are hybrid in the sense that: (i) the state  set possesses continuous and discrete components, and (ii) system evolution may  occur in both continuous and discrete time. One important class of hybrid systems is  that characterized by a feedback configuration of a set of continuous controlled low  level systems and a high level discrete controller; such systems appear frequently  in engineering and are particularly evident when a system is required to operate in  a number of distinct modes. Other classes of hybrid systems are found in such  diverse areas as (i) air traffic management systems, (ii) chemical process control,  (iii) automotive engine-transmission systems, and (iv) intelligent vehicle-highway  systems. In this thesis we first formulate a class of hybrid optimal  control problems (HOCPs) for systems with controlled and autonomous location  transitions and then present necessary conditions for hybrid system trajectory  optimality. These necessary conditions constitute generalizations of the standard  Minimum Principle (MP) and are presented for the cases of open bounded control value  sets and compact control value sets. These conditions give information about the  behaviour of the Hamiltonian and the adjoint process at both autonomous and  controlled switching times. Such proofs of the necessary conditions for hybrid systems  optimality which can be found in the literature are sufficiently complex that they  are difficult to verify and use; in contrast, the formulation of the HOCP given in  Chapter 2 of this thesis, together with the use of (i) classical variational methods  and more recent needle variation techniques, and (ii) a local controllability  condition, called the small time tubular fountain (STTF) condition, make the proofs  in that chapter comparatively accessible. We note that the STTF condition is used to  establish the adjoint and Hamiltonian jump conditions in the autonomous switchings  case. A hybrid Dynamic Programming Principle (HDPP) generalizing the  standard dynamic programming principle to hybrid systems is also derived and this  leads to hybrid Hamilton-Jacobi-Bellman (HJB) equation which is then used to  establish a verification theorem within this framework. (Abstract shortened by  UMI.)</description><creator>Shaikh, Mohammad Shahid</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Optimal control of hybrid systems : theory and algorithms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55mc51k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343s68c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53jx52s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tributyltin compounds have been used on a global scale for many  decades now, and thus have become global environmental contaminants. These compounds  are highly toxic, and deleterious effects on numerous organisms have been  demonstrated. Yet, little is known of the molecular mechanisms of tributyltin's  extreme toxicity. To obtain a better understanding of such mechanisms, a luxAB  gene-fusion library of Escherichia coli was screened for changes in gene expression  upon cellular exposure to tributyltin. Two clones, designated TBT1 and TBT3, were  thus found, both showing an increased light emission in the presence of added  tributyltin. Northern blotting analyses confirmed a marked increase in the  transcription of the tributyltin-responsive gene identified from each clone. These  genes appear to play a protective role when cells are exposed to tributyltin at  concentrations &amp;gE; 10 mug/ml, with minimal-dose responses of 0.1 mug/l when  grown on LB media. Speciation studies indicated TBT+ as the active chemical species  in eliciting these responses. Mapping and sequencing of these tributyltin-responsive  genes revealed that the luxAB reporter element had inserted within the uhpT gene in  the TBT1 clone. This gene encodes a sugar-phosphate transporter protein, which has  been shown to be up-regulated by external glucose-6-phosphate and  2-deoxyglucose-6-phosphate. On a kinetic level, the increased expression of uhpT by  tributyltin closely mirrors that produced by 2-deoxyglucose-6-phosphate. In addition  to tributyltin, TBT1 also responds to dibutyltin, monobutyltin, trimethyltin,  triethyltin, tripropyltin, trifluoroacetic acid, and vanadium. Similar mapping and  sequencing experiments revealed the luxAB reporter genes within the stpA gene in the  TBT3 clone, but in an antisense orientation, such that they were not under the  regulatory control of stpA. The lack of an appropriate open reading frame for this  140-nucleotide transcript (identified by Northern blo</description><creator>Briscoe, Scott F.</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Toxicology.</subject><title>Tributyltin : molecular approaches to an environmental problem</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nk987.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53jx52s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mj46x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sex differences have been established in a number of behaviours,  including aspects of cognition, aggression, and sexuality. Although there has been a  considerable amount of research concerning the influence of estrogen on sexually  dimorphic behaviours, there has been a dearth of investigations on the role of  testosterone (T) in these behaviours in women. The studies presented here were  undertaken to elucidate the role of T in sexually-dimorphic aspects of psychological  functioning in women. In Study 1, users and non-users of oral contraceptives were  tested with a battery of neuropsychological tests and questionnaires at two  different phases of the menstrual cycle. Results showed that women with chronic low  levels of free T induced by oral contraceptives demonstrated better verbal fluency  and visuospatial memory performance and reported lower levels of verbal aggression  than naturally-cycling women whose free T levels were within the normal female  range. Furthermore, although self-ratings of hostility fluctuated across test  sessions concomitant with changes in free T levels, performance on cognitive tests  did not appear to be influenced by the fluctuations in T levels across the menstrual  cycle. In Study 2, women with elevated free T levels due to polycystic ovary  syndrome (PCOS) demonstrated worse verbal fluency, verbal memory, manual dexterity,  and visuospatial working memory performance, but reported higher levels of anger  than healthy, matched control women. Women with PCOS also reported lower levels of  sexual cognition and arousal than healthy controls. In Study 3, women with PCOS were  randomly assigned to receive 3 months of treatment with an anti-androgen or placebo.  Anti-androgen treatment resulted in significant reductions in free T levels and in  improvements in verbal fluency performance. Taken together, the results of these  three studies suggest that T has a detrimental effect on aspects of cognitive  functioning in women, particu</description><creator>Schattman, Linda</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Stein-Leventhal syndrome.</subject><subject>Women -- Psychology.</subject><subject>Testosterone.</subject><title>The role of testosterone in aspects of cognition, aggression, and sexual functioning in women with polycystic ovary syndrome and in healthy young women /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021f69s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mj46x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65v838h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The British colonial administration in India transformed Muslim  law in the nineteenth century through the three concurrent processes of translation,  legislation, and adjudication. Although Indian Muslims were gradually displaced in  their traditional position as interpreters of that law in the role of muftis,  discerning and applying the shari'ah according to Hanafi principles of fiqh, they  nonetheless played a vital role in the transformation of Muslim law. Towards the end  of the nineteenth century, Muslim participation became more noticeable and  significant as they moved into increasingly influential positions in the British  judicial administration. Syed Mahmood (1850-1903) was a pioneer in this movement,  being one of the first Indian Muslims to study law and become a barrister in  England, being the first non-European member of the Allahabad Bar, and being the  first Indian Muslim appointed to any High Court in British India. During his tenure  as judge of the High Court at Allahabad, he wrote numerous judgments on matters of  civil law, including matters which the British regime had determined were to be  governed by Muslim law, or rather, by the amalgam of Muslim and English law called  "Anglo-Mohammedan law" into which it had been transformed. He understood  certain aspects Muslim law, especially criminal law and laws of evidence, to have  been abrogated by British law in India, but stoutly resisted the incursion of  English law and promoted the acceptance of Muslim law as the customary law in other  areas. His critique of the British administration of justice in India and his  persistent independence of thought while serving on the High Court brought him into  conflict with his fellow judges. He was eventually forced to resign in 1892, but his  recorded judgments in the Indian Law Reports continued to provide an authoritative  exposition of Muslim law for succeeding generations of jurists. In addition to  elucidating the transformation of Muslim law</description><creator>Guenther, Alan M.</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Islamic law -- India</subject><subject>India -- History -- British occupation, 1765-1947</subject><subject>Mahmood, Syed</subject><title>Syed Mahmood and the transformation of Muslim law in British India</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306sz73m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65v838h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j333270j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>My dissertation is focused on a cycle of Saraha's Adamantine  Songs and their relationship to the Great Seal. Belonging to a genre known as  'Adamantine Songs'---Vajra Giti in Sanskrit, or rDo rje 'i gLu in Tibetan---their  titles are: "A Body Treasury called the Immortal Adamantine Song"; "A  Speech Treasury called the Manjughosa Adamantine Song" and "A Mind  Treasury called the Unborn Adamantine Song". The dissertation is divided into  two parts: the first is the contextualization of a Great Seal (Sanskrit: mahamudra;  Tibetan: phyag rgya chenpo) root text by the adept Saraha; and the second is a  critical edition of the Tibetan text along with the first full translation of the  text into English. The critical edition of the Tibetan is based on versions of the  poems drawn from five different Tibetan sources---four scriptural (the sDe dge, Co  ne, sNar thang and 'Peking' bsTan 'gyurs) and one literary (Mipham Rinpoche's 19th  century collection 'phags yul grub dbang dam pa rnams kyi zab mo'i do ha rnams las  kho la byung mu tig phreng ba or "Pearl Garland of the Profound Dohas of the  Noble Great Siddhas of India"). The first chapters of the dissertation explore the contexts of  this song cycle, its author and traditions that relate to it, in particular the  Karma Kagyu (karma bka' brgyud) school of Tibetan Buddhism. The first chapter is a  discussion of the author, Saraha, the tales of whose many 'lives' pervade Tibetan  Buddhist traditions to this day. Chapter 2 explores the broader context of South  Asian siddha traditions, while Chapters 3 and 4 provide an analysis of the Great  Seal both as it emerges through Saraba's work and as it exists as a living tradition  in the Tibetan Buddhist context. As mentioned above, particular emphasis is given to  the Karma Kagyu school. Finally, Chapter 5 provides an introduction to Tibetan  poetics and the Sanskrit traditions that influence it.</description><creator>Braitstein, Lara, 1971-</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Mahāmudrā (Tantric rite)</subject><subject>Sarahapāda, 8th cent.</subject><subject>Spiritual life -- Buddhism.</subject><title>Saraha's Adamantine Songs : texts, contexts, translations and traditions of the Great Seal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bm15p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j333270j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247ds630</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There is an ongoing debate as to the role of women in Israel's  army and to the degree of integration of women into male-dominated military  positions. Using qualitative methods (in-depth interviews and participant  observation), this dissertation examines the participation of women in the Israeli  Defence Forces with a focus on organizational belonging and military  status. Women soldiers find distinct ways of experiencing organizational  belonging and gaining status in the army. Much of women's variation in  organizational belonging is linked, not to positions held, but, rather, to the kind  of base at which a woman served during her service. Those serving in closed bases  (at which soldiers stay to sleep), report developing a greater sense of  organizational belonging than those serving in open bases (at which soldiers return  home to sleep). This distinction is linked to notions of combat. Those serving at  closed bases are more likely to serve in close proximity to combat. As well, closed  bases are associated with combat more than are open bases regardless of the nature  of individual closed bases. Thus, women serving on closed bases benefit from the  prestige associated with combat positions as well as from the organizationally  bonding experience of staying to sleep on the base. This stands in contrast with  women serving on open bases who are more likely to have their sense of  organizational belonging affected by their actual army position and rank and tend to  seek status through association with higher ranking soldiers such as their officers  and commanders. There has been a great deal of literary discourse concerning  women's participation in the IDF concentrating on women's military positions and  ranks. While my research relates to this discourse, it differs through its emphasis  on base placement over army position/rank. My study concludes with a discussion of  my contribution to organizational belonging literature and with reflections on the  implications of my findings for both the IDF and Jewish women in  Israel.</description><creator>Hauser, Orlee</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Women soldiers -- Israel</subject><subject>Israel -- Armed Forces -- Women</subject><title>Doing army feeling army : women and organizational belonging in the Israeli Defence Forces</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f634t.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247ds630</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mm747</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents the design and validation of a method for  digitally reconstructing white matter fibre tracts in vivo using magnetic resonance  imaging (MRI). The technique uses diffusion weighted MRI to estimate a likelihood  distribution function for the fibre direction(s) in each imaging voxel, and  subsequently infers connectivity from any point in the central nervous system to  another. The fibre tracking algorithm addresses issues that can confound fibre tract  reconstruction, such as imaging noise, subvoxel partial volume averaging of fibre  directions, and problems with the estimate of the diffusion probability density  function (pdf). It can take as input a diffusion pdf estimated using either the  traditional diffusion tensor approach or more recent high angular resolution  diffusion approaches. The fibre tracking technique is validated using in vivo human  brain diffusion imaging data and using a phantom constructed from excised rat spinal  cord, which provides a "gold standard" connectivity map. The results are  promising, especially for regions of the brain where tracking using previously  described algorithms has been difficult to perform, for example, the regions of  complex fibre structure near the cortex. As the cortex is critical for functional  activity in the brain, this may have widespread implications for our understanding  of the human brain in healthy subjects and in disease.</description><creator>Campbell, Jennifer S. W.</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Diffusion imaging of white matter fibre tracts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dg20f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mm747</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9c67wn36f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The evaluation of human de novo T cell production is critical  for a better understanding of T cell homeostasis and the immune reconstitution  processes. The presence of a functional thymus post-puberty has been unsuspected due  to the paucity of tools. This thesis provides direct evidence for a functional  thymus, which can contribute to the diversity of the immune reconstitution in  pathological situations where the immune system is severely destroyed. Through  peripheral blood PCR-based quantification of TCR alpha and beta rearrangement  excision/deletion circles (TREC), by-products of gene rearrangement events, we  demonstrated that a diversified de novo T cell production occurs throughout life,  even though thymic function decreases with age. De novo T cell production remains  intact following allogenic hematopoietic stem cell transplantation (AHSCT) in the  absence of graft-versus-host disease (GVHD) and therefore a reduced thymus function  cannot be responsible for the long-lasting reduction in peripheral blood naive T  cells observed in transplanted patients. As naive T cells from AHSCT patients have  reduced levels of IL-7Ralpha chain (CD 127) expression, we propose that their low  frequencies reflect an impaired naive T cell survival rather than thymic dysfunction  as signaling through CD127 was previously reported to upregulate Bcl-2 expression.  Evidence gathered in this thesis supports the concept that such naive T cells try to  replenish themselves through enhanced levels of proliferation but fail to do so and  likely die in the process. Monitoring of the peripheral alpha and beta TREC ratio, a marker  of intrathymic proliferation, demonstrated that HIV infection either induces the  cellular depletion or inhibits the cell cycling of differentiating thymocytes. As  intrathymic proliferation is important for both the magnitude and diversity of  thymic function, the results of this thesis indicate that the replenishment of the  naive T cell peripheral compartment through de novo T cell production is both  quantitatively and qualitatively limited in HIV-infected individuals leading to the  contraction of the peripheral T cell repertoire. Although peripheral blood quantification of alpha and beta TREC  can estimate peripheral blood RTE frequencies, reflective of thymopoiesis levels, it  does not constitute a method that can lead to the characterization of this important  T cell subset. To better understand the biology of RTEs, we engineered a transgene  with restricted GFP expression in T cell that recently rearranged their TCR. This  model would be very useful for the identification of molecules capable of modulating  thymic function as well as serving as a source for obtaining a highly purified  population of RTEs, then allowing the characterization of their gene expression  profile. Taken together, this thesis demonstrates the contribution of the  adult thymus to immune reconstitution following AHSCT and during HIV  infection.</description><creator>Poulin, Jean-François, 1974-</creator><contributor>Sekaly, Rafick-Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Quantitative and qualitative analysis of human de novo T cell production using T cell receptor alpha and beta excision circles</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021f723.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wn36f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:765371727</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Escherichia coli (E. coli) and Staphylococcus aureus (S. aureus)  are the most prevalent pathogens to induce mastitis. The pathogenesis of infections  induced by E. coli is sophisticatedly modulated by lipopolysaccharide (LPS), LPS  binding protein, membrane CD14 (mCD14), and soluble CD14 (sCD14). In the first  study, administration of recombinant bovine sCD14 (rbosCDl4) significantly reduced  the fatality of LPS challenged mice and the severity of mouse mastitis in terms of  clinical signs, bacterial load, and TNF-alpha production. Before investigating the  potential of this strategy in dairy cows, endogenous sCD14 in milk was  characterized. Based on the data of 396 quarters, the milk concentration of sCD14  was 6.67 +/- 0.44 mug/ml. The stages of lactation affected the concentration of  sCD14 in milk, which was higher in transitional milk (0--4 days postpartum). Milk  sCD14 also increased during an intramammary LPS challenge, which paralleled with SCC  increase. The protective effect of sCD14 on bovine E. coli mastitis was then  investigated. It was shown that rbosCDl4 sensitized the mammary gland to recruit  leukocytes in response to LPS. To prove that the early recruitment of leukocytes  plays a role in preventing intramammary E. coli infections, E. coli mastitis was  induced in 9 dairy cows with or without 100 mug rbosCD14. Quarters challenged with  E. coli plus rbosCD14 had a more rapid recruitment of neutrophils, a faster  clearance of bacteria, reduced concentrations of TNF-alpha and IL-8 in milk, and  reduced clinical symptoms than quarters injected with saline. For S. aureus mastitis, a newly designed trivalent whole-cell  vaccine being composed of the most dominant serotypes (T5, T8, and T336) was  evaluated. The vaccine was immunized with or without either one of the two  adjuvants, aluminum hydroxide (ALUM) and Freund's incomplete adjuvant (FICA). The  vaccine, with or without the presence of adjuvants, increased antigen-specific IgG1,  IgG2, but not IgM, in serum. However, all formulations only had limited effects on  lymphocyte subsets, interferon (IFN)-gamma mRNA expression, and neutrophil  phagocytosis in comparison with the control. Taken together, the results indicated that increasing the  concentration of sCD14 in milk might be a potential strategy to prevent or reduce  severity of E. coli mastitis. On the other hand, both ALUM and FICA did not augment  the immune responses when formulated with trivalent vaccine. A more  immunostimulatory adjuvant will be required to improve the efficacy of the novel  trivalent vaccine against S. aureus mastitis.</description><creator>Lee, Jai-Wei, 1970-</creator><contributor>Zhao, Xin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Mastitis -- Prevention.</subject><subject>Staphylococcus aureus.</subject><subject>Antigens, CD14.</subject><subject>Escherichia coli.</subject><subject>CD antigens.</subject><subject>Mastitis -- Vaccination.</subject><title>Application of soluble CD14 and a trivalent vaccine to prevent mastitis caused by Escherichia coli and Staphylococcus aureus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h248s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/765371727</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd375w805</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:20:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation explores the significance of law and religion  to the Scottish Revolution through the career of Archibald Johnston of Wariston. As  a lawyer committed to the defense of Scottish Presbyterianism against the  Anglicanism of Charles I, Wariston epitomized the legal and religious objectives of  the Revolution. While his importance to the Revolution is marked in the  historiography, Wariston has received little specialized study. This work draws on  manuscript collections from Edinburgh University Library, the National Archives of  Scotland and the National Library of Scotland to reconstruct his vision of the  Scottish constitution. As the most intimate source of his religious life, his diary  is explored in a social and political context to construct a composite view of his  private piety and his public policy. Wariston joined visceral opposition to innovations in religious  worship imposed by Charles I. He rose in prominence because his legal expertise was  indispensable to a Revolution predicated on a constitutional challenge of the  authority of the Crown. The Revolution was a nationalist revolt against an alleged  English imperialism. Wariston's religious experience in the Revolution revealed that  the Church was the touchstone for a revival of national consciousness of Scottish  laws, courts, customs and history. Wariston participated in the rediscovery and  reinterpretation of Scottish law to undo decades of Anglicized Crown reform in  Church and State. When war began in 1639 Wariston became central to intelligence  gathering and the forging of a loose alliance with English opponents of Charles I.  This intelligence network informed Scottish propaganda to England and proved  decisive in turning English popular opinion against the King. In 1640 Charles was  forced to abandon war and enter into the negotiations which led to the London Treaty  of 1641. Wariston pursued two main objectives---Scottish independence and permanent  institutions of Anglo-Scottish cooperation---to ensure Scottish influence in English  policy. While the latter initiatives were deferred in the Treaty, the Revolution  achieved independence and the preservation of Scottish Presbyterianism. This study  finds that ideas of religion and law in the Revolution were shaped by the  overarching imperative of independence and a renewed Scottish  nationalism.</description><creator>Cookson, Robert J.</creator><contributor>Maxwell, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Warriston, Archibald Johnston, Lord, 1611-1663</subject><subject>Scotland -- History -- Charles I, 1625-1649</subject><subject>National Covenant (1638)</subject><title>Archibald Johnston of Wariston, religion and law in the Covenanting revolution, 1637-1641</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881m46z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375w805</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43025</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>