<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:20:29Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):7850" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3484zk43w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:53:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Singing transcription refers to the automatic conversion of a recorded singing signal into a sequence of notes parameterized by onset time, offset time, and fundamental frequency, by applying signal processing method. Automatic singing transcription is an important topic in the field of music information retrieval as it enables the computers to extract the information carried by singing and facilitates the direct musical interaction between humans and computers.This thesis studies the use of feature selection in machine learning-based singing transcription systems, as none of such systems has hitherto taken full advantage of it. Feature selection is a machine learning technique that selects a subset of features that characterize specific aspects of an audio signal (such as fundamental frequency, harmonicity, and spectral shape), and it has been found to improve the performance of machine learning systems in general and various music information retrieval systems in particular.This thesis first presents an overview of machine learning in music applications, concerning the audio features, the feature selection, the genetic algorithms (GAs), and the hidden Markov models (HMMs). This thesis then surveys the approaches for melody transcription, a broader topic that contains the singing transcription. Finally, this thesis builds an HMM-based singing transcription system, evaluates the performance of different feature selection methods, and compares it with the performance of other recent singing transcription systems. The result shows that the GA-based feature selection had the best improvement in F-measures of correctness rate (up to 12.70%) and suggests that feature selection is effective for improving recalls and F measures of machine learning-based singing transcription systems using HMMs.</description><description>« La transcription de mélodies chantées » se réfère à la conversion automatique d'un signal de chant enregistrée à une séquence de notes paramétrées par l'instant de début, l'instant de fin et la fréquence fondamentale par l'application de méthode de traitement du signal. La transcription automatique de mélodies chantées est un sujet important dans le domaine de la recherche d'information en musique, car elle permet aux ordinateurs d'extraire l'information portée par le chant et facilite l'interaction musicale directe entre les humains et les ordinateurs.Cette thèse étudie l'utilisation de la sélection d'attributs dans les systèmes de transcription de mélodies chantées basés sur l'apprentissage machine, car aucun de ces systèmes n'en a jusqu'ici pleinement profité. La sélection d'attributs est une technique d'apprentissage qui sélectionne un sous-ensemble d'attributs caractérisant les aspects spécifiques d'un signal audio (tels que la fréquence fondamentale, l'harmonicité et la forme d'enveloppe spectrale). Elle a été prouvée qu'elle améliore la performance des systèmes d'apprentissage machine en général et de divers systèmes de la recherche d'information en musique en particulier.Cette thèse présente d'abord un aperçu de l'apprentissage machine dans les applications de musique, concernant les attributs audio, la sélection d'attributs, les algorithmes génétiques (AGs), et le modèle de Markov caché (MMC). Cette thèse passe ensuite en revue les approches pour la transcription de mélodies, un sujet plus large qui contient la transcription de mélodies chantées. Enfin, cette thèse construit un système de transcription de mélodies chantées basée sur le MMC, évalue la performance des différentes méthodes de sélection d'attributs dans ce système et compare cette performance avec celles d'autres systèmes récents de la transcription de mélodies chantées. Le résultat montre que la sélection d'attributs basée sur les AGs a donné lieu à la meilleure amélioration de F mesures de taux d'exactitude (jusqu'à 12,70 %) et suggère que la sélection d'attributs est efficace pour améliorer les rappels et les F-mesures de systèmes de la transcription de mélodies chantées basée sur l'apprentissage machine en utilisant le MMC.</description><creator>Yang, Ling-Xiao</creator><contributor>Ichiro Fujinaga (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Music</subject><title>Singing transcription using machine learning with feature selection</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tv25f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zk43w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:12579v991</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:53:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Food processing and preservation techniques provide high quality nutritive food, reduce the risk of contracting food-borne diseases and increase the shelf life of food products. Processing techniques further increase the digestibility of food, resulting in greater bioavailability of the nutrients and also in the elimination of undesirable factors. Though extensive studies have been performed using various commercial processing methods such as sterilization, pasteurization, autoclaving, extrusion, homogenization, blanching, batch boiling, steam injection, ultra-high temperature (UHT), high temperature and pressure combination, ohmic heating and high pressure processing (HPP), for producing quality food, limited knowledge is available in terms of the effects of processing at atomic and molecular level. Thus, the studies to understand the changes at molecular level could help industrialists to design processing methods with increased nutritive and sensory appeal of food products.In this study, the effects of conventional thermal and microwave treatments on raw soymilk samples for the inactivation of soybean trypsin inhibitors were evaluated. In- vitro protein digestibility (IVPD) studies were also conducted for understanding the effects of aforementioned processing techniques on soymilk proteins. The levels of microwave processing (70⁰C, 85⁰C and 100⁰C for 2, 5, 8 min) and conventional treatment (70⁰C, 85⁰C and 100⁰C for 10, 20, 30 min) were optimized using Response Surface Methodology (RSM).Molecular dynamics (MD) simulation modelling techniques have been applied to explore and visualize the behavior of proteins, at ambient conditions and under the influence of external electric field stress, temperature and time. Soybean trypsin inhibitor (STI) protein was selected for MD simulations. By performing these simulations under the electric field strength of 0.5 V/nm, a valuable insight into the effects of electric field on protein conformation was noted and evaluated using through Root Mean Square Deviation (RMSD), Solvent Accessible Surface Area (SASA) and Ramachandran plot analysis. It was observed that STI has an unusual β-sheet structural stability under the influence of oscillating electric fields. Ramachandran plots were also used to analyze the stability of the molecules obtained on treatment with temperatures (300 K to 393 K) and oscillating electric fields (0.5 V/nm at 2.45 GHz).The experimental results showed that the in-vitro protein digestibility increased with increase in time and temperature during microwave processing and conventional thermal processing. Similarly reduced trypsin inhibitor activity (TIA) values were obtained with an increase in time and temperature of the processing conditions. Therefore, microwave processing can be used as a potential alternative method of processing to improve the overall quality of soymilk. MD simulations have been introduced as a tool to visualize the changes in the stability of secondary protein structures during various processing conditions of time and temperature. The studies also established the relation between various processing methods and conformations of secondary structure of proteins. The solvent accessible area of cysteine residues increased with an increase in the temperature (300 K to 394 K), both in the presence and absence of the oscillating electric field, influencing the disulphide bridge stability. The results showed that the core tryptophan residues of the STI protein increased significantly by changing the conformation of the secondary structure during conventional heating and microwave processing, thus affecting the functional properties of the protein.</description><description>Les techniques de traitement et conservation des denrées périssables permettent de fabriquer des aliments nutritif et salubre, et d'augmenter la durée de conservation des produits alimentaires. Certaines de ces techniques permettent d'accroître la digestibilité des aliments, entraînant une plus grande biodisponibilité des nutriments et l'élimination de facteurs indésirables. Bien que plusieurs études ont été effectuées pour établir la validité de diverses méthodes de traitement comme la stérilisation, la pasteurisation, l'extrusion, l'homogénéisation, le blanchiment, l'injection de vapeur, les ultra-hautes températures, l'utilisation combinée de hautes températures et pressions, le chauffage ohmique et les traitements à très haute pressions, on constate que l'état de la connaissance sur les effets de la transformation au niveau atomique et moléculaire des aliments est limité. Une meilleure compréhension des changements au niveau moléculaire causés par les procédés de transformation est nécessaire pour développer de nouveaux procédés industriels pour la fabrication d'aliments nutritifs, savoureux et sécuritaires. Dans cette étude, les effets des traitements thermiques conventionnels et par micro-ondes sur des échantillons de lait de soja brut pour l'inactivation des inhibiteurs de la trypsine ont été évalués. Des essais sur la digestibilité in-vitro des protéines ont été menés pour mieux comprendre les effets de ces procédés sur les protéines de lait de soja. Les traitements par micro-ondes (70⁰C, 85⁰C et 100⁰C pour 2, 5, et 8 min) ont été comparés aux traitements thermiques conventionnels (70⁰C, 85⁰C et 100⁰C pour 10, 20, et 30 min) et optimisés en utilisant la méthodologie des surfaces de réponses.Des techniques de simulation de la dynamique moléculaire ont été utilisées pour étudier et visualiser le comportement des protéines exposées à des stresses externes causés par les champs micro-ondes, les températures élevées et les durées de traitement. La protéine de soya qui agit comme inhibiteur de l'activité enzymatique de la trypsine et de la chymotrypsine a été utilisée pour les simulations MD. Lors de ces simulations, l'intensité du champ électromagnétique était de 0,5 V/nm et la fréquence de 2450 MHz. Cette simulation a permis d'avoir un aperçu  de l'effet du champ électromagnétique sur la conformation des protéines. Ces effets ont été évalués et comparés par le biais des déviations de l'écart quadratique moyen (RMSD), les surfaces de la zone accessible aux solvants (SASA) et les tracés de Ramachandran. Les tracés de Ramachandran ont également été utilisés pour analyser la stabilité des molécules obtenues après le traitement à des températures allant de 300 à 393 K et exposées aux microondes. Les résultats ont démontré que la digestibilité in-vitro des protéines augmentait avec l'augmentation du temps et de la température de traitement (micro-ondes et thermique conventionnel). De plus, l'activité d'inhibiteur de trypsine (AIT) a diminué avec l'augmentation du temps et de la température des traitements. Le sur-traitement thermique conventionnel requis pour la désactivation des inhibiteurs de trypsine a endommagé d'autres protéines du soya et du fait réduit sa qualité nutritive. Du fait, cette étude a démontré que le traitement par micro-ondes du lait de soya permettaient de fabriquer un lait de meilleur qualité. De plus, il a été observé que les surfaces de la zone accessible aux solvants des résidus de cystéine augmentaient avec l'augmentation de la température (300 K à 394K), à la fois en présence et en l'absence du champ électrique oscillant, et influencé la stabilité des ponts disulfure. On a trouvé que les résidus de noyaux de tryptophane de la protéine STI avaient augmenté de manière significative en modifiant la conformation de la structure secondaire, lors du traitement thermique conventionnel et par traitement de micro-ondes, ce qui a altéré les propriétés fonctionnelles de la protéine.</description><creator>Harish Vagadia, Brinda</creator><contributor>G S Vijaya Raghavan (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Bioresource Engineering</subject><title>Effects of conventional and microwave treatments on inhibitory activity and structural conformation of trypsin inhibitor protein</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mj146.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579v991</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859j324</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:53:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Over the past decades, Australia's refugee policy has been increasingly carried out outside its territory, with many services to detained asylum seekers being outsourced to private contractors. The so-called Offshore Processing Centres of Nauru and Manus Island operate in uncertain areas of international human rights law, where the classic rules of attribution and remedies for human rights violations are challenged by the extraterritorial and outsourced nature of the policy. Recent investigations have shed light on systemic human rights abuses being committed in detention centres, without a clear scheme of accountability under international law.This thesis seeks to reveal the critical limits of international human rights law that these policies highlight. The complex network of private and public actors involved in human rights violations remains unmatched by the international legal framework meant to address them. The state-centred rules of attribution fail to account for different degrees of responsibility from state and non-state actors, which further blurs the fragmented and underdeveloped scheme of remedies for such violations. As a result, individuals who are formally protected by human rights treaties remain in practice unable to hold perpetrators to account.This analysis of the weaknesses in the legal framework seeks to highlight the existence of viable alternatives to address the accountability gap in Offshore Processing Centres: the flexible and evolving nature of international human rights law provides a sound basis on which to rethink the legal expression of rights claims. Providing better avenues to attribute human rights violations and access to remedies for victims appears necessary for human rights law to remain at the centre of refugee protection.</description><description>Sur les dix dernières années, les politiques australiennes en matière de droit d'asile ont été en large partie menées hors du territoire national, sur les iles de Nauru et Manus Island. En vertu d'accords diplomatiques, les demandeurs d'asile sont détenus dans des centres gérés par des acteurs privés. Ces politiques opèrent dans une zone d'ombre du droit international : leur aspect extraterritorial et le rôle central qu'y jouent des acteurs non-étatiques remettent en question l'application des règles d'attribution et d'accès aux réparations en matière de violations des droits de la personne. De nombreuses enquêtes ont récemment dévoilé les abus systématiques commis dans ces centres de détention, sans un clair processus de responsabilité en droit international des droits de la personne. Ce mémoire vise à analyser les limites importantes du droit international que ces politiques révèlent. La place prépondérante de l'état en droit international excluant en principe les actes commis hors du territoire et par les acteurs privés, les droits de la personne peinent à refléter les différents degrés de responsabilité des acteurs publics comme privés sur Manus Island et Nauru. Ce schéma complexe et les difficultés qu'il crée viennent troubler un système de réparations pour les victimes déjà fragmenté et sous développé. Les victimes d'abus, bien que formellement protégées par les traités internationaux, se trouvent dès lors sans mode d'action pour défendre leurs droits et faire condamner les responsables.Cette analyse des faiblesses du système juridique cherche à souligner les potentielles avenues que le droit international pourrait prendre pour contrecarrer le vide de responsabilité pour les abus commis dans les centres de Nauru et Manus Island. Le droit international des droits de la personne étant par nature malléable et évolutif, il constitue une base idéale pour reconceptualiser l'expression juridique des droits fondamentaux.  L'optimisation des modes d'attribution et de réparation des violations des droits fondamentaux est indispensable pour que le droit international des droits de la personne continue à jouer un rôle clé dans la protection des réfugiés et demandeurs d'asile.</description><creator>Ballard, Suzanne</creator><contributor>François Crépeau (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Law</subject><title>None of our business: The fragmentation of Australia's human rights obligations under refugee outsourcing agreements in Nauru and Manus Island</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544bs15f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859j324</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827f302</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:53:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis investigates the effect HIV has on the brain, as captured by magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), using advanced image processing methods: deformation-based morphometry (DBM) and voxel-based morphometry (VBM). It begins with a brief introduction to the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV), followed by the motivation and scientific objectives of the study. Chapter 2 provides an in-depth overview of HIV, its replication cycle, the mechanisms it uses to induce immune deficiency and HIV-associated neurocognitive disorders, and provides a short review of anti-retroviral therapy. Background information on magnetic resonance imaging, medical image processing, the MNI processing pipeline and statistical analysis are also outlined in Chapter 2. Chapter 3 takes the form a manuscript that provides evidence of regionally specific brain volume changes in a large sample of HIV+ patients on stable treatment with effective viral suppression. It should be noted that due to the nature of a Master's manuscript-based thesis, many key ideas and points will be repeated throughout this dissertation.HIV is commonly associated with cognitive impairment, even when viral replication is effectively suppressed with highly active anti-retroviral therapy (HAART). Cognitive deficits may arise from brain injury directly related to the virus, to possible neurotoxic effects triggered at the time of initial infection, or to the many co-morbidities that may have a negative impact on brain function. Although several HIV-related MRI studies have provided vital information about the brain regions affected in HIV+ patients, the exact mechanisms underlying brain injury remain unclear. The aims of the study in Chapter 3 were to characterize the nature and extent of regional brain volume differences between HIV+ individuals and a demographically similar HIV- group, and to assess whether measures of immune status, and current and past HIV infection severity are related to measures of regional brain volumes. We applied advanced neuroimaging analytic methods: DBM and VBM, to structural MRIs acquired in a large sample of HIV+ patients drawn from a United States infectious disease clinic, and a healthy HIV- comparison group drawn from the local community. We report regionally specific patterns of reduced subcortical volumes in the HIV+ sample, despite HAART yielding full viral suppression in the majority. Reduced white matter and subcortical volumes were related to nadir CD4 counts. However, current viral suppression and immune status did not relate to any regional brain volume changes. Our findings argue for the importance of early treatment with HAART, before significant CD4 cell count decline, in protecting long term brain health.</description><description>Cette thèse étudie l'effet du VIH sur le cerveau, comme capturé par imagerie par résonance magnétique (IRM), en utilisant des méthodes avancées de traitement d'image: morphométrie-déformation (DBM) et morphométrie voxel (VBM). Il commence par une brève introduction au virus de l'immunodéficience humaine (VIH), suivie par la motivation et les objectifs scientifiques de cette thèse. Le chapitre 2 donne un aperçu en profondeur du VIH, son cycle de réplication, les mécanismes qu'il utilise pour induire un déficit immunitaire et des troubles neurocognitifs associés au VIH, et fournit un bref examen de la thérapie anti-rétrovirale. Informations générales sur l'imagerie par résonance magnétique, traitement d'images médicales, le pipeline de traitement de l'INM et l'analyse statistique sont également décrites dans le chapitre 2. Le chapitre 3 prend la forme d'un manuscrit qui fournit des preuves de changements spécifiques à la région de volume du cerveau dans un grand échantillon de patients VIH + sur stable traitement avec une suppression virale efficace. Il convient de noter qu'en raison de la nature de la thèse sur la base de manuscrit d'une maîtrise, de nombreuses idées et les points clés seront répétées tout au long de cette thèse.VIH est souvent associée à des troubles cognitifs, même lorsque la réplication virale est supprimée efficacement avec la thérapie anti-rétrovirale hautement active (HAART). Les déficits cognitifs peuvent découler de lésions cérébrales directement lié au virus, aux effets neurotoxiques possibles déclenchées au moment de l'infection initiale, ou pour les nombreuses co-morbidités qui pourraient avoir un impact négatif sur le fonctionnement du cerveau. Bien que plusieurs études IRM liées au VIH ont fourni des informations essentielles sur les régions du cerveau touchées dans les patients VIH +, les mécanismes exacts qui sous-tendent une lésion cérébrale restent floues.Les objectifs de l'étude dans le chapitre 3 étaient de caractériser la nature et l'étendue des différences régionales de volume du cerveau entre les individus VIH + et un groupe VIH démographiquement similaire, et d'évaluer si des mesures de l'état immunitaire, et de gravité de l'infection actuelle et passée du VIH sont liés à mesures de volumes régionaux cérébraux. Nous avons appliqué des méthodes avancées d'analyse neuro-imagerie: DBM et VBM, à l'IRM structurelles acquises dans un large échantillon de patients VIH + tirée d'une maladie infectieuse clinique aux États-Unis, et un groupe de comparaison VIH saine tirée de la communauté locale. Nous rapportons les modèles spécifiques à la région de volumes sous-cortical réduits dans l'échantillon VIH +, malgré la multi thérapie cédant suppression virale complète dans la majorité. Substance blanche réduite et des volumes sous-cortical étaient liés à nadir de CD4. Cependant, la suppression virale actuelle et l'état immunitaire ne se rapportent pas à des changements régionaux de volume du cerveau. Nos résultats plaident en faveur de l'importance d'un traitement précoce avec HAART, avant CD4 baisse significative de la numération cellulaire, dans la protection de la santé du cerveau à long terme.</description><creator>Sanford, Ryan</creator><contributor>Louis Collins (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Biomedical Engineering</subject><title>Impact of HIV on regionally specific brain volumes in the HAART era: A deformation- and voxel-based morphometry study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd473010h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827f302</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306t1893</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:53:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Modern aviation is most arguably defined by the presence of automation in the cockpit.   From the inception of jet transport, computers have been an omnipresent symbol of assurance against the certain uncertainty of human error.  In the business of commercial aviation, computers are considered to be the first line of defense against risk.  Major manufacturers, such as Boeing, Airbus, Bombardier, Embraer, Dassault, and Eclipse have updated the design of their most modern aircraft to include state-of-the-art computing systems and "fly-by-wire" technology under the guise that the computers always know best.  However, pilot certification programs and the international regulatory laws that govern them must be equally revised to insure the human component - as the other side of the equation of modern day aviation - is always up to task.  Many of the most recent major accidents and incidents over the last three decades have been the result of automation errors or failures in human response to those errors.  This thesis explores the effect automation and the incidents caused as a result thereof have had on the dissemination of liability amongst major aircraft manufactures, insurers, and airlines in the wake of such events.  It also explores the effect, if any, these issues have had on products liability, aviation insurance, and private international air law.  And lastly, this thesis suggests both regulatory and educational reforms the industry could adopt to reduce dangers associated with automation complacency  in hopes of eventually reducing or even eradicating such risk.  Despite the threat of catastrophic litigation and demands by the public and leading regulatory authorities for improvements in regulatory policy and laws, however, industry motivation to address problems with automation through specific improvements in training, technology and design continues to remain low; therefore creating a seminal question lingering amongst all members of the modern aviation industry: can the advanced complexity of automation ever be considered failsafe against the imperfection of man? This thesis sets out to explore this quandary. </description><description>L'aviation moderne se caractérise sans aucun doute par l'automatisation des diverses opérations de la cabine de pilotage. Ainsi, depuis les débuts du transport aérien, les ordinateurs ont contribué à pallier aux possibles erreurs humaines. Dans le secteur de l'aviation commerciale, les ordinateurs sont considérés comme l'un des moyens de défense les plus efficaces face aux risques. D'importants manufacturiers tels que Boeing, Airbus, Bombardier, Embraer, Dassault et Eclipse conçoivent désormais leurs avions en y incluant les toutes dernières technologies informatiques et des systèmes de commandes de vol électriques, au motif que les ordinateurs sont plus efficaces. Toutefois, les programmes de certification des pilotes et les réglementations internationales qui les encadrent doivent également faire l'objet d'une révision afin d'assurer que la composante humaine, l'autre partie de l'équation de l'aviation moderne, puisse également être mise à jour.  Bon nombre des plus récents incidents et accidents majeurs dans le domaine de l'aviation au cours des trois dernières décennies ont été le résultat d'erreurs d'automatisation ou encore d'échecs dans la réponse humaine apportée à ces erreurs. Le présent mémoire abordera les conséquences de l'automatisation et les incidents provoqués par celle-ci quant à la responsabilité des grands manufacturiers, des assureurs et des transporteurs aériens à la suite de ces événements. De plus, ce mémoire étudiera également les effets, le cas échéant, que ces questions ont eu sur la responsabilité des produits, l'assurance dans le domaine de l'aviation ainsi que le droit international privé de l'aviation. Enfin, ce mémoire suggère deux réformes à la fois règlementaire et éducationnelle pouvant être adoptées par l'industrie. Ces réformes permettraient de réduire les dangers associés à l'automatisation de complaisance, dans l'espoir de finalement réduire et possiblement même éradiquer ce risque. Malgré les menaces de poursuites et demandes répétées par les autorités publiques réglementaires visant une révision des politiques et des lois dans ce domaine, les motivations du secteur privé à résoudre les problèmes d'automatisation par le biais notamment d'amélioration au niveau de la formation, de la technologie et de la conception demeurent faibles. Par conséquent, cela engendre une question fondamentale persistante entre tous les membres de l'industrie de l'aviation moderne: la complexité de l'automatisation pourrait-elle un jour être considérée comme infaillible face à l'erreur humaine? Ce mémoire se propose d'explorer ce dilemme.</description><creator>Hochman, Dayan</creator><contributor>Paul Stephen Dempsey (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Air and Space Law</subject><title>"Failsafe"? The effect of advanced automation on commercial aviation liability law</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246v546.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t1893</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924f39s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:53:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>ABSTRACTTraffic-related air pollution has been widely considered to be significantly associated with chronic and acute adverse health effects in urban environments. Since high-density traffic emits a considerable amount of pollutants, which are often trapped within urban canyons, individuals living in these areas are exposed to higher levels of traffic-related air pollution. A marked trend towards increasing global urbanization highlights the importance of understanding the patterns of traffic-related air pollution dispersion and recirculation and identifying a proper methodology to reproduce them.The objective of this thesis includes two main components: 1) the integration of microscopic traffic simulation, emission computation and dispersion modeling that reproduces air pollution recirculation patterns in urban environments, and 2) estimation, validation and comparison between different dispersion algorithms.In order to fulfill these objectives, near-road concentrations of nitrogen dioxide (NO2), a known marker of traffic-related air pollution, were simulated along a busy urban corridor in Montreal, Canada using a combination of microscopic traffic simulation, instantaneous emission modeling, and air pollution dispersion. Measurements of NO2 were conducted mid-block along four segments of the corridor throughout a 4-week campaign conducted between March and April 2015. The four segments were chosen to be consecutive and yet exhibiting variability in road configuration and built environment characteristics. Roadside NO2 measurements were also paired with on-site meteorological data collected using a portable meteorological station. In addition, traffic volumes, composition, and routing decisions were collected using video-cameras located at upstream and downstream intersections. Dispersion of simulated emissions was calculated for 8 time slots and under a range of meteorological conditions using three different models (OSPM, CALINE4, and SIRANE) with vastly different dispersion algorithms. While OSPM and SIRANE led to simulated concentrations having a better match against measured concentrations on road segments with buildings on both sides, CALINE4 led to a better match with measured data when the built environment mostly involves open terrain. All three models revealed a better performance when wind speed was higher than 1.5 m/s. The performances of OSPM and CALINE4 were also constrained by wind direction, while SIRANE overcame this shortcoming. In conclusion, SIRANE exhibited better overall performance compared to the other two dispersion models. </description><description>RÉSUMÉLa pollution atmosphérique liée aux transports est associée à des effets indésirables sur la santé dans les milieux urbains. Ces effets néfastes sont plus prononcés à cause de la circulation routière qui est un produit des quartiers résidentiels et commerciaux à haute densité, ainsi que les effets du cadre bâti qui peuvent exacerber les symptômes des maladies respiratoires. Puisque les risques de l'exposition prolongée aux polluants atmosphériques sont plus élevés dans les régions urbaines, il est donc nécessaire de mieux comprendre les effets de la dispersion atmosphérique et de la recirculation de l'air et également d'identifier les méthodologies afin de les reproduire. Le but de cette dissertation s'agit de deux composants principaux. Le premier but concerne l'intégration de la simulation microscopique de la circulation routière, le calcul des émissions et la modélisation de la dispersion atmosphérique qui peuvent reproduire la recirculation de la pollution de l'air dans les environnements urbains. Le deuxième objectif examine l'estimation, la validation et la comparaison des modèles qui peuvent ensuite déterminer le modèle optimal selon la forme du cadre bâti. Afin d'accomplir ces objectifs, les concentrations du dioxyde d'azote (NO2) mesurées au bord de la rue, un marqueur de la pollution de l'air liée à la circulation, ont été simulé au bord d'une artère importante située à Montréal, Québec en utilisant des méthodes de simulation microscopique de la circulation, modélisation d'émissions instantanées, et la dispersion de la pollution atmosphérique. Les mesures NO2 ont été exécutées sur quatre segments de la rue pour quatre semaines pendant les mois de mars et d'avril 2015. Les points de mesure ont été choisis pour refléter les différences des caractéristiques portant sur l'orientation de la voie de la circulation et du cadre bâti. Les mesures NO2 ont été couplées avec les données météorologiques mesurées sur place par une station météo portable.Ensuite, les volumes de la circulation routière, leur composition, ainsi que les décisions routières ont été accueillies en utilisant des caméras vidéos situés en amont et en aval des carrefours. L'effet de la dispersion des émissions simulées a été effectué pour huit périodes temporales qui démontrent une variété des conditions météorologiques en utilisant trois modèles différents (OSPM, CALINE4, et SIRANE). Tandis que l'utilisation d'OSPM et SIRANE a mené à des concentrations simulées qui sont plus similaires avec les concentrations mesurées lorsque le point de mesure est situé dans un canyon urbain, les résultats de CALINE4 a été plus compatible avec les données réelles où les espaces ouverts sont impliqués. En plus, quand la vitesse du vent a été plus forte que 1.5 m/s, les performances des modèles ont amélioré. L'efficacité de l'OSPM et CALINE4 a été affectée négativement par la direction du vent, tandis que ce paramètre a compté un effet neutre en utilisant SIRANE. En conclusion, SIRANE a démontré les meilleurs résultats parmi les trois modèles.</description><creator>Wang, An</creator><contributor>Ronald Gehr (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Civil Engineering &amp; Applied Mechanics</subject><title>Characterizing near-road air pollution using local-scale emission and dispersion models and validation against in-situ measurements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257h62h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924f39s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:794080867</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:53:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Depuis déjà deux décennies, l'Assemblée générale de l'Organisation des Nations Unies planifie la réforme du Conseil de sécurité, alors que la restructuration de ce dernier demeure complexe. Nous tenterons donc, dans notre mémoire, d'expliquer pourquoi après tant d'années, près de 193 États membres s'intéressent activement à cette réforme et comment il est possible d'observer leurs engagements à ce propos. Afin d'analyser les efforts et les différents obstacles quant à cette dite réforme du Conseil de sécurité, les motivations des États membres lors du processus seront analysées. Nous avançons donc l'idée selon laquelle les États membres possèdent tous un même objectif, soit réformer le CS, mais qu'ils le font pour de multiples raisons. Basé sur la théorie néo-institutionnelle, il sera démontré comment certains États membres agissent selon leurs propres intérêts à la suite de calculs stratégiques, alors qu'au contraire, certains d'entre eux agissent de façon normative par rapport à ce qu'ils considèrent convenable. Par ailleurs, notre mémoire démontre que malgré un faible support de la réforme par certains États membres, aucun d'eux ne peut la dénoncer publiquement, puisqu'elle est devenue un incontournable. L'emphase sera mise sur la réforme structurelle, soit l'élargissement du CS, aussi bien que sur l'amélioration de ses méthodes de travail. Malgré le manque de restructuration formelle, le Conseil de sécurité ne cesse de s'adapter afin d'être pertinent toujours au XXIe siècle.</description><description>Reforming the United Nations Security Council has been on the agenda of the General Assembly for over two decades. However, structural reform of the Council remains elusive. This research paper will seek to explain why after so many years nearly all 193 states within the UN remain actively seized on the matter of reform, and ongoing commitment to Council reform can be observed. In order to properly analyze SC reform efforts and the various obstacles along the way, this paper emphasizes states' motivations during the reform process. This thesis argues that although states work on the same objective, namely that of reforming the UNSC, they do so for varying reasons. With the help of new institutionalist theory, an argument is formed that highlights how certain states are more driven by strategic calculations and self-interest, while others are more normatively motivated, and thus are more driven by what is considered appropriate. Furthermore, this thesis highlights that despite only lukewarm support for reform from certain states, not a single state can publicly denounce Council reform, because the reform issue itself has become an ingrained norm. Emphasis will be given to structural reform, such as increasing the size of the Council, as well as improving the SC's working methods. Despite the lack of formal reform, the SC has continually proven to be adaptive in order to remain relevant well into the 21st century. </description><creator>Schaefer, Kai</creator><contributor>Fernando Nunez (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Political Science</subject><title>Reforming the United Nations Security Council: Feasibility or Utopia?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732dc60b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/794080867</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z903254d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:53:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sepsis is a clinical condition of dysregulated systemic inflammation and pervasive tissue damage. Patients with severe sepsis are prone to skeletal muscle dysfunction which is manifested as fiber atrophy and depressed contractile performance. The causes of sepsis induced muscle atrophy remain under investigation. In this thesis, we hypothesize that sepsis triggers fiber atrophy in both the ventilatory and limb muscles and that fiber atrophy is the result of significant reduction in protein contents of various myofilament proteins including Myosin Heavy and Light Chain, Troponins and Tropomyosin. We also propose that the degree of myofiber atrophy and contractile protein degradation triggered by severe sepsis is related to muscle oxidative capacity with the diaphragm showing relatively lesser degree of atrophy and protein degradation than the limb muscles. Finally, we propose that reduction in myofilament protein contents of skeletal muscles is mediated through both increased proteolysis and reduction in mRNA expression of myofilament genes.Sepsis was induced in adult C57/Bl6 mice by cecal ligation and perforation (CLP) technique. Control animals (Sham) were subjected to an identical surgical procedure with the exclusion of cecum perforation. Sham and CLP animals were investigated after 24, 48, and 96h post-surgical procedure and the diaphragm (DIA) and tibialis anterior (TA) muscles were quickly excised as representative of the ventilatory and limb muscles, respectively. Muscle atrophy was quantified by measuring myofiber diameter. Myofilament protein contents were measured with immunoblotting using antibodies selective to Myosin Heavy Chain, Myosin Light Chain,Actin, Troponin-T, Troponin-I, Troponin-C and Tropomyosin proteins. Expression of mRNA of various myofilament genes was measured with real-time PCR.Sepsis induced significant atrophy of DIA and TA fibers in mice. The time course and the degree of atrophy in the two muscles differed significantly. While DIA atrophy developed only after 24h of sepsis and was relatively mild in nature, atrophy of TA muscle fibers was detected after 24, 48, and 96h of sepsis and was relatively more severe than that of the DIA. Sepsis also triggered significant increase in the mRNA expression of two muscle-specific E3 ligases involved in protein ubiquitination (Atrogin-1 and MuRF1). The relative induction of Atrogin-1 and MuRF1 mRNA expression was stronger in the TA compared to the DIA. Sepsis was also associated with significant decreases in mRNA and protein levels of various myofilament contractile proteins in the DIA and TA. However, the time course and sensitivity to sepsis differed among various myofilament proteins with Actin and Troponin-I being less sensitive to the inhibitory effects of sepsis while mRNA and protein levels of Myosin Heavy Chain, Myosin Light Chain, Troponin-T, Troponin-C and Tropomyosin were strongly influenced by sepsis. Finally, reduction of Myosin Heavy Chain and Myosin Light Chain protein contents was sustained even after 96h of CLP while the decline in Troponin-T, Troponin-I, Troponin-C and Tropomyosin mRNA and protein levels in DIA and TA was restricted to 24 and 48h after induction of sepsis.Our study is the first to show that sepsis triggers significant and more severe fiber atrophy in limb muscles compared to the DIA and that sepsis is associated with significant reductions in the contents of various myofilament proteins including those of thick contractile elements (Myosin Heavy and Light Chains) and regulatory proteins such as Troponins and Tropomyosin. Finally, our study indicates for the first time that decreased skeletal muscle myofilament protein contents in septic animals is mediated through increased proteolysis and decreased mRNA expression of these proteins.</description><description>La septicémie est un état clinique d'inflammation systémique dérégulée menant à des lésions tissulaires omniprésente. Les patients qui développent les stages ultérieurs, sont sujets à un dysfonctionnement du muscle squelettique se traduisant par une atrophie et une détérioration de la contractilité du muscle. Les causes sous-jacentes à l'atrophie musculaire induite par la septicémie restent ambiguës et non entièrement exploré. Dans cette thèse, nous émettons l'hypothèse que atrophie du muscle squelettique induite par la septicémie est une résultante de la dégradation différentielles de protéines ciblant les diverses protéines contractiles myofibrillaires. Nous suggérons également que le degré d'atrophie des myofibre et le degré de dégradation des protéines contractiles généré en réponse à une septicémie ne sont pas uniformes dans toute la musculature : les muscles ayant une capacité oxydative relativement élevée tels que le diaphragme (DIA) devrait subir moins d'atrophie et moins d'activité protéolytique en comparaison aux muscles de capacité oxydative relativement faible tels que le jambier antérieur (JA). La septicémie a été induite chez les souris adultes C57 / BL6 en employant la procédure de ligature et perforation du cæcum (LPC). Les animaux témoins (Sham) ont été soumis à une intervention chirurgicale identique à celle du groupe LPC à l'exclusion toutefois de la perforation du caecum. Les animaux Sham et LPC ont été étudiés 24h, 48h, 96h post-chirurgie. L'atrophie musculaire a ensuite été quantifiée par la mesure du diamètre des fibres musculaires. La dégradation différentielle des protéines contractile a été évaluée par mesure de l'expression de plusieurs protéines des fibresmusculaires, notamment la troponine C , Troponine I , la troponine T, MYL2 (f) MYL1 (f), S21 MYL3 (s), tropomyosine (TPM ), l'actine sarcomérique, l'actinin, MyHC totale, MyHC IIB et MyHC IIA. L'expression des gènes codant pour ces protéines a également été étudiée en quantifiant l'expression relative de leur ARNm par la méthode de PCR en temps réel. La septicémie induit une atrophie significative des fibres du DIA et du JA chez la souris. Le cours du temps de l'atrophie musculaire dans les deux muscle diffère largement de sorte que l'atrophie du DIA se développe uniquement après 24h de septicémie tandis que dans le JA une importante atrophie des fibres persiste au cours des 24, 48 et 96h de la septicémie. La septicémie à également suscité une dimunition significative et différentielle du niveau d'expression de diverses protéines et conséquemment de leur ARNm spécifique, dans le DIA et JA. Cependant, le cours du temps et la sensibilité à la septicémie menant à une réduction dans l'expression protéique et génique, diverge entre plusieurs protéines des myofilaments.actine et Troponine-I semblait être moins sensibles aux effets inhibiteurs de la septicémie tandis que les niveaux d'ARNm et protéiques de la chaîne de myosine lourde, de la chaîne légère de la myosine, la troponine-T, Troponine-C et Tropomyosin sont fortement influencés par la septicémie.Enfin, la réduction du niveau d'expression des chaînes myosine lourde et légère est soutenue même après 96h post-LPC tandis que la baisse des taux de protéines et d'ARNm de la troponine-T, Troponine-I, troponine C et Tropomyosin s'est limité à 24h et 48h après l'induction de la septicémie.Notre étude est la première extrapolant que la LPC déclenche une atrophie significative dans le muscle squelettique tout en explorant les mécanismes au niveau des protéines contractiles myofirillaire dans les muscles squeletique des membres inferieurs ainsi que dans les muscles respiratoires. En outre, cette étude démontre également que la dégradation différentielle de différentes protéines contractiles est induite dans une grande mesure dans les muscles des membres inférieurs ayant une capacité d'oxydation faible par rapport aux muscles respiratoires ayant une capacité oxydative habituellement plus élevée.</description><creator>Moarbes, Vanessa</creator><contributor>Sabah N A Hussain (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Differential regulation of skeletal muscle myofilament protein expression in sepsis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75rb58n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903254d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b6196</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:53:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les biolipides sont largement utilisé dans l'industrie des produits oléochimiques ainsi que dans la production de biocarburants, de tensioactifs biologiques et de biolubrifiants. Ces lipides biologiques ont le potentiel d'éventuellement remplacer plusieurs produits pétrochimiques. La demande croissante de biolipides dans plusieurs secteurs industriels intensifie l'importance d'huiles végétales sur une échelle mondiale. Au delà de 30% du régime quotidien calorifique humain est comblé par des huiles comestibles, ce qui représente 80% de la production mondiale d'huiles végétales. Afin de répondre à la demande, la production d'oléagineux a augmenté grâce à une amélioration en termes de la culture sélective et de l'extension des zones de culture et par la production de plantes génétiquement modifiées. Le pois (Pisum sativum L.) est l'une des cultures les plus rependues et importantes au monde. Ainsi, une augmentation significative de la teneur en lipides des graines du pois cultivé pourrait faciliter la production d'huile végétale. Les pois possèdent une concentration importante de protéines et d'amidon. Cependant, la concentration de lipides présentes dans le pois cultivé doit accroitre pour éventuellement considérer cette légumineuse comme source importante de biolipides. Bien que les voies de biosynthèse de lipides chez les plantes supérieures ont été découverts, notre compréhension du mécanisme de régulation de l'accumulation de lipides est encore limitée. Par conséquent, cette étude examine la corrélation entre la teneur en lipides et d'autres marqueurs phénotypiques du pois cultivé. Des semences provenant de huit accessions de pois ont été dépistées pour leur teneur en lipides ainsi que pour d'autres marqueurs phénotypiques tels que leur teneur en glucides, protéines, caroténoïdes, flavonoïdes, chlorophylle, humidité, cendres, phénols, amidon et finalement en terme d'activité antioxydante. La teneur en lipides des semences de pois cultivés était faible, se situant entre 1,3 à 2,6%, alors que la teneur en protéines et en glucides était relativement élevée, variant de 155 à 232 mg d'ASB par gramme d'échantillon (ASB, albumine de sérum bovin) et de 357 à 453 mg par g d'échantillon, respectivement. L'analyse statistique révèle qu'il existe une corrélation entre la teneur en lipides et la variété, la forme des graines, la couleur des graines, la teneur en cendres et la teneur en amidon, mais la corrélation entre la teneur en lipides et la teneur en protéine était négligeable. Il existe une forte corrélation positive entre la teneur en lipides et une haute teneur en cendres, et les graines de couleur brune et verte. Il existe une corrélation négative entre la teneur en lipides et une surface de graine lisse, la couleur de graine jaune, une haute teneur en amidon et un volume de graine plus élevé. En utilisant l'analyse statistique des marqueurs phénotypiques, la variété de pois souhaitée peut être facilement sélectionné et la modification significative peut encore être effectué pour améliorer la qualité nutritionnelle.</description><description>Bio-lipid products are extensively used in the production of biofuels, bio-surfactants, bio-lubricants and the oleo-chemical industry, which has the potential to replace many of the petrochemical based products. Growing demand for bio-oils in various industries has increased the importance of vegetable oil production globally. Over 30 % of daily calories in the human diet are supplied by edible oil, which accounts for 80 % of the total vegetable oil produced in the world. In order to meet the demand, oilseed production has increased through improvements in breeding, extending the cultivation area and by producing genetically modified plants. Pea (Pisum sativum L.) is one of the most world's important crops and a significant increase in the lipid content of the field pea seeds could facilitate increased vegetable oil production around the world. Previous research has reported that peas are a valuable source of protein and starch, but the lipid concentration in their seeds has been undervalued. Although the pathways for lipid biosynthesis in higher plants have been uncovered, our understanding of the regulatory mechanism controlling lipid accumulation is still limited. Therefore this study investigated the correlation between the lipid content and other field pea phenotypic markers. Seeds of eight pea accessions were screened for lipid content and other phenotypic markers such as content of carbohydrate, proteins, carotenoids, flavonoids, chlorophyll, moisture, ash, phenols, starch and antioxidant activity. The lipid content in field pea seeds was low and ranges from 1.3 to 2.6 %, whereas protein and carbohydrate content was comparatively high and varies from 155 to 232 mg of BSA / g of sample (BSA, Bovine serum albumin) and 357 to 453 mg / g of sample, respectively. Statistical analysis revealed that lipid content was correlated to the variety, seed shape, seed colour, ash content and starch content, but the correlation to protein was insignificant. Lipid content was found to have a strong positive correlation with high ash content, brown color seeds and green color seeds, and negative correlation with smooth surface, yellow colour, high starch content and larger seed volume. On the basis of statistical analysis of phenotypic markers, desired pea variety can be easily selected and significant modification in the field peas can be further performed to improve the nutritional quality. </description><creator>Kalia, Richa</creator><contributor>Mark Lefsrud (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Valerie Orsat (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Bioresource Engineering</subject><title>Correlation of lipid content and phenotypic markers of Canadian field peas «Pisum sativum»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333509z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b6196</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w032582c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:53:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'objectif de ce projet de recherche était de réaliser une analyse en trois-dimensions du patinage sur glace à l'accélération et de comparer les mouvements entre les joueurs et joueuses de hockey sur glace de haut calibre. Nous avons utilisé un système de capture de mouvement comprenant dix-huit caméras infrarouges sur la glace. Le but était de déterminer s'il existe une différence entre la cinématique du patinage entre les hommes et les femmes, tout comme il en existe chez les coureurs. Pour ce projet, les sept premiers coups de patins des sujets à partir d'un départ avant de hockey ont été analysés. Les résultats indiquent qu'il existe des différences de cinématique au niveau de la hanche, du genou et de la cheville entre les hommes et les femmes, pendant une accélération maximale de patinage. En tout temps, les femmes ont les hanches davantage en adduction comparé aux hommes, ainsi que les genoux plus en extension quand le patin contact sur la glace. De plus, nous avons trouvé des différences au niveau de la performance et des paramètres spatio-temporels entre les groupes par exemple la largeur du pas de patin. Ces résultats ont des implications pour les instructeurs de patinage, les entraîneurs, les professionnelles de la réhabilitation et les compagnies d'équipement de hockey.</description><description>The aim of this Master's study was to examine the kinematics of ice-skating between high caliber male and female ice hockey players, using eighteen three-dimensional motion capture cameras. This would serve to determine if there are differences in the biomechanics of ice-skating between male and female skaters, as is seen in male and female runners. Participants performed a skating acceleration task from a static start and the first seven steps were analyzed as part of this study. Results of this study show that there are differences in the kinematics of the hip, knee and ankle during skating acceleration between male and female ice hockey players. The female skaters were more adducted at the hip through the task and more extended at the knee at ice contact compared to the male subjects. Furthermore, there are also differences in skating performance and spatiotemporal parameters analyzed, such as step width. These results have implications for skating instruction and training, injury rehabilitation and ice hockey equipment development.</description><creator>Shell, Jaymee</creator><contributor>David J Pearsall (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Kinesiology and Physical Education</subject><title>Skating propulsion: three-dimensional kinematic analysis of high caliber male and female ice hockey players</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f403z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032582c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s1784p32s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:53:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Species of crucifers such as Eruca sativa (rocket, roquette) are known to contain a variety of bioactive compounds such as phenolic compounds, flavonols, and isothiocyanates. In this study, two different drying procedures were used to compare the levels of bioactive compounds, antioxidant activity, and chemical profiles of arugula leaves and stems after treatment. The overall comparison of the bioactive compounds and chemical profiles of lyophilized (LR) and tray-dried rocket samples (TDR), conditions of 55 C for 6 hours, was performed using chromogenic assays and chromatographic analysis. Total flavonoid assay showed significantly different concentrations between the LR (3.29 ± 0.15 g/100g) and TDR samples (2.42 ± 0.22 g/100g) measured as quercetin equivalents (QE) although the total phenolic content between the samples showed no difference: 8.67 ± 0.6 g/100g QE and 8.5 ± 0.8 g/100g QE, for LR and TDR respectively. The antioxidant activity in the LR sample as measured using the DPPH• assay indicated a scavenging activity of 28.01% while a result of 27.96 % was obtained for the TDR sample. Moreover, total isothiocyanate contents measured by the cyclocondensation reaction analyzed by GC-MS showed a concentration twofold higher in the TDR sample (6.05 ± 0.83 μg/g) as opposed to the LR sample (3.26 ± 0.59 μg/g). Chemical fingerprinting of the LR and TDR samples using pyrolysis-GC/MS was investigated to identify volatile compounds; this revealed minor differences in compounds observed between the samples. LC-ESI-qTOF-MS analysis was also employed for the identification of possible structural configurations of non-volatile compounds, which indicated the presence of glycosides in the LR sample in contrast to the TDR sample that harbored aglycones instead. Furthermore, infrared spectra obtained using FTIR-ATR for both samples showed minimal variations between those, although TDR displayed a slightly higher number of peaks. Images from Scanning Electron Microscopy (SEM) revealed variations in the average particle diameter in TDR due to thermal processing, and only minor shrinkage in the case of LR particles.   </description><description>Plusieurs espèces de crucifères tel que Eruca sativa contiennent une série de substances bioactives, par exemple des composés phénoliques, des flavonols, de même que certains isothiocyanates. La présente étude visait à comparer les effets post-traitement de deux méthodes de déshydratation sur (i) les niveaux de composés bioactifs, (ii) l'activité antioxidative, et (iii) la composition chimique, des feuilles et tiges de laitue roquette (également connue sous le terme arugula). Principalement, des analyses par réactions chromogéniques et par chromatographie ont permis de comparer les composés bioactifs et la composition chimique d'échantillons soit lyophilisés (RL) soit séchés sur  plateaux à 55 C durant 6 heures (RSP). La quantification des flavonoïdes totaux a montré des différences significatives entre RL (3.29 ± 0.15 g/100g) et RSP (2.42 ± 0.22 g/100g) tel que mesuré en équivalents quercétine ou EQ; toutefois le contenu en composes phénoliques totaux s'est avéré similaire entre les deux traitements. soit: 8.67 ± 0.6 g/100g EQ et 8.5 ± 0.8 g/100g EQ respectivement. L'activité antiradicalaire mesurée par la méthode de piégeage du DPPH• pour l'échantillon RL a indiqué une activité de 28.01% alors qu'une valeur de 27.96% a été obtenue pour RSP. Par ailleurs, le contenu en isothiocyanates mesuré via cyclocondensation suivie d'injection sur unité GC-MS a révélé une teneur deux fois supérieure dans l'échantillon RSP (6.05 ± 0.83 μg/g vs 3.26 ± 0.59 μg/g). Les empreintes chimiques des deux types d'échantillons ont été obtenues par pyrolyse/GC-MS et la comparaison des composés volatils ainsi identifiés a indiqué une différence mineure entre les deux traitements. Une analyse par LC-ESI-qTOF-MS a également été utilisée afin d'identifier certaines configurations structurales de composés  non-volatils; cette étape a permis de confirmer la présence de glycosides dans le produit lyophilisé, contrairement à l'échantillon séché sur plateau qui lui contenait de son còté  des aglycones. De plus, l'analyse spectrale par FTIR-ATR des deux types d`échantillons n'a montré qu'une faible variation, malgré un nombre de pics légèrement supérieur pour RSP. Les images par microscopie électronique à balayage (SEM) ont confirmé des variations au niveau du diamètre moyen des particules RSP, conséquentes au traitement thermique et ceci par contraste au phénomène de rétraction observé dans l'échantillon lyophilisé. </description><creator>Alruwaih, Noor</creator><contributor>Varoujan Yaylayan (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</subject><title>Chemical profiling and comparative evaluation of bioactive compounds in lyophilized and tray-dried rocket «Eruca sativa»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xf50q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s1784p32s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8p58pg670</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:53:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>     Des isolats de protéines de roquette (Eruca sativa) furent extraits à partir de graines et de feuilles par NaOH et précipités par techniques isoélectriques, éthanol et cryoprécipitation.  Les propriétés moléculaires et nutritives des isolats de protéines ont été examiné par des techniques d'électrophorèse, de calorimétrie différentielle à balayage (DSC), de spectroscopie infrarouge à transformée de Fourier (FTIR), de degré d'hydrolyse (DH), et d'activité antioxidante.  L'analyse des isolats de protéines par électrophorèse SDS-PAGE a démontré 6 bandes majeures pour les isolats provenant des graines et 5 bandes majeures pour ceux provenant de plants complets, entre 108-17 kDa et 131-17 kDa, respectivement.  L'électrophorèse sous conditions non-dénaturantes révéla une bande intense pour chaque isolat de protéines provenant des graines (536 kDa) et des feuilles (600 kDa), sauf pour les isolats qui ont été précipité par éthanol et cryoprécipitation où aucune bande n'ont été détecté.  L'analyse DH par trypsine des isolats de protéines résulta entre 34-51% pour les graines et 44-65% pour les feuilles avec une augmentation continue de l'hydrolyse.  Avec un mélange de trypsine et de chymotypsine, la DH augmenta jusqu'à 90 minutes suivi par une baisse.  Les résultats finaux ont été 57-66% pour les isolats de protéines provenant des graines et 50-61% pour ceux provenant des feuilles.  Les hydrolysats de protéines avaient une plus grande activité antioxidante que les isolats de protéines pour toutes les analyses réalisées; analyse par (1,1-diphenyl-2 picrylhydrazyl) DPPH et par chélateur de métaux.  L'activité antioxidante a varié entre 5-15% pour les isolats de protéines et 12.5-27.5% pour les hydrolysats de protéines.  Les résultats obtenus par analyse DSC ont démontré une grande stabilité thermique pour les isolats de protéines provenant des graines ainsi que ceux provenant des feuilles, où la plus haute température de dénaturation (Td) a été enregistré pour le control de plante de roquette complète (123.9°C) alors que la plus basse Td a été obtenu avec l'isolat de protéines de la plante complète qui avait été traité par cryoprécipitation (105.8°C).  Les résultats obtenus par FTIR étaient surtout des structures β dans les régions d'amide I et d'amide II pour tous les isolats de protéines.  Les structures de feuillet β obtenus confirment la dénaturation des protéines comparativement à l'échantillon brute de poudre de graines qui démontra seulement que des structures secondaires à hélice α et à boucle aléatoire.</description><description>Arugula (Eruca sativa) protein isolates from seeds and leaves were extracted by NaOH and precipitated by isoelectric, ethanol and cryoprecipitation techniques. Molecular and nutritional properties of protein isolates were examined by electrophoresis, differential scanning calorimetry (DSC), fourier transform infrared (FTIR) spectroscopy, degree of hydrolysis (DH), and antioxidant activity techniques. SDS-PAGE of protein isolates showed 6 major bands for seed isolates and 5 major bands for whole plant isolates ranged between 108-17 kDa and 131-17 kDa, respectively. Native-PAGE revealed 1 intense band for each protein isolate in seeds (536 kDa) and leaves (600 kDa) except for isolates that were precipitated by ethanol and cryoprecipitation that did not show any bands. DH by trypsin ranged from 34-51 % for seed and 44-65 % for leaf protein isolates with continuous increase. Through trypsin-chymotrypsin mixture, there was increase until 90 minutes and after that a decrease was observed. Final results were 57-66 % for seed and 50-61 % for leaf protein isolates. Protein hydrolysates had higher antioxidant activity than protein isolates for all assays that they were subjected to; (1,1-diphenyl-2 picrylhydrazyl) DPPH and metal chelating assays. Antioxidant activity ranged between 5-15 % for protein isolates and 12.5-27.5 % for protein hydrolysates. DSC results demonstrated high thermal stability for both seed and leaf protein isolates where highest temperature of denaturation (Td) was for arugula whole plant control (123.9 °C) and lowest Td referred to arugula whole plant protein isolate-cryoprecipitation (105.8 °C). FTIR results were mostly β structures in amide I and amide II regions for all protein isolates. β-sheet structures are confirmation of protein denaturation compared to raw seed powder that showed only α-helix and random coil secondary structure.</description><creator>ALSalman, Fatemah</creator><contributor>Inteaz Alli (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</subject><title>Isolation and molecular and nutritional properties of proteins from Eruca sativa leaves and seeds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pq67m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pg670</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b883d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:53:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La virtualisation des réseaux sans fil est considérée comme un modèle prometteur pour régler la crise spectrale et l'ossification des réseaux. Notamment, celle-ci se fait en partageant, entre les fournisseurs de service, des ressources sans fil communes, généralement référé en tant que tranches. De plus, à cause de la nature aléatoire des canaux radio et des ressources limitées, un réseau sans fil virtualisé (VWN) demande une provision efficace des ressources pour fonctionner. L'objective de cette thèse est donc d'étudier et de proposer un algorithme de provision de ressources en tenant compte de la qualité de service (Qos-aware) applicable aux VWNs.  La première partie de cette thèse se concentre sur la conception des politiques de provisionnement des ressources pour satisfaire aux exigences instantanées (ex., débit et ressource bases réservé) des tranches et minimiser l'interruption de service des VWN dû à l'infaisabilité. D'abord, un algorithme optimal de provisionnement de ressource est développé pour satisfaire simultanément au débit et aux ressources (puissance et sous porteuses) requis par deux groupes de tranches. Ensuite, pour faire face à la question de l'infaisabilité des VWNs causées par les ressources sans fil limitées, une politique de contrôle d'admission est proposée. Dans ce contexte, un algorithme de contrôle d'admission optimal est développé pour ajuster dynamiquement les exigences des tranches, selon les informations d'état de canal (CSI) et les priorités des tranches. Enfin, pour améliorer encore la région de faisabilité, un algorithme d'allocation conjointe de puissances, de sous porteuses et d'antennes est développé pour les VWNs avec une configuration de multiples antennes à grande échelle, où la station de base (BS), équipée avec un large nombre d'antennes, sert des utilisateurs appartenant à différentes tranches.La deuxième partie de cette thèse propose une conception réaliste des VWNs. Plus précisément, les questions de l'arrivée aléatoire de trafic en rafales dans la file d'attente, de l'efficacité énergétique des utilisateurs, de l'incertitude de la CSI à la BS, souvent éprouvées en pratique, sont abordées à travers des politiques de provisionnement des ressources. Premièrement, pour améliorer l'expérience de l'utilisateur final, les politiques de provisionnement des ressources inter-couches sont présentés. Dans ce contexte, une politique de provisionnement dynamique des ressources, adaptable à la fois aux informations d'état de canal (CSI) et de file d'attente (QSI) des VWNs, est proposée pour maintenir la stabilité des files d'attente du VWNs. Ensuite, pour minimiser la consommation d'énergie, une politique de provisionnement des ressources est proposée pour satisfaire au maximum des retards moyens de transmission de paquets, afin d'offrir une expérience fiable aux utilisateurs finaux des VWNs. Enfin, la question de la CSI incertaine au BS en raison d'erreurs d'estimation est abordée à travers une politique de provisionnement des ressources qui est à la fois robuste et efficace énergétiquement. La consommation totale d'énergie du VWN est facilement contrôlable via les facteurs de coût de tranches dans la politique proposée. Des simulations sont effectuées pour analyser en profondeur les effets des paramètres du système sur la performance des VWNs.</description><description>Wireless virtualization is emerging as a promising paradigm to tackle the issues of spectrum-crisis and network ossification via enabling common shared substrate of wireless resources among service providers, commonly referred as slices.  Due to random nature of wireless channels and limited resources, virtualized wireless network (VWN) requires an efficient resource provisioning policy to operate. The objective of this thesis is to study and propose quality-of-service-aware (QoS-aware) resource provisioning policies applicable to VWNs.The first part of the thesis focuses on the design of resource provisioning policies to satisfy instantaneous requirements (e.g., minimum reserved rates and resources) of slices and minimize the VWN outage due to infeasibility.  At first, an optimal algorithm for resource provisioning is developed to simultaneously satisfy the rate and resource (power and sub-carriers) based requirements of two groups of slices. Afterwards, to deal with the issue of infeasibility in VWNs due to limited wireless resources, an admission control policy is proposed.  In this context, an optimal admission control algorithm is developed to dynamically adjust the requirements of slices according to channel state information (CSI) and priorities of slices. Finally, to further improve the feasibility region, a joint power, sub-carrier and antenna allocation algorithm is developed for VWN with massive multiple input multiple output (MIMO) setup, where a base station (BS), equipped with large number of antennas, serves users belonging to different slices.The second part of the thesis focuses on more realistic design of VWNs. Specifically, the issues of random, bursty traffic arrival in users' queue, energy-efficiency and uncertain CSI at the BS, often experienced in practice, are addressed through resource provisioning policies. At first, to improve end-user service experience, cross-layer resource provisioning policies are presented. In this context, a dynamic resource provisioning policy, adaptable to both CSI and queue state information (QSI) of VWNs, is proposed to maintain the stable queue state of VWN.  Afterwards, to minimize energy consumption, a resource provisioning policy is proposed to satisfy the maximum average packet transmission delay in VWNs to offer reliable end-users' experience. Finally, the issue of uncertain CSI at the BS due to estimation errors is addressed through an energy-efficient robust resource provisioning policy. The total energy consumption of VWN is easily controllable via the cost factors of slices in the proposed policy. Simulations are performed to deeply analyze the effects of system parameters on VWN's performance.</description><creator>Jumba, Vikas</creator><contributor>Tho Le-Ngoc (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</subject><title>QoS-aware resource provisioning in virtualized wireless networks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128d75t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b883d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ht24wm98h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:53:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Late blight, caused by the oomycete Phytophthora infestans (Mont.) De Bary, is the most devastating disease affecting the potato, accounting for over six billion United States dollars worldwide each year due to production losses and prevention measures. For many years, synthetic fungicides have been used heavily by potato producers to minimize disease severity and prevent spread. But the incidence of new, more virulent P. infestans genotypes – many of which now fungicide-resistant – has made it increasingly difficult and costly for producers to prevent late blight epidemics. The use of biological fungicides has thus been of considerable interest among plant pathologists in recent years for their ability to produce powerful antifungal compounds and to induce systemic resistance in host plants. This M.Sc. project, in collaboration with Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada, used detached fed-leaf bioassays to test the effectiveness of six bacterial strain whole cultures against four P. infestans isolates for use as potential biocontrol agents. Data analysis revealed that the level of biocontrol differed greatly among the six bacterial strains; 189 (Pseudomonas chlororaphis) being significantly different than the control for 28 of the 32 measurements while this was true for OY3WO11 (Arthrobacter phenanthrenivorans) only once. The top two candidates 189 and WAUSV36 (Bacillus subtilis) were then compared to the commercial synthetic fungicide DithaneTM DG 75 which displayed the strongest levels of late blight control with median disease severity ratings of 0% and 3% after seven and ten days, respectively. Nonetheless, bacterial strains 189 (18% and 40%) and WAUSV36 (48% and 78%) were also significantly different from the untreated control (100% on both measurement days). Time-delay experiments were also conducted in order to determine if differences in biocontrol existed when the time between treatments and infection was increased. A significantly reduced biocontrol efficacy was detected when bacterial treatments were applied 24 hours before infection (compared to 2 and 18 hours) from measurements taken after seven days only (not ten). Integrating the use of bacterial antagonists into late blight management strategies can prove to be an effective addition to current prevention methods and help curb the heavy use of synthetic fungicides in potato production.</description><description>Le mildiou, causé par l'oomycète Phytophthora infestans (Mont.) De Bary, est la maladie la plus dévastatrice affectant la pomme de terre, provoquant des coûts de plus de six milliards de dollars américains au niveau mondial à chaque année en raison de pertes de production et de mesures de prévention. Depuis plusieurs années, les fongicides synthétiques sont largement utilisés par les producteurs de pommes de terre afin de minimiser la gravité de la maladie et d'empêcher sa propagation. L'incidence de nouveaux génotypes de P. infestans plus virulents dont plusieurs sont maintenant résistants aux fongicides, a fait en sorte qu'il est maintenant de plus en plus difficile et coûteux pour les producteurs de prévenir des épidémies de mildiou. Depuis quelques années, l'utilisation de fongicides biologiques a soulevé l'intérêt des phytopathologistes pour leur capacité à produire de puissants composés antifongiques et à induire une résistance systémique chez les plantes hôtes. Ce projet de maîtrise, en collaboration avec Agriculture et Agroalimentaire Canada, vise à utiliser des bio-essais de feuilles détachées et nourries pour tester l'efficacité de six cultures bactériennes entières contre quatre isolats de P. infestans pour leur utilisation potentielle en tant qu'agents de lutte biologique. L'analyse des données a révélé que le niveau de lutte biologique différait grandement entre les six souches bactériennes; 189 (Pseudomonas chlororaphis) étant significativement différente du témoin pour 28 des 32 mesures ce qui était vrai qu'une seule fois pour OY3WO11 (Arthrobacter phenanthrenivorans). Les deux meilleurs candidats 189 et WAUSV36 (Bacillus subtilis) ont ensuite été comparés au fongicide synthétique commercial DithaneTM DG 75 qui a présenté les niveaux les plus forts de contrôle au mildiou avec des indices médians de sévérité de la maladie de 0% et 3% après sept et dix jours respectivement. Néanmoins, les souches bactériennes 189 (18% et 40%) et WAUSV36 (48% et 78%) étaient aussi significativement différentes du témoin non traité (100% sur les deux jours mesurés). Des expériences de temporisation ont également été menées afin de déterminer si des différences dans la lutte biologique existaient lorsque le temps entre les traitements et l'infection était augmenté. Une efficacité de lutte biologique considérablement réduite a été détectée lorsque les traitements bactériens ont été appliqués 24 heures avant l'infection (par rapport à 2 et 18 heures) et ce, à partir de mesures prises après sept jours seulement (pas dix). Intégrer l'utilisation d'antagonistes bactériens dans les stratégies de gestion de mildiou peut se révéler comme un complément efficace aux méthodes de prévention actuelles et aider à freiner l'usage intensif de fongicides synthétiques dans la production de pommes de terre.</description><creator>Foran, Nicholas</creator><contributor>Valérie Gravel (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Plant Science</subject><title>Bacterial antagonists as a biological solution for control of potato late blight disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225d78w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wm98h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:12579w00k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:53:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>RÉSUMÉLa texture du sol et la teneur en matière organique sont des indicateurs importants de la qualité et de la santé du sol. Ils affectent un grand nombre de propriétés et de procédés du sol, plus précisément ils sont essentiels dans les secteurs de l'agriculture et du génie civil. En considérant ces derniers attributes, plusieurs processus traditionnels et techniques de prises de mesures avancées ont pour but de les quantifier. Toutefois, leurs coûts, leurs temps, les méthodes d'analyse sophistiquées et inadaptable en pratique in situ posent un défi majeur à la mesure rapide. Cette recherche révèle la conception et le développement d'un système de traitement d'image qui prédit la texture du sol et la quantité de matière organique présente. Cette recherche a été conçue de deux manières différentes sur l'espace de deux ans. Les deux méthodes de résolution ont été faites à base des algorithmes. Pour le premier procédé, des images d'échantillons de sols séchés à l'air en provenance du terrain 26 de la ferme du campus Macdonald ont été utilisées (datant de l'année 2014, sol organique) . La base de données d'images a été analysée afin de reconnaître le contenu de sable et de matière organique du sol. Ceci a été possible en appliquant l'analyse des données géospatiales tout en validant avec les données obtenues par méthode conventionnelle en laboratoire. Des relations prédictives ont été développées par des simples régressions linéaires établies sur le contenu de sable et de matière organique du sol. Ceci a été possible en utilisant différents paramètres calculés de l'imagerie acquise tels que la teinte, la saturation, la valeur, la porosité et les estimés de variance. Les modèles de prédictions pour le contenu de sable et matière organique obtiennent des coefficients de déterminations (R2) de 0.63 et 0.83. Tout cela avec une racine carrée du précédent (RMSE) de 84.7 g/kg  pour le contenu de sable et 0.11 log sur le marché boursier. En addition de la première base de données d'images, la deuxième expérience a exploré à la fois les données prises en laboratoire ainsi que les mesures prises in-situ du terrain 86. (datant de l'année 2014, sol minéral) Ce procédé a utilisé la transformée en ondelettes continue pour caractérisé le contenu de sable. Cette méthode confirme avec les données du laboratoire ( r2 = - 0.86  et  RMSE = - 44.7 g/kg pour le sol organique, r2 = - 0.87 ; RMSE =  - 40.2 g/kg pour le sol minéral). Cependant, l'efficacité de cet algorithme pour les images in-situ était bien moins précise ( r2 = – 0.48 ; et RMSE - 80.6 g/kg). Ceci était dû à la grande quantité d'eau présente dans le sol et pourrait être effectué avec des modifications au support pour le microscope et au protocol.  La mobilité du système d'acquisition d'images et de la bonne performance de l'algorithme d'ondelettes sont prometteuses pour l'utilisation future du système développé pour quantifier rapidement les principaux attributs physique du sol. </description><description>ABSTRACTSoil texture and organic matter content are important indicators of the quality and health of soil. They affect a range of soil properties and processes, which are fundamental for agriculture and civil engineering. Several traditional methods and advanced measurement techniques aim to address the challenge of quantifying these attributes. However, their cost, time requirements, sophisticated analytical methods and in-situ inapplicability pose a major challenge to rapid measurement. This research discloses the development of a new, inexpensive, microscope-based sensor system to estimate content of both sand and organic matter. The research was divided into two experiments conducted over a span of two years, each approaching the problem from two different computational perspectives. The first experiment involved images of air dried soil samples from Field 26 (acquired in 2014, organic soil) of the Macdonald Campus Farm of McGill University. The set of images was analyzed for sand and organic matter content using color and spatial image analysis, then validated against data obtained using conventional methods in a laboratory. Predictive relationships were developed using simple linear regressions based on parameters computed from the acquired imagery, such as hue, saturation, value, porosity, and variance estimates. The best sand and organic matter prediction models exhibited coefficients of determination (R2) values of 0.63 and 0.83, respectively, with RMSE = 84.7 g/kg for sand content and 0.11 for log SOM. In addition to the first set of images, the second experiment explored both laboratory and in situ measurements from Field 86 (acquired in 2015, mineral soil). This method used a continuous wavelet transform to characterize sand content which was in strong agreement with the laboratory measurements (r2 = 0.86 and RMSE = 44.7 g/kg for organic soil; r2 = 0.87 and RMSE = 40.2 g/kg for mineral soil). However, the efficiency of this algorithm was subpar for the images collected in-situ (r2 = 0.48 and RMSE = 80.6 g/kg). This was due to the excessive soil water content, which can be addressed by modifying the microscope holder design and data collection protocol. The portable nature of the image acquisition system and the good performance of the wavelet algorithm shows promise for the future use of the system to rapidly quantify key soil physical attributes. </description><creator>Sudarsan, Bharath</creator><contributor>Viacheslav Adamchuk (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Bioresource Engineering</subject><title>Assessment of soil properties using microscope based computer vision</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nd87r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579w00k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv9355670</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:53:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The leishmaniases are a group of sand fly-transmitted diseases caused by various species of the protozoan parasite, Leishmania. With an annual incidence of over 1 million in tropical and subtropical regions of the world, some 300 million people living in Leishmania-endemic regions, and over 20,000 deaths each year, leishmaniasis is a major global public health concern. Phlebotomine sand flies are well-known as the vectors of Leishmania, but they are also the vectors of various phleboviruses, including Sand fly Fever Sicilian Virus (SFSV).Cutaneous leishmaniasis (CL), caused by Leishmania major (L. major), amongst other species, results in development of skin lesions on the infected host. Importantly, there exists much variation in CL pathology between individuals. We propose that phleboviruses, vectored by and found in the same sand fly guts as Leishmania, may be a factor in determining CL severity. We hypothesized that upon taking a blood meal, the sand fly vector infects the host with Leishmania parasites as well as phleboviruses, and this viral coinfection will result in a modulation of leishmaniasis. In macrophages, we observed that SFSV modulates MAP kinase signaling, as well as activity in the IRF3 pathway, and results in a proinflammatory phenotype. We also found that SFSV and L. major coinfection resulted in an exacerbation of leishmaniasis in vivo, and by using endosomal TLR knock-out, in addition to MAVS knock-out mice, deduced that SFSV's hyperinflammatory effect was TLR3- and RIG-I-dependent. Critically, we observed that L. major-infected C57BL/6 mice coinfected with SFSV suffered from significantly higher parasite burden than C57BL/6 mice solely infected with L. major. Overall our work represents novel and critical findings towards understanding the causal mechanisms governing CL cutaneous leishmaniasis pathology.  </description><description>Les protozoaires parasitaires du genre Leishmania sont les agents étiologiques des leishmanioses. Les leishmanioses forment un problème important de santé mondiale : 300 millions personnes vivent dans des régions où les parasites Leishmania sont endémiques, et chaque année, plus d'un million de personnes tombent malade et au moins 20 000 en meurent. Les mouches phlébotomes sont connues comme étant des vecteurs de Leishmania, mais ces insectes sont aussi responsables de la transmission des virus du genre Phlebovirus, dont le virus sicilien de la fièvre à phlébotomes (SFSV). La leishmaniose cutanée (LC), principalement provoquée par Leishmania major (L.major), est une infection cutanée caractérisée par des lésions enflammées. Il existe cependant une grande variation des pathologies parmi les différents individus souffrant de LC. Nous proposons ici que les virus du genre Phlebovirus, qui sont transmis par et trouvés dans les mêmes intestins que les parasites Leishmania, peuvent être un facteur déterminant de la sévérité de la leishmaniose cutanée. Nous avons formulé l'hypothèse que lorsqu'un phlébotome pique une personne, la mouche transmet les parasites Leishmania ainsi que les virus des fièvres à phlébotomes dans le sang de l'hôte; cette co-infection mène à une modification de la LC.   Nous avons observé que dans les macrophages le SFSV peut entraîner un état pro-inflammatoire par des changements de la signalisation intracellulaire des MAPKs et aussi de l'activité de voie signalisation d'IRF3. Nous avons également trouvé que la co-infection SFSV et L. major résultait en une exacerbation de la LC in vivo. De plus, en utilisant des souris knock-out pour les TLRs endosomaux et les MAVS nous avons pu déduire que l'effet hyper inflammatoire était dépendant de TLR3 et de la signalisation intracellulaire de RIG-I. Nous avons de plus remarqué que les souris co-infectées avec L. major et VFPS souffraient d'une charge parasitaire plus élevée que les souris infectées uniquement avec L. major. Ainsi, les travaux présentés dans ce mémoire permettent une meilleure compréhension des mécanismes gouvernants la pathologie de la leishmaniose cutanée. </description><creator>MacLean, Emily</creator><contributor>Martin Olivier (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Microbiology &amp; Immunology</subject><title>Modulation of cutaneous leishmaniasis by sand fly fever Sicilian virus coinfection</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773z41q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv9355670</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859j33d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:54:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Des mutations dans les gènes codant PINK1 et Parkin causent une forme récessive autosomale de la maladie de Parkinson. PINK1 est une kinase de protéine, bien connu pour son rôle dans la signalisation de dommages mitochondriaux et conséquemment l'initiation de mécanismes de réparations par autophagie. PINK1 s'accumule sur la membrane externe des mitochondries (MEM) endommagées, et ensuite recrute la ligase d'ubiquitine Parkin via son activité kinase. Dès lors, Parkin ubiquitine de nombreuses protéines de la MEM, ce qui entraine la destruction autophagique de ces mitochondries. Au cours des cinq dernières années, les mécanismes de recrutement et d'activation de Parkin dans le contexte de l'activité kinase de PINK1 furent l'objet de plusieurs études. Ces études ont convergées sur un modèle où PINK1 phosphoryle Parkin (dans son domaine similaire à l'ubiquitine) et l'ubiquitine sur Ser65, résultant dans l'activation complète de Parkin. Ceci fait donc de PINK1 la première kinase d'ubiquitine connue. Hors, les mécanismes moléculaires de l'activation de Parkin reste énigmatiques. Dans cette thèse, j'ai développé un système de production de PINK1 pour caractériser la cinétique de phosphorylation de Parkin et de l'ubiquitine, ainsi que pour déterminer les conséquences sur l'activation de Parkin. Après optimisation, j'ai découvert que l'orthologue de PINK1 dérivée de l'insecte Tribolium castaneum (TcPINK1) exprime bien dans E. coli, se purifie en solution, et produit une kinase active. Cette PINK1 recombinante fut essentielle afin d'élucider le rôle de l'ubiquitine phosphorylée (pUb) dans la stimulation de la phosphorylation de Parkin par PINK1, établissant donc le rôle de pUb dans la voie de contrôle de qualité des mitochondries. Des expériences de résonance magnétique nucléaire et des essais de phosphorylation couplés à de la mutagénèse ont révélés les acides aminés dans Parkin qui sont essentielles pour son interaction avec PINK1. Ces travaux préparent le terrain pour des études plus approfondies sur les attributs structuraux de PINK1 qui lui permettent de reconnaitre le domaine ubiquitine et de phosphoryler spécifiquement la Ser65.</description><description>Mutations in the PINK1- and Parkin-encoding genes cause autosomal recessive form of Parkinson's disease. PINK1 is a protein kinase, best known for its role in signaling mitochondrial damage and consequently initiating mitochondrial repair or autophagy mechanisms. Upon mitochondrial damage, PINK1 accumulates on the outer membrane (OMM) of the mitochondria, and recruits the E3 ubiquitin ligase Parkin in a kinase activity-dependent fashion. Parkin then ubiquitinates multiple OMM proteins and signals mitochondria for autophagic destruction. In recent years, the mechanism for Parkin's recruitment and activation has been a subject of extensive study in the context of PINK1's kinase activity. The most recent evidence suggests that the role of PINK1 is to phosphorylate both Parkin (on its ubiquitin-like domain) and ubiquitin on Ser65 for a complete activation of Parkin. This makes PINK1 the first known ubiquitin kinase. However the underlying molecular mechanisms underlying Parkin's activation are unknown. Here, I have developed a PINK1 production system to characterize the kinetics of Parkin and ubiquitin phosphorylation and its consequences for the activation of Parkin. After optimization, I found that the PINK1 ortholog from the insect species Tribolium castaneum (TcPINK1) expresses well in E. coli, can be purified in solution, and produces an active kinase. This recombinant PINK1 was essential to elucidate the role of phosphorylated ubiquitin (pUb) as an enhancer for Parkin phosphorylation by PINK1, hence establishing a role of pUb in the mitochondrial quality control pathway. Nuclear magnetic resonance studies and phosphorylation assays combined with mutagenesis reveal the residues in Parkin that are critical for the interactions with PINK1. This work sets the stage for more detailed investigations of the structural features of PINK1 that allow the enzyme to recognize ubiquitin domains and phosphorylate specifically Ser65. </description><creator>Rasool, Shafqat</creator><contributor>Kalle Burgess Gehring (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Jean Francois Trempe (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Biochemistry</subject><title>Characterization of the ubiquitin kinase activity of PINK1</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88ck28n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859j33d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75rb59x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:54:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>  Despite concerns regarding the oral health of rural Canadians, estimates of oral health-related quality of life do not exist in published provincial data. The objective of this population-based cross-sectional study was to estimate rural-urban differences in oral health-related quality of life (OHRQoL). Using Andersen's behavioral model for health services utilization as the conceptual framework, data from 1,788 parents/caregivers of schoolchildren from 8 regions of Quebec, Canada were collected through the employment of a two-stage sampling technique. Place of residency was defined according to Statistics Canada's Census Metropolitan Area and Census Agglomeration Influenced Zone classification. The outcome of interest was OHRQoL, measured using a validated Oral Health Impact Profile-14 (OHIP-14) questionnaire. The prevalence, extent and severity of negative oral health impacts were calculated after applying data heightening.  Descriptive statistics, bivariate analyses and binary logistic regressions were performed using SPSS version 22. Our results showed that residents of rural areas had poorer oral health-related quality of life than those living in urban zones (P=0.02). Rural residents reported higher negative daily-life impacts in pain, psychological discomfort and social disability OHIP-14 domains (P&lt;0.05). Additionally, there was a statistically significant difference between rural and urban populations in the extent of negative oral health impacts (P=0.03). However, the difference in severity of poor oral health was not statistically significant for the two population groups. Logistic regression indicated that factors such as the place of residency (OR=1.6; 95%CI=1.1-2.5; P=0.022), perceived oral health (OR=9.4; 95%CI= 5.7-15.5; P&lt;0.001), dental treatment needs factors (perceived need for dental treatment, pain, dental care seeking) (OR=8.7; 95%CI=4.8-15.6; P&lt;0.001) and education (OR=2.7; 95%CI=1.8-3.9; P&lt;0.001) significantly affect OHRQoL. Based on these findings, we conclude that there is a rural-urban difference in OHRQoL in Quebec, Canada. Policies focusing on oral health promotion, educational interventions and tailored need-based programs are necessary to improve the OHRQoL of vulnerable populations. </description><description>Malgré les inquiétudes au sujet de la santé buccodentaire des Canadiens résidant dans les régions rurales, il n'existe pas de données provinciales publiées sur les mesures de la qualité de vie  reliée à la santé buccodentaire (OHRQoL). L'objectif de cette étude populationnelle transversale est d'estimer les différences rurales-urbaines en ce qui a trait à l'OHRQoL. La collecte des données a eu lieu en se basant sur le modèle comportemental d'Andersen de l'utilisation des services de santé. Au total, 1,788 parents/tuteurs légaux des écoliers des 8 régions de Québec, Canada ont été sélectionnés suivant un plan d'échantillonnage complexe à deux étapes. Les lieux de résidence ont été établis selon la définition de Statistiques Canada, soit en considérant le code postal et les zones d'influence des régions métropolitaines de recensement et des agglomérations de recensement (ZIM). L'indicateur de qualité de vie reliée à la santé buccodentaires a été évalué à l'aide d'un questionnaire d'Oral Health Impact Profile (OHIP-14) validé au préalable. La prévalence, l'étendue et la sévérité des impacts négatifs sur la santé buccodentaire ont été calculées après pondération des données. Des statistiques descriptives, analytiques bivariées ainsi qu'une régression logistique binaire ont été réalisées par le logiciel SPSS-version 22.  Nos résultats ont montré que les personnes vivant en régions rurales ont une qualité de vie reliée à la santé bucco-dentaire plus mauvaise que celles vivant en région urbaine (p=0.02). Les résidents dans les zones rurales ont signalé des effets négatifs d'une mauvaise santé buccodentaire plus graves spécialement au niveau de la douleur, l'inconfort psychologique et le dysfonctionnement social  (P&lt;0.05). En plus, la différence quant à l'ampleur de l'impact négatif d'une mauvaise santé bucco-dentaire entre les parents des régions rurales ou urbaines a été statistiquement significative (p=0.03). Cependant, la différence au niveau de degré de sévérité de la mauvaise santé buccodentaire entre les deux groupes à l'étude n'a pas été significative. La régression logistique a indiqué que des facteurs tels que le lieu de résidence (OR=1.6; IC à 95% =1.1 à 2.5; P=0.022), la perception de la santé buccodentaire  (OR=9.4; IC à 95%=5.7 à 15.5; P&lt;0.001), les besoins en services dentaires (perception des besoins de soins en santé buccodentaires, la douleur, le recours aux soins dentaires) (OR=8.7; IC à 95%=4.8 à 15.6; P&lt;0.001) et l'éducation (OR=2.7; IC à 95%=1.8 à 3.9; P&lt;0.001) affectent d'une manière significative l'OHRQoL. Ces résultats nous permettent de conclure qu'il existe une disparité rurale-urbaine en ce qui concerne la qualité de vie reliée à la santé buccodentaire au Québec. D'où la nécessité de développer des politiques de promotion de la santé buccodentaire. La mise en place des interventions d'éducation populationnelle basées sur les besoins des personnes vulnérables s'avère crutiale pour améliorer leur OHRQoL. </description><creator>Gaber, Amal</creator><contributor>Jocelyne Feine (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Elham Emami (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Dentistry</subject><title>Rural-urban differences in oral health-related quality of life</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53wz509.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75rb59x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v559g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:54:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Contexte: Les personnes ayant des problèmes de santé mentale ont de nombreux besoins de support qui sont souvent remplis de manière inadéquate. Les jeunes avec un premier épisode psychotique (PEP) représentent un groupe avec des besoins particulièrement grands de soutien. Bien que différentes parties prenantes sont actuellement impliquées dans le soutien des personnes ayant des problèmes de santé mentale, les perceptions de qui devrait être responsable de répondre aux différents besoins de ces personnes restent inexplorées. Ceci est un manque important dans les connaissances, puisque des perceptions variées entre les différentes parties prenantes pourraient être la cause des besoins non satisfaits en matière de soutien. Objectifs: Les objectifs des études suivantes ont été (1) de découvrir ce qui est connu sur les perceptions du lieu de la responsabilité pour soutenir les personnes ayant des problèmes de santé mentale, quels facteurs façonnent ces perceptions, et comment ces facteurs sont liés les uns aux autres; et (2) d'explorer les perceptions des différents acteurs clés sur qui détient la responsabilité de soutenir les personnes ayant des problèmes de santé mentale. Méthodes: Une revue critique de la littérature a été réalisée, dans laquelle les contributions conceptuelles et les limites de travaux pertinents ont été évaluées de façon critique et une carte conceptuelle a été créé. Une étude descriptive qualitative a ensuite été entreprise. Des groupes de discussion ont été menés auprès de patients avec PEP, leurs familles, et les fournisseurs de soins et des entretiens individuels ont été menés avec les preneurs de décisions sur les politiques en santé mentale. Les transcriptions ont été analysées thématiquement. Résultats: La revue critique a identifié des concepts saillants de la littérature sur les attitudes du public envers l'État-providence et les vues de la responsabilité individuelle versus gouvernementale de répondre aux besoins et en matière de santé; les obligations interpersonnelles/l'éthique du "care"; et les attributions de responsabilité pour la maladie mentale. Un cadre conceptuel a été construit à partir de ces résultats. L'étude qualitative a révélé que les personnes ayant eux-mêmes des problèmes de santé mentale; les parties prenantes dans les réseaux sociaux immédiats et extérieurs de ces personnes; les parties prenantes avec de l'influence au niveau macro; et la société dans son ensemble ont été perçus comme ayant un large éventail de responsabilités dans le support aux personnes ayant des problèmes de santé mentale. Les thèmes relatifs à la structure et à la nature des rôles et des responsabilités ont également été identifiés. Discussion: La revue critique et la carte conceptuelle résultante ont mis en lumière les différents facteurs qui peuvent façonner les perceptions au sujet du lieu de responsabilité à soutenir les personnes ayant des problèmes de santé mentale, alors que l'étude qualitative a révélé que les intervenants clés attribuent un large éventail de rôles et de responsabilités aux différentes parties prenantes. Ensemble, ces études comblent un vide important de connaissances sur les perceptions de qui devrait être responsable de soutenir les personnes ayant des problèmes de santé mentale, et les résultats ont des implications importantes pour les pratiques de santé mentale, les politiques et la recherche.</description><description>Background: Individuals with mental health problems have many support needs that are often inadequately met. Youth with first-episode psychosis (FEP) represent a group with particularly great needs for support. While various parties are currently involved in supporting persons with mental health problems, perceptions of who should be responsible for meeting the various needs of these individuals remain unexplored. This is an important knowledge gap, as varying perceptions among different stakeholders could be the cause of unmet needs for support. Objectives: The objectives of the following studies were (1) to discover what is known about perceptions of locus of responsibility for supporting individuals with mental health problems, what factors shape these perceptions, and how these factors relate to one another; and (2) to explore various key stakeholders' perceptions of who should be responsible for supporting individuals with mental health problems. Methods: A critical literature review was conducted, in which the conceptual contributions and limitations of relevant works were critically evaluated and a concept map was created. A qualitative descriptive study was then undertaken. Focus groups were conducted with FEP patients, their families, and treatment providers and individual interviews were conducted with mental health policy/decision makers. Transcripts were analyzed thematically. Results: The critical review identified salient concepts from literature on public attitudes towards the welfare state and views of individual versus governmental responsibility for need provision and health; the morality of caring; and attributions of responsibility for mental illness. A conceptual framework was built from these findings. The qualitative study revealed that individuals with mental health problems themselves; stakeholders in the immediate and extended social networks of these individuals; macro-level stakeholders with influence; and society as a whole were perceived to have a wide range of responsibilities for supporting persons with mental health problems. Themes relating to the structure and nature of roles and responsibilities were also identified. Discussion: The critical review and resulting concept map have shed light on the different factors that may shape perceptions about locus of responsibility for supporting individuals with mental health problems, while the qualitative study has revealed that key stakeholders ascribe a wide range of roles and responsibilities to various parties. Together, these studies fill a large knowledge gap about perceptions of who should be responsible for supporting individuals with mental health problems, and the findings have significant implications for mental health practices, policies, and research.</description><creator>Pope, Megan</creator><contributor>Srividya Iyer (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Ashok Malla (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Psychiatry</subject><title>Who should be responsible for supporting individuals with mental health problems? perceptions of multiple stakeholders</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zr31v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v559g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65vb38x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:54:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'industrie horticulturale a démontré un intérêt marqué pour remplacer l'utilisation de matériaux non-renouvelables, entre autres les substrats de croissance à base de tourbe, par des solutions et matériaux s'inscrivant dans le mouvement du développement durable. Le biochar ainsi que la zeolite sont des matériaux renouvelables qui ont attiré beaucoup d'intérêt dans les dernières années. La capacité de ces deux matériaux, lorsqu'utilisés comme amendements dans le sol ou substrat, dans le but d'accélérer la croissance et améliorer la qualité des plantes a été démontrée dans de multiples études (Kolar et al., 2010; Yao et al., 2013 and Lija et al., 2014). Cependant, d'autre études (Huang et al., 2013) ont démontré que le biochar et la zeolite n'ont pas d'impact positif sans application de fertilisant. De plus, la littérature concernant la combinaison de biochar et de zeolite est limitée. Par conséquent, nous avons voulu investiguer l'utilisation de biochar et de zeolite pré-chargés en fertilisant (NPK) comme amendement de substrat artificiel dans le but de diminuer l'impact environnementale de la production en serre. Nous avons donc émis l'hypothèse que le biochar et la zeolite pré-chargé en NPK peut libérer des éléments nutritifs et agir comme un fertilisant à libération lente (FLL). De plus, la combinaison de biochar et zeolite pré-chargés devrait augmenter le rendement ainsi que la qualité des plantes suivant l'application de faibles doses. Deux espèces de plantes à croissance rapide, le basilic (Ocimum basilicum L.) et l'épinard (Spinacia oleracea L.), ont été sélectionnées pour ce projet. Le biochar et la zeolite pré-chargés en NPK augmentent de façon significative la croissance des jeunes plantes et l'accumulation d'azote (N) dans les plantes, sans avoir un effet sur la germination des semis. Cependant, en comparaison avec les amendements non-chargés en NPK, les amendements chargés réduisent la quantité de P chez le basilic ce qui entraine une diminution du poids des plants. Le choix du ratio de biochar et zeolite n'était pas un facteur significatif sur la croissance des plantes, par contre, l'addition des amendements ont augmenté la croissance des plantes comparés aux contrôles. En addition, un effet allant de neutre a positif sur la croissance du basilic suivant l'application de faibles quantités de biochar (5%) et de zeolite (10%) a été observé. Une augmentation des niveaux d'acide oxalique et de sucres ont été observé dans le basilic grandi dans les amendements, ce qui suggère que les amendements stressent le basilic. Ce projet a démontré de façon claire que le biochar et la zeolite pré-chargés en NPK et utilisés comme amendements pour substrat à faible dose pourraient servir de FLL et effectivement remplacer des FLL commerciaux et les substrats à base de tourbe. Cependant, la balance nutritive et le taux de libération doivent être ajustés et surveillés selon les besoins spécifiques de chaque espèce de plante.</description><description>Growing global awareness of the importance of sustainability and knowledge of the environmental impacts of the non-renewable materials in the horticultural industry are leading to ongoing research to discover viable alternatives. In recent years, biochar and zeolite have drawn significant attention, and have been proven to have many benefits in promoting plant growth and quality (Kolar et al., 2010; Yao et al., 2013 and Lija et al., 2014). However, some studies have questioned the positive impact without additional fertilizer application (Huang et al., 2013). Moreover, studies on the effects of biochar and zeolite when used in combination have been limited. Therefore, we proposed the use of nitrogen-phosphorous-potassium (NPK) pre-charged biochar and zeolite as soilless substrate amendments in order to increase greenhouse production sustainability. We hypothesized that NPK pre-charged biochar and zeolite could release plant nutrients in biologically available forms, and effectively act as a slow release fertilizer (SRF). The combination of charged biochar and zeolite was expected to increase crop yield and promote a better crop quality at low levels of application. Two relatively fast growing plants, Sweet basil (Ocimum basilicum L.) and Tyee spinach (Spinacia oleracea L.) were selected for this study. Seed germination was not affected by any factors. NPK charging had a neutral to positive effect on seedling growth of both species, as well as on mature spinach plants. In addition, plant nitrogen accumulation was significantly improved by NPK charging. However, its effect on basil plants and plant phosphorus accumulation was negative to natural. The choice of amendment ratio was not a significant factor on altering all seedlings and spinach plants growth, but amended substrate had neutral to positive impacts when compared to the control. In the plant stage, substrate amended with less biochar supported the best basil growth. A minor abiotic stress on spinach may was caused by amendments, as showed by increases in oxalic acid and sugar content on leaves and reduction in shoot phosphorus content. This research clearly demonstrates that NPK charged biochar, when used in combination with zeolite, could be used as a SRF to replace commercial product and as a substrate amendment to partially replace peat-based medium. According to the specific crop needs, for better Tyee spinach plant growth, substrate amended with 22.5% charged biochar and 20% charged zeolite is recommended; however, it is only suggested to use 5% charged biochar in paired with 10% charged zeolite for better basil growth and quality.</description><creator>Huang, Xiaoling</creator><contributor>Valérie Gravel (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Suha Jabaji (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Plant Science</subject><title>Pre-charged biochar and zeolite as soilless substrate amendments and slow release fertilizers: effects on basil and spinach quality</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f4047.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65vb38x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mq16z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:54:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le cancer colorectal (CCR) est la deuxième cause la plus importante de mortalité dérivée du cancer en Amérique du Nord. La mort causée par le CCR peut être attribuée à la métastase du cancer. Le site le plus fréquent de métastase éloignée de l'origine du CCR est le foie. Si cela est possible, la chirurgie donne la seule occasion de traitement pour les patients avec des métastases hépatiques du cancer colorectal (MHCCR). Les soins administrés après résection ainsi que le choix de chimiothérapie adjuvante dépendent de l'évaluation  pathologique du grade de la tumeur. Plusieurs méthodes d'évaluation histopathologique ont été dévelopées, mais leurs corrélations avec les résultats des patients sont variables. Jusqu'à date, le « Tumor Regression Grade » (TRG) avait la plus forte corrélation avec les résultats des patients. Celui-ci marque les lésions selon la proportion de fibrose sur la somme de tumeurs viables et de nécrose. Pourtant, l'usage répandu d'agents anti-angiogéniques qui causent la nécrose lors de la période préopératoire a poussé le TRG à évoluer en TRG modifié (mTRG). Le mTRG différencie entre deux types de nécrose qui ont des rôles prognostiques différents : la Nécrose Commune (NC) et la Necrose qui ressemble à une infarctus (ILN). De plus, les évaluations pathologiques restent quand-même limitées par leur nature subjective. Le projet présenté dans ce mémoire décrit l'utilisation de l'imagerie de spectroscopie de masse (ISM) par Désorption/Ionisation Laser assistée par Matrice (MALDI) afin de définir les signatures lipidiques signatures pour des topographies différentes. Nous avons initialement appliqué une approche histologique semi-supervisée afin de construire notre banque spectrale par une méthode automatique de classification (k-means) et des corrélations histologiques visuelles directes (panneau de 5 couleurs) sur une série d'échantillons préparatoire (n=12). Nous avons identifié six signatures lipidiques qui sont mises en corrélation par histologie et puis, nous les avons exploitées afin de découvrir des marqueurs lipidiques discriminants. Nous avons utilisé la méthode d'analyse « Partial Least Squares-Discriminant » (PLS-DA) afin de mettre en place notre banque spectrale sur une cohorte de validation indépendante de 40 patients. De plus, en analysant les signatures lipidiques, nous avons identifié des fractions lipidiques uniques distinguant les NC et les ILN, qui peuvent potentiellement être utilisées comme biomarqueurs pour évaluer la réaction au  traitement. En utilisant ces signatures et marqueurs lipidiques, nous avons obtenu  un score de mTRG quantifié par histologie et objectif. </description><description>Colorectal Cancer (CRC) is the second leading cause of cancer mortality in North America. Death from CRC is largely due to metastatic disease and the liver is the most common site of distant metastasis. Surgery when feasible carries the only chance of cure for Colorectal Cancer Liver Metastasis (CRCLM) patients. Post surgical resection further patient management and choice of adjuvant chemotherapy relies on pathological assessment of tumor grade. Multiple histopathologic assessment methods have been developed with variable correlation with patients' outcome. Until recently the Tumor Regression Grade (TRG) had the strongest correlation with patients' outcome. It scores lesions according to the ratio of fibrosis against the sum of viable tumor and necrosis. However with the widespread use of anti-angiogenic agents that causes necrosis as a form of response in the preoperative setting the modified Tumor Regression Grade (mTRG) evolved. It differentiates between two types of necrosis with different prognostic roles, Usual Necrosis (UN) and Infarct-Like Necrosis (ILN). Nonetheless pathological evaluation remains limited by its subjective nature. Our works describes the use of Matrix Assisted Laser Desorption and Ionization (MALDI) imaging mass spectrometry (IMS) to generate lipid signatures for different topographies.  To do so we initially applied a semi-supervised histology driven approach to build our spectral library using an automated clustering method (k-means) and direct visual histological correlations (5-stain panel) on a training set (n=12). We identified six histologically correlated lipid signatures and further mined them for discriminate lipid markers. We used partial Least Squares-Discriminant Analysis (PLS-DA) to implement our spectral library on an independent validation cohort (n=40). Additionally, by dissecting out the lipid signatures we have identified single lipid moieties that are unique to UN and ILN that could potentially be used as new biomarkers for assessing response to therapy. Using these signatures and lipid markers we obtained a histologically quantitative and objective mTRG score. </description><creator>Alabdulkarim, Balqis</creator><contributor>Peter Metrakos (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Pathology</subject><title>Imaging mass spectrometry application in colorectal cancer liver metastasis pathological evaluation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bm068.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mq16z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fb494c00r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:54:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Testicular cancer is currently the most common cancer affecting men of reproductive age. The coadministration of bleomycin, etoposide, and cisplatin (BEP) subsequent to orchidectomy, has increased the cure rate of these patients to over 90%. However, as these patients are between the ages of 15-35 years, many of whom have not yet started a family of their own, emphasis has been put on the effect of BEP on fertility. The effect of this treatment on reproductive chemotoxicity and progeny outcome has been established. Of particular importance was the persistent effect of BEP treatment on chromatin compaction in mature spermatozoa. With evidence suggesting the involvement of epigenetic histone marks as a BEP target, we sought to elucidate a mechanism of BEP-induced effect on chromatin remodeling in male germ cells. Immunohistochemical analysis demonstrated the basal expression of transcription activating or repressive epigenetic histone marks in spermatogenesis. Western blot and confocal microscopy analyses demonstrated that BEP treatment altered the expression of histone H4 acetylated on lysines 8 and 12, and histone H3 monomethylated on lysine 9 (H3K9m) in a cell-type and stage-specific manner. We propose that this leads to three major consequences: (1) chromatin compaction in pachytene spermatocytes to prevent transcription of key post-meiotic genes important in chromatin remodeling, (2) chromatin stabilization in round spermatids such that histones are not removed and replaced with testis-specific variants, and (3) failure for testis-specific bromodomain (BRDT) protein to remove histone H4 in elongating spermatids, thereby preventing transition proteins (TPs) and protamine 1 (PRM1) binding. The resulting incompacted sperm chromatin can have an adverse effect on male fertility, with alterations to the sperm epigenome potentially having a negative impact on progeny outcome. </description><description>Le cancer du testicule est actuellement le plus courant chez les hommes en âge de procréer. L'administration en association de bléomycine, etoposide et cisplatine (BEP) à la suite d'une orchidectomie a fait passer le taux de guérison de ces patients au delà de 90%. Ce traitement n'est cependant pas sans effet sur la fertilité des patients, dont beaucoup, âgés de 15 à 35 ans, n'ont pas encore fondé de famille. En effet, la toxicité de ce traitement chimiothérapique sur la fonction reproductive et la descendance a été établie. Parmi les effets secondaires observés, l'altération persistante de la compaction de la chromatine spermatique revêt une importance particulière. De récentes données suggérant l'implication du BEP dans la modification de marques épigénétiques apposées aux histones nous ont conduit à explorer les effets du BEP dans le remodelage de la chromatine des cellules germinales mâles. Nous avons tout d'abord étudié l'expression basale de marques épigénétiques activatrices et inhibitrices de la transcription au cours de la spermatogenèse à l'aide de marquages immunohistochimiques. La combinaison d'immunobuvardages et d'analyses en microscopie confocale nous ont ensuite permis de démontrer une altération de l'expression de l'histone H4 acétylé aux résidus lysine 8 et 12 (H4K8 et H4K12) et de l'histone H3 monométhylé au résidu lysine 9 (H3K9m) dépendamment du type cellulaire et du stade de la spermatogenèse. Nous émettons l'hypothèse que ces modifications ont trois conséquences majeures : (i) la compaction de la chromatine dans les spermatocytes pachytènes, prévenant la transcription de gènes clés dans le remodelage de la chromatine ; (ii) la stabilisation de la chromatine dans les spermatides rondes, prévenant le retrait des histones et leur remplacement par des histones spécifiques au testicule ; (iii) l'impossibilité pour la protéine à bromodomaines spécifique au testicule, BRDT, d'ôter les histones H4 dans les spermatides allongées, empêchant le rattachement de les protéines de transition (TPs) et la protamine 1 (PRM1). Ainsi, l'altération de la compaction de la chromatine pourrait produire des effets négatifs sur la fertilité des hommes traités au BEP, et la modification de l'épigénome spermatique avoir un impact négatif sur la progéniture de ces derniers.</description><creator>Bagheri-Sereshki, Negar</creator><contributor>Bernard Robaire (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Pharmacology &amp; Therapeutics</subject><title>The effect of chemotherapeutic agents, bleomycin, etoposide, and cisplatin on chromatin remodeling in male germ cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zd945.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494c00r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967644s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:54:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Integer least squares (ILS) is an important class of optimization problems, which can arise in many applications, such as communications, cryptography and cryptanalysis and global navigation satellite systems. This thesis is concerned with solving the underdetermined box constrained ILS (UBILS) problems. For the two existing algorithms, the direct tree search (DTS) algorithm and the partial regularization (PR) algorithm, we propose to incorporate some lower bounds to speed up the search process. Simulation results show that the proposed lower bounds can make the search process of the DTS algorithm perform more efficiently than the original one. Then we propose a modified DTS algorithm by partially using a best-first search strategy in the search process. Numerical tests results indicate that the new search algorithm is very effective in improving the efficiency of the DTS algorithm with or without incorporating the proposed lower bounds.</description><description>Les moindres carrés en nombres entiers (ILS) est une méthode d'optimisation des problèmes,  qui  peut être  appliqué  dans  beaucoup  de  domaines,  comme  la  communication,  la  cryptographie  et  la  cryptanalyse  les  systèmes  de  navigation  mondiaux par  satellite.   Dans  cette  thèse,  on  étudiera  trois  types  de  problèmes  concernant  les moindres carrés en nombres entiers:  les problèmes de moindres carrés en nombre entiers classiques (OILS), les problèmes hyperdéterminés (OBILS) et hypodéterminés (UBILS) avec les contraintes de boites.  Dans un premier temps, on va faire un rappel de dedirents algorithmes pour résoudre ces trois types de problèmes, suivi par une présentation dedirents  minorations  afin  d'augmenter  l'efficacité  du  processus  de  recherche.   Pour les  deux  algorithmes  existants  l'algorithme  de  recherche  en  arbre  directe (DTS)  et l'algorithme  de  régularisation  partielle  (RP),  on  va  proposer  les  minorations  correspondantes  afin  d'accélérer  le  processus  de  recherche.   On  montrera  les  résultats  de simulation qui justifient que les minorations qu'on propose peut faire le processus de recherche par l'algorithme de recherche en arbre directe plus performante que la méthode classique.  Puis,  on va proposer un nouveau algorithme de recherche pour résoudre les problèmes UBILS, qui est en fait une modification directe sur l'algorithme de  recherche  en  arbre  directe  en  utilsant  la  stratégie  de  recherche  le  meilleur  en premier (best-first)  dans  le  processus  de  recherche.   Les  résultats  de  test  numérique montrera que le nouvel algorithme de recherche est plus efficace que la méthode de recherche en arbre directe existante</description><creator>Zhu, Jing</creator><contributor>Xiao-Wen Chang (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Computer Science</subject><title>Numerical methods for underdetermined box-constrained integer least squares problems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430737s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967644s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33s027j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:54:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La plaine inondable du fleuve Amazone offre un grand potentiel pour l'agriculture, mais, c'est un environnement à risque élevé pour les agriculteurs qui travaillent cette terre fertile prône aux inondations.  Les dépôts annuels d'inondation sont des sédiments riches en nutriments en provenance des Andes, et c'est ce qui permet une haute productivité agricole durant la saison des marées basses. Alors que l'inondation annuelle fournit une injection essentielle à la fertilité, le risque de perte de récolte influence les agriculteurs à prendre des décisions de production qui sont sûrs, ce qui ne leurs permettent pas de tirer profit de la fertilité afin de maximiser la rentabilité, par exemple, la sélection de variétés qui sont à faible rendement ou de courte durée. Dans cette thèse, je décris les pratiques agricoles dans la plaine inondable; identifie les risques de la production agricole en mettant l'emphase sur la perte de riz en raison des inondations; et examine comment les caractéristiques comportementales influencent les stratégies de réduction des risques d'inondation et la portée des opportunités pour les programmes de réduction des risques pour la région. La collecte de données a été recueillie auprès des agriculteurs dans quatre communautés se situant le long du fleuve Amazone près de Iquitos, au Pérou par l'entremise d'enquêtes auprès des ménages (n = 83) sur la perte de la récolte, les risques perçus, les stratégies d'adaptation, la volonté de payer pour les programmes de réduction des risques, et une expérience de préférence de risque; de groupes de discussion (n = 8); d'entrevues avec des informateurs clés (n = 9); et d'une enquête sur l'élévation du terrain. La production dans la plaine inondable peut être rentable, cependant, la perte de récolte due aux inondations peut être élevée. Il existe des possibilités de réduction des risques - en particulier par le biais de l'assurance indexée - pour aider les agriculteurs à tirer davantage profit de l'utilisation de la plaine inondable de l'Amazone.</description><description>The floodplain of the Amazon river offers much potential for agriculture but it is a risk-filled environment for farmers working the fertile but flood-prone land. The annual flood deposits nutrient-rich sediment from the Andes, which allows for high agricultural productivity during the low water season. While the annual flood provides an essential boost to fertility, the risk of crop loss influences farmers to make production decisions that are safe and may not take advantage of the fertility in a way that maximizes profitability, e.g., selecting low yielding, short duration varieties. In this thesis, I describe agricultural practices in the floodplain, identify the risks to agricultural production with emphasis on rice loss due to flooding, and examine how behavioural characteristics influence flood risk reduction strategies while scoping the opportunities for risk reduction programming for the region. Data were gathered among farmers in four communities along the Amazon river near Iquitos, Peru from household surveys (n=83) on crop loss, perceived risks, coping strategies, willingness to pay for risk reduction programming, and a risk preference experiment. Additional data were gathered from focus groups discussion (n=8), key informant interviews (n=9), and a land elevation survey. Production in the floodplain can be profitable; however, potential crop loss from flooding can be high. There are opportunities for risk reduction – especially through index-based insurance – to assist farmers to make fuller use of the Amazon floodplain.</description><creator>List, Geneva</creator><contributor>Oliver T Coomes (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Geography</subject><title>Agriculture and the risk of crop loss due to flooding in the Amazon river floodplain of Peru</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82kb01v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33s027j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v828j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:54:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Deux études ont été effectués pour évaluer l'effet de deux types de moulées à base des graines de lin extrudées (EF1 et EF2; lin:luzerne 4:1) sur le dépôt des acides gras oméga-3 et du cholestérol dans l'oeuf, les paramètres de production, les composants de l'œuf (les pourcentages du jaune, l'albumine et de coquille), et la digestibilité totale apparente des nutriments chez des poules pondeuses. En outre, dans l'étude 2, les poules avaient été euthanasiés pour mesurer les concentrations des acides gras dans le sang et les tissues du foie. Soixante-douze poules pondeuses ont été répartis au hasard à 1 des 4 traitements diététiques (6 cage répliqués; 3 poules/cage) et ont été élevés pendant une période expérimentale de 8 semaines. Les traitements diététiques étaient: une moulée standard à base de maïs-soja contenant 0%, 7.5%, 15% et 22.5% de EF1 dans l'étude 1, et 0%, 3%, 6% et 9% de EF2 dans l'étude 2.Dans l'étude 1, l'incorporation de EF1 jusqu'à 22.5% de la moulée n'a eu aucun effet sur la consommation, la production des œufs et l'indice de conversion alimentaire. Les pourcentages du jaune d'œuf et de l'albumen étaient similaires entre les traitements. Cependant, le pourcentage de coquille d'œuf avait augmenté (P &lt; 0.05) lorsque les moulées contenaient des plus forts niveaux de EF1. En comparaison avec la moulée contrôle, les poules pondeuses nourrit avec EF1 ont déposés plus (P &lt; 0.05) d'acides gras oméga-3 polyinsaturés dans l'œuf. Par exemple, pendant la deuxième semaine de l'étude, l'acide linoléique (LNA) avait augmenté (P &lt; 0.05) par 610% chez les pondeuses alimentés avec 22.5% de EF1 comparativement à celles nourries avec la moulée contrôle. De plus, les concentrations des acides Eicosapentaénoïque (EPA) et Docosahexaénoïque (DHA), autres types d'acides gras oméga-3, dans l'œuf étaient plus élevés (P &lt; 0.05) en raison d'une supplémentation en EF1 dans la moulée. Cependant, l'incorporation de EF1 dans la moulée n'a eu aucun effet sur les niveaux de cholestérol de l'œuf, mais a significativement réduit (P &lt; 0.05) AMEn et la digestibilité totale apparente de la matière sèche, la matière organique, la protéine brute et l'énergie brute.Dans l'étude 2, l'incorporation de EF2 jusqu'à 9% de la moulée n'a eu aucun effet sur la consommation, la production d'œuf, l'indice de conversion alimentaire, et les composants de l'œuf. Cependant, EF2 a augmenté de façon significative (P &lt; 0.05) les concentrations en acides gras oméga-3 polyinsaturés dans le jaune d'œuf, le sang (plasma) et les tissus du foie. Par exemple, en comparaison avec la moulée contrôle, les poules nourries avec 9% de EF2 avaient des concentrations plus élevés en LNA (551%, 558% et 363%, respectivement) et DHA (60%, 46% et 66%, respectivement) dans les jaune d'œufs, le sang (plasma) et les tissus du foie à la huitième semaine de l'étude. Toutefois, EF2 n'avait aucun effet sur le niveau de cholestérol dans l'œuf. Par contre, AMEn et la digestibilité totale apparente des nutriments de matières sèche, la matière organique, et de l'énergie brute ont été significativement réduite (P &lt; 0.05) chez les pondeuses nourrit avec 9% d'EF2.En conclusion, des niveaux modérés d'EF1 (7.5%) et EF2 (6%) pourraient être des régimes alimentaires efficaces pour la production d'œufs enrichis en acides gras oméga-3 (n-3 acides gras ≥ 300 mg par œuf conformément à la réglementation du Canadian Food inspection Agency), sans compromettre la production d'œuf et de la digestibilité des nutriments.</description><description>Two experiments were conducted to evaluate the effects of 2 extruded flaxseed meals (EF1 and EF2; flaxseed:alfalfa 4:1) on n-3 fatty acids deposition in eggs, egg production parameters, egg components (i.e. yolk, albumen and eggshell percentages) and cholesterol concentrations, and apparent total tract nutrient digestibility of laying hens. Moreover, in Experiment 2, birds were euthanized for measurements of blood plasma and liver fatty acid concentrations. Seventy two layers were randomly allotted to 1 of 4 dietary treatments (6 cage replicates; 3 hens/cage) and raised over an 8-week experimental period. Dietary treatments included a standard corn-soybean meal diet containing 0%, 7.5%, 15% and 22.5% EF1 for Experiment 1, and 0%, 3%, 6%, and 9% EF2 for Experiment 2.In Experiment 1, feeding layers with EF1 up to 22.5% of the diet had no effect on feed intake, egg production and feed conversion ratio. Egg yolk and albumen percentages were similar among treatments. However, eggshell percentage increased (P &lt; 0.05) with increasing level of dietary EF1. Layers fed EF1 deposited more (P &lt; 0.05) total n-3 poly-unsaturated fatty acids than layers fed the control diet. For example, linolenic acid (LNA) increased (P &lt; 0.05) by 610% in layers fed 22.5% EF1 compared with those fed the control diet during week 2. Eicosapentaenoic (EPA) and docosahexaenoic (DHA) acids were also increased (P &lt; 0.05) as a result of EF1 supplementation. However, dietary EF1 had no effect on egg cholesterol, but significantly reduced (P &lt; 0.05) AMEn and apparent total tract digestibility of dry matter, organic matter, crude protein and gross energy.In Experiment 2, incorporating EF2 up to 9% of the diet had no effect on feed intake, egg production, feed conversion ratio, and egg components. However, dietary EF2 significantly increased (P &lt; 0.05) total n-3 poly-unsaturated fatty acids in egg yolk, plasma and liver tissues. For example, when compared to the control diet, hens fed 9% EF2 had higher LNA (551%, 558% and 363%, respectively) and DHA (60%, 46% and 66%, respectively) in yolk, plasma and liver at week 8. Egg cholesterol was not affected by dietary EF2. Similarly, AMEn and apparent total tract nutrient digestibility of dry matter, organic matter, and gross energy were significantly reduced (P &lt; 0.05) among birds fed 9% EF2.In conclusion, moderate levels of EF1 (i.e. 7.5%) and EF2 (i.e. 6%) are effective dietary strategies for the production of omega-3 enriched eggs (n-3 fatty acids ≥ 300 mg per egg according to regulations of the Canadian Food Inspection Agency), without compromising egg production and nutrient digestibility.</description><creator>Huang, Siyuan</creator><contributor>Bushansingh Baurhoo (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Arif Mustafa (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Animal Science</subject><title>Effects of feeding extruded flaxseed on layer performance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042w65k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v828j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):7875</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>