<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:37:22Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):38625" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b513b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In 1988, The Canada and the United States of America signed the Free-trade Agreement of North America. They wrote in a compulsory licence of cable distribution: cable distributors could, without consent, intercept the broadcasting waves but would also have to give them a financial compensation. In 1995, the WTO2 elaborated the Trade related intellectual property agreement (TRIPS). The latter grants the broadcasters a right to authorize or to prevent the communication of their waves to the public. Is the existence of the compulsory licence compromised by this agreement? We believe not. Indeed, justifications to the compulsory licence are found in the TRIPS: the general derogation of section 13 and the insertion of the Berne Convention through section 9 allow such licence. We also establish that the national treatment and the most-favoured nation clauses do not apply to the compulsory licence.
</description><creator>Simard, Marie-Pierre.</creator><contributor>Lametti, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Cable television -- Law and legislation -- United States.</subject><subject>Television broadcasting -- Licenses -- Canada.</subject><subject>Copyright -- Broadcasting rights -- Canada.</subject><subject>Copyright -- Broadcasting rights -- United States.</subject><subject>Television broadcasting -- Licenses -- United States.</subject><subject>Cable television -- Law and legislation -- Canada.</subject><title>Accord sur les aspects des droits de proprieté intellectuelle qui touchent au commerce : la licence obligatoire de câblodistribution canado-américaine y survivra-t-elle?</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gv408.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b513b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913r631</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>On 24 February 1996, two US-registered civil aircraft operated by members of the anti-Castro organisation Brothers to the Rescue were shot down by Cuban fighters. This action was denounced by the United States and the majority of the international community on the grounds that international air law, as reflected in Article 3bis of the Chicago Convention, prohibits the use of force against civil aircraft. However, at the time of the incident, the 1984 Protocol introducing Article 3bis in the Chicago Convention was not in force nor had it been ratified by Cuba or the United States. This thesis will examine the international legal rules applicable to the incident and will assess the legality of the Cuban action.</description><creator>Simantirakis, Christina.</creator><contributor>Prevost, Rene (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Airspace (International law)</subject><subject>Cuba -- Foreign relations -- United States.</subject><subject>United States -- Foreign relations -- Cuba.</subject><title>The Cuban shoot-down of two US-registered civil aircraft on 24 February 1996 : study of a new case of use of weapons against civil aircraft</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m846d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913r631</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gm703</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Echoes is an interactive composition for amplified chamber ensemble and computer. The entire research that led to this piece was based on the exploration of the evolution of the sound produced initially by the acoustic instruments and then interpreted by the computer. Why "Echoes"? As a sonic phenomenon the echo has several fairly distinct dimensions. These are commonly understood to include the following: the repetition of a sound by reflection of sound waves from a surface; any repetition or imitation of words, style or ideas; the sympathetic sound response; and, in music, a soft repetition of a phrase. Note that these standard definitions include the figurative dimensions, as in the 'imitation of style or ideas.' This is no coincidence, since I am very much intrigued by the idea of a computer first imitating the actual instrument and then expanding that instrument's possibilities far beyond its timbre.</description><creator>Elezovic, Ivan.</creator><contributor>Lanza, Alcides (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Instrumental ensembles -- Scores.</subject><subject>Computer music.</subject><subject>Electronic music.</subject><title>Echoes : [for] tenor, chamber ensemble &amp; computer</title><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh38v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gm703</identifier><degree><name>Master of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386m20r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>From Heaven, Through the World, to Hell is a theatrical piece which makes reference to various versions of the Faust legend. There are two versions of the piece: the full version for actress-singer, CD, computer, and four chamber ensembles (piano quintet, baroque trio, jazz quartet and modern ensemble), and the solo version for actress-singer, CD, and computer. The work explores the Faust legend within a technological musical theatre framework, and makes extensive use of live computer interaction using the Max/MSP programming environment. The singer interacts with the computer using an infrared sensor, allowing her to trigger as well as shape many of the sounds in the piece through physical gestures. This piece was written for g.e.m.s. (the Group of the Electronic Music Studio) as part of the McGill University Faculty of Music composer-in-residence program between 1998--1999.</description><creator>Wierckx, Marcel.</creator><contributor>Lanza, Alcides (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Faust, d. ca. 1540 -- Songs and music.</subject><subject>Dramatic music.</subject><subject>Computer music.</subject><title>From heaven, through the world, to hell</title><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj139381s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386m20r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82k901n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A common wastewater treatment process practised in zinc production plants is the single stage mixing of acidic wastewaters with slaked lime, inducing the reactive precipitation of fine (~1 mum) gypsum (CaSO 4·2H2O) and other solids with a solids density of less than 10%. These solids report to tailings ponds for containment. The solid-liquid separation step would be more efficient if the size and density of the precipitated solids were increased. Tailings pond life would be increased if the solids density of the precipitated solids was improved. It is the scope of this thesis to report on how high density and clean gypsum may be produced by implementing staging and product recycling. According to this work a staged neutralisation process (each neutralisation reactor operating at different pH) leads to production of large sized gypsum crystals with a high solids density. A continuous lab scale circuit run with synthetic zinc plant effluent produced large (~100 mum) gypsum crystals with a solids density of 35%. The effect of various metal impurities (such as Zn, Mn, Mg, Fe(II), Cd, Na) in concentrations ranging from 0.1 g/l to 10 g/l on the morphology of gypsum and their uptake by gypsum is investigated with the view of ultimately controlling gypsum contamination. By implementing staging and product recycling gypsum was produced containing less than 0.025% zinc and minor quantities of other elements hence meeting all industrial specifications for synthetic gypsum.</description><creator>Verbaan, Cornelis Niels Martijn.</creator><contributor>Demopoulos, G. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><subject>Engineering, Environmental.</subject><title>Impurity uptake duting gypsum crystallisation in wastewater treatment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w1544.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k901n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:000001936</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The research reported here deals with the design of the uplink flow control in a CDMA-based wireless access network. Demand from each source is assumed infinitely divisible, the control is rate-based and the service model is ATM/ABR (Available Bit Rate). The flow control problem in general is to manage---dynamically, and subject to prescribed constraints on transmitter power and signal-to-interference ratio---the instantaneous allocation of rate to individual sources. Our particular interest is in settings where the controller has access to information on downstream congestion (real or virtual) for each connection, and where quality-of-service is specified on time scales that are slow relative to the rate of channel variation. Our objective is to exploit the congestion feedback, as well as the temporal flexibility in the quality-of-service specification, to refine the match between resource allocation and need. We propose a framework in which the problem can be posed precisely, and provide a solution in the case that there is but a single base station. The solution has two components. One describes the set of rate allocations that are consistent with the power and SIR constraints. The other uses the congestion feedback, modeled by the states of certain reference buffers downstream of the base station, to select a specific rate allocation within the admissible rate region. The benefit in terms of call-carrying capacity is indicated through simulations.</description><creator>Sun, Xumin, 1972-</creator><contributor>Kaplan, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Medium access control with congestion feedback in CDMA based networks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wh828.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000001936</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53wx60b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The CCD (Charge Coupled Device) image formation theory is at the foundation of 3D vision systems. Ideally, a five-element block diagram can model this process. The first block represents the nonlinear distortions caused by camera lenses. The second and third elements gather the low-pass filter effects due to lens aberrations and CCD phenomenon. A fourth block illustrates the quantization effects induced by a series of discrete photosensitive elements on the CCD and by the A/D conversion for analog cameras. The last block represents the addition of random noise on the discrete signal. Because step-like luminance transitions undergoing lens distortion remain step-like, it is possible to precisely correct for the distortions after the edge localization. The efficient distortion correction process is exactly where the camera lens calibration challenge resides. The calibration exercise also seeks the intrinsic and extrinsic camera parameters, i.e. the information that relates to the camera optics and the information that describes the location and orientation of the camera in 3D space. This thesis presents a review and evaluation of several methods designed for optimal accuracy on the parameters evaluation. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Valois, Jean-Sébastien.</creator><contributor>Ferrie, F. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Monocular camera calibration assessment for mid-range photogrammetry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892c63v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wx60b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n870zs510</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An adaptive-grid numerical method for the computer simulation of steady-state, two-dimensional, solid-liquid phase change systems is presented. The grid is designed to delineate the solid-liquid interface using a structured adaptation technique. The fluid flow and thermal fields are solved concurrently using a control-volume finite element method. Of particular interest is the modelling of industrial solidification processes, such as the continuous casting of metal. The combined adaptive-grid, CVFEM method is formulated for the solution of two-dimensional planar and axisymmetric problems. The proposed method is tested by application to natural convection in closed solid-liquid systems. Test problems in two-dimensional rectangular, cylindrical, and spherical axisymmetric enclosures, are presented. An analytical solution of an idealized, one-dimensional, steady-state, continuous phase change process is derived. The numerical method is further tested with this analytical solution, and then applied to the continuous casting of aluminum into a cylindrical ingot. Comparisons of the calculated solid-liquid interface geometry with those reported in earlier experimental and numerical studies are encouraging. In addition, the role of natural convection in this casting process is investigated and presented.</description><creator>Sinton, David A.</creator><contributor>Baliga, B. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Computational modelling of solid-liquid phase change with applications to continuous casting</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zw24f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zs510</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p210r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sludges formed by lime treatment of acidic mine effluents are a widespread environmental hazard. One treatment option is to recover the toxic and potentially valuable contained metals. A method has been reported to selectively recover the metals by leaching with a complexing agent, diethylenetriamine (DETA). In this thesis a novel method has been developed to recover metals from the metal---DETA complexes by direct electrowinning. Copper was studied initially as a test system due to the relative ease with which it is recovered in conventional sulphate electrowinning. The main industrial interest, and hence the main focus of the work, is in the nickel---DETA system. For both metals, initially batch tests were run to determine acceptable electrowinning conditions. These were followed by recycle tests to simulate a potential process flowsheet. In the nickel-DETA system the effects of pH, nickel concentration, temperature, and DETA to nickel ratio on current efficiency were determined. Recycle tests for copper showed that a steady DETA concentration was achieved after ca. six hours. In the case of nickel, the system seemed to continually deteriorate. A pH range of 4.6 to 4.8 maximized the current efficiency, due to a competition between hydrogen formation at low pH and increased complex stability at high pH. Both increasing Ni concentration and temperature increased the current efficiency, while increasing the DETA to nickel ratio lowered it.</description><creator>Felsher, Dave.</creator><contributor>Finch, J. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Electrowinning of metal - DETA complexes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sf43z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p210r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zw12z7151</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Microflotation, laboratory batch, and continuous in-plant minicell tests were conducted to determine if copper ions not only activate sphalerite but also depress pyrite when the minerals are together. Microflotation was performed on mineral samples over a pH range of 3.5--11. It was found that pyrite recovery increased with addition of copper ions when alone, but decreased by more than 25% (absolute) when sphalerite was also present for the pH range 6--9.5. Bench flotation tests were performed on Louvicourt Mine ore and Red Dog Mine ore. The results for Red Dog showed that upon addition of copper, pyrite recovery decreased significantly. Pyrite recovery decreased from ca. 70% (no copper) to ca. 10% (4.5 g Cu/kg Zn) at a sphalerite recovery of ca. 70%. Continuous in-plant minicell tests at Louvicourt Mine also showed that pyrite recovery decreased with addition of copper and further indicated that with excess copper (20 g Cu/kg Zn) pyrite recovery can increase. The mechanism responsible for the depression of pyrite seems to be competition first for copper then xanthate that favours sphalerite over pyrite. To take advantage of this competition it may be necessary to control the sequence and rate of copper, collector, and lime addition.</description><creator>Dichmann, Tara Kristine.</creator><contributor>Finch, J. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>The role of copper ions in sphalerite and pyrite flotation selectivity /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn107091h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z7151</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn301310d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Submarine cable systems are a vital and expanding part of the world wide telecommunication network. The systems are laid in the ocean using a cable ship. During the deployment of a submarine cable, the cable ship has only limited information about the behaviour of the cable once it leaves the vessel and begins its descent to the seabed. The present thesis studies the cable dynamics and control during laying operations. The cable dynamics is modeled using the continuum approach. Using the model developed, the cable configuration and tension are obtained for the two dimensional steady state and transient motions, when different parameters such as the ship velocity, hydrodynamic constant, and current direction, are varied. Also, the out of plane angle of inclination and corresponding maximum displacement for the three dimensional steady state case are determined. Then the possibility of controlling the cable oscillations by varying the payout rate is explored. In the case of the controlled response the results show that, in principle, the deviation of the in plane angle can be effectively reduced to zero, but the value of the input payout rate needed is unrealistic in practice.</description><creator>Dziubinschi, Gabriela.</creator><contributor>Misra, A. K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Mechanics and control of submarine cable laying</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zc914.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301310d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:js956h70k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research presents the development of a novel dynamic walking controller for a simple quadrupedal robot, Scout II. Since Scout II does not have knees, a modified version of the bound, which we call a walking bound was studied. To gain understanding of system behaviour, an iterative approach of simulation, analysis, and experimentation was pursued. First a simulation study used in the development of rocking and walking controllers was undertaken. Attempts to experimentally implement the mentioned controllers revealed unmodelled dynamics having significant effects on system behaviour. Therefore, another walking algorithm based on commanding constant hip velocity was experimentally developed. This algorithm proved successful, yielding stable walking for narrow ranges of operating conditions despite a simple open loop strategy using minimal feedback. Typical mechanical and electrical power, as well as specific resistance for Scout II compliant walking are quantified.</description><creator>De Lasa, Martin.</creator><contributor>Buehler, Martin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Dynamic compliant walking of the Scout II quadruped</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fj89c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956h70k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1544br246</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Alain Robbe-Grillet's Les Gommes, Michel Butor's L'Emploi du temps as well as Claude Simon's La Bataille de Pharsale are all New Novels in which Greek and Latin "mythemes" play various roles in the reception of the text by its reader. These roles represent our object of study. As a result of the possibilities and, more specifically, the many difficulties involved in reconstructing the original mythological plot, the reader realizes that the mythemes form a sort of "secondary plot" which both reflects the "first plot" (the novel's narrative) and determines its complexity. In this way, the mythemes guarantee a certain balance in the reader's level of understanding. However, they still bring out important problems: for example, they contribute to the redefining of certain familiar classical concepts and to the production of manifold interpretative choices. It follows that the mythemes are instrumental in making the reader the privileged spectator of the reconstruction of the horizon of expectations.</description><creator>Mineau, Marie-Elaine.</creator><contributor>Lane-Mercier, Gillian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Robbe-Grillet, Alain, 1922-2008. Gommes.</subject><subject>Mythology, Classical, in literature.</subject><subject>Simon, Claude. Bataille de Pharsale.</subject><subject>French fiction -- 20th century -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Butor, Michel. Emploi du temps.</subject><title>Rôle des mythèmes dans la lecture de trois nouveaux romans</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719p02d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544br246</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q811km49m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The intent of this thesis, as the title suggests, is to explore the autobiographical and religious writings of Edith Stein---philosopher and protegee of the phenomenologist, Edmund Husserl, Carmelite nun and religious thinker---in order to establish the validity of attributing a theology of the cross to her life and works. This theological method---or way of "doing" theology---unites the cognitive and practical dimensions of Christian life. The investigation is, therefore, directed at underscoring the relational dynamics, core dispositions and philosophical/religious directives that highlight the unity of praxis and intellection in Stein's personhood and thought-world. The search for correlations is restricted (wherever possible) to her own words and a chronological/cumulative format is maintained throughout to trace the links between her Hebraic roots, philosophical world view, theory of empathy, familiarity with Luther's theology of the cross, and her own reflections on the cross. What comes through is a Judeo-Christian theological outlook that grew out of the empathetic phenomenon and gained momentum in the paradox of the cross.</description><creator>Nemazee, Rowshan.</creator><contributor>Kirkpatrick, Patricia G. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Farrow, Douglas (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Suffering -- Religious aspects -- Christianity.</subject><subject>Stein, Edith, Saint, 1891-1942</subject><subject>Holy Cross.</subject><title>"Ave Crux, spes unica" : the theology of the cross in the life and works of Edith Stein</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z9554.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811km49m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128ng444</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main objective of this study is to analyze the political struggle between the Indonesian army and Islamic political parties in the New Order era between 1966--1977. The historical background of the involvement of the army in politics and the attempt of political Islam to establish an Islamic state is a central issue that characterized the relationship between these two groups. When the New Order came to power in 1966, it has exercised strict control over politically organized Islam. With the army emerged as the most significant political force, there was no choice for political Islam except to reformulate its political agenda in order to suit national development program undertaken by the military backed government. The future of political Islam and the involvement of the army in the social and political arena in Indonesia field has since then been central to the development of political system in that country.</description><creator>Muluk, Safrul.</creator><contributor>Turgay, A. Uner (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Indonesia -- Politics and government -- 1966-1998.</subject><subject>Indonesia. Angkatan Bersenjata -- Political activity.</subject><subject>Islam and politics -- Indonesia.</subject><title>The Indonesian army and political Islam : a political encounter 1966-1977</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cc718.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128ng444</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f777t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One aspect of Giorgio Bassani's narrative that requires to be examined is that of the narrator, the narrative voice and therefore the point of view from which the facts are narrated. The identification of these elements is fundamental because they influence the author's expressive choices, and thus determine the way in which the reader approaches the events described. This study posits an analysis of the narrative techniques used by the author to develop Le storie ferraresi, and aims to assess the ends, partially explicit, he intends to meet.</description><creator>Patruno, Giovanna.</creator><contributor>Kroha, Lucienne (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Bassani, Giorgio -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>La tecnica narrativa nelle Storie ferraresi di Giorgio Bassani /</title><language>ita</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xt578.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f777t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Italian</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rj94x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis focuses on the Immigration and Refugee Board of Canada's Guidelines on Women Refugee Claimants Fearing Gender-Related Persecution, released in 1993. The guidelines were designed to address a perceived shortcoming in international refugee law and its domestic applications, namely, the omission of gender-based persecution from the protection of the 1951 United Nations Convention Relating to the Status of Refugees. The omission of gender from the UN Convention had resulted in gender inequalities in the evaluation of asylum claims, inequalities the Canadian guidelines were designed to correct. However, since the inception of the guidelines, critics have dismissed the directives as numerically ineffective, pointing to the low numbers of women requesting asylum on the basis of gender-related persecution. While such a numerical analysis may be useful, the thesis argues it is incomplete. The thesis centres instead on the vital consciousness-raising role played by the guidelines, both domestically and abroad, and on the concrete results engendered by this function in the international realm of women's human rights.</description><creator>Guha, Julia Patricia.</creator><contributor>Black, Jerome (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Canada -- Emigration and immigration -- Government policy.</subject><subject>Refugees -- Government policy -- Canada.</subject><subject>Women refugees -- Canada.</subject><title>The immigration and refugee board of Canada's guidelines on gender-related persecution : an evaluation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87ps20v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rj94x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149r46n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to separate acute and chronic effects of moderate exercise on the immune system by analyzing three sets of experimental and control groups; (1) 72 hours, (2) 1 week, (3) 2 weeks post exercise. Mice swam 5 days per week for 3 weeks accumulating a total of 125, 225, and 225 minutes of exercise in weeks 1, 2, and 3, respectively. Moderate swimming exercise did not result in a significant increase in SDH levels (p &gt; 0.05). There was no change in tissue cell responses as measured by mitogen responsiveness, nor in splenic and thymic cell counts in response to the training regimen at any time point (p ≥ 0.05). Total, CD4, CD8, and T cell counts in the lymph nodes were significantly suppressed at 72 hours and 2 weeks post exercise (p ≤ 0.05). It appears that chronic exercise resulted in an increased trafficking of lymphatic cells, which could be interpreted as a sign of heightened immune reactivity.</description><creator>Hoyeck, Edward.</creator><contributor>Turcotte, Rene (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Molecular immunology.</subject><subject>Cellular immunity.</subject><subject>Mice -- Immunology.</subject><subject>Exercise -- Immunological aspects.</subject><subject>Swimming -- Physiological aspects.</subject><title>The effects of moderate swimming exercise on immune system function in C57 BL/6(B6) mice /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515q16n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149r46n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2r36v036d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Concerned with the survival of Christianity in the Middle-East, Rene Habachi engages a dialogue between thinking and life. Half a century ahead of his time, Habachi puts forward a proposal for peaceful coexistence---something which today's diplomacy is still struggling to sketch out. In a Mediterranean where traditions abound, nationalities vary, cultures overlap and civilisations succeed one another, Habachi opts for a philosophy anchored in the present, having recourse to traditions of the past, so as to prepare a better future. Respectful of the three monotheistic religions in the Middle-East and cognizant of the practical difficulty in managing a peaceful coexistence, Habachi calls for dialogue between the three religions, while assigning to each a specific task: for Judaism, the task of hospitality; for Islam, the task of tolerance; and for Christianity, the task of gratuitousness. Habachi remains convinced that only healthy and equitable economy is the basis for solidarity.</description><creator>Hoss, Chantal.</creator><contributor>Bautin, Maurice (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><subject>Religion, Philosophy of.</subject><title>Pensée méditerranéenne et religions monothéistes selon René Habachi</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77ft20z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36v036d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wf572</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of this thesis is to examine the relationship between race, masculinity, and the politics of success as they relate to the figure of Harry Belafonte. During the 1950s and 1960s he was, by all accounts, a wildly successful performer and, due to his celebrity, avoided many of indignities which plagued the daily lives of most African Americans. Although this was typically taken as a sign of race's declining importance in American culture, the varied reaction to his success show that even 'success stories' of integration during this period were far from clear cut.</description><creator>Hayward, Mark, 1975-</creator><contributor>Straw, Will (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Belafonte, Harry, 1927-</subject><subject>United States -- Race relations -- History -- 20th century.</subject><subject>African American entertainers.</subject><title>Harry Belafonte, race, and the politics of success</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d1750.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wf572</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52j975v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Spinal adaptive response in the frontal plane was investigated in relationship to pelvic unleveling during gait. Kinematic data were collected from 10 healthy adult subjects (5 male, 5 female) for walking and running on the treadmill at self-selected speeds. Spine and pelvic kinematic patterns and ranges of motion (ROM) were investigated with gender, speed and slope as factors. Speed and slope had the greatest impact on changes in the amplitude of the spine's kinematic patterns. Interaction effects were seen for speed and slope for the ROM, particularly of the greater trochanter (p &lt; .047), PSIS (p &lt; .011) and for the shoulders (p &lt; 0.077). Gender presented more changes in the pelvic kinematics than the spine's kinematics. A significant trend in the females of greater ROM for T8 with increases in speed and slope was shown (p &lt; 0.001). From this study it was concluded that speed, slope and gender were significant factors that affect the spine's ability to adapt to pelvic unleveling. In all conditions there was a coupled relationship found between the thoracic spine, lumbar spine and pelvis. In particular there was an oppositional movement found within the spine such that as the lumbar spine had convexity towards the swing leg then the thoracic spine had the opposite convexity. Hence, these factors are important when assessing posture and biomechanics of running and walking.</description><creator>Abbatt, Joanna.</creator><contributor>Pearsall, D. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Spine -- Movements.</subject><subject>Pelvis -- Movements.</subject><subject>Running.</subject><subject>Gait in humans.</subject><subject>Walking.</subject><title>Spine and pelvis coupled movements in the frontal plane during inclined walking and running</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f3059.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j975v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zw25q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Community-university projects have been a common practice in most western countries since the 1960s. However, such projects are very rare in Israel. This thesis explores the possible methods by which architecture and urban planning schools and low-income communities can cooperate and examines the ways these methods can be implemented in Israel. The research investigates several community-university projects practiced in North America between the 1960s and 1990s. A set of interviews conducted with directors of schools of architecture and urban planning as well as with different actors in community-based organizations in Israel enlarges, hopefully, the understanding of the eventual possibility for such projects to exist in Israel. This research reveals that although involvement of Israeli architecture and urban planning students in community issues has been so far rather limited, there are both demand and will among schools of architecture and community-based organizations to cooperate in the future. In conclusions, basic guidelines for a community-university project are given, tailor made for the Israeli context.</description><creator>Weinberg, Yoav.</creator><contributor>Bhatt, Vikram (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Urban renewal -- Israel -- Citizen participation</subject><subject>Urban renewal -- Citizen participation</subject><subject>Architects and community</subject><subject>Community and college -- Israel</subject><subject>Architects and community -- Israel</subject><subject>Community Outreach Partnership Centers Program (U.S.)</subject><subject>Community and college</subject><title>Community-university partnership : past and present experiences with reference to the Israeli context</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55md63k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zw25q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62fb10g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The symbolism of the heavenly, represented in the Temple of Jerusalem, has inspired diverse interpretations of both mystical and archaeological type. The reconstruction by the Jesuit, Juan Bautista Villalpando (1552--1608), which took place amidst hermetic teachings, vitruvian norms, and in a religious Spain, merges all these aspects into a harmonious order that spawns a model of perfect architecture as well as the consummate religious edifice. In this vision of the Temple, deciphered from the prophet Ezechiel's abstract and messianic description, the ideal order of divine creation is drawn. Villalpando's drawings and explanations aim to reconcile the sublime in geometry with matter, therefore imitating divine creation while not ceasing to be an imaginative, worldly interpretation. According to Villalpando, in Ezechiel's vision, the spiritual aspect of the Temple of Salomon, God revealed the future Church. After the incarnation of Christ, this Church can be a reality. Villalpando's conception, which was embodied in the palace and monastery of El Escorial, represents the built ideal.</description><creator>Osorovich, Yanina.</creator><contributor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Villalpando, Juan Bautista.</subject><subject>Church architecture -- Philosophy.</subject><subject>Temple of Jerusalem (Jerusalem)</subject><subject>Symbolism in architecture.</subject><title>Re-describing the real : Villapando's [sic] ideal image of the temple of Jerusalem</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vd24r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fb10g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8049g681s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>With the development of free-economy relations and with the changes in the social life of Russia that continue to this day, a construction boom in the low-storied housing market, which began in 1991, continues. However, despite the rapid development of the low-storied market itself, the construction industry was unable to adapt to the new economic relations and the high consumer demands being placed on it. This led to an increase in prices for low-storied housing and made it unaffordable for most strata of the population. This paper will consider the peculiarities of applying new construction technologies in the market for low-storied housing in Russia, with the aim of reducing the cost of construction. The paper concentrates on studying previous experience in industrial construction in Russia, as well as on studying the peculiarities of today's low-storied housing market. As a result of this research, the author identifies a number of specific peculiarities which new construction technology should possess in order to be able to adapt itself more rapidly and neatly on the Russian low-storied housing market.</description><creator>Tulupnikov, Ivan S.</creator><contributor>Bhatt, Vikram C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Prefabricated houses -- Russia.</subject><subject>Housing -- Russia.</subject><title>Prefabricated housing for Russia : the past, present and future of prefabricated low-rise residential construction in Russia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cv76w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g681s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5999n508g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The ticket distribution industry is changing rapidly. The traditional travel distribution chain comprised airlines, travel agents, and computer reservation systems (CRSs). With the current migration of travel distribution to the Internet, the way in which these actors interact has been radically altered. After deregulation, the airlines' dependence on travel agents and CRSs led to high commission and booking fees respectively. The Internet now offers airlines a means to directly distribute their product to the travelling public with minimal expense. The airlines are eagerly shifting as many of their distribution activities as possible to different forms of web-based distribution, hoping to bypass both travel agents and CRSs. This has allowed them to reduce the commission fees they pay to travel agents. Travel agents too are going online, competing vigorously with the airlines. The combined effect of these (r)evolutions has put the airlines firmly in charge of their own distribution system. Any such a fundamental change in a sector of industry is bound to raise anticompetitive concerns, especially for those who stand to lose the most. These concerns are at the centre of this thesis. After their examination and evaluation, I conclude that anticompetitive concerns do indeed exist and that the regulatory or antitrust authorities have the unenviable task of preserving competition, not competitors, in a new and rapidly evolving market.</description><creator>Vergote, Brecht G. W.</creator><contributor>Janda, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Electronic commerce -- Law and legislation.</subject><subject>Airlines -- Reservation systems.</subject><title>Migrating to the Web : the legal dimension of the e-travel revolution</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sr793.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n508g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):38650</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>