<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:53:13Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):550" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311r360</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although considerable evidence indicates that somatostatin (SRIF) exerts direct actions on growth hormone-releasing hormone (GHRH)-containing arcuate neurons within the hypothalamus to modulate hypophyseal growth hormone (GH) secretion, the underlying mechanism(s) remains to be elucidated. We have recently demonstrated high levels of expression of the mRNAs coding for two prototypic receptors of the recently cloned SRIF receptor (SSTR) family, SSTR1 and SSTR2, in the arcuate nucleus of the rat hypothalamus. However, information on the biological role(s) of these receptor subtypes and on the regulation of their expression is lacking. In the present study, we hypothesized that perturbations in GH would influence SSTR mRNA levels in cells of the arcuate nucleus. To test this hypothesis, we examined the effects of hypophysectomy (HPX), and HPX with GH replacement, on SSTR1 and SSTR2 mRNA levels in the brain of adult male rats by in situ hybridization using $ sp{35}$S-labeled antisense riboprobes, and standard autoradiographic techniques. The number of labeled cells and the density of silver grains per cell were quantified by a computer-assisted image analysis system (Biocom). The results imply a role for both SSTR1 and SSTR2 receptor subtypes in that GH may participate in the regulation of its own secretion by influencing the expression of SSTR1 and SSTR2 receptor genes in the arcuate nucleus. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Guo, Fang.</creator><date>1995</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Regulation of expression of SSTR1 and SSTR2 somatostatin receptor mRNAs in the arcuate nucleus by growth hormone</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sc223.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311r360</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f1881p011</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to determine if islets of Langerhans transplanted into the submucosal compartment of the duodenum survive after implantation, and to establish their replication rate. Our goal was also to evaluate both the number of islets needed to achieve normoglycemia in diabetes and the potential of the implant to maintain glucose homeostasis. Experiments were performed using Syrian hamsters. Islets of Langerhans were obtained by collagenase digestion of pancreata and purified on a BSA gradient. Following transplantation, islet morphology and insulin synthesis were maintained. Normoglycemia was not achieved in hyperglycemic animals transplanted with $&lt;$800 islets, but was achieved in 8/11 diabetic animals transplanted with $ ge$800 islets. Reversal of hyperglycemia occurred over 2-5 weeks. The $ beta$-cells remained well-granulated in recipients of $ ge$800 islets and euglycemia was maintained until sacrifice up to 20 weeks post-transplantation. Glucose utilization was similar in normoglycemic controls and in recipients of $ ge$800 islets, but was significantly impaired in all diabetic animals. In conclusion, (1) the submucosal space supports islet graft viability at least up to 20 weeks post-implantation, (2) the grafts function to reverse the diabetic state, but (3) a critical islet cell mass is necessary to reverse hyperglycemia and maintain normal glucose homeostasis. The submucosal space of the duodenum appears to be an effective site for islet implantation, but additional studies are required to further evaluate the benefits.</description><creator>Tchervenivanov, Nikolay</creator><contributor>Rosenberg, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Biology of the islet graft transplanted into the submucosal space of the hamster</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cw04v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881p011</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hm50tt613</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The knowledge of the viscoelastic properties of molten polymers and the ability to predict their behavior under deformation is of prime interest to polymer scientists and industry. The discrete linear relaxation spectrum $ lbrack G sb{i}, lambda sb{i} rbrack$ is one of the important viscoelastic properties and it is widely used to characterize molten polymers. This spectrum is obtained from experimental values of the dynamic moduli $ lbrack G sp prime( omega), G sp{ prime prime}( omega) rbrack$. A linear regression method with and without regularization and a nonlinear regression method were compared for inferring a discrete spectrum from experimental data. Since experimental values are used, errors in the data will affect the reliability of the spectrum. Because of the limitations of the experimental apparatus, the moduli can only be determined over a certain frequency range. The values of the relaxation times ($ lambda sb{i}$) and the corresponding elastic moduli ($G sb{i}$) depend on the range of frequencies over which the storage and loss moduli ($G sp prime( omega$) and $G sp{ prime prime}( omega$)) are measured and the method used to calculate them. Also, experimental sources of errors such as uncertainty in the gap measurement, variation in the shape of the edge, residual stress due to the preparation of the sample, and temperature uncertainty will induce experimental errors in $G sp prime( omega)$ and $G sp{ prime prime}( omega)$. This work investigates the effect of time-scale truncation and experimental errors on the discrete relaxation spectrum.</description><creator>Gilbert, Valérie.</creator><contributor>Dealy, J. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>The effect of time-scale truncation and data errors on the linear relaxation spectrum</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193b96s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tt613</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f328m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Self-cycling fermentation (SCF) in a stirred tank reactor was applied to the biodegradation of phenol and sodium benzoate by Pseudomonas putida. The technique resulted in stable and repeatable performance for both single and mixed substrate studies. Complete substrate consumption was achieved in every instance, even when there were fluctuations in the inlet concentrations. SCF resulted in consumption rates higher than other biodegradation techniques applied to the same compounds. The mathematical model of the self-cycling fermentation process was expanded to include inhibitory substrate-microorganism combinations.</description><creator>Hughes, Scot</creator><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><title>Biodegradation of aromatics using self-cycling fermentation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322g34g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f328m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h415pc46x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This Thesis deals with the problem of selfhood and otherhood, or selfhood vs otherhood from the point of view of contemporary postmodern, structuralist, psychoanalytic and developmentalist theories. In the first chapter, Jean Baudrillard and Jacques Lacan are examples of theories of exteriority. In chapter II, Sigmund Freud and Melanie Klein present arguments for theories of interiority. In the third and final chapter, Daniel Stern' s analysis allows for a reconciliation of the two opposing points of view about the nature of the Subject. His work is significant in that it offers a synthetic view of the Self and its relationship to the Other.</description><creator>Gedeon, Randa</creator><contributor>Massumi, Brian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Self in children.</subject><subject>Self.</subject><title>Selfhood and otherhood, or selfhood vs otherhood? : questions of interiority and exteriority in contemporary cultural theory</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cm93n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pc46x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w032497s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis traces the developments of imaging technologies used for medical diagnosis. Giddens' sociological theory of modernity serves as a basis for the consideration of the bureaucratisation of medicine and the use of the patient file as source of information about health. The importance of 'inscriptions', in relation to scientific knowledge and power, is analysed through Bruno Latour's theory. Donna Haraway's call to rethink objectivity, not as a quality of universal knowledge, but as a given point of view, also influence the approach of this discussion of diagnostic practices. The author demonstrates the need for abstract concepts of patient and disease to achieve modern medicine. The links between theoretical notions (anatomical pathology, in particular) and diagnostic practices, as well as the concept of objectivity underlying the use of technology to gather information about health are examined. The effects of the biostatistical method used to evaluate health are also discussed. Finally, the importance of context in the experience of illness is noted.</description><creator>Beaulieu, Anne</creator><contributor>Burnett, Ron (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Diagnostic imaging -- Philosophy.</subject><subject>Medical personnel and patient.</subject><subject>Diagnosis -- Philosophy.</subject><title>The truth of the trace : constructing the power of the medical image</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn9998621.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032497s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m039k714w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chitin is a polysaccharide found in abundance in the shell of crustaceans. In this study, chitin was first extracted from shrimp waste material previously demineralized, using proteolytic enzymes, i.e., chymotrypsin and papain. The conditions used for the deproteinization were optimized with respect to 3 factors, viz., pH, temperature, and enzyme to waste (E/W) ratio, using response surface methodology (RSM). In a second part of the study, chitosan was prepared from chitin by partial deacetylation and its capacity to preserve whole and headless fresh shrimps was evaluated. The shrimps (Pandalus borealis) were dipped in chitosan (1 and 2% w:v), and stored on ice. Chemical indicators such as pH, drip loss, total volatile bases (TVB), nucleotide degradation, and sensory indicators of appearance (including melanosis) and odor, as well as total microbial counts were monitored during 20 days. As a third and final part, the antimicrobial properties of chitosan were evaluated using several microorganisms implicated in food spoilage and/or food poisoning outbreaks, especially those associated with fish and seafood products. Chitosan prepared from crab offal and used in the previous study on shrimp preservation was compared with commercially available chitosan from Sigma Chemical Co. (St-Louis, MO). (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Gagné, Nellie</creator><contributor>Simpson, Benjamin K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Chitin.</subject><subject>Fishery processing industries -- By-products.</subject><subject>Shrimp industry -- By-products.</subject><subject>Chitosan.</subject><title>Production of chitin and chitosan from crustacean waste and their use as a food processing aid</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pc476.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k714w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05fd82w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of business modelling is the design, analysis, and simulation of an enterprise's architectural structures and their information technology components. To comprehensively support business modelling, an appropriate modelling environment with adequate visualization mechanisms is required. Such an environment may handle model information in a flexible, yet expressive way and support substitution, documentation, validation and dynamic analysis of models as well as model visualization and alternative representations. We have developed a business modelling approach which is based on the formalism of extended, colored Petri nets. To support and validate our approach, we have engineered the Macrotec environment. Macrotec meets a list of requirements we have identified as crucial for the quality of a comprehensive modelling environment. It is conceived as a set of various tools which are seamlessly integrated. Our experience with Macrotec suggests that our concepts and environment substantially facilitate business modelling.</description><creator>Shen, Xijin, 1966-</creator><contributor>Keller, Rudolf K. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>De Mori, Renato (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Industrial.</subject><subject>Engineering, System Science.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Environment support for business modelling : concepts, architecture and implementation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x590k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fd82w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72p9161</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, mechanisms of immunoregulation by CD4$ sp+$ T cells during blood-stage P. chabaudi AS infection in C57BL/6 mice were studied. The kinetics of in vitro production of the Th1-derived cytokine, IFN-$ gamma$, versus the Th2-derived cyokines, IL-4, IL-5 and IL-10, by spleen cells as well as of polyclonal and malaria-specific antibodies in the sera were examined during infection using enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays. Upon antigenic stimulation, spleen cells were found to produce high levels of IFN-$ gamma$ several days prior to peak parasitemia, while high levels of IL-10 production occurred at the time of peak parasitemia followed by IL-4 and IL-5 later in infection. The levels of polyclonal IgG2a isotype were found to be increased during both the acute and chronic phases of infection, whereas the levels of polyclonal IgM, IgG1 and IgG2b isotypes were found to be increased only during the chronic phase of infection. High titers of malaria-specific IgG2a and IgG1 were detected during the primary as well as secondary infections. Investigation of in vitro proliferation of spleen cells to mitogens and malaria specific antigen revealed that the responses of splenic lymphocytes from infected mice to Con A, PHA and LPS were suppressed, with the most severe suppression occurring during the first 14 days post infection. Evidence is provided demonstrating that nitric oxide (NO) and prostaglandins (PG), products of activated macrophages, mediated suppression of lymphocyte proliferation in response to Con A and PHA, whereas only PG were found to suppress LPS-stimulated proliferation. In addition, NO was found to mediate suppression of proliferation of spleen cells from infected mice in response to parasite antigen. Taken together, results from these studies suggest that immune activation and immunosuppression occur simultaneously during blood-stage malaria with P. chabaudi AS infection in C57BL/6 mice. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Ahvazi, Behrouz C.</creator><contributor>Stevenson, Mary M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Malaria -- Immunological aspects.</subject><title>Mechanisms of modulation of immune responses during blood-stage malaria</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666658k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p9161</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k06989515</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Laundering is a general term that comprises all the acts aiming at bringing back into circulation criminal funds, and especially drug trade benefits. So it became urgent to mobilize the financial and banking institutions into joining the repressive authorities' action. Thus the different states involved examined how the proceeds of crimes and offences linked to the sale of narcotics could be detected and identified. However the variations between all the national laws were likely to damage the fight that was getting itself better organized and internationalized. A true international crusade took place. Finally all the European and international authorities recommended that the member states should have their laws drawn closer to one another and have effective measures adopted.</description><creator>Tomianka, Nathalie</creator><date>1994</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Sociology, Criminology and Penology.</subject><title>La lutte contre le blanchiment des capitaux provenant du trafic de stupéfiants en Amérique du Nord et dans quelques pays européens</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wj02j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k06989515</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:th83m144g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In response to the increasing maritime litigations that come along with the rapid growth of foreign trade in recent years, China opportunely adopted its Maritime Code and the Special Rules. This is certainly a significant progress in Chinese maritime legislation because for a long time neither a practical, substantive law for maritime disputes nor an appropriate procedural law for admiralty litigation was available in China. The Chinese courts had to deal with maritime disputes mainly by seeking reference from the general principles of relevant international practices. To improve this situation, the adoption of the Chinese Maritime Code and the Special Rules is undoubtedly long awaited by both Chinese legal regime and the international maritime law society. Nevertheless, as China's maritime legislation is still in its early stage, the imperfection in its drafting, the inadequacy of its judicial consideration and the inconsistency between its admiralty practices are virtually inevitable. In a comparative sense, in order to further improve the maritime law regime, China might well draw some beneficial references from the experience of the admiralty practice in some other legal systems. This thesis commences with a brief historical review of maritime lien laws. It then proceeds to evaluate the Chinese substantive laws relating to maritime liens. Finally, the thesis attempts to address the procedural issues in the enforcement of maritime liens.</description><creator>Liu, Zhong, 1952-</creator><contributor>Tetley, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>A comparative study of Chinese laws relating to Maritime liens</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k4668.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m144g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gj44k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since the early 1960s, some scholars of international commercial law and arbitration have begun to introduce new sources of law, other than domestic law, for international transactions. This is the result of two factors: (1) the immense growth of transnational contracts; and (2) their distinctive nature. This line of thought generated a lively battle over delocalization or domestication of transborder contract which still exists today. Scholars of different legal systems have introduced diverse theories including that of lex mercatoria which has received considerable attention. The controversy is not merely over the terminology, but also concerns the complex issue of the delocalization of substantive law in international commercial dispute resolution. A few scholars have maintained that this idea constitutes a third legal system described as a transnational legal system, in addition to the national and international systems. In turn, opponents claim that such a substantive law exists, if at all, only within the ambit of domestic jurisdiction. The main theme of the present study is to identify the major schools of thought with respect to the theory of new lex mercatoria, and then to trace its influence and impact on scholarly writings, national and international legislation, transnational practices, and case law.</description><creator>Khadjavi, Hodjat</creator><contributor>Tetley, William (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>Theory of lex mercatoria and recent developments</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021h190.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gj44k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644t58x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis addresses the issue of international trade and environmental protection, more particularly within the framework of the GATT dispute settlement system. In May 1993, the European Union took issue with the U.S. taxes on automobiles aimed primarily at environmental concerns. The European Union claims that the gas guzzler tax, the luxury tax and the corporate average fuel economy (CAFE) payment are discriminatory and therefore contrary to the principles of GATT Article III. The study of this dispute and the prospective analysis of its outcome show that both the gas guzzler tax and the luxury tax do not constitute a violation of the General Agreement. However, the CAFE payment violate the national treatment obligation and is not justified under the GATT general exceptions. The CAFE payment, despite that it is primarily aimed at fuel conservation, constitute a means of arbitrary and unjustifiable discrimination. The outcome of this dispute confirms the permissiveness and limits of the GATT rules toward legitimate environmental policies.</description><creator>Giroux, André François</creator><date>1994</date><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><subject>Energy.</subject><title>The settlement of international environmental trade dispute in GATT : a case study of the European Union - United States gas guzzler tax Dispute</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580p536.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644t58x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053j11w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this work is to analyze the principles of human rights theory underlying the protection of freedom of expression and the normative limits imposed on communication. The analysis involves those principles argued in American and Canadian judicial review. The curtailment of sexual expression is at the core of the discussion of the nature of human beings and their relationship with the state power. By analyzing the way in which governments ban sexual messages, one can infer with a great degree of accuracy how they will react toward other forms of expression. This connection can be established because arguments justifying restrictions on pornography may be extended to justify prohibitions on other form of communication. Inasmuch as freedom of expression meets the basic need for communication inherent to autonomous and morally responsible individuals, any restriction on it must stem from the principle that rights-protection is the highest value as supreme law rather than from a majority assertion of what is good for the individual and society as a whole.</description><creator>Fuentes, Graciela</creator><contributor>Cotler, Irwin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Political Science, Public Administration.</subject><subject>Law.</subject><title>Constitutional guarantees and normative limits to free communication</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff3657233.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053j11w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65v975v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the fundamental principles of the Chicago Convention is the principle of nationality of aircraft. It is the means by which the Convention attaches most of the rights and obligations that it creates to aircraft and state of registry, irrespective of who owns or operates the aircraft. Yet the rules of the Convention on nationality and registration can give rise to serious practical problems when an aircraft registered in one state is cooperatively arranged to be operated by an operator belonging to another state. This thesis takes a closer look at the principle of nationality of aircraft in international aviation law and gives an outline of the history of this concept. Further, it explains how nowadays this principle is applied to aircraft operated by international operating agencies, and to aircraft registered in one state and leased, chartered or inter-changed by operators belonging to other states. The concept of 'nationality of aircraft' should not be confused with the concept of 'nationality of airlines'. Another part of my thesis is dedicated to this concept of 'nationality of airlines', which is of major importance in aviation too. This part contains a general explanation on this concept as well as some examples of the ownership and control requirements in different national laws. Besides introducing the Community Air Carrier concept, it focusses on the question if the ownership and control clauses included in bilateral agreements are compatible with today's trend towards global carriers and international mergers. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Dikkerboom, Anneloes</creator><date>1994</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><subject>Transportation.</subject><title>'Nationality of aircraft and 'nationality of airlines' in the perspective of globalization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zw46g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65v975v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547t48f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Understanding bladder mechanics and the changes caused by bladder outlet obstruction is an important task in urology. In this work, bladder mechanics are examined in terms of bladder hydrodynamics: the relation between a perturbing volume applied to the bladder and the evoked pressure change. A PC-based experimental system was built which can generate a computer-controlled perturbation volume and measure volume and pressure signals. The bladders of six minipigs, three normal and three obstructed, were subjected to stochastic volume perturbations about different average volume levels and evoked pressure changes were measured. The hydrodynamic stiffness transfer function relating volume and pressure was calculated and described by a second-order, lumped parametric model having inertial, viscous and elastic terms. Estimates of the elastic constant (K) increased linearly with volume in both normal and obstructed animals. The rate of increase was substantially greater in the obstructed animals than in the normals. Consequently, this approach shows promise for distinguishing normal and obstructed bladder mechanics.</description><creator>Zhang, Jing, 1961-</creator><contributor>Kearney, Robert E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Biophysics, Medical.</subject><title>System identification of bladder hydrodynamics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sx85f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547t48f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827d624</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents the design and implementation of a framework for audio/video services for a virtual laboratory. A library of subroutines was developed to support a network video/audio server, capable of performing multimedia interactive presentations in this networked environment. The network video/audio server is an upgraded form of ACME. In a virtual laboratory, the server's file system can be used to store laboratory lessons, combining circuit simulations such as SPICE or mathematical computations using MATLAB with sounds and video sequences. The clients are able to access the server's file system via TCP/IP connections and to playback a sound or a video sequence, to record a voice message, and to send a voice message or a video sequence to another workstation. The server's workstation and the client's workstations are able to perform real time audio voice communication between each other via the video/audio server. The clients can also send voice commands from the local workstation to the voice recognition toolkit in the server workstation via a TCP/IP connection with the audio/video server for hands-free interactive presentations. The experimental results indicate that the audio/video performance is suitable for multimedia presentations in a virtual laboratory environment. The suggestions for the future development of the virtual laboratory design are presented.</description><creator>Wang, Yifan, 1963-</creator><contributor>Malowany, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Mass Communications.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Audiovideo services for a virtual laboratory</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jn496.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827d624</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t399f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The electromagnetic environment outside and inside five urban hospitals, due to fixed, EXTERNAL TRANSMTTERS (30-1000 MHz range), was characterized by measurement. Measured fields generally remained below 130 dB$ mu$V/m (3 V/m). Four computational prediction methods, based on line-of-site free-space propagation, Uniform Geometric Theory of Diffraction, and urban clutter models, were evolved. Fields predicted outside these hospitals were compared to the measured fields. A simple line-of-sight method predicted fields within 20 dB of those measured, thereby easily providing an estimate of the worst-case fields at a hospital. The most complex of these prediction methods estimated field levels to within 10 dB. Measurements were also used to analyze signal propagation characteristics inside buildings due to INTERNAL SOURCES operating at 433, 861, and 1705 MHz. Cross-floor propagation paths, where multiple floors and walls were traversed, showed fields were independent of the transmitter-receiver separation distance. Signals measured for a separation of one floor were higher than same-floor signal levels.</description><creator>Vlach, Philip Thomas</creator><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Health Care Management.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Measurement, prediction and analysis of the radio frequency electromagnetic environment outside and inside hospitals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hm21q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t399f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf2687112</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A methodology is presented to calculate the response of a wing as well as the aerodynamic forces on the wing, due to forced aileron oscillations. The purpose of oscillating the ailerons in flight is to excite the vibration modes of the wing. From vibration recordings and knowledge of the aerodynamic forces induced by the aileron oscillation, the vibration modes of the wing can be identified. Identified modes may then be compared to wing vibration modes which are calculated through aeroelastic analyses of the wing. In particular, the flutter characteristics of the wing, predicted through aeroelastic analyses, can be verified. The flutter and forced aileron oscillation analyses are performed on the aeroelastic equations built for a finite-element model of the wing. An existing finite-element model is used. The aerodynamic forces induced by wing vibrations are calculated through the doublet-lattice method, using existing software. The flutter and forced aileron oscillation analyses are based on the modal form of the aeroelastic equations. The modal transformation and the resulting equations are rigourously outlined. A physical interpretation of the mathematical formulae is given. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Vermaut, Mahendra</creator><contributor>Price, S. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><title>Flutter and forced aileron oscillation analyses of an aircraft wing including the effect of the nonlinear wing-fold hinge</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354h321.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf2687112</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149r68p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents an implementation of a controller for a redundantly-actuated parallel mechanism. Firstly, an introduction to the structure and kinematic properties of the parallel mechanism is presented. We begin by describing the ASI hydraulic actuator, the main constituents of the mechanism, and move on to review the properties of the whole system. The inverse and forward relationships are derived, and the Jacobian matrix of the system is calculated using velocity analysis. The controller of the shoulder employs the above properties and relationships to balance for any external forces, in particular the gravity, and to estimate its magnitude. This is done in two steps: damping the motion to rest primarily, and subsequently, determining the bias and actual force vectors in static equilibrium. Finally, the results of the experiments are presented. The formulation of the optimization of the force distribution problem is then studied. Given an overdetermined system, we present two methods for finding the optimal minimum-norm vector of forces, one in Hilbert space and the other in a generalized complete normed space. The latter is indeed an algorithmic procedure for obtaining a minimum $ infty$-norm or a minimum effort solution, which is a solution of a set of equations whose maximum component's magnitude is the smallest possible. In this method, the dual of problem is solved and then the optimal solution is generated by using concepts from functional analysis.</description><creator>Vaezi, Hamid Reza</creator><contributor>Hayward, Vincent (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Force balancing in a parallel redundantly-actuated mechanism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v9764.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149r68p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z708z86d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Post-tensioning rehabilitation technique is often used to improve the static and dynamic stability of concrete gravity dams. The required post-tensioning force has often been estimated from the gravity method using simple static rigid body equilibrium. However, the application of linear and nonlinear (fracture) analysis techniques using the finite element method could be advantageous to optimize the design of post-tensioning strengthening schemes, specially under seismic loads where controlled damage is an acceptable performance criterion. In this study, the flood and seismic safety evaluations of prestressed dams were carried out using the gravity method, and linear and fracture finite element methods. Two typical concrete gravity dam models, 35 m and 90 m in heights, were examined. The performance of different post-tensioning modelling techniques such as the equivalent force method, and bonded/unbonded cable elements was examined in finite element analyses. A new nonlinear analysis methodology using displacement control was studied to determine the required amount of post-tensioning forces under flood condition. Sliding stability (local and global), overstressing, and controlled damage requirements were considered to develop post-tensioning design criteria in rehabilitation of concrete gravity dams. Various schemes of post-tensioning cable layouts were examined in seismic analyses. The different prestressing modelling techniques present almost identical static and seismic structural behaviours. The material properties of the horizontal joint at the dam-foundation interface, and the tendon layouts were found the key prestressing design parameters. Linear finite element analyses predict higher required prestressing forces compared to other analysis methods. In general, flood resistant: design of prestressing also presents adequate seismic performance for small dams. However, additional partial prestressing is required near the downstream face of higher dams to prevent cracking at this location.</description><creator>Tofangchi Mahyari, Abbas-Ali</creator><contributor>Smith, B. Stratford (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Leger, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Static and seismic rehabilitation of concrete gravity dams by post-tensioning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c4672.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708z86d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3484zj724</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Smooth design spectra are generally used to describe the seismic excitation provided by the maximum design earthquake for safety evaluation of critical facilities located in Eastern Canada. However, a comprehensive study of the inelastic behaviour of critical structural systems requires step-by-step inelastic analysis in the time domain. This thesis presents a study of inelastic seismic analysis of short-period structures subjected to ground motion acceleration time histories compatible with Eastern Canadian conditions and defined (i) from historical records scaled to the smooth design spectrum intensity, (ii) from spectrum-compatible accelerograms generated by random vibration theory, and (iii) from the modification of the Fourier Spectrum coefficients of historical records while preserving the original phase angles. The ductility demand, the input energy, the hysteretic energy, the number of yield events, and other performance indices, are examined in parametric analyses to identify the type of earthquake motions that is critical for earthquake resistant design of ductile short-period structures. The linear and cracking responses of concrete gravity dams of three different heights (90m, 45m, and 22.5m), that exhibit a brittle response to strong ground shaking, are also examined for the different types of spectrum-compatible accelerograms. It is generally concluded that in the absence of suitable spectrum-compatible historical accelerograms, either historical records with modified Fourier spectra or synthetic records can be used to evaluate the linear structural response. For nonlinear analysis, historical records with modified Fourier amplitude spectra tend to produce closer results to those obtained from real earthquakes for cumulative damage indices, as compared to the results computed from synthetic accelerograms.</description><creator>Tayebi, Abdelkader Kamel</creator><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>An evaluation of spectrum-compatible accelerograms for nonlinear analysis of short-period structures located in eastern Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365724c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zj724</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bg257g95v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Metal and acid containing effluents generated by industry are most commonly treated with lime which neutralizes the acid and precipitates the dissolved metals. The resulting sludge contains gypsum which has a high water content and requires large landfill volumes. It is therefore desirable to find a neutralizing agent which has a good neutralizing capacity and a dense precipitate which can be easily dewatered at low cost. A dense, fast settling sludge would also reduce the cost of the process and the volume to be landfilled. Magnesium hydroxide has been examined in this research as a neutralizing agent for a simulated iron-containing acidic solution. The effects of reaction temperature, dosage, rate of Mg(OH)$ sb2$ addition, and recycle on the neutralization of acidic iron solutions with magnesium hydroxide were studied. Magnesium hydroxide was found to be an effective precipitating agent removing over 98.3% of the iron from solution and an effective neutralizing agent exhibiting a buffering effect which stabilized the pH between 8.8 to 9.7 even with overtreatment. Observation of precipitate colour suggested that at lower pH values (2.2 to 4.3) ferric hydroxide was formed in the sludge whereas at higher pH values (9.3 to 9.7) the sludge consisted primarily of ferrous hydroxide. Increasing reaction temperatures from 10$ sp circ$C to 25$ sp circ$C did decrease reaction time but had insignificant effects on sludge production or characteristics. However, slow Mg(OH)$ sb2$ addition to the acidic iron solution as well as the use of a recycle both resulted in the production of larger sludge particles which resulted in a denser, fast-settling sludge.</description><creator>Tam, Kawai, 1969-</creator><contributor>Simandl, Jana (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><title>Neutralization of an acidic effluent using magnesium hydroxide</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mr87w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257g95v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c534fq83x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Iron and silicon are the major impurities in the 1000 series of wrought aluminum alloys. As the aluminum is recycled, it picks up more and more of these impurities which cannot economically be refined out of the aluminum. When the concentration of these impurities reaches a certain limit (maximum limit in 1000 series is 1 weight percent (Fe+Si)), the aluminum must be downgraded. The Fe and Si form brittle intermetallic phases in these alloys. The two main phases are the plate-like $ beta$-AlFeSi (Al$ sb5$FeSi) and $ alpha$-AlFeSi (Al$ sb8$Fe$ sb2$Si) which has a Chinese Script morphology. The mechanical properties of these alloys are believed to depend largely on the nature of these intermetallics. In the first part of this study, the conditions at which the intermetallics form, along with the ability of strontium to modify them were investigated. The second part consisted of determining how the morphology of the Al-Fe-Si phases affects the mechanical properties of the worked product. It was found that the formation of the Chinese Script morphology is promoted with increasing cooling rates, Fe/Si ratios and additions of strontium. However, the relative amount of Chinese Script was found to decrease with increasing (Fe+Si) levels. Tensile testing and formability testing (Erichsen ball punch deformation test) revealed that the presence of a Chinese Script morphology of Al-Fe-Si intermetallics (as opposed to the plate-like morphology) imparts no significant beneficial effect on the formability of the final rolled sheet.</description><creator>Stephen, Gail</creator><contributor>Gruzleski, J. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Al-Fe-Si intermetallics in 1000 series aluminum alloys</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qf02j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fq83x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3n204117p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:07:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An experimental investigation of the influence of upstream turbulence on discrete-hole film cooling of a model blade in confined cross flow is presented and discussed. A model blade and test section were designed and constructed. A system for constant-temperature hot-wire anemometry was implemented. A microcomputer-based data acquisition, control, and processing system was designed and implemented. The model blade was a blunt body with a semicircular leading edge, a flat after body, and a tapered trailing edge. Local heat transfer coefficients without injection of a secondary fluid were determined using a thin-film technique. In the film cooling studies, two rows of discrete injection holes at $ pm$30$ sp circ$ from the stagnation line were used. The injection tubes were oriented normal to the surface of the model blade and were coplanar with the primary flow velocity vector. Nominal turbulence intensities of 0.7%, 9.8%, and 14.4% at a location 1.3 diameters upstream of the stagnation line on the semicircular leading edge of the model blade were investigated. The range of Reynolds number, based on the diameter of the semicircular leading edge and upstream velocity, was 23,000 to 75,000. In the discrete-hole film cooling studies, mass flux ratios in the range 0.6 $&lt;$ M $&lt;$ 2.0 were considered. The heat transfer results are presented in terms of the distributions of local Nusselt number and a nondimensional temperature on the surface of the blade. The results of the film cooling studies are presented in terms of the distributions of the effectiveness.</description><creator>Stathopoulos, Nicholas</creator><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Influence of upstream turbulence on discrete-hole film cooling of a model blade in confined cross flow</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q351t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n204117p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):575</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>