<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:34:34Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11725" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v6000</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Despite rapid advances in medical knowledge, the alimentary tract still presents a clinical problem. Complaints referable to this system are, it is recognized, among the most common of clinical symptoms, and frequently the most baffling. Thus, while the pathologist recognizes a variety of intestinal lesions, cases which reach autopsy represent only a fraction of patients with digestive complaints. Similarly, the Roentgenologist and the surgeon often cannot demonstrate a cause for digestive symptoms. To the internist falls the unhappy task of treating that large number of patients with gastro-intestinal disorders lacking any apparent organic basis.[...]</description><creator>Friedman, Sydney Murray.</creator><contributor>Martin, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946. </date><subject>Alimentary canal.</subject><subject>Abdomen -- Anatomy.</subject><title>The living anatomy of the abdominal alimentary tract.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sn53m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v6000</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227mt063</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Aluminum bronzes comprise that group of copper-aluminum alloys containing from very small amounts up to approximately l6 per cent aluminum by weight. Appreciable quantities of iron, manganese, nickel, and other elements are frequently added which results in complex alloys where more than one of the above elements are added to the bronze.Considered in the light of properties obtainable by heat treatment these alloys represent some of the most versatile non-ferrous alloys in wide use today. They combine the property of great strength, which can be altered as required by proper heat treatment, with excellent corrosion resistance. The alloys can be subjected to heat treatments similar to those used for the heat treating of steel. By means of suitable treatments, it is possible to obtain increased strength, good ductility and other desirable qualities. The many good features of this series of alloys make them useful for a large variety of modern industrial application, particularly in the marine, automative, and chemical industries.[...]</description><creator>Trudeau, Guy.</creator><contributor>MacEwan, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Engineering.</subject><title>The effect of iron on aluminium bronze.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bj110.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mt063</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42nc07w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Holden and Diver (1) in 1935 reported the isolation of a potassium acid salt (C7H9011NK) from Spanish ergot, and an acid (C6H8010) derived from this salt, that had not been reported before as constituents of ergot. The analysis and chemical properties of this acid led these authors to postulate the following structure for this substance, COOH.CHOH.C(OH)(COOH).C(0H)2.COOH (1,1,2,3, tetrahydroxypropane 1,2,3, tricarboxylic acid). The proposed identity of this acid relates It structurally to citric acid, COOH.CHg.C(OH)(COOH).CH2.COOH, (2 hydroxypropane 1,2,3, tricarboxylic acid), and for this reason, was named citergic acid, under which name it will be referre to.[...]</description><creator>Dechene, Earl Bernard.</creator><contributor>Nicholls, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947. </date><subject>Chemistry. </subject><title>The characterisation of a new hydroxy acid isolated from Spanish ergot.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r860j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42nc07w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x697q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>For the purpose of this report, adsorption may be defined as that process whereby the molecules of a gas or vapor, when that gas or vapor is placed in contact with a previously evacuated solid, become attached to the surface of the solid. An adsorption isotherm expresses the quantity adsorbed as a function of the pressure at constant temperature.[...] Information necessary to a full understanding of the phenomenon of adsorption cannot be obtained from the measurement of adsorption isotherms and heats of adsorption. For this reason, within recent years, work has been done on the determination of the structure of the adsorbent and of the state of the adsorbate. The purpose of this project is to measure the density of certain adsorbates on activated charcoal, and thereby, to obtain information on the state of the adsorbate and on the mechanism of adsorption.</description><creator>Tuck, Norman G.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The density of adsorbed layers.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qt031.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x697q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82kb491</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the present difficulties of soil chemistry is a satisfactory evaluation of soil fertility. The answer to this problem lies quite obviously, in no simple criterion such as crop yields, but in a critical consideration of yields, fertilizer response and soil analysis, bearing in mind also the effects of soil type and past management. To help interpret all these factors, under such a wide range of conditions, in as short a period as possible, the rapid, semi-quantitative tissue tests and soil tests have been developed. This investigation is a comparison of the tests more widely used in the United States, applied to two soil types in Quebec, as an aid in determining the nutrient status of the soil. The rapid soil tests were compared with values obtained by standard quantitative procedures now in general use for soil analyses, and also with crop yields, from these areas.</description><creator>Cordukes, W.E.</creator><contributor>Summerby, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946. </date><subject>Agronomy. </subject><title>Chemical evaluation of the nutrient status of soils with respect to phosphorus and potassium.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p786w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82kb491</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agronomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1j92gb42b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Conditions were found whereby a maximum yield of the isomeric cis-cis-cis-, cis-cis-trans- and cis-trans-cis- 1,2,3-trihydroxycyclohexanes (pyrogallitols) was obtained by the high pressure hydrogenation of pyrogallol over Raney nickel. The individual amounts of the three triols, together with those of the cis- and trans-cyclohexanediols simultaneously formed, were determined for various times of hydrogenation. Theories were advanced to account for the various yields. The geometrical configurations of the three pyrogallitols were definitely established for the first time by a study of their relative rates of reaction with lead tetraacetate and periodate. The cis- and trans-1,2-dinitrates of cyclohexanediol and the three trinitrates of the pyrogallitols were prepared and characterized. These five nitrates reacted inalkaline media in different ways and the rates of hydrolysis, of nitrite and color formation, were determined in each case. An attempt was made to explain these results. Several explosiveproperties, such as thermal stability, sensitivity to shock and compatibility with nitrocellulose, were determined for one or more of these five cyclohexane nitrates. Some correlation was found between these properties and the behavior of the nitrates in alkali.</description><creator>Christian, William Ramsey.</creator><contributor>Purves, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Chemistry. </subject><title>The isomeric cis-trans trinitrates of pyrogallitol.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dq412.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92gb42b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cf95jf31b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The ridge of Ordovician rocks at St. Dominique, Quebec, abounds in problems of stratigraphical, paleontological and structural importance, yet, in spite of its nearness to Montreal, it has so far received only cursory attention from geologists. Because of these features the present writer considers himself fortunate to be able to devote himself to this nearby though practically untouched field.[...]</description><creator>Usher, John Leslie.</creator><contributor>Clark, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>The geology of the St. Dominique ridge, Bagot County, Quebec.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s3463.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jf31b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3f462854j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>[...] In experiments (2) which demonstrated the importance of the sulphonation of ohlorobenzene, it was found, using 98.5% sulphuric acid at 30° C, and keeping the molar ratio of chloral: sulphurio acid at 1:20, that the crude yield obtained with one mole of chloral per mole of ohlorobenzene (i.e. half the theoretical amount) was 51% of that obtained with two moles of ohlorobenzene. There was a decrease of rate within 15 minutes, indicating that the DDT reaction was not far from completion, and that the ohlorobenzene was nearly all consumed.[...]</description><creator>Chin-Yee, Harold Reginald.</creator><contributor>Winkler, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946. </date><subject>Chemistry. </subject><title>Kinetics of the sulphonation of chlorobenzine : a thesis.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vp12r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f462854j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085p381</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La «légende» de Voltaire semble de tous temps avoir dépassé la simple vérité sur l’homme et l’oeuvre. En effet, lorsqu’on lit ses ouvrages, rien ne porte à croire que l’écrivain cynique, le terrible critique de l’ancien régime, l’apôtre de la tolérance, dont la sonorité sut tenir l’Europe en éveil pendant une grande partie du 18e siècle, avait cependant un véritable fonds de bonté, de compassion, et même, au sens restreint du mot, de sensibilité. Le Voltaire aimable, poli, sympathique, cependant, se retrouve presque à chaque page de sa Correspondance, qui comprend plus de 12,000 lettres - la plus volumineuse que nous connaissions après celle de Horace Walpole. Là, il se montre tel qu’il était véritablement, affairé, remueménage, jetant les hauts cris, poussant des hurlements, mais en même temps gracieux, plein de tact, de souplesse, de bonté, de compassion. Et c’est précisément lorsqu’il écrit aux femmes qu’il intéresse notre sympathie et même notre admiration. Il n’en sort jamais diminué à nos yeux: c’est même cela, j’ose l’espérer, qui ressortira de ce modeste travail.[...]</description><creator>Wilkinson, Ida Gertrude.</creator><contributor>Furness, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Voltaire, 1694-1778 -- Relations with women.</subject><title>Les femmes dans la correspondence de Voltaire.</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63t0117.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085p381</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c534fs04p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Up to the present, investigations of the organic matter characteristic of soils have not yielded much specific information respecting the major components. Individual organic compounds of a considerable variety have been isolated in small amounts. From the study of decomposing plant residues, of synthetic mixtures of isolated lignin fractions and proteins and of soil organic matter itself , it has been inferred that the major part of the latter consists of a complex of protein-like and lignin-like materials, and that a carbohydrate-like compound occurs next in amount. [...]</description><creator>Cann, Everett Douglas.</creator><contributor>DeLong, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry. </subject><title>Fractionation of soil organic matter.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hn50c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fs04p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752m05k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This Thesis concerns the influence upon the properties of cellulose nltr~te exerted by the moisture history of the original cellulose. It is shown that the wetting and direct redrying of highly swollen cotton llntera, followed by technioal nitrition, yields a nitrate whose nitrogen content is perceptibly diminished from the normal value. Systematic  fractionation of such nitrates suggested that degredation during nitration was slightly less severe. In an effort to discover whether wetting and redrying of the cellulose eventuslly yielded nitrates in which the distribution of the nitrate groups in the cellulose\ macromolecule wae abnormal, technically nitrated products were oxidized with lead tetraacette. Although differences in the level of oxidation were observed,in these nitrates, and also in twelve commercial nitrocelluloses, the meaning of these differencee was not clarified. Published experiments to determine the effect of wetting and redrying on the physical structure of the celluloee were repeated. Although the work oould not be exactly reproduced, its main inference received some support.</description><creator>Brown, Robert Karl.</creator><contributor>Purves, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Chemistry. </subject><title>Effects of the accessible fraction of cellulose on some properties of its nitrates.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nx83v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752m05k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33s070t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Vitamin C or ascorbic acid is oxidized reversibly to dehydroascorbic acid and irreversibly to 2:3-diketo-l-gulonic acid. Ascorbic acid and dehydroascorbic acid are biologically active but 2:3-diketo-l-gulonic acid is inactive. During the study of the stability of ascorbic acid in fortified apple juice as compared to unfortified tomato juice and other juices, the methods of determining vitamin C have been thoroughly investigated. The most serious criticism of the methods studied is that in Roe’s 2:4-dinitrophenylhydrazine method, 2:3-diketo-1-gulonic acid is included in the values for dehydroascorbic acid so that inaccurately high antiscorbutic potencies are indicated in extracts analyzed by this widely used method. To eliminate this error, attempts have been made to modify the procedure so that 2:3-diketo-l-gulonic acid is separated from the biologically active acids, ascorbic and dehydroascorbic. This would give authentic vitamin C values, as determined by this method.</description><creator>Wong, Esther Violet.</creator><contributor>McFarlane, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>Studies on the determination of ascorbic acid.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b4257.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33s070t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128nh85k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>No discussion of the women in Mrs.Woolf's fiction would be complete without a brief survey of some previous English heroines, and the methods by which their characters are revealed. Earliest in the line of English novel heroines is Samuel Richardson1s Pamela— the virtuous lady's maid whose campaign to preserve her virtue against the repeated onslaughts of Mr. B. is minutely described by the author.\ The novel is in many ways a penetrating study of the adolescent girl, half-child in the face of her master1 s bold and unprincipled attacks; half-woman in her intelligence,\ determination and conscious self-valuation. She makes skilful use of moral rectitude and the pathos of her position as a Damsel in Distress; and at last, after harrowing treatment at the hands of Mr.B., Pamela's strategy is crowned with the respect and love of her pursuer,and a wedding-ring.[...]</description><creator>Beresford-Howe, Constance.</creator><contributor>Files, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946. </date><subject>Woolf, Virginia, 1882-1941.</subject><title>The heroines of Virginia Woolf.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f681f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nh85k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k35697471</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Oxygen consumption measurements on thirty-two women and thirty-six female guinea pigs were used to compare basal and resting metabolism in these species. In order to remove variations due to differences in body size the results were expressed per unit of "Metabolic weight" (Wb). It was found that heat production values were significantly higher for the guinea pigs than for the women. No difference between basal and resting metabolism occurred except in the older group of women. A significant difference between the heat production values of the two age groups was noted. There was no difference in the variation of heat production values computed using the derived formula, Calories per 24 hours = 63.8 Wkgm#. .76, from those computed using Brody's formula, Calories per 24 hours = 70.5 Wkgm..75.</description><creator>MacNeil, Ruby Jean.</creator><contributor>Crampton, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1948. </date><subject>Nutrition. </subject><title>A comparison of basal and resting metabolism in humans and guinea pigs.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161942c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k35697471</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pk427</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The role of phosphorus in the national and world problem of food production and adequate nutrition is so great that it has sometimes been called the master key to agriculture. Its importance is indicated by the fact that low crop production is associated more often with a phosphorus deficiency than with a lack of any other element. Pierre (37) says, "Phosphorus is so basic to the whole problem of crop production that probably no other subject in the field of soil fertility has received more attention through the years than the phosphorus problem in its various soil-plant and soil-animal relationships, and it probably will continue to challenge the best efforts of investigators for many years."[...] </description><creator>MacLean, Angus Augustine.</creator><contributor>DeLong, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1948. </date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry. </subject><title>Partition of soil phosphorus as affected by variations of soil properties.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386n773.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pk427</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n009w5525</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Very soon after it was established that, as a general rule, the passage of an electric current through an aqueous solution results in the liberation of hydrogen at the cathode and oxygen at the anode, the early workers in this field realized that under these conditions electricity may be regarded as a potential reducing or oxidizing agent. The experiments of Faraday, Schonbein and many others proved this assumption to be quite tenable, and that it had a wide range of applications both in the sphere of organic and Inorganic chemistry.[...]</description><creator>MacKenzie, James Stewart.</creator><contributor>Winkler, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1948. </date><subject>Chemistry. </subject><title>The electrolytic reduction of ammonium nitrate.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687m413.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w5525</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4x51hn51n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Shortly after the production of experimental diabetes by von Mering and Minkowski in 1889 it was noted that the pancreatectomized dog manifested not only impairment of carbohydrate metabolism but evidence of altered fat metabolism as well with a tendency to deposit fat in the liver. Sandmeyer in 1895 demonstrated the beneficial effect of feeding raw pancreas in the amelioration of this complication and postulated that the presence of certain digestive enzymes of the pancreas was essential for the prolonged survival of dogs after pancreatectomy.[...]</description><creator>McKendry, J.B.R.</creator><contributor>Hoffman, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1948. </date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>Some aspects of choline metabolism.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x4542.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hn51n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cx33h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The land use survey is becoming an increasingly important item in geographic studies. This is especially so when such studies are undertaken for the solution of land use problems, because a knowledge of the present use of the land is usually deemed basic to efficient physical planning. Canada has many land use problems which need to be solved if the natural resources of the nation are to be conserved for the welfare of present and future generations. But Canada is a country of wide extent and scattered population, so that her geographers, few in number, need to find some method of survey which will enable them to study large areas with a minimum expenditure of time and money. [...]</description><creator>Lash, Harry Newton.</creator><contributor>Mackay, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1948. </date><subject>Economic geography.</subject><subject>Soils.</subject><title>A sampling method for the study of rural land use.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gh068.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cx33h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j421b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present investigation is concerned primarily with a detailed faunal study of the Nanaimo series of Upper Cretaceous age along the east coast of Vancouver Island, British Columbia. The underlying purpose is three-fold: (1) to supplement and aid the stratigraphical, structural and economical studies of the group which are being carried on by the Geological Survey of Canada; (2) to so re-describe and re-illustrate the faunas that they might be more readily identifiable in other localities; (3) to fix more precisely than heretofore their stratigraphic and chronologic position. [...]</description><creator>Usher, John Leslie.</creator><contributor>Clark, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>The stratigraphy and palaeontology of the upper cretaceous rocks of Vancouver Island, B.C.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jv373.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j421b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2v23vx191</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Microchemlcal analysis is one of the many methods used in the chemical examination of minerals. This method requires a petrographic microscope and also a knowledge of optical mineralogy. Since the microchemlcal method requires only a small sample, it is preferable to other methods in determinative mineralogy. The purpose of this paper is to present a description of the characteristic reactions and of the optical properties of the resultant crystalline precipitates of certain common elements. The optical constants are worked out in detail, in so far as the technique used permits. It will be noted that a number of these are not in complete agreement with those given in authoritative tables. An attempt has been made to interpret the interference reactions resulting from the test solution of some complex minerals with the reagents, in the hope that they may prove useful to the detection of cations and, therefore, to the determination of the composition of minerals.[...]</description><creator>Yu, P.L.</creator><contributor>Jolliff, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1948. </date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>Micro-chemical methods for mineral determination.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b6595.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vx191</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vp131</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Throughout the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries, Hume's philosophical -writings received little attention, except in Scottish circles, and it was not until the present century that Hume came to be generally regarded as one of the greatest British philosophers. At the time when I began this thesis, there was still relatively little published criticism of his ethical thought, for reasons which are discussed elsewhere. Interest has largely been confined to his epistemology, and his ethics have been neglected or treated as subsidiary to his theory of knowledge. It was never suggested, I think, until Professor Kemp Smith's Philosophy of David Hume appeared in 1941, that moral philosophy was Hume's original, and perhaps his main, concern. This suggestion, coming from such an authoritative source, might alone be thought to justify a re-examination of his ethical writings.[...]</description><creator>Yalden-Thomson, David C.</creator><contributor>Maclennan, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1948. </date><subject>Hume, David, 1711-1776.</subject><subject>ETHICS.</subject><title>Hume’s moral philosophy in the Treatise of human nature.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n204231q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vp131</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf268846c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The investigation to be described in this thesis forms part of a larger study which has been carried on in the Department of Biochemistry at McGill University since January 1940. The work was initiated at the beginning of the second World War under the sponsorship of the National Research Council of Canada with the object of improving the methods of preserving and administering human blood and with a view to the application of improvements in the use of blood in the treatment of the wounded. During the years of the war rapid advances were made in blood préservation as a resuit of the concerted efforts of numerous groups of investigators particularly in America and Great Britain.[...]The investigation to be described in this thesis forms part of a larger study which has been carried on in the Department of Biochemistry at McGill University since January 1940. The work was initiated at the beginning of the second World War under the sponsorship of the National Research Council of Canada with the object of improving the methods of preserving and administering human blood and with a view to the application of improvements in the use of blood in the treatment of the wounded. During the years of the war rapid advances were made in blood préservation as a resuit of the concerted efforts of numerous groups of investigators particularly in America and Great Britain.[...]</description><creator>Woodford, V.R.</creator><contributor>Denstedt, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1948. </date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>The influence of various factors on glycolysis in human blood during storage.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/794081235.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268846c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qf85nf34x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A study of the beta decay of 275 day Ce144 and its daughter 17.5 min. Pr144 , has been made using a thin lens magnetic spectrometer. Analysis of the beta-spectrum Indicates the presence of five spectra with end-points at 3.06 ± 0.09, 1.05 ± 0.05, 0.517 ± O.O36, 0.303 ± 0.020, and 0.179 ± 0.015 Mev. The first three have been assigned to Pr1 , the remaining two to Ce1 . Conversion lines at 90.1 ± 0.9 and 125 ± 1.3 Kev. are attributed to internal conversion of a 132 Kev. gamma-ray following the 0.179 Mev. beta-disintegration of Ce144 . Measurement of gammaray energies by spectrometric methods proved Impractical with the activity available, but absorption methods reveal three other gamma-rays of energies about 2, 0.5 and 0.22 Mev. The results of coincidence experiments are, on the whole, inconclusive, but indicate in general the complexity of the spectra. Tentative disintegration schemes are presented.</description><creator>Wolfson, Joseph Laurence.</creator><contributor>Foster, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1948. </date><subject>Physics. </subject><title>Disintegration of cerium of mass 144.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sx00d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nf34x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gh93h2766</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study has been stimulated by the increasing interest and efforts in the preschool education movement in Montreal, in which the writer has been fortunate to have had an active part. It has been the goal of the writer to help those people teaching and directing nursery schools in this area to establish minimum standards of education. It is hoped that data from the present study may be, in some way, useful in accomplishing this goal.[...]</description><creator>Willis, Edith Blair.</creator><contributor>Alexander, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1948. </date><subject>KINDERGARTEN.</subject><subject>Psychology.</subject><subject>CHILD STUDY.</subject><subject>PSYCHOLOGY, EDUCATIONAL.</subject><title>Factors relating to the teacher-child contacts in preschool education.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kt56p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h2766</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053k466</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Good Hope mine at Hedley , British Columbia , was discovered four years ago . Since then , a few thousand tons of gold ore have been mined . The purpose of this paper is to present the evidence that has been assembled indicating the controls that resulted in the formation of the known orebodies . The ore occurs as irregular bodies of skarn within the limestone members of an assemblage of volcanic rocks and limestone lenses . The writer concludes that the skarn bodies were produced by alteration of limestone , that the gold was introduced during this alteration , and that a set of vertical fractures in underlying rocks were probably the channels by which replacing solutions entered the limestone . A nearby dioritic stock may have been the source of the solutions . The report was planned as a preliminary study , to be revised and expanded following further work at the property.</description><creator>Whiting, Francis Beaumont.</creator><contributor>O'Neill, J.  (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1948. </date><subject>Geological Sciences. </subject><title>An investigation of the Good Hope mine, Hedley, B.C.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w295k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053k466</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11750</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>