<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:22:30Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):20925" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:02870w97d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The action of many antimicrobial agents is dependent on their ability to interact with biological membranes. A group of polypeptide antibiotics was found to have surface activite properties. One of them, gramicidinS, produced a minimum in the surface tension curve, which was attributed to instabilities in the intra-molecular hydrogen bonds. Biosurfactants were found to have a great effect on the two phase hydrolysis of cellulose by cellulase. Seven times as much sugar was produced by the hydrolysis of Sigmacell 100 when the biosurfactant sophorolipid was present. The surfactant affects the adsorption of cellulase onto cellulose, and prevents the cellulase from binding irreversibly to the cellulose and becoming inactive.</description><creator>Helle, Steve</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Biosurfactants &amp; cellulose hydrolysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806089v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870w97d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d093q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigates the coping methods, styles and strategies of 35 homosexual men who are infected with the human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) but remain asymptomatic. Subjects were recruited from a Montreal AIDS clinic and support groups for men with HIV. The effectiveness of the coping mechanisms were evaluated by correlating these to measures of depression, state and trait anxiety, psychosomatic symptomatology, perceived social support and global health. Data analyses revealed that men with HIV infection were generally well-adjusted and employed a variety of coping techniques. Cognitive attempts at coping were the most frequently used and were related to elevated levels of state and trait anxiety and poorer global health. Perceived social support proved to be an important determinant of global health, and a buffer for anxiety. Religious identity was related to an enhanced perception of social support, while individuals who had sought counselling were reported to be more anxious and in poorer health. Finally, education level was related to the development of effective and diverse coping methods, styles and strategies. The implication of these results and suggestions for further research are discussed.</description><creator>Bensoussan, Stephane</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Adjustment (Psychology)</subject><subject>HIV infections -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><title>Investigating the efficacy of coping styles of men with HIV infection</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128b965.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d093q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x2477</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Henry-Emile Chevalier was forced in exile by the December 1851 Coup d'Etat in France. In March 1853, he came to Montreal and joined Georges-Hippolythe Cherrier who had just started a new periodical called La Ruche Litteraire Illustree. In addition, during his stay in Montreal, Chevalier worked for several periodicals, was an active member of the Institut canadien de Montreal, and wrote many novels and serials depicting Canada's exoticism. This thesis will provide the most accurate biography of Chevalier up to date, it will also present an analysis of the exoticism in his novels and serials (1853-1960), and of his contribution to the evolution of serials in French Canada.</description><creator>Beauchamp, Claude</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Chevalier, H. Emile (Henri Emile), 1828-1879</subject><subject>Chevalier, H. Emile (Henri Emile), 1828-1879 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Authors, French-Canadian -- 19th century -- Biography</subject><title>Henry-Emile Chevalier et le feuilleton canadien-français (1853-1860)</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vp65h.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x2477</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vq27zp53g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recently, there has been growing interest in the status of functional projections (i.e. the determiner phrase (DP), the inflectional phrase (IP), and the complementizer phrase (CP)) in first language (L1) development. The purpose of this study of child second language (L2) acquisition was to determine the status of functional projections in the first months of L2 development. Data from two child subjects (with English as their L1) acquiring French as an L2 were examined for evidence of DP, IP and CP. The results show that all functional projections are present in the grammar from the earliest months of child L2 development. The implications of this finding for L1 and L2 acquisition theories are discussed.</description><creator>Grondin, Nathalie D.</creator><contributor>White, Lydia (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>French language -- Study and teaching -- Foreign speakers</subject><title>Functional projections in child second language acquisition of French</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t035k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zp53g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nv70c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Besides providing a biographical sketch of Bint al-Shati', this thesis analyzes her intellectual growth and provides the necessary information about her works relating to Qur'anic studies. The study also surveys al-Khuli's method of Qur'anic exegesis and Bint al-Shati' thinspace's attempts to apply it to her own works. Our analysis focuses on her works on Qur'anic studies such as al-Tafsir al-Bayani li al-Qur'an al-Karim, Maqal fi al-Insan and al-I'jaz al-Bayani li al-Qur'an wa Masa'il Ibn al-Azraq. The distinguishing features of her philological and thermatic approach are discussed and the main results obtained by the practical application of this method are shown to bring refreshing insights into the meaning of the Qur'an.</description><creator>Amīn, Muḥammad</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Bint al-Shāṭiʾ</subject><title>A study of Bint al-Shāṭiʾ's exegesis /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26xz40c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nv70c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mw386</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Policy research in education is a relatively new discipline which deals with the analysis of public policies governing education. The professional literature provides both a conceptual and methodological basis for defining what constitutes a public policy and the means to carry out different types of analysis. Using such a framework, this study analyzes the policy of the Government of Quebec with respect to the education of exceptional children. More specifically, the study focuses on the policy goals and legislative action of the Government. Three separate research questions are each addressed by a systematic analytical framework using a form of qualitative content analysis. The methodology consists first of summarizing all policy data in a computerized database and then scrutinizing these summary statements to search for and analyze emergent themes and the content of policy objectives and standing decisions. The relation between these elements is then determined on the basis of specified decision rules. This analysis has also been subjected to an inquiry audit to test for the dependability and trustworthiness of the results. The analysis reveals three emergent policy themes, over eighty specific objectives and almost 100 standing decisions, which are found in statutes, regulations, ententes and administrative documents. Various incongruencies between the goals and the legislative action are identified and discussed; implications for further research are presented, with reference to the literature.</description><creator>Smith, William J., 1947-</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Gifted children -- Education -- Law and legislation -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Education and state -- Québec (Province)</subject><title>The education of exceptional children in Québec : a study of government policy goals and legislative action</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cr49m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mw386</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cn69m5230</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The 1st of April, 1980 is a landmark date for the peoples of Southern Africa, for the SOUTHERN AFRICAN DEVELOPMENT COORDINATION CONFERENCE--SADCC--came into being on that day in Lusaka. At first sight, SADCC would seem to be an organization like others scattered all over the African continent and aiming at common development. However, although it can be compared with others in terms of objectives and organisation, new elements have emerged since its inception: modest short-term objectives, and ambitious long-term ones; a light organizational structure, and a commitment of the Governments involved to achieve the goals. One can ask what the trends in Civil Aviation are, given this background. This thesis presents a study not with the aim to fully respond to the question above, but to identify the path followed by Civil Aviation as a component of the integrated development sought by SADCC countries. For this purpose, special attention will be paid to the SOUTHERN AFRICA TRANSPORT AND COMMUNICATIONS COMMISSION--SATCC.</description><creator>Deus, Delfim de, 1942-</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>Civil aviation in SADCC countries : a new type of co-operation?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hg648.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m5230</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tn137</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The partition of surfactants and of a biosurfactant-producing microorganism was studied in polyethylene glycol and dextran aqueous two-phase systems. In the presence of sodium phosphate, surfactants distributed themselves according to their charge. Cationic surfactants preferred the bottom phase, while anionic surfactants were attracted to the top phase. Increasing the phosphate molarity, the pH, the polymer concentration or molecular weight all resulted in a more one-sided surfactant partitioning. Biosurfactant partition was weaker than synthetic surfactant partition due to their weaker effective charge and lack of strong specific affinity for one of the polymers. Bacillus subtilis cells partitioned very strongly to the bottom phase. Its biosurfactant, surfactin, was found in slightly larger quantities in the top phase. Batch fermentations were carried out in an aqueous two-phase system. Bacterial growth was not inhibited by the high polymer concentration. Surfactin was produced earlier and in larger quantities than in the regular mineral salts medium.</description><creator>Drouin, Carole M.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Partition of biosurfactants in two-phase fermentation media</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rf645.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tn137</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qt21c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Studies of proteoglycan-induced arthritis in mice revealed two previously unidentified features: polymorphonuclear leucocytes in knee joint cavities and sacroiliac joint involvement. Immunological studies of cellular responses to the proteoglycan revealed a lack of response prior to arthritis which was produced by a further injection. Further studies revealed that depletion of suppressor/cytotoxic T cells in vitro led to an increased response to antigen. Cellular responses in immune and preimmune mice involve helper T lymphocytes. The preimmune but not immune responses wee inhibited by mouse serum and involved a helper T cell dependent response. It did not involve detectable cell death or suppressor/cytotoxic T lymphocytes. Bacteria isolated from mice did not produce arthritis and showed no immune cross-reactivity with proteoglycan.</description><creator>Mathai, Lalitha</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Studies of proteoglycan induced arthritis in BALBc mice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m288h.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qt21c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r216k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The regional distribution of Holocene sediments of eastern Hudson Bay off the Great Whale River mouth was mapped using a grid of reflection seismic lines over 60 km long and covering an area of approximately 800 km$ sp2$ and data from eight piston cores. A larger data base and a greater area of study than that used in previous studies significantly increases our understanding of the sedimentation and deglaciation processes that have occurred in the area since the last deglaciation. Based on the seismic records and piston cores, four stratigraphic units overlying the Proterozoic bedrock (unit 1) were defined and interpreted: unit 2, glacial till deposited by a westward flowing ice sheet; unit 3, glaciolacustrine stratified muds deposited in glacial Lake Ojibway; unit 4, postglacial marine muds deposited in Tyrell Sea; unit 5, distal fluvio-deltaic sediments from the Great Whale River. Textural and geochemical analyses of individual laminae suggest that unit 3 rhythmites are true varves; dark "summer" laminae were deposited mainly by underflows during the open water season, and light "winter" laminae were deposited by overflows-interflows under a seasonal ice cover. Unit 5 covers approximately 400 km$ sp2$ and occurs as a deltaic constructional wedge which reaches 11 km offshore of the Great Whale River entrance. It was deposited between 3500 BP and 2800 BP from material supplied by the erosion of the Sakami Moraine and of glaciolacustrine and marine muds exposed along the river banks.</description><creator>Gonthier, Nicole</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>Holocene stratigraphy and sedimentation off the Great Whale River entrance, southeastern Hudson Bay</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dg86j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r216k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rf65f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The development of animal models for pancreatic cancer has magnified the controversy regarding the cell of origin of the tumor in animals and man. In rats, most pancreatic tumors have an acinar histology. By contrast, tumors in hamsters have a ductular morphology, resembling the predominant type of human exocrine pancreatic cancer. While some workers advocate a ductular origin for hamster tumors, others insist that the progenitor is an acinar cell. With the use of normal adult rat pancreatic ductular cell lines, this work shows that four representative pancreatic carcinogens all display dose-related genotoxicity to rat pancreatic ductular cells in vitro. Further, repeated exposure to sublethal doses induced anchorage-independent growth. Transformed cells, injected subcutaneously into isogeneic newborn rats, produced malignant tumors with ductular morphology. A novel achievement of this work was the production of ductular adenocarcinomas using streptozotocin, previously reported as only inducing islet cell tumors.</description><creator>Shepherd, Jessica</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Malignant transformation and differentiation of adult rat pancreatic duct cells in vitro</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x249s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rf65f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fj19p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Acid Deposition and Oxidant Model (ADOM) is an Eulerian long-range transport and deposition model. One of the most highly parametrized and least well established parts of the model is the cloud module that describes cloud formation, pollutant scavenging, aqueous-phase chemistry and wet deposition. As a means of gaining insight into the cloud module, results from simulations with the module are compared with the results of simulations for equivalent conditions with a three-dimensional dynamic cloud chemistry model. Comparisons of results for a variety of initial conditions show that wet-deposition of sulphate, nitrate and ammonium ions tend to be underpredicted by the cloud module and that the pH of the rain is overpredicted. However, the differences are for the most part not large. Concentrations of hydrogen peroxide deposited at the surface are significantly smaller in the ADOM module than in the cloud chemistry model. The results of the cloud module do seem to be sensitive to the model cloud top height.</description><creator>Glazer, Anna</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>Evaluation of the ADOM cloud module</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pp03v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fj19p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fm78p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A design for a unified model based on the hypermedia paradigm is proposed as a means to a better synergism of the functionalities of different knowledge manipulation tools. A survey of past and present hypermdia systems has been achieved, and their characteristics examined. Intelligent hypermedia-based system architectures have been evaluated, from which functional requirements for a unified architecture have been derived. Equivalence mappings based on Petri nets, that equate the structure and behavior of hypermedia networks and expert systems in a loose way, have ben developed. A unified model, that synthesizes the structural and behavioral equivalences among different knowledge representations in an object-oriented architecture is proposed.</description><creator>Fayad, Gilles</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Artificial Intelligence.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Towards the design of an intelligent hypermedia architecture</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gf11q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fm78p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xs55md10j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis seeks to determine if juvenile birds preferentially select foraging information from their parents, by examining the acquisition of novel food-finding skills in juveniles of a flock-feeding species, the ringdove (Streptopelia risoria). The first experimental examined the flock feeding behaviour of juvenile ringdoves foraging in a small aviary flock composed of kin and non-kin; frequencies of local enhancement, food begging and aggression were recorded, as well as the individuals that the juvenile associated with while searching for food. Juvenile ringdoves foraged significantly more often with their kin and were aggressed more by non-kin. The last three experiments tested juveniles on three components of foraging: novel food type, environmental colour cues associated with food and novel food-searching techniques. All three involved a choice-test where the juveniles had their father and an unrelated flock member as demonstrators. All three choice-tests showed there was no preference for selecting either demonstrator's solution. Juvenile doves in the field may appear to learn from their parents simply because they associate more with them. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Kapuscinsky Hatch, Karen</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Ringdove -- Behavior</subject><subject>Birds -- Food.</subject><subject>Birds -- Behavior.</subject><subject>Ringdove -- Food</subject><title>Acquisition of foraging skills in juvenile ringdoves : who do they learn from?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483k44c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55md10j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wh13v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Leaf surface wetness duration time is an important agrometeorological parameter that determines fungal infections and spread of plant diseases. Surface wetness could also contribute to the reduction of transpiration and enhance pesticide effectiveness. For these reasons, field and laboratory performances of commonly used electrical resistance (ER) sensors were compared with a beta-ray gauge (BRG). The BRG provided the most accurate measure of surface wetness duration which agreed favourably with visual observations since it uses a real leaf as a sensor. A commercially available electric grid sensor (Model 237, Campbell Scientific), which employs a hard epoxy-fibreglass board, was found to be accurate in the determination of wetness duration for tobacco but not for soybean leaves. A second cotton cloth ER sensor was found to record accurately wetness duration on tobacco leaves. The data indicated that the choice of an ER sensor for best results depends on the density of the crop canopy. If accurate measurements of leaf surface wetness are critical it is suggested that the BRG system be used.</description><creator>Armstrong, Robert</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Engineering, Agricultural.</subject><title>A comparative study between three electronic leaf wetness sensors and a beta-ray gauge /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j96021922.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wh13v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Renewable Resources</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tq57ns17z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Abnormally slow processing of language may be a factor contributing to the poor verbal memory seen in many patients with lesions of the anterior temporal region in the left hemisphere. This possibility was examined by comparing the performance of 12 patients with left temporal-lobe resections (LT), 10 patients with similar lesions in the right hemisphere (RT) and 13 normal control (NC) subjects on a lexical-decision task, a sentence-plausibility-judgement task, and a story-recall task. Stimuli were presented aurally, and, in the latter two tasks, at 5 different speech rates ranging from 125 words per minute (wpm) to 325 wpm. Recall of stories by LT subjects was not abnormally sensitive to the effect of increasing rate, although it was inferior to that by NC subjects at all speeds. LT patients presented aurally but not visually (Frisk and Milner, 1991), suggesting that the left anterior temporal region plays a special role in the processing of speech sounds.</description><creator>Johnsrude, Ingrid S.</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Recollection (Psychology)</subject><subject>Speech perception.</subject><subject>Temporal lobectomy.</subject><subject>Temporal lobe epilepsy.</subject><title>The effect of presentation rate on the comprehension and recall of speech after anterior temporal-lobe resection /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r2184.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57ns17z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cv12b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis aims to present and understand various accounts composed by medieval writers against the Isma'ilis and to determine the substance of the arguments forged by each writer to counter the Isma'ilis. Such writings were accepted without question by earlier researchers, and although a revision has been undertaken in more recent studies, the specific nature and orientation of anti-Isma'ili polemics has not been adequately investigated. Through a careful study of different arguments--arguments at times quite sophisticated and difficult to appreciate fully--, we try to show the evolution and development of the style of anti-Isma'ili polemics, the different temperaments of the polemicists studied, and some of the permanent and complimentary features within this tradition. An additional question examined in this study is the extent to which social, cultural and political factors had an impact on the shaping of this tradition and the various arguments employed within it.</description><creator>Merchant, Alnoor Jehangir</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Ismailites -- Controversial literature -- History and criticism</subject><subject>Ismailites -- Doctrines</subject><title>Types and uses of argument in anti-Ismāʻīlī polemics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73px125.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cv12b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tw286</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Blood lactate concentration and mean power output were examined over a series of maximal intermittent exercise bouts with varying recovery patterns. Thirteen elite male cyclists completed four randomly assigned experimental conditions. Each exercise/recovery condition consisted of twelve 10 s maximal exercise bouts on a Monark cycle ergometer. Four different recovery patterns (30, 60, 90 and 120 s) followed the repeated 10 s all-out efforts. Results revealed that the mean power output averaged over the 12 trials was 12.7, 13.0, 13.2 and 13.4 W/kg, for the 30, 60, 90 and 120 s conditions, respectively. Blood lactate concentration during exercise were 9.9, 9.2, 6.5 and 6.0 mmol/1, for the 30, 60, 90 and 120 s conditions, respectively. The 30 and 60 s conditions yielded significantly lower mean power output values compared to the 90 and 120 s conditions. Following the repeated maximal 10 s efforts, blood lactate concentration was significantly greater in the 30 and 60 s recovery conditions compared to the 90 and 120 s conditions.</description><creator>Mancini, Wendy F.</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Blood lactate.</subject><subject>Physical fitness -- Testing</subject><subject>Cycling -- Physiological aspects</subject><title>Power output and lactate concentration following repeated 10 s intervals using varying recovery patterns</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20st810.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tw286</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qb98mg658</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Montreal Repertory Theatre mounted a regular series of play productions every year from 1930 to 1961. They deliberately set out to follow the Little Theatre tradition of Antoine while profiting from later developments in England, Ireland and the United States. At a time when no alternatives existed in Montreal they provided theatre education at a high level and helped in the formation of many distinguished careers. This study examines the work of MRT in a historical context, and as revealed in the company's surviving documents and in contemporary reports. The written record is supplemented by interviews with persons who worked with MRT. A number of these have made contributions on a national scale to Canadian theatre.</description><creator>Booth, Philip, 1937-</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Theaters -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History</subject><subject>Montreal Repertory Theatre -- History</subject><subject>Little theater movement -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><title>The Montreal Repertory Theatre, 1930-1961 : a history and handlist of productions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719n468.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mg658</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w95051623</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines the relationship of Sir Sayyid Ahmad $ underline{ rm Kh}$an with the Indian $ sp{ rm c}$ulama'. As part of his reform movement, and in particular through his journal Tahzibu'l-Akhlaq, Sir Sayyid launched a severe attack on the $ sp{ rm c}$ulama'. He held the $ sp{ rm c}$ulama' directly responsible for leading the community to the verge of disintegration. For their part, the $ sp{ rm c}$ulama' thinspace's opposition to Sir Sayyid seems to have been inspired not so much by the theological ideas of Sir Sayyid as by the $ sp{ rm c}$ulama' thinspace's perception that Sir Sayyid's ideas, criticism and his reform movement in general were a challenge to their position and role in society. The $ sp{ rm c}$ulama' thinspace's opposition was venomous but, for a variety of reasons, it did not prove strong enough to deal a mortal blow to the reform movement of Sir Sayyid.</description><creator>Azizalam, Shaista</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Aḥmad Ḵẖāṉ, Sayyid, Sir, 1817-1898.</subject><subject>Ulama -- India</subject><title>Sayyid Aḥmad Khān and the ʻUlamāʾ : a study in socio-political context</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w3763806g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95051623</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514nm622</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this study of Vlady Kociancich's Ultimos dias de William Shakespeare, it will be shown how a totalitarian regime comes to consolidate its power through the imposition of a priviledged discourse that is postulated as the absolute truth. It will likewise be demonstrated that the characters trapped in this system are subjected to one single possible interpretation of individual and social realities. We will then examine the role played by the two protagonists, Santiago Bonday and Renata, in the closed world of Ultimos dias, as well as study the possibilities that these two main characters have of escaping the big lie of the official discourse. We will therefore see that the character's role as writers is fundamental.</description><creator>Romero, Victoria</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Kociancich, Vlady. Ultimos días de William Shakespeare</subject><title>La dialectica entre el "ser" O "no ser" en el mundo represivo de Ultimos dias de William Shakespeare de Vlady Kociancich /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t745d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nm622</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Hispanic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dn54q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>That Ghana derives her foreign exchange earnings mainly from cocoa and gold exports cannot be over emphasised. There is therefore the need to forecast these commodities prices as accurately as possible for proper planning and execution of major policies, since the prices have been notoriously volatile during the past two decades and attempts to stabilize especially the price of the beans (which contributes about 60% of the country's foreign exchange) through the system of buffer stock and export restrictions have not been successful. In this regard, autoregressive integrated moving averages models are built and used to generate short run forecasts for the beans and the precious metal price series. These models are simple to build and appear not only to describe the behaviour of the series but provide good forecasts of the prices.</description><creator>Ankrah, Samuel K. O.</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Cocoa -- Prices -- Mathematical models</subject><subject>Gold -- Prices -- Mathematical models</subject><subject>Prices -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>A case study of short-run forecasting of commodity prices : an application of autoregressive integrated moving average models</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kb85n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dn54q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj430588v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the Hebrew Bible, literary patterns of revelation and concealment are based on humanity's initial encounter with God in the Garden of Eden. God asks the question "Where are you?" Adam and Eve reveal themselves by articulating their concealment behind the fig leaf. This paradox effects their exile from Eden, and their progeny must henceforth mediate this paradox in their future verbal intercourse with God. It is the intention of this work to suggest how in certain textual passages, this paradox is defined and structured according to a literary dichotomy of language and silence. After the exile, biblical characters proclaim their presence before God by uttering a password ("Here I am") which is, in effect, an existential utterance of dialogic reconstruction. Through various literary devices, I hope to show how this "vertical" dialogue is re-established by Adam and Eve's progeny, and how the biblical narrator(s) uses language to show silence as a "phenomenon" of the word.</description><creator>Paul, Eddie</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Silence -- Religious aspects -- Judaism</subject><subject>Silence in the Bible</subject><title>Shibboleth into silence : a commentary on presence in the Hebrew Bible</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f4608.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430588v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752h79r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Japanese labour market is analyzed within a dual labour market context and an emphasis on firm size differentiation. Labour market segmentation theories are presented for the purpose of understanding the differences that can exist between industries, or in this case, between firm sizes. Data on labour market variables such as wages, unionism, and promotion illustrates the different employment package that employees face in small firms as compared to workers in large companies. Unique Japanese labour market traits such as the expectation of lifetime employment, enterprise unionism, and seniority-based wages are also observed to evaluate their application in different company sizes. Japan's labour market segmentation is primarily a study of differences between firm sizes. The dissimilarities in employment characteristics between small and large firms are thoroughly examined and evaluated for a solid understanding of Japan's duality in the labour market.</description><creator>Chrisanthopoulos, Themistoklis</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Labor market -- Japan</subject><subject>Business enterprises -- Japan</subject><title>Firm size differentiation in Japan</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n4487.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752h79r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hq37vp68b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research focuses on the involvement of chemists in professional Canadian environmentalism. We confront opposed research and development sector perspectives (government, industry, and university) to describe how incompatabilities between them resist cross-sectoral interaction and limit disciplinary greening. We then refer to original questionnaire and interview data to discuss the greening force of professional associations on a multisectoral discipline (chemistry). Finally, we consider plausible research avenues in the sociology of environment to address the current and future status of environmental chemistry.</description><creator>Bourdeau, Jean Pierre</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Chemical industry -- Environmental aspects -- Canada</subject><subject>Chemists -- Canada</subject><title>Professional environmentalism in Canadian chemistry : the greening of a discipline?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hg65j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vp68b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):20950</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>