<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T04:09:07Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):45725" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ms35tc12d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Interactions entre paiements pour services hydrologiques et transitions forestières: étude de cas du bassin hydrographique du Rio Cuale, Mexique. La conversion de forêts en terrains agricoles est actuellement considérée comme la cause principale de déforestation dans les tropiques. Malgré les tendances à la déforestation tropicale, certaines régions présentent maintenant un revirement du couvert forestier. Ce revirement de zones forestières a été appelé transition forestière et est basé sur le regain d'arbres en zones agricoles. L'objectif de cette étude est d'analyser les changements dans le paysage du bassin versant du Rio Cuale, une région où un mécanisme de compensation nommé 'paiement pour services écologiques (PSE) a été implémenté en 2005 afin d'éviter des futures pertes forestières. Nous avons utilisé des images satellitaires afin de détecter temporellement les changements d'utilisation du territoire au niveau régional (Landsat MSS pour 1979, TM pour 1990 et ETM pour 2002). Nous avons également réalisé des entrevues avec des ménages choisis aléatoirement dans les deux communautés propriétaires terriennes afin de déterminer les perceptions relatives à l'utilisation du territoire et l'utilité des PSE.  Nos résultats ont révélés, que contrairement aux tendances nationales, ce bassin versant présente un rétablissement des forêts. Les personnes entrevues ont identifiées plusieurs facteurs qui contribuent à ce revirement forestier, tels que la réduction de la surface cultivée et une augmentation de parcelles abandonnées. Ce processus a pour origine l'exode rural, les diversifications des modes de vies et les politiques locales. Cette enquête a également démontrée que malgré les taux négatifs de perte de couvert forestier, les propriétaires terriens acceptent volontairement des mécanismes de conservation visant à promouvoir la préservation du couvert forestier.   En conclusion, le rétablissement du</description><description>INTERACTIONS OF PAYMENT FOR HYDROLOGICAL SERVICES AND FOREST TRANSITIONS: A CASE STUDY OF THE RIO CUALE WATERSHED Conversion of forest cover to agricultural fields is currently considered the main cause of deforestation in the tropics. Despite the trends of tropical deforestation, certain areas are now presenting a turnaround in forest cover. This process of forest recovery has been called forest transition, and is based on the re-growth of trees in abandoned agricultural fields. The objective of this research is to analyze the changes in the landscape of the Rio Cuale watershed, an area where a compensatory mechanism called 'Payment for Ecosystem Services' (PES) was implemented in 2005 to avoid future forest loss.   In this case-study, we used satellite imagery to detect land-use changes over time at the regional level (Landsat MSS for 1979, TM for 1990 and ETM for 2002). In addition, we randomly sampled the two landholder communities and conducted a household survey to detect land use perceptions and suitability of PES.  Our results revealed, contrary to the national trends, that the watershed has been going through a forest recovery. Survey participants identified several factors of change that drove this forest recovery process, such as a decrease in land surface cropped and increase in parcels abandonment. These were caused by rural-to-urban migration, diversification of livelihood and local policies. The survey also revealed that despite the negative rates of forest loss, landholders willingly accept conservatory mechanisms that promote forest cover preservation.  Therefore, we conclude that the forest recovery trend is due to a change in economic demography in the watershed; however, this trend may be fostered by the PES program.</description><creator>Bauche, Paola</creator><contributor>Raja Sengupta (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2007</date><subject>Social Sciences - Geography</subject><title>Interactions of payment for hydrological services and forest transitions: a case study of the Rio Cuale watershed</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cn61k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tc12d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75dg448</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La présente étude introduit une nouvelle approche qui facilite l'exécution du balancement des bras pendant la marche chez des patients. Les principaux objectifs de cette étude étaient d'évaluer (1) les effets de l'utilisation de ces poignées coulissantes sur la coordination des membres supérieurs et inférieurs lors de la marche, et (2) les effets du balancement des bras, avec ou sans poignées coulissantes, sur la cinématique et les patrons d'activation des muscles des jambes. Dix patients ayant subi un accident vasculaire cérébral et dix adultes en santé ont marché sur un tapis roulant en balançant les bras naturellement de chaque côté du corps ou en tenant des poignées qui étaient soient coulissantes ou fixes sur les barres d'appui latérales du tapis roulant. Les données enregistrées incluent la cinématique et l'activité électromyographique des muscles des membres supérieurs et inférieurs. Les résultats ont démontré que les patrons de coordination bras-jambe ne sont pas influencés par l'utilisation des poignées coulissantes. Le balancement des bras a influencé l'activation des muscles des jambes. Ces résultats soutiennent la proposition d'inclure le balancement des bras dans des protocoles de réadaptation à la marche. Également, pour les patients incapables de marcher sans support externe, l'utilisation d'un tapis roulant équipé de poignées coulissantes s'avère être un substitut intéressant à la marche avec balancement naturel des bras.</description><description>This thesis introduces a new paradigm that is designed to facilitate the performance of arm movements during gait rehabilitation. The main purposes of the thesis were to assess (1) the effects of performing arm movements using this paradigm on the coordination of upper and lower limbs, and (2) the effects of arm movements on lower limb kinematic and muscle activation patterns.  Ten stroke and ten healthy subjects walked on a treadmill while swinging their arms naturally, and while holding onto handles that were either fixed in place or allowed to slide along horizontal handrails. Full-body kinematics were recorded, along with bilateral surface EMG from upper and lower body muscles.  Arm-leg coordination patterns were unaffected by the use of the sliding handles, and performing arm movements influenced lower limb muscle activation.  Overall, results support the inclusion of arm movements in gait rehabilitation protocols and, for patients who are unable to walk without any external support, the use of sliding handles appears to be a useful surrogate to natural arm swing.</description><creator>Stephenson, Jennifer</creator><contributor>Sophie Jeannine De Serres (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Anouk Lamontagne (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2007</date><subject>Health Sciences - Physical Therapy</subject><title>Coordination of upper and lower limbs during walking in stroke and healthy individuals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gw54t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75dg448</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04ds42h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La chrysomèle rayée du concombre (CRC) est le principal insecte ravageur des cucurbitacées. L'efficacité du kaolin pour contrôler la CRC (Acalymma vittatum) a été testée dans une culture de concombres. Un essai en champ de deux ans a comparé le kaolin (Surround WP) à un insecticide (carbaryl; Sevin XLR) et un témoin non traité. En 2005, la moyenne saisonnière de CRC était inférieure dans le kaolin. Le flétrissement bactérien (Erwinia tracheiphila) était plus abondant dans le témoin et le kaolin avait des rendements vendables significativement supérieurs aux autres traitements. En 2006, la moyenne de CRC dans le kaolin était comparable aux autres traitements. Le rendement vendable était significativement supérieur dans les parcelles traitées à l'insecticide. Une ou plusieurs applications de kaolin ont eu des effets négatifs sur les échanges gazeux de la feuille à court terme mais des effets négligeables sur la croissance des plants en serre. Lors de l'étude du comportement, le kaolin a réduit la présence des CRC et les dommages sur le feuillage. Le kaolin montre un bon potentiel comme alternative aux insecticides pour protéger les jeunes plants de cucurbitacées.</description><description>Striped cucumber beetle (SCB) is the main pest of cucurbits in northeastern America. This project examined the efficacy of kaolin clay in controlling SCB (Acalymma vittatum; Coleoptera: Chrysomelidae) in cucumbers. Field experiments compared kaolin (Surround WP), insecticide (carbaryl; Sevin XLR) and untreated controls. In 2005, mean number of beetles was lowest in the kaolin treatment. Bacterial wilt (Erwinia tracheiphila) was greater in the controls and kaolin plants had significantly higher marketable yields than the two other treatments. In 2006, SCB numbers in kaolin were similar to the other treatments. Total marketable yield was significantly higher in the insecticide than the other treatments. Single and multiple applications of kaolin had negative short term effects on gas exchange and only negligible effects on greenhouse grown plants. In behavior experiments, kaolin reduced settling and feeding damage by SCB on treated plants. Kaolin shows potential as an alternative to insecticide especially to protect seedlings and young plants.</description><creator>Legault, Geneviève</creator><contributor>Katrine A Stewart (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2007</date><subject>Biology - Entomology</subject><title>Effect of kaolin on the striped cucumber beetle («Acalymma vittatum») and cucumber growth and development</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892d79z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04ds42h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v569q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>As solutions of the Einstein-Maxwell field equations, the Kerr-Newman-de Sitter geometries are spacetimes that model the outer geometry of a charged, rotating black hole.  We re-derive, using a lemma of Brandon Carter, first-order conserved quantities for the motion of zero rest mass and massive test particles in the Kerr-Newman-de Sitter spacetimes.  The Liouville-Arnol'd integrability theory allows us to use first integral equations in place of second-order equations in the dynamical analysis.  In examining the effects of first integral data on the equations, we expose some differences between particle dynamics in the electrically-neutral, asymptotically-flat Kerr geometries and those in the charged, de Sitter geometries.</description><description>Les géométries de Kerr-Newman-de Sitter sont des solutions des équations d'Einstein-Maxwell avec constante cosmologique modélisant la partie extérieure de l'espace-temps au voisinage d'une configuration d'équilibre d'un trou noir en rotation. Nous calculons a l'aide d'un lemme de Brandon Carter les quantités conservées du premier ordre associées au mouvement de particules d'épreuve de masse nulle et non-nulle dans la métrique de Kerr-Newman-de Sitter. Le théorème d'intégrabilité de Liouville-Arnol'd nous permet d'utiliser ces quantités conservées pour analyser la dynamique. Ceci nous permet de mettre en evidence les différences entre la dynamique des particules selon que l'on introduit ou non un champ électromagnétique et une constante cosmologique.</description><creator>Rayan, Steven</creator><contributor>Niky Kamran (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2007</date><subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics</subject><title>Particle dynamics in Kerr-Newman-de Sitter spacetimes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bm157.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v569q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591c086</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La prépondérance des études en psychothérapie sont menées avec les clients de la culture majoritaire. Ceci a généré un besoin de saisir l'impact de la culture sur le processus thérapeutique. Cette étude a évalué un modèle qui explique l'impact des éléments tels que l'intégration, les valeurs individualistes-collectivistes et de l'accord ou désaccord des valeurs entre client et thérapeute sur le développement du rapport thérapeutique et de la fin prématurée. Le modèle suggère que le dégré de franchise du client est lié aux variables culturelles et est important au développement du rapport thérapeutique. La compétence multiculturelle du thérapeute a été évaluée en tant que médiateur et modérateur.  Quarante-un clients et quinze conseillers ont été suivis durant la première phase de thérapie. Les thérapeutes et clients ont complété des questionnaires évaluant leur perspective de la compétence multiculturelle des thérapeutes ainsi que leurs propres valeurs individualistes-collectivistes. Les clients ont aussi évalué leur dégré d'intégration. Après les premiers entretiens, les clients ont évalué leur dégré de franchise et l'alliance thérapeutique. Les conseillers ont indiqué si les clients ont mis fin prématurément à la thérapie. Les données ont soutenu un modèle où la compétence multiculturelle du thérapeute a prédit la franchise du client, et par conséquent le niveau de l'alliance thérapeutique. La compétence multiculturelle a aussi tempéré l'impact de la franchise du client et de l'alliance thérapeutique pour les clients avec une plus forte identité culturelle et sur l'alliance pour les clients moins individualistes. La perception du client, plutôt que celui du thérapeute a prédit le processus de psychothérapie. De plus, ces deux perspectives de compétence n'avaient pas de corrélation.  Les résultats suggèrent que la compétence multiculturelle a un impact important sur la franchise</description><description>The prevalence in psychotherapy research of studies conducted with European-American clients has created a need for research on the impact of ethnicity and culture on the process of psychotherapy. This study tested a model examining the impact of client acculturation, individualism-collectivism and match in worldview between client and counsellor on the development of the therapeutic alliance and premature termination. Client openness was hypothesized to mediate the relationship between the cultural variables and the working alliance. Therapist multicultural competence was tested as both a mediator and a moderator of the impact of the independent variables on client openness and the working alliance.  Forty one dyads (41 clients, 15 counsellors) were followed during the early phase of therapy. Counsellors and clients completed measures of perceived counsellor multicultural competence and Individualism-Collectivism and clients also reported their current levels of acculturation. After each early session, clients reported their perceptions of openness and alliance. Counsellors indicated if clients terminated prematurely.  The data supported a smaller model than originally proposed in which counsellor multicultural competence related to client openness, which in turn affected the strength of the working alliance. Multicultural competence also moderated the impact on openness and alliance for clients with a stronger heritage identity and on the alliance for less individualistic clients. In these findings, client rather than counsellor ratings predicted psychotherapy process; these two perspectives of competence were not correlated.      Results suggest that multicultural competence has an important impact on openness and the working alliance with all diverse clients, more specifically with clients closer to their heritage identity and less individualistic values. The findings also indicate that client cultural variables (acculturation, individualism-collectivism and</description><creator>Jaouich, Alexia</creator><contributor>Marilyn R Fitzpatrick (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2007</date><subject>Education - Psychology</subject><title>The impact of cultural variables and multicultural competence: a model of early therapy process</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zk509.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591c086</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj1394810</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le gène troponin I rapide (TnIfast) est un member d'une famille de gènes multiple don't   les members s'expriment d'une façons differente celon le type de fibre du muscle   squelettique.  La spécificité pour le type de tissue et le type de fibre du gène TnIfast est   due a un "intronic regulatory element" (IRE) situé dans le premier intron.  Le IRE est un   enhancer de 148 bp qui contient quatre éléments-cis connus; E-box, MEF2, CCAC et le   CAGG elements.  Une étude précédente dans notre laboratoire a suggeré que la   spécificité du gène troponin I rapide pour le type de fibre est due a des éléments résidant   dans les 30 pair de bases situé dans l'éxtrimité gauche du IRE, une région qui contient le   site "E-box".  Mon but initial était de localise cet élément hypothétique dans ces 30 pairs   de bases de l' IRE.  Mon approche experimental était de préparer des versions du IRE   mutées ou tronquées partiellement.  Ces derives de IRE ont été couplés a un gène signal   consistant en un promoter TnI fast minimal lié avec le gène LacZ.  L'activité   transcriptionnelle de ces construits été evalué par transfert de gène in vivo dans le muscle   squelettique de souris adults.  Cela été suivit par l'analyse histochimique de l'expression   du gène signal, le LacZ.  Mes resultats ont montre que le E-box n'était pas essentielle   pour l'expression ou la spécificité pour les fibre rapide de l' IRE dans les muscle   squelettique.  De plus, des experiences additionelle ont indique que les 30 bp sont pas   essentiel pour la spécificité pour le type de fibre rapide et cela en contradiction avec   l'étude précédant.  Dans des études additionelles j'ai pu montrer qu'un sègment de 49 bp   de l' IRE, inclue les éléments MEF2 et CCAC, est suffisant pour causée l'expression de   la spécificité pour le fibre rapide.</description><description>The troponin I fast (TnIfast) gene, a member of a differentially-expressed three-member   TnI multigene family is expressed specifically in fast skeletal muscle fibers.  The tissue   and fiber type specificity of the TnIfast gene is driven by an Intronic Regulatory Element   (IRE) in the first intron.  The IRE is a 148 bp transcriptional enhancer, that contains four   known or suspected cis regulatory elements; E-box, MEF2, CCAC, and CAGG elements.    A previous study in this lab suggested that fast-fiber type specificity is driven by   elements that reside in the 5'-most 30 bp of the IRE, a region that includes the E-box   motif.  My initial goal was to further localize the hypothetical fast fiber type specific   element(s) within this region.  The experimental approach was to make IRE partial   deletions and mutations in reporter gene constructs in which IRE derivatives were cloned   upstream of an enhancer-dependent TnI fast minimal promoter driving the reporter gene   LacZ.  The transcriptional activity of these constructs in fast and slow muscle fibers was   evaluated by direct gene transfer into adult mouse skeletal muscle followed by   histochemical analysis of LacZ reporter expression.  My results showed that the E-box   was not required for IRE fast-fiber specificity or high-level expression in adult skeletal   muscles.  Moreover, additional deletion constructs indicated, in contrast with the previous   study, that the 5'-most 30 bp segment is not required for fast-fiber-specificity.  I was able   to show that a 49 bp IRE segment, not including the 5'-most 30 bp, but including MEF2   and CCAC elements, is sufficient to drive fast-fiber specific expression in adult mouse   skeletal muscles.  I discuss possible causes for the discordant results between the two   studies, and the implications of my findings for the regulatory mechanisms of the IRE.</description><creator>Awad, Lamia</creator><contributor>Kenneth E M Hastings (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2007</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>A 49 base-pair region of the IRE enhancer directs fast skeletal muscle fiber-type-specific expression of the troponin I (fast) gene</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816q255.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj1394810</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7m01bp38d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'étude des hydrates gazeux est un sujet de recherche très actif dû à la vaste quantité de méthane présente sur Terre sous cette forme ainsi que la possibilité de pouvoir réduire les émissions de gaz à effet de serre grâce à la séquestration du dioxyde de carbone sous forme d'hydrate gazeux.  Cette étude présente les différentes relations d'équilibre de phases entre la pression, la température et la composition des phases liquide, vapeur et d'hydrate pour deux systèmes; un système propane-eau et un système CO2-CH4-eau. La première partie de cette étude consistait à déterminer la concentration de propane dissous dans l'eau en présence d'hydrates de propane à des températures et des pressions variant respectivement entre 274 et 277 K et 150 à 350 kPa.  Les solubilités mesurées en absence d'hydrates étaient en accordance avec les données de littérature disponibles, prédisant une augmentation de la solubilité avec une diminution de température.  La solubilité du propane dans la région de formation d'hydrate a une relation inverse par rapport à la solubilité dans la région gaz-liquide.  Conséquemment, la solubilité du propane en présence d'hydrates diminue avec une diminution de la température.  Les résultats obtenus montrent également que la pression a une faible influence sur la solubilité en présence d'hydrates gazeux. La deuxième partie de cette étude consistait à étudier les relations d'équilibre de phases pour un système d'hydrates mixte de CH4/CO2 –eau à des températures variant entre 274 et 282 K et des pressions variant entre 2000 et 2500 kPa.  En l'absence d'hydrates, la solubilité de chaque gaz dans la phase liquide décroissait avec une augmentation de la température.  Dans la région de formation d'hydrates gazeux, la solubilité du CH4 et du CO2 dans l'eau diminuait avec une diminution de la température.  Similairement à des systèmes avec un seul gaz, la formation d'hydrate gazeux inverse$</description><description>Gas hydrates are a topic of intense investigation primarily due to the vast amount of methane trapped in the form of gas hydrate on Earth and to the possibility of reducing greenhouse gas emissions via the sequestration of carbon dioxide in the form of gas hydrate. In the present study, phase equilibrium relationships of pressure, temperature, and composition in the liquid, vapour, and hydrate phases for the pure propane-water and CO2-CH4 mixed hydrate-water systems have been investigated. In the first part of the study, the concentration of propane dissolved in water in the presence of propane gas hydrates has been measured at temperatures from 274 K to 277 K and pressures ranging from 150 kPa to 350 kPa. Solubility measurements in the absence of hydrate were found to be in agreement with literature values, which predict an increase in solubility as temperature is decreased. In the hydrate formation region, the solubility of propane decreased with decreasing temperature. Therefore, hydrate formation reverses the gas-liquid solubility trend. Results also show that pressure does not have a strong influence on solubility in the presence of gas hydrate.  In the second part of the study, phase equilibrium relationships for a 50/50 CH4/CO2 mixed hydrate-water system have been investigated at temperatures between 274 K and 282 K and at pressures of 2000 kPa and 2500 kPa. In the absence of hydrate, solubility of each gas in the aqueous phase decreased with increasing temperature. In the hydrate formation region, solubility of both CH4 and CO2 in water was found to decrease with decreasing temperature. Therefore, as previously concluded with single gas systems, hydrate formation reversed the gas-liquid solubility trend for each gaseous component in the mixed hydrate system. Results also showed that pressure did not have a strong influence on the solubility of each component in the presence of mixed gas hydrate. Furthermore, by mole balance, water-free mixed hydrate compo</description><creator>Gaudette, Jason</creator><contributor>Phillip Servio (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2007</date><subject>Engineering - Chemical</subject><title>Phase equilibria and solubility measurements of gases in water in the hydrate formation region</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g290f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bp38d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dz010s90d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Head motion is a significant source of image quality degradation in neurological PET scans.  It is especially detrimental in PET scanners with high resolution, specifically the HRRT (High Resolution Research Tomograph) with a spatial resolution of approximately 2.5 mm.  Head restraints are often used to minimize subject movement and subject comfort is essential to obtain reliable data.  We have investigated subject movement during long scans (over an hour) and subject repositioning accuracy for a series of scans.  The Polaris Vicra is a commercially available optical measurement device we used to measure the position and orientation of the subject's head over the course of the scan.  A tracking tool was attached to a swim cap worn by the subject and tracked relative to a second tool attached to the scanner gantry.  The head is a body part that can be treated as a rigid body.  For rigid bodies, movement detected at the surface can be directly translated to any point in that body.  We have used this principle and the Polaris Vicra's movement data to track several ROIs in subject's brains.  We found that over the course of a long scan, ROIs placed near the occipital pole can move as much as 14 mm.  This will cause significant blurring in images taken with the HRRT.  The repositioning device tested was very accurate and repositioned the subject within 2 mm of her initial position.</description><description>Les mouvements de la tête sont une source significative de dégradation de la qualité de l'image provenant de PET scans.  Ils jouent un rôle particulièrement négatif avec les scanners PET à haute définition comme le HHRT (High Resolution Research Tomograph) qui possède une résolution approximative de 2,5 mm.  Différents outils de stabilisation de la tête sont souvent utilisés afin de minimiser les mouvements, et le confort du sujet est essentiel pour obtenir des résultats fiables.  Nous avons testé les mouvements du sujet au cours de longs scans (plus d'une heure) ainsi que la précision du repositionnement du sujet lors d'une série de scans.  Le Polaris Vicra est un instrument de mesure optique disponible sur le marché que nous avons utilisé pour mesurer la position et l'orientation de la tête du sujet durant le scan. Un outil mesurant les mouvements de la tête relativement au scanner a été attaché à un bonnet de bain déposé sur la tête du sujet.  La tête peut être considérée comme un corps rigide.  Pour les corps rigides, un mouvement détecté à la surface est directement relié au mouvement de n'importe quel point sur ce corps.  Nous avons utilié ce principe ainsi que les données de mouvement du Polaris Vicra afin de dépister plusieurs régions d'intérêts dans le cerveau du sujet.  Nous démontrons que durant un long scan, les régions d'intérêts situés près du pôle occipital peuvent se déplacer sur près de 12 mm.  Ceci peut donc rendre l'image floue.  L'outil de repositionnement testé s'est avéré très précis et a repositionné le sujet en deçà de 2 mm de sa position initiale.</description><creator>Woch, Katherine</creator><contributor>Christopher J Thompson (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2007</date><subject>Physics - Radiation</subject><title>Use of the Polaris Vicra for monitoring subject head movement during neurological PET scans</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gw553.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010s90d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Medical Physics Unit</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1544bs209</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Des structures formées de couches minces métalliques et céramiques sont couramment utilisées dans la conception de microsystèmes électromécaniques (MEMS). Ces derniers se retrouvent dans plusieurs domaines, tels que les capteurs, les vidéoprojecteurs et les systèmes de génération d'énergie portable. Pour concevoir des MEMS fiables, les propriétés mécaniques de ces couches minces doivent êtres connues précisément. Le but de cette thèse est d'utiliser la méthode de nanoindentation pour déterminer les propriétés mécaniques des couches minces de carbure de silicium Hexoloy-SG. Ce matériel à été développé pour des microsystèmes opérant dans des conditions thermiques et chimiques extrêmes. La nanoindentation a été réalisée par le système TriboIndenter® de Hysitron équipé d'une pointe Berkovich en diamant, de forme pyramidale à base triangulaire. Chaque indentation comprend un cycle charge/décharge durant lequel la pointe indentatrice est enfoncée et retirée du matériel par une force calibrée, tandis que la profondeur de l'indentation est surveillée continuellement au nanomètre près. La première partie de cette thèse décrit une procédure détaillée pour la nanoindentation avec le système TriboIndenter®, incluant la calibration de l'instrument utilisant une norme en quartz monolithique. Également, l'identification d'erreurs expérimentales reliées au système de nanoindentation dues à la dérive, aux vibrations et à la rugosité de l'échantillon et leurs mesures correctrices sont présentées. Par après, cette méthodologie a été utilisée pour tester les propriétés mécaniques d'une couche mince de Hexoloy-SG mesurant 2.1 µm d'épaisseur, déposée sur un substrat de silicium monocristallin comptant 500 µm d'épaisseur. La force exercée par l'indentateur sur l'échantillon varie de 1,000 µN à 11,000 µN, pour que la profondeur de l'indentation demeure en deçà de 10% de l'épaisseur totale de la co</description><description>Thin films of metals and ceramics are commonly used as the structural materials for microelectromechanical systems (MEMS). These systems are used for a wide range of applications that include sensors, displays, and portable power generators. Accurate measurement of the mechanical properties of these thin films is essential for the robust design of high-performance and reliable MEMS. In this thesis, the method of nanoindentation is used to characterize the elastic properties of thin films of Hexoloy-SG silicon carbide. This material is of particular interest for MEMS operating in harsh, hightemperature environments. Nanoindentation was performed using a commercial Hysitron TriboIndenter® equipped with a diamond Berkovich nanoindenter tip. During each nanoindentation test, the indenter was forced into the specimen by a calibrated load, while the indentation depth was recorded continuously with nanometer resolution. The first part of this thesis describes a detailed protocol for nanoindentation testing using the TriboIndenter® and discusses the calibration of the instrument using a quartz standard. The identification of errors due to drift, vibrations, and surface inhomogeneities is described in detail. This protocol was then used to test a 2.1 µm thick film of Hexoloy-SG silicon carbide film deposited on a 500 µm thick single-crystal silicon substrate. The film was tested with loads varying from 1,000 µN to 13,000 µN, such that the maximum indentation was always less than 10% of the film thickness. The nanoindentation load-displacement curves from a total of 155 individual indents were analyzed using three different methods to extract the value of the Young's modulus of the Hexoloy film. The first method, developed by Oliver and Pharr, is widely used in nanoindentation analysis, but does not account explicitly for the effects of the underlying substrate. It is valid strictly for monolithic materials. Therefore, refinements of the Oliver-Pharr method by King a</description><creator>Crocker, Janina</creator><contributor>Srikar Vengallatore (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2007</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical</subject><title>Measurement of the Young's modulus of Hexoloy silicon carbide thin films using nanoindentation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395wb25f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bs209</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kd52h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Flow through the Keeyask Generating Station's diversion and spillway (rollway), to be constructed 730km north of Winnipeg, Canada on the Nelson River, is investigated by a comparison of a numerical model and a 1:50 scaled sectional physical model.  The physical model was constructed at the LaSalle Consulting Group's laboratory in a permanent flume.  A commercially available computational fluid dynamics (CFD) program, Flow3D, was used to model the physical model by using the Reynolds-averaged Navier-Stokes equations in combination with the standard K-e eddy-viscosity closure model.  In order to determine the required mesh size to obtain a mesh independent solution tests were conducted on the diversion structure in 2D for four partial gate openings and in 3D for a fully open gate condition, as 2D did not model the contraction of the physical model adequately.  Mesh independence was only obtained for the fully open condition and was nearly obtained for a 6m gate opening while other gate openings diverged with refinement.  Further refinement was not realistic due to excessive computing times.  The two meshes that adequately modeled the flow were used for all subsequent investigations.  Sensitivity tests were performed for the diversion structure for the fully open case in 3D and the 6m gate opening in 2D in order to observe the effects of the numerical model scale (prototype, 1:50 scale) and the effects of two turbulence models (K-e, RNG).  For both tests, similar results were obtained.   Finally, numerical modeling was performed in 3D for the fully open gate condition for both the diversion and rollway structures in order to compare discharges/discharge coefficients, water surfaces and pressures to those of the physical model.  Modeling of partial gate openings in 3D was not possible due to large calculation times.  Results for the fully open case showed that the numerical model and physical model are in reasonably good agreement with one another.</description><description>L'écoulement des eaux vers l'ouvrage de dérivation et l'évacuateur de crues de la centrale Keeyask, qui sont projetés sur la rivière Nelson, à 730 km au nord de Winnipeg (Canada), est étudié par la comparaison d'un modèle numérique et d'un modèle réduit à l'échelle 1:50, qui a été construit dans le laboratoire du Groupe-Conseil LaSalle.  Le logiciel Flow3D a été utilisé pour simuler les conditions étudiées au modèle réduit, en utilisant les équations de Reynolds en combinaison avec la méthode de fermeture K-e.  Pour s'assurer que le maillage du modèle était adéquat pour modéliser l'écoulement, des essais ont été effectués sur l'ouvrage de dérivation en 2D pour des ouvertures partielles des vannes et en 3D pour l'ouverture complète (le 2D n'étant pas en mesure de modéliser la réduction en largeur simulée sur le modèle réduit) afin de déterminer le niveau de raffinement du maillage requis pour obtenir une solution indépendante de ce dernier. L'indépendance du maillage a été atteinte uniquement pour une ouverture complète de la vanne et presque atteinte pour une ouverture de 6m.   Pour des raisons inconnues, toutes autres ouvertures partielles des vannes ont conduit à des solutions divergentes.  De plus, le raffinement supplémentaire des maillages n'était pas possible, à cause des temps de calcul excessifs.   Les maillages utilisés pour l'ouverture complète et l'ouverture de 6m ont donc été utilisés pour toutes les autres simulations.  Des essais de sensibilité ont été effectués sur l'ouvrage de dérivation pour ces deux ouvertures, en vue d'observer l'effet du changement de l'échelle du modèle numérique (échelle 1:50 et prototype) et l'effet de deux différentes méthode de fermeture (K-e et RNG) sur l'écoulement.  Pour les deux essais, des solutions semblables ont été obtenues.  Finalement, des simulations numériques ont été effectuées en 3D pour une ouverture complète sur l'ouvrage de dériva</description><creator>Gacek, Julian</creator><contributor>Susan J Gaskin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2007</date><subject>Engineering - Civil</subject><title>Numerical simulation of flow through a spillway and diversion structure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j333516c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kd52h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vk709</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigates consequences of hiring native English speakers, many of whom are untrained as teachers, to teach English in foreign language contexts. The focus is on Assistant Language Teachers (ALTs) on the Japan Exchange and Teaching (JET) Programme. Two discourses, nihonjinron (theories of Japanese distinctiveness) and kokusaika (internationalisation), upon which the programme is founded, provide the framework for analysis. Through surveys and interviews, ALTs' attitudes towards the global spread of English and models of English teaching are elicited. Participants were 120 ALT alumni from the five Inner Circle (Kachru, 1985) countries. Surveys yielded quantitative and qualitative data. Content analysis of four in-depth interviews complements the analysis of survey findings. Results reveal a general lack awareness of the global role of English and its impact on English teaching. The major implication is that training could alleviate many of the consequences that follow from this result.</description><description>La présente étude examine les conséquences de l'embauche, comme enseignants, de personnes de langue maternelle anglaise pour dispenser des cours d'anglais dans des pays étrangers; ces nouveaux enseignants n'ayant pour la plupart pas suivi de formation à cette fin. Nous nous sommes intéressés plus particulièrement aux auxiliaires d'enseignement au sein du programme Japan Exchange and Teaching (JET). Le cadre théorique se construit à partir des deux discours sur lesquels ce programme est fondé: le nihonjinron (théories de particularités japonaises) et le kokusaika (théorie de l'internationalisation). À travers des sondages et des entretiens, nous avons examiné l'attitude de 120 auxiliaires d'enseignement, originaires des cinq pays du cercle intérieur (Kachru, 1985), face à l'expansion globale de l'utilisation de l'anglais et face aux différents modèles d'enseignement de l'anglais. Nos sondages visaient la collection de données tant qualitatives que quantitatives. De plus, le contenu de quatre entretiens nous a permis d'approfondir l'analyse des résultats des sondages recueillis. Nos résultats révèlent un manque général de connaissance concernant le rôle mondial de l'anglais et des impactes qui en découlent pour l'enseignement dispensé. Une formation adéquate des enseignants devrait atténuer les conséquences néfastes qu'un tel manque de connaissance peut engendrer.</description><creator>Crump, Alison</creator><contributor>Carolyn E Turner (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Mekhala Sarkar (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2007</date><subject>Education - General</subject><title>Examining the role of assistant language teachers on the JET Programme within the context of Nihonjinron and Kokusaika: perspectives from ALTs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gr09d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vk709</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74ct43c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>En Trinidad les implications de la haute concentration de sédiments devient un grand souci. Trois modèles ont été utilisés pour estimer les quantités de sédiments des pertes du sol causé par la pluie dans les 41 Km2 de St. Joseph River Catchment. Les deux modèles empiriques ont été RUSLE et MUSLE pour la prédiction d'événements simples et le modèle physique, Erosion 3, utilisé aussi pour la prédiction d'événements simples. Un réseau hydrologique a été construit en incluant un Optical Backscatter sensor (OBS) en ligne, et un échantillonneur de la qualité de l'eau. RUSLE a prédit sept fois plus de sédiments pour l'année 2006 que la valeur réelle mesurée. MUSLE a prouvé être un modèle précis lorsque les pluies atteignent plus de 10mm de colonne. Erosion 3D est considéré précis pour des hauteurs de colonne de plus de 6mm. Les deux modèles deviennent plus précis en fonction de l'augmentation de la quantité de sédiments, et de l'hauteur de la colonne d'eau.</description><description>In Trinidad the implications of high sediment concentrations in the rivers are becoming a major concern. Three models were used to estimate sediment loads from soil loss due to rainfall in the 41 km2 St. Joseph River Catchment. The models were the empirically-based RUSLE and MUSLE for annual and single event loading predictions, respectively and the physically based, Erosion 3D, for single event loading predictions.  A hydrologic network was constructed that included an on-line Optical Backscatter sensor (OBS), and a water quality sampler. RUSLE overpredicted the measured sediment yield for the year 2006 seven-fold. MUSLE provided reasonable estimates for rain events greater than 10 mm. For Erosion 3D, estimates for rainfall depths greater than 6 mm were reasonably predicted. For both models, estimates improved with increasing sediment load and rainfall depth.</description><creator>Jaramillo, Fernando</creator><contributor>Vincent Anthony Cooper (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Susan J Gaskin (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2007</date><subject>Engineering - Civil</subject><title>Estimating and modeling soil loss and sediment yield in the Maracas-St. Joseph River catchment with empirical models (RUSLE and MUSLE) and a physically based model (EROSION 3D)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sg435.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74ct43c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214s024</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La transcriptase inverse du Virus d’Immunodéficience Humaine de type 1 (VIH-1) est responsable de la transcription du génome viral composé d’ARN simple brin en ADN double brin.  Étant donné son rôle vital dans le cycle viral, cet enzyme est une cible de choix pour le traitement des patients infectés par le VIH-1.  Les inhibiteurs qui bloquent la transcriptase inverse affectent régulièrement l’incorporation des nucléotides.  Après l’incorporation d’un nucléotide, ce dernier est toujours situé dans le site de liaison des nucléotides.  Afin de libérer ce site, la transcriptase inverse doit se déplacer d’un nucléotide par rapport à la matrice d’acide nucléique, déplacement que nous appelons la translocation.  Celle-ci est un mouvement très rapide qui est cinétiquement invisible.  Afin d’étudier le mécanisme de translocation, j’ai dévelopé des tests d’empreinte moléculaire ayant une résolution d’un seul nucléotide nous permettant de détecter la position précise de l’enzyme sur une matrice d’ADN.  En utilisant ces tests, en combinaison avec des analyses cinétiques et autres expériences enzymatiques, j’ai étudié le statut translocationel de la transcriptase inverse, et nous en sommes venus à la conclusion que cet enzyme se déplace selon un modèle dans lequel un mouvement Brownien est responsable du déplacement de l’enzyme.  Celui-ci est stabilisé par la liaison d’un nucléotide dans le stade post-translocationel.  J’ai identifié des facteurs importants influençant la translocation : la séquence de la matrice d’acide nucléique, la nature du nucléotide à l’extrémité 3’ de l’amorce, la présence d’erreurs d’association dans le substrat d’acide nucléique double brin, la présence de nucléotides, la présence d’inhibiteurs, la nature de ces inhibiteurs, la présence de mutations conférant une résistance aux médicaments et la température ont tous été démontrés comme mod</description><description>The reverse transcriptase of the Human Immunodeficiency Virus type 1 (HIV-1) is responsible for transcribing the viral single-stranded RNA genome into double-stranded DNA.  Due to its vital role in the viral life cycle, it is often targeted in the treatment of HIV-1 infected patients.  Inhibitors that block the reverse transcriptase enzyme were shown to interfere with nucleotide incorporation.  At the end of a nucleotide incorporation cycle, the newly incorporated substrate is still located in the nucleotide binding site.  In order to continue the elongation of the DNA chain, the enzyme has to move by one nucleotide relative to the nucleic acid template to free the nucleotide binding site.  This movement is referred to as translocation.  Translocation is extremely rapid and is therefore kinetically invisible.  In order to study the mechanism of translocation, I developed site-specific footprinting assays with a resolution of a single nucleotide, which allowed us to detect the precise positioning of the reverse transcriptase on a DNA template.  Using these techniques, in combination with kinetic analysis as well as other enzymatic assays, I studied the translocational status of the reverse transcriptase in various conditions, and concluded that this enzyme translocates according to a “Brownian ratchet model”.  In this model, the enzyme oscillates between pre- and post-translocated positions and the nucleotide substrate traps the post-translocational state.  I identified important factors that affect the translocational equilibrium: the sequence of the nucleic acid template, the nature of the nucleotide at the 3’ end of the primer, the presence of mismatches in the double-stranded nucleic acid substrate, the presence of nucleotides, the presence of inhibitors, the nature of these inhibitors, the presence of drug resistance conferring mutations and the temperature are parameters that have all been shown to modify the translocational equilibrium of the reverse</description><creator>Marchand, Bruno</creator><contributor>Matthias Gotte (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2007</date><subject>Biology - Microbiology</subject><title>Effects of antiretroviral drugs on the translocation status of Human Immunodeficiency Virus type 1 reverse transcriptase</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hs50x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214s024</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cd69f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>SOMMAIRE  L’application des méthodes d’essai dynamiques aux structures de génie civil permet d’améliorer notre compréhension du comportement sismique des structures par une meilleure connaissance de leurs caractéristiques dynamiques. Des exemples de méthodes courantes de mesures expérimentales pour les bâtiments sont : la réponse en vibration forcée (FV), le monitorage sismique, la réponse aux vibrations ambiantes (AV) et la réponse transitoire en vibration libre. La méthode de mesure des vibrations ambiantes a gagné en popularité avec l’avancement des hautes technologies compte tenu de ses nombreux avantages pratiques et économiques.  Dans cette recherche, l’auteure étudie la faisabilité d’utiliser la méthode AV pour obtenir des valeurs fiables et réalistes de la période fondamentale des bâtiments. Des mesures de vibrations ambiantes ont été faites dans le bâtiment Burnside Hall du campus de l’Université McGill .  Toutes les mesures ont été prises à l’aide de deux paires de vibromètres sensibles aux micro-mouvements et leur système d’acquisition CityShark II. Les données recueillies ont ensuite été traitées selon trois approches courantes d’identification des systèmes : la transformée de Fourier, la densité spectrale, et la méthode ARMA (Auto-Regressive-Moving-Average). Les résultats des différentes techniques d’analyse ont été comparés afin de recommander la meilleure approche possible pour une campagne de mesure exhaustive. En conclusion, l’auteure recommande d’utiliser ensemble la méthode de la transformée de Fourier et la méthode ARMA pour extraire les fréquences naturelles fondamentales. La méthode de la densité spectrale est douteuse dans cette application car elle peut facilement filtrer des signaux de fréquences critiques compte tenu de la faible amplitude typique des micro-mouvements ambiants.   Les résultats obtenus pour Burnside Hall ont permis d’identifier la période fon</description><description>ABSTRACT  The application of dynamic testing to civil engineering structures provides a means to understanding a structure’s dynamic properties.  Such testing includes Forced Vibration Test (FVT), Earthquake Response Test, Ambient Vibration Testing (AVT), and Free Response Test.  AVT has become a popular dynamic testing methodology due to its practical and economical advantages.    In this research, the feasibility of employing AVT to obtain reliable fundamental frequencies of buildings was studied by performing AVT inside the Burnside Hall building of McGill University.  All measurements were taken by two pairs of CityShark II Microtremor Acquisition and velocimetres.  Three system identification approaches, direct Fourier Transform, Power Spectrum Density, and Auto-Regressive-Moving-Average were studied and compared.    It is recommended to use both the direct Fourier Transform and the Auto-Regressive-Moving-Average to extract frequency contents from AVT data.  Use of the Power Spectrum Density could easily filter out important frequency content because AVT signals typically have small amplitude.    The lowest translational frequency of the Burnside building was identified to be 1.4 Hz, and the lowest rotational frequency was identified to be 2.2 Hz.  Translational modes were best obtained by placing sensors near the centre of rigidity, and rotational modes were best obtained by placing sensors at corners of the building.  In addition, the amplitude of the modal peaks increased as the floor elevation increased.  Strong wind amplified the fundamental modes, whereas mild wind excited all modes almost equally.    The fundamental periods calculated from the 1995 and 2005 NBCC were larger than that obtained from the experimental AVT period.  This shows that non-structural components could contribute significantly to the stiffness of a building when the excitation is small.</description><creator>Huang, Kuei-hua</creator><contributor>Ghyslaine McClure (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2007</date><subject>Engineering - Civil</subject><title>Experimental evaluation of fundamental frequencies of buildings</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cw88w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cd69f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hj37s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La popularité des jeux massivement multijoueurs a augmenté de façon phénoménale au cours des dernières années. Les fournisseurs de jeux rencontrent de plus en plus de problèmes d’extensibilité pour supporter des populations croissantes de joueurs. La diffusion à tous les joueurs des changements réalisés dans le monde virtuel n’est pas une solution viable pour maintenir une vision cohérente du monde dans un jeu massivement multijoueurs. Pour surmonter ce défi d’extensibilité, les jeux massivement multijoueurs doivent utiliser des techniques de gestion d’intérêt sophistiquées qui relaient seulement l’information pertinente vers chaque joueur.   Dans cette thèse nous développons une technique de partition de l’espace qui s’adapte aux obstacles du monde virtuel en utilisant une triangulation. Nous présentons des algorithmes sensible-aux-obstacles de gestion d’intérêt qui emploient les partitions triangulaires pour déterminer la pertinence des objets pour chaque joueur, selon l’occlusion créée par les obstacles. Nous comparons l’efficacité des algorithmes sensible-aux-obstacles et d’autres algorithmes modernes de gestion d’intérêt à l’aide de données obtenues d’un vrai jeu massivement multijoueurs. À cet effet, nous utilisons à la fois des actions de vrais joueurs et des actions de joueurs générées par ordinateur. Nous démontrons que les algorithmes sensible-aux-obstacles de gestion d’intérêt peuvent réduirent le nombre de messages relayés entre les joueurs. Nous démontrons également que les algorithmes utilisant notre partition triangulaire peuvent s’adapter à un plus grand nombre d’objets tout en conservant de bonnes performances. Nos expériences suggèrent également que les résultats obtenus à partir de joueurs contrôlés par ordinateur se déplaçant aléatoirement ce rapprochent des résultats obtenus avec de vrais joueurs, dans la mesure où les actions aléatoires des joueurs son</description><description>The popularity of massively multiplayer games has increased in recent years and game providers are facing scalability problems to accomodate growing populations of users. Broadcasting all state changes to every player is not a viable solution to maintain a consistent game state in a massively multiplayer game. To successfully overcome the challenge of scale, massively multiplayer games have to employ sophisticated interest management techniques that only send relevant state changes to each player.  In this thesis we develop a space partitioning technique based on triangulation that adapts to the world’s obstacles. We introduce obstacle-aware interest management algorithms that use the triangular partitioning to determine the relevance of objects based on the occlusion created by obstacles. We compare the performance of both obstacle-aware and state-of-the-art interest management algorithms based on measurements obtained in a real massively multiplayer game using human and computer-generated player actions. We show that obstacle-aware interest management algorithms can reduce the number of update messages between players and that algorithms based on our triangle-based partitioning can scale to a larger number of objects. The experiments also show that measurements obtained with computer-controlled players performing random actions can approximate measurements of games played by real humans, provided that the traces of the random players are designed adequately. As the size of the world and the number of players of massively multiplayer games increases, adaptive interest management techniques such as the ones studied in this thesis will become increasingly important.</description><creator>Boulanger, Jean-Sebastien</creator><contributor>Clark Verbrugge (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Jorg Andreas Kienzle (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2007</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>Interest management for massively multiplayer games</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xx862.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hj37s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88ck40x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>I argue that contemporary philosophy of language in the analytic tradition rests on two fundamentally wrong assumptions: empiricism and externalism.  After I show why these two assumptions are incorrect, I turn my attention to biological rationalism.  Biological rationalism—a research program inspired by the work of Noam Chomsky—is committed to nativism and internalism.  I believe biological rationalism provides the best framework to achieve a genuine understanding of language.  I try to show this by considering the biological rationalist answers to major problems in philosophy of language.</description><description>Je soutiens que la philosophie du langage telle qu’élaborée dans la tradition analytique contemporaine repose sur deux hypothèses erronées: l’empirisme et l’externalisme.  Après avoir démontré que ces deux hypothèses sont incorrectes, j’examine le rationalisme biologique.  Le rationalisme biologique—un programme de recherches inspiré par les travaux de Noam Chomsky—repose sur deux idées directrices: l’innéisme et l’internalisme.  Je crois que le rationalisme biologique offre le meilleur cadre afin d’obtenir une compréhension réelle du langage.  Je cherche le démontrer en examinant les réponses qu’apporte le rationalisme biologique à certains problèmes majeurs en philosophie du langage.</description><creator>McKay, Steve</creator><contributor>David Davies (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>James A McGilvray (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2007</date><subject>Philosophy</subject><title>Biological rationalism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623g32h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88ck40x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60d037m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mental health disorders in childhood are highly prevalent throughout North America and can result in drastic impairments in a child's social, emotional and academic functioning. Recent initiatives for the delivery of mental health care services across Canada and the United States of America include a model of recovery-oriented care, whereby clients become active participants in making health care decisions and become experts in the management of their difficulties. As children are becoming increasingly recognized as competent reporters about their health needs, this collaborative process between professionals and clients when making health care decisions has now extended to include children. As such, the development of self-reporting measures allowing children to express their needs is growing. A scoping review of the literature identified thirty-three self-report measures used with children among a range of disciplines. However, among these child-focused assessment tools used in rehabilitation, most are created using adult-defined constructs and consist of questionnaire format which can limit the scope of the dialogue between client and professional. While these tools allow children to be part of the rehabilitation process, the information obtained does not necessarily reflect what matters to children. Furthermore, many clinicians continue to rely on the reports of parents or other proxy reports rather than the child's perspective directly. This is particularly true for children with mental illness whose views are often ignored. Therefore, more research is needed on clinical approaches that directly address the unique experiences of children with mental illness. Qualitative methods have been used to explore the lived experiences of children. The methods employed in this particular study consisted of a narrative-phenomenological approach to a focused ethnography in order to examine the experiences of four children with a mental health disorder before, during and after nine PhotoVoice sessions. The purpose of this study was to examine what the PhotoVoice process can add to self-report measures for children with mental health disorders. The PhotoVoice approach and the ethnographic methods employed in this study allowed us to capture the experiences of children with a mental health disorder, and specifically to understand what mattered in those experiences. The results of this study highlight how the PhotoVoice process could provide a medium through which the children articulated what mattered about particular activities. The PhotoVoice activity also demonstrated the potential to empower the children as active participants and resulted in child-driven content, in line with the principles of recovery-oriented services. In addition, the ethnographic methods employed, i.e. interviews and participant observations, allowed for observation beyond performance of an activity to include meaning and the real-world context of the child's experiences. Thus, the PhotoVoice activity offered several advantages as a potential activity-based intervention. This is particularly important for occupational therapists who promote the client's engagement in activities that are meaningful, purposeful and goal-directed, while supporting child-driven recovery initiatives.</description><description>Les troubles de santé mentale de l'enfance sont très répandus en Amérique du Nord et peuvent entraîner des dépréciations sévères dans le fonctionnement social, affectif et scolaire de l'enfant. Les initiatives récentes pour la prestation de services de soins de santé mentale au Canada et aux États-Unis amènent un modèle axé sur le rétablissement ou « Recovery », par lequel les clients deviennent des participants actifs dans la prise de décisions de soins de santé et des experts dans la gestion de leurs difficultés. Comme les enfants sont reconnus de plus en plus compétents au sujet de leurs besoins de santé, cette collaboration entre professionnels et clients est maintenant étendue pour inclure les enfants.À cet effet, le développement de mesures d'auto-évaluation permettant aux enfants d'exprimer leurs besoins augmente. Une revue de la littérature a identifié trente-trois mesures d'auto-évaluations utilisées avec des enfants parmi plusieurs disciplines. Cependant, la plupart des outils d'évaluation sont créés en utilisant des concepts définis par les adultes et consistent en forme de questionnaire qui peut limiter la portée du dialogue entre le client et professionnel. Bien que ces outils permettent aux enfants de faire partie du processus de réadaptation, les informations recueillies ne reflètent pas nécessairement ce qui compte pour les enfants. De plus, de nombreux cliniciens continuent de compter sur les rapports des parents ou d'autres rapports de proxy plutôt que la perspective de l'enfant directement. Cela est particulièrement le cas pour les enfants souffrant de troubles de santé mentale, dont les vues sont souvent négligées. Par conséquent, plus de recherche est nécessaire sur les approches cliniques qui répondent directement aux expériences uniques des enfants atteints de troubles de santé mentale. Les méthodes de recherche qualitatives sont souvent utilisées pour étudier les expériences vécues par les enfants. Les méthodes empruntées dans cette étude consistent d'une approche narrative - phénoménologique à une ethnographie qui vise d'examiner les expériences de quatre enfants avec un trouble de santé mentale avant, pendant et après neuf séances de PhotoVoice. L'objectif de cette étude était d'observer ce que le processus de PhotoVoice peut accroître aux mesures d'auto-évaluation pour les enfants souffrant de troubles de santé mentale.L'approche de PhotoVoice et les méthodes ethnographiques utilisées dans cette étude nous ont permis de saisir les expériences vécues des enfants avec un trouble de santé mentale, et en particulier à les comprendre ce qui leur comptait. Les résultats obtenus mettent en évidence la manière dont le processus de PhotoVoice fournit un moyen par lequel les enfants expriment ce qui comptait par rapport à leurs activités et expériences particulières. L'activité de PhotoVoice démontre également le potentiel d'habiliter les enfants en tant que participants actifs, en ligne avec les principes des services axés sur le rétablissement, et résultant en données emmenées par l'enfant. De plus, les méthodes ethnographiques, c'est-à-dire les entrevues et les observations des participants, ont permis l'observation au-delà de la performance d'une activité pour inclure la signification et le contexte réel des expériences de l'enfant. Donc, le processus de PhotoVoice offert plusieurs avantages comme une intervention axée sur l'activité. Ceci est particulièrement important pour les ergothérapeutes qui favorisent l'engagement du client à des activités significatives, ciblées et orientées vers un but, tout en soutenant les initiatives de l'enfant.</description><creator>Greco, Vanessa</creator><contributor>Melissa Park (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Physical &amp; Occupational Therapy</subject><title>The experiences of children with a mental health disorder: a photovoice approach to understanding what matters</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225d905.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60d037m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mz39w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A large body of literature has explored the variables contributing to individual differences in the quality of maternal behavior. Psychosocial factors, including history of adversity, attachment insecurity, and mental health problems, have been linked to poorer maternal care. In recent years, there has been increasing interest in identifying the neurobiological substrates of maternal behavior. The neuropeptide oxytocin (OT) has been shown to promote maternal behavior, and varies with a history of adversity, attachment insecurity, and mental health problems. Thus, OT may represent a biological mechanism underlying the relationship between these psychosocial characteristics and maternal interactive behavior. The present thesis is designed to address two primary goals: (1) Study 1 and 3 examined psychosocial factors associated with individual differences in circulating concentrations of OT; (2) Study 2 explored the moderating role of mental health in the relationship between OT levels and maternal interactive behaviors.OT has been linked to adult attachment but studies have yielded inconsistent results, leaving it unclear why OT would be inversely associated with attachment insecurity in some adults but not others. History of adversity may help to shed light on these divergent findings, as it has been associated with both attachment insecurity and lower concentrations of OT. To determine whether adversity moderates the relationship between OT and attachment, Study 1 examined the association between OT and attachment in a clinical sample of pregnant women who had endured high rates of adversity throughout life. We found lower OT concentrations in insecurely than securely attached women, and in those who experienced stressful life events in the last 12 months. Study 3 compared the relationship between OT and attachment insecurity in childbearing women with and without a background of early adversity. Results showed that early adversity moderated the association between OT and attachment insecurity; OT levels were inversely associated with attachment avoidance, but only in those with a history of early adversity. These studies underline the need to consider the role of adversity in order to obtain a more complete understanding of the relationship between OT levels and adult attachment. Study 2 was designed to investigate the moderating role of mental health in the relationship between OT levels and maternal interactive behaviors. Because OT exerts anti-stress and anxiolytic effects, it may be particularly beneficial to the interactive behaviors of mothers with mental health problems. We hypothesized that mental health would moderate the association between OT levels and interactive behaviors. To test this hypothesis, Study 2 compared the association between OT concentrations and interactive behavior in mothers with versus without mental health problems. Higher levels of OT were associated with less intrusive interactive behavior in the overall sample. Consistent with our hypothesis, OT was also associated with less depressive (tense, self-focused, lethargic) interactive behaviors, but only in mothers with mood, anxiety or adjustment disorders. These results suggest that higher levels of OT may buffer the effects of their mental health problems on their interactive behaviors, and these anti-stress and anxiolytic effects of OT could be less necessary or apparent in mothers without such problems. Overall, the results of the current thesis highlight the importance of examining the relationships among multiple psychosocial variables in order to better account for individual differences in circulating concentrations of OT, as well as the importance of considering both biological and psychosocial variables in an effort to more fully comprehend individual differences in the quality of maternal behavior. </description><description>De nombreuses publications ont exploré les facteurs contribuant aux différences individuelles de qualité de comportement maternel. Les facteurs psychosociaux, tels que les antécédents d'adversité, l'attachement de type insécurisant, et les problèmes de santé mentale, sont liés à des soins maternels de plus faible qualité. Récemment, les chercheurs s'intéressent aux origines neurobiologiques du comportement maternel. La neuropeptide ocytocine est liée à de meilleurs comportements maternels, et peut varier avec des antécédents d'adversité, l'attachement de type insécurisant, et des problèmes de santé mentale. L'ocytocine pourrait ainsi être un mécanisme biologique expliquant le lien entre ces facteurs psychosociaux et les comportements maternels. Cette thèse vise à atteindre deux objectifs: (1) Les études 1 et 3 examinent les facteurs psychosociaux associés aux différences individuelles de taux d'ocytocine endogène; (2) L'étude 2 explore le rôle modérateur de la santé mentale dans le lien entre l'ocytocine et le comportement maternel.Certaines études ont lié l'ocytocine à l'attachement adulte, mais les trouvailles sont contradictoires. Les raisons pour lesquelles l'ocytocine serait inversement liée à l'attachement insécurisant chez certains adultes mais pas d'autres restent ambigües. Des antécédents d'adversité pourraient élucider ces trouvailles, car ils sont liés à l'attachement de type insécurisant et à de plus faibles taux d'ocytocine. Afin de déterminer si les antécédents d'adversité ont un rôle modérateur dans le lien entre l'ocytocine et l'attachement, l'étude 1 examine l'association entre l'ocytocine et l'attachement chez des femmes enceintes ayant vécu des taux élevés d'adversité. Les résultats indiquent que les taux d'ocytocine étaient plus bas chez les femmes ayant un attachement de type insécurisant et chez les femmes ayant vécu des évènements stressants dans les 12 derniers mois. L'étude 3 compare le lien entre l'ocytocine et l'attachement de type insécurisant chez les femmes avec ou sans antécédents d'adversité. L'adversité en enfance jouait un rôle modérateur dans le lien entre l'ocytocine et l'attachement de type insécurisant; les taux d'ocytocine étaient inversement liés à un style d'attachement de type évitant, mais seulement chez les femmes ayant des antécédents d'adversité en enfance.  Ces études confirment le besoin de considérer l'adversité dans le lien entre les taux d'ocytocine et l'attachement adulte.L'étude 2 visait à examiner le rôle modérateur de la santé mentale dans le lien entre l'ocytocine et les comportements maternels. L'ocytocine a des effets antistress et anxiolytiques, et pourrait d'autant plus bénéficier les comportements interactifs des mères ayant des problèmes de santé mentale. Nous avons émis l'hypothèse que la santé mentale modérerait le lien entre l'ocytocine et les comportements interactifs. Afin de tester cette hypothèse, l'étude a comparé le lien entre l'ocytocine et les comportements interactifs chez des mères avec ou sans problèmes de santé mentale. Chez toutes les femmes, des taux d'ocytocine plus élevés étaient associés à des comportements maternels moins envahissants. Confirmant notre hypothèse, l'ocytocine était aussi liée à des comportements interactifs moins dépressifs, mais seulement chez les mères ayant des troubles d'humeur, d'anxiété ou d'ajustement.  Ces résultats suggèrent que l'ocytocine pourrait atténuer les effets des problèmes de santé mentale sur les comportements interactifs. Cependant, les effets antistress et anxiolytiques de l'ocytocine pourraient être moins nécessaires ou évidents chez les mères sans ces problèmes.Globalement, les résultats de cette thèse soulignent l'importance de considérer les facteurs psychosociaux dans les différences individuelles d'ocytocine endogène, ainsi que l'importance de considérer les facteurs biologiques et psychosociaux pour mieux comprendre les différences de qualité de comportements maternels. </description><creator>Samuel, Simcha</creator><contributor>Phyllis Zelkowitz (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Psychology</subject><title>Oxytocin, adversity and attachment contribute to the interactive behavior of mothers with and without mental illness</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741v42g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mz39w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m039k7928</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>RÉSUMÉLes interactions entre le carbonate de calcium précipité (PCC) et la nanocellulose cristalline électrostériquement stabilisé (ENCC) et la cellulose carboxylée dissous (DCC) ont été étudiés dans cette thèse. ENCC et DCC ont généralement une concentration élevée en carboxylate de méthyle (3.5 mmol/g ou plus) et peuvent être produits par les oxydations avec le periodate, le chlorite et TEMPO. ENCC/ DCC a une grande efficacité de floculer des particules PCC et induit la floculation de PCC par une combinaison de forces électrostatiques et de pontage. ENCC/DCC induit la floculation maximale PCC lorsque des particules PCC atteignent le point isoélectrique. Des nouvelles particules de nanocellulose ont été préparées  par une oxydation periodate dans cette étude. Pour une oxydation partielle (degré de substitution (DS) &lt; 2), les trois produits suivants ont été générés: la cellulose fibreuse, la cellulose dialdéhyde en forme de tige (DAC) et les nanofibres, dont nous nous référons comme nanocellulose cristalline stabilisée stériquement (SNCC), et nous référons DAC dissous comme cellulose dialdéhyde modifié (DAMC). SNCC a des dimensions similaires (100-200 nm de long et 8.5 nm de large) que la cellulose nanocristalline conventionnelle  (CCN) qui est produit par  hydrolyse à l'acide sulfurique. SNCC a été caractérisée et ses propriétés ont été comparées à la CCN. En outre,  les caractéristiques morphologiques et les distributions de tailles des trois SNCCs préparés par différents degrés d'oxydation ont été mesurées par microscopie électronique à transmission et diffusion de lumière dynamique (DLS). Il a été démontré que les trois SNCCs ont des diamètres similaires (5-10 nm). Cependant, la longueur moyenne des SNCC diminue avec la concentration d'aldéhyde: à partir d'approximativement de 590 nm après 26 heures d'oxydation à 100 nm après une période d'oxydation de 84 heures. Cela révèle que la morphologie de SNCC peut être bien contrôlée par le degré d'oxydation periodate, qui dépend de la quantité de periodate et le temps de réaction. En basant sur ce constat, nous proposons que le periodate réagit préférentiellement avec la région amorphe de la cellulose, puis en procédant à la limite des régions amorphes et cristallins. La stabilité stérique de la SNCC est prouvée par DLS lors de l'ajout des co-solvants dans des suspensions aqueuses SNCC. La floculation des PCC induite par la SNCC a également été étudiée. Les particules SNCC peuvent créer des liens de pontages avec PCC pour induire la floculation à faible dose (supérieure à 1 mg/g). SNCC induit la floculation maximale lorsque sa couverture fractionnaire est égale à Θ = 1 / (2- α22/α12), (où α22 est l'efficacité de floculation entre les particules SNCC et α12 est celui entre le PCC et les particules SNCC). Les isothermes d'adsorption des trois SNCCs et cellulose de dialdéhyde modifié (DAMC) sur des particules de PCC ont été mesurées. Il a été démontré que DAMC avait une plus grande affinité que les trois SNCC, et l'affinité de SNCC augmente avec le temps de réaction. Cela indique que les chaînes DAMC adsorbent  plus fort que les parties nanocristallins de SNCC sur PCC. </description><description>ABSTRACTThe interactions between precipitated calcium carbonate (PCC) and electrosterically stabilized nanocrystalline cellulose (ENCC) and dissolved carboxylated cellulose (DCC) have been studied in this thesis. ENCC and DCC usually have a high carboxylate content (3.5 mmol/g or higher) and can be produced by periodate, chlorite and TEMPO oxidations. ENCC/DCC showed a high flocculation efficiency with PCC particles and induced PCC flocculation by a combination of electrostatic and bridging forces. ENCC/DCC induces the maximum PCC flocculation when PCC particles reach to isoelectric point.  Novel nanocellulose particles were prepared by periodate oxidation in this study. For partial oxidation (degree of substitution (DS)&lt;2), three products were generated: fibrous cellulose, rod-like dialdehyde cellulose (DAC) nanofibers, which we refer to as sterically stabilized nanocrystalline cellulose (SNCC), and dissolved DAC which we refer to as dialdehyde modified cellulose (DAMC). SNCC has similar dimension (100–200 nm in length and 5–8 nm in width) as conventional nanocrystalline cellulose (NCC) made by sulfuric acid hydrolysis. SNCC was characterized and its properties were compared to NCC. In addition, morphological features and size distributions of three SNCCs prepared by different degrees of oxidation were measured by transmission electron microscopy and dynamic light scattering (DLS). It shows that the three SNCCs have similar diameters (5-10 nm). However, the average length of SNCC decreases with aldehyde content: from approximately 590 nm after 26 hrs of oxidation to 100 nm for an oxidation period of 84 hrs. It indicates that the morphology of SNCC can be well controlled by the degree of periodate oxidation, which depends on the amount of periodate and the reaction time.  Based on this observation, we propose that periodate reacts preferentially with the amorphous region of cellulose, followed by proceeding at the boundary of amorphous and crystalline regions. The steric stability of SNCC is proved by DLS when adding cosolvents into aqueous SNCC suspensions. The flocculation of PCC induced by SNCC was also studied. SNCC particles can bridge PCC to induce flocculation at low dosage (above 1mg/g). SNCC induced the maximum flocculation when its fractional coverage was more than half coverage because SNCC particles become unstable after deposition on PCC. Adsorption isotherms of three SNCCs and dialdehyde modified cellulose (DAMC) on PCC particles were measured. It was found that DAMC had a higher affinity than three SNCCs with different aldehyde contents, and the affinity of SNCC increased with reaction time. This indicates DAMC chains adsorb stronger than nanocrystalline parts of SNCC on PCC.  </description><creator>Chen, Dezhi</creator><contributor>Theodorus G Van de Ven (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Sylvain Coulombe (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Chemical Engineering</subject><title>Flocculation kinetics of precipitated calcium carbonate induced by functional nanocellulose</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kq94r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k7928</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m039k793j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>With the traditional recording industry experiencing a period of relative uncertainty, there are new opportunities for independent musicians to reach new audiences and establish a career. SoundCloud, a web platform that allows user to upload and share their music, represents one of the most significant instances of newfound musical opportunity. However, despite a rhetoric lauding the potential of such technology to democratize music making, platforms like SoundCloud are also indicative of the changing conditions of contemporary musical labour. Indeed, they demonstrate the new skills and working habits required to succeed in a competitive labour market. Under these new conditions, musicians must perform work that would have previously been carried out by intermediary figures and become increasingly self-reliant without the support of previously existing industry institutions. Consequently, musical labour begins to take on the qualities of post-Fordism, and work on SoundCloud in particular comes to resemble immaterial labour. In order to demonstrate this shift and its negative implications for musicians, I will conduct a historical overview of music labour so as to establish that contemporary circumstances represent a significant departure from the practices that characterized twentieth century music making. I will then employ theories of post-Fordism and immaterial labour to provide a conceptual framework for understanding the novel qualities of musical work. Finally, in my case study of SoundCloud, I will examine user experiences to demonstrate that this immaterial musical labour in effect normalizes a host of new working practices with associated risks of exploitation and precarity. Through this analysis, I aim to problematize these new sites of musical labour and establish the dangers that musicians may face in using them, as well as propose that truly emancipatory conditions for artists require institutions of mutual aid rather than tools that promote individual success and self-realization.</description><description>Tandis que l'industrie du disque connait une période d'incertitude, plusieurs musiciens indépendants semblent pouvoir profiter de nouvelles ressources pour trouver des auditeurs et établir une carrière. SoundCloud, un site web qui permet aux utilisateurs de télécharger leur musique vers un server et ensuite la partager en ligne, est un des outils les plus populaires disponibles en ce moment. Cependant, même si ce genre de site est supposé améliorer l'accès à une carrière musicale, en réalité SoundCloud indique le changement des conditions de travail des musiciens contemporains et l'exigence de nouvelles compétences et d'habitudes de travail pour réussir dans un marché du travail compétitif. Les musiciens doivent donc compléter des tâches qui dans le passé auraient été la responsabilité d'un intermédiaire pour devenir de plus en plus autonomes sans le soutien des institutions de l'industrie. Par conséquent, le travail musical commence à manifester les qualités du post-fordisme et le travail sur SoundCloud en particulier devient une forme de travail immatériel. Pour démontrer cette évolution, j'effectuerai un aperçu historique du travail musical pour prouver que les conditions contemporaines de ce travail ont beaucoup changé relativement à celles du vingtième siècle. Par la suite, je vais employer les théories du post-fordisme et le travail immatériel pour mieux expliquer ces nouvelles conditions de travail. Pour terminer, je vais entreprendre une étude de cas sur le travail musical effectué sur SoundCloud. En considérant les expériences des utilisateurs, je démontrerai que le travail immatériel des musiciens sur le site normalise des pratiques associées à un risque accru d'exploitation et de précarité. Le but de cette analyse est de problématiser ces nouveaux sites musicaux et de dévoiler leurs dangers associés, ainsi que de suggérer la nécessité d'institutions d'aide mutuel au lieu des outils basés sur la réussite individuelle et la réalisation de soi, afin de mieux promouvoir des conditions d'émancipation pour les musiciens indépendants.</description><creator>Maturo, Nicolas</creator><contributor>Barney, Darin (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Art History and Communications Studies</subject><title>Music as immaterial labour: soundCloud and the changing working conditions of independent musicians</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602375t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k793j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mq355</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>IEEE 802.11 wireless local area networks (WLANs) become more and more popular and widely deployed in public hotspots, enterprise environments, and residential areas to provide seamless coverage and improve user connectivity. However, the high density of Access Points (APs) and the stations (STAs) associated to each AP results in increased intra-cell and inter-cell interference, which can cause high collision rates, long backoff intervals, and degraded received signal-to-interference-plus-noise ratio (SINR). To manage such interference, it is required to explore medium access control (MAC) enhancement, efficient channel assignment, and load balancing techniques, which can improve the performance experienced by users. In this work, we develop and evaluate interference-aware enhanced MAC and radio resource allocation algorithms in 802.11 WLANs, aiming to increase the network throughput.  To improve the achievable throughput in a single-cell WLAN, a channel-aware adaptive carrier sensing multiple access with collision avoidance (CSMA/CA) scheme is developed to take advantage of multi-user diversity, while supporting distributed and asynchronous operation. By dynamically adjusting the contention window of each STA according to its channel state, this approach prioritizes STAs who gain most from using a channel and enhances channel utilization. A three-dimensional Markov chain is developed to model and evaluate the proposed adaptive CSMA/CA, which significantly improves throughput, especially in a large network.To manage the inter-cell interference in a multi-cell WLAN, the channel assignment and AP-STA association are investigated. Applying difference-of-convex-functions (DC) programming, two different optimization problems are solved aiming to minimize interference sum utility and maximize STA throughput. Distributed schemes are also developed in which APs and STAs can self-configure channel selection and association to mitigate the interference and thereby improve the network throughput. It is shown that the proposed approaches are highly efficient and robust with fast convergence and low complexity.To balance the load and provide service customization in a multi-cell WLAN, AP-STA association and airtime control are studied in a virtualized network, where physical APs are shared by multiple Internet service providers (ISPs). More specifically, an optimization problem is formulated on the STAs' transmission probabilities to maximize the overall network throughput, while providing airtime usage guarantees for the ISPs. The algorithm to reach the optimal transmission probability and detailed implementation are also discussed. Illustrative results confirm the superior and robust performance of the developed association and airtime control scheme.</description><description>Les réseaux locaux sans fil (WLANs), conformes à la norme IEEE 802.11, sont de plus en plus populaires et largement déployés dans les points  d'accès, les environnements d'entreprise et les zones résidentielles afin de fournir une couverture sans failles et d'améliorer la connectivité des utilisateurs. Cependant, la haute densité des points d'accès (APs) et des stations (STAs) associées à chaque AP résulte en une hausse du brouillage intercellulaire et intracellulaire, qui peut causer des taux de collision élevés, augmenter l'intervalle de temporisation, ainsi que de dégrader le rapport signal/brouillage-et-bruit (SINR) du signal reçu. Pour gérer de tels brouillages, il est nécessaire d'explorer des techniques d'améliorations du contrôle d'accès au médium (MAC), d'attribution des canaux et d'équilibrer la charge qui peut améliorer la performance que connaissent les utilisateurs. Dans cette étude, nous développons et évaluons  la couche MAC en présence d'interférence, ainsi que des algorithmes d'attribution de ressources radio dans le but d'augmenter le débit du réseau.Pour améliorer le débit réalisable au sein d'un réseau WLAN unicellulaire,  une méthode adaptative d'accès multiple avec écoute de porteuse et évitement de collision (CSMA/CA), consciente des canaux, est développée pour profiter de la diversité multi-utilisateur tout en soutenant une opération distribuée et asynchrone. Cette approche améliore l'utilisation d'un canal en accordant la priorité aux stations qui bénéficient le plus de l'utilisation du canal, en ajustant dynamiquement la fenêtre de conflit de chaque station, selon son état de canal. Une chaîne de Markov à trois dimensions est conçue pour modéliser et évaluer la méthode CSMA/CA adaptative proposée qui, selon les résultats, améliore considérablement le débit, en particulier dans un grand réseau.Pour gérer les brouillages intercellulaires dans un réseau WLAN multicellulaire, l'attribution de canal et l'association AP-STA sont étudiées. En appliquant la méthode de programmation des différences de fonctions convexes (DC), deux problèmes d'optimisations différentes sont etudiées en visant la minimisation des brouillages et la maximisation du débit des stations. Des mécanismes distribués sont aussi développés dans lesquels les points d'accès et les stations peuvent auto-configurer leur sélection et association de canal afin d'atténuer les brouillages et ainsi améliorer le débit du réseau. Cette étude démontre que les méthodes proposées sont très efficaces et fiables avec une convergence rapide à faible complexité.Afin d'équilibrer la charge et de fournir un service de personnalisation dans un réseau WLAN multicellulaire, l'association AP-STA et le contrôle du temps de transmission sont étudiés dans un réseau virtuel, où des points d'accès physiques sont partagés par plusieurs fournisseurs de services internet (ISPs). Plus précisément, un problème d'optimisation est formulé, selon les probabilités de transmission des stations, dans le but de maximiser le débit global du réseau, tout en offrant des garanties de temps d'antenne pour les fournisseurs de services internet. L'algorithme pour atteindre la probabilité de transmission optimale ainsi que sa mise en œuvre sont aussi détaillés. Finalement, les résultats représentatifs confirment la performance supérieure et robuste des mécanismes proposés (pour l'association et le contrôle du temps de transmission) en tant que le débit et l'équité du réseau.</description><creator>Wang, Xiaowei</creator><contributor>Tho Le-Ngoc (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</subject><title>Interference-aware resource allocation in high-density WLANs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225d92q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mq355</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qq03n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Au cours des dernières décennies, l'électrification de l'industrie du transport a poussé pour améliorer la performance de la transmission électrique et, en particulier, les applications de traction. Les récentes fluctuations du prix et de l'offre des aimants permanents de terres rares (AP), qui sont principalement utilisés dans la plupart des moteurs de traction électriques, ont encouragé les chercheurs à explorer plusieurs topologies de moteurs, tels que le moteur synchrone à réluctance (MSynR). Même si les MSynR bénéficient de la fabrication de rotors simples et un coût de matériaux faible, ils ne parviennent pas à rivaliser le fort rapport couple/densité volumique, rendement, facteur de puissance, et fonctionnement à puissance constante des moteurs à aimant permanent. Il est possible de régler les limites de performance des MSynR standards en faisant insérer des aimants permanents à faibles coûts à l'intérieur du rotor pour créer un MSynR assisté d'aimants permanents. Cependant, il y a plusieurs goulots d'étranglement qui préventent une solution de conception de MSynR assisté AP optimale. Si les méthodes correctes ne sont pas utilisés, une solution optimale peut ou ne peut pas être trouvé avec confiance. Par conséquent, cette thèse aborde les défis de calculs et de conception impliqués dans l'optimisation de la conception du rotor de MSynR assisté AP pour les applications de traction. Sur présentation d'une théorie de commande électrique, une étude de cas de prise directe est utilisé pour illustrer les optimisations globales et locales de rotor en utilisant des méthodes d'intelligence artificielle et d'algorithmes génétiques. Plusieurs méthodologies nouvelles pour la modélisation et l'optimisation des rotors de MSynR sont présentés. Ceux-ci peuvent trouver l'ensemble des solutions optimales globales en utilisant moins de calculs, peuvent comparer les modèles de rotor généraux en utilisant une surface de réponses, peuvent généraliser la cartographie de l'espace à partir d'une conception de rotor à barrière simple ou à barrières multiples, et peuvent indiquer si une solution est globalement optimale à l'aide d'une fonction analytique proposé. Les topologies de rotor à barrière simple et à barrières multiples du MSynR sont explorées, et des améliorations du modèle sont validés à l'aide de simulations numériques précises. La conception du rotor final est ensuite comparé avec un moteur à prise directe utilisée dans les applications automobiles, tout en tenant compte des limites actuelles de tension et de courant de l'onduleur. En outre, une brève analyse de la robustesse du MSynR assisté AP final est effectuée pour tenir compte des imperfections et des incertitudes dans le processus de fabrication du rotor, les propriétés des matériaux magnétiques, et les points de réglage du moteur.</description><description>In the past decades, the electrification of the transportation industry has pushed to improve the performance of the electric drivetrain, especially the electric motor, in traction applications. Recent fluctuations in the price and supply of rare-earth permanent magnets (PMs), which are primarily used in most traction electric motors, has driven researchers to explore alternative motor topologies such as the Synchronous Reluctance Machine (SynRM). Although pure SynRMs benefit from simple rotor manufacturing and low material cost, they fail to directly compete with the high torque-to-rotor-volume density, efficiency, power factor and Constant Power Speed Range of Interior Permanent Magnet machines. It is possible to address the pure SynRM's performance limitations by inserting low-cost PMs inside its rotor structure to give rise to a Permanent Magnet-assisted SynRM. There are, however, computational bottlenecks in arriving at an optimal PM-assisted SynRM design solution. If correct methodologies are not employed, an optimal solution may or may not be found with less confidence in its optimality properties. This thesis addresses the computational and design challenges involved in the rotor design optimization of PM-assisted Synchronous Reluctance Machines for traction applications. Upon presenting a brief theory of electric drives, a case study for a direct-drive application is used to illustrate the global and local rotor optimizations by using artificial intelligence and genetic algorithm methods. Novel methodologies for modelling and optimizing SynRM rotors are presented. These can be used to find the set of global optimal solutions using less computational effort, compare general rotor models using a Response Surface map, generalize the space mapping from a single-barrier to a multiple-barrier rotor design, and indicate whether a suggested solution is globally optimal using a proposed analytical function. Both single and multiple-barrier SynRM rotor topologies are explored, and model improvements are validated using accurate numerical simulations. The final rotor design is then compared with a direct-drive motor used in automotive applications, while considering the current and voltage limitations of the inverter drive system. In addition, a brief robustness analysis is performed for the final PM-assisted SynRM solution to account for imperfections and uncertainties in the rotor manufacturing process, magnetic material properties and motor controller setpoints.</description><creator>Mohammadi, Mohammad Hossain</creator><contributor>David Alister Lowther (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</subject><title>Rotor design optimization of permanent magnet–assisted synchronous reluctance machines for traction applications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999946v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qq03n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2j62s769d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Régulation de l'expression génique par microARN médiée par la séquence RGD de la fibrilline-1 Introduction et objectifs : Les fibrillines sont des composantes majeurs des microfibrilles de la matrice extracellulaire des tissus élastiques ou non-élastiques. Ce sont des protéines à multiples domaines, majoritairement constituées de domaines de type « calcium-binding epidermal growth factor" et repetitions de 8-cystéines. La fibrilline-1 contient une séquence Arg-Gly-Asp (RGD) conservée au sein des espèces, qui est requise pour les intéractions cellule/matrice en liant les intégrines de surface. Des mutations dans ce domaine sont à l'origine de troubles héréditaires, comme de syndrome de Marfan, ou le « stiff-skin syndrome ». L'objectif de cette étude est de déterminer le rôle du motif RGD de la fibrilline-1 dans la signalisation cellulaire dans le contexte de la régulation génique miARN  dépendante.Méthodes: Deux fragments de fibriliine-1 recombinante ont été produits, l'un contenant le motif sauvage RGD, l'autre une séquence mutante RGA. Les interactions entre des fibroblastes humains de peau (HSFs) et les deux fragments ont été analysées en microscopie optique et fluorescente. Afin de déterminer les variations dans la régulation de la signalisation cellulaire, l'expression des ARN messagers (ARNm) ainsi que celles des miARN ont été analysées. Les miARN jouent un rôle clé dans la régulation de l'expression génique, en ciblant les ARNm. Des PCR en temps réel ont été effectuées afin de valider les résultats des analyses par micropuces, et pour étudier l'expression des miARN au cours du temps. Une analyse bioinformatique ont permis de prédire les interactions entre les miARN et les ARNm, résultats par la suite validées en culture cellulaire grâce au système mirTrap. L'effet de la surexpression ou de l'inhibition des miARN a été étudié en culture cellulaire grâce à l'utilisation de miARN imitateurs ou inhibiteurs. Résultats et conclusion : Les HSF ont été capables d'adhérer et de s'étendre sur une surface recouverte du fragment RGD, mais pas avec le fragment mutant RGA. En immunofluorescence, l'interaction des HSF avec le motif RGD de la fibrilline-1 a  montré un effet sur la prolifération cellulaire. Étonnamment, l'analyse par micropuces a révélé une variation de l'expression de nombreux miARN après 24h d'interaction entre les cellules et les deux fragments, différences déjà observables après 2h. L'interaction avec la fibrilline-1 impacte également sur l'expression d'ARNm codant pour des protéines qui jouent un rôle dans les voies de signalisation des facteurs de croissance, les interactions avec l'actine, les intégrines, les metalloprotéinases de matrice, et les récepteurs couplés aux protéines G.  Les ARNm cibles ont été identifiés parmi les voies liées aux facteurs de croissance, aux interactions avec l'actine et avec les intégrines. La surexpression ou l'inhibition des miARN s'est révélée avoir un effet important sur la signalisation du TGF- β et de l'actine. En conclusion, cette étude apporte de nouveaux éléments sur la fonction de l'interaction fibrilline-1/intégrine et son impact sur la régulation des miARN.</description><description>Background and Aim: Fibrillins are the major components of microfibrils in the extracellular matrix of elastic and non-elastic tissues. They are multi-domain proteins, containing mainly calcium-binding epidermal growth factor-like domains and 8-cysteine/TB domains. Fibrillin-1 contains one evolutionarily conserved Arg-Gly-Asp (RGD) sequence in its fourth TB domain which is required to mediate cell-matrix interactions by binding to cell-surface integrins. Mutations in this domain lead to heritable disorders, including Marfan syndrome and stiff skin syndrome. This study aims to determine the cell signaling function of the fibrillin-1 RGD sequence in regard to microRNA (miRNA)-dependent gene regulation.Experimental Procedures: Two recombinant fibrillin-1 fragments were produced, one wild-type RGD-containing fragment and one fragment containing a mutant RGA sequence. The characteristics of interactions between human skin fibroblasts (HSFs) and the two fragments were analyzed by light and fluorescence microscopy. To determine the differential regulation of signaling pathways, microarray analysis of miRNA as well as mRNA expression was conducted. miRNAs play a key role in the regulation of gene expression by targeting mRNAs. Real-time quantitative PCR was used to validate the microarray results for a selection of miRNAs and mRNAs, as well as to perform a time course analysis of differential miRNA expression. Interactions between miRNAs and mRNAs were predicted by bioinformatics analysis and validated in cell culture using the mirTrap system. Cell culture studies using miRNA mimics or inhibitors were used to study the functional effects of miRNA overexpression or inhibition. Results: HSFs attached and spread to plates coated with the wild-type fragment, but not to the RGA-containing fragment. The interaction of HSFs with the RGD sequence of fibrillin 1 showed proliferative potential in immunofluorescence assays. Surprisingly, the microarray displayed differential expression of many miRNAs after 24 h of interaction between HSFs and the two recombinant fibrillin-1 fragments. Differential miRNA expression was evident already after 2 h of interaction. Comparative mRNA microarrays also revealed extensive differentially regulated mRNAs triggered by fibrillin-1 ligation, with predicted regulated pathways in growth factor signaling, actin binding, integrin binding, matrix metalloproteinases and G-protein coupled receptor signaling. Target mRNAs were identified in the growth factor, actin binding and integrin binding pathways. miRNA overexpression and inhibition revealed profound effects on TGF-β signaling and actin binding. In summary, the study provides important functional insights into fibrillin-1-integrin mediated miRNA regulation.</description><creator>Zeyer, Karina</creator><contributor>Dieter Reinhardt (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Anatomy and Cell Biology</subject><title>The RGD sequence of fibrillin-1 regulates gene expression through microRNAs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956j712.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s769d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qs56v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the recent years, Deep Neural Network-Hidden Markov Model (DNN-HMM) systems have overtaken the traditional Gaussian Mixture Model-Hidden Markov Model (GMM-HMM) systems as the state-of-the-art acoustic models in Automatic Speech Recognition (ASR). A lot of effort has been put in studying different deep learning architectures to improve ASR performance. However, most of these systems operate on the standard hand crafted spectral features which were used in the GMM-HMM systems. Recent research has shown that DNNs can operate directly on raw speech waveform input features. This thesismainly focuses on such network architectures which can operate directly on the speech waveform input features offering an alternative to standard signal processing. This thesis at first evaluates existing DNN based acoustic models trained on spectral features, analyzing various parameters affecting the performance of such networks. The ability of these DNN based systems to automatically acquire internal representation that are similar to mel-scale filter banks when fed with raw waveform input features is demonstrated. It is shown that increasing the size of the corpus helps in reducing the gap which exists between the Windowed Speech Waveform (WSW) DNNs and the Mel Frequency Spectral Coefficient (MFSC) DNNs performance. An investigation into efficient WSW DNN architectures is done and a proposed stacked bottleneck architecture is shown to reduce the gap that exists between the WSW DNN and the MFSC DNN by capturing improved spectral dynamic information. A combination of spectral features and waveformbased features is shown to improve the performance by providing additional information to the network. At last, redundancies associated with these systems are addressed and possible solutions are provided for reducing the size and complexity by using structured initialization and Singular Value Decomposition (SVD) based restructuring.</description><description>Les systèmes combinant réseau de neurones profond et modèle Markovien caché (DNN-HMM) ont maintenant remplacé les systèmes traditionnels combinant modèles à mélange Gaussian (GMM-HMM) comme pointe de la technologie en matière de modèles acoustiques pour la reconnaissance de la parole (ASR). Bien qu'il y a eu des études approfondies de l'impact des différentes architectures à apprentissage profonds sur la performance des systèmes d'ASR, ces études utilisaient les techniques de caractérisation spectral développées pour les systèmes GMM-HMM. Des études récentes ont démontrées que les réseaux de neurones profonds (DNN) peuvent directement utiliser le signal de parole digitalisé, sans analyse préliminaire du signal. Cette thèse se concentre principalement sur l'étude d'architectures qui peuvent utiliser le signal digitalisé, offrant ainsi une alternative aux techniques de traitement de signaux standards.Cette thèse consiste d'abord d'une discussion des différents paramètres affectant la performance de DNNs utilisés pour la modélisation acoustique, utilisant les caractéristiques spectrales traditionnelles. Il est démontré que les systèmes basés sur un DNN peuvent apprendre automatiquement, à partir du signal digitalisé, une représentation interne du signal similaire à une batterie de filtre utilisant l'échelle de Mel. L'augmentation de la taille du corpus utilisé réduit la différence entre la performance des DNNs utilisant le signal digitalisé (WSW) et les DNNs utilisant une batterie de filtre à l'échelle de Mel (MFSC). Une investigation d'architecture WSW DNN efficaces permet de proposer une architecture utilisant plusieurs couches avec rétrécissement, qui réduit la différence de performance entre les WSW DNNs et les MFSC DNNs en capturant les caractéristiques dynamiques de l'information spectrale. Une combinaison des caractéristiques spectrales et du signal digitalisé améliore les performances en fournissant de l'information supplémentaire au DNN. Finalement, les redondances associées à ces systèmes sont étudiées, conduisant à la proposition de techniques permettant de réduire la taille et la complexité de ces systèmes et utilisant une initialisation structurée ainsi qu'une restructuration du modèle utilisant une décomposition en valeurs singulières (SVD).</description><creator>Bhargava, Mayank</creator><contributor>Richard Rose (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Milica Popovich (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</subject><title>Architectures for deep neural network based acoustic models for automatic speech recognition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33s041c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qs56v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z903264n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:38:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette recherche se concentre sur l'évaluation des coefficients de transfert de chaleur et de la qualité des particules en conserve dans des fluides non-Newtoniens subissant un traitement thermique dans un autoclave alternatif. Cependant, au cours du traitement thermique sous agitation, la vitesse de chauffage augmente largement, rendant l'évaluation du coefficient global (U) et du coefficient de transfert de chaleur entre le fluide et les particules (hfp) difficile et peu fiable. La nouvelle méthode a été prouvée vigoureuse et fournit des valeurs fiables et cohérentes de U et hfp, selon les conditions d'agitation réciproque. Par la suite, l'effet de divers procédés et produits sur U et hfp, pendant le traitement thermique par l'agitation réciproque, a été évalué en utilisant la méthodologie de surface de réponse. Les variables choisies pour cette analyse étaient: la température de fonctionnement (110-130 oC), la fréquence de l'agitation réciproque (1-4 Hz), l'amplitude de l'agitation réciproque  (5-25 cm), l'espace de tête (6-12 mm), la viscosité du liquide (0-1 % solution CMC), la taille des particules (15-25 mm), la densité des particules un (polypropylène, nylon, téflon), la concentration des particules (20-40% v/v), et la forme des particules (cube, une sphère, et le cylindre). Les résultats ont montré qu'avec une augmentation de la température, la fréquence, l'amplitude et de l'espace de tête, les valeurs de U et hfp ont augmenté. Cependant, avec l'augmentation de la viscosité et de la taille des particules, les valeurs de U et hfp ont diminué. En ce qui concerne des particules, U &amp; hfp suivent l'ordre suivant: Nylon&gt;Téflon&gt;polypropylène et Cube&gt;Sphère&gt;Cylindre. Avec l'augmentation de la concentration de particules, U et hfp ont augmenté jusqu'à avoir atteint un maximum puis ont diminué. Ainsi, il a été conclu qu'une intensité de mouvement alternatif de moins de 18 ms-2 est la mieux adaptée pour les produits sensibles à l'agitation. Par la suite, la qualité des légumes en conserve (haricots verts) soumis au traitement d'agitation thermique réciproque a été étudiée. Les haricots verts soumis à des températures élevées et à une fréquence de déplacement alternatif, présentaient une teneur plus élevée en chlorophylle ainsi qu'une meilleure rétention de l'activité des antioxydants. Cependant, les résultats ont également montré que la fréquence très élevée de la réciprocité pourrait endommager la texture des particules. Afin de réduire l'impact de l'agitation et de minimiser les pertes de la qualité qui pourraient résulter du mouvement rapide de va-et-vient des boîtes de conserve, un nouveau concept a été proposé. Celui-ci consiste à arrêter les agitations à mi-chemin pendant le processus, après un développement suffisant de la température au point froid.  Les résultats ont montré que l'arrêt des agitations, après un développement suffisant de la température au point froid, est un moyen efficace afin de réduire les dommages causés au produit en raison de l'agitation (ex. rupture des haricots et leur déversement dans le liquide). Les agitations dont la différence de température logarithmique est inférieure ou égale à 1, ont résulté en une meilleure couleur du produit ainsi qu'en une amélioration de la texture et de la qualité du produit. Ce dernier est un liquide contenant des particules ayant une faible viscosité. Cependant, les agitations prolongées, allant jusqu'au temps d'équilibrage ont été trouvées plus efficaces pour les produits ayant une grande viscosité.Enfin, le modèle artificiel de réseau de neurones (ANN) a été développé afin de réaliser une modélisation prédictive des coefficients de transfert de chaleur ainsi que du temps de traitement recommandé pour un traitement thermique d'agitation. Un modèle ANN couplé avec le modèle ANN-FD a également été développé afin de prédire la durée recommandée du processus qui permettrait d'obtenir la létalité désirée du produit soumis au traitement thermique. </description><description>This research focuses on evaluating heat transfer coefficients (using model particles) and quality of real food particulates in non-Newtonian fluids undergoing thermal processing in a lab-scale reciprocating retort. Evaluation of the heat transfer coefficient is the first step in any heat transfer study. During reciprocating agitation thermal processing (RA-TP) very rapid heating conditions exist which make evaluation of overall (U) and fluid-to-particle (hfp) heat transfer coefficients difficult and unreliable. Hence, a new methodology was proposed for evaluating U and hfp by using an average retort temperature and heat penetration parameter. The new method was found to be robust and produced reliable and consistent values of U and hfp, under reciprocating agitation conditions. Subsequent to this, the effect of various process and product variables on U and hfp during reciprocating agitation thermal processing were evaluated using a response surface methodology. The variables chosen for this analysis were: operating temperature (110-130 oC), reciprocation frequency (1-4 Hz), reciprocation amplitude (5-25 cm), can headspace (6-12 mm), liquid viscosity (0-1% CMC solution), particle size (15-25 mm), particle density (Polypropylene, Nylon, Teflon), particle concentration (20, 30, 40% v/v), and particle shape (cube, sphere, and cylinder). Results showed that with an increase in temperature, frequency, amplitude, and headspace, associated U and hfp values increased, but with an increasing liquid viscosity and particle size, U and hfp decreased. For particle density, U &amp; hfp followed the order: Nylon (1128 kg/m3)&gt; Teflon (2210 kg/m3)&gt; polypropylene (830 kg/m3). Amongst the three particle shapes studied, both heat transfer coefficients followed the trend: cube &gt; sphere &gt; cylinder. With an increase in particle concentration, U and hfp increased up to a maximum value and then decreased. It was concluded that a reciprocation intensity less than 18 ms-2 is best suited for products susceptible to agitation induced quality losses, and vice-versa. Following the heat transfer analysis, quality of canned green beans processed in RA-TP was studied. Green bean processed at higher temperatures and higher reciprocation frequency resulted in greener green beans with a better chlorophyll and better antioxidant activity retention. However, results also showed that very high reciprocation frequency can cause texture damage to food particulates (breakage of beans, increased turbidity of can fluid and leaching of chlorophyll etc.). In order to reduce the impact of agitation and to minimize the quality damage due to rapid back and forth motion of cans, a new concept of stopping agitations mid-way (after sufficient development of cold-spot temperature) during process was proposed. Results showed that stopping agitation after sufficient development of cold-spot temperatures is an effective way of reducing product damage caused by agitation (ex. breakage of beans and its leaching into liquid). Agitation continued  until achieving a product temperature 10oC lower than the retort  temperature gave the best color, texture and visual product quality for low viscosity liquid-particulate mixture and extended agitation till equilibration time was found to be best for high viscosity products. Finally, artificial neural network (ANN) models were developed for predictive modeling of heat transfer coefficients and process time in reciprocating agitation thermal processing.  The developed ANN model was found to accurately predict the heat transfer coefficients for canned green beans. An ANN model coupled with finite difference (ANN-FD model) was also developed for prediction of process time to provide desired lethality to a thermally processed product. This ANN-FD model gave process times comparable to Ball's formula method matched for most processing scenarios.</description><creator>Singh, Anika</creator><contributor>Hosahalli Ramaswamy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</subject><title>Studies on reciprocating agitation thermal processing of canned particulates in non-Newtonian fluid</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sw55s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903264n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):45750</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>