<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:22:50Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):21000" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f710f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In order to describe the ontogeny of solid food consumption by pigs and determine its influence on weight gain, before and after an abrupt weaning at 4 weeks of age, individual feed consumption was measured using a technique that combined load cells and video images. Feed consumption varied greatly both between and within litters. Within litters, consumption was positively correlated with birth weight, and with early weight gains. This suggests that greater feed intake was typical of larger and more mature pigs rather than reflecting compensation for poor milk intake by smaller litter-mates. Within-litter differences in weight gain during the two weeks after weaning were positively correlated with birth weight but not correlated with pre-weaning creep feed intake. Creep feed intake appeared to contribute to pre-weaning gains and these were correlated with post-weaning gains; however a more direct affect on post-weaning gain could not be detected.</description><creator>Pajor, Edmond A.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Swine -- Feeding and feeds.</subject><subject>Animal behavior</subject><title>The correlates of individual variation in the ontogeny of solid food consumption in pigs /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021g42k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f710f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053h15s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis describes the design and hardware implementation of a high speed multi-processor interface used in a colour graphics animation system. The design involves the use of Direct Memory Access to move data between the memories of the various CPUs constituting the Grads system. The system accommodates the various bus protocols, word sizes, and interrupt schemes of the different processors. An evaluation of the completed system is presented.</description><creator>Pancholy, Rajiv</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>A multiprocessor interface for a colour graphics animation system /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096818r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053h15s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j674j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study determines the effects of variations in suspended biomass, organic carbon, and pH on the time course of 2,2$ sp prime$,4,4$ sp prime$,5,5$ sp prime$-hexachlorobiphenyl uptake by laboratory cultures of Selenastrum capricornutum. Variations in pH had no effect, but uptake was enhanced by higher levels of biomass and depressed by higher levels of organic carbon. The coefficients for these measured effects on hexachlorobiphenyl were combined with existing relations based on molecular connectivity (X) or capacity ratio (K$ sp prime$) to yield semi-empirical equations to predict the instantaneous rate of uptake and bioconcentration factor (BCF) of organic contaminants as: eqalign{&amp; rm Log rate = {-}3.30 + 0.32 X + 1.1 Log biomass {-}0.42 Log Abs cr&amp; rm Log BCF = 4.11 + 0.86 Log K sp prime {-}0.87 Log biomass {-}0.22 Log Abs cr} The utility of these equations was assessed by comparing time courses of hexachlorobiphenyl uptake predicted from them with time courses observed in water from eleven Quebec lakes.</description><creator>Richer, Guylaine</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Selenastrum capricornutum.</subject><subject>Plankton -- Effect of water pollution on.</subject><subject>Polychlorinated biphenyls -- Physiological effect.</subject><title>Determinants of the short term dynamics of PCB uptake by the plankton</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mw407.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j674j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712m775n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The evolution of the Unemployment Insurance Programme since 1940 has led to the abandonment of the intended insurance nature of the programme. As a result, it can no longer be considered solely an income protection scheme. Rather, it has evolved into an income maintenance plan aimed at supplementing the income of seasonal workers in high unemployment regions. As a consequence, there has been an interprovincial transfer of unemployment insurance funds from low to high unemployment regions. The regional characteristics of the programme have also distorted the structure of labour markets in high unemployment regions by attracting workers in seasonal industries therefore maintaining unemployment rates high.</description><creator>Rochon, Louis-Philippe</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Unemployment -- Newfoundland and Labrador</subject><subject>Unemployment -- Ontario</subject><subject>Unemployment -- Effect of unemployment insurance on</subject><subject>Insurance, Unemployment -- Canada -- History</subject><title>The regionalization of the unemployment insurance programme in Canada : its effect on income redistribution, Newfoundland and Ontario, 1980-1988</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dg89c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m775n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88ch80g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the main responsibilities of a sound engineer is to control the quality of the sound during the recording process. An important qualitative aspect of a recording, besides the musicality of the performance, is its timbral content. Proper level and spectral balance between the mixed elements of the recording and the absence of extraneous noises and distortion are key elements. Therefore, timbre perception acuity is an essential skill for sound engineers. This thesis proposes a computer-assisted system as a training tool for developing and maintaining aural skills related to timbre perception. A set of criteria for the design of such a system based on current knowledge in timbre perception is presented and an exploratory implementation is described. Limits of the current system are discussed and areas that need further investigation are identified.</description><creator>Quesnel, René</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Tone color (Music)</subject><subject>Auditory perception</subject><subject>Ear training -- Computer-assisted instruction</subject><title>A computer-assisted program in timbral ear training : a preliminary study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n2262.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88ch80g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311q41n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The picritic volcanic suite of Baffin Island is comprised of two different types of magmas which are analogous to N and E-MORB. Although these two picritic lavas-types are spatially intermixed in the stratigraphic succession, they are distinct in terms of light rare earth elements (LREE), K/Ti and $ sp{87}$Sr/$ sp{86}$Sr ratios. N-type lavas are depleted in LREE and have K/Ti ratio  0.5 and $ sp{87}$Sr/$ sp{86}$Sr ratios ranging between 0.7032 and 0.7039. Olivine fractionation and partial melting models involving a single homogeneous source can not reproduce the trace element differences between these two magma types. The generation of N and E-type magmas is most easily explained by small scale mantle heterogeneity. A possible model for the nature of the source is that of the head of a mantle plume which has an entrained depleted mantle.</description><creator>Robillard, Isabelle</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>Trace element constraints on the origin of the Baffin Bay lavas</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d7733.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311q41n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn009z968</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chaos theory has only recently been related to various phenomena in the earth sciences. Here, using systems theory in a description of geological processes, we study the chaotic development of sedimentary sequences. The geosystem is treated as a partially specified system in order to apply qualitative stability analysis in the investigation of sedimentation behaviour and interactions among geological processes. The analysis suggests that the sedimentary system is unstable. This instability in conjunction with the system's sensitive dependence to internal fluctuations (i.e., those generated within the system) provide supporting evidence to suggest a chaotic behaviour for the sedimentation system. We suggest that chaos could act as the common underlying mechanism which is manifest as the fractal-flicker noise character observed in reflectivity well logs. Acoustic impedance variations--the geophysical measures of lithologic variability--represent the internal organization of the interacting geological processes. This organization under a chaotic regime is responsible for the common statistical character found in various sedimentary basins.</description><creator>Karavas, Costas</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Geology.</subject><subject>Geophysics.</subject><title>Fractal chaotic systems : investigation of the geological system and its sedimentation behaviour</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mr001.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn009z968</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2v23vv393</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines how Aristotle's theory of friendship deals with differences between persons, given that his paradigm case is that of friendship between men who are excellent without qualification. I argue that because of his teleological understanding of human virtue, Aristotle believes that such men will share a comprehensive set of affective and rational apprehensions of the good; true friends will love and understand each other because of their identity in virtue. I establish my interpretation against a rival view, which sees Aristotle as sensitive to the need for attentiveness to and valuation of differences between friends: while I show this latter view to be exegetically untenable, I suggest that it is informed by modern understandings of individual uniqueness which provide the basis for a critique of Aristotle. Finally, I explore the implications of a 'difference' critique of Aristotle for his understanding of the bonds which unite political communities.</description><creator>Kahane, David J (David Joshua), 1962-</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Friendship -- Philosophy</subject><subject>Aristotle -- Views on friendship</subject><subject>Ethics</subject><title>Identity and difference in Aristotle's theory of perfect friendship</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gh45n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vv393</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mk218</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to compare the concentration of and the time to peak blood lactate following three 90-s cycle ergometer tests--intermittent all-out (Int-A), continuous all-out (Cont-A), and continuous constant (Cont-C), and to compare group peak lactate to blood lactate at individual peak time. Eight fingertip blood samples were drawn between 1 and 12min post-exercise. Subjects were university hockey players (n = 19) and physical education students (n = 19). The two all-out tests had a higher peak concentration than the Cont-C test (P $&lt;$ 0.05). The Int-A test had an earlier peak than the two continuous tests (P $&lt;$ 0.05) but this difference vanished if peak time was measured from the onset of the tests. A number of sampling times had lactate concentrations similar to the individual peak concentration (P $&lt;$ 0.05): (1) 1, 2, 3, and 4min for Int-A; (2) 2, 3, 4, 5, and 6min for Cont-A; (3) 2 and 4min for Cont-C.</description><creator>Koziris, L. Perry (Lymperis Perry)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Blood lactate.</subject><subject>Physical fitness -- Testing</subject><subject>Cycling -- Physiological aspects</subject><title>Blood lactates following intermittent and continuous cycling tests of anaerobic capacity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n227b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mk218</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33rx839</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The northern Park Ranges are underlain by middle and upper Miette Group (+/$-$ 2800 m thick), Gog Group (700 to 1200 m thick) and unnamed Middle Cambrian(?) ($&gt;$1000 m thick) strata. The regional structure is dominated by the southeast-plunging Porcupine Creek Anticlinorium (PCA). The core of the PCA is characterized by large-scale upright folds broken by thrust faults. The west flank of the PCA and the adjacent Baker syncline (BS) are deformed by steeply southwest-dipping post-metamorphic thrust faults and Eocene (?) normal faults. The Precambrian Hugh Allan Gneiss is faulted against the west flank of the PCA by a post-metamorphic thrust, the Hugh Allan thrust. The Hugh Allan thrust has been correlated with the Purcell thrust of southern British Columbia. Metamorphic grade increases from greenschist in the east to lower amphibolite in the west adjacent to the Hugh Allan (Purcell) thrust.</description><creator>Klein, Gabriela, 1963-</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>Geology of the northern park ranges and Porcupine Creek Anticlinorium, British Columbia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117q084.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33rx839</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311q42x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Leather tanning, one of mankind's oldest industries, is in a time of environmental transition. Traditionally a "wet" industry, many processes result in pollution loads which are not acceptable in today's legislative environment. For this study, the largest Canadian Retanner, located outside of Montreal, Quebec, allowed its processes and associated waste products and loads to be characterized. A physico-chemical treatment regime, utilizing precipitation, coagulation, and flocculation technology, was then proposed and implemented on the laboratory level. The results were positive, but the solid waste product from treatment was found to present its own set of environmental problems. Finally, the various reuse, recycling, and reduction opportunities applicable to the tanning industry were explored, as was their applicability to the re-tanner in question.</description><creator>Di Perno, Norman J. (Norman Joseph)</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><subject>Engineering, Sanitary and Municipal.</subject><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Physico-chemical and resource management options for a Canadian leather retanner</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hk29q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311q42x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440t579</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Observations of tidally forced flow in a constricted region of a highly stratified sound are examined as a problem of two-layer hydraulic exchange. It is shown that the narrowest section and the region downstream of the narrowest section were subject to internal hydraulic control. Bores moved upstream and evolved into packets of internal solitary waves with 3-6 minute period when the tide turned to ebb. Using results from different models of the solitary wave based on the KdV equation, it is shown that the second-order nonlinear term must be included in the two-layer model. The results from a first-order continuously stratified model gave similar good results. This implies that two-layer models may ignore some properties of the real fluid and that the internal solitons are also sensitive to the stratification characteristics of the water column. It is found that the mixing was related to both the vertical velocity shear, the hydraulic characteristics of the flow and the presence of solitary waves.</description><creator>Gan, Jianping, 1962-</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Physical Oceanography.</subject><title>Internal hydraulics, solutions and associated mixing in a stratified sound</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m054h.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440t579</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tw32s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the hypothesis that social learning in Zenaida dove (Zenaida aurita) functions primarily in a mixed species foraging context. The field study recorded foraging associations and interactions between Zenaida doves and other species. The Carib grackle (Quiscalus lugubris) was the most frequent foraging associate of Zenaida doves. The laboratory study consisted of two experiments where conflicting information about a novel food type and novel food-finding problem was provided simultaneously by a conspecific and a heterospecific (grackle) demonstrator. Both experiments showed that not only could Zenaida doves learn from another species, but that they preferred the heterospecific demonstrator over the conspecific. The results suggest that social information may be obtained more readily from foraging associations rather than interference competition and that the role of conspecifics may be overemphasized in cultural learning.</description><creator>Dolman, Carrie</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Zenaida -- Behavior.</subject><subject>Social learning.</subject><title>Preference for a heterospecific demonstrator in a territorial dove</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676w790.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tw32s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nj25r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main purpose of this thesis is to investigate a method for estimating loop integrals containing large masses. Working in Feynman parameter space, the method consists of determining the regions of integration that give the dominant contributions. The method is applied to some integrals that have been worked out in the literature, and it is found that the method can be simple to apply. The percent difference between the approximate and exact results using masses consistent with the Standard Model is typically roughly 30%. Also given are general formulae for arbitrary convergent and divergent one loop integrals with the external momenta set equal to zero.</description><creator>Dhirani, Al-Amin</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Physics, General.</subject><title>Loop integrals containing large masses</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cx613.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nj25r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644s743</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In an epidemiological study of mental health in couples, individual and systemic approaches were compared in terms of their appropriateness for general versus clinical populations. The primary results from the study of 845 couples in the general population suggest that there exists a significant spouse-similarity across the various mental health dimensions examined (psychological distress, general well-being, and role satisfaction). The main results from the study of 17 couples in marital therapy suggest that significant sex differences exist in dyadic adjustment. Sex differences were also noted in the correlations between dyadic adjustment and depressive symptoms. In conclusion, it appears that epidemiological research on the mental health of couples should have as its objective a simultaneous consideration of both the individual and the couple, as well as a simultaneous consideration of clinical and general populations, in order to create a double complementarity out of this apparent double dichotomy.</description><creator>Galbaud du Fort, Guillaume</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Psychology, Social.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health.</subject><title>Epidémiologie et santé mentale du couple : etude comparée de données populationnelles et de données cliniques</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mn34g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644s743</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82k830w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The presence of the Gulf Stream in the cold season, and a cold air outbreak following a previous cyclone passage are two important precursors of a case of rapid cyclogenesis on 13-14 December 1988. The study showed that a large area of conditional instability in the lower troposphere, and an area of symmetric instability primarily over the sea, coinciding with small values of isentropic potential vorticity below the 290$ sp circ$K level were associated with strong surface heat fluxes. During the time prior to the onset of this cyclogenesis, the surface frontogenetical forcing was dominated by diabatic frontogenesis, and later, by geostrophic frontogenesis, though the diabatic heating still contributed substantially to this forcing. The cyclone formed and continued to travel along a prominent axis of frontogenetic forcing. Kinematically-computed vertical motions, derived from both conventional and special ERICA soundings, show good agreement with analyses and diagnostics in the domain.</description><creator>Trat, Diep N.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>Frontogenesis and surface heat fluxes associated with a case of rapid cyclogenesis during ERICA</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn3012441.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k830w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52j922t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis deals with problems of conflict of laws and its latest developments, especially in Europe, in relation to international air transport. (1) The contractual situations connected with air transport are analysed in light of the applicable international air law conventions and of a comparative survey of the conflict of laws rules of some states and international conventions on conflict of laws concerning contracts. Where the international air law conventions do not supply the solution or where they are not applicable resort has to be made to the conflict of laws. (2) Conflict of laws also arises in the legal interaction (contracts, sale of goods, transfer of ownership--res in transitu, torts, marriages, wills, etc.) between persons onboard an aircraft in flight. (3) The aircraft as an expensive and highly mobile chattel poses problems from the rights in rem point of view in the conflict of laws. (4) Aircraft accidents and the tortious liability of persons and entities involved as well as obligations arising from assistance and rescue operations pose conflict of laws problems.</description><creator>Lagerberg, Eric M.</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Law.</subject><title>Conflicts of laws in private international air law</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d538d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j922t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:73666565s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Non-metallic inclusions in steel such as alumina, silicates, etc. are detrimental to many steel properties. Elimination of these inclusions has long been a major target in steelmaking. In this investigation, attempts have been made to remove these non-metallic inclusions by passing the liquid steel through a ceramic filter. It was found that this approach is very effective for removing solid non-wetting inclusions such as alumina. It appeared that liquid silicates could also be removed to some degree.</description><creator>Tian, Chenguo</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>On the removal of non-metallic inclusions from molten steel through filtration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s358n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666565s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j6731511t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>$ sp1$H nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) studies were carried out on blends of lightly sulfonated polystyrenes (PS-SSA) (5 to 15 mole % sulfonation) of molecular weight (MW's) ranging from 5000 to 100,000, with poly(methyl methacrylate-co-4-vinyl pyridine) (PMMA-4VP) copolymers (5 to 11 mole %) of MW = 100,000. The process of coil overlap was monitored as a function of time by the acquisition of a proton spectra, which showed the gradual disappearance of the original methoxy signal and the appearance of a new signal originating from the shielded methoxy protons. The contributions of the two species were separated using a deconvolution program. In order to propose a complete model for the coil overlap phenomenon, parameters that can influence the kinetics of the process were studied. The parameters included the water content of the solution, the ion content of copolymers, the temperature, the MW of PS-SSA and the total polymer concentration. It was found that the water content had no influence on the shielding process. The study of all the other parameters showed that the overlap was occurring through a complex mechanism. It was determined that the true order (n$ sb{c}$) for the shielding process was second-order, reflecting the early stages of the mixing process. In the stage in which the "ladder" like complex is produced, the experimental data can be best represented by a kinetic expression containing two opposing first order reactions.</description><creator>Bossé, Francis</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Kinetics of coil overlap in ionomer blends by 1H NMR in DMSOd6</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kk815.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j6731511t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wh246t16k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study is concerned with the biodegradation of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons (PAHs), particularly the utilization of biological processes in the bioremediation of PAH-contaminated soils. In this regard, the effects of the contaminant bioavailability and the redox environment on the biodegradation process have been investigated. First, the mineralization of naphthalene in soil/water systems under denitrifying conditions has been studied. Results showed that naphthalene mineralization is influenced by its availability to the microbial population, which in turn is a function of the compound initial concentration, the sorption/desorption characteristics of the soil/contaminant complex and the organic content of the soil. Second, the biodegradation of four PAH compounds, acenaphthene, acenaphthylene, fluorene and anthracene, in a soil/water system under four redox environments has been studied. Both aerobic and denitrifying environments supported appreciable PAH biodegradation rates. The denitrifying environment was chosen for a further experiment to investigate the performance of a bioreactor system in treating PAH-contaminated soils. Results showed that by enlarging the scale of the reactor by approximately eight times and simultaneously reducing the mixing intensity of the soil slurry, the biodegradation rates of the PAH compounds remained virtually unchanged.</description><creator>Al-Bashir, Bilal</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><subject>Engineering, Sanitary and Municipal.</subject><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Biodegradation of polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbons in soilwater systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k6256.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246t16k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d56zx74k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Field research was carried out in the community of Notre Dame de Grace, an urban environment typical of the kind in which more and more older women will reside as Canada's population ages. Results of a questionnaire administered to 232 older urban dwellers demonstrate there are significant differences, especially with regard to fearfulness, in the ways in which elderly women who live alone, elderly women who do not live alone and elderly men know and use urban environments. Recommendations are made for changes to the planning process which would result in urban communities better suited to the needs of elderly women. Anthony Gidden's structuration theory is applied as a framework for explaining why older women are more fearful than elderly men, and why older women alone are the most fearful group. Deficiencies in feminist and gerontological approaches are identified, and an argument is made for greater integration of these perspectives.</description><creator>Charlton, Wendy</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Older women -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Community development, Urban</subject><subject>Notre-Dame-de-Grâce (Montréal, Québec).</subject><subject>Urban ecology -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><title>Gender differences in fearfulness among elderly urban dwellers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fq162.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zx74k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m039k626g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Distributing discrete event simulations among several processors appears to be a promising approach to speed up simulations and reduce the complexity of the tasks to be accomplished by each processor. Processing the events in parallel requires a synchronization technique which would insure the simulation correctness while keeping the overhead relatively low. In a distributed simulation, the simulation progresses at a different speed in every processor. The main problem consists in enabling a processor to know if it holds all the information needed to correctly make a further step in the simulation. We describe an algorithm having fixed memory requirements and allowing a processor to know if it holds a complete set of information in order to correctly continue the simulation. The algorithm also forces missing information to arrive at a processor that requested it.</description><creator>Côté, Claire</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Pseudosimulation in distributed simulations : a deadlock prevention algorithm with fixed memory requirements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042v091.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k626g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pg15bg177</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of the present investigation was to study the aggregating proteoglycans in rib cartilages from patients with pseudoachondroplasia in comparison with those from age-matched normals. Biochemical and immunochemical analyses using antibodies against different substructures of these molecules permitted an investigation of their contents, structures, sizes, and aggregatability with hyaluronic acid. The structural changes in proteoglycans were characterized by longer chondroitin sulfate chains, with reduced 4-sulfation, unchanged 6-sulfation and increased non-sulfation, which resulted in larger molecules. These chains were attached to proteolgycan core protein by fewer chondroitin 4-sulfate linkage regions and more unsulfated chondroitin linkage regions. There were three populations of proteolgycans of different sizes in normals at all ages (4, 11 and 30 years old) and an adult patient (31 years old). These three populations were characterized by an abundance of chondroitin 6-sulfate epitope and fetal-specific epitope 846, of chondroitin 4-sulfate epitope, and of keratan sulfate in order of decreasing sizes. There was an absence of the population of proteoglycans of intermediate size recognized in young patients (4 and 12 years old). There were also decreased contents of the hyaluronic acid-binding region and keratan sulfate in the adult patient. Hyaluronic acid content was considerably increased in these patients. The latter changes may reflect differences in turnover of proteoglycans in the cartilage matrix in pseudoachondroplasia.</description><creator>Hirata, Soichiro</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Immunochemical studies of aggregating cartilage proteoglycans in pseudoachondroplasia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73px214.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bg177</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n583xw15w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Article 22 of the Warsaw Convention, 1929 limits the liability of the air carrier in the event of death or wounding of a passenger to 125,000 Francs-Poincare based on a defined gold value. In 1955, the limitation has been raised to 250,000 Francs-Poincare. As gold has lost its special position in the monetary system the value of the limitation of liability has decreased and some plaintiffs have argued that the limitation of liability is unconstitutional. The Warsaw System is presented, the grounds for a limitation of liability, and Article 22 are analyzed. The relationship between municipal law and international law is described. The constitutionality of Article 22 is examined for the jurisdictions of Italy, the Federal Republic of Germany and the United States of America. Those lines of argumentation that could be used to challenge Article 22 in all constitutional systems similar to those of the abovementioned States are presented.</description><creator>Hirt, Michael</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>The constitutions of Italy, the Federal Republic of Germany and the United States of America in relation to Article 22 of the Warsaw Convention /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xw165.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xw15w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vc637</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:47:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Both in Canada and in the United States the law disadvantages gay men and lesbians. This master's thesis considers whether the guarantee of equality in the U.S. Constitution and in the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms can change this situation. The first part argues that in theory the Fourteenth Amendment's equal protection clause provides a promising basis for challenges to policies and statutes that discriminate against gays. Nevertheless, these challenges are unlikely to be successful because most U.S. courts fail to see beyond the stereotypes that prevent homosexuals from gaining access to their civil rights. The second part contends that the approach to constitutional equality taken by the Supreme Court of Canada might be more helpful in eradicating discrimination against gays. Challenges of, e.g., policies excluding homosexuals from the Canadian Forces or the exclusion of same-sex couples from the benefits that heterosexual couples enjoy should be successful.</description><creator>Jürgens, Ralf Erich, 1961-</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Political Science, Public Administration.</subject><title>Equality and gay rights in the United States and in Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vs097.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vc637</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):21025</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>