<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:51:14Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):25525" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74cr048</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:15:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Standards are complex phenomena that exist in almost every area  of human life, whether in the form of language, stock scenes in literature and  films, computer user interfaces or protocols that allow data transfer over the  internet. They are important building blocks for any form of human activity.  Property rights in standards, provided by the laws of intellectual property, can  foster their development by giving incentives to create technologies or works that  are capable to become standards; but property rights can also impede further  innovation since they allow the owner to exclude others from the use of the  protected standard. Furthermore, standards are perceived to offer higher returns in  form of royalties than "regular" technologies. In this context,  standardization has been used as an argument to reduce the scope of protection for  standard technologies with respect to computer user interfaces. The thesis evaluates the soundness of a general argument of  standardization for weaker protection in intellectual property law. It elaborates  the arguments that are put forward to justify weaker protection in standards  regarding the characteristics of standards and standardization as well as the  justifications for intellectual property. It analyses the applicability of  trademark, copyright and patent law to both already existing as well as developing  standards. In particular, the concepts of genericness and descriptiveness in  trademark law, the merger and scenes a faire doctrines in copyright law and the  doctrines of patent misuse and patent abuse in patent law are  discussed.</description><creator>Fraessdorf, Henning</creator><contributor>Lametti, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Industrial property</subject><subject>Standardization -- Law and legislation</subject><subject>Standardization</subject><title>Intellectual property in standards</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386j86f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cr048</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78tc63m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:15:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The following qualitative study explored self-reported  iatrogenic effects of intervention with data collected through semi-structured  interviews. This small clinical sample consisted of four female adult  "survivors" between the age of 34 and 47 who had experienced childhood  sexual abuse perpetrated by at least one caregiver. The findings indicated  significant iatrogenic effects particularly for the victims who disclosed in  childhood that included a strong theme of betrayal by the systems that were supposed  to protect them. One woman continued to be sexually abused, while another woman was  returned to the home where she had been physically abused, following no intervention  and/or protection by child protection services. Although other services such as  police, crown attorney, medical and therapeutic systems were involved in some of  these situations, the survivors perceived these as inadequate and leading to strong  distrust of intervention. In contrast, those survivors who disclosed again in  adulthood reported a significantly improved experience with less iatrogenic effects.  The iatrogenic effects of intervention require further research with a larger and  diversified sample in order to identify current iatrogenic effects of each  intervention for children and survivors.</description><creator>Ryan, Eithne</creator><contributor>Thompson, Ingrid (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Sexual abuse victims</subject><subject>Child welfare</subject><title>The iatrogenic effects of intervention with sexual abuse victims from a retrospective position /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns064668n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tc63m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d035t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:15:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to explore the experiences and  needs of families during the admission of a child to a paediatric ward in an acute  care hospital. Qualitative research methods were used to access the caregivers' and  professionals' perceptions of the culture that families experience in a paediatric  in-patient setting. For this project, data collection methods included a review of  the literature in the area, individual interviews with caregivers, and focus groups  with paediatric health care professionals. In the study, both parents and paediatric professionals  described a multitude of experiences and needs of families during a child's  admission to a paediatric ward in an acute care setting. Understanding the  experiences and needs of families is important for professionals. The information  collected in this study provides some insight into the culture that families  experience when their child is admitted to a paediatric ward in an acute care  hospital.</description><creator>O'Reilly, Glenda</creator><contributor>Lach, Lucyna (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Children -- Hospital care</subject><subject>Hospitals -- Admission and discharge</subject><title>Families in today's health care system : the experience of families during pediatric admission</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580n20f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d035t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78tc64w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:15:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Culture shock and reverse culture shock are profoundly personal  experiences affecting individuals in a multitude of diverse ways. They happen inside  each person who encounters unfamiliar events and unexpected situations. For people  who work abroad (sojourners), cultural adjustment is a significant time in their  lives. Following the examination of cultural adjustment, a review of literature is  explored, highlighting sojourners' acculturation and coping strategies. A case study  of the JET (Japanese Exchange Teaching) Programme is presented through an analysis  of public documents and interviews with JET staff and former sojourners. Findings  report that JET sojourners experience adjustment difficulties with reverse culture  shock and that there exists an unavailability of resources providing support.  Limitations of the study are highlighted; areas of weakness were found in the lack  of literature addressing the needs and experiences of sojourners, particularly JETs.  Recommendations and suggestions for future research in the field of social work are  made.</description><creator>Callender, Shauna</creator><contributor>Wehbi, Samantha (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Culture shock.</subject><subject>Canadians -- Japan.</subject><subject>Foreign workers -- Japan.</subject><subject>Reverse culture shock.</subject><subject>JET Puroguramu</subject><title>Cultural adjustment : an exploratory case study of the Japanese Exchange Teaching programme and its implication for social work practice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440t030.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tc64w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rf55z844d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:15:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A most deafening silence is the effect created by the omission  of Whiteness from racial discourses. Those within the social work profession, who  seek to eradicate racism have for the most part, restricted their analyses to  dissecting and defining the racial "Other". This has perhaps unwittingly  implied an acceptance of "Whiteness" as an all-powerful, unnamed  normality, exempted from the requirement of definition. This examination of White  racial identity is an attempt to engage in a discussion of a different  sort---exploring racism at its source. Those actively involved in the practice  and/or study of Social Work in Montreal (Quebec) were asked to contemplate the  meaning of "Whiteness" in society and in their own lives. Their  interpretations were aligned with social and cultural interpretations, as well as my  own interpretations. This study illustrates that, in spite of its elusive nature,  Whiteness does indeed have very powerful meanings for those who have access to this  racial category, those excluded, and the society in which we live.</description><creator>Ferguson, Debbie Elizabeth</creator><contributor>Leonard, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Whites -- Race identity</subject><subject>Social workers -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Attitudes</subject><title>White racial identity and social work practice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429981x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55z844d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tv75c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:15:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Concentrated solutions of hydroxypropylcellulose in aqueous and in polar organic solvents form lyotropic liquid crystalline phases. The critical concentration of hydroxypropylcellulose needed for anisotropic phase separation is dependent upon the solvent and is much greater than that expected for rod-like species in solution. The flexibility of the cellulosic chains in a particular solvent is believed to be the main factor governing the critical hydroxypropylcellulose volume fraction at phase separation. The anisotropic phase exhibits birefringence, iridescence, and very high optical activity, properties characteristic of cholesteric liquid crystals. The helicoidal pitch for most of these cholesteric samples in water and organic solvents varies from 280 to 700 nm, but in certain organic solvents the helicoidal pitch ranges up to 6000 nm. The latter samples exhibit fingerprint-like periodicity lines in the light microscope and distinctive "shimmering" colors. For both types of samples the helicoidal pitch is found to vary inversely with the third power of the hydroxypropylcellulose volume fraction. A model is proposed for the cholesteric structure in which the average separation, d, between the chain molecules varies with (phi)(,2)('- 1/2), where (phi)(,2) is the polymer volume fraction. The experimental x-ray diffraction data are in accord with this relationship. The angular twist between the molecules in adjacent cholesteric layers is calculated to vary from 0.30 to 1.8(DEGREES) over the mesophase concentration range investigated. Light scattering measurements give twice the weight average molar mass for hydroxypropylcellulose as do sedimentation equilibrium measurements. Viscosity measurements in organic solvents show that the hydroxypropylcellulose conformation in dilute solution is neither that of a random coil nor that of a rigid rod. All aqueous hydroxypropylcellulose solutions show a lower consolute temperature that varies more with the sample molar substitution than with its molar mass. A qualitative "phase" diagram for aqueous hydroxypropylcellulose solutions is also included.</description><creator>Werbowyj, Rita Stephania.</creator><date>1982</date><subject>Polymers.</subject><subject>Liquid crystals.</subject><title>Characterization of hydroxypropylcellulose cholesteric lyomesophases</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zx16p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tv75c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558d93g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:15:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The behavior of biphenyl and naphthyl sulfinate and sulfoxylate esters under flash vacuum thermolytic and photolytic conditions was studied and a new tetrasubstituted dihydrophenanthrene was isolated. Several, 2,2'-biphenyl diols were synthesized including some with specifically deuterated alkyl chains. These diols were cyclized to give symmetrically substituted as well as cis-/trans- unsymmetrically substituted dibenzoxepins. The dynamic NMR properties of these dibenzoxepins were studied and the free energy barriers of conformational inversion were measured and related to the steric interactions of the alkyl substituents. The preferred conformations of the trans-dibenzoxepins were related to the relative stabilities of the alkyl substituents in the axial or equatorial position. The reaction of the 2,2'-biphenyl diols with trimethylsilylbromide yielded diolefinic biphenyls. In some other cases rearrangements to cyclized products were observed. The photolytic cyclization of the diolefinic biphenyls resulted in new tetrasubstituted tetrahydropyrenes and pyrenes.</description><creator>Mullins, Dennis F.</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Biphenyl compounds.</subject><subject>Diolefins.</subject><title>2, 21-biphenyl diols : synthesis and reaction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h257r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558d93g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526c98r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:15:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The fatigue of the human diaphragm during resting ventilation^was found to be determined by the fraction of the maximal trans-^diaphragmatic pressure used at each inspiration (Pdi/Pdi(' )max) and the fraction of the breathing cycle time spent in inspiration (T(,I)/T(,TOT)). A fatigue threshold relation was found between the Pdi/Pdi(' )max and the T(,I)/T(,TOT). This fatigue threshold corresponds to a quadratic hyperbola function given by the product (Pdi/Pdi(' )max) times (T(,I)/T(,TOT)). This product was termed the diaphragmatic tension-time index (TTdi) and at the fatigue threshold is equal to .15 (TTdi crit). Above TTdi crit the endurance time is limited and is accompanied by a progressive shift of the EMG power spectrum towards lower frequencies. The rate of shift of the EMG power spectrum is proportional to the endurance time. Patients with chronic obstructive lung disease breathe at rest closer to the fatigue threshold than normals secondary to an increased airway resistance and a decreased Pdi max. Minor modifications of the breathing cycle in those patients were found to cause diaphragmatic fatigue. Diaphragmatic blood flow (Qdi)(' )in dogs was measured during static continuous and intermittent stimulated contractions. Qdi(' )was found to be related to the TTdi and to be maximal at a TTdi of .20. At higher and lower TTdi,(' )Qdi decreases and is zero at TTdi of .75. When the TTdi was greater than .20, a post contraction hyperaemia was present and increased as a function of TTdi, thus indicating that the(' )Qdi was limited in the preceding contractions.</description><creator>Bellemare, François.</creator><date>1982</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Diaphragmatic fatigue : mechanisms and assessment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429983g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526c98r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vh405</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:15:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Rabbits with experimentally-induced inflammatory and degenerative arthritic lesions were examined for the development of immunity to homologous collagens and cartilage proteoglycans. Cellular immunity, assessed in vitro by the stimulation of ('3)H-thymidine incorporation into spleen and blood lymphocytes, could be detected to types I, II and III collagens and proteoglycans. The responses to collagens were primarily detected with degraded molecules whereas responses to proteoglycans could be detected with both native and degraded preparations. Anti-proteoglycan antibodies could be detected in the sera of rabbits with inflammatory, but not degenerative, arthritis. Anti-collagen antibodies were never detected. Cellular, but not humoral, immunity to proteoglycans and degraded type III collagen could also be induced by injection of these antigens in Freund's complete adjuvant. Age-related changes in the structure of rabbit costal cartilage proteoglycans and in the antigenicity of human articular cartilage proteoglycans were also demonstrated. The data presented have paved the way for future experiments designed to investigate the role of immunity to proteoglycans and collagens in perpetuating arthritic lesions.</description><creator>Champion, Brian Robert.</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Immunity to homologous collagens and cartilage proteoglycans in rabbits with experimental arthritis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nr63v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vh405</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v373w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:15:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the coalescence zone, we obtained ozone concentration profiles of pairs of bubbles in vertical and oblique alignments, which show rapid decrease in the interaction period and more gradual decline in the late stages of coalescence. In the grid region, the hydrodynamics of a stream of gas injected vertically into a bed of solids was observed in a semi-circular column containing particles of several sizes and densities. This was found to be similar to those reported in the literature. Furthermore, experiments were carried out in a 15 cm diameter column to characterize the magnitude of gas transfer from spout to dense phase and from forming bubbles to dense phase. The results show that the transfer from the spout is mainly due to convective gas outflow with some molecular diffusion. While during bubble formation, the transfer seems to be molecular diffusion only, being similar in magnitude to single bubbles in fluidized beds.</description><creator>Sit, Song P.</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Mass transfer.</subject><subject>Bubbles.</subject><subject>Fluidized reactors.</subject><title>Grid region and and coalescence zone gas exchange in fluidized beds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vr58z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v373w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602127r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:15:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis contains eight chapters. The first deals with Gide's knowledge of English, the second with his ideas on translation. The remaining six examine his versions of the following: Gitanjali by Rabindranath Tagore, parts of Leaves of Grass by Walt Whitman, The Post Office by Tagore, Typhoon by Joseph Conrad, The Marriage of Heaven and Hell by William Blake and the preface of The Old Wive's Tale by Arnold Bennett. The principal conclusions reached are that his English was alarmingly weak, that he must have depended a good deal on the help of others, that his theory of translation was extremely subjective, and that the translations examined, although original, concise and elegant (indeed more elegant than the English text in the case of the two works by Tagore), are too free as well as being simply erroneous in many places.</description><creator>Sims, Nicholas</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Gide, André, 1869-1951 -- Knowledge -- Languages.</subject><subject>Translating and interpreting.</subject><subject>Gide, André, 1869-1951 -- Careers.</subject><title>André Gide, traducteur d'anglais littéraire</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644s166.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602127r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816n172</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:15:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Learning disabled boys were categorized on the basis of consistency of lowest WISC/WISC-R factor scores over time. The Consistent subgroup with lowest scores on factor 3 also displayed significant factor score discrepancy. The Inconsistent subgroup had varying lowest factor scores with no significant discrepancy, such variation not apparently related to a delay hypothesis. Patterns in the Consistent Factor 3 group could be suggestive of either a delay or deficit. Group differences occurred frequently in patterns, rather than levels of performance, the Inconsistents displaying patterns similar to able learners. Disorders of sequential processing and abnormal right hemisphere specialization characterized the Consistent Factor 3 group, inefficient selective attention the Inconsistent group. Pervasive group differences in holistic versus sequential processing were related to the hemisphere specialization index and both were related to WISC-R discrepancy scores. Thus, factor score discrepancies may usefully define these subgroups. A model of hemisphere functioning was offered in explanation of these results.</description><creator>MacKenzie, Joan P.</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Ability -- Testing.</subject><subject>Learning disabilities.</subject><subject>Wechsler Intelligence Scale for Children.</subject><title>Some characteristics of two learning disabled subgroups identified from WISCWISC-R factor score patterns</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53ww43g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816n172</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wd37c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:15:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The European refugee problem between 1933 and 1947 posed serious difficulties for the nations of asylum. Despite the trend towards immigration restriction, France and the United States remained the foremost countries of refuge and resettlement during the interwar years. The overwhelming numbers of refugees, however, tested their tradition of asylum, and both nations failed that tradition from the humanitarian point of view. During the 1930's, the French harried the Americans for refusing to aid and resettle the refugees from France, complicating the diplomatic relations between the two countries. Disagreements over the proper handling of refugee affairs continued throughout the war years. After the war, the Americans and the French concluded that their disagreements postponed a successful solution to the refugee problem, and by 1947 they had embarked on a more cooperative refugee relationship through the auspices of the United Nations.</description><creator>Maga, Timothy P., 1952-</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Asylum, Right of.</subject><subject>United States -- Emigration and immigration.</subject><subject>France -- Emigration and immigration.</subject><subject>Emigration and immigration law -- France.</subject><subject>Emigration and immigration law -- United States.</subject><title>The United States, France, and the refugee problem, 1933-1947 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sk18m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wd37c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v8381219</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:15:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Labour stability and strong community organization can be achieved in Northern towns only by fostering among recent arrivals a commitment to permanent settlement in town. Migrational processes associated with the development of commitment are therefore central to the industrialization and urbanization of the North. Exploratory field research in a Northern Quebec mining town was carried out over a 3 1/2 year period, in which commitment was studied through an ethnoscientific study of migrants' social identities. Conceptualization emphasized two theoretical perspectives that have been employed in psychological anthropology, interactionist social psychology and ethnoscience (or cognition). Conceptual relationships between these fields have been noted by many authors, but unfortunately interconnections have not been exploited in most applications of either theoretical base. Research focused on one small sector of the area of overlap, concerned with what Wallerstein has called 'social definition'. The project centers around a concept of 'social identity' which denotes one social psychological factor that (along with others) influences social interaction in a given society. At the same time, 'conceptual systems' of social categories (which are, Stone informs us, social identities) are examined through 'ethnosociology'--the ethnoscientific study of social knowledge as a cultural phenomenon. Migrants and their commitment are scrutinized in migrants' self-definitions and in their social understandings that signal the possession of certain social identities associated with commitment to their new home. The development of commitment, then, is viewed as a change in social identity--a change that is accompanied by changes in 'perspective' bearing on the social make-up of one's social universe. Formal and conventional anthropological methods were employed in the collection and analysis of data. Formal ethnoscientific eliciting was carried out in interviews with a primary sample of six French-Canadian residents and two Cree Indian residents. Conventional interviewing and ethnography rounded out the final analysis and provided cross-checks by which the use of formal methods could be evaluated. Social terminologies were analyzed in order to discover foci and structuring principles central to informants' constructions of their social worlds. Qualitative analysis of self-attitudes, images of their town, migration experiences, and background factors provided insight into recurrent patterns in migration to this Northern town. A cross-tabulation of various factors permitted an exploration into the operation of migrational and assimilative processes associated with the development of commitment. Both factors connected with the migrant's background and factors related to his reception in town must be taken into account to make sense of observed patterns of migration. Native townsmen not permitted to assimilate fully into the new community are unlikely to develop commitment because to do so would place them in a position of 'marginality'. French-Canadians who do not feel called upon to assimilate to a new order also do not develop commitment to the town. Other observed patterns may be explained by reference to the same cognitive and social-psychological processes, though the importance of symbolic anchors for identity in such processes must also be recognized. Observations and findings add to our knowledge of Cree Indian culture, French Canada, and Northern towns and also to our understanding of migration and related phenomena.</description><creator>Stewart, Donald Alexander.</creator><date>1980</date><subject>Chibougamau (Quebec) -- Social conditions.</subject><subject>Social participation -- Québec (Province) -- Chibougamou.</subject><subject>Identity (Psychology)</subject><subject>Community development -- Québec (Province) -- Psychological aspects.</subject><title>Social identity and commitment : migration and settlement of new northern towns</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655h26g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v8381219</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb397893w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:15:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study has investigated the early establishment of Trichinella spiralis and Nematospiroides dubius in the gastrointestinal tracts of their hosts. By using different vehicles of infection, different pre-treatments of the infective stages, by changing intestinal motility and by implantation of the infective stages directly into the intestine, significant changes in the longitudinal distribution were obtained. Surgical procedures, including gastrectomy, duodenal by-pass, ligation of the pancreatic duct and ligation or relocation of the bile duct, performed on rats prior to infection, have elucidated the central roles of bile, chloride and enterokinase. In vitro studies have corroborated in vivo studies. New categories of movement were observed in T. spiralis and new activity patterns were found to be stimulated in N. dubius exposed to bile. These observations are discussed in the context of site selection by intestinal nematodes with emphasis on critical factors which activate infective larval stages during their passive transport down the intestinal tract.</description><creator>Sukhdeo, Michael Vinoba Krishna</creator><date>1980</date><subject>Biology, Zoology.</subject><title>Studies on site selection in some gastrointestinal nematodes of mammals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859g32q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397893w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dw186</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:15:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation explores the social and political thought of Francis Bacon. While Bacon's contribution to the philosophy of science is recognized, his work is seen as having been focused primarily on the reform of the human estate. Bacon's Great Instauration, his programme for the advancement of learning and the restoration of mankind to pre-lapsarian dominion over nature, is examined for the influence of four main Renaissance perspectives: humanism, Christianity, millenarianism and historical optimism. Bacon wedded Renaissance humanism to millenarian-eschatology to provide an alternative to the classically-oriented interpretation of universal history. Despite the frequent use of millenarian-eschatological metaphors, Bacon's proposed reforms were based on human endeavour, not on divine will. The New Atlantis, Bacon's utopian portrayal of ideal social order, expresses his vision of the advancement of learning and its relation to politics. There the principal problem he confronts is resolving the contradiction between the mutability of all things, human and natural, and the inexorable progress promised by the new learning. Bacon's solution in the New Atlantis is ultimately unsatisfactory for it is based on a radical separation of the active will from the public sphere, and is thus achieved only at the expense of politics.</description><creator>McKay, Allyson.</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Bacon, Francis, 1561-1626.</subject><subject>Bacon, Francis, 1561-1626. New Atlantis.</subject><title>Francis Bacon, the ideology of utopia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d486v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dw186</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2r36tz204</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:15:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Using a social historical framework applied to Gottingen, North Germany, from the sixteenth century to 1948, the dynamics of local government structure are researched. This is seen through time as a corporate organisation of domains of externally oriented activity variably integrated with a decision-making core as an involute structure. Through examination of recruitment practices, administrative allocation and decision-making it is shown how integrated processes of decision-making (means of choice) constitute a framework for political action, where individuals have differential access to and control over critical events and modes of communication within that framework. Deriving from this, political activity in local government is analysed in terms of a categorisation of means and dimensional properties of power in local government. A link is made to a theoretical enquiry of the nature of social classes and the state and their implications for community politics. This provides the basis for an examination of class relations in Gottingen.</description><creator>Lewis, G. J.</creator><date>1980</date><subject>Municipal government -- Germany -- Göttingen -- History.</subject><subject>Göttingen (Germany) -- Politics and government.</subject><subject>Social classes -- Germany -- GÜttingen.</subject><title>Local government in a North German town, 1513-1948 : a study in class and power</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xv61s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36tz204</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j3332855</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:15:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Hill, Robert Andrew</creator><date>1970</date><subject>Sellar, Robert, 1841-1919</subject><title>Robert Sellar and the Huntingdon Gleaner : the conscience of rural protestant Quebec, 1863-1919</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405s9956.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j3332855</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n870zr36p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Rayman, Mohamad Khalil.</creator><date>1970</date><subject>Marine microbiology</subject><subject>Bacterial cell walls</subject><subject>Cells</subject><title>Lysis of a marine pseudomonad.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591912c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zr36p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dj52w546f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Gill, Denis Ernest.</creator><date>1970</date><subject>Tunnel lining</subject><subject>Soil mechanics</subject><title>A mathematical model for lining design in linear visco-elastic ground.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418n908.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w546f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining Engineering and Applied Geophysics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tx31qj33m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Matsunaga, Kikuo.</creator><date>1969</date><subject>Religion, General.</subject><title>Powers in conflict : a new clue to the interpretation of the fourth gospel.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50gw82d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qj33m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Divinity</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526c991</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Maisondieu, Philippe Jacques Christian</creator><date>1968</date><subject>Membranes (Technology)</subject><subject>Ion exchange</subject><subject>Ion flow dynamics</subject><title>Transport mechanisms and structure of a heterogeneous ion-exchange membrane.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666515k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526c991</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9g54xj26f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Raphael, R. M. (Robert Morton)</creator><date>1969</date><subject>Rings (Algebra)</subject><title>Algebraic extensions of regular rings</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hj76w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xj26f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s4655h27r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Malcuzynski, M.-Pierrette</creator><contributor>Angenot, Marc (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1981</date><subject>Criticism.</subject><subject>Aquin, Hubert, 1929-1977 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Cabrera Infante, G. (Guillermo), 1929- -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Bakhtin, M. M. (Mikhail Mikhaĭlovich), 1895-1975.</subject><subject>Pynchon, Thomas -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>La fiction néobaroque aux Amériques, 1960-1970 : littérature carnavalisée et aliénation narrative chez Hubert Aquin, Guillermo Cabrera Infante et Thomas Pynchon</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n203z768.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655h27r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Languages, Literatures, and Cultures</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343s851</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:16:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Goldstein, Stan.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Social Sciences, Law</subject><title>Banking and communications in an electronic age : contemporary issues of law, policy, and regulation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021f901.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343s851</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):25550</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>