<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:13:21Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):31150" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj1393598</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Integrated inductors are one of the most basic elements used in the design of modern electronic systems. However, they generally suffer from poor quality and are inherently area intensive, thus limiting system performance and prove to be a bottleneck for compact system integration. Several research efforts have been devoted to the development of miniaturized, high quality inductors. One such method proposes the use of an Artificial Magnetic Conductor (AMC) surface to enhance the inductor performance by creating a second inductive region thereby enabling inductor reuse. It can theoretically be shown, through image theory, that an AMC reflector can be used to effectively double the inductance of an inductor component. Accordingly, in order to validate this concept, two AMC surface designs are investigated for both on-chip and PCB-based implementations. The designed AMC surfaces are then integrated with standard loop inductor components in order to justify their performance benefits through measurement results of the fabricated prototypes. Finally, the practicality of this approach is demonstrated through the application of mm-wave VCOs by replacing a standard LC-VCO tank inductor with a miniaturized AMC-backed inductor. In order to do so, mm-wave LC-VCO prototypes are designed, fabricated and characterized through measurements.</description><description>Les inducteurs intégrés sont parmi les éléments élémentaires les plus utilisés dans la conception de systèmes électroniques modernes. Cependant, ils souffrent généralement d’une faible qualité et d’une large consomption d’espace, limitant ainsi les performances du système et compliquent donc l’intégration de systèmes compactes. Plusieurs efforts en recherche ont été consacrés au développement d’inducteurs de haute qualité miniatures. Une de ces méthodes proposent l’utilisation d’un Conducteur Magnétique Artificiel (CMA) comme surface pour améliorer la performance de l’inducteur en créant une deuxième région inductive ainsi permettant la réutilisation de l’inducteur. Il peut être démontré théoriquement, par la théorie des images, qu’un réflecteur CMA peut être utilisé pour doubler l’inductance total d’un inducteur. Par conséquent, afin de valider ce concept, deux designs de surfaces CMA sont investigués pour l’intégration sur puce (on-chip) et sur carte (PCB). Les surfaces CMA sont ensuite intégrées avec des composantes d’inducteurs en boucle standards afin de justifier leurs avantages en termes de performances par les résultats expérimentaux obtenus par ces prototypes. Finalement, le caractère pratique de cette approche est démontré par l’application d’un Oscillateur (VCO) d’ondes-mm en remplaçant le réservoir-LC par une version miniaturisée d’un inducteur par CMA. Pour ce faire, les prototypes d’Oscillateur-LC à ondes-mm sont conçus, fabriqués et caractérisé de façon expérimentale.</description><creator>Kostka, Darryl</creator><contributor>Ramesh Abhari (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Mourad N El-Gamal (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Enhancement of printed inductors using artificial magnetic conductor (AMC) surfaces for millimeter-wave applications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655j17q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj1393598</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30pv17d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>After over 50 years of development, aircraft financing has made significant achievements in expanding the domestic and global air transport system. An aircraft financing transaction is a complicated process which may involve not only the final users of the aircraft but also the manufacturers, banks or other private investors, trustees, lessors, and institutional lenders, concerning many areas of various subjects. This paper focuses on legal aspects of aircraft financing, especially on China’s current legal system of aircraft financing.  Chapter One examines the history of aircraft financing in the United States, Japan and China. Chapter Two discusses different types of financing, and analyzes the classification of Leasing, the most frequently used type of aircraft financing. Chapter Three outlines main international conventions which have built the legal framework of international aircraft financing. Chapter Four turns to China’s current legal framework of aircraft financing. Chapter Five studies new challenges posed to China’s leasing industry in recent years. A few short paragraphs concludes the large gap between China’s domestic aircraft financing industry and the foreign ones, and the efforts that China is making to explore a new way of aircraft financing to harmonise Chinese ideals with international practices.</description><description>Après plus de 50 ans de développement, le financement aéronautique a fait des pas importants dans l’expansion du transport aérien, chez nous et sur la scène internationale. Le financement d’un avion est un processus compliqué qui concerne non seulement les utilisateurs d’avions, mais aussi les fabricants, les banques ou autres investisseurs privés, les fiduciaires, les locateurs, les prêteurs institutionnels, en ce qui a trait a plusieurs aspects d’une variété de sujets. Le présent document se concentre sur les aspects juridiques du financement d'aéronefs, en particulier sur le courant système juridique de financement aéronautique de la Chine. Le premier chapitre examine l'histoire du financement aéronautique aux États-Unis, au Japon et en Chine. Le deuxième chapitre traite de différents types de financement, et analyse le crédit-bail, le type de financement aéronautique le plus souvent utilise. Chapitre trois décrit les principales conventions internationales qui ont servi à construire le cadre juridique international de financement aéronautique. Chapitre quatre se tourne vers le courant cadre juridique de financement aéronautique de la Chine. Chapitre cinq étudie les nouveaux défis auxquels l'industrie de location a fait face en Chine au cours des dernières années. Quelques courts paragraphes démontrent un écart important entre l’industrie du financement aéronautique en Chine et celle d’autres pays, et démontrent aussi les efforts que la Chine fait pour explorer un nouveau mode de financement aéronautique pour harmoniser les aspirations des chinois avec les pratiques internationales.</description><creator>Chen, Qian</creator><contributor>Donald H Bunker (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Paul Stephen Dempsey (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>Legal aspects of aircraft financing and new challenges for China</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676x30r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pv17d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k643b262z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les solutions analytiques basées sur des lignes de transmission ont simplifié l'ingénierie de circuits micro-ondes complexes, tel que les EBG. La présente thèse étudie les structures coplanaires EBG à partir d'éléments discrets et de modèles de lignes de transmission, auxquels sont ensuite appliquées des formules analytiques. Grâce à cette approche, un logiciel a été développé permettant de prédire les caractéristiques de dispersion de ces structures périodiques en quelques secondes seulement. Les structures coplanaires EBG contenant des sections courbes sont étudiées et un modèle de circuit équivalent à la portion courbe est proposé. L'analyse des structures EBG commence par une simple géométrie 1D, puis est étendue à des géométries 2D plus complexes. Le résultat des simulations analytiques est évalué par rapport au résultat des simulations analogues. Lorsque les sections courbes sont incluses, le début de la bande interdite est porté en deçà de 1GHz, rendant la structure plus intéressante pour le filtrage basse fréquence omni- directionnel.</description><description>The transmission line based analytical solutions have simplified engineering of complex microwave circuits like electromagnetic bandgap structures (EBGs). In this thesis, planar EBG structures are studied by derivation of lumped element and transmission line equivalent circuits followed by utilizing analytical formulations. Based on this approach, a code is developed that predicts the dispersion characteristics of these periodic structures in a matter of few seconds. Planar EBG structures containing meander sections are investigated and a method for development of an equivalent circuit for the meander line portion is presented. The analysis of the studied EBG structures begins from a simple 1D geometry and is extended to more complex 2D geometries. The analytical simulation results are evaluated against full-wave simulations. Inclusion of the meander sections reduces the beginning of the bandgap to below 1GHz resulting in a more attractive structure for low frequency omni-directional filtering.</description><creator>Venkateswaran, Ajay</creator><contributor>Ramesh Abhari (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Analysis of planar EBG structures using transmission line models</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j0401.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b262z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd375x97j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A complete understanding of the the ν = 5/2 fractional quantum hall effect (FQHE) continues to be among the most exciting problems in semiconductor physics. It is widely believed that this unique electron state is described by the Moore-Read Pfaffian wavefunction, resulting from a BCS-like pairing of composite fermions. In recent years this wavefunction has received special interest owing to its non-abelian quantum statistics which underlies a new paradigm for fault tolerant quantum computation. However, in spite of several theoretical advancements, an unequivocal experimental verification of the Moore-Read description is still missing.  We studied the 5/2 state in a very high quality 2DEG sample with the lowest electron density reported to date, by nearly a factor of two. We demonstrate that large discrepancies between experimentally measured values of the 5/2 energy gap, and theoretical calculations based on the Moore-Read theory, can not be trivially attributed to disorder as has conventionally been assumed. Using a tilted field geometry, we investigated the effect of applying an in-plane magnetic field on the 5/2 state. We observe the 5/2 energy gap to collapse linearly with the in-plane field, whereas the neighbouring 7/3 shows a strong enhancement. The opposite behaviour between the two states is in startling contrast to theory which predicts both gaps should be similarly suppressed. Since the early theoretical foundation in support of the Moore-Read interpretation presumed the two states should behave the same, our experimental finding of opposite behaviour may necessitate a fundamental rethinking of the nature of the 5/2 FQHE.  A crucial step towards verifying the Moore-Read description of the ν = 5/2 FQHE will be an unambiguous measurement of its spin state. In an effort to measure the 5/2 spin directly, we implemented a resistively detected nuclear magnetic resonance (RDNMR) technique. I report on our detailed study of the anomalous RDNMR lineshape ar</description><description>Une compr\'ehension compl\`ete de l'effet Hallquantique fractionnaire (EHQF) \`a $\nu = \frac{5}{2}$ continue \`afaire partie des probl\`emes les plus passionnants de la physiquedes semi-conducteurs. On estime g\'en\'eralement que cet \'etat\'electronique unique est d\'ecrit par la fonction d'onde deMoore-Read connue sous le nom de ``Pfaffien'', r\'esultant d'unappariement de type BCS de fermions composites. Cette fonctiond'onde a r\'ecemment suscit\'e un int\'er\^et tout particulier enraison de ses statistiques quantiques non-ab\'eliennes quisous tendent un nouveau paradigme pour le calcul quantique insensibleaux d\'efaillances. En d\'epit de plusieurs avanc\'ees th\'eoriques,il manque toutefois une v\'erification exp\'erimentaled\'efinitive de la description Moore-Read.Nous avons \'etudi\'e l'\'etat $\frac{5}{2}$ dans un gaz\'electronique bidimensionnel de tr\`es haute mobilit\'e ayant laplus faible densit\'e d'\'electrons report\'ee \`a ce jour, cecide par un facteur proche de deux. Nous d\'emontrons que lesimportants \'ecarts entre les valeurs du gap d'\'energie \`a$\frac{5}{2}$ mesur\'ees exp\'erimentalement et les calculsth\'eoriques bas\'es sur la th\'eorie Moore-Read ne peuvent pas\^etre uniquement attribu\'es au d\'esordre, comme cela atraditionnellement \'et\'e propos\'e. En utilisant un champ \`ag\'eom\'etrie inclin\'ee, nous avons \'etudi\'e l'effet del'application d'un champ magn\'etique dans le plan sur l'\'etat$\frac{5}{2}$. Nous observons une d\'ecroissance lin\'eaire du gapd'\'energie \`a $\frac{5}{2}$ en fonction du champ magn\'etiquedans le plan, tandis que le gap d'\'energie d'\'etat fractionnairevoisin $\frac{7}{3}$ exhibe une forte augmentation. Lecomportement oppos\'e des deux \'etats est en contraste avec lath\'eorie qui pr\'evoit que les deux gaps doivent \^etresupprim\'es par l'application d'un champ magn\'etique dans le plan, ce quin\'ecessite un nouvel examen de la nature de l'EHQF$\frac{5}{2}$.Une \'etape cruciale vers la v\'erificati</description><creator>Dean, Cory</creator><contributor>Guillaume Gervais (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Physics - Solid State</subject><title>A study of the fractional quantum hall energy gap at half filling</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440v10m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375x97j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w95052077</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>DNA replication initiates at replication origins and involves the ordered assembly of a pre-Replicative Complex (pre-RC), consisting of the ORC1-6, Cdc6, Cdt1 and MCM2-7 proteins. The Ku heterodimer (Ku70/Ku80) was previously implicated in the pre-RC assembly but its mechanism of action is yet unknown. Here, Ku is shown to form a complex with DNA topoisomerase IIβ (topo IIβ) both in vitro and in vivo and target it onto replication origins. The enzymatic activity of topo IIβ creates transient, origin-specific dsDNA breaks thus affecting the DNA topology during pre-RC assembly. Pharmacological inhibition of the topo II activity interferes with the pre-RC assembly at the level of ORC, Cdt1 and Cdc45 recruitment resulting in prolonged G1 phase. Similarly, RNAi-mediated inhibition of the Ku80 expression leads to reduced chromatin loading of pre-RC proteins, decreased origin activation, and activation of a cell cycle checkpoint through a mechanism involving low Cdk2 activity. Overall, the data implicate Ku in the initiation of DNA replication through regulation of the DNA topology and suggest the interplay of the DNA replication and cell-cycle machineries.  Pre-RC assembly is followed by the recruitment of the replicative machinery which initiates DNA replication. Study of the chromatin structure of the human lamin B2 and hOrs8 and the monkey Ors8 origin revealed that dynamic changes within the levels of post-translationaly modified histone H3 occur during their activation, which differ between early- and late-firing origins. Late origins have a compact chromatin structure during S phase, which transiently opens during their activation, whereas early origins display histone modifications associated with open chromatin structure, which is only passively affected during their activation by passage of the replication fork.</description><description>La réplication de l’ADN commence aux origines de réplication et nécessite l’assemblage méthodique du complexe pré-réplicatif (pre-RC), qui consiste des protéines ORC1-6, Cdc6, Cdt1 et MCM2-7. L’hétérodimer Ku (Ku70/Ku80) a été précédemment impliqué dans l’assemblage du pre-RC, mais le mécanisme de cette action est inconnu jusqu’à présent. Ici, Ku est montré former un complexe avec la topoisomérase IIβ (topo IIβ), tant in vitro qu’in vivo et le conduire aux origines de la réplication. L’activité enzymatique de topo IIβ crèe de brisures transitoires et specifiques aux origines, lesquelles affectent la topologie de l’ADN pendant l’assemblage du pre-RC. L’inhibition pharmacologique de l’activité de topo IIβ tripote avec l’assemblage du pre-RC au niveau du récrutement des protéines ORC, Cdt1 et Cdc45, ayant comme résultat la prolongation de la phase G1. De même, une inhibition de l’expéssion de Ku80 mène à un chargement réduit des proteins du pre-RC sur la chromatine, à une activation réduite des origines de réplication, ainsi qu’ à l’activation d’un contrôle du cycle céllulaire par un mécanisme qui implique une activité réduite de Cdk2. En général, les donnés impliquent Ku dans l’initiation de la réplication de l’ADN par la régulation de la topologie de l’ADN et suggèrent une réciprocité entre les machinéries de la réplication de l’ADN et du cycle cellulaire.  L’assemblage du pre-RC est suivi du récrutement de la machinérie réplicative, qui initie la réplication de l’ADN. Une étude de la structure de la chromatine des origines de la réplication humaines lamin B2 et hOrs8, ainsi que celle du singe Ors8, a montré des changements dynamiques aux niveaux des histones H3 modifiés qui ont lieu pendant leur activation et lesquelles diffèrent entre les origines qui sont actives tôt et tard dans la phase S. Les dernières possèdent une structure de chromatine qui est co</description><creator>Rampakakis, Emmanouil</creator><contributor>Maria Hadjopoulos (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Regulation of the initiation of DNA replication: Interplay between DNA topology and chromatin structure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r0067.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w95052077</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9c67wp407</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La Leucémie Myéloïde Aigue (LMA) est associée à une survie après cinq ans qui varie entre 20 et 30% en dépit de l’administration des régimes de chimiothérapie les plus intensifs, d’où la nécessité de développer de nouvelles stratégies thérapeutiques. Une importante variation de sensibilité cellulaire à l’AVE9633, un immunoconjugué anti-CD33 très prometteur, a été observée entre les patients. Le but de ce projet est d’identifier les mécanismes responsables de la résistance des cellules de LMA à l’AVE9633. En employant la lignée LMA sensible à AVE9633, HL60, et sa variante résistante, HL60/s, nous avons découvert que les deux lignées internalisent autant d’immunotoxine. Le découplage de l’anticorps du récepteur est significativement moindre dans la lignée résistante HL60/s. La dégradation de CD33 est réduite chez HL60/s alors que la protéine « Suppressor Of Cytokine Signalling 3 », SOCS3, jouant un rôle dans la dégradation de CD33, est uniquement exprimée dans la lignée cellulaire sensible. En conclusion, nous avons démontré que le découplage anticorps-récepteur et la dégradation de CD33 sont associés à la résistance de la lignée HL60/s à l’AVE9633. L’identification de ces mécanismes de résistance devrait pouvoir nous offrir des moyens d’identifier les patients les plus susceptibles de bénéficier d’un traitement par AVE9633 et de découvrir de nouvelles façons de traiter les patients ne répondant point aux traitements actuels du cancer.</description><description>Acute myelogenous leukemia (AML) five year survival ranges between 20-30% despite the administration of the most intensive chemotherapy regimen, hence the need to develop new therapeutic strategies. Substantial inter-patient variation in sensitivity to AVE9633, a very promising anti-CD33 immunoconjugate, was observed. The goal of this project is to identify the mechanisms underlying resistance of AML cells to AVE9633. Using the AVE9633 sensitive AML cell line, HL60, and its resistant variant HL60/s, we found that both internalize the immunotoxin to a similar extent. The uncoupling of the antibody from the CD33 receptor is significantly lower in HL60/s. CD33 degradation was seen to be reduced in the resistant cell line while Suppressor Of Cytokine Signalling 3, SOCS3, playing a role in CD33 degradation, is only expressed in the sensitive cell line. In conclusion, antibody-receptor uncoupling and CD33 degradation defects were shown to be associated with resistance to AVE9633 in the HL60/s cell line. The identification of these mechanisms of resistance could provide means to screen-out patients most likely to benefit from treatment with AVE9633 and identify new approaches to treat patients refractory to current cancer treatments.</description><creator>Caudrelier, Marie</creator><contributor>Denis Roy (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Luis Fernando Congote (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health Sciences - Immunology</subject><title>Mechanisms underlying the variability in response of Acute Myelogenous Leukemia cells to the immunotoxin AVE9633</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21th050.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wp407</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945s44x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L’anhydride arsénieux (As2O3) est un traitement efficace contre la leucémie aigue myéloide (LAM). La sensibilité envers l’As2O3 peut être attribué à l’induction de stress oxidative. Cependant, l’usage d’ As2O3 dans le cadre d’autres malignités est limité par la posologie clinique. Pour élargir le potential thérapeutique de l’arsenic, un nouveau composé arsenical, le darinaparsin (ZIO-101), est plus efficace in vitro que l’ As2O3 dans une variété de cellules hématopoïétiques malines. Dans des conditions d’équimolarité, le darinaparsin est beaucoup plus puissant que l’ As2O3 pour provoquer des voies métaboliques requises pour l’apoptose. De plus, contrairemet à l’ As2O3, le darinaparsin insite séléctivement l’antioxidant Nrf2. Ce dernier produit un stress oxidative incontesté qui permet l’apoptose dans le cadre de la LAM. Curieusement, le darinaparsin ne répond pas à l’inhibition de l‘ABCC1 (Mrp 1), un transporteur qui confère de la résistance contre l’arsenic. Ceci suggère que le darinaparsin peut être un traitement efficace contre des tumeurs qui possèdent une importante quantitée d’ABCC1.</description><description>Arsenic trioxide (As2O3) is an effective treatment strategy for acute promyelocytic leukemia (APL), as sensitivity to As2O3 may correlate with the induction of oxidative stress. However, the use of As2O3 in other malignancies is limited at clinically achievable doses. To expand the clinical potential of arsenic to other malignancies, a promising novel arsenical, darinaparsin (S-dimethylarsino-glutathione, ZIO-101) is more potent in vitro than As2O3 in a variety of hematopoietic malignant cell lines. At equimolar concentrations, darinaparsin is significantly more potent than As2O3 in inducing signalling pathways known to be required for arsenic-induced apoptosis. Moreover, unlike As2O3, darinaparsin is a selective inducer of Nrf2 antioxidant responses, thereby generating unopposed oxidative stress response and apoptosis in APL. Interestingly, darinaparsin does not demonstrate sensitivity to inhibition of ABCC1 (Mrp1), a known transporter involved in resistance to arsenic, suggesting that darinaparsin may be an effective treatment in tumours that overexpress ABCC1.</description><creator>Kourelis, Maria</creator><contributor>Wilson H Miller (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery</subject><title>Characterization of the novel arsenical darinaparsin (ZIO- 101, S-dimethylarsino-glutathione) as a more potent inducer of oxidative stress and apoptosis than arsenic trioxide in acute promyelocytic leukemia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848s13p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945s44x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4f16c430d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dans cette dissertation, les techniques de la physique à plusieurs corps sont utilisées afin d'étudier et d'améliorer certaines idées reliées à la description des collisions d'ions lourds à haute énergie. La première partie de cette thèse s'intéresse à la production des mésons tenseurs dans les collisions proton-proton (pp). Une théorie effective où le méson f2 couple avec le tenseur énergie-impulsion est proposée et une étude comparative de la section efficace calculée dans les formalismes de la factorisation colinéaire,  de la factorisation-kT et du color glass condensate (CGC) est entreprise. La phénoménologie dans les collisions pp montre que la section efficace est très sensible à la paramétrisation des fonctions de distribution non-intégrées. En conséquence, la production de mésons f2 peut être utilisée pour améliorer notre compréhension de la fonction d'onde du proton. Dans la seconde partie, une investigation similaire est entreprise où la section efficace de production de mésons eta' est analysée dans les collisions pp et proton-noyau (pA). Le noyau et le proton sont décrits par le CGC et la factorisation-kT respectivement. Une nouvelle technique pour le calcul des correlateurs de lignes de Wilson - densités de charge de couleur dans le modèle de McLerran-Venugopalan est développée. La phénoménologie nous démontre ensuite que la section efficace dans les collisions pA est très sensible à la valeur de l'échelle de saturation, qui est un des éléments crucial dans l'approche du CGC. Dans la troisième partie de cette thèse, le terme de collision de l'équation de Boltzmann est dérivé à partir de principes premiers en utilisant l'expansion en collisions multiples. Finalement, l'émission de photons à partir d'un champs non-abélien classique fort est étudiée. Un formalisme basé sur les propagateurs de Schwinger-Keldysh et qui relie le taux de production des photons à la solution retardée de l'équa</description><description>In this dissertation, many-body physics techniques are used to study and improve ideas related to the description of heavy ion collisions at very high energy. The first part of the thesis concerns the production of tensor mesons in proton-proton (pp) collisions.  An effective theory where the f2 meson couples to the energy-momentum tensor is proposed and a comparison of the inclusive cross-section computed in the collinear factorization, the kT-factorization and the color glass condensate is performed. A study of the phenomenology in pp collisions then shows a strong dependence on the parametrization of the unintegrated distribution function. The conclusion is that f2 meson production can be utilized to improve the understanding of the proton wave-function. In the second part, a similar investigation is performed by analysing the production cross-section of the eta' meson in pp and proton-nucleus (pA) collisions. The nucleus and proton are described by the CGC and the kT-factorization respectively. A new technique for the computation of Wilson lines - color charge densities correlators in the McLerran-Venugopalan model is developped. The phenomenology shows that the cross-section in pA collisions is very sensitive to the value of the saturation scale, a crucial ingredient of the CGC picture. In the third part of the thesis, the collision term of the Boltzmann equation is derived from first principles at all orders and for any number of participating particles, starting from the full out-of-equilibrium quantum field theory and using the multiple scattering expansion. Finally, the emission of photons from a non-abelian strong classical field is investigated. A formalism based on Schwinger-Keldysh propagators relating the production rate of photons to the retarded solution of the Dirac equation in a background field is presented.</description><creator>Fillion-Gourdeau, François</creator><contributor>Sang Yong Jeon (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Physics - Nuclear</subject><title>Applications of many-body physics to relativistic heavy ion collisions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sv328.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c430d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2b88qd739</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La jonction neuromusculaire est un model fréquemment employé pour étudier la formation ainsi que le fonctionnement des synapses du système nerveux central. De plus, de nombreuses études sur la jonction neuromusculaire ont fourni de précieux renseignements par rapport aux mécanismes qui gouvernent les changements structurels des synapses menant à leur renforcement suite à l’activité. L’apposition précise entre la spécialisation postsynaptique et les ramifications des terminaux nerveux est une caractéristique essentielle pour le bon fonctionnement des synapses. Récemment, des chercheurs ont démontré que la protéine laminine, qui est une importante composante de la membrane basale, agit comme un signal servant à démarrer la formation des agrégats de récepteurs d’acétylcholine à la surface des cellules musculaires en l’absence de facteurs nerveux. Nous ne savons toujours pas comment la formation des agrégats de récepteurs d’acétylcholine est régulée. De plus, malgré le fait que nous savons que la dystroglycane est requise dans le processus d’assemblage des plaques de récepteurs d’acétylcholine a la surface des fibres musculaires, nous ne savons pas exactement quelle est la contribution des autres récepteurs de laminine à la surface des fibres musculaires dans le contexte de la formation des agrégats d’acétylcholine. Dans ma thèse, je décris un nouveau mécanisme à travers lequel l’activité cellulaire réprime la formation des agrégats complexes de récepteurs d’acétylcholine à la surface des cellules musculaires en la présence de la laminine. Un bloque de l’activité cellulaire via l’inhibition des canaux sodiques en utilisant la tétrodotoxine crée un état permissif sous lequel des agrégats complexes de récepteurs d’acétylcholine se forment à la surface des cellules musculaires en réponses [...]</description><description>The neuromuscular junction is widely used as a model to study the formation and function of synapses of the central nervous system. In addition, studies at the neuromuscular junction have provided insight on the molecular mechanisms that govern changes in synaptic structure and strength in response to activity. The precise apposition of the postsynaptic specialization with the complex branched nerve terminal is an essential functional characteristic of synapses. Recently, it was demonstrated that laminin, a key structural protein at the basement membrane, acts as a signaling molecule that can initiate the formation of acetylcholine receptor aggregates on muscle fibers in the absence of nerve-derived factors.  How the formation of acetylcholine receptor aggregates on the surface of myotubes in response to laminin is regulated is still unknown. Moreover, although dystroglycan is known to be required for the proper assembly of acetylcholine receptor densities on muscle fibers, the contribution of other laminin-receptors at the surface of muscle fibers in the formation of acetylcholine receptor (AChR) aggregates in response to laminin remains unknown. In my thesis, I describe a novel mechanism by which cellular activity represses the formation of complex acetylcholine receptor aggregates on the surface of myotubes in response to laminin. Blocking activity via inhibition of sodium channels with tetrodotoxin creates a permissive state under which complex AChR aggregates form on the surface of myotubes in response to laminin signaling. Furthermore, I show that this permissive state can also be achieved using verapamil to block voltage-gated calcium channels or KN62 to inhibit calcium/calmodulin dependent Kinase II (CaMKII) activation, indicating that calcium signaling via CaMKII downstream of activity represses aggregation of AChRs in response to laminin. [...]</description><creator>Vézina-Audette, Raphaël</creator><contributor>Salvatore T Carbonetto (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience</subject><title>Calcium Calmodulin Kinase II downstream of muscle activity regulates the aggregation of acetylcholine receptors in response to laminin</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x0562.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qd739</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988m63p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Est-ce que les électeurs informés prennent compte d'un plus grand nombre de facteurs quand vient le temps de voter? Est-ce que les variations quant aux choix des considérations prises en compte mènent à des choix électoraux différents? Est-ce que les institutions politiques et la complexité électorale ont une incidence sur les processus de décision des électeurs et le choix du vote? À l'aide de données recueillies en Australie, en Grande-Bretagne, au Canada, en Nouvelle-Zélande et aux États-Unis (21 enquêtes au total), cette recherche examine comment l'hétérogénéité dans le niveau d'information des électeurs influence le choix du vote ainsi que le processus qui y mène, le tout en tenant compte de la complexité de l'environnement de l'électeur.Nous testerons d'abord si l'hétérogénéité du niveau d'information des électeurs entraîne des différences dans le processus de décision du vote et si ces différences influencent de façon significative le choix du vote comme tel. Deuxièmement, nous verrons si l'effet du niveau d'information de l'électeur est fonction du contexte et si un environnement complexe entraîne de plus grandes différences entre électeurs.Les résultats tendent à démontrer que les variations dans le niveau d'information mènent à des différences dans le calcul du vote, et du choix du vote des électeurs. Par contre, contrairement à ce qui était attendu, le niveau de complexité de l'élection n'affecte pas davantage le choix du vote. C'est plutôt l'opposé qui est observé. En effet, c'est lors des situations les plus complexes que l'effet d'information est le moindre. Ce résultat est disséqué à l'aide d'une série de simulations où l'on compare le vote reporté des électeurs avec celui que l'on aurait observé si tous les électeurs avaient suivi le même processus décisionnel. Une différence significative est observée dans le choix du vote entre les électeurs très informés et peu informés da</description><description>Do more informed voters take account of a wider range of factors in formulating their vote choice? Do differences in the considerations employed in the vote calculus lead to different vote outcomes? Do political institutions and electoral complexity affect the relationship between information and the vote decision process and vote choice? Using survey data from the Australian, British, Canadian, New Zealand, and U.S. election studies (21 studies in total), this research tests how political information heterogeneity affects both the vote decision process and choice. In addition, this relationship is examined according to the complexity of the decision environment in which the decision is made.   The primary proposition tested contends that information heterogeneity produces differences in the vote calculus that in turn lead to systematic and significant variation in vote choice. Secondly, this work tests the assumption that the magnitude of information effects will be a function of context complexity, with increased complexity resulting in greater information- based differences.   The findings support the proposition that differences in political information lead to alternative decisions processes and vote outcomes. However, the difference in vote outcome across information cohorts does not increase with context complexity as expected.  In fact, the opposite relationship is found. Under the most complex conditions vote choice differences between the most and least informed is nearly eliminated. This counter-intuitive finding is dissected using a series of simulations that compare actual vote choice to the choice individuals would have made had they all pursued the same decision calculus. The results reveal a significant divergence between high and low information vote choices given alternative decision processes that hold important implications for election outcomes.</description><creator>Roy, Jason</creator><contributor>Elisabeth Gidengil (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Political Science - General</subject><title>How we vote: information heterogeneity, process and choice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859h16j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988m63p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5138jg42t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The hepatitis C virus (HCV) is a positive-strand RNA virus that belongs to the Flaviviridae family. HCV expresses the non-structural protein, NS5B, an RNA-dependent RNA polymerase required for genome replication. Here, we describe the allosteric properties of both the GTP-specific binding site (G-site) of the HCV polymerase and VIR-1327, a benzimidazole-derivative non-nucleoside inhibitor (NNI). Using biochemical assays, we identified certain G-site residues that affect NS5B activity, including serine-29, proline-495 and valine-499. We also demonstrated that VIR-1327 is a potent inhibitor with a resistance profile consisting of P495A and V499A mutants, but is non-competitive with regards to GTP. Moreover, biophysical results suggest that the mechanism of action of VIR-1327 is to prevent the formation of a stable enzyme-template complex. Further analysis of the G-site and NNIs will not only provide a better understanding of HCV replication, but also validate different allosteric sites as virus-specific targets for the development of anti-HCV therapeutics.</description><description>Le virus de l’hépatite C (VHC) est un virus d’ARN de polarité positive qui appartient à la famille Flaviviridae. Le VHC exprime la protéine non-structurelle NS5B, une ARN polymérase dépendante de l’ARN indispensable à la réplication du génome virale. Nous décrivons ici les propriétés allostériques du site GTP-spécifique (site-G) du VHC polymérase, ainsi que les propriétés allostériques de VIR-1327, un inhibiteur non-nucléoside (INN) qui est dérivé du benzimidazole. En utilisant des tests biochimiques, nous avons identifié certains résidus du site-G qui influencent l’activité du NS5B, incluant sérine-29, proline-495 et valine-499. Nous avons également démontré que VIR-1327 est un puissant inhibiteur avec un profil de résistance comprenant les mutants P495A et V499A, mais qu’il est non-compétitif avec le GTP. De plus, des résultats biophysiques suggèrent que le méchanisme d’action de VIR-1327 est de prévenir la formation d’un complexe enzyme-matrice stable. D’autres analyses du site-G et des INN vont non seulement fournir une meilleure compréhension de la réplication du VHC, mais aussi valider différents sites allostériques comme étant des cibles virus-spécifiques pour le développement de thérapeutiques contre le VHC.</description><creator>Vasquez, Colins</creator><contributor>Matthias Gotte (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health Sciences - General</subject><title>Allosteric effects of the GTP-specific binding site and a benzimidazole-derivative non-nucleoside inhibitor on the hepatitis C virus RNA-dependent RNA polymerase</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rm88z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5138jg42t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999824m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Much educational research has suggested that information and communication technologies (ICTs) promote constructivist classroom. In contrast, most teachers in actual classrooms continue to struggle with the pedagogical and practical challenges in using ICTs to facilitate student knowledge construction and collaboration. This dissertation presents a new approach to overcome problems with ICT integration in K-12 school education. The study examined a Grade 7 teacher’s constructivist instructional practices in a technology-rich mathematics classroom through a lens of cultural-historical activity theory (CHAT) and consisted of two phases: contradiction analysis and on-site intervention. Findings from the contradiction analysis indicated that it was not ICTs per-se that made contradictions in the ICT-supported constructivist activity; rather it was the changed nature of the class activity system due to the introduction of ICTs that called for systemic adjustment of classroom practices as a whole. Based on the identified contradictions, on-site intervention was designed and implemented. It focused on transforming an ill-formed activity system of the current instructional practices of the participant teacher into a well-formed one, where all the interwoven components and mediators, such as rules of interaction, division of labor, and the use of tools, adequately support activities that members carry out. Results indicated that the intervention and the modified unit played a large role in resolving the identified contradictions in the participant teacher’s instructional practices and restructuring his existing pure-discovery mode of instruction into new practices, a guided discovery mode of instruction. The intervened instructional practices helped students establish a more effective division of labor, which led to more successful learning outcomes than those prior to the intervention. A new role of researchers is suggested to lessen a gap between theory and practice</description><description>Une grande part de la recherche en éducation semble indiquer que les technologies de la communication et de l’information (TIC) encouragent l’essor de la salle de classe constructiviste. En revanche, la plupart des professeurs sur le terrain font toujours face à des défis pédagogiques et pratiques lorsqu’ils utilisent les TIC pour faciliter la collaboration et la construction du savoir des étudiants. Cette dissertation présente une nouvelle approche visant à surmonter les problèmes d’intégration des TIC dans l’éducation scolaire de la maternelle à la 12ème année. De la perspective de la théorie culturelle-historique de l'activité, cette étude examine les méthodes d’enseignement constructivistes d’un professeur de 7ème année dans une classe de mathématiques riche en technologies. L’étude comporte deux phases : l’analyse des contradictions et l’intervention sur le terrain. Les résultats de l’analyse des contradictions ont indiqué que ce n’était pas les TIC en tant que telles qui généraient des contradictions dans une activité constructiviste soutenu par les TIC. Plutôt, c’est le changement de nature du système d’activité en classe dû à l’introduction des TIC qui exige des changements systémiques dans les pratiques d’enseignement. L’intervention sur le terrain a été conçue et mise en application à partir des contradictions identifiées. Elle visait à transformer un système d’activité mal conçu issu des méthodes d’enseignement habituelles du professeur participant en un système bien conçu, où tous les constituants et les médiateurs entrecroisés, comme les règles d’interaction, la division des tâches et l’utilisation des outils, appuyaient adéquatement les activités des membres. Les résultats ont indiqué que l’intervention et l’unité modifiée ont joué un rôle important dans la résolution des contradictions identifiées dans les méthodes d’enseignement du professe</description><creator>Park, Jonghwi</creator><contributor>Robert J Bracewell (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Education - Teacher Training</subject><title>Designing a well-formed activity system for an ICT- supported constructivist learning environment: A CHAT perspective</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bg64m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999824m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386k94b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>My dissertation explores the eclectic singing careers of sisters Eva and Juliette Gauthier. Born in Ottawa, Eva and Juliettte were aided in their musical aspirations by the patronage of Prime Minister Wilfred Laurier and his wife Lady Zoë. They both received classical vocal training in Europe. Eva spent four years in Java. She studied the local music, which later became incorporated into her concert repertoire in North America. She went on to become a leading interpreter of modern art song. Juliette became a performer of Canadian folk music in Canada, the United States and Europe, aiming to reproduce folk music “realistically” in a concert setting.  My dissertation is the result of examining archival materials pertaining to their careers, combined with research into the various social and cultural worlds they traversed. Eva and Juliette’s careers are revealing of a period of transition in the arts and in social experience more generally. These transitions are related to the exploitation of non-Western people, uses of the “folk,” and the emergence of a cultural marketplace that was defined by a mixture of highbrow institutions and mass culture industries. My methodology draws from the sociology of art and cultural history, transposing Eva and Juliette Gauthier against the backdrop of the social, cultural and economic conditions that shaped their career trajectories and made them possible.</description><description>Ma thèse de doctorat explore les carrières éclectiques des chanteuses Eva et Juliette Gauthier. Nées à Ottawa, ces deux sœurs ont été supportées par le Premier Ministre Wilfred Laurier et sa femme Lady Zoë dans la poursuite de leurs aspirations musicales. Toutes deux ont suivi des cours de chant classiques en Europe, Eva passant quatre ans à Java où elle étudia la musique locale qu’elle a ensuite introduite dans son répertoire de concert en Amérique du Nord.  Elle devint ainsi une des interprètes principales de la chanson de l’école moderne. Pour sa part, Juliette est devenue chanteuse de musique folk canadienne, donnant des concerts tant au Canada et aux Etats-Unis qu’en Europe, dans le but d’en donner une représentation « réaliste » à l’intérieur même d’un concert.Ma thèse est le résultat de l’analyse des documents d’archive portant sur leurs carrières et de la recherche des divers milieux sociaux et culturels qu’elles ont traversés. Les carrières d’Eva et de Juliette sont révélatrices d’une période de transition dans le domaine des arts et, de façon générale, dans l’expérience sociale. Ces transitions sont reliées à l’exploitation des peuples non-occidentaux, à l’usage du « folk »  et à l’émergence d’un marché culturel défini par le mélange des institutions établies et des industries de la culture de masse. Ma méthodologie puise dans la sociologie de l’histoire de l’art et de la culture, mettant Eva et Juliette Gauthier en relief dans le contexte des conditions sociales, culturelles et économiques qui ont marqué et rendu possible la trajectoire de leurs carrières.</description><creator>Slominska, Anita Marie</creator><contributor>Straw, William O. (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Mass Communications</subject><title>Interpreting success and failure: the eclectic careers of Eva and Juliette Gauthier</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892c39s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386k94b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r715h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research involved numerous team based industrial campaigns to measure hydrodynamic conditions (superficial gas velocity (Jg), gas hold-up (g), bubble diameter (Db) and frother concentration) in industrial flotation cells. The primary focus of this thesis is the data collected at Agnico-Eagle Mines Ltd.’s LaRonde concentrator and Inmet Mining Corp’s Troilus concentrator. These campaigns helped identify key measurements and required steps toward controlling hydrodynamic characteristics for cells and banks of cells. This research sought to investigate the dependence of bank performance on the setting of profiles for both gas velocity and frother concentration. Some cell characterization and frother analysis work is described. The difficulty of manipulating frother addition rates on the plant scale identified laboratory opportunities to study the interaction of frothers to link hydrodynamic characteristics and froth quality. The laboratory experimental set up involved the use of a laboratory scale flotation column. This set up was used to investigate independent addition of a bubble size controlling frother (e.g., pentanol) with a froth quality controlling frother (e.g., Flottec F150) to test for independent control over the two functions.</description><description>Cette recherche a inclus plusieurs visites en équipe aux usines industrielles pour mesurer les conditions hydrodynamiques (vélocité de gaz superficiel (Jg), rétention de gaz (g), diamètre de bulles (Db) et concentration de moussant) dans les cellules de flottation industrielles. Cette thèse vise principalement les données enregistrer au concentrateur de la mine Agnico-Eagle Ltd. LaRonde et le concentrateur de la mine Troilus de Inmet Mining Corp. Ces campagnes ont aidé à identifier les mesures importantes et étapes requis pour contrôler les caractéristiques  hydrodynamiques dans les cellules et bancs de cellules. On a essayé d’investiguer la dépendance de la performance des bancs en fixant des profiles de vélocité de gaz superficiel et de concentration de moussant. Du travail en caractérisation de cellules et analyse de moussant sont décrits. La difficulté de manipuler l’addition de moussant au niveau de l’usine a mené à l’opportunité d’étudier l’interaction entre moussants pour trouver un lien entre les conditions hydrodynamiques et la qualité de l’écume. Le plan d’expériences a utilisé une colonne de flottation d’échelle laboratoire. On a examiné l’addition indépendante d’une moussant qui contrôle la taille de bulles (pentanol) avec une moussant qui a un effet sur l’écume (Flottec F-150) pour examiner le contrôle indépendant sur ces deux fonctions.</description><creator>Knuutila, Davin Andrew</creator><contributor>James A Finch (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Metallurgy</subject><title>Analysis of air and frother profiles in flotation banks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gp91z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r715h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xt293</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le règlement de paix entre le gouvernement ougandais et le LRA, prévoit que les chefs de ce dernier, accusés devant la CPI, seraient poursuivis devant des tribunaux nationaux et feraient face à des peines «alternatives ».  Les chefs du LRA requièrent que ces mandats soient retirés afin de signer une entente.  Bien que la proposition ougandaise ne puisse satisfaire au régime d’admissibilité prévu dans le Statut de Rome, cette thèse prétend que dans certaines circonstances, le Procureur de la CPI pourrait arrêter les procédures afin de permettre le déroulement de procédures nationales qui ne constituent pas de la justice formelle, et ce dans les « intérêts de la justice » prévus à l’Article 53.  Le Procureur devra développer une politique l’application de ce critère discrétionnaire, plus particulièrement dans l’adoption de lignes directrices.  Cette thèse argue qu’afin d’atteindre les objectifs de la CPI, de respecter sa nature complémentaire ainsi que pour reconnaître la nature unique de chaque situation d’atrocités, le Procureur devrait adopter une interprétation pluraliste des « intérêts de la justice ».</description><description>Uganda has reached a peace agreement with the leaders of the LRA, indicted by the ICC, in which they would be tried by national tribunals and serve “alternative sentences”.  The LRA demands the withdrawal of the ICC warrants as a pre-condition to any settlement.  While this peace proposal may not satisfy the admissibility regime of the Rome Statute, this thesis argues that in certain circumstances the ICC Prosecutor could defer to accountability mechanisms falling short of formal prosecution and punishment if it is in the “interests of justice” to do so pursuant to Article 53 of the Rome Statute.  The ICC OTP must however develop a policy on the application of this discretionary criterion which remains undefined, preferably in the form of prosecutorial guidelines.  A pluralist interpretation of the “interests of justice” is most consistent with the objectives of the Rome Statute, the complementary nature of the ICC and the unique context of each situation of mass atrocity.</description><creator>Antonopoulos, Constantina</creator><contributor>Rene Provost (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>The ICC, the "interests of justice" and national efforts at accountability falling short of formal justice: an exercise in prosecutorial discretion</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c210r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xt293</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:td96k420n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le co-transporteur d’ions K+ et Cl- (KCC2), spécifique aux neurones, est l’un des plus importants co-transporteurs de cations chlorure (CCC) du système nerveux central. Il contrôle l’homéostasie de la cellule en régulant l’extrusion d’ions chlorure. KCC2 est reconnu comme étant une protéine essentielle à la maturation de l’inhibition synaptique au cours du développement et au contrôle de l’excitabilité des neurones dans le système nerveux central de l’adulte. Bien que les mécanismes régulant l’expression de KCC2 soient connus, de nouvelles données suggèrent que l’activité de KCC2 peut aussi être modifiée sur de plus courtes périodes, de l’ordre de 10 à 20 minutes. Ceci suggère qu’un contrôle post-traductionnel, agissant beaucoup plus rapidement qu’un contrôle transcriptionnel, pourrait aussi être important dans la régulation de l’activité de KCC2. Toutefois, la nature de ces mécanismes post-traductionnels et la façon par laquelle ils contribuent à la fonction de KCC2 demeurent inconnus.Dans cette thèse, je vise à caractériser les mécanismes moléculaires qui gouvernent la régulation post-traductionnelle de KCC2, incluant son expression à la surface cellulaire, son endocytose et son assemblage quaternaire. Plus spécifiquement, mes résultats suggèrent que: 1) Le KCC2 endogène interagit avec la machinerie d’endocytose par clathrines (CME) ; 2) Le KCC2 est endocyté constitutivement par un mécanisme dépendant des clathrines; 3) Le motif di-leucine 657LL658 est essentiel non seulement à l’endocytose constitutive de KCC2, mais aussi à l’interaction entre KCC2 et le complexe protéique adaptateur AP-2; 4) Deux régions à l’intérieur de KCC2, l’une proximale et l’autre centrale à l’extrémité C-terminale, sont responsables de la dimérisation de KCC2 qui peut être abrogée par la substitution des leucine 657 et 658 par des alanines; 5) La séquence 657LL658 est très conservée par</description><description>The neuron-specific K+/Cl- cotransporter 2 (KCC2) is one of the major cation Cl- cotransporter (CCC) proteins in the central nervous system that controls Cl- homeostasis via mediating Cl- extrusion. KCC2 has been established as an essential protein in promoting the maturation of synaptic inhibition during development and controlling neuronal excitibility in the adult central nervous system (CNS). Although various mechanisms are known to regulate KCC2 gene expression, accumulating evidence has shown KCC2 activity can be altered on much shorter time scales in a manner of 10-20 minutes. This suggested post-translational mechanisms, which take place much more rapidly than gene expression, may also be an important means by which KCC2 function can be regulated. However, what these post-translational mechanisms are and how they contribute to the control of KCC2 function remain elusive.  In this thesis, I set out to characterize the molecular mechanisms governing the post-translational regulation of KCC2, including its endocytosis, quaternary assembly, and cell surface expression. Specifically, my results suggest: 1) Endogenous KCC2 interacts with the clathrin-mediated endocytosis (CME) machinery; 2) KCC2 is constitutively endocytosed via a CME-dependent mechanism; 3) A di-leucine motif, 657LL658, is essential for both KCC2 constitutive endocytosis and the binding of KCC2 to the CME adaptor protein AP-2 complex; 4) Two regions within KCC2 proximal and central carboxyl terminus respectively mediate KCC2 dimerization, and in particular mutating the 657LL658 residues to alanines completely abolishes KCC2 dimerization; 5) The 657LL658 sequence is highly conserved amongst closely related K+/Cl- cotransporter proteins, but absent from the more distant Na+/Cl- cotransporters controlling Cl- uptake, suggesting an evolutionarily conserved mechanism may regulate the constitutive endocytosis and dimerization of functionally homologous KCC members; and 6) KCC2 expression at the neur</description><creator>Zhao, Beibei</creator><contributor>Fiona Kay Bedford (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Cell</subject><title>Identification of the cellular and molecular mechanisms governing the post-translational regulation of the neuron- specific potassium/chloride cotransporter KCC2</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh041.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k420n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s1690</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La rupture de plaques athérosclérotiques est la condition pathologique la plus fréquente impliquée dans le syndrome ischémique aigu pouvant mener à l’infarctus du myocarde et à  la mort du à l’arrêt cardiaque. La rupture du cap fibreux de la plaque coronarienne peut résulter dans la formation d’un thrombus qui peut éventuellement empêcher la perfusion sanguine en aval du lit myocardique. Une cause possible de la rupture de la plaque est l’établissement de contraintes mécanique induites par la déformation de la paroi artérielle sous l’écoulement sanguin et la pression intraluminale à l’intérieur des artères coronaires. Nous avons utilisé des méthodes de simulation par interaction fluide-structure pour analyser les effets de l’écoulement coronarien sur les plaques athérosclérotiques pour déterminer les contraintes mécaniques sur les constituants de la plaque. Nous avons analysé l’effet de l’épaisseur du cap fibreux, la rigidité de l’inclusion nécrotique et le pourcentage en surface de la sténose sur les contraintes mécaniques en utilisant des modèles similaires d’artères sténosées. Nous avons ensuite analysé l’effet de l’écoulement hémodynamique transitoire avec des géométries réalistes spécifiques à certains patients sous des conditions normales de flot sanguin et de pression sanguine. Les résultats transitoires ont été utilisés pour calculer l’amplitude et la valeur moyenne des contraintes pour les analyses de fatigue. En se basant sur cette approche, nous avons développé certaines hypothèses: la fatigue mécanique du cap fibreux (FMCF) est la caractéristique ultime qui initie la rupture; la FMCF peut être le résultat des effets combinés de l’épaisseur du cap, des valeurs relatives des rigidités des inclusions et le pourcentage de sténose; la FMCF peut être influencée par la structure globale de la pathologie obstructive en particulier dans le contexte de sténoses multiple</description><description>Atherosclerotic plaque rupture is the common pathological condition of the acute ischemic syndromes of sudden cardiac death and acute myocardial infarction. The rupture of the fibrous cap of a coronary plaque may result in a thrombus formation that would prevent the perfusion of blood downstream of the myocardium. A probable cause of plaque rupture is the mechanical stress induced by the artery wall stretching from the physiological flow of blood and the intraluminal pressure within the coronary arteries. We used computational fluid-structure interaction methods to analyze the effects of coronary blood flow on stenotic atherosclerotic plaques to determine the mechanical stresses within the plaque’s components. We analyzed the effect of the fibrous cap thickness, necrotic core stiffness, and percentage of area stenosis on the mechanical stresses within using comparable models of stenosed arteries. We then analyzed the effect of transient hemodynamic flow using realistic patient-specific geometries under normal coronary flow and pressure. The transient results were used to calculate the amplitude and mean stress for fatigue analyses. Based on this approach, we developed several hypotheses: mechanical fatigue in the fibrous cap is the ultimate characteristic that triggers the rupture; fibrous cap mechanical fatigue (FCMF) can be the result of the combined effects of the cap thickness, relative inclusion stiffness and percentage of stenosis; FCMF can be influenced by the global structure of the obstructive pathology in particular in the context of multiple stenoses, we also show that the anisotropic properties of the collagen fibers within the cap can influence the rupture mechanism.  Our results indicate that the combination of a thin fibrous cap, a soft lipid core and a large percentage of stenosis contribute to high mechanical stress magnitudes. Such stresses in mild stenoses can have similar critical behaviors to those normally associated with higher percentage</description><creator>Galaz Mendez, Ramsés</creator><contributor>Jean Claude Tardif (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Rosaire Mongrain (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health Sciences - General</subject><title>A computational study to assess the effect of the coronary hemodynamics on the mechanical stresses of stenotic atherosclerotic plaques</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nc72x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s1690</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qb98mh21d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Migration law and policy are clearly committed to the state (and its citizens) at the expense of the migrant. Receiving societies regard the migrant as a threat to the order and unity of national identity but the migrant is, in fact, also constitutive of that order and unity. This reveals a paradoxical relationship of the migrant to law. Questions of identity and alterity occupy a pivotal place in investigations related to the treatment of the migrant subject. Identity is a construct which is indeterminate and relational. This construct of the migrant brings to the fore the dependence of the migration system on the image of the migrant as repressed and marginalized. Within the international legal system, definitional discourses regarding forced/voluntary migration also have serious identity and policy related implications. The exclusion of migrants who does not fit within the narrow “boxes” of international migration law occurs precisely because international law cannot develop its ideal self-image without a caste of international refusés. Like the nation-state, international migration law achieves parts of its legitimacy through exclusion. International migration law also provide an escape mechanism which the state can access in order to advance its political goals. Both domestically and internationally, migrants are subjected by the legal discourse on migration to a form of violence which suppresses their humanity. Migrants are commandeered to help constitute the identity of international law and national societies. This de-ethicalizes the relationship with the migrant by negating the migrant’s autonomous nature. It therefore becomes necessary to introduce the ethics of alterity in law and to move the migrant back into the centre of the migration discourse. A significant way to do this is to be aware of the violence which is perpetrated upon the migrant and to work towards the elaboration of a less state-centred system open to constant reconsideration.</description><description>Le droit et les politiques migratoires servent de manière délibérée l’intérêt de l’État (et de ses citoyens) au dépend de celui des migrants. Les sociétés d’accueil considèrent que le migrant est une menace à l’ordre et à l’unité de l’identité nationale mais le migrant est en en fait nécessaire pour la constitution d’une identité nationale ordonnée et unitaire. Ceci démontre la relation ambiguë entre le droit et le migrant. Les questions d’identité et d’altérité occupent une place centrale dans toute réflexion portant sur le traitement juridique du migrant. L’identité est un construit vague et relationnel et le système migratoire repose sur une image du migrant réprimé et marginalisé. Au sein du système juridique international, les discours portant sur la définition de la migration forcée/volontaire ont aussi des implications identitaires et politiques. En effet, l’exclusion du migrant qui ne correspond pas aux critères étroits du droit international des migrations est possible précisément parce que le droit international ne peut maintenir une image idéale sans une caste mondiale de refusés. Au même titre que l’État nation, le droit international des migrations construit donc, du moins partiellement, sa propre identité à travers des mécanismes d’exclusion. Le droit international des migrations constitue aussi une échappatoire utile pour faire avancer les visés politiques de l’État. Ainsi, à tous les niveaux, national et international, le migrant est assujetti à une forme de violence qui nie son humanité. Puisque le migrant existe aux yeux de l’État uniquement pour renforcer l’identité de celui-ci et du droit international, la relation entre le droit et le migrant s’en trouve vidée de son contenu éthique, notamment en refusant d’accorder au migrant toute autonomie. Il s’avère alors nécessaire d’introduire l’éthique de l’altérité dans le droit et de ramener le migr</description><creator>Nakache, Delphine</creator><contributor>Rene Provost (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>The "Othering" process: exploring the instrumentalisation of law in migration policy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cj186.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mh21d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xs55md45n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La présente thèse examine la relation entre l’éternité et le temps telle que développée dans la théologie de Karl Barth (1886-1968), en particulier dans sa Dogmatique.  S’éloignant des interprétations traditionnelles, Karl Barth définit l’éternité en référence aux doctrines chrétiennes essentielles de la Trinité et de l’Incarnation.  L’éternité est ainsi définie non pas seulement par sa différence au temps, mais en tant que vie, ordre et mouvement du Père, du Fils et du Saint-Esprit.  Cette approche dynamique de l’éternité entraîne une relation créative et positive avec la temporalité créée.Afin de démontrer que cette relation positive se retrouve dans les œuvres de Barth, la présente thèse se concentre sur les volumes III et IV de la Dogmatique.  En examinant brièvement la doctrine de la Trinité trouvée en Dogmatique  I/1 et de la perfection de l’éternité en II/1, la thèse se penche particulièrement sur la manière dont Barth discute de la temporalité dans les volumes subséquents.  Ce qui s’y développe est une réinterprétation trinitarienne du temps : le Père crée et préserve le temps comme le théâtre des relations de l’Alliance; le Fils incarné récapitule en restaurant la fonction originelle du temps créé, que l’humanité déchue a égarée, et en redirigeant tout temps comme se dirigeant vers l’eschaton; l’Esprit Saint crée le temps de la communauté en tant que réalité correspondant à la réalisation du temps par le Fils.  Les vues de Barth contiennent implicitement une vision narrative du temps.  Non seulement le temps est créé en vue des relations de l’Alliance, le récit global de la création, réconciliation et rédemption de Dieu dirige les différentes discussions portant sur le temps.Afin de développer ces points, le chapitre premier examine les interprétations traditionnelles de l’éternité, décrit sommairement les doctrines de la Trinité et de l’éternité$</description><description>This thesis examines the relation of eternity and time in the theology of Karl Barth (1886-1968), specifically the Church Dogmatics. In contrast to traditional views, Karl Barth defines eternity with reference to the central Christian doctrines of the Trinity and incarnation. Eternity is understood, then, not merely in its difference from time but as the life, order, and movement of the Father, Son, and Spirit. This dynamic view of eternity ensures a creative and positive relation to created temporality.   To demonstrate this positive relation in Barth this thesis focuses on volumes III and IV of the Church Dogmatics. While briefly examining the doctrine of the Trinity in CD I/1 and the perfection of eternity in II/1, the bulk of the thesis examines how the discussion of temporality unfolds in later volumes. What develops is a trinitarian reinterpretation of time: the Father creates and preserves time as the theatre of covenantal relations; the incarnate Son recapitulates time by retrieving the original purpose of created time, which is lost to fallen humanity, and by redirecting all time on the way to the eschaton; while the Holy Spirit creates the time of the community as the correspondence to the fulfilling of time by the Son. Implicit in Barth’s view is a narrative view of time. Not only is time created for covenantal relations but also the overall narrative of God’s creating, reconciling, and redeeming work controls the varied discussions of time.   To explicate this, the first chapter examines traditional interpretations of eternity, briefly outlines Barth’s doctrines of the Trinity and eternity in CD I and II, and surveys the secondary literature. The second chapter outlines the argument of the dissertation by discussing time and analogy, and then by suggesting Barth’s position as an analogia trinitaria temporis. The next three chapters examine the times of the Father, Son, and Spirit respectively. The conclusion summarizes the dissertation by sugg</description><creator>Langdon, Adrian</creator><contributor>Douglas B Farrow (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Theology</subject><title>God the eternal contemporary: Trinity, eternity and time in Karl Barth's «Church Dogmatics»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rq357.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xs55md45n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s170r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The first example of a stable triple-stranded helix consisting of exclusively T$ cdot$AT (reverse-Hoogsteen$ cdot$Watson/Crick) base triplets is reported. This approach to induce and stabilize the anti-parallel triplex involves the use of a branched oligonucleotide with two parallel dT$ sb{10}$ strands joined to riboadenosine via $2 prime$-$5 prime$ and $3 prime$-$5 prime$ phosphodiester linkages, i.e., rA$ rm sp{ lbrack 2 prime-5 prime-dT10 rbrack} sb{ lbrack3 prime-5 prime-dT10 rbrack}$ (underbar2.1). Triple helix formation by branched oligonucleotide underbar2.1 and dA$ sb{10}$ was investigated by thermal denaturation analysis, circular dichroism spectroscopy, PAGE retardation assays and fluorescent studies. A linear oligonucleotide with a loop made of four dC residues between two dT$ sb{10}$ strands, and with a $5 prime$-$5 prime$-phosphodiester linkage at one of the C/T$ sb{10}$ junctions, i.e., $3 prime$-$ rm dT sb{10}C sb4$-$5 prime$-$5 prime$-$ rm dT sb{10}$-$3 prime$ did not form a similar triple helical structure. This result shows that the conformational rigidity imparted to the pyrimidine strands, by the branch point in underbar2.1 serves to pre-organize and stabilize the complex. A fibre optic sensor was designed and constructed for the fluorimetric detection of TAT triple-helical DNA hybridization. Fluorescent studies were then conducted and showed unequivocal hybridization of support bound oligomer with complementary oligonucleotides from the solution phase, as inferred by ethidium bromide staining. A thymidine nucleoside containing a flexible linker at the N$ sp3$ position served as a replacement for nucleotide loops in triplex forming DNA. Moreover, a new solid-phase methodology for constructing "Y" branched nucleic acids having a flexible linker was developed. This branched oligonucleotide contains two binding domains, one involving Watson-Crick base pairing, and the other involving triplex formation via Hoogsteen base pairing. The synthesis of a $2 prime,5 prime$-linked antisense oligoribonucleotide (RNA) containing the four natural bases (Ad, Gu, Cy, Ur) and that is complementary to HIV-1 genomic RNA is reported for the first time. This oligomer exhibited remarkable hybridization properties, binding more strongly to $3 prime,5 prime$-linked RNA than a single stranded $3 prime,5 prime$-linked DNA. This oligomer was capable of inhibiting reverse transcription in vitro and HIV-1 replication in cell cultures. N$ sp6$-Benzoyl-$5 prime$-O-dimethoxyltrityl-$3 prime$-O-methyl-$2 prime$-O-$ rm N,N prime$-diisopropyl$( beta$-cyanoethyl)adenosine phosphoramidite was prepared via methylation of the $2 prime$-O-silylated monomer and subsequently incorporation into an oligodeoxynucleotide to afford the first oligomer containing a $3 prime$-O-methyl nucleoside. Finally, a $2 prime,5 prime$-linked oligoribonucleotide built from unnatural L-adenosine was synthesized and was found to hybridize better to poly (rU) and (dT) than either of the corresponding $2 prime,5 prime$ and $3 prime,5 prime$-linked oligomers built from D-adenosine.</description><creator>Uddin, André Hameed.</creator><contributor>Damha, Masad J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Synthesis and studies on branched and 2,́5-́linked oligonucleotides</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd375x98t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s170r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nw147</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A field survey was conducted in eight villages in Northeastern Thailand to examine the impact of non-farm employment on rice production during the 1994-95 crop year. This study uses the human ecology approach based on the conceptual framework of Duncan's (1959) ecological complex. This study found that participation in non-farm employment directly affects whether the household will produce rice, but its impacts vary according to the extent of participation. Full-time employment, particularly with the yearlong absence of the male head of household, appears to inhibit rice production because it has the potential to cause a critical farm labor shortage. Part-time employment creates opportunities for farmers to integrate both farm and non-farm production to sustain their households. Women and elders have become the principal labor source for their own farms and waged labor for others. The traditional pattern of exchange labor can hardly be practiced when the demand for hired labor exceeds the supply. Waged laborers receive the same pay regardless of age and gender, and employers have no control over the wage rate. The use of machines is increasing. The supply of threshers exceeds demand, but there is a shortage of power-tillers. However, non-farm employment does not lead to increased levels of farm investment as hypothesized, because a large proportion of waged income was used for other purposes, including daily consumption and debt repayment. Consequently, there is no significant difference in farm productivity (kg. of paddy/unit area) between households with and without participation in non-farm employment. Out-migration to participate in non-farm employment seems inevitable in the face of population growth and land scarcity, but its impacts on rice production vary according to how farmers adapt to the changing resource base and use of modern farm technology. If possible, farmers tend to continue farm and non-farm employment to distribute their risks. However, it is crucial to retain a balance between the types of employment so that the loss of labor does not lead to poor farm productivity nor to production costs that exceed the farm household's means.</description><creator>Surintaraseree, Pimjai.</creator><contributor>Locher, Uli (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Rice -- Thailand.</subject><subject>Rice farmers -- Employment -- Thailand.</subject><subject>Thailand -- Rural conditions.</subject><title>Doing more with less : impacts of non-farm employment on rice production in Northeastern Thailand</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m091n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nw147</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rj63x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The first chapter of this dissertation uses a three-sector intertemporal general equilibrium model to examine the effects of various taxes and favorable depreciation rules on capital accumulation and the depletion of natural resources. We find that in a world of infinitely lived firms and households, under certain conditions, taxation causes the steady-state level of capital to be lower than the no-tax level. This divergence, however is reduced by lower capital gains tax rates and favorable depreciation rules. We also find that taxation causes the extraction rate of natural resources to be faster than the social optimum. Although this difference is lessened by lower capital gains tax rates, it is exacerbated by a generous depreciation system. These results challenge the "conventional wisdom" that depreciation rules should be the same for all sectors. Although the first chapter highlights the importance of a general equilibrium analysis of a multi-sector economy with intertemporally optimizing firms and consumers, there are a number of issues that it neglects. Among these are the adjustment costs associated with investments, and the fact that consumers might plan only for a finite horizon. The second and third chapters of this dissertation take up these issues. The second chapter, which also uses an intertemporal model, determines theoretically how various taxes and adjustment costs affect the growth paths of domestic corporations and foreign subsidiaries of American multinationals. We find that the effects of capital gains taxation and adjustment costs on the growth paths of domestic corporations and foreign subsidiaries of American multinationals are likely to be unfavorable. Finally, the third chapter uses a three period overlapping generations model to examine the effects of the capital income tax, the labour income tax, and favorable depreciation rules on human and physical capital accumulation. We find that, under certain conditions, the capital income tax has a negative impact on steady-state levels of physical and human capital, and the steady-state physical capital to human capital ratio. Moreover favorable depreciation rules are shown to reduce the impact of the capital income tax.</description><creator>Toppa, Rebecca Saunders.</creator><contributor>Long, N. V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Capital levy -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Some of the effects of capital taxation : a theoretical and empirical analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h340s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rj63x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zc736</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Consumers are demanding more and more value for each dollar spent on new electronic equipment. Built-In Self-Test (BIST) of electronic circuits and equipment will help to satiate the demand for self test, self diagnostics, and self repair. This dissertation explores a technique for a Mixed Analog Digital BIST (MADBIST) on a mixed-signal Integrated Circuit (IC). Specifically, on-chip tests for the Analog-to-Digital Converter and Digital-to-Analog Converter on the mixed-signal IC are developed. (The digital portion of the IC can be tested using digital BIST techniques). The tests implemented include Frequency Response, Signal-to-Noise Ratio, Gain Tracking, Inter-Modulation Distortion, and Harmonic Distortion. A precision analog test stimulus is efficiently generated on-chip using digital circuitry. The test stimulus itself is encoded within a Pulse-Density-Modulated bit stream. A narrow-band digital filter is employed to extract the measurement results. Experimental results from a test chip and a prototype circuit board are provided. Some of the engineering and economical trade-offs associated with the design of the tests are considered. The overhead required to implement several types of tests is dealt with. We also explore the relationship between the accuracy achieved by the test and the amount of resources required to implement it.</description><creator>Toner, Michael F.</creator><contributor>Roberts, Gordon W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>MADBIST : a scheme for built-in self-test of mixed analog-digital integrated circuits</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42n9529.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zc736</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f283g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Selective isolation protocols of selenium (Se) species integrated to Se specific atomic absorption spectroscopy (AAS) detection were developed and optimized for Se speciation in food supplements, including selenized yeasts. By ultrafiltration, 69.18% of Se in the extract was found as a low molecular weight soluble form, the remaining 30.82% was bound to high molecular weight components. After a cation-exchange chromatography of the ultrafiltrate, 3.77% of the Se in the extract was found in the aqueous washings of the column indicating the presence of free inorganic anions of Se; the 65.41% of Se retained on the column corresponded to the free organic Se cations. The limit of detection for the HPLC-THG-AAS system was 1.85 ng of Se. Se was shown to be widely distributed over all the proteins with one sharp peak corresponding to the free forms of Se. Four major peaks were found at MW $&gt;$ 250 000 Da (15.97% of Se recovered), between 102 330 and 117 490 Da (7.06%), between 48 977 and 53 703 Da (12.71%) and close to the dye migration band (17.25%). Selective isolation and HPLC-AAS protocols were also developed and optimized for the determination of free organic forms e.g. selenomethionine (SeMet), selenocystine (SeCystine) and inorganic forms of selenium in aqueous solutions, and in complex matrices such as nutritional supplements and mixtures of free amino acids. The selenoamino acid in alkaline solution was first derivatized with 1-fluoro-2,4-dinitrobenzene. After removal of excess of reagent by partitioning with diethyl ether, the N-dinitrophenyl (DNP)-derivatized selenoamino acid was acidified and extracted with diethyl ether. Inorganic Se(IV) was extracted from the acidic aqueous phases by complexation with 1,2-phenylenediamine, forming a piazselenol. Se derivatives were determined selectively by HPLC-THG-AAS. A selective chromatographic mechanism based on $ pi$-electron interactions was optimized using a silica stationary phase derivatized with p-nitrophenyl moieties. Co-injections of DNP-SeMet, DNP-SeCystine and piazselenol save retention times of 3.7, 4.0 and 4.9 min, respectively, using a methanolic mobile phase containing 1.5% triethylamine and 0.013M acetic acid. Primary analytical validation parameters including stability, linearity and limits of detection were obtained using purified DNP-SeMet, DNP-SeCystine and piazselenol standards which were characterized by $ sp1$H-, $ sp{13}$C- and $ sp{77}$Se-NMR analysis and/or fast atom bombardment MS techniques. The calibration graphs for sequential dilutions of these Se standards were linear and the limits of detection from the resultant calibration graphs were 17 ng, 0.21 ng and 18.53 ng of Se, respectively. The purified DNP-SeMet and DNP-SeCystine were found to be photosensitive. The recovery of SeMet, SeCystine and inorganic Se from the stock solutions and/or nutritional supplements was virtually quantitative. In the presence of a 500-fold excess of other amino acids, the recovery of SeMet and SeCystine (96.1 +- pm +- 3.9% and 98.08 +- pm +- 4.2%, respectively) was in an acceptable range to allow the accurate
determination ofthese selenoamino acids in a protein hydrolysate.</description><creator>Matni, Gisèle.</creator><contributor>Blais, Jean Simon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Dietary supplements.</subject><subject>Selenium -- Speciation.</subject><subject>Selenium -- Analysis.</subject><subject>Selenium -- Physiological effect.</subject><subject>Yeast.</subject><title>Speciation of selenium in food supplements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xd344.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f283g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827d314</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:23:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Protein import into the mitochondria is a result of a series of sequential binding interactions between a mitochondrial targeting signal and the translocation machinery of both mitochondrial membranes. The targeting signals contained within protein of the outer membrane are distinct from those which target proteins to other subcompartments. The transmembrane domain of the yeast outer membrane receptor protein yTom70 is capable of both targeting and inserting the protein into the outer membrane. The efficiency of this process is increased by the addition of a positively-charged region preceding the transmembrane region. These two structural domains co-operate to form a signal-anchor sequence selective for the outer membrane, since this is the first membrane encountered by the targeting signal. Consistent with this model, the signal-anchor sequence of the outer membrane protein yTom70 is also capable of importing into the inner membrane of mitochondria when the outer membrane is selectively removed. Import into the inner membrane requires the presence of an electrochemical potential across the lipid bilayer. Import proceeds in the absence of $ Delta Psi$ only when constructs are used which lack the positively-charged amino terminal region of the signal-anchor sequence. These results suggest that the positively-charged presequence leads the transmembrane domain into the import machinery and that $ Delta Psi$ is required to clear this region in order that the distal transmembrane region can enter the translocation pathway. The charged N-terminal 10 residues of yTom70 are incapable of directing import into intact mammalian mitochondria, however, are able to efficiently direct import into the matrix of yeast mitochondria or mammalian mitoplasts. This potentially cryptic signal is excluded from intact mammalian mitochondria due to the presence of the receptor protein Tom20, since replacement of yeast Tom20 with mammalian Tom20 confers the mammalian phenotype onto yeast. These results suggest that receptor proteins may also have the ability to screen potentially cryptic signals from distal components of the outer and inner membrane translocation machinery.</description><creator>McBride, Heidi May</creator><contributor>Shore, Gordon C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Protein import into and across the mitochondrial outer membrane</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/df65v947p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827d314</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):31175</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>