<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:28:55Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):36850" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cm79b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Early records of the St. Gabriel Street Church are contained in the Presbytery Office of The Presbyterian Church in Canada located in the Dominion Square Building. There are none in the First Presbyterian Church in Montreal. The register of the St. Peter Street Church is to be found in the archives of the Church of St. Andrew and St. Paul although apparently, not the Minute Book of the Church Committee. A manuscript source of great value, if it could be located, is the diary of William Hunter, in which he is said to have noted the ecclesiastical events of his day. Before he helped form the St. Peter Street congregation, he had been an elder in the St. Gabriel Street Church. His diary was used by Robert Campbell in 1887. The most valuable printed material relating to the St. Gabriel Street Church and the individuals who formed its membership, is found in Robert Campbell’s book of 800 pages, entitled “History of the Scotch Church St. Gabriel Street, Montreal”, and published in 1887. It also contains useful information concerning the St. Peter Street Church. In addition we have a short, almost contemporary history of the St. Peter Street Church. It was written by Dr. Alexander Mathieson in 1832, and is found in “The Life of Alexander Mathieson”, published by James Croil in 1870.</description><creator>McDougall, Elizabeth Ann</creator><contributor>Cooper, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1965</date><subject>Montréal (Québec) -- Church history.</subject><subject>Presbyterian Church -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History.</subject><subject>History, Church.</subject><title>The American element in the early Presbyterian Church in Montreal (1786-1824)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kf92p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cm79b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289p14s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Measurements of the spin-lattice relaxation time, T1, and spin-spin relaxation time, T2, of potassium ferricyanide diluted by potassium coba1ticyanide were made by the CW saturation method. Crystals of two concentrations of Fe3+ in K3Co(CN)6 were investigated: 0.5% and 1.0%. The results are the same for both concentrations to within the probable error. The mean relaxation times for the two concentrations are quoted to one significant figure, together with the probable errors: T1 =(1 +- 0.15) x 10-4 sec and T2 = (9 +- 0.4) x 10-9 sec. Calculations have been made to determine the angular dependence of the paramagnetic resonance spectra of potassium ferricyanide. Three graphs have been plotted which may be useful for comparison with future measurements.</description><creator>Kipling, Arlin Lloyd</creator><contributor>Woonton, G.A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1961</date><subject>Physics, Electricity and Magnetism.</subject><title>Paramagnetic resonant-relaxation in potassium ferricyanide</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fh11j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289p14s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80j0786</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>At the court of Louis XIV during the first weeks of 1686, a group of very influential people were doing everything in their power to have the intendant of New France, the sieur de Meulles, recalled from his post and replaced by his predecessor, the sieur Duchesneau. [...]</description><creator>Eccles, W. J. (William John).</creator><contributor>Cooper, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1951</date><subject>History.</subject><subject>Colonial administrators -- New France.</subject><subject>Bochart de Champigny, Jean, sieur de Noroy et de Verneuil, ca. 1645-1720.</subject><title>Jean Bochart de Champigny, intendant of New France, 1686-1702.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89db64r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80j0786</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150p241</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis uses multiscale computational modelling to find the fundamental principles that govern defects forming during the operation of new electro-optical devices and the processing of spider silk fibers. The generalized approach developed in this thesis bridges engineering devices and biological processes based on liquid crystalline materials. Three types of defects are encountered: inversion walls, lines and points. Inversion wall defects are found in the electro-optical device when a nematic thin film undergoes a temperature-induced surface anchoring transition. Point defects naturally occur in the tubular extrusion duct of spiders, while line defects present close topological connections with point defects and are widespread in many high-performance industrial fibers. Three models are used in this thesis and their usage is dependent on the characteristics of the defects studied. In the case of inversion wall defects, computational modelling is used to verify, complement and analyze experimental measurements made with fluorescence confocal polarizing microscopy by our collaborator at the Georgia Institute of Technology. The various simulation results agree and explain very well experimental observations and provide a thorough understanding of the wall defects behavior. A computational technique is developed to enable the precise determination of the interaction between the liquid crystal and the device substrate. Understanding the behavior of wall defects and estimating interfacial properties are indispensable to the development and optimization of the electro-optical device as they affect properties like temperature of operation, switching voltages and response time. Computational modelling is also used to investigate the behavior of nematic point defects confined in cylindrical cavities as observed along spiders' spinning apparatus, and to examined textural connections with other well know structures seen in industrial fibers. The various scenarios investigated include: interactions between point defects, topological transformations between point, line and ring defects as well as interactions between ring defects. The simulation results agree and complement previous investigations but also offer a new fundamental understanding on the nature and stability of defects in cylindrical cavities. Understanding the behavior of nematic point and line defects in cylindrical geometries is important as they play a fundamental role in the processing of natural and industrial high-performance fibers.</description><creator>De Luca, Gino.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Liquid crystals -- Defects.</subject><subject>Polymer liquid crystals -- Defects.</subject><subject>Spider webs.</subject><title>Computational modelling of nematic liquid crystal defects in devices and fiber processing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Gino De Luca, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jw272.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150p241</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn1073230</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although the native conformation of a protein is thermodynamically its most stable form, this stability is only marginal. As a consequence, globular proteins have a certain amount of flexibility in their backbones which allows for conformational changes in the course of their biological function. In the course of this thesis, we study protein models at the edge of stability in different contexts: (1) First, we use molecular dynamics to determine the force needed to rupture a chain molecule (an unfolded protein) being stretched at constant loading rate and temperature. When all energy bonds of the molecule are identical, we find that the force F depends on the pulling rate r and temperature T according to F ~ const -- T 1/3|ln(r/T)|1/3 When a single weak bond is introduced, this result is modified to F ~ const -- T2/3|ln(r/ T)|2/3 This scaling, which is model independent, can be used with force-spectroscopy experiment to quantitatively extract relevant microscopic parameters of biomolecules. (2) Second, we study the structural stability of models of proteins for which the selected folds are unusually stable to mutation, that is, designable. A two-dimensional hydrophobic-polar lattice model is used to determine designable folds and these folds were investigated under shear through Langevin dynamics. We find that the phase diagram of these proteins depends on their designability. In particular, highly designable folds are found to be weaker, i.e. easier to unfold, than low designable ones. This is argued to be related to protein flexibility. (3) Third, we study the mechanism of cold denaturation through constant-pressure simulations for a model of hydrophobic molecules in an explicit solvent. We find that the temperature dependence of the hydrophobic effect is the driving force for cold denaturation. The physical mechanism underlying this phenomenon is identified as the destabilization of hydrophobic contact in favor of solvent separated configurations, the same mechanism seen in pressure induced denaturation. A phenomenological explanation proposed for the mechanism is suggested as being responsible for cold denaturation in real proteins.</description><creator>Dias, Cristiano L.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Proteins -- Denaturation.</subject><subject>Proteins -- Stability.</subject><subject>Proteins -- Conformation.</subject><subject>Globular proteins.</subject><title>Models of the stability of proteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Cristiano L. Dias, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qh347.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn1073230</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cn69m8255</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In causal reasoning the presence of a strong predictor of an outcome interferes with causal judgments of a moderate co-occurring predictor. Causal competition effects have generally been demonstrated with a strong competing predictor that is followed by an outcome with a higher probability than a moderate target predictor, and that also signals as many or more of the total outcome occurrences than the moderate target predictor. Confounding these two distinct aspects of predictiveness has constrained the ability to examine their respective importance for the relative validity of predictors in causal competition. By examining the effects of one and two strong competing causes on judgments of a moderate cause, varying the proportion of total outcomes that the competing predictors are paired with while holding overall outcome frequency constant, this series of experiments begins to disentangle these aspects of predictiveness. It demonstrates competition effects with a strong predictor that predicts fewer outcomes than the moderate target predictor. In addition, causal competition was examined between positive predictors (those signaling the occurrence of the outcome), between negative predictors (those signaling the absence of the outcome) and between predictors of opposite polarity (positive and negative). Causal candidates of opposite polarity were found to enhance rather than reduce causal judgments of moderate positive and negative predictors, posing a challenge for some of the most influential theories of causal learning that explain competition effects as the discounting of the moderate predictor or a failure to learn its association with the outcome. Rather, these results are consistent with a contrast mechanism whereby causal judgments of moderate predictors are not necessarily reduced toward zero in the presence of stronger predictors, but are adjusted along the causal judgment scale in opposite direction from the strong predictors. When the competing predictors are of the same polarity causal judgments of moderate predictors appear to be reduced, but when they are of opposite polarity judgments are enhanced. The implications for various associative and statistical models of causal learning are discussed.</description><creator>Darredeau, Christine.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Judgment.</subject><subject>Prediction (Psychology)</subject><title>Casual judgements from contingency information : competition between multiple causes of a single outcome</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Christine Darredeau, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j945q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m8255</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x3323</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Through the use of chronic experimental animal models, the majority of in vitro investigations of temporal lobe epilepsy have demonstrated enhanced network activity within the subdivisions of the hippocampal formation. However, clinical evidence in combination with in vivo and in vitro studies indicates that structures external to the hippocampus contribute to the genesis of seizure activity. To address the effects of limbic network excitation, I have utilized combined hippocampal---entorhinal cortex brain slices from pilocarpine-treated rats that display chronic seizures. My investigations have focused upon three structures, the subiculum, entorhinal cortex and the insular cortex. The experiments in the pilocarpine-treated subiculum demonstrated increased network excitability that was attributed to a more positive GABAA receptor mediated inhibitory post-synaptic potential (IPSP) reversal point coupled with a reduced IPSP peak conductance. Utilizing RT-PCR analysis and immunohistochemical staining we observed a decline in K+-Cl- cotransporter mRNA expression and a reduced number of parvalbumin-positive, presumptive inhibitory interneurons. My second project assessed the network hyperexcitability in layer V of the lateral entorhinal cortex. This is the first study to report spontaneous bursting, in the absence of epileptogenic agents, in the epileptic entorhinal cortex. We attributed this level of network excitation to reduced GABAA receptor mediated inhibition and increased synaptic sprouting. In the final project, we extended our slice preparation to include the insular cortex, a structure external to the temporal lobe. Our investigations identified a mechanism of NMDA receptor dependent synaptic bursting that masked GABA A receptor mediated conductances.</description><creator>De Guzman, Philip Henry.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Pilocarpine.</subject><subject>Epilepsy, Temporal Lobe.</subject><subject>Hippocampus.</subject><subject>Entorhinal Cortex.</subject><title>Enhanced limbic network excitation in the pilocarpine animal model of temporal lobe epilepsy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Philip Henry De Guzman, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hd99h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x3323</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289p152</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Risk assessment of trace-metal contamination in soils requires predictive models that can accurately describe the complex uptake processes at the soil-plant interface, which are usually characterized by the coexistence of and interaction between multiple components. Competing cations such as Ca and H can affect metal availability to plants and subsequent rhizotoxicity. The biotic ligand model (BLM) has been proposed as a promising approach to model these interactive processes. Under the BLM assumption, we designed experiments to investigate how the solution chemistry is correlated with metal uptake and rhizotoxicity. Our first goal is to acquire a set of BLM parameters that can accurately represent the experimental data over varied solution conditions and parameters that are easy to integrate with general speciation models. The second objective is to get insight into the physical nature of the interactions. Our titration experiments revealed three types of biotic ligands in the pea roots with defined site densities and stability constants with H. Our ion sorption experiments estimated the surface-adsorption stability constants of Ca, Mg, Cd, Cu, Ni, and Zn with excised fresh pea roots. Our 48-h root growth tests have established the formation constants (KMe's) of living pea roots with Ca, Cd, Cu, Ni, and Zn. In these studies, we hypothesized and confirmed that the concentration of the metal-root complexes correlated with observed rhizotoxicity and that Ca, H, and trace metals competed for root absorption where lower solution pH decreased both Ca and metal uptake. Root elongation was found to be highly sensitive to root Ca content rather than merely to the direct toxic effects of the trace metals. It is shown that the physiological complexity arising from a living root affected our modeling so that adjustable KMe values, as a function of solution and root chemistry, are required for good model fits. The established model parameters were tested in hydroponic mixture solutions for their ability to predict the uptake of multiple metals simultaneously. The joint effects of Cd, Cu, and Ni in mixtures on root growth were studied and the potential interactions between these ions were also investigated.</description><creator>Wu, Yonghong, 1969-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Plants -- Effect of trace elements on.</subject><subject>Trace elements -- Bioavailability.</subject><subject>Peas -- Effect of heavy metals on.</subject><title>Bioavailability and rhizotoxicity of trace metals to pea : development of a terrestrial biotic ligand model</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Yonghong Wu, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343w97f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289p152</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dz010v12f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cerebral Cavernous Malformations (CCM) and Intracranial Aneurysms (IA) are cerebrovascular disorders that can lead to a hemorrhagic stroke and other neurological problems. CCMs are characterized by abnormally enlarged capillary cavities while IAs are saccular outpouchings of intracranial arteries. CCM is found in approximately 0.4% to 0.9% of the population, while IA is more common (3-6%). This dissertation aimed to add to the body of research for CCM and IA and was divided into two parts. Initial work focused on the characterization and identification of the genes involved in CCM; the second phase focused on the identification of a susceptibility gene for IA. In the first phase, the CCM1, CCM2 and CCM3 genes were characterized in families and in sporadic cases of CCM. In both cohorts, a causative mutation was identified in 71% of the cases. Subsequent MLPA analysis of subjects with no CCM mutations revealed that large genomic deletions and duplications are a common cause of CCM. In addition, investigation of CCM1 point mutations revealed that these were not simple missense mutations but that they rather activated cryptic splice-donor sites and caused aberrant splicing. Furthermore, the genetic predisposition to CCM in sporadic cases with a single lesion was determined to be different from sporadic cases with multiple malformations. Investigation into the loss of heterozygosity demonstrated a plausible mechanism for CCM pathogenesis involving a second somatic hit at the site of the lesion, suggesting that CCM may be caused by a complete loss of CCM protein function. In the second phase, a genome-wide scan of a large family and subsequent linkage analysis using a monogenic approach identified a susceptibility locus for IA (ANIB4). As a result of this research, we have greatly contributed to the field of CCM, most specifically to its clinical diagnosis. A greater understanding of the genetics involved in CCM will facilitate and permit better management care for patients. Furthermore, the possibility of identification of a gene with a major effect for IA will give us more insight into which pathways are involved in IA formation.</description><creator>Verlaan, Dominique Jacqueline.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Intracranial Aneurysm -- genetics.</subject><subject>Intracranial Arteriovenous Malformations -- genetics.</subject><title>Genetic investigation of cerebrovascular disorders : cerebral cavernous malformations and intracranial aneurysms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Dominique Jacqueline Verlaan, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569839j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010v12f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p096c130</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation comprises three essays. In the first essay, I develop a contingent-claims model to investigate the impact of managerial entrenchment on corporate policies and security valuation. The model emphasizes the role that managerial agency issues play in determining both a firm's dividend payout and capital structure. I show quantitatively that self-interested managers' leverage choices deviate from those ex ante maximize firm values. The results suggest that dividend yields are negatively affected by both leverage ratios and managerial entrenchment. They provide implications for empirical research attempting to relate dividend policy to capital structure. In addition, the model offers a new framework to measure managerial entrenchment using observed leverage and dividend payout. In the second essay, we use a set of structural models to evaluate the price of default protection for a sample of US corporations. In contrast to previous evidence from corporate bond data, CDS premia are not systematically underestimated. In fact, one of our studied models has little difficulty on average in predicting their level. For robustness, we perform the same exercise for bond spreads by the same issuers on the same trading date. As expected, bond spreads relative to the Treasury curve are systematically underestimated, consistent with their being driven by significant non-default components. This is not the case when the swap curve is used as a benchmark, suggesting that previously documented underestimation results may be sensitive to the choice of risk free rate. In the third essay, we develop a valuation model that simultaneously captures credit risk and interest rate risk, and apply it to study the valuation of putable corporate bonds. We ask what risks put features provide insurance against in practice - credit risk, liquidity risk or interest rate risk - and to what degree? We find that they reduce the components of all three risks in bond spreads. The most important, perhaps surprisingly is default or spread risk, followed by term structure risk. The reduction in the liquidity component is present but rather small.</description><creator>Wang, Hao, 1973-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Corporations -- Finance -- Decision-making.</subject><subject>Debt financing (Corporations)</subject><title>Three essays on corporate debt, capital structure and managerial entrenchment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Hao Wang, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vq137.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p096c130</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Desautels Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289p16b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis numerically solves the tensor order parameter continuum theory equations for nematic liquid crystals to investigate liquid crystal texturing mechanisms during an isotropic to nematic phase transition in a bulk unstable isotropic phase and next to solid surfaces. The Time Dependent Ginsburg Landau equation with a Landau de Gennes Helmholtz free energy density description is used to predict the shapes, textures and defect mechanisms that occur in the expanding droplets and films of a 4'-pentyl-4-cyanobiphenyl (5CB) nematic phase immediately after their nucleation from an unstable isotropic phase, due to a temperature quench. To create a robust simulation method able to tackle high curvature, defect nucleation, heterogeneous substrates and phase ordering interfaces, particular attention was paid to adapting the mathematical model and computational methods to what was previously known about the nucleation and growth events that occur experimentally during a bulk 5CB isotropic to nematic phase transition and next to decorated solid surfaces. The numerical simulations provide detailed predictions about (i) growth rates for different temperature quenches, (ii) structure of the isotropic-nematic interface, (iii) shapes of expanding nano and submicron nematic droplets, (iv) texturing within growing nano and submicron nematic droplets, (v) a new defect formation mechanism called "interfacial defect shedding", and (vi) the effect of contact angle and interface curvature next to a solid surface with anchoring switches. The main contributions of this thesis are its detailed predictions that emerge from the liquid crystal simulation results, the careful adaptation of the mathematical model and numerical method to what is currently known about early stage growth in a nematic liquid crystal phase, and the validation of new theory by the simulation results.</description><creator>Wincure, Benjamin, 1966-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Liquid crystals -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Phase transformations (Statistical physics) -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>Computational modeling of a liquid crystal phase transition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Benjamin Wincure, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t626j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289p16b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cz45h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Societies that foster high quality social environments and integration produce healthier populations. The mechanisms underlying the protective effect of social integration appear to be through various forms of social support. In the Canadian Aboriginal context, few authors have explored the relationship between health and social support. This gap in understanding is significant because Aboriginal frameworks of health point to the salience of larger social structures (i.e., family), yet patterns of population health point to distinctly social causes of morbidity and mortality (e.g., violence, alcoholism). An interesting paradox emerges: patterns of Aboriginal health suggest that social support is not working to promote health. This dissertation explores this paradox through a mixed-methods approach to describe the value of social support for Aboriginal health, and to critically examine the social-structural processes and mechanisms through which social support influences Aboriginal health at the community level. Principal components analyses of the 2001 Aboriginal Peoples Survey (APS) identified social support as a consistent dimension of Metis and Inuit health, and multivariable logistic regression modelling of the 2001 APS identified social support to be a significant determinant of thriving health among Indigenous men and women (e.g., those reporting their health as excellent/very good versus good/fair/poor). The results also indicate a distinct social gradient in thriving health status and social support among Aboriginal Canadians. Narrative analyses of 26 interviews with Aboriginal Community Health Representatives point to two key explanations for the health-support paradox: (i) social support is not a widely accessible resource; and (ii) the negative health effects of social support can outweigh the positive ones. The formation of health behaviours and cultural norms - which underpin social supports - are inextricably tied to the poor material circumstances that characterize Canada's Aboriginal communities. The thesis concludes with a critical examination of the processes through which environmental dispossession has influenced the determinants of Aboriginal health, broadly speaking. Effects are most acute within the material and social environments of Aboriginal communities. More research attention should focus on identifying the pathways through which the physical, material and social environments interact to influence the health of Aboriginal Canadians.</description><creator>Richmond, Chantelle Anne Marie.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Métis -- Health and hygiene -- Canada.</subject><subject>Inuit -- Health and hygiene -- Canada.</subject><subject>Social integration -- Canada.</subject><subject>Indians of North America -- Health and hygiene -- Canada.</subject><subject>Health status indicators -- Canada.</subject><title>Social support, material circumstance and health : understanding the links in Canada's aboriginal population</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Chantelle Anne Marie Richmond, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752m979.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cz45h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dr30r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study of diabetes mellitus is vital in this day and age because its incidence is increasing at an alarming rate. Diabetes results in the loss of function of beta-cells within the pancreas. Insulin resistance contributes to diabetes but the human body can compensate in various ways such as increasing the islet cell mass, glucose disposal and insulin secretion, in order to prevent the onset of diabetes. Growth hormone (GH) and insulin-like growth factor-I (IGF-I) are two integral hormones important in both glucose homeostasis and islet cell growth. Early studies using cultured islet cells have demonstrated positive regulation of beta-cell growth by both GH and IGF-I. To evaluate their relevance on normal beta-cell growth, compensatory growth, as well as in insulin responsiveness, we have used two mouse models that represent opposite manipulations of the GH/IGF-I axis. Specifically, the growth hormone receptor gene deficient (GHR-/-) and the IGF-I overexpression (MT-IGF) mice, to help understand the role of glucose homeostasis and islet cell growth in the GH/IGF-I axis. GH is essential for somatic growth and development as well as maintaining metabolic homeostasis. It is known that GH stimulates normal islet cell growth. Moreover, GH may also participate in islet cell overgrowth and compensate for insulin resistance induced by obesity. To determine whether the islet cell overgrowth is dependent on GH signaling, we studied the response of GHR-/- mice to high-fat diet (HFD)-induced obesity. We also studied the insulin responsiveness in GHR-/- mice. On the other hand, IGF-I promotes embryonic development, postnatal growth and the maturation of various organ systems. The notion that IGF-I stimulates islet cell growth has been challenged in recent years by results from IGF-I and receptor gene targeted models. We have characterized MT-IGF mice which overexpress the IGF-I gene. The results of our studies indicate that (1) GH is essential for normal islet cell growth, but not required for compensatory overgrowth of the islets in response to obesity, (2) GHR gene deficiency caused delayed insulin responsiveness in skeletal muscle; in contrast to elevated insulin sensitivity in the liver; (3) although overexpression does not stimulate islet cell growth, a chronic IGF-I elevation caused significant hypoglycemia, hypoinsulinemia, and improved glucose tolerance, (4) finally IGF-I overexpression mice are resistant to experimental diabetes.</description><creator>Robertson, Katherine.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Insulin -- secretion.</subject><subject>Insulin-Secreting Cells -- physiology.</subject><subject>Insulin-Like Growth Factor I -- physiology.</subject><subject>Growth Hormone -- physiology.</subject><title>The role of the growth hormone/IGF-I system on islet cell growth and insulin action /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Katherine Robertson, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qp00w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dr30r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rz753</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bowlby's notion that client secure attachment to the therapist leads to deeper client exploration, is considered an important corner stone of the therapeutic process. Psychotherapy researchers have neglected the study of therapist contributions and observer perspectives when studying this important therapeutic phenomenon. Studies of therapeutic secure base have shown that there is a relationship between client general attachment patterns and those with therapist, as well as that this secure attachment to therapist relates to deeper sessions. The main objectives of the present research was to extend the study of secure base in therapy to include consideration of therapist attachment processes and to improve the methodology used in attachment research by adding the expert observer perspective to operationalize session exploration. The first study explored the secure base hypothesis, the transference hypothesis and the role of therapist attachment in the process. Sixty-seven clients and therapists in-training, in short term therapy, completed the Experiences in Close Relationship Scale (ECRS), the Client Attachment to Therapist Scale (CATS), Working Alliance Inventory (WAI), and a measure of session depth; the Session Evaluation Questionnaire-Depth subscale. In line with Bowlby's (1988) secure base hypothesis, secure attachment to therapist was significantly associated with session depth. Therapist insecure adult attachment was negatively associated with client secure attachment to therapist. The second study addressed methodological limitations found in previous studies by using both client and expert observer perspectives in the operationalization of session exploration. Thirty-one clients assessed depth in the middle sessions of their short-term therapies and rated their attachment to their therapists. Raters assessed experiencing in the same sessions using the Experiencing Scale. Secure attachment to therapist was positively and significantly associated with experiencing levels. However, the two perspectives on session exploration did not converge, suggesting that each taps a distinct aspect of session exploration and underlining the importance of rater perspective in the operationalization of this construct. Taken together, the results of these two studies offer a strong support for the secure base hypothesis. Clinical and research implications are discussed.</description><creator>Romano, Vera.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Attachment behavior.</subject><subject>Therapist and patient.</subject><title>Attachment in psychotherapy : the secure base hypothesis and the role of the therapist</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Vera Romano, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702qb59n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rz753</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cm81c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Conceptualizing the locality today in the global context means to be able to consider a level of denationalisation of the actor (of a locality) participating in a networked situation with actors from other localities. This thesis introduces a new conceptualization of the locality participating in a transnational network. The network, CEARENAD, involved six localities (Brazil, Chili, Costa-Rica, Senegal, Mauritius and Canada) who co-constructed contents for five years. This research is about presenting not a "mode d'emploi" about whether this particular network was successful or not. What truly motivated me, during and about this research, was to reflect on my observations of this network to build a new conceptualisation about the intertwinments of a locality and another space. This is what this thesis is about. "La sedimentation du passage" renders a rigorous description of the numerous processes which bring the locality to the front line. This study shows the description (Latour: 1987, 1999) of the participative actions of the actors involved in the network. The sedimentation of the passage reveals the repercussions of the mediations between the localities. This theorization activates, in other ways, the denationalization of actors, and, adds to the cultural construct of the network as well as to the possibilities of the Politic (Sassen: 2006). This is an example of a networked knowledge production while, at the same time, and this may be of most importance, it is also an example of how today's reading of the locality deepens the necessity of participative actions in the mediations and mediatizations (Darbellay: 2006) of materialities in the contemporary globalization. The sedimentation of the passage allows one to read what circulation(s) are actually chosen to be materialized in and for the locality.</description><creator>Roberge, Claire.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Transnationalism.</subject><subject>Computer networks -- Social aspects.</subject><subject>Space and time.</subject><title>L'espace transnational et la localité : le réseautage et la sédimentation du passage</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Claire Roberge, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kp85w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cm81c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wh698</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Aboriginal youth well-being is an increasingly important topic. Research with mainstream populations highlights two keys to well-being, namely perceived personal control, and a clear sense of self-identity. However, despite relevance for Aboriginal groups, underappreciated to date is the potential role of perceived collective control, and clarity of collective identity, for well-being. Thus, the present program of research investigated the impact of collective control and identity on the well-being of Aboriginal youth. Residents of two Cree communities in northern Manitoba collaborated in the research. Based on community members' input on important community and youth issues, we developed two surveys on youth well-being, which were completed by students in grades 7 and up. The results of Study 1 indicated that greater perceived individual-level internal control was associated with greater psychological well-being. As well, investigating for the first time perceived group-level control and Aboriginal youth well-being, the results indicated that greater perceived group-level internal control was associated with greater well-being. However, the results additionally suggested an association between greater perceived external control (Others and Creator) and greater well-being. The effect of group-level internal control on well-being was mediated by individual-level internal control, but not moderated by strength of Native identity. Finally, the results suggested a significant relationship between greater strength of aspects of cultural identity and greater well-being. Study 2 expanded upon these findings, employing revised measures to assess perceived control, identity clarity, and substance use. Similar to Study 1, the results of Study 2 indicated an association between greater perceived individual-level internal control and greater psychological well-being, as well as between individual-level others control and well-being. Additionally, multidimensional measures of control indicated an association between greater perceived individual-level control over drinking and decreased well-being. Furthermore, Study 2 indicated an association between greater perceived group-level internal control and greater psychological well-being. This relationship was partially mediated by individual-level internal control. Finally, the results suggested an association between greater strength of cultural identity and greater well-being. Overall, the present program of research provides key preliminary support for a greater consideration of group-level factors in well-being, particularly in efforts to enhance and support Aboriginal youth well-being.</description><creator>Mair Tiessen, Melissa Shannon.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Cree teenagers -- Manitoba -- Psychology.</subject><subject>Cree teenagers -- Manitoba -- Ethnic identity.</subject><title>Collective control, cultural identity, and the psychological well-being of northern Manitoba Cree youth</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Melissa Shannon Mair Tiessen, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nv91n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wh698</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311t59q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Uveal melanoma is the most common primary intraocular malignant tumour in adults. Despite improvements in the diagnosis and treatment of the primary tumour, patients continue to have the same mortality rate as several decades ago, reflecting our poor understanding of the mechanisms behind the formation of metastases in this disease. The purpose of this study was therefore to characterize an animal model of uveal melanoma and use this model to study the transcriptional changes that cells undergo from culture to intraocular tumour, to circulation and finally to the formation of a metastatic nodule. Using microarrays we identified 314 changes in transcript abundance between the intraocular tumour and metastatic lesions. Principal Components Analysis was used to cluster these transcripts into four distinct groups. A further 61 gene transcripts showed statistically significant changes between re-cultured cells isolated from the model, with the circulating malignant cells representing an intermediate step between cells isolated from intraocular tumours and metastatic lesions. We have produced a detailed analysis of the molecular changes that take place as human uveal melanoma cells evolve from a primary tumour to metastasis in an animal model, including the decrease in expression of specific melanoma markers. These changes were verified using quantitative real time polymerase chain reaction and three different functional assays. In addition we sought to describe the genetic changes that are present in these cells. Using comparative genomic hybridization arrays we were able to successfully describe the deletions and amplifications that are present in genomic DNA extracted from paraffin embedded sections of the primary tumour. This represents the first time that archival tissue has successfully been used for this sort of analysis in uveal melanoma. We identified several genomic amplifications and deletions including an area of amplification of Wnt2, which is involved in beta-catenin regulation and C-Met, which plays a role in tumour cell homing to the liver in patients. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first time that a detailed genetic analysis has been carried out on the progression of uveal melanoma from intraocular tumour, to circulation, to the formation of metastases.</description><creator>Marshall, Jean-Claude.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Melanoma -- genetics.</subject><subject>Gene Expression Profiling -- methods.</subject><subject>Uveal Neoplasms -- genetics.</subject><subject>Oligonucleotide Array Sequence Analysis -- methods.</subject><title>Transcriptional and genetic profiling of human uveal melanoma from an immunosuppressed rabbit model</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Jean-Claude Marshall, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k942g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311t59q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tr119</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study explores the phenomenon of gendered harassment in secondary schools from the teachers' perspectives. The few studies that address the biased behaviors that are linked under the concept of gendered harassment (sexual harassment, homophobic harassment, and harassment for gender non-conformity) indicate that teachers are less likely to intervene in these incidents. This dissertation explores how teachers understand and respond to (hetero)sexist and homophobic behaviors when they occur. Six teachers in one urban school board participated in a series of three open-ended in-depth interviews where they spoke about the many factors that influenced how they saw and intervened in various forms of bullying and harassment in their schools. Interview data were analyzed using contextual and thematic codes to locate similarities, differences, and stories in the data. This study is informed by critical, feminist and queer theories. The findings have been organized in a conceptual framework that emerged from the research. Findings indicate that there are both external and internal influences that shape how teachers view and respond to gendered harassment in schools. The external factors, also described as school culture, include both structural-formal and structural-informal influences. Formal influences include policies, training, curriculum and contracts. Informal influences refer to leadership style, relationships with colleagues, policy implementation, and community values. Internal influences that shape teachers' perceptions and responses include: educational biography, teaching philosophy, and personal identities. The implications of this study for research and practice can have impacts on the fields of school policy, teacher education, curriculum, and educational leadership. It provides a framework for understanding how school cultures interact with teachers' identities and shape how policies and curricula are implemented. It also offers suggestions for scholars, advocates, and educational leaders to proactively address the negative impacts of gendered harassment by transforming teacher education, educational leadership programs, and in turn, school cultures.</description><creator>Meyer, Elizabeth J., 1971-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Sex discrimination.</subject><subject>Homophobia in schools.</subject><subject>Bullying in schools.</subject><subject>Harassment.</subject><title>Gendered harassment in secondary schools : understanding teachers' perceptions of and responses to the problem</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Elizabeth J. Meyer, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p458b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tr119</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70n049h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores the significance of digital cinematic technology within the independent film community. The main objective of this study is to demonstrate how various forms of digital technology (including cameras, non-linear editing software, and projection systems) are "democratizing" the processes of production, post-production, distribution, and theatrical exhibition.</description><creator>Mak, Monica.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Digital cinematography.</subject><subject>Independent filmmakers.</subject><title>Digital cinematic technology and the democratization of independent cinema</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Monica Mak, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096c148.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70n049h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k643b532v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The long-held notion that gifted students prefer to work alone is reported in several general textbooks on gifted children. However, studies addressing this issue are mixed and certainly not conclusive. Earlier studies disagree on whether those gifted children who claim a preference for working alone do so as a function of grade and maturational stage, sex, or personality characteristics commensurate with increasingly higher IQs. The current study re-examines this notion through the lens of motivation through social-constructivist theory. Two hundred and forty-seven American school-identified gifted, high achieving, and non-identified (i.e., non-gifted, regular education) students in grades 4 through 12 participated. The measure used in this study was a survey comprising items used in past learning style-related research, items adapted from a personality index and an interest profile, as well as locally-developed open-ended questions regarding preferred learning conditions, learning-related personality characteristics, and perceptions of support in their learning. Participants also had the opportunity to offer ideas about ideal learning situations, and their beliefs on why some children versus others might prefer to work alone. Finally, this study attempted to confirm the hypothesis that those gifted students who feel adequately supported by those in their environment will be less likely to indicate a preference for working alone, compared to those who do not feel supported. Although some indication of a preference of gifted students to work alone was present, this preference was not strong because it varied based on how the question was posed. Moreover, sex and grade-related differences were noted. Perhaps most interestingly, in support of the hypothesis of the study, those participants who reported feeling least supported by others reported the strongest preference to work alone. Implications of these findings on classroom curriculum, future career functioning, and mental health are discussed.</description><creator>French, Lisa Rebecca.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Gifted children.</subject><subject>Learning, Psychology of.</subject><subject>Cognitive styles.</subject><title>Do gifted children prefer to work alone? : a social-constructivist re-examination of the longstanding claim</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Lisa Rebecca French, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042z33q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b532v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s161b401</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Electronics involve an elaborate process of waste-making, from the mining of raw materials to the production of microchips through toxic solvents, to the eventual recycling or disposal of obsolete equipment. These processes of pollution, remainder and decay reveal other orders of materiality that have yet to enter the sense of the digital. This thesis investigates electronics through this waste and remainder. The thesis is guided by Walter Benjamin's notion of "natural history," and focuses on the dynamic, transient and poetic qualities of outmoded or "fossilized" commodities. Described here are electronic versions of such fossils, as well as the more formless residues that are sloughed off in the pursuit of technological advance. Electronic technologies expand beyond devices and programs to an assemblage of sites and systems. Instead of a collection of outdated artifacts, this study further suggests that it is necessary not to focus solely on the abandoned electronic gadget, but also to consider the extended contexts through which electronics and electronic waste circulate. My intention here is to crack open the black box of electronics, and track their transformation to waste across a number of fields, from manufacture to disposal, and from archive to landfill, which inform the chapters below. By focusing on waste, this study is less interested in material comprehensiveness, or all that goes into electronics, and is instead more attentive toward material proliferations. In this way, I work through the "inputs and outputs" that take place not only at a material level, but also at cultural, political and economic levels. There is much more to electronics than raw materials transformed into neat gadgets that swiftly become obsolete. This study then considers electronics not from the perspective of all that is new, but rather from the perspective of all that is discarded. These discards, this study suggests, direct us toward considerations of electronics, technologies and material culture that are informed not by "upgrades," but instead by politics and poetics.</description><creator>Gabrys, Jennifer.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Electronic apparatus and appliances.</subject><subject>Electronic waste.</subject><subject>Waste products.</subject><title>The natural history of electronics /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Jennifer Gabrys, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v983t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161b401</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v692tb48v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is dedicated to the study of gain transients of discrete fiber Raman amplifiers and to the all-optical gain-clamping technique which is used to mitigate those transients. First, we study the standing-wave and the traveling-wave gain-clamping techniques when applied to a single discrete fiber Raman amplifier in the context of WDM channel add and drop. We take into account the operational regime of the amplifier and the location of the surviving channel in the amplification band. We demonstrate that the gain-clamped amplifier has to be operated in a regime below the critical regime to ensure that gain-clamping will be in effect. The efficiency of gain-clamping also depends on the feedback level of the lasing signal and on the implementation. Next, we investigate the dynamic behaviour of a single discrete fiber Raman amplifier fed by multi-channel packet traffic. Our study shows that the efficiency of the gain-clamping technique to reduce the gain transients is dependent upon the operational regime of the amplifier and the packet duration. However, we also demonstrate that gain-clamping is not required to control the gain transients as the gain variations of the unclamped amplifier are small enough to be neglected. We then theoretically analyse the dynamic response of cascades of discrete fiber Raman amplifiers subject to WDM channel add and drop. We consider cascades of mixed unclamped and gain-clamped amplifiers, varying the number and the position of the gain-clamped amplifiers in the cascade and taking into account the location of the surviving channel and the operational regime of the amplifiers. Our results show that the location of the gain-clamped amplifiers in a mixed cascade affects the transient characteristics and that it is possible to control the transients within tolerable limits. Finally, we investigate the gain transients that occur in hybrid amplifiers in the presence of channel add and drop. We demonstrate that the gain-clamping technique can be used to mitigate the gain transients in hybrid amplifiers and that the surviving channel location does not influence the transient characteristics, contrary to the case of single and cascaded fiber Raman amplifiers.</description><creator>Gest, Johann.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Optical communications.</subject><subject>Raman effect.</subject><subject>Optical amplifiers.</subject><subject>Computer networks.</subject><subject>Data transmission systems.</subject><title>Discrete fiber Raman amplifiers for agile all-photonic networks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Johann Gest, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892g26b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692tb48v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042z32f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We compute the electrical conductivity and shear viscosity at leading order in hot Quantum Electrodynamics. Starting from the Kubo relation for electrical conductivity and shear viscosity, we use diagrammatic methods to write down the appropriate integral equations for bosonic and fermionic effective vertices. We also show how Ward identities can be used to put constraints on these integral equations. One of our main results is an equation relating the kernels of the integral equations with functional derivatives of the full self-energy; it is similar to what is obtained with two-particle-irreducible effective action methods. However, since we use Ward identities as our starting point, gauge invariance is preserved. Using these constraints obtained from Ward identities and also power counting arguments, we select the necessary diagrams that must be resummed at leading order. This includes all non-collinear (corresponding to 2 to 2 scatterings) and collinear (corresponding to 1+N to 2+N collinear scatterings) rungs responsible for the Landau-Pomeranchuk-Migdal effect. We also show the equivalence between our integral equations and the linearized Boltzmann equations of Arnold, Moore and Yaffe obtained using effective kinetic theory.</description><creator>Gagnon, Jean-Sébastien.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Quantum electrodynamics.</subject><subject>Gauge fields (Physics)</subject><subject>Transport theory -- Mathematics.</subject><title>Leading order calculation of transport coefficients in hot quantum electrodynamics from diagrammatic methods</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Jean-Sébastien Gagnon, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fd44q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042z32f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qf85ng36p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The development of healthy gametes is paramount to the health of progeny and to the survival of a species. Epigenetic information contained within gametic DNA in the form of DNA methylation is essential for germ cell and embryo development. DNA methylation is a genome-wide phenomenon involved in the control of gene expression and chromosome structure and stability. During germ line development, patterns of DNA methylation are established in a sex- and sequence-specific manner. The primary goal of the work presented in this thesis is to gain an understanding of the nature of the genome-wide pattern of DNA methylation in germ cells and to study its progression during germ cell development. The complexity of male germ cell development has been well studied in mice and thus makes an excellent system in which to study germ cell DNA methylation. Firstly, genome-wide patterns of DNA methylation in adult male germ cells were determined using a variety of techniques. Results from these studies demonstrate that the DNA methylation pattern in male germ cells is highly distinct from that of somatic cells. The reorganization of the germ cell pattern is associated with chromosomal features such as the chromosomal banding pattern and regional GC content. Secondly, by examining purified populations of male germ cells, we have determined that patterns of DNA methylation are being acquired during spermatogenesis. De novo methylation and demethylation events occur in a sequence-specific manner prior to the meiotic phase of germ cell development. Finally, the stability of these patterns was studied by perturbing DNA methyltransferase activity. The study of germ cells lacking a functional Dnmt3L gene demonstrates that the abnormalities displayed in these cells are associated with a failure to acquire normal levels of DNA methylation. In addition, the treatment of mice with the hypomethylating agent, 5-aza-2'-deoxycytidine, results in adverse effects on sperm function and is associated with sequence-specific hypomethylation. Collectively, these studies have uncovered several novel aspects of DNA methylation in male germ cells and contribute to our understanding of the roles) for epigenetic phenomena in the development and maintenance of healthy gametes.</description><creator>Oakes, Christopher Charles.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>DNA methylation in male germ cells : the acquisition and maintenance of unique genome-wide patterns</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Christopher Charles Oakes, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vz090.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85ng36p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30px87h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T05:02:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Leishmania protozoan parasites, the causative agent of leishmaniasis, a disease endemic in more than 80 countries, undergo two main developmental stages during its life cycle: the extracellular flagellated promastigote residing in the midget of the sandfly vector and the obligate intracellular amastigotes which multiply in the phagolysosome of infected macrophages within the mammalian host. The differentiation process from promastigote to amastigote allows Leishmania parasites to adapt to different environments and is essential for parasite proliferation and survival. However, the molecular events that regulate this process are not well understood. In higher eukaryotes, cellular proliferation, differentiation and function are governed largely by protein phosphorylation, which is controlled by protein kinases and phosphatases. The research described in this thesis has investigated the role of protein tyrosine phosphatase in controlling the differentiation and proliferation of the Leishmania pathogen in different life cycle stages, by analogy to what happens in higher eukaryotes. The focus was on protein phosphatases because in general, there are fewer phosphatases than kinases in the eukaryotic cells and therefore there is less likelihood of redundancy under conditions where it is possible to genetically develop mutants in phosphatase genes. By undertaking a predominantly genetic approach, we show the protein tyrosine phosphatase may play a role in L. donovani differentiation and is clearly required for parasite virulence as defined by survival in the mammalian host. The results from this study suggest that Leishmania PTP1 represents a potential drug target. However it is also revealed that the overall three dimensional structure of the active site of Leishmania PTP1 is very similar to the human PTP1B arguing that it may be difficult to develop parasite specific inhibitors. Taken together this study represents the first genetic analysis of a key regulatory gene in Leishmania, which establishes the foundation for future more biochemical approaches to study protein phosphorylation in Leishmania.</description><creator>Nascimento, Mirna G.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Involvement of tyrosine phosphatases in Leishmania differentiation and virulence</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Mirna G. Nascimento, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wp44m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30px87h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):36875</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>