<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:20:57Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):20500" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fx719n22p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, we examine the numerical simulation of transient viscoelastic flows with two moving free surfaces. A modified Galerkin finite element method is implemented to the two-dimensional non-steady motion of a viscoelastic fluid. The fluid is initially placed between two parallel plates and bounded by two straight free boundaries. In this Lagrangian finite element method, the spatial mesh deforms in time along with the moving free boundaries. The unknown shape of free surfaces is determined with the flow field u, v, $ tau$, p by the deformable finite element method, combined with a predictor-corrector scheme in an uncoupled fashion. In this study, the moving free surfaces and fluid motion of both Newtonian and non-Newtonian flows are investigated. The results include the influence of the time increment and the finite element mesh size, the effects of surface tension, fluid inertia and elasticity.</description><creator>Mao, Wenqun</creator><contributor>Khayat, Roger E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Numerical simulation of transient viscoelastic flows with two free surfaces</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/707958605.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719n22p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085m04s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>DNA profiles have become an extremely important tool in forensic investigations, and a match between a suspect and a crime scene specimen is highly incriminating. Presentation of this evidence in court, however, requires a statistical interpretation, one which reflects the uncertainty in the results due to measurement imprecision and sampling variability. No consensus has been reached about how to quantify this uncertainty, and the literature to date is lacking an objective review of possible methods. This thesis provides a survey of approaches to statistical analysis of DNA profile data currently in use, as well as proposed methods which seem promising. A comparison of frequentist and Bayesian approaches is made, as well as a careful examination of the assumptions required for each method.</description><creator>McClelland, Robyn L. (Robyn Leagh)</creator><contributor>Wolfson, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Statistics.</subject><title>Statistical analysis of DNA profiles</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h040d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085m04s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rf55z872k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Calcite overgrowths were precipitated from artificial seawater at 25$ sp circ$C on synthetic calcite seeds using a chemo-stat precipitation technique to investigate the influence of the $P sb{CO sb2}$ on magnesium incorporation. Powder X-ray diffraction (APXRD) analyses of the overgrowths indicate that the amount of MgCO$ sb3$ incorporated during precipitation is independent of the $P sb{CO sb2}$ over 4 orders of magnitude (10$ sp{-0.5}$ to 10$ sp{-4.6}$atm). The magnesium content of the overgrowths estimated from mass balance calculations of carbonate alkalinity of the reacting solutions ($ Delta$Ac) and flame spectrophotometric (AAS) analyses of the reacted solids yield similar results away from the extremes of $P sb{CO sb2}$ investigated in this study. These results contrast with those obtained from previous investigations and indicate that variations in the composition of magnesium calcite cements during the Phanerozoic cannot be explained solely on the basis of atmospheric $P sb{CO sb2}$ excursions. The concentration of sulfate and sodium in the overgrowths, however, appears to correlate with variations in $P sb{CO sb2}$. In a separate set of experiments, using the same precipitation technique, the influence of a biogenic seed material on the composition and mineralogy of overgrowths was investigated. The mineralogy of these precipitates was characterized by APXRD and Guinier-Hagg film x-ray diffraction. Overgrowths of aragonite and a high Mg-calcite (16.7 mole % MgCO$ sb3$) were precipitated from artificial seawater on crushed interambulacral shells of the sea urchin Diadema at a $P sb{CO sb2}$ of 10$ sp{-2.5}$ atm over a range of saturation states ($ Omega sb{ rm calcite}$ = 6.0 to 11.6). When compared to results of the previous study, it was not possible to determine unequivocally if the difference in composition and mineralogy of the overgrowths resulted from the influence of either the structure of the seed material or residual skeletal matrix organic manner. Transmission and scanning electron micrographs of solid overgrowths and substrates from the two series of experiments provide physical evidence of the existence and morphology of the precipitates.</description><creator>Hartley, George</creator><contributor>Mucci, Alfonso (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Geochemistry.</subject><title>The influence of the partial pressure of carbon dioxide and substrate on the composition and mineralogy of carbonate overgrowths precipitated from seawater /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fc55s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55z872k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mw11s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Considerable progress has been made in the past decades on the life cycle of rapidly deepening winter cyclones. However, little attention has been paid to the roles of mesoscale convective systems (MCSs) in extratropical cyclogenesis that occurs within weak baroclinic environments. In this thesis, the impact of an MCS on the subsequent surface cyclogenesis is investigated, using a 36-h three-dimensional, high-resolution simulations of the famous 10-12 June squall line that occurred during PRE-STORM. The model simulates remarkably well the initiation of the squall line, numerous mesoscale surface pressure perturbations and midlevel circulation structures during the mature stage, and the subsequent surface cyclogenesis after the dissipation of the system. It is found that the squall line is initiated ahead of a weak surface front with the aid of baroclinic forcing. Once initiated, the squall system is more or less driven by the interaction of convectively generated circulations with the potential unstable environment ahead. The baroclinic forcing only provides a favorable environment for the evolution of the squall system. As the squall system rapidly intensifies and accelerates eastward, it enhances the larger-scale baroclinicity and produces a phase-lag between the pressure and thermal waves so that the baroclinic environment is more favorable for surface cyclogenesis. To isolate the roles of moist convection in the surface cyclogenesis, a "moist" and a "dry" simulation are compared. It is found that in the absence of moist convection the model could also produce a surface cyclone, but with much weaker intensity, much smaller extent and slower displacement. The effects of moist convection are shown not only to increase the upper-level and decrease the lower-level height of isobaric surfaces, but also to condition the baroclinic environment by increasing the phase lag between the pressure and thermal waves and enhancing the large-scale baroclinicity.</description><creator>Harvey, Richard</creator><contributor>Zhang, Da-Lin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>A numerical study of the impact of an intense squall system on surface cyclogenesis /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bv49c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mw11s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:np193988w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The problem of reduced appetite in ruminants fed silages persists but the factors responsible for reduced intake of silage have not been elucidated. This study was conducted with the objective of testing the hypothesis that ammonia loading in ruminants could suppress appetite. In a 5 x 5 latin square design, sheep were fed alfalfa silage (S), fresh alfalfa (FA), and FA with added equimolar amounts (450 mmol. kg$ sp{-1}$ feed DM) of NH$ sb4$Cl, NH$ sb4$HCO$ sb3$ and urea; the latter was infused directly into the rumen. The silage had a DM content of 33.1%, pH 4.4, and a lactic acid content of 4.3% of DM. Unfermented herbage had a pH of 5.5 and lactic acid content of 0.2% of DM. Digestibility of organic matter (OMD) exceeded 70% for both S and FA. Organic matter intake (OMI), digestible organic matter intake (DOMI), concentration of rumen NH$ sb3$, rumen pH, osmolality and volatile fatty acids (VFAs) did not differ (P $&gt;$ 0.05) among treatment groups. The lack of differences among treatments may have been as a result of a failure to accentuate qualitative and quantitative differences between the FA and S and to raise ammonia in the rumen and peripheral blood to levels that could alter appetite.</description><creator>Harrison, Harry</creator><contributor>Phillip, L. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Ammonia in animal nutrition.</subject><subject>Lambs -- Feeding and feeds.</subject><subject>Alfalfa -- Silage.</subject><title>An evaluation of the role of ammonia load in the control of food intake by lambs fed fresh and ensiled alfalfa, (Medicago sativa) /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440t28v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193988w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8s45q9836</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One-dimensional formal groups were classified by W. Hill who showed in particular that one-dimensional formal groups are isomorphic over p-adic integers if and only if they have the same associated Eisenstein polynomial. This result can be applied to show that the torsion points on any supersingular elliptic curve over the field of p-adic numbers generate abelian extensions of the unramified quadradic extension of the field. The theorem cannot be extended to classify formal groups of higher dimension. Counterexamples will be provided both in the case of two-dimensional formal groups and when the formal group is defined over an extension of the p-adic integers. Constructions and classifications of higher dimensional formal groups due to T. Nakamura and M. Hazewinkel will also be explored.</description><creator>Hofmann, Natalie</creator><contributor>Dummit, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Hill's theorem of formal groups : applications, generalizations and counterexamples</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn3012174.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45q9836</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qq44n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We examined how fast- and slow-growing families (based on height at 10 years) of Pinus banksiana Lamb. are affected by a climate altered by CO$ sb2$ during their first growing season. Our primary objective was to evaluate the possibility that genotypes performing best under present conditions may not necessarily do best under projected warmer climate. Seedlings were grown for six months in two climatic environments (350 $ mu$L/L CO$ sb2$ x present temperatures and 700 $ mu$L/L CO$ sb2$ x 4$ sp circ$C warmer temperatures) and with 100 ppm and 5 ppm nitrogen. The CO$ sb2$T$ sp circ$ environment had a significant effect on most biomass components of seedlings and water-use efficiency but not on height and other growth variables. The nitrogen fertilization was generally the most significant effect of the treatments for most growth variables. All the families responded in a similar way to variations in the growing environments except for WUE. Family differences were more important for measurements of height and growth variables than for biomass components. The architecture of seedlings was also highly variable between families. Norm of reaction graphs were built for several growth variables to outline which families were overall most successful in an enriched CO$ sb2$T$ sp circ$ environment. Of the 15 families studied, four of them were classified as most successful in a projected high CO$ sb2$T$ sp circ$ climate.</description><creator>Cantin, Danielle, 1967-</creator><contributor>Potvin, Catherine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Jack pine -- Growth.</subject><subject>Atmospheric carbon dioxide -- Environmental aspects.</subject><subject>Global warming -- Environmental aspects.</subject><subject>Greenhouse effect, Atmospheric -- Environmental aspects.</subject><title>Response of Pinus banksiana (Lamb.) families to a global change environment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848r50m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qq44n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zv25h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A number of T-cell membrane molecules influence the outcome of antigen recognition by TCR/CD3 complex. CD4, by virtue of its non-covalent association with the protein tyrosine kinase lck has the capacity to enhance TCR$ alpha beta$ signalling. The extracellular domain of CD4 interacts with monomorphic determinants of Major Histocompatibility complex class-II molecules such that antigen presented in association with MHC class-II to CD4$ sp+$ T-cells results in the coaggregation of CD4 and TCR/CD3, thus juxtaposing lck and the antigen-receptor complex. Anti-CD4 antibodies abrogate both antigen and anti-TCR-induced T-cell activation. Studies using antigen specific T-cell clones that express either no CD4, wild type CD4 or mutated CD4 that cannot associate with lck (Db CYS) indicate that CD4 sequesters the majority of cellular lck and when not coaggregated with TCR/CD3, prevents the generation of prerequisite signals. Results presented in this thesis indicate that while CD4-associated lck is providing prerequisite signals for TCR/CD3 signalling, the contribution of CD4 must be more than simply providing a shuttle for lck. Specifically, anti-CD4 inhibits the antigen response of Db CYS CD4-expressing clones. This result cannot be accounted for either by CD4 sequestration of lck, or reduction of avidity of the interaction between the T-cell and the antigen presenting cell, since CD4$ sp-$ variants exhibit an antigen response comparable to that of CD4$ sp+$ variants. Rather, they suggest a novel role for the ectodomain of CD4 in antigen-induced T-cell activation.</description><creator>Bonnard, Madeleine</creator><contributor>Julius, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>A novel role for CD4 in antigen-mediated T-cell activation /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150k13w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zv25h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322f127</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study of radiative transfer in multifractal clouds is of great interest, an important application being to Global Climate Models. In this work we develop a formalism analogous to the multifractal singularity formalism for understanding photon scattering statistics in radiative transfer in multifractals, and test the results numerically on lognormal multifractals. Although the results are only exactly valid in the thick cloud limit, the approximation is found to be quite accurate down to optical thickness of $ tau approx1$-10, so the results may be widely applicable. Furthermore we show the possibility of "renormalizing" the multifractal by replacing it with a near equivalent homogeneous medium but with a "renormalized" optical thickness $ tau sp{1/(1+C sb1)}$ where C$ sb1$ is the codimension of the mean singularity of the cloud. We argue that this approximation is likely to continue to be valid for multiple scattering, and is also compatible with recent results for diffusion on multifractals. Finally we analyze cloud liquid water content data and estimate the universal multifractal indices. We find that the scaling is respected over the whole range 5m-330km and that the cloud can in fact be reasonably described by a lognormal multifractal.</description><creator>Brösamlen, Gerd</creator><contributor>Lovejoy, Shaun (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>Radiative transfer in lognormal multifractal clouds and analysis of cloud liquid water data</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nc12g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322f127</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vd66w079s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chipmunk antipredator calls were examined during the summers of 1990 and 1991. The structural characteristics of the three calls, chipping, chucking and the trill, were obtained through taped recordings and sonagraphic analysis. Behavioural observations indicated that chucking by choruses of individuals occurs in the presence of aerial predators, chipping by choruses of individuals occurs in the presence of terrestrial predators and the trill is given by single individuals when fleeing from predators. Experiments were carried out to determine the function of the trill and chipping. Demographic and contextual effects indicate that the trill is in part a call which functions to warn kin but may also indicate to conspecifics that the caller has escaped into a refuge. An experiment with a tethered cat concluded that chipping is likely to function to deter predators from hunting in the area. This is done through vocal mobbing by several individuals whose home ranges overlap.</description><creator>Burke da Silva, Karen</creator><contributor>Kramer, D. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Eastern chipmunk -- Behavior.</subject><subject>Predation (Biology)</subject><subject>Eastern chipmunk -- Vocalization.</subject><title>Antipredator calling by the eastern chipmunk, Tamius striatus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430568c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w079s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k643b2106</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Luigi Pirandello's two short stories La verita and Certi obblighi and the play derived from them Il berretto a sonagli seem to be, at least on the surface, about adultery. The three male protagonists' dilemmas come about as a result of their wives' sexual transgressions, which consequently impose certain "obligations" upon them. The themes of adultery and betrayal, however, are merely surface elements, used to explore the theatrical nature of identity and of all social experience. Specifically, the three works show how role-playing-within-roles safeguards the identity of the betrayed husbands, by protecting them from social humiliation. Since all Pirandellian characters role-play, and as a consequence portray and assume multiple identities, this thesis examines the function and significance of this technique in both narrative and theatrical contexts. It attempts to show that while the device is a feature common to all three works, it is in the dramatic adaptation that role-playing in relation to identity acquires its more visible and effective treatment.</description><creator>Mastrogianakos, John</creator><contributor>Kroha, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Adultery in literature.</subject><subject>Pirandello, Luigi, 1867-1936. Berretto a sonagli.</subject><subject>Pirandello, Luigi, 1867-1936 -- Characters -- Men.</subject><title>The role-within-the-role : two Pirandellian novellas and their dramatic adaptation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w032390n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b2106</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Italian</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj1392788</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Despite the social reforms led by Bourguiba during his presidency, the state of Tunisia, as modern as it was, gave way to a thriving Islamic revival movement to such an extent that during the '80s their activities disturbed Tunisia's political life. The years between 1986 and 1991 were marked by open conflict between the regime and the Islamists. Since this conflict was an ideological one, the population was influenced only marginally by its outcome. Perhaps the concerns of the Islamists were not involved enough with those of most Tunisians. An analytical approach to Tunisian Islamist thought reveals that political matters, inspired by Islamic teachings as well as secular ones, formed its ideological basis. The ideological needs of the population were not a priority. Being easily influenced by mainstream thought, Tunisians were easily conditioned by the state and the mass media to reject any form of Islamism.</description><creator>Lozowy, Dominique</creator><date>1993</date><subject>Islam -- Tunisia</subject><subject>Islam and politics -- Tunisia</subject><title>L'impact socio-politique du discours islamiste en Tunisie</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722h9741.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj1392788</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vx021g109</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Textual repetitions abound in verses of the Seven Penitential Psalms of Lassus and this research attempts to discover their function. A total of one hundred and thirty-two verses were analyzed. The results of this investigation exhibit numerous mathematical figures underlying the entire work's structure, and the influence of repetitions is conspicuous in each figure's organization. Moreover, this study shows, in a smaller measure, the mutual influence between form and text expression. A detailed method of calculation is also provided which may eventually be applied to other works of the repertoire of the sixteenth century.</description><creator>Lessoil-Daelman, Marcelle</creator><contributor>Schubert, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Lasso, Orlando di, 1532-1594. Psalmi Davidis poenitentiales</subject><title>Rôle des répétitions textuelles dans les Psaumes de la Pénitence de LASSUS</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t720j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021g109</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801ph123</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is concerned with the Shadhiliyya Sufi Order as it is found in Tunis. The work discusses the development of the Order and the role of its central institution (the zawiya) in a modern setting. The largest part deals with the ritual prayer of the Order--in particular the ahzab (s.hizb). In dealing with both the ritual/experiential context, and the literary content and form of the prayers, the intention is to bring to light the significance of the ahzab, and to begin to accord them their proper place in the study of Sufism. Research is based on historical sources, manuals and prayer books of the Shadhiliyya, and the personal observations of the author. A translation of the Arabic "Hizb al-Kabir" is given in the appendix.</description><creator>McGregor, Richard J. A.</creator><contributor>Ormsby, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Sufism -- Tunisia -- Tunis</subject><subject>Shādhilīyah</subject><title>The Shādhiliyya in Tunis : prayer and brotherhood</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr171z06z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801ph123</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306t0153</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The role of teaching experience has been acknowledged in the development of pedagogical expertise, however, past research has failed to specify the relationship between experience and expertise. The ill-defined nature of the teaching task has led researchers to inadequately define pedagogical expertise directly in terms of years of teaching experience. Moreover, the literature on pedagogical expertise is primarily based on data from school teachers, who typically are not subject matter experts in the topics they teach. This study attempted to establish the differences and similarities between experienced and inexperienced university professors in the planning and delivery of teaching and the extent to which these activities and processes resembled expert characteristics. Indices of teaching effectiveness were derived from both theoretical and empirical sources and applied to the practices of 11 university professors, ranging in experience from 1 to 30 years. After the conduction of a lecture, subjects were interviewed and asked to elaborate on planning decisions made prior to teaching and to trace the events of the class. Protocols were then analyzed for the presence of characteristics of pedagogical expertise as defined above. Important differences were revealed between the teaching practices of experienced and less experienced professors which involved: (1) automaticity of activities, (2) teaching a lecture as part of the global task of teaching, (3) knowledge integration, (4) flexibility of plan implementation, (5) use of planning notes, (6) time management, and (7) reflections. Important group similarities were also revealed. Implications for the development of pedagogical expertise are discussed.</description><creator>Gendron, Marie-Josée</creator><contributor>Saroyan, Alenoush (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Teaching</subject><subject>Lesson planning.</subject><title>An investigation of pedagogical expertise in the planning practices of professors with varying degrees of teaching experience /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nm355.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t0153</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1544bq194</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In recent years, very few Japanese women have entered the fields of science and technology despite the fact that Japan has specialized in these areas. This study attempts to develop a preliminary profile of those women who have despite odds, made careers in science. Generally, these women were found to come from families of high socio-economic status. These families had socialization patterns typical of middle and upper classes which included the teaching of universal, rather than of local, values, little sex-stereotyping, non-arbitrary verbal communication between generations, and field-independent views. Families of respondents valued education and were interested in science. In many cases they included persons who were causal and creative. Familial males shared their activities with respondents and familial females modelled an independent, nonpassive role. Respondents often had their first positive science experience within the family, but there were also teachers, primarily at secondary and university levels, who encouraged them. In addition, critical experiences and role models also influenced them. Role models were sometimes persons the respondents knew; in other cases, they were literary figures. In spite of frustrations and some gender discrimination in the workplace, respondents for the most part are happy to have chosen science as their profession.</description><creator>Ghezzi, Beverley J.</creator><contributor>Ghosh, Ratna (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Women scientists -- Japan</subject><subject>Women in science -- Japan</subject><title>Women and science in Japan</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kk459.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1544bq194</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tm91d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Residential change is a pervasive condition of North American society. In a lifetime, a person may go through many decisive and interrelated changes in occupational status, family situation and dwelling-place. This research tests the relationships among three major processes: residential mobility, social mobility, and family formation in Montreal between 1861 and 1901. Using sample households from three cultural communities: French Canadian, Irish Catholic, and British Protestants, it was determined that the majority of households were highly mobile, yet remained within a compact geographical area. Mobility is seen as a response to a changing set of needs and opportunities, and families facilitated adjustment through extensive networks of kinship and neighbouring. Studies of present-day household mobility provide a well-developed set of theories, on which several hypotheses were based. Multivariate regression analysis was performed using the binomial logit model to assess the relative effects of ethnicity, tenure, occupational status, age, household size, marital status and rent, on rates of household persistence.</description><creator>Gilliland, Jason A.</creator><contributor>Olson, Sherry (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Montréal (Québec) -- Social conditions</subject><subject>Residential mobility -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History -- 19th century</subject><title>Residential mobility in Montreal, 1861-1901</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mn10w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tm91d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dn26j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the semi-autobiographical work of Maria Beig in the context of traditional and contemporary regional literature. It attempts to do justice to her work as a whole. The style and content of her work are discussed with reference to topics of literary theory relating to regional literature, such as the village novella, or anti-idyllic elements, to mention only those most discussed. A further emphasis of the thesis is the question of academic reception of regional literature, in relation to the genre generally and to Maria Beig's work--that of a "poeta non docta"--in particular. Finally there is a (short) discussion of "women's issues". Such a discussion cannot be omitted, as Maria Beig is a modern woman writer whose main characters are almost exclusively feminine, and whose texts often raise questions concerned with gender. Included in the appendix are a transcript of an interview between Maria Beig and the author, and a self-written life story which Maria Beig made available to the author. These represent an indispensable aid to the reading and understanding of the thesis.</description><creator>Galbraith, Katharina S.</creator><contributor>Schmidt, Joseph (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Beig, Maria, 1920- -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>Maria Beig : neue Heimatliteratur zwischen Nostalgie und Zuversicht</title><language>ger</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085m06b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dn26j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of German</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p0967887</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A study has been made of the xerographic properties of amorphous selenium doped with chlorine at concentrations below 100 parts per million (ppm) by weight. The sample consisted, in each case, of an aluminum plate with a thin deposited r.f. sputtered aluminum oxide film, on which a 50 micrometer layer of amorphous selenium was deposited by evaporation, with a substrate temperature of 50$ sp circ$C. It was found that the chlorine decreased the acceptance voltage following corona charging, increased the dark decay rate and decreased the residual voltage after illumination discharge. The changes were such as to be beneficial xerographically for small additions of chlorine to the selenium in the ppm range. Analysis of the time derivative of the dark decay voltage indicated that depletion discharge was the dominant process in the decrease of dark decay voltage with time and a modified relation was introduced to describe the increase of bulk space charge density with time, arising from thermal excitation of holes from deep discrete centres in the photoreceptor. This analysis indicated a decrease of the release time of the holes with increase of chlorine content, whereas an observed decrease of single cycle and cycled-up residual voltages with increased chlorine indicated an increase of hole capture time from their relevant trapping centres. Capacitance and incremental resistance measurements on the aluminum oxide blocking layers indicated higher resistance in films deposited by r.f. sputtering than by d.c. reactive sputtering on aluminum substrates. However, no difference in xerographic performance could be detected between the two sputtering methods. Oxide layers were also deposited on nickel and gold substrates by r.f. sputtering.</description><creator>Wang, Yan, 1961-</creator><contributor>Champness, C. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Xerographic properties of chlorine-doped amorphous selenium</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k3441.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p0967887</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42n8876</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis focuses on the routing, power control and channel allocation of Packet Radio Network (PRnet) with multiple channels. The Nearest Forward with Progress (NFP) routing policy is known to achieve higher throughput in the single channel setting than the Most Forward with Progress (MFP) strategy. This observation motivates our work on the variant of the Shacham/King model in which MFR is replaced by NFP in a multi-channel case. The resulting network shows that the superiority of NFP relative to MFP persists. Another way to improve network performance is to control the network topology by restricting the set of possible paths. Pairwise Channel Assignment (PCA), which assigns the different channels to the restricted paths, is modified so as to expand its applicability and reduce its computational burden without significant loss of throughput. The performance evaluations are based on a combination of analysis and simulation.</description><creator>Wong, Chung Kit</creator><contributor>Morgera, Salvatore (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Resource allocation for multihop packet radio networks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xg030.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42n8876</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mj875</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A mathematical model that predicts the biomass, limiting substrate, and dissolved oxygen concentrations during the periodic steady state operation of Self-Cycling Fermentation (SCF) was created. The model was used to develop a computer simulation for SCF. To validate the model, predictions from the computer simulation were compared to experimental SCF laboratory data using the bacteria A. calcoaceticus with ethanol as the limiting substrate. The successful fit of the model to the laboratory data supports the hypotheses that, at periodic steady state, cells in the SCF are always growing exponentially, biomass growth is proportional to both the limiting substrate depletion and to oxygen consumption by the organism, and k$ sb{ rm L}$a and the dissolved oxygen level at 100% saturation are constant. The SCF model predicts that SCF will stabilize into a periodic steady state for all emptying/refilling fractions greater than 0 but less than 1.</description><creator>Wincure, Benjamin, 1966-</creator><contributor>Cooper, D. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Rey, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Mathematical modelling of self-cycling fermentation (SCF)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vk89r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mj875</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k643b211g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Self-cycling fermentation is a new technique used to cultivate synchronous populations of cells. This work used the technique in the production of citric acid from a strain of Candida lipolytica. Application of this technique resulted in extremely stable, reproducible patterns of growth and induced a high level of cell synchrony. Synchrony was maintained even throughout long periods of extended nutrient starvation. Thus, self-cycling fermentations can be operated with cycle times significantly longer than the doubling time of the microorganism. Use of this technique led to a full order of magnitude increase in the specific biomass production rate compared to literature values. This biomass was found to be suitable for the production of citric acid in a second stage reactor. Although this preliminary work with the second stage reactor was not optimized, the specific citric acid production rate obtained was comparable to rates found in the literature.</description><creator>Wentworth, Stephen</creator><contributor>Cooper, D. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Citric acid production using the self-cycling fermentation technique</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mq70h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b211g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zb94r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Majerus, Yvette Viviane.</creator><date>1971</date><subject>Education -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Lartigue, Jean-Jacques, 1777-1840.</subject><subject>Bourget, Ignace, 1799-1885.</subject><title>L'éducation dans le diocèse de Montréal d'après la correspondance de ses deux premiers évéques, Mgr. J.J. Lartigne et Mgr. I. Bourget, de 1820 à 1867.</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483k191.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zb94r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wm117p83g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Boyarsky, Abraham Joseph.</creator><date>1970</date><subject>Measure theory</subject><subject>Control theory</subject><subject>Stochastic processes</subject><subject>Metric spaces</subject><title>Control and stability theory in the space of measures.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vc28n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117p83g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b7063</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:44:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Hepler, Norva Kay.</creator><date>1971</date><subject>Visual perception</subject><title>Motion-picture color aftereffects : a lasting modification of perception.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pt61r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b7063</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):20525</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>