<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:56:35Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):26800" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z903017v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The perioperative use of cardiac medical therapy (aspirin, angiotensin-converting-enzyme (ACE) inhibitors, lipid lowering agents (including statins), and beta-blockers) holds the potential to improve clinical outcomes among patients undergoing coronary artery bypass graft surgery (CABG). These medications have been shown to be efficacious in reducing adverse events in a small number of trials involving non-cardiac surgery patients. However, their use has not been closely examined among CABG patients. We performed a systematic review of the literature in which we identified all studies that examined the perioperative use of cardiac medical therapy among CABG patients. We also examined the use and effectiveness of these medications using a cohort of 2,389 consecutive CABG patients. We found that in-hospital medication use was low for all 4 medication classes. We also found a trend indicating an association between perioperative beta-blocker and statin use and a decrease in in-hospital mortality or non-fatal cardiac complications. Increasing perioperative cardiac medical therapy use may therefore lead to improved clinical outcomes among patients undergoing CABG.</description><creator>Filion, Kristian B., 1980-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Use and effectiveness of perioperative cardiac medical therapy among patients undergoing coronary artery bypass graft surgery</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Kristian B. Filion, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hj32t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903017v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j130p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis describes a new computational method for a comparative genomics approach called phylogenetic footprinting, for predicting transcription factor binding sites in DNA sequences. The traditional approaches have been divided into two main families: alignment-based and motif-based approaches. In this thesis, we present a new approach for phylogenetic footprinting that takes advantage of the strengths of the two approaches, while correcting their weaknesses. Our new method uses alignment information when it is available and reliable as the guide for the identification of conserved regions. We formalize the ideas into a new algorithmic problem, the Alignment-Compatible Substring Parsimony Problem, where we ask to discover short substrings that are phylogenetically conserved and whose positions are compatible with a set of local alignments. This problem can be solved with a practical, fast and exact algorithm. Our new approach yields a significant reduction of the false-positive rate in the identification of conserved regions, producing predictions that are more accurate than both alignment-based and motif-based approaches. Our program can also obtain a more sensitive search by reducing the stringency of the search criteria, while keeping improved specificity.</description><creator>Fang, Fei, 1983-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Algorithms for phylogenetic footprinting in semi-alignable sequences</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Fei Fang, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gn476.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j130p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z316q180v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Brain image segmentation is an active research in computer image analysis. The challenge lies in the fact that the brain anatomy is not identical for all normal subjects let alone subjects with abnormal tissue. In this thesis, we explain the research we have implemented to extract the brain from T1-weighted MRI images, and then segment the brain into the three prominent compartments (i.e. the cerebellum and the two hemispheres of the cerebrum). The brain extraction is implemented using morphological operations after thresholding. The brain segmentation, however, is implemented in two separate steps. The first step segments the two hemispheres by approximating the midsagittal surface using mainly Radon transform. The second step segments the cerebellum using an atlas-based contour as an initial contour for the gradient vector flow active contour algorithm. Validation tests have been performed for the brain extraction and cerebellum segmentation methods.</description><creator>Ezzadeen, Hani.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Biophysics, Medical.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Extraction and segmentation of MRI brain images</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Hani Ezzadeen, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rd79k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q180v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nh426</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The term nowcast is used to emphasize that a forecast is being produced for very short lead times, typically 0 to 6 h. Most nowcasting systems use weather radar as the primary tool for forecasting. Modern techniques use computer algorithms to compute these short-term forecasts, and have been shown to have more skill than human forecasters or numerical models alone. Applications of nowcasting span across many industries, with aviation being of particular importance. The essence of nowcasting can be summarized in two steps: (1) obtain a motion estimate for an existing storm, and (2) advect the current storm using the derived motion estimate. Since the inception of weather radar, nowcasting methods have noticeably improved, particularly with respect to estimating storm motion. However, nowcasting is still largely based on Lagrangian persistence, where the forecast field (i.e. reflectivity) is held constant in the Lagrangian frame. This has been done principally because of the difficulties associated with forecasting storm growth and decay. In this paper, an attempt is made to incorporate storm growth and decay into the McGill Algorithm for Precipitation Nowcasting by Lagrangian Extrapolation (MAPLE), by using mesoscale parameters to physically constrain the evolution storm systems. The analysis is conducted on a continental scale, over the contiguous United States. The parameters selected for study were equivalent potential temperature (thetae) and convective available potential energy (CAPE), because they have been shown by theory and observations to be directly related to the intensity and duration of storm systems (Zawadzki and Ro 1978 and Zawadzki et al. 1981, 1994). While past studies were based on observations on a local scale, valid on a day-to-day basis, the current work is applied to a continental scale, on an hour-by-hour basis. Results of the study show little promise for application to nowcasting. No correlations were found between various measures of storm growth/decay and the mesoscale parameters. Several explanations for the results are proposed, which include poor data quality, insufficient sample size and the possibility of a land-surface feedback.</description><creator>Czernkovich, Nick.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Oceanography.</subject><subject>Atmospheric Sciences.</subject><title>An attempt to incorporate growth and decay into MAPLE nowcasts /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Nick Czernkovich, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55mc37r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nh426</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wc97m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In upcoming decades, the conservation and sustainable use of coastal and marine resources will become a major political and environmental challenge, as two-thirds of the world's population lives in coastal zones. The issue will likely become more problematic in developing countries, where an important number of coastal inhabitants still rely on marginal extractive activities such as fishing, farming and cattle ranching for subsistence, and where the rural poor's demand for development often lead to unsustainable extractive practices. Thus, innovative solutions need to be developed to ensure the long-term conservation and sound management of marine and coastal resources. This Masters thesis addresses the case of Coiba National Park, a marine protected area located in the Gulf of Chiriqui, Panama, and its relationship with coastal fishing and farming communities located at its outskirt. Particularly, this thesis aims to discover the drivers that pushed an important number of coastal agro-pastoralists of Coiba National Park's buffer zone to switch to artisanal fishing over the past three decades, and to determine the social, economic, and environmental impacts that resulted from that switch. In addition, this thesis analyses the relationship between Coiba National Park's authorities and buffer zone communities, and how this relationship has evolved over the years as more and more resource-users exploit the marine resources of the park. Finally, this work analyses Coiba National Park's current management strategy, how park authorities have been able to adapt their planning and management activities over the years, and explores alternatives to improve Coiba National Park's management strategy so that it can better adapt to the ever changing social, economic, and environmental conditions in which Coiba National Park's buffer zone operates.</description><creator>Crête, Philippe.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Traditional farming -- Panama -- Chiriquí Gulf Region.</subject><subject>Marine parks and reserves -- Panama -- Management.</subject><subject>Small-scale fisheries -- Panama -- Chiriquí Gulf.</subject><subject>Fishers -- Panama -- Chiriquí Gulf Region -- Economic conditions -- 20th century.</subject><title>Agro-pastoralists turned fishermen : socio-economic and environmental changes in the buffer zone of Coiba National Park, Panama</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Philippe Crête, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720d088.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wc97m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hc49s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During 30 years of worldwide use, measles virus (MV) vaccination has brought about a dramatic reduction in the morbidity and mortality due to measles infection. In spite of extensive evidence confirming the safety of the vaccine, concerns have recently been raised about possible links with inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) and autism spectrum disorder (ASD). The publication of this work, which arose principally from a research group in the United Kingdom, has caused a drop in vaccination uptake and subsequently resulted in re-establishment of endemic measles in various parts of Europe. In this thesis, we sought to replicate the real-time reverse transcription-polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) assays designed by this research group to determine whether MV genes were present in intestinal samples from patients with Crohn's disease (CD), ulcerative colitis (UC) and non-IBD controls, as well as in PBMC specimens from children with ASD and developmentally healthy controls. We also developed a probe-based real-time RT-PCR assay to detect MV genes in these same samples. We found no evidence to support the contention that MV persists in individuals with IBD or ASD.</description><creator>D'Souza, Yasmin.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Virology.</subject><title>No evidence of persisting measles virus in specimens from patients with inflammatory bowel disease and autism spectrum disorder</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Yasmin D'Souza, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544bp430.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hc49s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289j30b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Given that a greater injury incidence has been shown for indoor versus outdoor running tracks, attention to mechanical differences in curve running is warranted. Hence, the main objective of this study was to compare knee and ankle kinematics of runners while running on an indoor track with a flat curve and a banked-curve in young elite runners. Six elite runners participated in the study. Knee and ankle kinematics were measured while the subjects ran on a flat curve and a 19% banked-curve. No significant differences were observed in left and right knee and ankle peak angular displacements between the two different curves. Angular displacements measured have demonstrated similar profiles to those presented in previous studies. However, significant differences were found in body lean angle between speeds but not between curve inclinations. In conclusion, the results suggest that curve inclination does not perturb lower limb kinematics for elite runners.</description><creator>De Garie, Luc.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><subject>Biology, Physiology.</subject><title>Effects of banked-curves on ankle and knee kinematics during running</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Luc De Garie, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128b20t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289j30b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s4655g99s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis deals with the problem of detecting binding sites in coding regions. A new comparative analysis method is developed by improving an existing method called COSMO. The inter-species sequence conservation observed in coding regions may be the result of two types of selective pressure: the selective pressure on the protein encoded and, sometimes, the selective pressure on the binding sites. To predict some region in coding regions as a binding site, one needs to make sure that the conservation observed in this region is not due to the selective pressure on the protein encoded. To achieve this, COSMO built a null model with only the selective pressure on the protein encoded and computed p-values for the observed conservation scores, conditional on the fixed set of amino acids observed at the leaves. It is believed, however, that the selective pressure on the protein assumed in COSMO is overly strong. Consequently, some interesting regions may be left undetected. In this thesis, a new method, COSMO-2, is developed to relax this assumption. The amino acids are first classified into a fixed number of overlapping functional classes by applying an expectation maximization algorithm on a protein database. Two probabilities for each gene position are then calculated: (i) the probability of observing a certain degree of conservation in the orthologous sequences generated under each class in the null model (i.e. the p-value of the observed conservation under each class); and (ii) the probability that the codon column associated with that gene position belongs to each class. The p-value of the observed conservation for each gene position is the sum of the products of the two probabilities for all classes. Regions with low p-values are identified as potential binding sites. Five sets of orthologous genes are analyzed using COSMO-2. The results show that COSMO-2 can detect the interesting regions identified by COSMO and can detect more interesting regions than COSMO in some cases.</description><creator>Chen, Hui, 1974-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><subject>Biology, Bioinformatics.</subject><title>Algorithms and statistics for the detection of binding sites in coding regions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Hui Chen, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tc299.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655g99s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sd11g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A cis-regulatory module (CRM) is a DNA region of a few hundred base pairs that consists of clustering of several transcription factor binding sites and regulates the expression of a nearby gene. This thesis presents a new computational approach to CRM detection. It is believed that tissue-specific CRMs tend to regulate nearby genes in a certain tissue and that they consist of binding sites for transcription factors (TFs) that are also expressed in that tissue. These facts allow us to make use of tissue-specific gene expression data to detect tissue-specific CRMs and improve the specificity of module prediction. We build a Bayesian network to integrate the sequence information about TF binding sites and the expression information about TFs and regulated genes. The network is then used to infer whether a given genomic region indeed has regulatory activity in a given tissue. A novel EM algorithm incorporating probability tree learning is proposed to train the Bayesian network in an unsupervised way. A new probability tree learning algorithm is developed to learn the conditional probability distribution for a variable in the network that has a large number of hidden variables as its parents. Our approach is evaluated using biological data, and the results show that it is able to correctly discriminate among human liver-specific modules, erythroid-specific modules, and negative-control regions, even though no prior knowledge about the TFs and the target genes is employed in our algorithm. In a genome-wide scale, our network is trained to identify tissue-specific CRMs in ten tissues. Some known tissue-specific modules are rediscovered, and a set of novel modules are predicted to be related with tissue-specific expression.</description><creator>Chen, Xiaoyu, 1974-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><subject>Biology, Bioinformatics.</subject><title>Computational detection of tissue-specific cis-regulatory modules</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Xiaoyu Chen, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zt57k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sd11g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17ct18s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Relational databases are a popular method for organizing and storing data. Unfortunately, many machine-learning techniques are unable to handle complex relational models. The Probabilistic Relational Model (PRM) is an extension of the Bayesian Network framework that can express relational structure as well as probabilistic dependencies. In this thesis, we significantly expand and improve an implementation of PRMs that allows defining conditional probability distributions over discrete and continuous variables. The thesis uses as starting point an implementation that has various problems, and runs very slowly when using a database management system (DBMS) as storage. This thesis discusses alternative algorithms that improve the accuracy of the learned models, the computing performance, and correct the inference problems of the existing implementation. The focus is on techniques used to reduce the running time of the algorithms when the implementation is used to learn from data stored on a DBMS. The thesis provides experimental results using this package on both synthetic and real data sets.</description><creator>Chen, Yu, 1979-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Data mining relational databases with probabilistic relational models</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Yu Chen, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5999n366z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17ct18s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gk031</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Iron is indispensable for cell proliferation and growth, but it is potentially toxic when present in excess. Two homologous iron regulatory proteins (IRP1 and IRP2) control cellular iron homeostasis by binding to iron-responsive elements (IREs) and post-transcriptionally coordinating the expression of transferrin receptor 1 (TfR1) and ferritin. We have previously reported that overexpression of IRP1C437S, a constitutive IRP1 mutant, inhibits H1299 human lung cancer cell growth in vitro. In current study, we investigated the potential role of IRPs in tumor growth in vivo by the injection of H1299 cells expressing IRP1C437S or wild type IRP1 or IRP2 into the flanks of nude mice. We observed that overexpression of IRP1C437S or wild type IRP1 suppressed tumor growth in nude mice. In contrast, surprisingly, overexpression of wild type IRP2 promoted tumor growth. Our results suggest that IRP1 may exhibit tumor suppressor activity, while IRP2 may have oncogenic activity.</description><creator>Chen, Guohua, 1966-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>A potential role of iron-regulatory proteins in tumor growth /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Guohua Chen, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k5225.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gk031</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860724f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Apoptosis is a genetically programmed form of cell death that plays an essential role in the tissue homeostasis and development of multicellular organisms. Apoptotic cellular suicide is tightly regulated by both pro-apoptotic and anti-apoptotic proteins. The dysregulation of apoptosis manifests in a number of pathologies, such as cancer, autoimmunity and neurodegenerative disorders. Thus further insight into these mechanisms may provide a basis for therapeutic opportunities. The primary executioners of cell death belong to a family of cysteine proteases known as caspases that cleave numerous substrates resulting in the morphological characteristics of apoptosis. Caspase8 is the apical caspase involved in death receptor-mediated apoptosis, which upon activation can cleave downstream executioner caspases-3, -6, and -7. Interestingly, in humans, a deficiency in caspase-8 impairs lymphocyte activation and proliferation. Apoptotic signaling can be effectively blocked by Inhibitor of Apoptosis Proteins (IAPs), of which the X-linked Inhibitor of Apoptosis Protein (XIAP) is the best characterized. XIAP exerts it's anti-apoptotic effect by binding to caspases-3, -7, and -9, thus preventing their activation. In an attempt to characterize the function of caspase-8 in stress-induced apoptosis, RNA interference was employed to effectively and functionally silence caspase-8 in HeLa cells. Cells transfected with caspase-8-specifc siRNA were subsequently treated with the drug staurosporine, a general protein kinase inhibitor known to induce apoptosis via cell stress. Counter-intuitively, cells in which caspase-8 had been silenced exhibited increased cell death in response to staurosporine. I have shown that the increased sensitization to death in these cells may be ascribed to a concomitant decrease in XIAP protein levels due to increased degradation via the proteasome. The ability of caspase-8 to maintain the protein levels of XIAP was not a function of caspase-8's enzymatic activity, but may be attributed to a non-enzyme function of the protein. Collectively, these findings suggest that caspase-8 may provide a pro-survival signal through the maintenance and stabilization of an anti-apoptotic protein, XIAP, in response to staurosporine-induced apoptosis, and that this anti-apoptotic function of caspase-8 is irrespective of it's pro-apoptotic enzymatic activity.</description><creator>Bueler, Stephanie A.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>A pro-survival function of caspase-8 in stress-induced apoptosis /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Stephanie A. Bueler, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s044x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860724f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33rw98q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Neointima formation is the major limitation to the use of percutaneous transluminal coronary angioplasty in the treatment of coronary artery disease. It is caused by the proliferation and migration of vascular smooth muscle cells (SMCs) from the media into the intima resulting in narrowing of the luminal diameter. The ELN -/- mouse exhibits a similar phenotype in which overproliferation of SMCs into the lumen leads to obstruction of the aorta causing death at post-natal day 2.5. Based on this observation, a DNA microarray analysis of the ELN -/- aorta was conducted to identify candidate genes responsible for SMC proliferation and migration. Through this process thrombospondin-1 (TSP-1), an extracellular matrix glycoprotein implicated in SMC proliferation and migration, was identified as one of the genes upregulated in the ELN -/- aorta. This result was verified through RT-PCR and immunohistochemistry. To determine the role of TSP-1 in neointima formation, a mouse microsurgery model to simulate balloon angioplasty using the femoral artery was established. This procedure was then performed on TSP-1 +/+ and -/- mice. No difference in the extent of neointima formation was observed 28 days following surgery. However, extensive thrombus formation was observed in the TSP-1 -/- vessel, an unexpected finding of the original study. These results suggest that although TSP-1 is not involved in proliferation and migration of SMCs following balloon angioplasty, it is a critical factor in the regulation of thrombus growth following vascular injury.</description><creator>Budhani, Faisal.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>The role of thrombospondin-1 in smooth muscle cell proliferation and migration leading to neointima formation following balloon angioplasty /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Faisal Budhani, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059c774t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33rw98q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62f8501</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The 45kDa isoform of TC-PTP is a ubiquitous, predominantly nuclear protein. Reports demonstrate that it can exist outside the nucleus; however, immunofluorescence and cellular fractionation techniques point to an almost exclusive residence in the nucleus, and even within the nucleolus. Though the conditions of nucleolar enrichment appear to be serum-dependent, and may involve S52 phosphorylation, the exact circumstances necessary for this localization remain unknown, though TC-PTP C216S mutant, and not an S52A/C216S double mutant had the ability to trap a phosphorylated substrate of ~105kDa, thus encouraging further research into the identity of this phosphoprotein. There is also data implicating TC-PTP in the p53-dependent DNA damage response. TC-PTP WT pMEF's are more susceptible to apoptosis than KO pMEF's, thus suggesting a possible role as a tumor suppressor. Finally, in order to explore the physiological significance of possible non-hematopoietic roles of TC-PTP, a Cre-Lox targeting vector was constructed for the eventual generation of a conditional knockout.</description><creator>Brunet, Daniel V.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>The role of T-cell protein tyrosine phosphatase (TC-PTP) in the nucleus /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Daniel V. Brunet, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720d09j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62f8501</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nt85s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work focuses on two dimensional simply-connected complexes. In particular, I examine sufficient conditions on such a complex for convex hulls of compact sets to be compact. I show that there exist complexes where convex hulls of compact sets are not compact if no restriction is placed on the curvature. I prove that convex hulls of compact sets are compact for most nonpositively curved planar complexes, and for negatively curved simply-connected complexes composed of triangles.</description><creator>Burnell, Kevin.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Compactness of convex hulls in nonpositively curved 2-complexes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Kevin Burnell, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wg31k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nt85s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913q198</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Hepatitis C virus (HCV) has become a worldwide problem. Roughly 3% of world population are estimated to be infected with the virus, producing high rates of progressive liver disease, leading to cirrhosis and hepatocellular carcinoma. The present therapy, a combined administration of pegylated interferon-alpha (IFN) and ribavirin is costly and only successful in 50% of patients infected with HCV. It is also associated with serious side effects. Thus, there is an urgent need for better tolerated and more effective treatment modalities. A therapeutic vaccine may be the solution. Recent efforts to produce efficient vaccines require not only the identification of potential viral antigens but also vaccine adjuvants or enhancers of immunity. Dendritic cells (DC) are being considered one such adjuvant for the activation of CD4+ and CD8+ T-cells. As potent antigen presenting cells, they are capable of capturing antigens, processing them into peptides, and presenting them on products of the MHC to T cells. For such reasons, peptide loading of antigens onto DCs to enhance T cell responses is becoming of increasing interest. Using cell penetrating peptides, or motifs capable of transporting cargo freely across cell membranes, we have developed a peptide based delivery system suitable for the transport of all HCV proteins into immature DCs. In our studies we demonstrated that 3.1% of immature DCs internalized the reporter cargo, eGFP. This system was then optimized to 53.81 % in target HeLa cells. Another area of recent focus is the regulation of HCV translation and replication. Positive stranded viruses such as HCV use the genomic RNA as a common template for translation as well as for RNA replication, both proceeding in inverse directions. Thus, specific regulatory mechanisms must be in place in order to coordinate these two antagonistic processes. In this study, we investigated the role of HCV Core protein as a translational inhibitor and enhancer of replication. Using several transient and stable in vivo reporter assays, we showed that Core expression inhibited HCV IRES-mediated translation in trans, in a dose-dependent manner. Furthermore, HCV Core protein is able to dramatically inhibit HCV translation in the Huh7 replicon system, more so than the bicistronic reporter systems tested and subsequently increase total levels of replicon RNA by 1.5 log fold and thus, affect replication. We believe that Core may indeed be the sought regulator of translation and replication.</description><creator>Basak, Sanjukta.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Virology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Studies of Hepatitis C virus immunology : translation and replication</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Sanjukta Basak, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17ct192.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913q198</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cb135</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and chronic heart failure (CHF) patients show a marked reduction in exercise capacity compared to that of healthy age-matched individuals. While inadequate gas exchange and resulting hypoxemia appears as the primary factor in COPD, an impaired cardiac output is the predominant explanation for the reduced oxygen delivery in CHF. However, the extent of the contributions of other systemic factors remains unclear. In light of the potential interactions between cardiac output (Qc) and pulmonary hyperinflation, there is surprisingly little data thus far on ventilatory constraints in CHF and on the role of blood flow delivery in COPD which may further limit the exercise capacity. Thus, the purpose of this study was to compare the slope of the Qc versus oxygen uptake (VO2) response through several submaximal cycling loads in patients with moderately severe COPD and with that of moderate to severe CHF patients as well as age-matched healthy control subjects (CTRL). Also examined was the possibility that ventilatory constraints such as dynamic hyperinflation contribute to an abnormal stroke volume response in both diseases. Cardiac output was measured using the CO 2-rebreathing equilibrium technique during baseline conditions and cycling at 20, 40 and 65% of peak power in 17 COPD (Age: 64 +/- 8 yrs; FEV 1/FVC: 37 +/- 11%; FEV1: 41 +/- 15 % predicted), 10 CHF (Age: 57+/- 10 yrs; FEV1/FVC: 73.8 +/- 5.6%; FEV 1: 93 +/- 13% predicted) and 10 age-matched CTRL subjects. Inspiratory capacity (IC) was also measured for the determination of dynamic hyperinflation during the steady state exercise bouts. The results indicate that while the absolute Qc values are lower in COPD and in CHF than in CTRL during 65% peak power cycling (11.30 +/- 2.38 vs 12.40 +/- 2.08 vs 15.63 +/- 2.15 L•min-1 respectively, p &lt; 0.01), likely due to their lower exercise metabolic demand. The Qc/VO2 response to increasing levels of exercise intensity was lower or normal in CHF patients compared to CTRL, while normal or hyperdynamic in most COPD patients. Indeed, the majority of patients with COPD exhibited Qc/VO2 slopes greater than 7.0, which may be indicative of a peripheral muscle bioenergetic disturbance that may drive the need for greater oxygen delivery, and thus result in an exaggerated central circulatory response.</description><creator>Baril, Jacinthe.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Exercise therapy.</subject><subject>Heart -- Diseases.</subject><subject>Lungs -- Diseases, Obstructive.</subject><title>Interaction between circulatory and respiratory exercise adaptation in chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and chronic heart failure (CHF)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Jacinthe Baril, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wj72z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cb135</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278t377</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since the early 1990s, the concept of substantial equivalence has been a guiding principle of the Canadian Food Inspection Agency and Health Canada's regulatory approach toward products of plant biotechnology destined for the food and livestock feed markets. To assess substantial equivalence in terms of chemical composition, genetically modified (GM) plants are compared to conventional counterparts at the level of macro- and micro-nutrients, allergens and toxicants. Such targeted comparative analyses are limited in their scope and their capacity to detect unintended changes in chemical composition. There is a need to develop more effective testing protocols to improve the substantial equivalence assessment of GM crops. The objective of this thesis was to explore high-density oligoarrays as tools to assess substantial equivalence of Roundup Ready(TM) soybean. Three conventional and two GM soybean varieties were selected according to the similarity of their performance in field trials. Total RNA was extracted from first trifoliate leaves harvested from soybean plants grown in a controlled environment until the V2 stage. To annotate the 37 776 soybean probesets present on the multi-organism Soybean Affymetrix GeneChip(TM), consensus sequences were aligned with TIGR Soybean Gene Index tentative consensus sequences using BLASTN. After redefining the chip description file to exclude non-soybean probesets, the effects of three different normalization methods (Robust Multichip Average (RMA), Microarray Analysis Suite (MAS 5.0) and Model-Based Expression Index) were compared and Significance Analysis of Microarrays (SAM for R-Bioconductor) was applied to detect differential gene expression between conventional and GM soybean varieties. Eleven candidate genes were selected for further studies.</description><creator>Beaulieu, Julie.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Gene expression.</subject><subject>DNA microarrays.</subject><subject>Soybean -- Genetic engineering.</subject><subject>Transgenic plants.</subject><title>Exploration of high-density oligoarrays as tools to assess substantial equivalence of genetically modified crops</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Julie Beaulieu, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g7804.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278t377</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52j838h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Determining the factors responsible for the origin and maintenance of diversity remains a difficult problem in evolutionary biology. There is extensive theoretical work which suggests that environmental heterogeneity plays a major role. This theory argues that diversification is ultimately due to divergent natural selection for alternative resources. In this thesis I investigate adaptation and the evolution of diversity in experimental populations of the asexual bacterium Pseudomonas fluorescens. In all experiments I introduce clonal isolates of Pseudomonas to a novel environment and allow evolution to occur through the substitution of random mutations. Adaptation can then be quantified by comparing evolved genotypes to the ancestor. These experiments show that when Pseudomonas is selected in a complex environment containing several resources, sympatric genotypes adapt to use different resources, leading to the evolution of genetically diverse populations. In environments containing just a single resource, most genotypes adapt to use the same resource and no such diversity is observed. Adaptation in the experimental populations is caused by the fixation of beneficial mutations of intermediate fitness effect. My results highlight the value of microbial model systems for answering evolutionary questions and provide strong evidence for the role of ecological factors in the origin of diversity.</description><creator>Barrett, Rowan Douglas Hilton.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Pseudomonas fluorescens -- Adaptation.</subject><subject>Ecological heterogeneity.</subject><subject>Microbial populations.</subject><subject>Pseudomonas fluorescens -- Variation.</subject><title>Experimental evolution of Pseudomonas fluorescens in simple and complex environments</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Rowan Douglas Hilton Barrett, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gs96q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j838h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qm33r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The kidney filters blood through nephrons, to recycle water and solutes in order to maintain homeostasis in the body. A reduction in nephron formation during fetal development renders the affected individual susceptible to hypertension and end stage renal disease. Nephrogenesis relies on the iterative branching of the ureteric bud epithelium, which triggers the metanephric mesenchyme to condense and form nephrons at its tips. A critical question during kidney development is to identify the genes that are responsible for nephron formation. The culture of mouse embryonic kidneys has been an important in vitro model to examine the effects of candidate genes during nephrogenesis. By culturing embryonic kidneys in the presence of growth factors, blocking antibodies to specific proteins, or by blocking transcription using RNA interference, gene function can be ascertained. Microinjection and electroporation has also been used to overexpress DNA constructs in mouse embryonic kidneys. We have reviewed the method of microinjection and determined the optimal conditions for introducing DNA into embryonic kidneys. We examined high voltage/short pulse parameters and compared them to previously reported low voltage/long pulse settings. The use of a high voltage with a short pulse led to 100 fold more transgene expression and a longer duration of expression, when compared to a low voltage/long pulse protocol. Furthermore, we can target either the ureteric bud or the mesenchyme of the developing kidney, by selectively microinjecting the transgene in the organ. We have examined the expression pattern of Alk6 and members of the claudin gene family during kidney development. Their expression pattern along with their function has not been fully characterized in the embryonic kidney. In the future we plan to employ our novel electroporation protocol to study the function of these candidate genes in the developing kidney.</description><creator>Alie, Tristan MacKay.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>An innovative electroporation protocol to study candidate genes in the developing kidney /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Tristan MacKay Alie, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b386f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qm33r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1j92g781d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of pandemic influenza planning is to minimize health and economic losses in the event of a future pandemic. One of the numerous challenges associated with this goal is the need to ration limited medical supplies such as vaccines and antivirals. This thesis seeks to formulate an ethical framework for priority access to these resources. Prioritization strategies must be consistent with the goal of pandemic planning and should reflect societal norms for equitable distribution. According to an ethics framework based on the principles of utility and equity, three groups were granted highest priority for influenza vaccine, namely health care workers, emergency service workers, and high-risk individuals predisposed to severe outcomes following influenza infection. In the case of antivirals, the expectation is that there will be competition between treatment and prophylaxis uses of these drugs. The resulting dilemma---providing primary access to the critically ill in respect of the medical profession's duty of care or prioritizing prophylaxis of health care workers in respect of their right to protection---is the major question which the framework presented in this thesis seeks to resolve.</description><creator>Alfieri, Carolina.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Epidemiology.</subject><title>Proposal of an ethics-based framework for prioritization of scarce resources during an influenza pandemic</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Carolina Alfieri, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mm569.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g781d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j3332502</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An 1 out of 2 Oblivious Transfer (( 21 )-OT) is a two-party computation in which a sender A owning two secret bits b0, b 1 can transfer one to them, bc, to receiver Bob who chooses c. This is done in such a way that Alice does not learn anything about c and Bob does not learn anything other than bit bc. Security specifications for ( 21 )-OT are defined in terms of privacy and correctness. Privacy constraint enforces that B gets the bit of his choice and gains no knowledge about the other input bit of A , and A does not gain any knowledge of c. Correctness constraint enforces that the output received by B is not corrupted by a dishonest A . Traditionally privacy and correctness have been defined as disjoint security specifications, and various attempts have been made to merge these two constraints. We present a new set of security specifications for ( 21 ) -OT in which these two constraints are enforced concurrently. In addition, unlike the previous specifications, our new correctness constraint deals with the correct view of the protocol instead of output only. We also extend these security specifications to another variant of ( 21 )-OT called 1 out of 2 XOR Oblivious Transfer.</description><creator>Ahsan, Abdul Hannan.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>More robust security specifications for 1 out of 2 Oblivious Transfer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Abdul Hannan Ahsan, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j131z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j3332502</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429948w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We review basic concepts of the algebraic theory of combinatorial group theory, and try to emphasize the important role of groups represented with a set of generators and one defining relation.</description><creator>Alhazaa, Khalifa.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>A survey of one-relator groups /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Khalifa Alhazaa, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d684d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429948w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr171x577</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study describes the biomechanics of the foot during an ice hockey tight tum.Pressure data were collected with flexible piezo-resistive sensors from 15 anatomicalpoints on both left and right feet. Participants inc1uded 8 elite (86.82 Kg +/- 6.48Kg,179.69 cm +/-6.74cm) and 8 recreationallevel (82.10Kg, +/-7.49Kg, 175.63cm +/-6.37cm) hockey players, with the elite players being members ofthe McGill varsity teamand the recreational players participating in recreational organized hockey of 10wercaliber. The data from three to four tums for both left and right tight tums were collectedand normalized, with statistical measures taken for blade contact/tum initiation, peakpressure and peak pressure at push off. Two way ANOV As showed numerous areas ofstatistical significance (p ≤ 0.05) between the elite and recreational participants. Thetracking of center of pressure was also investigated leading to sorne speculations ofadvanced techniques for the successful execution of a tight tum.</description><description>Cette étude décrit les pressions du pied en dedans du patin pendant un viragebrisque. Des collections de données de pression ont été collectionnées avecdes détecteurs piezo résistifs à 15 endroits anatomiques sur les deux pieds. Les groupescomprenaient 8 joueurs de hockey élites (86.82 Kg +/- 6.48Kg, 179.69 cm +/-6.74cm) et8 joueurs de hockey de niveau récréatif(82.10Kg, +/- 7.49Kg, 175.63cm +/- 6.37cm).Les joueurs élites étaient tous membres de l'équipe de première catégorie de l'Universitéde McGill et les joueurs récréatifs participaient tous dans des ligues de hockey organiséesmais d'un niveau plus bas. Les données de trois à quatre virages sur le côté droit et côtégauche ont été collectionnées et normalisées. Les variables retirées de cette analysecomprenaient le contact de lame/initiation de virage, pression maximale et « peak pushoff ». Une analyse statistique (2 way ANOV A) a démontrée plusieurs différences (p ≤ 0.05) entre les sujets élites et les joueurs récréatifs. Le centre de pression a été tracé etétudié. Cette analyse a servi comme source de réflexion sur les techniques avancées pourexécution idéale d'un virage brisque.</description><creator>McGrail, J. Scott G.</creator><contributor>Turcotte, René (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2006</date><subject>Skating -- Physiological aspects.</subject><subject>Hockey players.</subject><title>Skate boot pressure analysis of elite and recreational ice hockey skaters during the execution of tight turns</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247ds46b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr171x577</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qm341</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two zoologists with considerable experience in the Canadian Arctic suggested to the writer that the “Gammarus Problem” would be an extremely interesting subject for investigation, and one which has several advantages, for material is relatively easy to obtain, and there are a number of species available. The precise studies on the species and sub-species of this amphipod genus in British estuaries are well known, and have been cited as examples in discussions on speciation and “new systematics”. In North America such studies are lacking and the time seemed opportune to try to elucidate the relationships between some of the forms living on these shores. In particular the species from northern waters were of interest. Dr. E.L. Bousfield (1958) has described the fresh-water amphipods of North America, and is currently preparing an account of the systematics of coastal species. This account provided material for the present discussion on the general relationships of North American species, but as it has not yet been published the reference “personal communication” or “pers. comm.” is used throughout the discussion. [...]</description><creator>MacIntyre, Robert John</creator><contributor>Dunbar, Dr. M. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1959</date><subject>Biology, Zoology.</subject><subject>Amphipoda -- Canada.</subject><title>Gammarus; some aspects of the genus with particular reference to Gammarus oceanicus from eastern Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128b213.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qm341</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):26825</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>