<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:16:31Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):19400" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns064976z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:16:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis traces the evolution of Arab nationalism in Syria from 1908 to 1920. It attempts to determine when Arab nationalism was accepted as the primary focus of political 1oya1ty by the Syrian Arabs during this period and what reasons prompted the Syrian Arabs to support Arab nationa1ism. It was found that during the years from 1908 to 1918 Arab nationa1sim as a po1itica1 force came into being in Syria and was embraced by a few Syrian Arabs. At this time, however, the majority of Syrian Arabs of all classes rejected Arab nationalism and maintained their po1itica1 allegiance to the Ottoman Empire. In 1918 with the destruction of the Ottoman Empire, Arab nationalism in Syria was accepted by most Syrian Arabs as the only ideological alternative now avai1ab1e by which to maintain and protect their traditional interests and to build a new po1itical community.</description><creator>Thomas, David S.</creator><contributor>Prof. Donald Little (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1969</date><subject>Syria -- Politics and government.</subject><subject>Nationalism -- Syria.</subject><title>The transformation of Syrian Arab nationalism, 1908-1920 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257j737.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064976z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04dt46t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:16:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is, as its title duely indicates, an attempt to establish and describe the facts or events of an aspect of the public life of Ibn Taymiya (661-728), namely, his mihan or the trials and tribulations he underwent apparently due to the stands he took on certain dogmatic issues of his time. This thesis is divided into two chapters: the first tries to determine the originality of the sources in relation to each other as well as in relation to the mihan -- and their reliability; in all eighteen sources are dealt with. The second chapter tries to reconstruct a plausible account of the mihan on the basis of the knowledge acquired of the sources.</description><creator>Murād, Ḥasan Qāsim</creator><date>1968</date><subject>Muslim scholars -- Islamic Empire -- Biography.</subject><subject>Ibn Taymīyah, Aḥmad ibn ʻAbd al-Ḥalīm, 1263-1328.</subject><subject>Islam -- Doctrines.</subject><title>The miḥan of Ibn Taymiya : a narrative account based on a comparative analysis of sources</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719r165.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dt46t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05fg900</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:16:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Controversies among ahl al-hadith and Hanafis had assumed serious proportions by the time of Wali Allah. Reconciliation of legal schools was a practical, rather than a merely theoretical problem. From the very beginning Wali Allah had ahl al-hadith proclivities and from that standpoint he bitterly denounced Hanafïs for deviating from sunnah. At this stage his basic aim was revival of pristine Shari'ah and reform of Hanafi legal doctrines by making them conform to sunnah. Later on, Wali Allah felt the futility of his intemperate opposition to Hanafi school and combined the aim of unifying the ummah with his original aim. He began to stress increasingly the validity of all schools. As for the hanafî school, he tried to reform its doctrines so as to make it harmonise with sunnah by introducing in it a selective process. Later he further widened the scope of his scheme to embrace all Sunni schools. The method he suggested was that of legal eclecticism and the underlying purpose was to reconcile and amalgamate the schools without destroying their entities.</description><creator>Muḥammad, Miʻrāj</creator><date>1969</date><subject>Islamic law.</subject><subject>Walī Allāh al-Dihlawī, 1702 or 3-1762 or 3.</subject><title>Shāh Walī Allāh's attempt to reconcile the schools of fiqh</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z9034090.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fg900</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:12579x429</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:16:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis aims at studying the life, works and thought of Louis Massignon and at demonstrating how they find their unity in the God of Abraham. It is not a chronological study but a study of the principal themes of his works, following the pattern he often used -- the five pillars of Islamic religious and social life: alms giving which includes the respect of the guest and his word, prayer seen under the aspect of intercession, pilgrimage, sacrifice exemplified in fasting and a witness to faith in the Judgment of God. In chapter VI an attempt is made to study the evolution of the thought of Massignon from 1914 to 1947 concerning some aspects of the Christian-Mus1im encounter which, for him, points to the Judgment.</description><creator>Landrien, Simone</creator><date>1968</date><subject>Abraham (Biblical patriarch)</subject><subject>Abraham (Biblical patriarch) -- In the Koran</subject><subject>Christianity and other religions -- Islam.</subject><subject>Islam -- Relations -- Christianity.</subject><subject>Massignon, Louis, 1883-1962</subject><title>Some aspects of the meaning of Abraham in the life, works and thought of Louis Massignon</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd473132r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579x429</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2r36v254r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:16:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study deals with the characteristics of Arabic historiography in Iraq down to the time of Abu Ja'fer Tabari (d. 310/923). The historical annals of Taberi provide both the specific focus of the study and a methodological approach. Since Tabari's work may be regarded as an anthology of the writings of the early historians, our first question concerns the characteristics of Iraqi historiography as they are reflected in the annals. Then we are concerned with the ways in which Tabari's work differed from his predecessors. Part One of the study comprises a historical survey of the main historians of the period including Tabari. Part two deals with certain specific characteristics of history writing, suoh as the khabar element, based upon illustrative material provided by a translated portion of the annals, which itself appears as an Appendix to the study. Again drawing upon the translated material, we deal with certain problems, such as the nature of the sources, with which Tabari was confronted in compiling his own work.</description><creator>Waines, David.</creator><contributor>Dr. Donald Little (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1968</date><subject>Iraq -- Historiography.</subject><subject>Ṭabarī, 838?-923. Tārīkh al-rusul wa-al-mulūk.</subject><title>Abū Ja'far Tabarī and his sources : an introduction to early 'Iraqī historiography</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698c73m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36v254r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816r617</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:16:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the most significant and least analyzed aspects of the Riddah or "apostasy" which occurred in the last years of Muhammad's life and in the caliphate of Abu Bakr (632-634) is the fact that the most adamant opposition to the incipient religious-economic political system of Islam in all regions of Arabia except al-Bahrayn and 'Uman was directed by the so-called "false prophets," four of whom are known by name: al-Aswad (Yemen), Tulayhah b. Khuwaylid (B. Asad), Sajah (B. Tamim), and Musaylimah b. habib (al-Yamamah).  The most significant of these "false prophets," and the one on which the most infonnation is available, ls Musaylimah. With an army of allegedly 40,000 men he crushed two Muslim armies before being overwhelmed by a third, under the Muslim general Khalid b. al-Walid.  Some accounts report that even in the victorious third battle, enough Qur'an reciters were lost to cause concern over the perpetuation of the Qur'an. Both V.V. Barthold and W. Montgomery Watt have assessed Musaylimah's movement to have been the most serious threat faced by the nascent Isiamic state. With the exception of V.V. Barthold, scholars dealing with the first half of the seventh century in Arabia have neglected to examine in detail the source materials on Musaylimah's movement - its formation, its membership, its organization, and the question of why it offered such bitter resistance to incorporation in the Islamic movement even when military defeat was imminent. This study is intended to fill that gap in our knowledge as far as possible, by gathering and critically analyzing materials in the primary (and secondary) sources relevant to the study of Musaylimah. From these I hope to present an account of his movement as comprehensive and coherent as the sources will permit.</description><creator>Eickelman, Dale F., 1942-</creator><date>1967</date><subject>Musaylimah, d. 633.</subject><subject>Muslims -- Saudi Arabia -- Biography.</subject><title>Musaylimah : an anthropological appraisal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827g94t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816r617</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2r36v2551</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:16:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is a small contribution to the growing amount of information that has been gathered about Arab nationalism. Its purpose is more specific than most studies of Arab nationalism have been in that it seeks to deal only with four figures who were Christian rather than Muslim and who happened to be Arabs of the fertile Crescent. Apart from placing these writers in a new perspective, this thesis has little that is very original to offer. But, it is hoped that the fairly careful and detailed analysis of some of the writings, offered in English for the first time, will be of some future use to others. [...]</description><creator>Lavan, Spencer.</creator><contributor>Abu-Lughud, I. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1966</date><subject>Islamic Studies.</subject><subject>Azoury, Negib</subject><subject>Nationalism -- Arab countries.</subject><subject>Bustānī, Buṭrus</subject><subject>Rabbāṭ, Idmūn</subject><subject>Aflaq, Michel, 1910-</subject><title>Four Christian Arab nationalists.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sx94p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36v2551</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19fb07r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:16:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cardiovascular disease is the leading cause of death in industrialized nations. Angioplasty is performed on millions of patients every year. It is, therefore, essential to constantly explore and investigate new approaches to study and improve the outcomes of this minimally-invasive procedure. In this thesis, novel applications of intravascular optical coherence tomography (IVOCT) are proposed, namely, monitoring, characterization, simulation, and control of balloon inflation.High-resolution IVOCT images lead to a detailed assessment of microstructures. Using image analysis techniques, IVOCT characterization of balloon deformation is presented as a method to validate the performance of balloons. IVOCT characterization of the deformation of artery phantoms is proposed as a method to study the tissue's response to various balloon sizes, various balloon folding strategies and various inflation strategies.In addition, IVOCT characterization of deformation is proposed as a method to validate simulation results. This thesis provides a comparison between finite-element simulation results and experimental results for two case studies, which investigate the effects of variation of mechanical properties as well as balloon unfolding and inflation process.Finally, in this thesis, methods are proposed to control the balloon inflation. During balloon inflation, the luminal diameter of an artery could be estimated in real-time and used in a feedback loop to control the inflation. The experimental relevance of this method is demonstrated when the balloon is inflated in an artery phantom, in an artery of an excised porcine heart and in an artery of a beating porcine heart.The methods and the results, provided in this thesis, could benefit the developers of angioplasty devices, cardiovascular research, and clinical users.</description><description>Les maladies cardiovasculaires sont la principale cause de décès dans les pays industrialisés. L'angioplastie est réalisée sur des millions de patients chaque année. Il est donc essentiel de constamment explorer et étudier de nouvelles approches pour étudier et améliorer les résultats de cette procédure peu invasive. Dans cette thèse, de nouvelles applications de la tomographie par cohérence optique intravasculaire (IVOCT) sont proposées, à savoir, la surveillance, la caractérisation, la simulation et le contrôle du gonflement du ballon.Des images haute résolution IVOCT mènent à une évaluation détaillée des microstructures. En utilisant des techniques d'analyse d'image, la caractérisation de la déformation du ballon est présentée comme une méthode pour valider la performance de ballons. La caractérisation de la déformation des fantômes est proposée comme une méthode pour étudier la réponse des tissus à des tailles différentes de ballons, et diverses stratégies de pliage et de gonflement du ballon. En outre, la caractérisation de la déformation est proposée pour valider les résultats de simulation. Une comparaison est fournie entre les résultats de la simulation par éléments finis et des résultats expérimentaux pour les deux études de cas, qui étudient les effets de la variation des propriétés mécaniques ainsi que le processus de déploiement et de gonflement du ballon. Enfin, dans cette thèse, des méthodes sont proposées pour contrôler le gonflement du ballon. Pendant le gonflement du ballon, le diamètre luminal de l'artère peut être estimé en temps réel et utilisé dans une boucle de rétroaction pour contrôler le gonflement. La pertinence expérimentale de cette méthode est démontrée lorsque le ballon est gonflé dans un fantôme, dans les artères porcines d'un cœur excisé et d'un cœur battant. Les méthodes et les résultats fournis dans cette thèse pourraient bénéficier aux développeurs de dispositifs d'angioplastie, à la recherche cardiovasculaire et aux utilisateurs cliniques.</description><creator>Azarnoush, Hamed</creator><contributor>Benoit Boulet (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Engineering - Biomedical</subject><title>Modeling and control of angioplasty balloon deployment based on intravascular optical coherence tomography</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19fb081.mov</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19fb07r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42nc904</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:16:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The first section of this thesis analyses the second person narrative in Édouard Levé's story, Suicide. Built upon studies in narratology on the problems of second person narrative, the analysis shows the voice in Suicide is part of an oscillation, which is also employed in the tense of the narrative, resulting in a neutral text in the sense defined by both Roland Barthes and Maurice Blanchot. The second section of the thesis presents a creative text; more specifically four short stories narrated by the same narrator-protagonist-narratee and linked by the same central theme of identity and representation. Through confession or inner trial, a young man in his thirties, Jérôme Borromée, revisits important friendships of his life, which left him with a feeling of guilt. This guilt arises primarily from doubts he has been having about his sexual orientation and from his aspiration to attain a prestigious socioprofessional identity. What links the two sections of this thesis is the use of the pronoun "you". Indeed, to showcase the protagonist's inner trial, Jérôme Borromée, like Suicide, is narrated in the second person singular.</description><description>Dans un premier temps, ce mémoire propose une analyse de la narration à la deuxième personne dans le récit Suicide, d'Édouard Levé. Appuyée sur des études en narratologie traitant de la problématique des narrations à la deuxième personne, l'analyse démontre que la voix de Suicide participe à une dynamique oscillatoire qui implique également le temps du récit, ce qui produit un texte neutre, au sens où Roland Barthes et Maurice Blanchot définissent le concept de Neutre. La deuxième partie du mémoire propose un texte de création, plus précisément quatre nouvelles liées par un même narrateur-protagoniste-narrataire et par la thématique de l'identité et de la représentation qui y est centrale. Jeune trentenaire, Jérôme Borromée revisite sous forme de confession ou de procès intérieur certaines relations amicales importantes de sa vie qui lui ont inspiré de la culpabilité. Cette culpabilité relève principalement des doutes qu'il a entretenus sur son orientation sexuelle et de ses aspirations à une identité socioprofessionnelle prestigieuse. Le lien entre les deux parties de ce mémoire tient de l'utilisation d'une adresse au « tu ». En effet, afin de bien mettre en évidence le procès intérieur que se livre son héros, Jérôme Borromée est narré à la deuxième personne du singulier, tout comme Suicide.</description><creator>Bourque, Guillaume</creator><contributor>Alain Farah (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Literature - Canadian (French)</subject><title>La narration à la deuxième personne du singulier dans «Suicide», d'Édouard Levé: oscillations identitaires et temporelles temporelles comme dynamique du Neutre suivi du texte de création «Jérome Borromée»</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w3830.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42nc904</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:000004013</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:16:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'hypercholestérolémie est un facteur de risque des maladies cardiovasculaires comme l'athérosclérose. L'athérosclérose est une maladie dans laquelle les globules blancs, des lipides (y compris le cholestérol), et d'autres débris cellulaires s'accumulent dans les parois des vaisseaux sanguins ce qui provoque l'inflammation et le rétrécissement des vaisseaux, menant finalement à une crise cardiaque. Les statines, des inhibiteurs de l'enzyme 3-hydroxy-3-méthylglutaryl coenzyme A (HMG-CoA) réductase, ont été conçus pour inhiber la synthèse du cholestérol en empêchant la conversion de l'HMG-CoA en mévalonate dans la voie de biosynthèse du cholestérol. Bien que efficace pour réduire les taux de cholestérol, les statines démontrent d'autres effets bénéfiques. Les scientifiques pensent que ces effets sont causés par l'influence positive des statines sur  les cellules endothéliales, la couche interne de la vascularisation qui est constamment exposée aux forces de cisaillement du fluide vasculaire.Ce travail étudie l'effet des statines et la contrainte de cisaillement sur la fonction et la structure des cellules endothéliales en utilisant un modèle tridimensionnel, in vitro de culture tissulaire. Les cellules ont été cultivées dans le modèle, exposées à une contrainte de cisaillement de 12,5 dynes/cm2, et traités avec la statine simvastatine pendant 24 heures. La morphologie des cellules endothéliale, l'arrangement du cytosquelette d'actine et l'adhésion des neutrophiles aux cellules endothéliales ont été analysés.Les statines ont causé l'arrondissement des cellules endothéliales, un phénotype malsain, qui n'a pas été renversé par la présence des forces de cisaillement. Le cytosquelette d'actine a été perturbé par le traitement aux statines, un effet qui n'a également pas été renversé par les forces de cisaillement. Il n'y avait pas de preuve que la thérapie aux statines affecte l'adhésion des neutrophiles, même si les forces de cisaillement ont diminué l'adhérence. L'ajout de mévalonate a inversé tous les effets des statines, ce qui confirme  la réglementation statine par la voie de biosynthèse du cholestérol. Comprendre comment les statines affectent les cellules endothéliales en présence de forces de cisaillement pourrait permettre de meilleures options de traitement dans l'avenir.</description><description>High blood cholesterol is a primary risk factor for cardiovascular diseases such as atherosclerosis. Atherosclerosis is a disease in which white blood cells, lipids (including cholesterol), and other cellular debris build up within the blood vessel walls to cause vessel inflammation and narrowing, ultimately leading to heart attack or stroke. Statin drugs, inhibitors of the enzyme 3-hydroxy-3-methylglutaryl coenzyme A (HMG-CoA) reductase, were designed to inhibit cholesterol synthesis by preventing the conversion of HMG-CoA to mevalonate within the cholesterol biosynthesis pathway. Although clinically effective at reducing circulating levels of cholesterol, statins have also been shown to have other beneficial effects, termed pleiotropic effects. Researchers believe that these pleiotropic effects are caused by the positive influence of statins on endothelial cells, the inner most layer of the vasculature that is constantly exposed to fluid wall shear stress.This work studied the cumulative effect of statin therapy and wall shear stress on endothelial cell structure and function using a three dimensional, in vitro tissue culture model. Endothelial cells were cultured within the model and exposed to 12.5 dynes/cm2 of wall shear stress and treated with the statin drug simvastatin for 24 hours. Endothelial cell morphology, F-actin cytoskeleton arrangement, and neutrophil adhesion to endothelial cells were analyzed.Statins caused endothelial cells to conform to a rounded, unhealthy phenotype, which was not reversed by the presence of wall shear stress. The F-actin cytoskeleton of the endothelial cells was disrupted by statin treatment, also non-reversible by wall shear stress. There was no conclusive evidence that statin therapy affected neutrophil adhesion, although wall shear stress significantly decreased adhesion. The addition of mevalonate reversed all statin effects, confirming statin regulation through the cholesterol biosynthesis pathway. Understanding how statin therapy affects endothelial cells in the presence of wall shear stress may allow for improved treatment options or more specific statin drugs in the future.</description><creator>Dick, Melissa</creator><contributor>Richard L Leask (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Engineering - Chemical</subject><title>The effect of statins on endothelial cell response to wall shear stress in three dimensional in vitro tissue culture models</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dr12t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000004013</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859k665</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:16:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le prétraitment  thermique de lentilles avant de les moudre en farine peut faciliter son utilisation dans la préparation de produits à valeur ajoutée. Cette étude porte sur l'évaluation des effets des prétraitments thermiques par chauffage par torréfaction(CT), par chauffage par microondes (CM), ou par l'eau bouillante (EB), sur la teneur en composés phénoliques totaux (CPT), sur l'activité anti-oxydante totale (AAOT), sur les teneurs en inhibiteur de trypsine, et sur la digestibilité in-vitro des protéines (DIVP). Les essais ont été faits sur des farines obtenues à partir de lentilles rouges décortiquées et de lentilles vertes non decortiquées après l'application des prétraitment thermiques. Les deux varieties de lentilles ont été prétraitées selon des combinaisons déterminées de températures et de durées de traitment. Les teneurs en CPT et l'AAOT ont été évaluées par spectrophotométrie à 760 nm en utilisant la méthode de Folin-Ciocalteu et la méthode DPPH (1, 1- diphényl-2-picrylhydrazyle) de piégeage des radicaux libres. Les résultats ont démontré des différences significatives entre les deux types de lentilles étudiées. Le prétraitement CM (5 min) a conduit à une augumentation significative (P≤0.05) de la teneur en CPT dans les échantillons de farine de lentilles vertes [8.85 mg GAE/g de poids sec (ps) lorsque comparé aux échantillons de farine de lentilles vertes non-traitées [7.5 JEU mg/g ps]. Une tendance similaire a été observée auprés des farines de lentilles vertes torréfiées au four pendant 20 min. L'AAOT des farines de lentilles vertes non-traitées était d'environ 86% et elle était supérieure à celle obtenue à partir de lentilles rouges non-traitées. Les teneurs en CPT observées dans les échantillons traités soit par CT soit par CM étaient plus élevées que celles des échantillons non traitées et peuvent refléter des réductions en AAOT obetnues. Les teneurs en CPT et en AAOT des échantillons obtenues à la suite du prétraitment EB étainet nettement inférieures et peut être attributées à plusieurs facteurs dans la matrice. Bien que les lentilles soit riches en protéines, plusiers facteurs limitent leurs utilisation pour la consommation humaine. Ces principaux facteurs sont : la présence de composants antinutritionnels, le temps nécessaire à la préparation, les saveurs désagréables, et la digestibilité réduites des protéines. On peut réduire l'impacte des facteurs antinutritionnels comme les inhibiteurs de la trypsine par des traitements thermiques. Les résultats ont demontré que l'utilisation du pretraitment CM permettait de réduire significativement (P≤0.05) l'activité des inhibiteurs de trypsine lorsque comparés aux prétraitments CT et EB. Il a aussi été démontré que l'augmentation de la dureé des prétraitments thermiques par CT ou par EB permettait d'accroitre la DIVP. Dans tous les cas étudiés, l'application d'un prétraitment thermique sur les lentilles a permis d'améliorer la DIVP.Mots clés : Lentilles vertes, lentilles rouges, farines, traitements thermiques, composés phénoliques totaux (CPT), activité anti-oxydante totale (AAOT), digestibilité in-vitro des protéines (DIVP), équivalent en acide gallique, chauffage par torréfaction (CT), chauffage par microondes (CM), chauffage par trempage dans l'eau bouillante (EB).</description><description>Heat pre-treatment of nutrient-rich lentil seeds prior to their processing into flour may enhance its use by reducing processing and preparation times in value added products. In this study, changes in trypsin inhibitor content, total phenolic content, antioxidant activity, and in-vitro protein digestibility of flours prepared from hulled red lentils and unhulled green lentils were determined subsequent to various processing methods such as oven roasting (OR), boiling and microwave heating (MH).  The increasing interest in the phenolic content of plant based food-stuffs made us to assess two different lentil cultivars processed under fixed temperature and time combination. Total phenolic content and antioxidant activity (TAC) of 70% acetone lentil extracts were assayed spectrophotometrically at 760nm using Folin-Ciocalteu and DPPH (1,1-diphenyl-2-picrylhydrazyl) radical scavenging activity methods, respectively. Significant differences in phenolic content and antioxidant activity were noted between hulled red and unhulled green lentil varieties.  MH (5 min) led to a significant increase (P ≤ 0.05) in total phenolic content in unhulled green lentil flours (GLF) [8.85 mg GAE/g dry weight (DW) while raw flour comparatively showed lower phenolic content [7.5 mg GAE/g DW]. A similar increase was found after oven-roasting this material for 20 min. The TAC of untreated unhulled green lentil range was around 86%, and it was higher than the value obtained for the flour from untreated hulled red lentils. The increase in TPC of OR samples and microwave-heated samples over untreated ones may reflect reductions in TAC. Flour samples obtained from boiled lentils showed a sharp decrease in TPC and TAC values, which may be attributable to a number of factors in the matrix.Though lentils are rich in protein, their anti-nutritional components, the length of the time required for their preparation, as well as their unfavorable flavor, and reduced protein digestibility have limited their frequency of use for human consumption. By applying heat, anti-nutritional factors such as trypsin inhibitors can be largely removed. Our results show that MH treatment produced significant reduction (P≤0.05) in trypsin inhibitor activity when compared to OR or boiling methods. In- vitro protein digestibility (IVPD) was improved after processing. Longer processing times associated with OR or boiling methods improved IVPD to a greater extent than MH.Keywords: TAC- Total antioxidant activity; GA- Gallic Acid equivalent; Lentils; TPC- Total phenolic content; IVPD- In-Vitro Protein digestibility; MH- Microwave heating; OR- Oven roasting; GLF- Green lentil flours; RLF- Red lentil flours</description><creator>Sampathkumar, Yamuna</creator><contributor>G S Vijaya Raghavan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Agriculture - Food Science and Technology</subject><title>Thermal processing effects on total phenolic content, antioxidant activity, trypsin inhibitor activity and in-vitro protein digestibility of lentils</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w867t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859k665</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82kc40r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:16:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Populations exposed to changing environments often decline in abundance and may therefore find themselves at risk of extinction. Safe abundances can be regained, and persistence secured, when populations can adapt fast enough. Here I ask how population and environmental factors determine a population's ability to persist in changing environments by adapting genetically. In Chapter 2 I investigate the response to a gradual, directional change in the environment and in Chapter 3 I investigate the response to a sudden, sustained shift. Chapter 3 also discusses the effects of interspecific competition. In both chapters I use the canonical equation of adaptive dynamics, which allows me to derive analytical expressions while including ecological process neglected in previous theory; in particular, I consider logistic population growth, frequency-dependent intraspecific competition, and interspecific competition. I use computer simulations to examine the accuracy of my analytical results when the simplifying assumptions of adaptive dynamics are relaxed. Chapter 2 derives the trait lag which maximizes the rate of evolution and also computes this maximum. Populations with higher mutational input experiencing stronger selection have the ability to adapt faster. Computer simulations show that the derived maximum rate of evolution is a good predictor of extinction across a wide range of parameter values, including those that deviate from the assumptions of adaptive dynamics. Chapter 3 first uncovers an expression for the population trait value across time and then uses this expression to calculate the time a population is below a threshold abundance, the 'time at risk'. The population trait value approaches the fitness peak quickly at first, and the rate declines exponentially. Populations with greater mutational input and maximum abundance, and those which are initially better adapted spend less time at risk. The time at risk is maximized at intermediate selection strengths, as strong selection lowers abundance and weak selection slows adaptation. Simulations show good alignment when mutations are rare and population sizes small. Interspecific competition lowers the abundance of the focal population, generally increasing the time at risk, but this can be compensated for under particular scenarios by increased selection pressure. Interspecific competition can sometimes speed adaptation and foster persistence. The ecological and evolutionary response of natural populations to environmental change depends on complex ecological interactions. Theory and experiments which include such interactions are needed for accurate descriptions of genetic adaptation to environmental change, in both the lab and in the wild.</description><description>Les populations exposées à des environnements changeants déclinent souvent en abondance et peuvent ainsi être confrontées à un risque d'extinction. Des abondances suffisantes peuvent être retrouvées, ainsi qu'une persistance durable, quand les populations peuvent s'adapter suffisamment vite. Dans cette étude, je me demande comment les facteurs des populations et de l'environnement déterminent la capacité des populations à persister dans des environnements changeants grâce à une adaptation génétique. Dans le chapitre 2, j'étudie la réponse à un changement graduel et directionnel de l'environnement, et dans le chapitre 3, j'étudie la réponse à un changement soudain et soutenu. Le chapitre 3 discute également les effets de la compétition interspécifique. Dans les deux chapitres, j'utilise l'équation canonique des dynamiques adaptatives, ce qui me permet d'en dériver des expressions analytiques ainsi que d'y inclure des processus écologiques négligés dans les théories précédentes; en particulier, je considère la croissance logistique des populations, la compétition intraspécifique fréquence-dépendante, et la compétition interspécifique. J'utilise des simulations informatiques pour examiner l'exactitude de mes résultats analytiques lorsque les hypothèses simplificatrices des dynamiques sont relâchées. Le chapitre 2 dérive le retard de trait, ce qui maximise le taux d'évolution, et aussi calcule ce maximum. Les populations avec le plus grand apport de mutation rencontrant une sélection plus forte ont la capacité de s'adapter plus vite. Les simulations informatiques montrent que le taux maximal d'évolution est un bon prédicteur de l'extinction pour une large gamme de valeur de paramètres, incluant ceux qui dévient des hypothèses de dynamiques adaptatives. Le chapitre 3 dérive, tout d'abord, une expression pour la valeur de trait de population au cours du temps et, ensuite, utilise cette expression pour calculer le temps durant lequel une population se trouve sous le seuil d'abondance, le « temps du risque ». La valeur de trait de population s'approche, tout d'abord, du pic de fitness, puis le taux décline de manière exponentielle. Les populations avec un plus grand apport de mutation et une abondance maximale, et celles qui sont initialement mieux adaptées passent moins de temps dans la zone à risque. Le temps du risque est maximal à des intensités de sélection intermédiaires, puisque de fortes sélections diminuent l'abondance et de faibles sélections ralentissent l'adaptation. Les simulations montrent un bon alignement quand les mutations sont rares et les tailles des populations sont petites. La compétition interspécifique diminue l'abondance de la population focale, en accroissant généralement le temps du risque, mais cela peut être compensé pour des scénarios particuliers par un accroissement de la pression de sélection. La réponse écologique et évolutive des populations naturelles à un changement environnemental dépend de phénomènes écologiques complexes. Les théories et les expériences qui incluent de tels phénomènes sont nécessaires pour des descriptions précises de l'adaptation génétique à un changement environnemental, à la fois en laboratoire et dans la nature.</description><creator>Osmond, Matthew</creator><contributor>Claire Seizilles de Mazancourt (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Biology - Ecology</subject><title>Eco-evolutionary rescue: an adaptive dynamic analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n2520.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82kc40r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hh32f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:17:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The retrovirus XMRV (xenotropic murine leukemia virus-related virus) was first identified in association with Chronic Fatigue Syndrome in 2009. Following the publication of this research there erupted a major controversy within the scientific literature over the status of the XMRV virus, that wound to a close in 2012 with the editorial retraction of the original research and the conclusion that the virus was a laboratory artefact. This paper maps the dynamics of the XMRV-CFS controversy, and how the status of the virus itself changed over the course thereof. The question of the "reality" of both the virus and its putative association with Chronic Fatigue Syndrome were pivotal to the actors involved, and the thesis focuses on how the endogenous discourses of artefactuality (along with the procedures, materials, and instrumentation with which such discourses were entangled) figured into the perpetuation and eventual resolution of the controversy.</description><description>Le rétrovirus XMRV (xenotropic murine leukemia virus-related virus) a été identifié pour la première fois en 2009 en association avec le Syndrome de fatigue chronique. Suite à la publication de ces recherches, une controverse importante a éclaté dans la presse scientifique quant au statut du virus XMRV. Cette controverse s'achèvera en 2012 avec la rétractation de l'article original et la révélation que le virus était en fait un artefact de laboratoire. Le présent mémoire retrace la dynamique de la controverse autour du couple XMRV-SFC en examinant de plu près le changement de statut du virus au cours de cette même controverse. La question de la « réalité » même du virus et celle de son lien putatif avec le Syndrome de fatigue chronique occupent une place centrale au sein du débat entre les scientifiques concernés. Le mémoire s'intéresse donc en particulier au rôle qu'ont joué dans la perpétuation et l'éventuelle résolution de la controverse les discours endogènes concernant l'artefactualité, ainsi que les instances matérielles (procédures, matériaux et équipements) rattachées à ces discours.</description><creator>Campbell, Jonah</creator><contributor>Alberto Cambrosio (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Sociology - Sociology General</subject><title>The XMRV virus: reality and artefactuality in scientific controversy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v667c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hh32f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pv63g416k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:17:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines two key periods in the American road movie genre with a particular emphasis on formations of identity as they are articulated through themes of marginality,freedom, and rebellion. The first period, what I term the "founding" period of the road moviegenre, includes six films of the 1960s and 1970s: Arthur Penn's Bonnie and Clyde (1967), Dennis Hopper's Easy Rider (1969), Francis Ford Coppola's The Rain People (1969), Monte Hellman's Two-Lane Blacktop (1971), Richard Sarafian's Vanishing Point (1971), and Joseph Strick's Road Movie (1974). The second period of the genre, what I identify as that of the "minority" road movie, occurs largely in the 1990s and includes Ridley Scott's Thelma &amp; Louise (1991), Gregg Araki's The Living End (1992), and Spike Lee's Get on the Bus (1996). Emphasizing the cinematic worlds, narrative trajectories, and identity politics of the road movie, I argue that "founding" road movies, though usually homogeneous in their portrayals of identity, are significant for later minority road movies because they establish points of rebellion that negotiate between dominant and marginal social relations that minority road movies would later revisit. These minority road movies (re)interpret the generic raw material of the past, tapping into a number of subgenres as well as themes of marginality, freedom, and rebellion, in order to introduce new identities to the genre. Important to the many exchanges between the two periods is the interplay of subgenres; as I will discuss, many of these films borrow, critique, and subvert the generic precedents of the past.</description><description>Cette thèse examine deux périodes clés du genre cinematographique des 'road-movies' américains en se concentrant sur les formations identitaires telles qu'elles sont articulées à travers les thèmes de la marginalité, de la liberté, et de la rébellion. La première période, que je qualifierais de période fondatrice du genre 'road-movie', comprend six films des années 1960 et1970: Bonnie and Clyde d'Arthur Penn (1967), Easy Rider de Dennis Hopper (1969), The Rain People de Francis Ford Coppola (1969), Two-Lane Blacktop de Monte Hellman (1971), Vanishing Point de Richard Sarafian (1971), et Road Movie de Joseph Strick (1974). La deuxième période du genre, que j'identifierais comme celle du 'road-movie' « minoritaire », est produite en grande partie dans les années 1990 et comprend Thelma &amp; Louise de Ridley Scott(1991), The Living End de Gregg Araki (1992), et Get on the Bus de Spike Lee (1996). En soulignant les univers cinématiques, les trajectoires narratives, et les politiques identitaires, je soutiens que les films «fondateurs», souvent homogènes dans leurs représentations identitaires, sont importants pour les « road-movies » minoritaires ultérieurs car ils établissent des points derébellion négociant entre des rapports sociaux de dominants a marginaux, eux-meme plus tard revisités par les films minoritaires. Ces « road-movies » minoritaires réinterpretent les matériaux génériques bruts du passé, mettant en valeur un certain nombre de sous-genres ainsi que les thèmes de la marginalité, la liberté, et la rébellion, afin d'introduire de nouvelles identités au genre. Le jeu des sous-genres est lui-meme important dans les nombreux échanges entre les deux périodes : je débats que plusieurs de ces films empruntent, critiquent et subvertissent les précédents génériques du passé.</description><creator>Hui-Bon-Hoa, Alan</creator><contributor>Straw, William O. (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Cinema</subject><title>Identity and marginality on the road: American road movies of the 1960s, 1970s and 1990s</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xj80h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pv63g416k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860b862</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:17:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Great competition drives the widespread application of lean value in many industries. Value identification and product delivery is challenging due to the various concerns of shareholders, the large number of disparate tasks, and the complex resource allocation process. The overall goal of this research, then, is to develop a value focused optimization process adopting an enterprise perspective by investigating value identification, decision support and resource allocation. Firstly, a multiple-attribute model is proposed to identify value covering all the important aspects of the decision objectives. Then, the large number of decision makers drives the development of a decision support method to determine value in an efficient and egalitarian way. Finally, the defined value is incorporated into a resource allocation procedure to optimize the value that is realized from limited resources. The research was validated through testing at an aerospace company.</description><description>La concurrence importante entraîne la mise en place des valeurs 'Lean' dans de nombreuses industries. L'identification de la valeur et la livraison du produit sont difficiles à cause des diverses soucis des parties prenantes, le nombre important des tâches distribuées et le processus complexe d'allocation des ressources. L'objectif global de cette recherche est de développer un processus d'optimisation basé sur le concept de valeur. Cela se fait en adoptant une perspective d'entreprise qui s'investit sur l'identification de valeur, l'aide à la décision et l'allocation des ressources.Tout d'abord, un modèle multi-attribut est proposé afin de définir la valeur comme étant un concept qui couvre tous les aspects importants des objectifs de décision. Puis, une méthode d'aide à la décision est développée à l'aide d'un grand nombre de décideurs pour déterminer la valeur d'une manière efficace et égalitaire. Enfin, la valeur définie est incorporée dans une procédure d'allocation des ressources, pour optimiser la valeur telle que réalisée à partir des ressources limitées. La recherche a été validée à travers une implémentation dans une entreprise aérospatiale.</description><creator>Zhang, Xiao Qi</creator><contributor>Vincent Thomson (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Akif Bulgak (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Engineering - Industrial</subject><title>Value optimization for engineering tasks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085q10j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860b862</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306t3224</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:17:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette étude porte sur l'Assemblée Générale de la Ville de New York (AGNY), une pratique délibérative basée sur le consensus. Cette pratique, qui épouse les valeurs d'inclusion et d'égalité, est au coeur des manifestations des indignés de « Occupy Wall Street ». La critique de cette pratique générée par des commentateurs politiques et selon laquelle celle-ci ne fabriquerait pas de demande singulière néglige cependant la matrice de valeurs et de normes sociales qui sous-tend tout événement communicatif, tels que l'AGNY. Par conséquent, le risque de cette critique est qu'elle ignore les façons dont l'AGNY construit, soutient et potentiellement transforme les relations sociales ainsi que leurs sujets socioculturels, et ce non seulement pendant, mais également au-delà des assemblées. Afin d'explorer ces processus de (re)production et de transformation de la vie sociale, cette étude propose une analyse linguistique de l'AGNY en deux parties : dans un premier temps, un examen des archives textuelles de l'AGNY (composées des documents écrits retenus par l'assemblée par voie de consensus, et des guides pratiques et des compte-rendus qui décrivent ces assemblées) et dans un deuxième temps, une analyse du déroulement de l'AGNY au travers de ses comptes-rendus et de ses enregistrements vidéo. Ces analyses démontrent que l'AGNY est un rituel pédagogique qui apprend à ces participants à intervenir (par voies d'interruptions ou plus idéalement, de transformations) au cours de discours interactifs, modifiant, par un processus de recontextualisation, les normes et les valeurs de ces discours.</description><description>This study focuses on a consensus-based deliberative practice, known as the New York City General Assembly (NYCGA). This practice, built on the values of inclusivity and equality of voice, is a key component of the Occupy Wall Street (OWS) protest. While political commentators have criticized the protest's lack of a singular demand, such a critique ignores the matrix of values and interactional norms that underlie communicative events occurring at the OWS camp, particularly the NYCGA.  Consequently, this critique risks overlooking the ways in which the NYCGA produces, reinforces, and potentially transforms social relationships and sociocultural subjects, both within the real-time of the assembly and beyond. To investigate these processes of (re)production and transformation of social life, I conduct a linguistic analysis of two different aspects of the NYCGA. Firstly, I analyze the textual archive of the NYCGA that comprises (1) written documents passed through the consensus process, and (2) how-to guides and minutes produced about the consensus process. Secondly, I analyze performances of this discursive practice reconstructed through minutes and video footage. I suggest the NYCGA is a pedagogic ritual that equips participants to disrupt, or more ideally transform, ongoing discursive interactions by recontextualizing them and thus shifting their norms and attendant values.</description><creator>McElgunn, Hannah</creator><contributor>Roberta Lentz (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>William O Straw (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Language - General</subject><title>The discursive (re)production and transformation of social life at the occupy wall street general assembly</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq9780030.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t3224</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214t25n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:17:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La masse ventriculaire gauche (MVG) du coeur corrèle étroitement avec la mortalité et morbidité cardio-vasculaires chez l'humain, et constitue un important facteur de risque indépendant.  En utilisant une collection de 24 souches de souris recombinantes consanguines AxB/BxA (dérivées de croisements entre les cousches parentales A/J et C57BL/6J), notre laboratoire avait précédemment identifié sur le chromosome (chr) 13 un locus majeur en liaison avec la MVG.  Pour élargir ces données, notre laboratoire a utilisé des micropuces à ADN Illumina pour mesurer le profil d'expression de gènes de 4 cœurs de souris mâles de chacune des souches recombinantes consanguines.  Sur la base d'une analyse préliminaire (utilisant une carte génomique d'une banque de données publique, notre laboratoire utilisa des puces à ADN Illumina pour analyser les profils d'expressions des gènes de 4 cœurs de souris mâles de chacune des souches recombinantes consanguines.  Une analyse préliminaire (utilisant une carte génomique disponible d'une banque de données publiques) permit ainsi d'identifier un total de 456 "cis-acting eQTLs » (cis-eQTLs), parmi lesquels 15 avaient des niveaux d'expression corrélant avec les valeurs de MVG.  Bien que les banques de données contenaient peu d'annotation concernant ces gènes, la banque de données SymAtlas indiquait que la plupart d'entre eux étaient exprimés de façon plus importante dans les cellules provenant de la lignée myéloïde (comprenant les macrophages et les mastocytes) que dans des myocytes cardiaques.  En faisant d'autres investigations à l'aide de cultures primaires de macrophages dérivées de moëlle osseuse de souris Balb/c, nous pûmes : 1) vérifier que ces gènes étaient effectivement exprimés dans ces cellules ; 2) observer que leur niveau d'expression était modulé par des conditions modifiant le phénotype des macrophages ; et 3) démontrer que leur niveau d'expression peut être diminué en transfectant les cellules par des « Dicer silencing RNAs ».    Lors d'une deuxième phase du projet, notre laboratoire obtint une carte génomique plus dense, ce qui permit d'identifier un total de 1195 cis-eQTLs.  Parmi ces gènes, 33 corrélaient de façon significative (P &lt; 0.05) avec les valeurs de MVG, et 10/33 étaient concentrés dans un intervalle de 10 MB centré autour du locus du chr13 en liason avec la MVG.  D'autres analyses de RT-PCR révélèrent que l'expression de ces gènes dans des cultures primaires de macrophages variaient en fonction du génotype A/B de ces cellules.  Comme une telle concentration de multiples cis-eQTLs corrélant tous avec les valeurs de MVG suggérait la présence d'un régulateur commun, nous avons poursuivi nos recherches dans des banques de données génomiques, et avons pu constater que ce même intervalle de 10 MB contenait le locus du gène de micro-ARN mir-23b-27b-24-1.  De façon intéressante, il a été rapporté que le micro-ARN mir-27b pouvait être lié à des changements de MVG. En résumé, ces travaux ont confirmé qu'il était faisable d'utiliser des cultures primaires de macrophages pour faire des validations biologiques concernant les rôles et/ou les caractéristiques de gènes candidats liés à la MVG.  L'utilisation de telles cellules permettra de tester si des altérations de la concentration intracellulaire de mir-27B peut réguler l'abondance des transcrits de certains de nos autres gènes candidats.  Puisque d'autres données de la littérature indiquent que les macrophages peuvent jouer un rôle dans les processus de remodelage ventriculaire, ces résultats pourront mener à d'autres expériences menant à déterminer si ces gènes peuvent mener à des changements de MVG via leur niveau d'expression dans les macrophages.</description><description>Cardiac left ventricular mass (LVM) correlates tightly with cardiovascular morbidity and mortality in human populations, and constitutes an important independent predictor of cardiovascular risk. Using 24 mouse AxB/BxA recombinant inbred strains (RIS) (derived from crosses between A/J and C57BL/6J parents), our laboratory previously detected one major QTL linked to LVM on Chromosome (chr) 13. To extend these data, our laboratory used Illumina microarrays to obtain the profile of gene expression in 4 hearts of male mice from all RIS. By using first a publicly available genomic map, our laboratory identified initially a total of 456 cis-acting eQTLs (cis-eQTLs), 15 of which showing expression levels correlating with LVM.  Although little functional annotation was available for these genes, the SymAtlas database indicated that most of them were expressed at higher levels in cells from the myeloid lineage (i.e. macrophages and/or mast cells) than in cardiac myocytes. By further using bone-marrow derived macrophages (BMDMΦ) from Balb/c mice, we: 1) verified that these genes were indeed expressed in such cells; 2) observed that their expression level was modulated by conditions known to affect the phenotypic properties of macrophages; 3) demonstrated that their expression could be knocked down by transfection with Dicer silencing RNAs.   In a second phase of the project, the laboratory obtained a denser genetic map that allowed for the identification of a total of 1195 cis-eQTLs.  Among corresponding genes, 33 showed significant correlation (p &lt; 0.05) with LVM, and 10/33 genes clustered within a 10 MB interval centered around the QTL linked to LVM on chr 13.  Further RT-PCR analyses revealed that the expression levels of these genes varied in BMDMΦ cells according to the A/B genotype.  Since the clustering of 10 cis-eQTLs all correlating with LVM suggested the presence of a common regulator, we further analyzed genome databases and noticed that the same interval contained the locus of the mir-23b-27b-24-1 microRNA gene cluster. Interestingly, mir-27b has been reported to be functionally related to changes in LVM.  Altogether, these experiments establish the feasibility of using primary macrophage cultures for further biologic validation of the roles and/or properties of candidate genes linked to LVM.  Using these cells, it will be possible to test whether alterations in the intracellular concentration of miR-27b may regulate the abundance of the transcripts of other candidate genes from our locus of interest. In light of evidence reporting that macrophages may play a role in left ventricular remodeling, this may lead to future experiments testing how these genes may contribute via expression within macrophages to changes in LVM.</description><creator>Gupta, Swati</creator><contributor>Christian Deschepper (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>Utilization of primary cultures of macrophages for biologic validation of candidate genes linked to left ventricular hypertrophy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999b75h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214t25n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pg15bk00p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:17:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Contexte: Metformine est un agent hypoglycémique oral (AHO) couramment prescrit chez les patients avec diabète de type 2 (DNID). In vivo et in vitro ont suggéré que la metformine a un potentiel anti-tumoral effets et donc le potentiel pour diminuer l'incidence du cancer. Alors que les études observationnelles ont également suggéré revendications similaires, ils avaient d'importantes limites méthodologiques afin que leurs résultats doivent être confirmés en utilisant des méthodes plus rigoureuses. Objective: Évaluez si la médication contre le diabète, metformine, est associé avec une diminution du taux d'incidence de cancer des poumons, et colorectal chez les patients avec DNID. Méthodes d'analyse et de conception: En utilisant les données de la base de données du United Kingdom General Practice Research Database (GPRD), une grande base de données informatisée composée de dossiers de soins primaires aux patients longitudinale, deux basées sur la population des études de cohorte ont été menées, l'une d'incidence du cancer colorectal enquêter chez les patients atteints de DNID et l'autre axée sur l'incidence du cancer du poumon chez les patients atteints de DNID. Tous les cas de cancer colorectal ou du poumon survenant au cours du suivi de la cohorte (selon la cohorte du cancer) de tous les patients atteints de DIND qui avaient été prescrits au moins un AHO entre 1988 et 2009 ont été identifiés. Jusqu'à 10 contrôles choisis au hasard ont été choisis au sein de la cohorte des risques fixés et appariés selon l'âge, le sexe, l'année civile de l'entrée dans la cohorte, et la durée du suivi. L'exposition primaire a été définie comme l'exposition à la metformine jamais avant l'ensemble des risques de suivi du temps, ainsi qu'en termes de nombre d'ordonnances a reçu la metformine pour examiner la relation dose-réponse. Une régression logistique conditionnelle a été utilisée pour estimer les rapports de taux ajustés (RRs) et les intervalles de confiance à 95% (IC).Résultats: La cohorte du cancer colorectal été compris de 115 578 utilisateurs des AHO, incluant 607 cas de cancer colorectal et 5837 contrôles jumelées. Metformine n'étais pas associé avec la risque du cancer colorectal (RR: 0.94; 95% IC: 0.7-1.2). De plus, il n'y avait aucune changement significatif observer concernant l'incidence des deux cancers quand le nombre de prescription de metformine et pris en compte.   La cohorte se composait de cancer du poumon 115 923 utilisateurs des AHOs, où 808 cas de cancer du poumon ont été appariés à 7764 contrôles. La metformine n'a eu aucune incidence sur le risque de cancer du poumon (RR: 0.94; 95% IC: 0.8-1.2). Il n'y avait aussi pas de changements significatifs observés dans l'incidence du cancer soit lors de l'examen pour le nombre de prescriptions de metformine reçue.Conclusions: L'utilisation de metformine n'est pas associée à une diminution colorectal ou de l'incidence du cancer du poumon chez les patients atteints de DNID. Ces résultats contredisent l'incidence du cancer ont diminué associés à l'utilisation de metformine rapportés dans les études observationnelles précédentes qui n'ont pas correctement en compte le temps.Mots Clés: Diabète de type 2 (DNID), Agent hypoglycémique oral (AHOs), Metformine, Cancer des poumons, Cancer colorectal, United Kingdom General Practice Research Database (GPRD)</description><description>Background: Metformin is an oral hypoglycemic agent (OHA) commonly prescribed in patients with type 2 diabetes (T2DM). In vivo and in vitro studies have suggested that metformin has potential anti-tumour effects and may thus decrease cancer incidence. While observational studies have also suggested similar effects, they had important methodological limitation so that their results need to be confirmed using more rigorous methods.Objective: To assess whether the anti-diabetic medication metformin is associated with a decreased incidence of lung and colorectal cancer in patients with T2DM.Research Design and Methods: Using data from the United Kingdom General Practice Research Database, a large computerized database composed of primary care longitudinal patient records; two population-based cohort studies were conducted, one investigating colorectal cancer incidence in patients with T2DM and the other focused on lung cancer incidence in patients with T2DM. All colorectal or lung cancer cases occurring during follow-up of the cohort (depending on cancer being studied) of all patients with T2DM who had been prescribed at least one OHAs between 1988 and 2009 were identified. For each study, up to 10 randomly selected controls were selected from the cohort within the risk set and matched on age, sex, calendar year of cohort entry, and duration of follow-up. Primary exposure was defined as ever exposure to metformin prior to the risk set follow-up time, as well as in terms of number of metformin prescriptions received to examine the dose-response relationship. Conditional logistic regression was used to estimate adjusted rate ratios (RRs) and corresponding 95% confidence intervals (CIs).Results: The colorectal cancer cohort was comprised of 115,578 users of OHAs, including 607 cases of colorectal cancer and 5837 matched controls. Metformin was not associated with a change in the incidence of colorectal cancer (RR: 0.94; 95% CI: 0.7-1.2). The lung cancer cohort consisted of 115,923 users of OHAs, where 808 cases of lung cancer were matched with 7764 controls. Metformin had no impact on the risk of lung cancer (RR: 0.94; 95% CI: 0.8-1.2). There were also no significant changes observed in incidence of either cancer when examining the number of prescriptions of metformin patients' received. Conclusions: Metformin use is not associated with a decreased colorectal or lung cancer incidence in patients with T2DM. These findings contradict decreased cancer incidence associated with metformin use reported in previous observational studies that did not properly account for time. Keywords: Type 2 Diabetes (T2DM), Oral Hypoglycemic Agents (OHAs), Metformin, Lung Cancer, Colorectal Cancer, United Kingdom General Practice Research Database (GPRD)</description><creator>Smiechowski, Brielan</creator><contributor>Samy Suissa (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</subject><title>Metformin use and the incidence of colorectal and lung cancer in patients with type 2 diabetes mellitus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pf584.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bk00p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z494m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:17:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les comptes rendus narratifs médiévaux du mauvais comportement des femmes sont profondément ancrés dans des perceptions sociales et des attentes qui découlent de notions du genre. Les femmes décrites dans ces récits non fictifs du douzième siècle et qui font l'objet de ce mémoire n'ont pas eu un mauvais comportement selon les normes légales ou morales de l'époque. Ce sont les objectifs et les intentions des femmes, plutôt que leurs gestes précis qui figurent comme source d'inquiétude dans ces textes. Dans tous les épisodes analysés, j'ai découvert une quête d'autonomie et d'indépendance des femmes par rapport aux  contrôles social et culturel. C'est ce désir volontaire d'autonomie qui suscite la désapprobation des auteurs médiévaux. Le premier chapitre est axé sur le choix matrimonial, un des rares domaines de la vie sociale médiévale où les jeunes femmes pouvaient exprimer un certain jugement indépendant en dépit des contraintes familiales, sociales et culturelles. Je soutiens que la résistance des femmes à la pression extérieure est souvent représentée sur des tons mysogynes exagérés. D'autre part, le comportement féminin qui inspire l'approbation d'un auteur est souvent transposé en caractéristiques masculines. Dans le deuxième chapitre, l'accent est mis sur la question du veuvage. Dans les représentations narratives des veuves, le lien profond entre l'exercice de l'autonomie féminine et le discours misogyne médiéval émerge. La perception médiévale du genre des sexes reposait forcément sur le concept central de la subordination des femmes comme étant naturel et nécessaire à l'organisation sociale. Les actions qui font fi de cet ordre des choses furent invariablement narrées de façon négative. Les veuves qui cherchent à briser les liens qui les unissent à leurs gardiens mâles sont notamment représentées en termes très critiques.</description><description>Medieval narrative accounts of female misbehaviour reflect deep social perceptions and expectations grounded in ideas of gender. The women described in the twelfth-century non-fiction narratives analysed in this thesis had not behaved in an objectively "bad" way, judged by legal or moral standards. Rather, the disapproving depiction of women's behaviour reflects the author's concern with the women's goals and intentions, rather than their specific actions. In all the episodes I analysed, I found a search for autonomy and independence from social and cultural control on the part of the women. It is this wilful desire for autonomy that incurs the medieval authors' disapproval. The first chapter focuses on marital choice, one of the few areas of medieval social life in which young women could express a certain degree of independent judgement in spite of familial, social, and cultural constraints. I argue that female resistance to outside pressure is often depicted in exaggerated misogynistic tones. On the other hand, female behaviour which inspires the approval of an author is often transposed into masculine characteristics. In the second chapter, the focus shifts to widowhood. In narrative depictions of widows, the deep connection between the exercise of female autonomy and medieval misogynistic discourse emerges. Medieval perceptions of gender necessarily rested on the core concept of female subordination as natural and necessary to social organization. Actions that challenged this assumption were invariably cast in a negative light. Widows seeking to sever the ties that bound them to male guardians are represented in highly critical terms.</description><creator>Vittorelli, Margherita</creator><contributor>Nancy F Partner (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>History - Medieval</subject><title>Women's stories, male voices: narratives of female misbehaviour in medieval Europe</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd3761741.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z494m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History and Classical Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns064978h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:17:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The environmental change experienced by many contemporary populations of living organisms poses a serious risk to their survival. From the theory of evolutionary rescue we predict that the combination of diversity and sex should increase the probability of survival by increasing genetic variation and consequently increasing the probability of generating a type that can tolerate the stressful environment. I tested this prediction by comparing six kinds of experimental populations of Chlamydomonas reinhardtii that differ in the initial amount of genetic diversity and in sexuality. The lines were serially propagated in an environment where the salt concentration increased over time, which strongly inhibits growth, going from fresh water conditions to the limits of marine conditions. Two evolutionary rescue events occurred, one attributable to the sorting of the genetic variation initially contained in each line and to selection on genetic variation generated by recombination, and the second attributable to selection on genetic variation generated by mutations. In spite of the initial costs of high diversity and sex, in the long term, the combination of high diversity and obligate sexuality greatly enhanced survival in the deteriorating environment. Most of the adaptation to high-salt environments in the obligate sexual-high diversity lines had occurred by mid-way through the experiment, indicating that positive genetic correlations of adaptation to lethal stress with adaptation to sublethal stress greatly increased the probability of evolutionary rescue. The evolutionary rescue events observed in this study provide evidence that major shifts in ways of life can arise within short time frames, through the action of natural selection.</description><description>La survie de plusieurs populations d'organismes vivants est sérieusement menacée actuellement par les changements environnementaux auxquels elles sont exposées. Selon la théorie de sauvetage évolutif, la haute diversité génétique et la reproduction sexuée en combiné devraient augmenter le taux de survie, en augmentant le montant de variation génétique et par conséquent en augmentant la probabilité qu'un type survienne qui soit résistant au stress. J'ai testé cette prédiction en comparant six différentes sorte de populations expérimentales de Chlamydomonas reinhardtii qui diffèrent par le niveau initial de diversité et par le mode de reproduction. Les lignées ont été propagées dans un environnement où la concentration en sel augmentait avec le temps, de façon à grandement inhiber leur croissance, allant de conditions d'eaux douces jusqu'aux limites des conditions marines. Deux évènements de sauvetage évolutifs ont été observés, le premier attribuable au triage de la variation génétique qui était présente dans les lignées au départ et à la sélection de la variation génétique qui a été générée par la recombinaison génétique, et le deuxième attribuable à la sélection de la variation génétique qui a été générée par des mutations. Malgré les coûts initiaux qu'ont engendré la haute diversité génétique et la reproduction sexuée, à  long terme, la combinaison de haute diversité génétique et de reproduction sexuée obligatoire a grandement augmenté le taux de survie dans l'environnement en détérioration. La grande majorité de l'adaptation à de hautes concentrations de sel est apparue dès la mi-chemin de l'expérience dans les lignés de reproduction sexuée obligatoire et haute diversité génétique, indiquant qu'une corrélation génétique positive entre l'adaptation à un stress létal et l'adaptation à un stress non-létal augmente considérablement la probabilité de sauvetage évolutif. Les évènements de sauvetage évolutifs observés dans cette étude démontrent que des changements importants dans le mode de vie peuvent survenir sur de courtes périodes de temps par l'entremise de la sélection naturelle.</description><creator>Lachapelle, Josianne</creator><contributor>Graham Bell (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Biology - Ecology</subject><title>The effect of sex and diversity on evolutionary rescue in experimental populations of Chlamydomonas reinhardtii</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h570x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064978h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52jc81d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:17:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>'Honeycrisp', une nouvelle variété de pommes, est susceptible à l'échaudure molle (ÉM) et au brunissement interne (BI). Des conditions froides à la fin du développement des pommes induiraient leur développement. Des 'Honeycrisp' ont été récoltées en Ontario (trois sites), au Québec (deux sites) et en Nouvelle-Écosse (un site), en 2009 et 2010, avec l'ajout de données de l'Ontario (quatre site) entre 2002 et 2006. Des analyses ont été faites pour lier la qualité des pommes aux conditions météorologiques. Une combinaison de conditions sèches (aux stades phénologiques BBCH 71-75) et de températures froides  (BBCH 65-71 et 77.5-80) augmenterait l'incidence d'ÉM, alors que des conditions froides et de fortes précipitations (BBCH 77.5-80) intensifierait le BI. Deux modèles de prédiction ont été développés pour l'ÉM (RMSE = 18.71) et le BI (RMSE = 6.88). Ceux-ci peuvent servir d'outils aidant les producteurs à élaborer une stratégie de mise en marché appropriée, selon les conditions régionales et saisonnières.</description><description>'Honeycrisp', a new apple cultivar, has high susceptibility to physiological disorders, including soft scald (SS) and soggy breakdown (SB). An important factor inducing these disorders is cool weather conditions at the end of the growing season. 'Honeycrisp' apples were harvested in Ontario (three sites), Québec (two sites) and in Nova Scotia (one site), in 2009 and 2010, in addition to data from Ontario (four sites), from 2002 to 2006. Analyses were made to link fruit quality to the weather at each site. A combination of dry conditions (for phenological stages BBCH 71-75), and cool conditions (BBCH 65-71 and 77.5-80) increased SS susceptibility. A combination of cool and wet conditions (BBCH 77.5-80) increased SB susceptibility. Models were developed for SS (RMSE = 18.71) and SB (RMSE = 6.88) predictions. Producers could use these in establishing more appropriate management of fresh fruit loads depending on regional and seasonal susceptibility to these disorders.</description><creator>Lachapelle, Maude</creator><contributor>Katrine A Stewart (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Philippe Seguin (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Agriculture - Plant Physiology</subject><title>Modelling the effect of preharvest climate conditions on the incidence of two postharvest physiological disorders of "Honeycrisp" apple</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042z10d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52jc81d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k0698c74w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:17:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recently, group III-nitride nanowire heterostructures have been extensively investigated. Due to the effective lateral stress relaxation, such nanoscale heterostructures can be epitaxially grown on silicon or other foreign substrates and can exhibit drastically reduced dislocations and polarization fields, compared to their planar counterparts. This dissertation reports on the achievement of a new class of III-nitride nanoscale heterostructures, including InGaN/GaN dot-in-a-wires and nearly defect-free InN nanowires on a silicon platform. We have further developed a new generation of nanowire devices, including ultrahigh-efficiency full-color light emitting diodes (LEDs) and solar cells on a silicon platform.We have identified two major mechanisms, including poor hole transport and electron overflow, that severely limit the performance of GaN-based nanowire LEDs. With the incorporation of the special techniques of p-type modulation doping and AlGaN electron blocking layer in the dot-in-a-wire LED active region, we have demonstrated phosphor-free white-light LEDs that can exhibit, for the first time, internal quantum efficiency of &gt; 50%, negligible efficiency droop up to ~ 2,000A/cm2, and extremely high stable emission characteristics at room temperature, which are ideally suited for future smart lighting and full-color display applications.We have also studied the epitaxial growth, fabrication and characterization of InN:Mg/i-InN/InN:Si nanowire axial structures on n-type Si(111) substrates and demonstrated the first InN nanowire solar cells. Under one-sun (AM 1.5G) illumination, the devices exhibit a short-circuit current density of ~ 14.4 mA/cm2, open circuit voltage of 0.14 V , fill factor of 34.0%, and energy conversion efficiency of 0.68%. This work opens up exciting possibilities for InGaN nanowire-based, full solar-spectrum third-generation solar cells.</description><description>Récemment, les hétérostructures à base de nitride et de groupe III ont fait l'objet de recherches intensives. Grâce à la relaxation latérale effective du stress, de telles hétérostructures d'échelle nanométrique peuvent être déposés sur du Silicium ou d'autres substrats. Celles-ci démontrent une réduction dramatique des dislocations et des champs de polarisations comparativement à leurs contreparties planes. Cette dissertation rapporte l'accomplissement d'une nouvelle classe de matériau nanométrique, soit des hétérostructures III-nitride incluant InGaN/GaN point dans fils ainsi que des nanofils d'InN presque sans défauts sur du Silicium. De plus, nous avons développé une nouvelle génération de dispositifs à base de nanofils, incluant des diodes émettrices de lumière (LEDs) à efficacité ultra haute et spectre visible complet ainsi que des cellules solaires sur une gaufre de Silicium. Nous avons identifié 2 mécanismes majeurs, incluant le faible transport des trous et le surplus d'électrons, qui limitent sérieusement la performance des LEDs à base de nanofils de GaN. Avec l'ajout de certaines techniques spéciales de modulation de type p, et une couche bloquante d'électrons faite de AlGaN dans la région active de la LED point dans fil. Par ailleurs, nous avons démontré des LEDs blanche sans phosphore qui démontrent, pour la première fois, une efficacité quantique supérieure à 50% ainsi qu'une baisse d'efficacité négligeable jusqu'à ~ 2,000A/cm2 et des caractéristiques d'émissions très hautes et stables à température pièce. Celles-ci sont donc toutes désignées pour des applications d'illumination intelligentes et des écrans pleines couleurs. La croissance par épitaxie, la fabrication et la caractérisation des nanofils d'InN:Mg/i-InN/InN:Si axiaux sur des substrats de Si(111) de type n et démontré la première cellule solaire à base d'InN. Sous l'illumination d'un soleil (AM 1.5G), les dispositifs démontrent une densité de courant de ~ 14.4 mA/cm2 en court-circuit, un voltage de circuit ouvert de 0.14V, un facteur de remplissage de 34.0% et une efficacité de conversion d'énergie de 0.68%. Ce travail ouvre des portes excitantes pour des cellules solaires plein spectre de troisième génération à base de nanofils d'InGaN.</description><creator>Nguyen, Hieu</creator><contributor>Zetian Mi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Engineering - Materials Science</subject><title>Molecular beam epitaxial growth, characterization and device applications of III-Nitride nanowire heterostructures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92gc30r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698c74w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150p08n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:17:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Land application of biosolids from activated sludge wastewater treatment plant (WWTP) is an attractive disposal solution. However, to be land applied in the US and Canada, biosolids need to meet specific pathogen loads regulations at the time of land application (i.e., not immediately after treatment). This study examined bacterial regrowth potential after electro-dewatering of biosolids. During a 8-min typical electro-dewatering treatment performed in the laboratory or a control heat treatment, Escherichia coli and fecal coliform (FC) counts were reduced to below the detection limit. After treatment, the extent of E. coli and FC regrowth was assessed by incubating the biosolids in aerobic or anaerobic conditions. After aerobic incubation, FC and E. coli counts stabilized between 107-109 MPN/g-dry solids in all biosolids samples irrespective of treatments (electro-dewatering, heat-treatment and no treatment) despite different levels of pH and dryness. Total aerobic counts also stabilized between 107-109 CFU/g-dry solids after four days of incubation. Finally, stable FC and E. coli counts at the end of incubation of samples prepared by belt filter press during winter were 1 log lower than in samples prepared by centrifuge press during the summer. Although similar trends about the effects of dewatering processes were reported in the literature, it is not be possible to conclude because seasonal factors are confounded with process factors. After anaerobic incubation, E. coli and FC counts in electro-dewatered biosolids stabilized 1 log lower than their respective counts in heat-treated or not treated biosolids (107-108 vs 108-109 MPN/g-dry solids, respectively). This difference was not changed when electro-dewatering filtrate was added back into the electro-dewatered biosolids. At WWTP, biosolids are typically stored as large piles. It is therefore likely that a major portion of piles is anaerobic, and that storage (hence regrowth) takes place under anaerobic condition. This study suggests that the electro-dewatered biosolids would exhibit a lower level of regrowth than other biosolids. Microbial counts observed in this study would not allow land application of these biosolids after 7-day storage because the lowest counts observed for electro-dewatered biosolids under anaerobic conditions were just above the requirements for the US-EPA Class B (FC counts above106 MPN/g-dry solids). However, these results suggest that this technology could be improved such that biosolids could meet land application regulations even after extended storage periods.</description><description>L'épandage de biosolides provenant des usines de traitement d'eaux usées par boues activées est une solution d'élimination intéressante. Toutefois, pour être épandues aux États-Unis et au Canada, les biosolides doivent répondre à des réglementations visant à limiter la quantité d'organismes pathogènes au moment de l'épandage (et non pas immédiatement après le traitement). Cette étude a examiné le potentiel de repousse bactérienne après électro-déshydratation des biosolides. Lors d'un traitement d'électro-déshydratation typique de 8 minutes effectué dans un laboratoire ou un traitement thermique de contrôle, le compte total d'Escherichia coli et de coliformes fécaux (CF) étaient en deca de la limite de détection. Après le traitement, l'étendue de la repousse de E. coli et de CF a été évaluée par incubation des biosolides dans des conditions aérobies ou anaérobies.Après une incubation aérobie, les comptes de CF et E. coli se sont stabilisés entre 107 à 109 NPP / g matières solides sèches dans tous les échantillons de biosolides, indépendamment des traitements (électro-déshydratation, traitement thermique et aucun traitement), malgré les différents niveaux de pH et de sécheresse. Les comptes aérobies totaux se sont également stabilisé entre 107 à 109 UFC / g de matières solides sèches, après quatre jours d'incubation. Enfin, le compte de FC et E. coli à la fin de l'incubation des échantillons préparés par des presses à filtres à bande au cours de l'hiver ont été 1 log inférieure à celle des échantillons préparés par des presses centrifugeuses pendant l'été. Bien que des tendances similaires sur les effets des procédés de déshydratation aient été rapportées dans la littérature, il n'est pas possible de conclure puisque les facteurs saisonniers sont confondus avec les facteurs de procédés. Après une incubation anaérobie, les comptes de E. coli et de CF dans les biosolides électro-déshydratées étaient 1 log inférieure aux compte respectif dans les biosolides traités thermiquement ou non traités (107-108 vs 108-109 NPP / g matières solides sèches, respectivement). Cette différence n'a pas été modifiée lorsque le filtrat d'électro-déshydratation a été rajouté dans le biosolides électro-déshydratées. A l'usine de traitement des eaux usées, les biosolides sont généralement stockés sous forme de monticule. Il est donc probable que la majeure partie des monticules soit anaérobie, et que le stockage (et donc la repousse) se déroule dans des conditions anaérobies. Cette étude suggère que les biosolides électro-déshydratées présentent un niveau inférieur de repousse des indicateurs pathogènes bactériens que d'autres biosolides. L'énumération microbienne observée dans cette étude ne permettrait pas l'épandage de ces biosolides après 7 jours d'entreposage, parce que même les énumérations les plus basses demeurent au-dessus des exigences pour le US-EPA classe B (FC &gt; 106 NPP / g matières solides sèches). Toutefois, ces résultats suggèrent que cette technologie pourrait être améliorée de telle sorte que les biosolides peuvent respecter les règlements d'application sur les terres arables, même après des périodes d'entreposage étendues.</description><creator>Gul-e-Hina, Ms</creator><contributor>Dominic Frigon (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Engineering - Civil</subject><title>Regrowth of bacterial pathogen indicators in electro- dewatered biosolids</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w6634748n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150p08n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d570153r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:17:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse présente une méthodologie pour la prédiction de la fiabilité des roues lunaires, et une technique pour évaluer la fiabilité de la conception de ces roues, pour lesquelles les données d'opération dans l'environnement lunaire ne sont pas disponibles, afin que nous puissions effectuer une analyse de fiabilité traditionnelle. La distance maximale traversée par le Rover Lunaire durant la mission Apollo 17 était d'environ 35.9 km. Aujourd'hui, l'Université de McGill, le groupe Neptec Design et l'Agence Spatiale Canadienne travaillent ensemble afin de développer une roue de Rover Lunaire pouvant être opérationnelle pendant 5 ans. Cela souligne l'importance de la fiabilité des roues, qui auront à traverser des milliers de kilomètres. Le groupe Neptec Design a réussi à développer une méthodologie afin d'estimer la fiabilité d'un rover lunaire, comme nous le montre le document Prédiction de Fiabilité de Rover Lunaire (PFRL) qui a été publié par l'entreprise. Cette méthodologie comprend deux phases.  Phase 1 contient trois étapes incluant les recherches approfondies concernant les différents modèles de fiabilité disponibles, les outils logiciels spécifiques qui permettent la mise en place de ces modèles, et l'habilité à adapter ces outils à l'environnement lunaire (par exemple, la température, la présence de régolite, les radiations, l'apesanteur). La Phase 2 décrit le processus d'estimation de la fiabilité du rover lunaire pour une durée de 5 ans sur la Lune, basé sur les recommandations détaillées dans la Phase 1.  Le PFRL a été un succès mais Neptec est seulement capable d'utiliser des données earthbound pour la méthodologie, ce qui est insuffisant. Donc, le domaine de l'usure à la cryogénie à été exploré à travers la littérature et les bases de données, et le résumé des éléments qui ont été relevés intéressants est le suivant : le taux d'usure de l'acier et du titane à 293K et 77K sont à peu près les mêmes, en dessous de 1m/s ; le taux d'usure à 77K en dessous de 1m/s est plus haut pour la plupart des matériaux et le coefficient de frottements pour l'acier sur l'acier à 77K et 273K est à peu près le même. Cela souligne la nécessité d'une méthodologie alternative, par exemple, la technique d'inspection visuelle, pour évaluer la fiabilité d'un système quand des données utiles ne sont pas disponible. La technique d'inspection visuelle est décrite et une analyse de 9 conceptions de roues (cinq anciennes roues et quatre nouvelles roues conçues par l'Université de McGill) est démontrée. Les conceptions des roues sont analysées visuellement en fonction de critères spécifiques, sans négliger les risques d'échec potentiels si l'on transpose aux conditions lunaires (température, aspiration, et régolites), la fiabilité mécanique, sans oublier les obstacles à la performance, la résistance à l'usure, la compatibilité thermale, la vitesse de chargement, la torsion, etc. Une échelle numérique a été créée et la performance potentielle de la roue a été quantifiée en prenant compte des évènements pouvant causer un échec comme les fluctuations de températures, le soudage à froid, les impacts de rochers, un excès de charge et une usure abrasive. Les résultats ont indiqué que la meilleure conception historique était la roue à treillis métallique d'Apollo 17 et que la meilleure conception contemporaine est la roue iRing. L'exposé donne aussi une "liste de conception pour la fiabilité", qui peut potentiellement servir de guide afin d'éviter les traits de conceptions avec des failles.  La technique d'inspection visuelle a été un succès et peut être appliquée à d'autres systèmes complexes où les tests expérimentaux dans les conditions actuelles ne sont pas possibles.  Cependant, des connaissances préliminaires et une expertise sont nécessaires afin de mettre en place l'évaluation.</description><description>This thesis presents a methodology for prediction of reliability for a lunar rover and a technique to evaluate reliability where data for operation in the lunar environment are not available in order to conduct traditional reliability analysis.  This technique was applied to lunar rover wheel designs.The maximum distance travelled by the Lunar Roving Vehicle (LRV) during the Apollo 17 mission was approximately 35.9 km. Presently, McGill University, Neptec and the Canadian Space Agency are collaborating to develop a wheel set for an LRV, which is targeted to have a five-year operational service. This underlines the importance of the reliability of an LRV, which will be required to travel thousands of kilometres. The Neptec Design Group has developed a methodology to estimate the reliability of a lunar rover, i.e., the Lunar Rover Reliability Prediction (LRRP) where the project was divided into two phases. Phase 1 consisted of three milestones which included background research of the various reliability models currently available, the specific software tools that execute these models, and the ability to adapt these tools to account for lunar environmental factors (e.g., temperature, regolith, low gravity). Results demonstrated that Relex provided a strong package of fully integrated software tools to execute a group of reliability models (FMEA [Failure Modes and Effects Analysis], Fault Tree, Standards Prediction, ALT [Accelerated Life Testing]). Mission simulation software was identified to be a worthwhile addition and GoldSim was considered to be the best choice to provide mission simulation analysis. Phase 2 outlined the process for estimating the reliability of a lunar rover for a 5-year operational life on the moon based on the recommendations detailed in Phase 1. LRRP has been a success, but Neptec was only able to obtain earth bound data for use in the methodology. Hence, research on cryogenic wear was explored and the summary of relevant findings is as follows: the wear rate of steel and titanium at 293K and 77K are about the same below a sliding speed of 1m/s; the wear rate at 77K above 1m/s is higher for most materials and the coefficient of friction for steel on steel at 77K and 273 K is about the same. The information present in the literature is insufficient to evaluate LRV reliability under lunar environmental conditions. This underlines the necessity for an alternative methodology, for instance, the visual inspection technique, to evaluate reliability of systems (e.g., a lunar rover), where useful data are not available.The visual inspection technique is described and an analysis of five historical wheels and four new wheels designed by McGill University is given. The wheel designs were visually analysed according to specific criteria with respect to potential failure under lunar conditions (temperature, vacuum, regolith) considering wear resistance, thermal compatibility, excess loading, torque, etc. Potential wheel performance was quantified using a numerical scale with respect to potential failure due to events, such as temperature fluctuation, wheel-rock impact, excess payload and abrasive wear. The best designs were the Apollo 17 wire mesh wheel (historical) and the iRing wheel (McGill). A reliability checklist for lunar wheel designs is given to serve as a guideline to avoid unreliable design features. The visual inspection technique was successful and can be applied to other complex systems where experimental testing under actual conditions is not possible, although background knowledge and expert opinion are necessary to perform an evaluation.</description><creator>Parbatani, Karim</creator><contributor>Vincent Thomson (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical</subject><title>Reliability analysis of lunar rover wheel designs - methodology and visual inspection technique</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q559f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d570153r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kx87r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T21:17:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les introns de groupe II sont de grands ribozymes qui s'épissent des transcrits pré-ARNm par eux mêmes de façon autocatalytique. Ils sont présents chez les bactéries, les archaebactéries et dans les organelles des eucaryotes inférieures et des plantes terrestres. Les introns de groupe II contiennent toutes les composantes nécessaires pour leur épissage, par contre, des facteurs d'épissage protéique sont essentiels in vivo pour induire le repliement tridimesionnel approprié de ces ARNs intronique. Les introns de groupe II chez les procaryotes encodent leurs propres facteurs d'épissage appelé protéine encodé dans l'intron (IEP). En revanche, la majorité des introns de groupe II dans les plantes à fleurs n'encodent pas une IEP. Au lieu, ces introns de groupe II dépendent d'un groupe divers de protéines liant l'ARN pour jouer le rôle de facteurs d'épissage. Notre but est d'explorer la diversité potentielle des facteurs d'épissage d'intron de groupe II chez les bactéries. Nous étudions l'intron de groupe II modèle Ll.LtrB de la bactérie à Gram positif Lactococcus lactis. Ll.LtrB encode la PEI LtrA qui est essentielle pour son épissage efficace et précis. Ll.LtrB interrompt le gène codant pour l'enzyme relaxase (LtrB) requise pour initier le transfert d'éléments conjugatifs chez L. lactis. Étant donné que la ligature des exons du gène ltrB est requise pour la conjugaison, l'efficacité d'épissage de Ll.LtrB du pré-ARNm de ltrB contrôle l'efficacité de transfert des éléments conjugatifs. Nous avons pris avantage de ce lien pour développer un essai de conjugaison sensible pour étudier un mutant de Ll.LtrB qui manque LtrA (Ll.LtrBΔLtrA) et qui ne peut s'épisser. Une banque d'expression génomique a précédemment été générée dans un plasmide conjugatif. Un essai de conjugaison a été effectué et a mené à la sélection de trois plasmides contenant des fragments génomiques (Lib7,9,11) qui peuvent secourir l'efficacité de conjugaison en l'absence de LtrA.Lib11 encode cinq cadres de lecture ouverts potentiels (ORFs) et deux ORFs partiels. Nous avons utilisés deux stratégies différentes pour déterminer quels ORFs peuvent être responsables de l'augmentation de l'efficacité de conjugaison observé et donc de secourir l'épissage. Premièrement, nous avons aboli l'expression des ORFs individuellement à partir d'un plasmide conjugatif. Deuxièmement, nous avons aboli l'expression des ORFs individuellement dans la construction originale, Lib11. De ces deux stratégies nous avons déterminé qu'ORF1 augmente l'efficacité de conjugaison mais que l'effet est variable. De façon similaire, d'autres études ont révélé que les souches qui contiennent Lib11 démontrent aussi un niveau de conjugaison variable. Nous avons donc réalisé une série de conjugaisons contrôles et identifié des conditions ou la variabilité de l'efficacité de conjugaison est réduite. Nous pouvons maintenant identifier quels ORFs sont responsables pour l'augmentation de l'efficacité de conjugaison.</description><description>Group II (GII) introns are large ribozymes that can autocatalytically excise themselves from pre-mRNA transcripts. They are found in bacteria, archaea, and the organelles of lower eukaryotes and land plants. GII introns contain all the necessary components for splicing, but protein splicing factors are essential to induce proper tridimensional folding of these intron RNAs in vivo. GII introns in bacteria and archaea usually encode their own splicing factor, termed the intron-encoded protein (IEP). In contrast, most GII introns in land plants do not encode an IEP. Instead, such GII introns depend on a diverse set of RNA-binding proteins to act as splicing factors. We aim to explore the potential diversity of group II intron splicing factors in bacteria.We study the model group II intron Ll.LtrB, from the Gram-positive bacterium Lactococcus lactis. Ll.LtrB encodes the IEP LtrA, which is essential for efficient and accurate splicing. Ll.LtrB interrupts the gene coding for the relaxase enzyme (LtrB), necessary to initiate the transfer of conjugative elements in L. lactis. Since ligation of ltrB exons is necessary for conjugation, splicing efficiency of Ll.LtrB from the ltrB pre-mRNA controls the transfer efficiency of conjugative elements. We took advantage of this relationship to develop a sensitive conjugation assay to study a splicing-deficient mutant of Ll.LtrB, which lacks LtrA (Ll.LtrBΔLtrA). Previously, a genomic expression library of L. lactis was generated in a conjugative plasmid. A conjugation assay was performed and led to the selection of three plasmids containing genomic fragments (Lib7,9,11) that can rescue conjugation efficiency in the absence of LtrA (Ll.LtrBΔLtrA).Lib11 encodes five putative open reading frames (ORFs) and two partial ORFs. We used two different strategies to determine which ORFs may be responsible for the observed increase in conjugation efficiency, and hence splicing rescue. First, we expressed individual ORFs from a conjugative plasmid. Second, we knocked out expression of individual ORFs within the original Lib11 construct. From these strategies, ORF1 was determined to increase conjugation efficiency, but the effect was variable. Similarly, further studies revealed that Lib11-containing strains also displayed variable levels of conjugation. We thus performed a series of control conjugations and identified conditions in which the variability in conjugation efficiency is reduced. We can now identify which of the ORFs is responsible for the increase in conjugation efficiency.</description><creator>Narcross, Lauren</creator><contributor>Benoit Gilbert Cousineau (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2012</date><subject>Biology - Microbiology</subject><title>Identifying novel splicing factors of the group II intron L1.LtrB from «Lactococcus lactis»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fw62w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kx87r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):19425</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>