<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:01:01Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2900" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pg15bh297</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study aims at measuring the impact of web-based self and peer assessment activities in a physics university level course.  These assessment activities were integrated into a first year experimental physics course.  Fifty seven students participated in the asynchronous self and peer assessment activities.  Dependent variables included: measures of students' monitoring abilities, the use of peer assessment to reinforce self assessment and the degree to which students endorsed the activities.  Due to missing data the repeated measure design had to be replaced by descriptive statistics.  Data collected do not confirm a significant decrease in the number of errors made by students but they suggest decrease in specific types of errors.  The study suggests that the self and peer assessments, even when they are similar in form, add to each other and provide users with useful information.  However, student level of endorsement of the activity is not conclusive and key changes need to be discussed to improve the activity.</description><description>Cette étude vise à mesurer l’impact d’une activité d’autoévaluation et d’évaluation entre pairs dans une classe de première année de physique au niveau universitaire.  Cette activité d’évaluation formative sur le Web a été intégrée à l’enseignement régulier dans le cadre d’un cours de physique expérimental de première année d’université. Cinquante sept étudiants ont participé aux exercices d’auto évaluation et d’évaluation entre pair de manière asynchrone sur le Web.  Les variables dépendantes comprennent diverses mesures dont l’habilité de révision des étudiants, l’utilité et la complémentarité de l’évaluation entre pairs, ainsi que du degré d’appropriation de l’activité par les étudiants.  Due au manque de données recueillies, le modèle de mesures répétées a été remplacé par des statistiques descriptives.  Les données ne nous permettent pas de confirmer que les activités ont eu un impact significatif sur le nombre d’erreur et la performance des étudiants mais elles indiquent un effet positif sur certains types d’erreur.  L’étude suggère aussi une complémentarité de l’autoévaluation avec l’évaluation entre pairs.  Cependant l’appropriation de l’activité par les étudiants n’est pas conclusive et certains changements sont à envisager pour améliorer l’activité. fr</description><creator>Gauthier, Geneviève</creator><contributor>Laura Winer (Co-Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Susanne P. Lajoie (Co-Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Education -- Tests and Measurements</subject><title>Web-based self and peer assessment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hr927.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bh297</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v838270f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le taux de synthèse fractionée (TSF) du cholestérol (Ch) endogène est inversement proportionnel à la prise alimentaire du Ch à 4 mois (mo).  L’objectif de cette étude était de verifier si ces différences du TSF persistent à 18 mo.  Quarante-sept enfants ont reçu, dès la naissance, soit lait maternel (HM), jusqu’au sevrage (n=15), ou ont reçu de façon aléatoire soit du lait maternisé (CF), à base lait de vache (n=17), ou une formule modifiée par l’addition de Ch (MCF, n=15) durant 12 mo.  Les HM, CF, et MCF contenaient respectivement 120, 80, 40 mg/L de Ch.  À 4 mois, le TSF dans HM était plus faible que chez CF, mais cette différence avait disparue à 18 mois avec le sevrage au régime sans restriction.  Ces données confirment que le Ch alimentaire chez le nourrisson n’affecte pas le TSF de façon permanente. fr</description><description>Endogenous cholesterol (Ch) fractional synthesis rate (FSR) is inversely related to infant dietary Ch at 4 months (mo) of age. The objective of the present study was to determine whether level of infant dietary Ch induced changes in FSR that persisted at 18 mo.  Forty-seven infants received, human milk (HM) from birth until weaned (n=15), or were randomized to receive modified cow-milk formula (MCF) with added Ch (n=15), or cow-milk formula (CF, n=17), for 12 mo.  Ch contents of HM, MCF, and CF were 120, 80, and 40 mg/L, respectively.  At 4 mo, FSR in the HM group was lower than in CF, but at 18 mo, there were no differences between groups.  Therefore, while Ch intake prior to weaning affects FSR, the differences do not persist after weaning to unrestricted diet.  These data provide further evidence that there is no imprinting of FSR in infancy by differing dietary levels of Ch.</description><creator>Demmers, Théa</creator><contributor>Peter J. H. Jones (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Health Sciences -- Nutrition</subject><title>Longer-term effects of early cholesterol intake on cholesterol biosynthesis and plasma lipids</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cd07f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838270f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795987s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Numerical simulation of forming processes has been an important means for material selection, tool design, and process optimization. A critical component of simulation, however, is an accurate material constitutive model, describing the response of the material under possible modes of deformation. The accuracy, in turn, is linked to the tests and techniques applied for identification of constitutive models: the more elaborate the identification, the more reliable the material parameters. For textile composites, uncontrollable factors such as contact friction, misalignment, slip, variations in local fiber volume, and tow compaction are sources that generate considerable scatter in the response of fabrics. Accordingly, characterization methods occasionally suffer from non-repeatability of test data even under similar testing conditions. Furthermore, it is typical that different deformation modes result in different sets of material parameters. If variance of material response within the replication of tests and deformation modes is neglected, then the identification of model parameters can be far from the true material behavior. In order to confront the above shortcomings, this work is an attempt to elaborate on the characterization of textile composites using a new inverse method by means of a signal-to-noise weighting scheme, and two constitutive models by means of a phenomenological invariant-based approach. A full identification of the developed constitutive models for a typical woven fabric is applied using the introduced inverse method and a set of data from standard testing methods, with close attention to the behavior of the composite constituents in a macro level.  Particularly, the effects of fiber-resin interactions and fiber misalignment are introduced. A novel modified picture frame test is also studied and used for validating the models. From the results of this work, it is expected that the use of a number of test methods simultaneously and the inclu</description><description>La simulation numérique pour les procédés de formation est un instrument important pour le choix des matériaux, la conception d'outils et l'optimisation des procédés. Un des composants critiques de la simulation reste cependant un modèle constitutif de matériaux précis, pouvant décrire la réponse du matériau sous des modes de déformation possibles. Par ailleurs, l'exactitude est liée aux essais et aux techniques appliqués pour l'identification des modèles constitutifs: plus l'identification est raffinée, plus les paramètres du matériau sont fiables. Pour des composés textiles, des facteurs incontrôlables tels que le frottement de contact, la déviation d'alignement, le glissement, les variations de volume local des fibres, et le tassement des fibres sont des sources qui produisent un éparpillement considérable dans la réponse des tissus. Par conséquent, les méthodes de caractérisation souffrent occasionnellement de la non-répétabilité des données des essais même lorsque les conditions d'essais sont semblables. De plus, il est typique que différents ensembles de paramètres du matériau soient obtenus à partir des différents modes de déformation. Si la variance de la réponse du matériau dans les répliques d’essais et les modes de déformation est négligée, l'identification des paramètres du modèle peut alors être loin du véritable comportement du matériau. Afin de confronter les imperfections mentionnées ci-dessus, la présente étude est une tentative d'élaboration de la caractérisation des composés textiles en utilisant une nouvelle méthode inverse basée sur un schéma pondéré signal/bruit et deux modèles constitutifs par le biais d’une approche basée sur l’invariance des phénomènes. Une identification complète des modèles constitutifs développés est appliquée à un tissu typique en utilisant la méthode inverse proposée et un ensemble de données obtenus à partir des méthodes d'essais stand</description><creator>Carlson, David</creator><contributor>Wayne H. Pollard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Physical Geography</subject><title>Dynamic process model of palsa genesis and development based on geomorphologic investigations at the Boundary Ridge Palsa Bog near Schefferville, Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jr047.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795987s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602315c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les litératures en diététique et en éducation nous rapellent, qu’en tant que diététiste, nous nous devons de développer les habiletés pour continuer à apprendre et pour améliorer notre pratique.  Bien que la réflexion soit une étape intégrale des stratégies de développement professionnel en diététique, nous en savons peu sur ce processus dans notre domaine.  Le but de cette étude est de faciliter l’apprentissage continu des diététistes et le développement de leur compétence.  Dans ce but, des expériences de diététistes sont recueillies et le processus de réflexion contenu dans ces données est examiné.  Les questions guidant cette exploration portent sur 1) le processus utilisé par des diététistes pour réfléchir à leur pratique, 2) le résultat des réflexions sur leur pratique et, 3) les conditions favorisant leur réflexion.  La réflexion se définit comme un processus de transformation d’expériences en connaissances sur la pratique et d’amélioration.  L’étude a été conçu selon la théorie ancrée puisque cette approche permet un examen détaillé des réflexions de diététistes et le développement d’une théorie.  La collecte de données comprenaient a) une étude pilote pour déterminer l’efficacité des instruments ainsi que des procédures, b) des entrevues permettant de recueillir des expériences de participantes et leurs pensées pendant, et après une expérience, et, c) des suivis pour vérifier l’interprétation des données et explorer des thèmes ayant surgit lors de l’analyse.  L’entrevue invitait les participantes à se remémorer et à détailler une situation incertaine, énigmatique, surprenante ou satisfaisante, une expérience ayant influencé le développment de leur savoir, leur conception ou leur approche en nutrition prénatale.  Six diététistes, pratiquant en nutrition prénatale dans le cadre de projets d’organismes communautaires ou de programmes gouvernementaux ciblant$</description><description>As a practicing dietitian, I am reminded by the dietetics and education literatures of just how important it is for me, and for the profession, to develop skills to continue to learn and improve practice.  Although reflection is an integral step of professional development strategies in dietetics, little is known about it in our context.  The study's purpose is to assist dietitians in their quest for continuous learning and improved practice by documenting experiences of dietitians and exploring the reflection process embedded in this data.  Research questions guiding this exploration focused on 1) the process through which dietitians reflect on their practice, 2) the outcomes of dietitians' reflection on practice and, 3) conditions influencing dietitians' reflection.  Reflection is defined as a process of turning experience into knowledge about practice and improving it.  The study was designed based on grounded theory to allow for detailed exploration of dietitians' reflection and theory generation.  Data collection consisted of a) a pilot study to determine effectiveness of instruments and procedures, b) formal interviews to document participant experiences and thinking during and following it, and, c) follow-up interviews to verify interpretation of data and to pursue themes arising from analysis.  Interview questions invited participants to recall and relate a time when they experienced something uncertain, puzzling, surprising or satisfying, an experience in which learning about prenatal nutrition occurred or one that had an impact on their thinking or approach. Participants were six dietitians practicing in prenatal projects sponsored by community organizations or in prenatal initiatives of governmental departments, both of which targeted pregnant women facing challenging social, economic or cultural situations.  Data analysis centered on identification of concepts and constant comparisons within and between participants.  Study findings suggest participan</description><creator>Beauchamp, Jacinthe</creator><contributor>Cynthia B. Weston (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Education -- Adult and Continuing</subject><title>How dietitians turn experience into knowledge about practice in community-based prenatal nutrition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544br688.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602315c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n870zs79p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Numerical simulation of forming processes has been an important means for material selection, tool design, and process optimization. A critical component of simulation, however, is an accurate material constitutive model, describing the response of the material under possible modes of deformation. The accuracy, in turn, is linked to the tests and techniques applied for identification of constitutive models: the more elaborate the identification, the more reliable the material parameters. For textile composites, uncontrollable factors such as contact friction, misalignment, slip, variations in local fiber volume, and tow compaction are sources that generate considerable scatter in the response of fabrics. Accordingly, characterization methods occasionally suffer from non-repeatability of test data even under similar testing conditions. Furthermore, it is typical that different deformation modes result in different sets of material parameters. If variance of material response within the replication of tests and deformation modes is neglected, then the identification of model parameters can be far from the true material behavior. In order to confront the above shortcomings, this work is an attempt to elaborate on the characterization of textile composites using a new inverse method by means of a signal-to-noise weighting scheme, and two constitutive models by means of a phenomenological invariant-based approach. A full identification of the developed constitutive models for a typical woven fabric is applied using the introduced inverse method and a set of data from standard testing methods, with close attention to the behavior of the composite constituents in a macro level.  Particularly, the effects of fiber-resin interactions and fiber misalignment are introduced. A novel modified picture frame test is also studied and used for validating the models. From the results of this work, it is expected that the use of a number of test methods simultaneously and the inclu</description><description>La simulation numérique pour les procédés de formation est un instrument important pour le choix des matériaux, la conception d'outils et l'optimisation des procédés. Un des composants critiques de la simulation reste cependant un modèle constitutif de matériaux précis, pouvant décrire la réponse du matériau sous des modes de déformation possibles. Par ailleurs, l'exactitude est liée aux essais et aux techniques appliqués pour l'identification des modèles constitutifs: plus l'identification est raffinée, plus les paramètres du matériau sont fiables. Pour des composés textiles, des facteurs incontrôlables tels que le frottement de contact, la déviation d'alignement, le glissement, les variations de volume local des fibres, et le tassement des fibres sont des sources qui produisent un éparpillement considérable dans la réponse des tissus. Par conséquent, les méthodes de caractérisation souffrent occasionnellement de la non-répétabilité des données des essais même lorsque les conditions d'essais sont semblables. De plus, il est typique que différents ensembles de paramètres du matériau soient obtenus à partir des différents modes de déformation. Si la variance de la réponse du matériau dans les répliques d’essais et les modes de déformation est négligée, l'identification des paramètres du modèle peut alors être loin du véritable comportement du matériau. Afin de confronter les imperfections mentionnées ci-dessus, la présente étude est une tentative d'élaboration de la caractérisation des composés textiles en utilisant une nouvelle méthode inverse basée sur un schéma pondéré signal/bruit et deux modèles constitutifs par le biais d’une approche basée sur l’invariance des phénomènes. Une identification complète des modèles constitutifs développés est appliquée à un tissu typique en utilisant la méthode inverse proposée et un ensemble de données obtenus à partir des méthodes d'essais stand</description><creator>Sadeghzadeh Milani, Abbas</creator><contributor>James Nemes (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2004</date><subject>Engineering -- Mechanical</subject><title>Multi-objective inverse method for obtaining constitutive material parameters of textile composites using two hyperelastic models</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237ht94z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zs79p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7m01bn91q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Duma pro Slipykh est une composition pour baryton solo, choeur mixte à 12 voix et petit orchestre de chambre, d'une durée approximative de 17 minutes et 30 secondes. L'œuvre met en musique deux poèmes ukrainiens: Sliptsi (1929), de Mykola Bazhan, et Yanholy i Vovky (1996), de Wolodymyr Tsybul'ko. Des extraits des deux poèmes sont combinés de diverses manières pour former le texte de la pièce. L'interprétation simultanée de multiples extraits présentant des éléments et thèmes communs cherche à recréer la frénésie et l'intensité du sentiment de frustration que les poètes tentaient d'exprimer à travers leurs poèmes. Bien que les deux poèmes aient été écrits à près de soixante-dix ans d'intervalle, les thèmes généraux de frustration et de colère, reliés à la corruption présente chez le gouvernement et la classe dirigeante ukrainiens, sont extrêmement similaires. L'essai traite des poèmes, des poètes, et situe chaque texte dans son contexte politique. TI se poursuit avec une analyse de la composition au niveau de la structure formelle, de la mise en musique du texte, de l'organisation des hauteurs de notes, ainsi que d'aspects reliés à la texture sonore.</description><description>Duma pro Slipykh is a composition for solo baritone, 12-part mixed choir and small chamber orchestra, lasting approximately 17 minutes and 30 seconds. The work sets excerpts from two Ukrainian poems: Mykola Bazhan's Sliptsi (1929) and Wolodymyr Tsybul'ko's Yanholy i Vovky (1996). Excerpts from both poems were layered in various ways to form the text of the piece. The simultaneous performance of multiple excerpts with common elements and themes was devised to emulate the frenetic energy and angry frustration the poets were trying to express in their poems. Although nearly seventy years separate the two poems, the general themes of anger and frustration with corruption in Ukraine's ruling class and government are unbelievably similar. The essay includes a brief discussion of the poems, the poets, the political context for each text, and continues with an analysis of the composition's form, setting of the text, pitch structure and texturaI matters.</description><creator>Talpash, Andriy</creator><contributor>Cherney, Brian (supervisor)</contributor><date>2005</date><subject>Instrumental ensembles -- Scores.</subject><title>Duma pro Slipykh for solo baritone, 12-part mixed choir and small chamber orchestra</title><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m176r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bn91q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042w13t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L’hydrolyse de l’agarose par une B-agarase obtenue de la bactérie marine Pseudomonas atlantica produit la tétrasaccharide néoagarotétraose. La liaison B (1-4) de la néoagarotétraose est hydrolysée par la B- néoagarotétraose hydrolase obtenue de la même souche, donnant deux molécules de disaccharide neoagarobiose. L’enzyme B- néoagarotétraose hydrolase a été purifiée et ses principales propriétés étudiées. Des données concernant l’induction, la localisation et le mode d’action de l’enzyme sont présentées. […]</description><description>Neoagarotetraose is a tetrasaccharide obtained on hydrolysis of agarose by a B-agarose from the marine bacterium Pseudomonas atlantica. The B (1-4) linkage in neoagarotetraose is cleaved by a B- neoagarotetraose hydrolase from the same organism to yield two molecules of neoagarobiose. The B- neoagarotetraose hydrolase has been purified and characterized. Data concerning induction, localization and mode of action of this enzyme are presented. […]</description><creator>Groleau, Denis</creator><contributor>Yaphe, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1976-08</date><subject>Microbiology and Immunology</subject><title>Enzymatic Hydrolysis of Agar: Studies on a B-Neoagarotetraose Hydrolase</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w687w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042w13t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j38609076</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette étude porte sur le développement d'une méthode de séchage en deux étapes pour sécher les drêches de brasserie comme procédé de valorisation des déchets. Du point de vue du brasseur, le séchage des drêches est bénéfique dans la mesure où elle permet de réduire les coûts d'élimination des déchets, en particulier lorsqu'elle est associée à une méthode de densification telle que la granulation, et qu'elle permet de faire un coproduit pouvant être utilisé comme aliment pour animaux, ou par d'autres industries, pour ses propriétés physiques et chimiques. Des techniques de séchage ont été évaluées en utilisant une méthodologie de surface de réponse ayant une conception composite centrale centrée sur la face. Les deux étapes comprenaient une étape initiale de déshydratation partielle par compression mécanique suivie d'un séchage thermique microonde pour réduire la teneur en eau et permettre un stockage sécuritaire. L'efficacité de la méthode de séchage en deux étapes a été évaluée et la qualité du produit traité a été suivie tout au long des essais.La condition optimale pour extraire la quantité maximale d'eau par compression mécanique a été optimisée et les résultats ont permis de développer un modèle prédictif. Le modèle était statistiquement significatif (p &lt;0,0001) et présentait une forte corrélation avec les résultats expérimentaux (R2 = 0,98). C'est ainsi qu'il a été possible de réduire de près de 35% la teneur en eau des drêches en maintenant une pression de 1,19 MPa pour une période de 2 minutes et 44 secondes. Par la suite, l'optimisation de la phase de séchage thermique a été étudiée. Sept variables liées à la qualité et à l'efficacité du procédé ont été mesurées en fonction du temps de séchage et de la densité de puissance des micro-ondes (W· g-1). Seule la réponse au temps de séchage a été modélisée de manière adéquate (p &lt;0,0006) avec un coefficient de détermination élevé (R2 = 0,99). Le modèle mathématique permet de prédire le temps de séchage en fonction des conditions utilisées. Les corrélations entre les conditions de séchage et la couleur, la protéine brute, la protéine détergente acide (ADP en% CP) et des fibres insolubles dans les détergents acides (ADF), n'étaient pas significatives. Les résultats ont permis d'identifier les conditions optimales de température de l'air et de la densité de puissance micro-ondes pour maximiser la pâleur de la couleur des drêches séchées (L *), pour minimiser le temps de séchage, pour minimiser le pourcentage de protéines liées aux fibres (ADP) et pour minimiser les fibres insoluble au détergent acide (ADF). Les deux derniers paramètres sont des indicateurs chimiques de la surchauffe du grain. Le paramètre de séchage le plus souhaitable pour minimiser le temps de séchage et pour optimiser la qualité du produit séché était une température de l'air de 64 ºC et une densité de puissance micro-ondes de 2 W· g-1 .</description><description>This thesis examines a two-stage drying method to dehydrate brewers' spent grains as part of exploring a waste valorization process.  Drying the grains may be beneficial from the brewer's perspective in that it (i) reduces waste disposal costs, especially when coupled with a densification method such as pelletizing, and (ii) produces a co-product that can be sold as animal feed, or to other industries, for its physical and chemical properties.  Drying parameters were evaluated using a response surface methodology having a face centered central composite design.  The two stages included dewatering initially to mechanically remove free water, followed by a thermal drying technique in order to reduce the moisture level enough for safe storage or further processing. The efficiency of the two-stage drying method was examined and the quality of the feed was assessed following each drying test.  The optimal condition to reduce the maximum amount of water through lab-scale mechanical pressing was found, and the predictive model was statistically significant (p &lt;0.0001) having a strong correlation with experimental results (R2=0.98). As a maximum, water content was reduced by 35%, which resulted from a pressure of 1.19 MPa and holding time of 2 minutes and 44 seconds. Subsequently optimization of the thermal drying stage was studied. Seven response variables related to quality and efficiency were measured as a function of drying time and microwave power density (W g-1).  Only the drying time response was adequately modeled (p&lt;0.0006) with a high coefficient of determination (R2=0.99) to predict the most efficient drying time. Predictive models were insignificant (p &gt;0.05) for color (i.e., L*, a* and b*), crude protein, acid detergent protein (ADP as % CP) and acid detergent fiber (ADF). Finally, air temperature and microwave density were optimized to yield increased grain lightness (L*), minimize drying time, minimize the percentage of bound protein to fiber (ADP) and minimize acid detergent fiber (ADF).  The latter two parameters are chemical indicators of grain overheating.  The most desirable drying parameter setting was an air temperature of 64 ºC and microwave assisted with a power density setting of 2 W g-1 in order to achieve the most efficient drying time with the best product quality.</description><creator>Crowe, Christine</creator><contributor>Mark Lefsrud (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Bioresource Engineering</subject><title>Optimization of a two-stage drying process for brewers' spent grains</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tr511.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j38609076</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w3763919r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Carbonyl reduction is a key process in chemistry, both in academic and industrial research. In the context of biomass valorization, C=O reduction shines as an essential upgrading pathway. Indeed, most biomass-derived molecules are naturally oxygen-rich in contrast to petroleum-based chemicals. H2 gas is the most ideal reductant in terms of atom-economy. Hydrogenation catalysts have been widely studied, such as Noyori-type catalysts for enantioselective reduction of prochiral ketones. Due to pressure and flammability constraints though, alternative reducing agents may be preferred. On big scale processes, hydride salts such as NaBH4 and LiAlH4 are commonly used, due to their high reactivity. However, stoichiometric amounts of waste are concomitantly formed during the process. Therefore, sustainable solutions need to be developed to decrease the environmental impact of chemical processes. Key factors are energy consumption, waste generation and safety. In this thesis, we have explored alternative energy sources and novel catalysts to solve the issues mentioned above. In the first part, we covered the catalytic applications of silver nanoparticles. Then, we applied microwave heating to the synthesis of magnetically recyclable silver nanoparticles, using a biomass-derived polymer (carboxymethyl cellulose) as a reductant and stabilizer. It was applied for the selective hydrogenation of C=O bonds in water. Then, we explored the metal-free and mechanochemical reduction of carbonyls, using polymethylhydrosiloxane as a reductant, that is a waste from the silicon industry. Due to the solvent-free conditions, we successfully reduced substrates having solubility issues (5-hydroxymethyl furfural and polyketone). Our mechanistic investigations showed the in situ formation of a highly reactive gas [H3SiFMe]- during the reaction, that was responsible for the reaction. Lastly, we explored the synthesis of magnetically recyclable (Ni0.5Cu0.5)Fe2O4 NPs by plasma induction. We have successfully applied them for the amination of alcohols under microwave irradiation, through a borrowing hydrogen pathway. Under our optimized conditions, the catalyst proved to be active at the 10-gram scale at metal loadings comparable to those of homogeneous complexes (&lt;2 mol%).Following the guiding principles of green chemistry, we have successfully applied various alternative sources to both nanoparticle synthesis and organic reactions. In every case they were exploited to solve issues linked to the use of solvents or due to conventional heating. </description><description>La reduction de carbonyles est un procédé crucial en chimie, autant en recherche académique qu'en industrie. Dans le contexte de la conversion de la biomasse, ce procédé est particulièrement important car les molécules biosourcées sont riches en oxygène, contrairement à ceux issus de l'industrie pétrolière. En termes d'économie d'atomes, l'hydrogène est le réducteur idéal. Les catalyseurs d'hydrogénation ont été l'objet de recherches poussées, tels que les catalyseurs de type Noyori pour la réduction énantiosélective de cétones prochirales. Mais des réducteurs alternatifs, ne posant pas de problèmes d'inflammabilité ou de pression, peuvent être utilisés. Des sels d'hydrure très réactifs tels que NaBH4 ou LiAlH4 sont communément utilisés à grande échelle. Mais ces sels génèrent aussi des quantités stœchiométriques de déchets. Il est donc nécessaire de développer des solutions plus durables, pour réduire l'impact de ces procédés chimiques sur l'environnement, en considérant la consommation d'énergie, les déchets générés, et la sécurité. Pour résoudre ces problèmes, nous avons exploré des sources d'énergie alternatives et des nouveaux catalyseurs.Tout d'abord, nous avons passé en revue les applications en catalyse des nanoparticules d'Argent. Puis, nous avons exploré la fabrication de nanoparticules d'Argent sur un support magnétique par micro-ondes, à l'aide d'un biopolymère (carboxyméthylcellulose) en tant que réducteur et stabilisateur. Ces nanoparticules se sont révélées sélective pour l'hydrogénation de liaisons C=O dans l'eau. Ensuite, nous avons exploré la réduction sans metal de carbonyles en mécanochimie, en utilisant le polymethylhydrosiloxane, un déchet de l'industrie du silicone, en tant que réducteur. Sans utiliser de solvant, nous avons résolu des problèmes de solubilité avec des substrats difficiles tels que la polycétone ou l'hydroxyméthylfurfural. Nous avons mis en évidence par des études mécanistiques la formation d'un réducteur gazeux pendant la réaction. Finalement, nous avons exploré la synthèse de nanoparticules magnétiques de (NiCu)Fe2O4 par induction plasma. Nous les avons utilisés pour catalyser l'amination d'alcools sous micro-ondes, par un mécanisme d'emprunt d'hydrogène. Nous montrons que le catalyseur fonctionne à l'échelle des 10 grammes, à des taux métalliques comparable à ceux des catalyseurs homogènes (&lt;2 mol%).En se basant sur les principes fondamentaux de la chimie verte, nous avons exploité des sources alternatives d'énergie sur la synthèse de nanoparticules et des réaction organiques pour résoudre des problèmes liés à l'utilisation de solvant ou du chauffage convectif.</description><creator>Li, Alain</creator><contributor>Audrey Moores-François (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Chaojun Li (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Chemistry</subject><title>Sustainable alternatives for carbonyl reduction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p939b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763919r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306t138m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ce mémoire donne une vue d'ensemble de l'amplification en chaîne de par polymérase (PCR) et de ses applications en recherche et en industrie. Il discute des composantes spécifiques et des étapes de la PCR et donne un aperçu des connaissances requises dans les domaines de la chimie, de l'ingénierie et de la biologie pour effectuer une électrophorèse sur gel et une PCR en temps réel. Nous abordons ensuite les lois de la physique qui sous-tendent le concept de chauffage direct sans contact, plusieurs techniques de thermométrie et les systèmes Single Input Single Output (SISO).Nous examinons également les propriétés d'inhibition des nanoparticules présentes dans une PCR. Grâce aux données de concentrations d'inhibition, nous déterminons l'absorbance maximale par unité de longueur requise pour effectuer une PCR de chacun des deux types de nanoparticules étudiées. En utilisant des techniques de chauffage et de thermométrie sans contact, nous déterminons la fiabilité de notre système de PCR et la comparons à celle d'éléments de Peltier conventionnels utilisés dans les laboratoires de recherche. Nous déterminons ensuite la température de maintien optimale et le temps de maintien minimal pour les phases d'appariement et de dénaturation. Puis, nous développons une méthode en temps réel sans marqueur de contrôle de la production d'acide désoxyribonucléique à double brins qui n'utilise qu'une diode émettant de la lumière ultraviolette et un photodétecteur de rayons ultraviolets. Finalement, nous comparons cette méthode à la technologie éprouvée de la PCR quantitative avec marqueurs fluorescents.</description><description>This thesis gives an overview of polymerase chain reaction (PCR) and where PCR is currently used in research and the industry. The thesis discusses the specific components and stages of PCR. It gives an overview of the chemistry, engineering and biology required to perform PCR in both real time and in gel electrophoresis.  We go through the underlying laws of physics involved in direct non-contact heating, various thermometry techniques, and single input single output (SISO) control systems. We investigate the inhibition properties of nanoparticles in PCR. With the inhibition concentration data, we determine the maximum absorbance per unit length of both nanoparticles to perform PCR. Using non-contact heating and non-contact thermometry, we explored the reliability of our PCR system and compared it to that of conventional Peltier elements used in research laboratories. We determine the optimal hold temperatures, and minimum hold time for both the annealing and denaturation stages.We demonstrate a simplistic real-time and label-free method to monitor double stranded deoxyribonucleic acid production using only a ultraviolet (UV) LED and a UV photodetector, and compare it to that of tried and tested fluorescent-based  quantitative PCR. </description><creator>Tran, Ngoc Anh Minh</creator><contributor>Andrew G Kirk (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</subject><title>Universal point of care biosensor using ultrafast plasmonic polymerase chain reaction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r9931.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t138m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b8515q674</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The failure of pancreatic β cells to produce insulin is a central problem in both Type 1 and Type 2 diabetes, however the molecular mechanisms leading to β cell failure remain unclear. Consequently, investigating mechanisms that promote β cell function and survival is paramount in the development of therapies to prevent and treat both types of diabetes.PKR-like endoplasmic reticulum kinase (PERK) is an ER transmembrane protein involved in maintaining β cell homeostasis. Previously, our group identified the adaptor protein Nck1 as a negative regulator of PERK. Indeed, we demonstrated that Nck1, by directly binding PERK autophosphorylated on Tyr561, limits PERK activation and signaling. In accordance, we found that Nck1 depletion in β cells promotes PERK activity and signaling, increases insulin biosynthesis, and promotes cell viability in response to diabetes-related stresses.Herein, we explore the therapeutic potential of abrogating the interaction between Nck and PERK in order to improve β cell function and survival. To do so, we used a peptide containing the minimal sequence of PERK that is involved in binding Nck1 conjugated to the cell permeable protein transduction domain from the HIV protein TAT. In the current study, we confirm that the synthetic phosphopeptide TAT-pY561 sequesters Nck and prevents its interaction with PERK. Moreover, we demonstrate that TAT-pY561 penetrates the β cell membrane and promotes basal PERK activity. Furthermore, we report that pretreatment of β cells with TAT-pY561 inhibits apoptosis induced by glucolipotoxicity. Finally, we further characterize TAT-pY561 at the biochemical level by comparing its affinity for Nck with unphosphorylated and mutant peptide variants. Taken together, our data support the potential of sequestering Nck using a synthetic peptide to enhance basal PERK activity and create more resilient β cells.</description><description>L'incapacité des cellules β du pancréas endocrine à produire suffisamment d'insuline est un problème majeur chez les diabétiques. Cependant, les mécanismes moléculaires menant à la défaillance des cellules β restent flous. Par conséquent, l'identification de mécanismes contrôlant la fonction des cellules β pancréatiques est d'importance majeure pour le design de thérapies efficaces visant à prévenir et traiter le diabète. Plusieurs études ont révélé le rôle essentiel de la protéine kinase du réticulum endoplasmique PERK dans le maintien fonctionnel des cellules β pancréatiques. Dans ce contexte, notre groupe a découvert que l'adaptateur Nck1 limite l'activation de PERK. En effet, nous avons démontré que la liaison directe de Nck1 au résidu Tyr561 phosphorylé de PERK réduit l'activité basale de PERK. Nous avons par ailleurs révélé que la déplétion de Nck1 dans les cellules β augmente l'activité basale de PERK et la biosynthèse de l'insuline, et améliore la viabilité des cellules β en réponse aux stress liés au diabète.Dans cette thèse, nous avons exploré le potentiel thérapeutique de prévenir l'interaction entre Nck et PERK afin d'améliorer la fonction et la survie des cellules β. Dans cette optique, nous avons utilisé le peptide TAT-pY561 composé de la séquence minimale de PERK impliquée dans la liaison avec Nck1 conjuguée au domaine de transduction protéique de la protéine TAT du VIH. Dans cette étude, nous confirmons que le phosphopeptide synthétique TAT-pY561 séquestre Nck et empêche son interaction avec PERK. En outre, nous démontrons que TAT-pY561 est capable de pénétrer la membrane des cellules β et d'augmenter l'activité basale de PERK. De plus, nous rapportons que le prétraitement des cellules β avec TAT-pY561 inhibe l'apoptose induite par la glucolipotoxicité. Finalement, nous avons plus amplement caractérisé le peptide TAT-pY561 en comparant son affinité pour Nck avec une variante non phosphorylée ou mutée du peptide TAT pY561. Dans leur ensemble, ces données supportent le potentiel de séquestration de Nck à travers l'usage d'un peptide synthétique afin d'améliorer l'activité basale de PERK et de créer des cellules β plus robustes.</description><creator>Kefalas, George</creator><contributor>Louise Larose (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2018</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>Targeting the Nck/PERK interaction to improve β cell function and survival</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q635r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515q674</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429c49k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Amanda "Fucking" Palmer began her musical career in 2000 as half of The Dresden Dolls and has since produced numerous solo albums and multimedia collaborations, garnering modest success in the U.S. Palmer's performances are often divisive; audiences have frequently damned and lauded Palmer's often darkly humorous portrayals of gender and sexual violence. In response to criticisms about "making light" of these issues, Palmer posits, "When you cannot joke about the darkness of life, that's when the darkness takes over." Drawing primarily on the work of Sara Ahmed, Jonathan Dollimore, and Bertolt Brecht, I explore Amanda Palmer's musical acts of feminist and queer transgression. I focus my study primarily on the elements of dark humor, trauma, and expressions of negativity. Examining the roots of her "Brechtian punk cabaret" aesthetic, I create a musicological framework for understanding Palmer's characteristically theatrical musical performance style that seeks to estrange audiences to create awareness and effect shifts in cultural ideology. I analyze several case studies of Palmer's music, lyrics, and performances alongside her own writings to trace her strategic uses of humor, trauma, and negative emotional expression, which seek to problematize societal norms surrounding self-expression in general. Finally, I show that Palmer's self-aware irreverence and intentional use of bad feelings simultaneously express what many fans feel are honest (if unpopular) responses to trauma and negativity, while also generating jarring, controversial, and political performances that ultimately lead to greater awareness of violence against women and gender/sexual minorities in society. </description><description>Amanda « Fucking » Palmer a débuté sa carrière musicale en 2000 en tant que l'une des deux « moitiés » des Dresden Dolls. Depuis, elle a produit de nombreux albums solo et collaborations multimédias qui ont remporté un succès notable, quoique modeste, aux États-Unis. Figure polarisante, Palmer a été à la fois condamnée et célébrée pour ses représentations souvent humoristiques de la violence genrée et sexuelle. En réponse à la critique voulant qu'elle « éclaircisse » son point de vue à ce sujet, elle répond : « Quand on ne peut pas plaisanter sur l'obscurité de la vie, c'est à ce moment que l'obscurité prend le dessus. » Cette thèse s'appuie sur les travaux de Sara Ahmed, de Jonathan Dollimore, et de Bertolt Brecht afin d'explorer les performances musicales de transgression féministe et queer d'Amanda Palmer. Mon étude se penche principalement sur les éléments de l'humour noir, les traumatismes, et les expressions de la négativité dans son œuvre. En examinant les racines de son esthétique de type « cabaret punk brechtien », je déploie un nouveau cadre musicologique afin d'aborder la théâtralité distinctive du style de performance musicale de Palmer, qui cherche d'une part à s'aliéner son public afin de susciter une prise de conscience, et d'autre part à entraîner de réels changements dans l'idéologie culturelle dominante. À travers plusieurs études de cas de la musique, des paroles, des performances de Palmer ainsi que de ses écrits, j'analyse ses utilisations stratégiques de l'humour, du traumatisme, et de l'expression émotionnelle négative afin de retracer de quelle manière Palmer problématise les normes de la société entourant l'expression de soi en général. Enfin, je montre que l'irrévérence consciente de Palmer ainsi que son utilisation intentionnelle de sentiments négatifs expriment simultanément ce que beaucoup de fans considèrent comme des réponses honnêtes, quoique impopulaires, aux traumatismes et à la négativité, tout en générant des performances surprenantes, controversées, et politiques qui mèneent à une plus grande prise de conscience de la violence envers les femmes, les minorités de genre, et les minorités sexuelles.Translation by/Traduction de Vanessa Blais-Tremblay, Ph.D.</description><creator>Flesher, Jackson</creator><contributor>Lisa Barg (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Lloyd Whitesell (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Music</subject><title>Joking about the darkness: affect, queerness, and politics in the work of Amanda Palmer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462765v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429c49k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fn884</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse examine le droit de la tentative criminelle, selon formulé au Canada, et avec référence particulière au droit de la Commonwealth et de les Etats Unis. Ou pertinent, les provisions légales de divers autres pays seront inclus et analysées. Les prochains sujets relatifs à la tentative criminelle seront considerés en succession: l'histoire, la rationale, l'élément mental, l'élément réel, l'impossibilité, l'abandonment, le succès, la preuve et les règles de procédure, et jugement. Deux appendices comprennant un abrégé international des provisions concernant l'attentat général, et une compilation de provisions particulières à l'attentat dans les statuts fédéraux et les règlements du Canada, y sont inclus. La thèse termine en soulignant des recommendations viz-à-viz la législation provisoire.</description><description>This thesis examines the particularly applied in Canada, law of criminal attempt, as and with special reference to the law in the Commonwealth and the United States of America. Wherever relevant, the laws of other countries are reviewed and included herein. The following areas of criminal attempt are considered in turn: history, rationale, mental element, factual element, impossibility, abandonment, success and merger, evidence and procedure, and sentencing. Two appendices comprising an international compendium of general attempt provisions, and a compilation of specific attempt provisions in Canadian federal statutes and regulations, are also included. The thesis concludes with recommended draft legislation. </description><creator>Meehan, Eugene</creator><contributor>Mewett, Alan W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1983</date><subject>Criminal attempt -- Canada.</subject><subject>Criminal attempt.</subject><subject>Criminal attempt -- United States.</subject><title>A Treatise on the Law of Criminal Attempt as Particularly Applied in Canada and with Special Reference to the Law in the Commonwealth and in the United States of America : Volume 1</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mx69d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fn884</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gh93h175q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ever since the discovery of Trichinella spiralis by Paget (1835) and its description by Owen (1835) as quoted by Gould ( 1945), there has been a continuous interest in the study of this nematode and the disease caused by it. This has been due to two reasons the first being economical, as trichiniasis is still one of the most important human health hazards, and the second deriving from the ease with which Trichinella spiralis con be maintained in vivo and its life cycle duplicated in laboratory animais. This has made T. spiralis one of the favourite models to study various aspects of host-parasite relationships in parasitic infections.[...]</description><creator>Siddiqi, Mohammad Nasim</creator><contributor>Meerovitch, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1970</date><subject>Parasitology</subject><subject>T. spiralis</subject><title>Host-parasite relationship in trichiniasis - a comparative study of different strains of Trichinella Spiralis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xt96z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h175q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nc580p803</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'éducation physique a pour objectif d'accroître la confiance, la compétence et la motivation des étudiants à mener une vie active. La recherche a montré que les étudiants dans les programmes d'enseignement de l'éducation physique ont tendance à être sexistes, élitistes et antipathiques envers les questions sociales. Actuellement, une lacune dans les formes d'éducation physique (ÉP) culturellement adaptées et socialement justes qui attirent l'attention sur le racisme, le colonialisme, le sexisme, l'hétéronormativité et d'autres problèmes sociaux nécessite une plus grande reconnaissance de la part des chercheurs. Le but de cette étude est (1) de mieux comprendre comment ces étudiants pourraient être engagés pour adopter un programme critique qui augmenterait leur volonté d'enseigner de manière adaptée à la culture et (2) de s'engager dans des formes d'ÉP plus justes sur le plan social. À l'aide d'une enquête narrative autobiographique, les étudiants confrontent et expliquent leurs réactions aux discours dominants qui ont façonné leur identité et réfléchissent de manière critique sur la manière dont leurs propres expériences peuvent être différentes de celles des étudiants qui seront dans leurs classes futures. En analysant de manière narrative les expériences de quatre enseignants en éducation physique débutants, l'auteur montre comment un point de départ différent dans la formation des enseignants peut enrichir et façonner la capacité des enseignants débutants d'enseigner de manière socialement juste. Cette compréhension a des implications pour les formateurs d'enseignants, ainsi que pour les écoles et les autres parties prenantes investies dans une pédagogie plus adaptée à la culture, ce qui entraîne une plus grande inclusivité et de meilleurs résultats pour les élèves.</description><description>The goal of PE is to increase student confidence, competence, and motivation to lead physically active lifestyles. Research has shown physical and health education teacher education (PHETE) students tend to be sexist, elitist and unsympathetic towards social issues. Currently, a gap in culturally responsive and socially just forms of physical education (PE) that bring attention to racism, colonialism, sexism, heteronormativity, and other social issues requires greater acknowledgement from researchers. The purpose of this study is to (1) better understand how PHETE students might be engaged to take on a critical agenda that would increase their willingness to teach in culturally responsive ways, and (2) engage in more socially just forms of PE. Using autobiographical narrative inquiry, students confront and explain their reactions to dominant discourses that have shaped their identities and think critically about how their own experiences may be different than the students who will be in their future classes. Narratively inquiring into four pre-service physical education teachers' experiences, the author illustrates how a different starting point in teacher education may enrich and shape beginning PE teacher's capacity to teach in socially just ways. This understanding has implications for teacher educators as well as schools and other stakeholders invested in more culturally responsive pedagogy resulting in greater inclusivity and improved student outcomes. </description><creator>Hennig, Lauren</creator><contributor>Lee Schaefer (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Kinesiology and Physical Education</subject><title>Preparing pre-service teachers to advocate for social justice in schools</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g954x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580p803</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rq95p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The CUX1 gene has been characterized genetically as a haploinsufficient tumour suppressor gene.  Paradoxically, CUX1 overexpression is observed in the majority of human cancers and is associated with shorter patient survival. While many transcriptional targets may explain how CUX1 overexpression promotes tumour development and/or progression, the biochemical function(s) of CUX1 that explain its role in tumour suppression remain(s) to be defined. Recent studies have established a role for the p200 CUX1 protein as an auxiliary factor in DNA repair. Specifically, the CUT domains within CUX1 were found to stimulate the enzymatic activities of three enzymes of the base excision repair pathway. This new function of CUX1 led us to hypothesize that diminished CUX1 expression may impair DNA repair efficiency and accelerate the accumulation of mutations, thereby increasing the risk of tumour initiation. As a first test of this hypothesis, we sought to measure the effect of CUX1 knockdown on mutation frequency using the hypoxanthine phosphoribosyltransferase (HPRT) mutation assay on the human lymphoblast cell line TK6. In multiple independent experiments we observed an increase in mutation frequency upon CUX1 knockdown. The increase in mutation frequency was exacerbated by treatment of cells with ionizing radiation. Using reverse-transcription polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR), we analyzed the mutation spectrum of 135 HPRT-negative mutant clones.  Consistent with the role of CUX1 in base excision repair, we observed an increase in the number of point mutations in the irradiated cell population following CUX1 knockdown. Surprisingly, however, we observed a greater increase in the number of large DNA deletions and rearrangements in both irradiated and non-irradiated cells. This finding suggests that CUX1 may also be involved in another DNA repair pathway.</description><description>Le gène Cux1 est décrit comme étant un gène haploinsuffisant suppresseur de tumeur. De manière paradoxale, la surexpression de Cux1 est observée dans la majorité des cancers et elle est souvent associée à une durée de vie réduite des patients. Bien que l'activité transcriptionnelle de Cux1 pourrait expliquer comment sa surexpression favorise le développement et la progression des tumeurs, ses fonctions biochimiques, qui expliqueraient son rôle de suppresseur de tumeur, doivent encore être élucidées. De récentes avancées ont permis de définir un rôle pour la protéine Cux p200 en tant que protéine auxiliaire dans la réparation de l'ADN. Plus précisément, il a été montré que les domaines CUT de la protéine Cux1 stimulent l'activité enzymatique de trois protéines clés de la voie de réparation par excision de base. Cette nouvelle fonction de Cux1 nous a permis de faire l'hypothèse que lors d'une expression réduite de Cux1, la réparation de l'ADN est compromise, ce qui menerait à des mutations plus fréquentes et donc a un risque plus élevé de développer une tumeur. Afin de tester cette hypothèse, nous avons décidé de mesurer la fréquence des mutations dans une lignée cellulaire de lymphoblastes, TK6, dans laquelle l'expression de Cux1 est réduite. De manière robuste, nous avons observé une hausse de la fréquence des mutations lorsque l'expression de Cux1 est réduite. Cette hausse est plus forte lorsque les cellules sont traitées avec des radiations ionisantes. Nous avons mesuré l'ensemble des mutations de 135 clones HPRT négatifs par RT-qPCR et avons observé une hausse de du nombre de mutations ponctuelles, ce qui est en accord avec un rôle de Cux1 dans la réparation par excision de base. Nous avons également observé un plus grand nombre de réarrangements de séquences ce qui suggère que Cux1 pourrait avoir un rôle plus étendu dans différents processus de réparation de l'ADN.</description><creator>Pacheco Gilardi, Daniela</creator><contributor>Alain Nepveu (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Biochemistry</subject><title>The tumour suppression function of CUX1</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161839v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rq95p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78tf25m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Contexte: À l'échelle mondiale mais particulièrement dans les pays à faible ou moyen revenu, les blessures sont responsables d'une charge de morbidité considérablement élevée. Une étude des données épidémiologiques des blessures peut permettre d'identifier leurs facteurs de risque et de cibler les interventions nécessaires pour améliorer la qualité des soins. Les registres de traumatisme ont été identifiés comme l'outil essentiel pour réduire les taux de décès et d'handicap dûs aux traumatismes.Leur importance est bien reconnu par les pays en développement mais ils sont encore sous-utilisés en raison d'un manque de sensibilisation, de ressources et de fonds. L'objectif de l'étude était d'explorer la faisabilité des registres de traumatisme en en mettant en place dans un hôpital de soins tertiaires, en Inde, et d'estimer l'épidémiologie des blessures. Méthode:L'étude a été menée au sein des urgences de l'hôpital Institut municipal d'éducation et de recherche médicales de Surat (SMIMER )à Surat, en Inde, de juin à août 2018. En ayant l'accord des patients qui se sont présentés aux urgences avec une blessure, leurs données ont été collectées sous la forme papier du registre de traumatisme (TR). Le concept du registre de traumatisme a été développé au sein de la chirurgie globale, au centre universitaire de santé McGill, à Montréal, au Canada. Les informations sur les données démographiques des patients, les événements qui ont causés les blessures, la physiologie liée aux blessures, les données anatomiques et les résultats cliniques ont été enregistrées. Les données ont été entrées dans la version électronique du registre de traumatisme et une analyse a été effectuée. Résultats: Un total de 716 patients ont participés à l'étude. L'âge moyen des patients était de 33 ans, mais la majorité avait un âge compris entre 20 et 25 ans ou entre 30 et 35 ans. 74,16% des patients étaient des hommes. Les accidents de la route (34,64%) et les chutes (29,89%) ont été les cause les plus fréquentes de blessures, suivis des traumatismes contondants (13,41%). Les étudiants (28%) et les chômeurs (17%) ont été les plus fréquemment blessés et une majorité des patients avaient une éducation primaire et secondaire. 39,25% des patients ont été transportés par ambulance, 30,31% sont arrivés en voiture personnelle et 22,35% en transport en commun. Les plaies ouvertes (46%) représentaient la majorité des blessures, suivies des blessures thoraciques (22%) et de la tête (19%). Selon le calcul du score de traumatologie de Kampala (KTS), 1,4% avaient de graves blessures, contre 91,8% de blessures légères. Vingt patients sont décédés à l'hôpital, surtout à cause d'une blessure dûe à une chute ou à un collision de véhicule à moteur. Conclusion: Le registre de traumatisme à été un outil très efficace pour la relève des informations liés aux blessures. En effet, toutes les informations utile pour évaluer le fardeau des traumatismes et l'efficacité des soins offerts aux patients se trouvaient dans un simple formulaire d'une page. L'utilisation continue de ce genre de registre est nécessaire afin d'assurer des donnés de haute qualité et de couvrir adéquatement la population. De plus, un effort de collaboration est requis en Inde pour une mise en œuvre réussie.    </description><description>Background: The injury is responsible for a significantly high burden of disease globally, particularly in the low and middle income countries (LMICs). The epidemiological data of injury can help to identify risk factors for injury and target interventions to improve quality of care. Trauma registries (TR) have been recognized as an essential tool in decreasing death and disability rates from injuries. The importance of trauma registry has been widely recognized in the developing countries, but it is still underutilized due to lack of awareness, resources, and funding. The objective of the study was to explore the feasibility of the trauma registry by implementing it at a tertiary care hospital and estimate the epidemiology of the injury.  Method:  The study was conducted at the casualty of the Surat Municipal Institute of Medical Education and Research (SMIMER) hospital, Surat, India during June 2018 to August 2018. Data were collected on the paper form of TR after taking consent from the patients presented to the casualty department with the sustained injury. TR was developed at the center of the global surgery, McGill University Health Centre, Montreal, Canada. Data about patient demographics, causal event, injury-related physiologic, anatomic data, and clinical outcomes were recorded. Data were entered in the electronic version of the TR and analysis was done.  Result: A total of 716 patients were included in the study. The mean age of the patient was 33 year, and 74.16% were male with maximum patients were in the age group of 20-25 and 30-35. Motor vehicle collision (34.64%) and Fall (29.89 %) were the most common causes of the injury followed by blunt trauma (13.41%). Students (28%) and unemployed (17%) were most frequently affected with majority of patients having primary and secondary education. 39.25 % were brought by the ambulance whereas 30.31% of patients arrived by private vehicle and 22.35% came by public transport. Cut/Open wound (46%) accounted for the majority of the injury followed by thoracic injury (22%) and head injury (19%). According to Kampala Trauma Score (KTS) calculation, 1.4% were severely injured compared to 91.8% mildly injured. Twenty patients died in the hospital, mainly injured due to fall and Motor Vehicle Collision.  Conclusion:Trauma registry was effective to capture injury-related information in a simple one-page proforma in the study which would be helpful to assess the trauma burden and evaluate the effectiveness of care given to the patients. The continuous use of the TR is imperative to ensure high quality data and adequate population coverage and a collaborative effort is needed in India for successful implementation.   </description><creator>Patel, Prachikumari</creator><contributor>Dan Leon Elazar Deckelbaum (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Surgery</subject><title>Implementation of a hospital-based trauma registry in India</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117r136.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tf25m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vx021h39g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background Bone graft procedures are commonly performed worldwide for segmental bone defects resulting from high-energy trauma, congenital deformity, infection or tumor resection. The current gold standard for repair of large long bone defects is the use of bone and blood vessels, as vascularized bone graft, harvested from another part of the body and transplanted to the area of the missing tissue. This creates significant donor site injury and is often an inadequate anatomical match. Making synthetic vascularized bone without recourse to potentially dangerous and expensive growth factors can potentially revolutionize reconstructive surgery and provide significant improvements in patients' lives.  Inducing new blood vessels and engineering bones to custom geometry is the objective of many researchers but several technological hurdles remain. My thesis explores whether axial vascularization of a bioceramic affects bone generation from marrow aspirate and, to understand the impact of axial vascularization in bio-scaffolds. Methods We designed, cross-shaped, monetite bioceramic to fit the rat femoral vein and impregnated the scaffold with autologous bone marrow taken from the other leg. This implant was then implanted circumferentially around the vein of 16 rats and removed after 8 weeks. The structure, stability, and composition of the new bone was be assessed by micro computed tomography (micro-CT), Scanning Electron Microscope (SEM), and histopathology examinations. Results Scaffolds were printed with a mean deviation of +150 µm compared to their theoretical CAD model, were mainly composed of monetite (80.2%wt) and unreacted α- (1.8 %wt) and β-TCP (18 %wt) phases and displayed a micro- (&gt; 50%vol between 1 and 10 µm) and Nano-porosity. A greater volume of new bone tissue was observed and quantified (SEM, µCT) in scaffolds perfused by a central vein compared with the non-perfused negative control (65.0 ± 5.6 % of the initial scaffold volume versus 29.0 ± 4.2%, P &lt; 0.0001, N=4 or 5, triplicate representative areas per sample). Bone formation and ceramic biodegradation were (2.2 ± 0.2) and (2.9 ± 0.3) times higher for the experimental group than for the control one, respectively. In addition, implant biodegradation for both control and experimental groups were far greater than for both historical controls (implant and implant vascularized by a vein, ≈ 16.5% degradation). Conclusion Experiments showed promising results, we produced an axially vascularized tissue-engineered bone using marrow at a higher level than has been reported in the literature. This illustrates the intimate relationship between angiogenesis and osteogenesis, this is especially important to tackle the issues encountered for regeneration of critical-sized bone defects. In this study we showed that the presence of a vein perfusing a blood marrow soaked monetite implant allowed for generating enormous amount of bone (up to 65%) replacing the quasi totality of the implant (≈ 15% remaining). Even more, the structure adopted by this host-made engineered construct may surprisingly remain the structure of long bone, including a low vascularized and dense cortical layer surrounding a highly vascularized trabecular zone which hosts the marrow. Future work will focus on the mechanical stability of these vascularized bone flaps in load bearing sites.  </description><description>ContexteLe manque de substance osseuse faisant suite à un traumatisme, malformation congénitale, infection ou encore à l'ablation d'une tumeur peut être compensé par une greffe autologue de substance osseuse. En cas de perte osseuse importante, la procédure privilégiée consiste à transplanter un greffon osseux vascularisé, provenant d'un site sain du patient, au sein du défaut osseux où il sera connecté aux vaisseaux sanguins environnants. Bien que très bénéfique, la forme du greffon est souvent mal adaptée au défaut osseux, et la procédure comporte des risques non-négligeables. Générer à façon un greffon synthétique vascularisé sans prélever d'os sain ou utiliser les techniques onéreuses et encore peu maitrisées d'ingénierie tissulaire représenterait une avancée significative dans le domaine de la chirurgie reconstructrice ainsi qu'une amélioration significative de la vie des patients. Induire la formation sur mesure d'un tissu osseux vascularisé a fait l'objet de nombreuses recherches, néanmoins de multiples verrous technologiques persistent. Mes recherches visent à étudier l'impact que pourrait avoir l'insertion d'une veine au sein d'un implant imprégné de moelle osseuse sur sa revascularisation et sur sa colonisation par une nouvelle matrice osseuse. Méthodes Des biocéramiques en monétite comportant un canal central ont été produites via fabrication additive. Un modèle murin (N=8 rats / group) a été utilisé pour cette étude. Après avoir été imprégné par de la moelle osseuse, prélevée sur un des fémurs, la biocéramique a été placée autour de la veine fémorale du site opposé. Après sacrifice (8 semaines d'implantation), la structure, organisation et composition du nouvel os formé a été évaluée par microCT, microscope électronique à balayage et histologie.RésultatsUn écart moyen de +150 µm entre la géométrie des biocéramiques imprimées et leur modèle CAD a été observé. Après stérilisation, les implants comportaient une microporosité ente 1 et 10 µm, leur composition étant 80.2% en masse de monétite et respectivement 1.8 et 18% massique de réactifs initiaux (α- et β-TCP). Les analyses des explants (µCT, SEM, N= 4-5 x3) après 8 semaines d'implantation ont révélé que (i) la formation osseuse était (2.2 ± 0.2) fois plus importante (P&lt;0.0001) lorsque la biocéramique était perfusée par la veine fémorale (65.0 ± 5.6% versus 29.0 ± 4.2%) et (ii) la biodégradation des céramiques était (2.9 ± 0.3) supérieure en présence de cette veine. En outre, notons que la présence de moelle osseuse au sein de ces biocéramiques a stimulé leur biodégradation (c.f. contrôles historiques). Conclusion L'approche considérée a permis le développement de volumes osseux vascularisés par des vaisseaux de taille importante (≈ 1mm) en site ectopique – les valeurs rapportées étant bien supérieures à celles trouvées dans la littérature. Nos résultats illustrent les liens intimes entre angiogenèse et ostéogenèse, et avancent des perspectives prometteuses pour la régénération des défauts osseux de taille critique. En bref, nous avons démontré que la présence d'une veine peut supporter la formation d'un os nouveaux en site ectopique (65% du volume de l'implant) qui vient se substituer à la biodégradation de sa structure d'accueil. De plus, la structure adoptée par l'os formé n'est pas sans rappeler la structure naturelle des os longs, avec une corticale dense et peu vascularisée et une zone trabéculaire largement vascularisée et accueillant la moelle osseuse. De futurs travaux se focaliseront sur la transplantation et stabilité de ces greffons synthétiques vascularisés en site porteur orthotopique (e.g. fémur).</description><creator>Baradaran, Aslan</creator><contributor>Jake Barralet (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Surgery</subject><title>Synthetic vascularized bone grafts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cs73w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021h39g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn3013579</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La transformation dynamique (TD) est définie comme la transformation de phase qui a lieu pendant la déformation. Dans l'acier, l'austénite peut transformer de manière dynamique en ferrite au-dessus de la température de transformation à l'équilibre Ae3. La présente étude analyse l'occurrence de la TD lors du laminage à chaude simulé d'un acier oléoduc X80. Des essais de torsion ont été réalisés dans des conditions de refroidissement continu à travers la gamme de température 920-830 °C, c'est-à-dire au-dessus de la température Ae3 calculée. Des temps d'interpassage de 1, 8 et 20 s ont été examinés. Les échantillons ont été trempés à l'eau avant et après les passes de nombre impair et les fractions volumiques de ferrite et martensite (austénite antérieure) ont été déterminés. La formation de ferrite TD a été observée sous toutes les conditions et sa fraction volumique a augmenté avec la déformation. Comme une preuve de la TD, l'augmentation de la contrainte avec la déformation a été inférieure aux prévisions sous toutes les conditions. Lorsque les temps d'interpassage plus longs étaient utilisés, les niveaux de contrainte ont été plus élevés car la ferrite se reconvertit en austénite lors du temps de  maintien après la déformation. Les déformations critiques pour l'apparition de TD et de la recristallisation dynamique (RD) ont été déterminées à l'aide de la méthode de différentiation double. La force motrice et l'énergie d'activation de la TD ont également été calculées, indiquant que l'occurrence de la TD est thermodynamiquement possible lors du laminage à chaude.</description><description>Dynamic transformation (DT) is defined as the phase transformation that occurs during deformation. In steels, austenite can dynamically transform into ferrite above the equilibrium transformation temperature Ae3. The occurrence of DT during the simulated hot rolling of an API-X80 steel is described in the present study. Torsion tests were carried out under continuous cooling conditions over the temperature range 920 to 830 °C, all of which are above the calculated Ae3 temperature. Interpass times of 1, 8 and 20 s were examined. Samples were water quenched before and after the odd-numbered passes and the volume fractions of ferrite and martensite (prior austenite) were determined. The formation of DT ferrite was observed under all conditions, the volume fraction of which increased with strain. As a result of DT, the increase in flow stress with strain was less than expected under all conditions. When longer interpass times were employed, the stress levels were higher because ferrite transforms back into the harder austenite during holding after deformation. The critical strains for the onset of DT and dynamic recrystallization (DRX) were determined using the double differentiation method. The driving forces and energy barriers for DT were also calculated, indicating that the occurrence of DT is thermodynamically possible during hot rolling. </description><creator>Mendes Fonseca, Nizia</creator><contributor>John Joseph Jonas (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Stephen Yue (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Mining and Materials</subject><title>Dynamic transformation during the simulated hot rolling of an API-X80 steel</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290c76r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn3013579</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720g14t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bullying at school is recognized as a global phenomenon and has serious impacts on students' well-being.  Previous studies have explored how parental practices as well as children's empathy were separately linked to children's bullying behaviors.  However, few studies have examined the combined association between parental practices, adolescents' empathy, and their bullying behaviors.  The present study investigated the relationship among Chinese adolescents' perceived parental practices (parental warmth, parental autonomy support, and parental psychological control), empathy (cognitive empathy and affective empathy), and bullying behaviors.  Participants of this study included 277 Chinese adolescents from grade seven to grade twelve.  Using the structural equation model, results indicated that affective empathy mediated between maternal warmth (but not paternal) and bullying behaviors.  In addition, both parental autonomy support and psychological control were mediated by cognitive empathy, which, in turn, were linked to bullying behaviors.  Findings from this study are expected to contribute to better understanding of how bullying behavior is related to parenting and adolescents' empathic development.  Further the information obtained in this study will provide parents and educators with useful insights in reducing bullying in the Chinese context.</description><description>L'intimidation à l'école est reconnue comme un phénomène mondial ayant de graves répercussions sur les élèves.  Bien que des études antérieures ont exploré la relation entre les pratiques parentales et l'empathie chez les enfants, séparément des comportements d'intimidation chez ceux-ci, peu d'études ont examiné/analysé l'interrelation des pratiques parentales, l'empathie des adolescents et leurs comportements d'intimidation.  L'objectif de la présente étude tente d'établir la relation entre les pratiques parentales perçues par des adolescents chinois (chaleur parentale, soutien à l'autonomie des adolescents par les parents et contrôle psychologique parental), l'empathie (empathie cognitive et empathie affective) et les comportements de harcèlement.  Pour ce faire, les données de 277 adolescents chinois de septième à douzième année ont été recueillies.  L'analyse de ces données, suivant le modèle d'équation structurelle, démontre que l'empathie affective était un médiateur entre le comportement chaleureux, uniquement de la mère, et des actes d'intimidation.  De plus, le soutien à l'autonomie des adolescents des parents et le contrôle psychologique, qui étaient médiés par l'empathie cognitive, étaient liés aux comportements d'intimidation.  Les résultats de cette étude devraient contribuer à une meilleure compréhension de la relation entre les comportements d'intimidation et le développement de l'empathie chez les parents et les adolescents.  De plus, les données de cette étude fourniront aux parents et aux éducateurs des informations utiles pour aider à réduire l'intimidation dans le contexte chinois.</description><creator>Kong, Xiaoxue</creator><contributor>Chiaki Konishi (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Educational and Counselling Psychology</subject><title>Bullying among Chinese adolescents: the roles of parental practices and empathy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff3657411.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720g14t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752k02j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dans cette thèse, Je développe un système complet de détection d'aliments multi-objets utilisant des réseaux de neurones à convolution profonde avec fonctions de transfert, qui a été conçu pour fonctionner sur un appareil mobile et étendu à la génération de masques. Tout d'abord, dans le but d'obtenir une grande précision, mais une taille de modèle réduite et une faible latence, je construis un réseau de neurones à convolution fusionnant avec un pipeline de détection unifié, YOLOv2. Deuxièmement, je montre comment tirer profit de la tâche de détection d'objet d'une tâche de classification d'image via un apprentissage par transfert, de sorte que la méthode de détection des aliments proposée offre une capacité d'apprentissage supérieure basée sur la connaissance préalable, avec un temps de formation plus court et une convergence plus rapide. Il établit un lien entre les deux sujets les plus fondamentaux de la vision par ordinateur. De plus, j'adapte le modèle d'apprentissage en profondeur formé pour qu'il fonctionne sur un téléphone portable classique avec caméra intégrée et présente des informations nutritionnelles obtenues à partir des résultats de détection. L'application mobile est capable de fonctionner en temps réel avec une déduction rapide. Enfin, j'étends l'approche de détection des aliments proposée à une architecture d'apprentissage multitâche que je nomme Mask-YOLO, afin d'effectuer non seulement la détection d'objets, mais également la segmentation d'instances en générant des masques sur chaque région candidate. Cette thèse aborde certaines des tâches liées à la mise en place d'un système de surveillance automatique des aliments idéal permettant aux personnes de garder une trace des éléments de repas et du contenu nutritionnel dans la vie quotidienne à des fins de perte de poids ou à des fins médicales.</description><description>Through this thesis, I develop a complete multi-object food detection system by deep convolutional neural networks with transferring features, which has been tailored to run on mobile device and further extended on mask generation. First, with the purpose of high accuracy but small model size and low latency, I construct a convolutional neural network merging with a unified detection pipeline, YOLOv2. Second, I demonstrate how to benefit the object detection task from image classification task via transfer learning, so that the proposed food detection approach has a superior learning capacity based on prior knowledge, with shorter training time and faster convergence. It bridges the gap between the most two fundamental computer vision topics. Furthermore, I adapt the trained deep learning model to run on a conventional mobile phone with built-in camera, and present with nutrition facts obtained from the detection results. The mobile app is capable of running in real-time with fast inference. Finally, I extend the proposed food detection approach to a multi-task learning architecture that I call it Mask-YOLO, to perform not only object detection, but instance segmentation by generating masks on each candidate region. This thesis tackles some of the tasks towards building an ideal automatic food monitoring system that allows people to keep track of meal items and nutrition contents in daily life for weight loss or medical purposes.</description><creator>Sun, Jianing</creator><contributor>Zeljko Zilic (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Electrical and Computer Engineering</subject><title>Food detection system design by deep convolutional neural networks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mm12h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752k02j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mx705</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background: Although there is empirical support for peer support programs for individuals with spinal cord injury (SCI), they have not been embedded within most Chinese rehabilitation hospitals. This study is to explore how Chinese adults with SCI needed and viewed hospital-based peer support programs. Methodology: Six inpatients with SCI from Tianjin, China were interviewed twice. The first interview explored participants' background (e.g., family) and life experiences pre- and post-injury. The second interview focused on their perspectives on peer support and their vision of delivering peer support programs. Thematic analysis was conducted. Results: Participants have varied life experiences pre- and post-SCI. Their perspectives on how peer support would help or impede their rehabilitation were different as they approach their rehabilitation in different ways based on their rehabilitation goals. For example, some participants solely focused on the recovery of physical functioning and highlighted that peers could supplement and help individualize rehabilitation exercise guidance. The participants who concentrated on their future lives believed that they could learn skills related to activities of daily living and obtain motivation and hope from peers who have integrated in the community. In addition, other participants reported not being able to trust peers, especially because peers have different injuries (type, level, and severity) and functioning status. In terms of peer support delivery, participants favored receiving peer support from one or multiple peers through online chat group (i.e., Wechat), in-person conversations, and mentoring lectures. Conclusion: Our findings suggest that participants in the current study have mixed perspectives on peer support but expressed overall needs for hospital-based peer support programs. Customized peer support programs designed based on individual's goals could be a viable rehabilitation option among Chinese SCI population.</description><description>Contexte: Bien qu'il y a un soutien empirique pour les programmes de soutien par les pairs pour les personnes atteintes de lésion médullaire (LM), ceux-ci ne sont pas intégrés dans la plupart des hôpitaux de réadaptation en Chine. Cette étude a pour objectif d'expliquer comment les adultes chinois ayant une LM avaient besoin et envisageaient des programmes de soutien par les pairs en milieu hospitalier. Méthodologie: Six patients hospitalisés avec une LM à Tianjin, Chine, ont passer un entretient à deux reprises. L'une des entriens a permis d'explorer les antécédents des participants (par exemple, la famille) et leurs expériences de vie avant et après leur blessure. La deuxième entrevue concernait leur point de vue sur le soutien par les pairs et leur vision de la prestation de programmes de soutien par les pairs. Une analyse thématique a été réalisée. Résultats: Les participants ont des expériences de vie variées avant et après la LM. Leurs points de vue sur la manière dont le soutien des pairs aiderait ou entraverait leur réadaptation sont également différente and lié à leurs objectifs concernant leur réadaptation. Par exemple, certains participants se concentrent uniquement sur le rétablissement de la fonction physique et ont souligné que les pairs pourraient complémenter et individualiser les conseils relatifs aux exercices de réadaptation. Les participants qui se concentrent sur leur vie future ont cru pouvoir acquérir des compétences liées aux activités de la vie quotidienne et obtenir de la motivation et de l'espoir de la part des leurs qui sont intégrés dans la communauté. En outre, d'autres participants ont déclaré ne pas pouvoir faire confiance à leurs pairs, notamment parce que leurs pairs ont des blessures (type, niveau et gravité) et un statut fonctionnel différents. En ce qui concerne la prestation du soutien par les pairs, les participants ont préféré recevoir du support d'un ou de plusieurs pairs par le biais de groupes de discussion en ligne (Wechat), de conversations en personne et de conférences de mentorat. Conclusion: Nos résultats suggèrent que les participants à la présente étude ont des points de vue mitigés sur le soutien par les pairs mais ont exprimé des besoin généraux en programmes de soutien par les pairs en milieu hospitalier. Des programmes personnalisés de soutien par les pairs conçus en fonction d'objectifs individuels pourraient constituer une option de réadaptation viable pour la population chinoise ayant une lésion médullaire.</description><creator>Shi, Zhiyang</creator><contributor>Shane Sweet (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Kinesiology and Physical Education</subject><title>Exploring the needs for hospital-based peer support programs of Chinese people living with spinal cord injury</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21th65f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mx705</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848s709</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Collective behavior has drawn much attention in recent years. Many models have been created to study the collective motion of cells. Nevertheless, the contribution of substrate deformation and its influence on the emergent properties of cells is less well known. One of the most successful models is the Vicsek model which uses the dynamical equations to describe the position and orientation of the cells. In this work, we have used the elastic free energy of cell pairs to and the repolarization ofthe cells due to soft and stiff substrates deformations. Various type of structures form as we change the substrate stiffness and cell-cell adhesion strength. Based on our simulations, cells exhibit highly correlated motions on stiff substrates, where the elastic forces are less dominant, and low correlated motions on the soft substrates. These results have been observed in the experiments as well. Furthermore, cells are known to be responsive to the gradients of stiffness in their environment. Such a phenomenon is called Durotaxis, which is a necessary element of the wound healing process. We show that our model can give rise to the directed migration of the cells towards rigid regions. Our results are in agreement with recent experimental work.</description><description>Le comportement collectif a attiré beaucoup d'attention ces derniéres années. De nombreux modéles ont été créés pour étudier le mouvement collectif des cellules. Néanmoins, la contribution de la déformation du substrat et son influence sur les propriétés émergentes des cellules sont moins connues. L'un des modéles les plus aboutis est le modéle de Vicsek, qui utilise les équations dynamiques pour décrire la position et l'orientation des cellules. Dans ce travail, nous avons utilisé l'énergie libre élastique des paires de cellules pour trouver la repolarisation des cellules due aux déformations des substrats souples et rigides. Différents types de structures se forment lorsque nous modifions la rigidité du substrat et la force d'adhésion cellule-cellule. Sur la base de nos simulations, les cellules présentent des mouvements fortement corrélés sur des substrats rigides, où les forces élastiques sont moins dominantes, et des mouvements peu corrélés sur les substrats souples. Ces résultats ont également été observés dans les expériences. De plus, nous savons que les cellules réagissent aux gradients de rigidité de leur environnement. Un tel phénoméne s'appelle la durotaxie, élément indispensable du processus de cicatrisation. Nous montrons que notre modéle peut donner lieu à la migration dirigée des cellules vers des régions rigides. Nos résultats concordent avec les travaux expérimentaux récents.</description><creator>Madanchi, Ata</creator><contributor>Martin Grant (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Physics</subject><title>Modeling collective behavior of cells in the presence of elastic forces</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hf39z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848s709</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bk128d16n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'utilisation excessive de combustibles fossiles non renouvelables a eu une influence considérable sur l'économie et l'environnement au niveau mondial. Actuellement, nous sommes en train de passer d'une source d'énergie à base de carbone (pétrole, gaz, charbon) à une énergie verte telle que le vent et le soleil sous forme d'électricité. Par conséquent, la demande et le marché des dispositifs de stockage d'énergie d'applications diverses ont augmenté rapidement au cours des dernières années.Les batteries, en tant que dispositifs de stockage d'énergie, sont actuellement privilégiées par le marché car elles ont une densité d'énergie élevée et peuvent fournir des niveaux de puissance de sortie appropriés pour diverses applications. Cependant, face à la demande croissante de performances d'appareils plus complexes, des inconvénients tels qu'une durée de vie réduite et une densité de puissance relativement faible ont limité leurs applications. Pour résoudre ce problème, une solution prometteuse consiste à combiner des batteries avec des supercondensateurs pour créer des sources d'alimentation hybrides. Actuellement, les électrodes de supercondensateurs sont principalement basées sur des matériaux à base de carbone et stockent de l'énergie par chargement électrostatique de la double couche électrochimique, ce qui limite leur densité d'énergie. Ainsi, de nombreuses recherches ont été consacrées au développement de nouveaux matériaux pour électrodes pouvant stocker une plus grande quantité d'énergie, notamment au développement de pseudo condensateurs basés sur l'utilisation d'électrodes MMO (Oxydes Métalliques Mixtes) pouvant générer une énergie et une densité de puissance plus élevées du fait de l'apparition de réactions redox rapides et réversibles en phase solide.Dans ce travail, des revêtements de RuxBi1-x-oxyde de différentes compositions préparés thermiquement ont été formés sur un substrat de Ti, dans le but d'étudier l'influence de l'addition de d'oxyde de Bi sur la capacité résultante de stockage/libération de charges de l'oxyde. Des tests électrochimiques (voltamètrie cyclique, charge/décharge galvanostatique et spectroscopie d'impédance électrochimique) ont été effectués sur les revêtements dans une cellule à trois électrodes à 295 K et sous pression atmosphérique, tandis que des expériences de charge/décharge galvanostatiques ont également été réalisées dans une cellule à deux électrodes. De plus, la topographie de surface et la morphologie des revêtements RuxBi1-x-oxyde et la distribution des éléments ont été étudiées par SEM/EDS.Il a été constaté que l'ajout d'oxyde de Bi dans le revêtement d'oxyde de Ru entraînait un changement significatif de la capacité de stocker/délivrer les charges de l'oxyde, produisant une dépendance en forme de cloche avec une valeur maximale offerte par le revêtement d'oxyde de Ru0.6Bi0.4 (195 ± 11 mF/cm2), ce qui est considérablement plus élevé que le matériau d'électrode de pointe actuel, à savoir l'oxyde de ruthénium pur. Dans la configuration à deux électrodes, le matériau permettait d'obtenir une capacité encore plus élevée (266 ± 51 mF/cm2 à 3 mA/cm2), ce qui en faisait un candidat prometteur en tant que matériau d'électrode pseudo-condensateur.</description><description>The global economy and environment have been influenced remarkably by the excessive use of non-renewable fossil fuels. Currently, we are undergoing a period that is shifting from relying on carbon-intensive sources of energy (oil, gas, coal) to green energy such as wind and solar in the form of electricity. Therefore, the demand and the market for energy storage devices of various applications has been increasing rapidly during the last few years. Batteries, as (surplus) energy-storage devices, are currently favored by the market because they have large energy density and can provide suitable levels of power output for various applications. However, with the increasing demand for power/performance of more complex electronic and other devices, the disadvantages such as short lifetime and relatively low power density limited their applications. To solve this problem, a promising solution is to combine batteries with supercapacitors to create hybrid power sources. Currently, supercapacitor electrodes are mainly based on carbon materials and store energy by electrostatic charging of the electrochemical double-layer, which limits their energy density. Thus, much of research has been focused on developing new electrode materials that can store a larger amount of energy, i.e. on developing pseudocapacitors based on the use of MMO (Mixed Metal Oxides) electrodes that can yield higher energy and power density due to the occurrence of fast and reversible redox reactions in the solid phase.In this work, thermally-prepared RuxBi1-x-oxide coatings of various composition were formed on a Ti substrate, with the aim of investigating the influence of Bi-oxide addition on the resulting charge storage/delivery capacity of the oxide. Electrochemical tests (cyclic voltammetry, galvanostatic charge/discharge, and electrochemical impedance spectroscopy) were performed on the coatings in a three-electrode cell at 295 K and under atmospheric pressure, while galvanostatic charge/discharge experiments were also performed in a two-electrode cell. In addition, the surface topography and morphology of RuxBi1-x-oxide coatings and distribution of elements were investigated by SEM/EDS.It was found that addition of Bi-oxide into the Ru-oxide coating resulted in a significant change in the oxide's charge storage/delivery capacity, yielding a bell-shaped dependence with a maximum value offered by the Ru0.6Bi0.4-oxide coating (195 ± 11 mF/cm2), which is significantly higher than the current state-of-the-art electrode material, pure ruthenium oxide. In the two-electrode configuration, the material yielded even a higher capacitance (266 ± 51 mF/cm2 at 3 mA/cm2), making this material a promising candidate as a pseudocapacitor electrode material. </description><creator>Yu, Hao</creator><contributor>Sasha Omanovic (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Chemical Engineering</subject><title>RuxBi1-x-oxide electrodes for electrochemical pseudo-capacitors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290c771.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128d16n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752k043</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:28:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The small fruit market (grapes, strawberries, blueberries and raspberries) is valued at more than $100 million per year in Quebec, Canada. Farmers seek to produce small fruits with high yield and quality. Wood-based biochar could be used as a soil amendment to improve soil quality, which may promote small fruit growth. The objectives of this research were to (1) determine if wood-based biochar can increase the yield and quality of grape, strawberry, blueberry and raspberry in southern Quebec,  (2) present a simple evaluation system  to compare fruit quality in biochar plots versus control plots, and (3) determine if wood-based biochar application resulted in a long-term improvement of soil physical and chemical properties in a vineyard in southern Quebec. It was hypothesized that wood-based biochar will boost the yield of grape, strawberry, blueberry and raspberry, and improve quality parameters like average fruit weight, fruit firmness, colour, juice pH, total soluble solids (TSS), total phenolic content (TPC) and antioxidant activity, for optimal fruit quality. Furthermore, it was hypothesized that that soil physical and chemical quality improvements will be detectable several years after applying wood-based biochar. The field trials for grapes, strawberries, blueberries and raspberries were established on commercial farms in southern Quebec. Plots received biochar (n=5 per site) and no biochar (n=5 per site) in April to May 2013. Small fruit yield was assessed throughout the fruit harvest period and samples were collected during September to October 2013 for fruit quality evaluation. Soil samples were collected from the vineyard in July 2018 to assess the long-term impact of wood-based biochar on soil quality. Average fruit weight of strawberry was significantly (P&lt;0.05) greater with the wood-based biochar application, possibly due to plant-available nutrients supplied by biochar, but there was no effect of biochar on the yield or quality of other small fruits. Grapes and raspberries had good fruit quality, similar to published ranges, in both biochar-amended and control plots. Strawberry TSS and TPC values were suboptimal due to cold weather condition and air exposure during fruit storage. Large blueberry fruit size in biochar-amended and control plots suggests that the crop should be profitable when sold as fresh blueberry. Among soil physico-chemical properties, only soil bulk density, extractable magnesium (Mg) and extractable boron (B) concentrations were significantly (P&lt;0.05) affected by the application of wood-based biochar applied five years earlier. Wood-based biochar application rates were considered to be too low to affect the small fruits growth, but still contributed to alleviate soil compaction by reducing soil bulk density and reduce nutrient loss by absorbing some nutritive elements (e.g., Mg and B) after five years. Overall, wood-based biochar is not expected to be an effective soil amendment to improve small fruit yield and quality in southern Quebec, Canada.</description><description>Le marché des petits fruits (raisins, fraises, bleuets et framboises) est évalué à plus de 100 millions de dollars par an au Québec, Canada. Les agriculteurs cherchent à produire de petits fruits avec un rendement et une qualité élevés. Le biocharbon à base de bois pourrait être utilisé comme amendement du sol pour améliorer la qualité du sol, ce qui pourrait favoriser la croissance de petits fruits. Les objectifs de cette recherche étaient (1) de déterminer si le biochar à base de bois pourrait augmenter le rendement et la qualité du raisin, de la fraise, du bleuet et de la framboise dans le sud du Québec, (2) de présenter un système d'évaluation simple permettant de comparer la qualité des fruits dans les parcelles de biochar et (3) déterminer si l'application de biocharbon à base de bois a entraîné une amélioration à long terme des propriétés physiques et chimiques du sol dans un vignoble du sud du Québec. On a émis l'hypothèse que le biocharbon à base de bois augmenterait le rendement en raisin, fraise, bleuet et framboise, et améliorerait les paramètres de qualité tels que le poids moyen des fruits, la fermeté des fruits, la couleur, le pH du jus, le total des solides solubles, le contenu phénolique total) et une activité antioxydante, pour une qualité optimale des fruits. En outre, il a été émis l'hypothèse que les améliorations de la qualité physique et chimique du sol seraient détectables plusieurs années après l'application du biocharbon à base de bois. Les essais au champ pour les raisins, les fraises, les bleuets et les framboises ont été réalisés dans des fermes commerciales du sud du Québec. Les parcelles ont reçu du biocharbon (n = 5 par site) et aucun biocharbon (n = 5 par site) en avril-mai 2013. Le rendement en petits fruits a été évalué pendant toute la période de récolte des fruits et des échantillons ont été recueillis de septembre à octobre 2013 pour l'évaluation de la qualité des fruits. Des échantillons de sol ont été recueillis dans le vignoble en juillet 2018 afin d'évaluer l'impact à long terme du biocharbon à base de bois sur la qualité du sol. Le poids moyen des fruits de la fraise était significativement (P &lt;0.05) supérieur avec l'application de biocharbon à base de bois, probablement en raison des éléments nutritifs disponibles fournis par le biocharbon, mais le n'avait aucun effet sur le rendement ou la qualité des autres petits fruits. Les raisins et les framboises avaient une qualité de fruit optimale dans les parcelles amendées au biochar et les parcelles témoins. Les valeurs de TSS et de TPC pour les fraises étaient sous-optimales en raison des conditions météorologiques froides et de l'exposition à l'air pendant le stockage des fruits. La taille des gros fruits de bleuet dans les parcelles amendées au biochar et les parcelles témoins suggère que la culture devrait être rentable lorsqu'elle est vendue comme bleuet frais. Parmi les propriétés physico-chimiques du sol, seules les concentrations de masse volumique apparente, de magnésium extractible (Mg) et de bore extractible (B) étaient significativement (P &lt;0.05) affectées par l'application de biocharbon à base de bois appliqué cinq ans auparavant. Les taux d'application du biocharbon à base de bois ont été jugés trop faibles pour affecter la croissance des petits fruits, mais ont néanmoins contribué à réduire le compactage du sol en réduisant la densité apparente du sol et la perte de nutriments en absorbant certains éléments nutritifs (par exemple, le Mg et le B) après cinq ans. Le biocharbon à base de bois ne s'est pas avéré être un amendement de sol efficace pour améliorer le rendement et la qualité des petits fruits dans le sud du Québec, au Canada.</description><creator>Shang, Xuan</creator><contributor>Joann Karen Whalen (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2019</date><subject>Natural Resource Sciences</subject><title>Effect of wood-based biochar on soil quality, small fruit yield and quality in southern Quebec, Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r778s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752k043</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2925</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>