<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T00:54:50Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):13450" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s585z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Certaines habiletés auditivomotrices, telles que parler ou jouer d'un instrument de musique, requièrent des compétences particulières sur les plans du traitement auditif des sons produits et de la production des actions menant à l'émission de ces sons. À cet égard, un nombre croissant de preuves empiriques suggère que les composantes de perception et de production des habiletés auditivomotrices s'incèrent à l'intérieur d'interactions réciproques entre le système auditif et le système moteur. Plusieurs questions concernant la façon dont des séquences auditives complexes s'alignent avec des séquences complexes de mouvements, telles que retrouvées dans la parole ou les performances musicales, demeurent néanmoins irrésolues. Notamment par rapport à la façon dont les interactions entre les systèmes auditif et moteur influencent l'apprentissage et la rétention de nouvelles séquences auditivomotrices chez des executants compétents. Les recherches décrites dans cette thèse visent à aborder ces questions dans le contexte de performances musicales. En effet, étant donné qu'elles requièrent un contrôle précis de la hauteur du son et de la sequence temporelle des événements, les performances musicales sont des comportements auditivomoteurs communs et complexes représentant un modèle avantageux dans l'examen des capacités auditivomotrices. Trois études sont proposées afin d'examiner l'influence des interactions entre les systèmes auditif et moteur sur la façon dont des musiciens compétents alignent la hauteur sonore et les sequences temporelles avec les mouvements requis lors de performances musicales, de même que sur la façon dont ils apprennent et retiennent une séquence musicale. La première étude examine la manière dont la hauteur sonore et la structuretemporelle d'une séquence musicale engagent certains réseaux neuronaux du système moteur sur le plan des interactions auditivomotrices (Chapitre 2). Cette étude révèle que les réseaux du système moteur sont sensibles à l'intensité sonore et à la structure temporelle lorsque des musiciens écoutent et jouent de la musique. Ces résultats suggèrent que le système moteur intègre de multiples dimensions relatives à la structure de la séquence auditive lorsque ces sequences auditives sont alignées avec des séquences motrices lors de performances musicales. La deuxième étude examine l'utilisation des informations auditives et motrices dans l'apprentissage de séquences auditives (Chapitre 3). Cette etude révèle que les musiciens reconnaissent mieux les séquences auditives qu'ils ont eu à apprendre en les jouant avec rétroaction auditive, par rapport à celles qu'ils ont uniquement eu à écouter. Ces résultats indiquent que l'apprentissage moteur facilite la mémorisation d'information auditive chez les exécutants compétents. La troisième étude examine l'influence des différences individuelles sur le plan des habiletés d'imagerie auditive et motrice, sur l'apprentissage de nouvelles séquences musicales et sur le rappel de ces mêmes séquences (Chapitre 4). Cette étude révèle que les habiletés d'imagerie auditive aident les exécutants à apprendre de nouvelles séquences musicales en compensant pour les sons manquants, de même qu'en réduisant l'interférence liée à l'informations non pertinente; les habiletés d'imagerie auditive améliorent également le rappel de séquences musicales lors de performances comportant une plus grande régularitétemporelle. De manière générale, ces résultats suggèrent que les habiletés d'imagerie auditive aident différemment à l'apprentissage de nouvelles sequences musicales et à leur rappel. Ensemble, ces études illustrent le fonctionnement des intégrations auditivomotrices chez les exécutants compétents, ainsi que leur contribution à l'apprentissage et à la mémorisation de séquences auditivomotrices.</description><description>Auditory-motor skills such as speaking or playing a musical instrument require skill in processing auditory outcomes and performing actions that produce those outcomes. A growing body of evidence suggests that perception and production components of auditory-motor skill are integrated by reciprocal auditory-to-motor and motor-to-auditory interactions. Much remains unknown about how complex auditory sequences map to complex movement sequences such as those required of speech or music performance. Less still is known about how auditory-motor interactions influence the way skilled performers learn and remember novel auditory-motor sequences. The research described in this thesis examined these questions in the context of music performance. Music performance is a common and complex auditory-motor behavior that presents a useful model for examining human auditory-motor capabilities as it requires precise control of both pitch and temporal sequences of events. Three studies examined how auditory-motor interactions influence the way skilled musicians map pitch and temporal sequences to movements and the way musicians learn and remember music. The first study examined how auditory pitch and temporal sequence structure in music engage motor neural networks in auditory-motor interactions (Chapter 2). This study revealed motor networks that are sensitive to both pitch and temporal structure when musicians listen to and subsequently perform music. This finding suggests that the motor system integrates multiple dimensions of auditory sequence structure when performers map auditory sequences to motor sequences. The second study examined how performers use auditory and motor information to learn auditory sequences (Chapter 3). This study revealed that musicians better recognize auditory sequences that they hadlearned while producing them with auditory feedback than while hearing them only, indicating that motor learning facilitates subsequent auditory memory for skilled performers. The third study examined how individual differences in auditory and motor imagery abilities influence the way musicians learn novel music and subsequently remember that music (Chapter 4). This study revealed that auditory imagery abilities help performers learn novel music by compensating for missing sound and reducing sensitivity to interfering information; auditory imagery abilities also help performers recall music during performance with greater temporal regularity. Overall, these results suggest that auditory imagery abilities aid learning and subsequent recall of music differently. Together, these studies illuminate how auditory-motor integration functions in skilled performance and how it contributes to auditory-motor sequence learning and memory.</description><creator>Brown, Rachel</creator><contributor>Caroline Palmer (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Psychology - Cognitive</subject><title>Auditory-motor integration in music performance, learning, and memory</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fq18v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s585z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4f16c595f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les aminoglycosides sont une classe d'antibiotiques à large-spectre qui ont vu leur utilisation augmenter dans les années 1950, surtout en raison de leur efficacité contre la tuberculose. La résistance aux aminoglycosides dans les bactéries devient cependant un problème de plus en plus important. Un des méchanismes les plus communs de résistance aux aminoglycosides résulte de l'expression de l'enzyme aminoglycoside N-6'-acetyltransférase (AAC(6ʹ)) par les bactéries. Pour addresser ce problème, des bisubstrats d'aminoglycoside-coenzyme A ont précédemment été reportés par le groupe Auclair et ce sont avérés être des inhibiteurs puissants de l'enzyme AAC(6ʹ). Malheureusement, la charge négative des groupements phosphate de ces molécules semble empêcher leur pénétration cellulaire. Ces groupements phosphate ont ensuite été remplacés par différents bioisostères. Un des ces composés a été démontré être le premier composé capable de bloquer AAC(6') dans des souches bactériennes résistantes. Malheureusement, l'activité inhibitrice de cette molécule envers AAC(6') était faible. Pour combattre la résistance aux aminoglycosides, les travaux de cette thèse se concentrent sur la génération de prodrogues activèes en bisubstrats aminoglycoside-coenzyme A dans les cellules bactériennes. Étant de puissants inhibiteurs d'AAC(6ʹ), ces bisubstrats vont resensibiliser les bactéries à l'effect des aminoglycosides. Cette approche est basée sur l'hypothèse que les molécules aminoglycoside-pantothéine perméables peuvent être transformées par les enzymes responsable de la synthèse du coenzyme A (CoA) dans les bactéries, pour produire des puissants inhibiteurs d'AAC(6ʹ) dans les cellules. Le chapitre 2 décrit le design et la synthèse de la première série d'inhibiteurs prodrogues, ainsi que les dérivés utilisés pour obtenir une relation structure-activité (SAR). Dans le chapitre 3, plusieurs études enzymatiques permettant de vérifier le méchanisme d'activation des dites prodrogues sont décrites. Les résultats montrent que la transformation de la prodrogue par les enzymes biosynthétiques de CoA (PanK, PPAT, DPCK) est possible avec une corrélation significative entre l'activité et la longueur de la chaine de carbone de ces molécules. Finalement, pour démontrer l'activité des prodrogues, le chapitre 4 traite d'expériences permettant de déterminer l'activité potentiatrice des prodrogues sur l'effet antibacterien des aminoglycosides contre les souches resistante. Les résultats montrent un niveau considérable d'augmentation de l'activité des aminoglycoside contre E. faecium, une souche bactérienne résistante aux aminoglycosides, en presence des prodrogues. Cet effet produit  une déduction du MIC50 allant jusqu'à 30 fois. En resumé, les travaux presentes dan cette thèse, valident l'hypothèse de recherche et présente une preuve de concept pour le potentiel d'inhibiteurs prodrogues d'AAC(6ʹ) dans le but de resensibiliser certaines souches bactériennes résistantes aux antibiotiques aminoglycosides.</description><description>Aminoglycosides are a class of broad-spectrum antibiotics that first came to prominence in the 1950s as the first effective treatment for tuberculosis. Aminoglycoside resistance in bacteria, however, is increasingly becoming a difficult problem to treat. One of the most common mechanisms of aminoglycoside resistance in bacteria is the expression of the clinically widespread enzyme, aminoglycoside N-6ʹ-acetyltransferase (AAC(6ʹ)). To address this problem, aminoglycoside-coenzyme A bisubstrates were previously reported by the Auclair lab and found to be potent inhibitors of AAC(6ʹ). Unfortunately, the negatively charged phosphate groups of these molecules likely prevent penetration through cellular membranes. Further research then replaced the phosphate groups of the aforementioned molecules with mimics that would not impede cell membrane penetration. One of these compounds was shown to be the first biologically active compound in blocking AAC(6ʹ) in a resistant strain of bacteria. However, the inhibitory activity of this derivative against AAC(6ʹ) was poor. To combat aminoglycoside resistance, this work focuses on the use of prodrugs to produce potent aminoglycoside-coenzyme A bisubstrates within bacterial cells, thereby resensitizing resistant strains of bacteria. This approach is based on the hypothesis that cell-permeable aminoglycoside-pantetheine molecules can be transformed by the bacterial coenzyme A (CoA) biosynthetic pathway to produce potent AAC(6ʹ) inhibitors within cells. Chapter 2 describes the design and synthesis of two generations of AAC(6ʹ) prodrug inhibitors. In Chapter 3, various in vitro enzymatic studies were performed to verify the mechanism of prodrug activation. Results show that prodrug transformation by the CoA biosynthetic enzymes, PanK, PPAT, and DPCK, was possible with a significant trend observed in relation to the carbon linker length of these molecules. Finally, to demonstrate the biological activity of the prodrugs, Chapter 4 focuses on experiments aimed at determining the potentiation activity of the prodrugs in blocking resistance within cells, thereby resensitizing bacteria to aminoglycosides. Results show considerable potentiation of aminoglycoside activity by the prodrugs against an aminoglycoside-resistant strain of E. faecium, with a reduction in the MIC50 by as much as 30 fold. Overall, this work successfully validates the research hypothesis and presents a proof-of-concept for the potential of AAC(6ʹ) prodrug inhibitors to resensitize select resistant bacteria to aminoglycoside antibiotics.</description><creator>Vong, Kenward</creator><contributor>Karine Auclair (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Chemistry - Biochemistry</subject><title>Prodrug inhibitors of the aminoglycoside resistance-causing enzyme aminoglycoside N-6'-acetyltransferase</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278x669.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c595f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vx021j438</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bien que beaucoup d'attention a été accordée à la compréhension des mécanismes d'initiation des tempêtes convectives sur un terrain montagneux, beaucoup moins a été mis sur les facteurs qui contrôlent leur évolution ultérieure. Ici, nous effectuons une enquête observationelle et numérique des tempêtes initiées par les montagnes Black Hills du South Dakota. Ces montagnes initient beaucoup de convection grace à leur accès à l'air humide et instable. L'application d'un algorithme suivant les pistes de 53 tempêtes initiés par les Black Hills a révélé trois types d'évolution: tempête de courte-piste, courte-durée; tempête de courte-piste, longue-durée; et tempête de longue-piste, longue-durée. Un analysis des profils de vents pendant chaque événement a révélé de légères differences entre les types de tempêtes, qui ont été testés par des simulations numériques. Les longueurs de piste et les durées des tempêtes produites dans ces simulations étaient similaires à celles des événements observés, ce qui démontre que ces légères différences dans les profils de vent pourraient en effet expliquer l'évolution de chaque type de tempête.</description><description>While significant attention has been given to understanding the initiation mechanisms of convective storms over mountainous terrain, far less has been given to the factors controlling their subsequent evolution. Here we perform an observational and numerical investigation of the evolution of convective storms initiated by the Black Hills mountains of South Dakota. These Hills are preferentially located within the United States to access moist, unstable air, and are thus a local hot-spot for convection initiation. Applying a convective-celltracking algorithm to 53 observed events initiated by the Black Hills revealed three types of storm evolution: short-lived, short-track cells; long-lived, short-trackcells; and long-lived, long-track cells. Analysis of the background wind profiles during each event revealed modest differences amongst the storm types, which were tested using quasi-idealized, convection-permitting numerical simulations. The track-lengths and durations of convective cells produced in these simulations were consistent with those in our observed events, demonstrating that these modest differences in background wind profile could indeed largely explain a convective storm's evolution.</description><creator>Soderholm, Brett</creator><contributor>Daniel Kirshbaum (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Atmospheric Sciences</subject><title>The evolution of convective storms initiated by an isolated mountain range</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58ph29s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021j438</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806337q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>CUX1 is a transcription factor implicated in the control of cell proliferation.  Over-expression of CUX1 is observed in many human tumors and cancer cell lines.  Cells constitutively over-expressing the p110 isoform of CUX1 proliferate faster and spend less time in G1 following quiescence.  We studied three aspects of CUX1 function and regulation during the cell cycle.  In the first part of this study we investigated how over-expression of p110 CUX1 results in a shortened G1.  Using quantitative PCR we showed that over-expression of p110 CUX1 caused an increase in the transcription of DDK genes (cdc7 and Dbf4) upon exit from quiescence.  Western blot analysis revealed that p110 CUX1 cells display elevated phosphorylation of MCM2 serine 5 (pS5-MCM2) during quiescence, indicating an increased activity of DDK.  This was associated with a faster loading of MCM2 onto the chromatin after re-entry into the cell cycle and a shortening of G1 as shown by FACS.  In a set of experiments, we investigated how the phosphorylation of CUX1 by cyclinD1-CDK4 contributes to cell cycle regulation.  Electrophoretic mobility shift assay (EMSA) analysis revealed that phosphorylation of a recombinant CUX1 protein (1125-1505) by cyclinD1-CDK4 inhibited its DNA binding while PKA activated it.  Another recombinant CUX1 protein (1125-1308), missing the C-terminal repression domains, is activated by cyclinD1-CDK4 and inhibited by PKA.  Autoradiography and western blot analysis revealed that cyclinD1-CDK4 phosphorylates CUX1 on S1216 while PKA phosphorylates S1215 and S1216.  FACS analyses showed that cells expressing mutant p110 CUX1S1215/1216A decrease in size with extended passages in culture and eventually die by apoptosis, indicating the importance of cyclinD1-CDK4 regulation in maintaining cell size.  Thirdly, during mitosis CUX1 appears ~15kDa larger when observed by SDS-PAGE.  We wanted to search for any large post translational modifications such as ubiquitin.  No such modifications were identified, however, using mass spectrometry we demonstrated that during mitosis CUX1 is phosphorylated on at least twelve residues compared to six during G2.</description><description>CUX1 est un facteur de transcription impliqué dans la régulation de la prolifération cellulaire. La surexpression de CUX1 est observée dans de nombreuses tumeurs humaines et lignées de cellules cancéreuses. Les cellules qui surexpriment constitutivement l'isoforme p110 de CUX1 prolifèrent plus rapidement et passent moins de temps en G1 après quiescence. Nous avons étudié trois aspects de la régulation de CUX1 au cours du cycle cellulaire.  Dans la première partie de cette étude, nous avons analysé le mécanisme par lequel la surexpression de p110 CUX1 conduit à une réduction dans la durée de la phase G1. En utilisant la méthode de PCR quantitative, nous avons montré que la surexpression de p110 CUX1 a augmenté la transcription de gènes DDK (Cdc7 et Dbf4) à la sortie de quiescence. L'analyse par immuno-buvardagea révélé que les cellules p110 CUX1 montrent une phosphorylation élevée de pS5-MCM2 pendant la quiescence, ce qui indique une augmentation de l'activité de DDK. Cette phosphorylation élevée est associée à un chargement plus rapide de MCM2 sur la chromatine après entrée dans le cycle cellulaire et un raccourcissement de la phase G1 tel que mesuré par FACS. Dans un deuxième projet, nous avons étudié l'effet de la phosphorylation de CUX1 par le complexe cyclin D1/CDK4 sur la régulation du cycle cellulaire. Des test de liaison à l'AND ont révélé que la phosphorylation d'une protéine recombinante CUX1 (1125-1505) par cyclinD1-CDK4 inhibeé sa liaison à l'ADN tandis que la PKA l'active. À l'inverse, une autre protéine recombinante CUX1 (1125-1308), qui ne contient pas les domaines répression en C-terminaux, est activée par cyclinD1-CDK4 et inhibée par la PKA.  L'autoradiographie et l'analyse par immuno-buvardage ont révélé que cyclinD1-CDK4 phosphoryle la sérine 1216, alors que PKA phosphoryle sur les sérines 1215 et 1216. Les analyses par FACS ont montré que les cellules exprimant un mutant p110 CUX1S1215/1216A passent moins de temps en G1, deviennent progressivement plus petites et finissent par mourir par apoptose.  Ces résultats suggèrent que la phosphorylation de CUX1 par le complexe cyclinD1-CDK4 sert à contrôler la taille des cellules. Finalement, au cours de la mitose, CUX1 semble ~ 15 kDa plus grands quand on l'observe par SDS-PAGE. Nous avons vérifié si cette différence de poids moléculaire résultait de modifications post-traductionnelles telles que l'ajout d'un peptide de la famille des ubiquitines. Aucune de ces modifications n'a été identifiée, mais en utilisant la spectrométrie de masse, nous avons démontré que, durant la mitose, CUX1 est phosphorylé sur au moins douze résidus par rapport à six au cours de G2.</description><creator>Lantela, Daniel</creator><contributor>Alain Nepveu (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>CUX1 and the Cell Cycle</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z8556.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806337q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f943d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Context:  Among women with a prior caesarean section, 82.2% will have another caesarean delivery. The Society of Obstetrics and Gynaecology of Canada (SOGC) recommends that physicians offer medically eligible women with a previous caesarean section a trial of labour, to attempt a vaginal delivery. With greater inclusion of the patient in medical decision-making, it is important to understand women's part in this decision-making process. Objectives: To describe women's decision-making by looking at: 1) whether the decision was reported as primarily physician- or patient-driven 2) women's reasons for repeat caesarean section, 3) women's main information sources. Methods: For one year women booked for a repeat elective caesarean section, who were eligible for a trial of labour according to the 2005 guidelines of the SOGC, were approached with the survey in hospital post-partum, and invited to participate in the study. Chart review was used to determine eligibility, and obtain other medical characteristics. Results: Most of the women (77 %) reported being involved in the decision about their caesarean section. However, almost a quarter reported wholly physician-driven decisions (23 %). The main reasons women selected for a caesarean section related to their previous birth experience, and the physician's recommendation. Women born outside of Canada, with less education or who were allophones, were less likely to report using certain information sources, such as the Internet, and to find the information in the hospital-provided pamphlet useful. All in all, the women who received less information were more likely to report solely physician-driven decisions. Conclusion: Although patient involvement in decision-making is the norm, some decisions for caesarean section are made without the patient. Women's concerns, such as fear of a failed vaginal delivery, play an important role in this decision-making. Overall, immigrant women may understand less about their birth options than their Canadian peers. Addressing these concerns during pre-natal counselling may aid more fully informed consent, help assuage women's fears of vaginal birth and may increase the number of women attempting a trial of labour.</description><description>Contexte : Parmi les femmes ayant déjà subi une césarienne, 82 % auront un autre accouchement par césarienne. La Société d'Obstétriques et Gynécologie du Canada (SOGC) conseille aux médecins d'offrir aux femmes éligibles l'option d'essayer un accouchement vaginal. Avec l'inclusion des patients dans les décisions médicales, il est important de comprendre le rôle des femmes dans ce processus de décision. Objectif : Décrire le processus de décision en évaluant : 1) si la décision vient premièrement du médecin ou du patient, 2) les raisons données par les femmes pour le choix d'une césarienne, 3) les principales sources d'information utilisées par les femmes. Méthodes : Au cours d'une année, les femmes enregistrées pour une césarienne, et éligible pour un accouchement vaginal selon le SOGC 2005, ont été approchées à l'hôpital postpartum et invitées à participer à l'étude. Le dossier médical a été utilisé pour déterminer l'éligibilité et d'autres caractéristiques médicales. Résultats : La majorité des femmes (77%) ont participé à la décision concernant le choix d'une césarienne, mais à peu près un quart (23 %) ont rapportée que la décision a été faite entièrement par le médecin. Les femmes ont indiqué que des raisons reliées aux peurs d'un accouchement vaginal, et aux recommandations du médecin, ont supporté le choix d'une césarienne. Les femmes nées ailleurs, avec moins de scolarité, ou allophones ont moins utilisé certaines sources d'informations, telles que l'Internet, et ont trouvé l'information dans le dépliant de l'hôpital moins utile. En général, les femmes ayant reçu moins d'information ont été plus susceptibles de rapporter une décision faite seulement par leur médecin. Conclusion : Bien qu'il y ait souvent la participation de la patiente dans le processus de décision, quelques décisions concernant le choix d'une césarienne sont faites sans la patiente. La peur d'un accouchement vaginal joue un rôle important dans la décision. Dans l'ensemble, les immigrantes pourraient moins bien comprendre  leurs options d'accouchement que les femmes canadiennes. Considérer ces problèmes lors du suivi pré-natal pourrait aider au processus de consentement, soulager les peurs reliées à un accouchement vaginal, et peut-être augmenter l'acceptante d'un essai d'accouchement vaginal.</description><creator>Handley-Derry, Frances</creator><contributor>Balbina Russillo (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Jean Lois Haggerty (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health Sciences - Obstetrics and Gynecology</subject><title>Repeat elective caesarean: decision-making for women with a previous caesarean section</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82kb687.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f943d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t549n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chronic low back pain (LBP) affects over 10% of Canadians and seriously decreases quality of life. The aging intervertebral disc (IVD) is prone to degeneration, frequently contributing to low back pain. Physical activity influences IVD physiology, and animal studies show that cyclic loading increases proteoglycan synthesis in the disc, suggesting a role for running exercise in disc repair. Our laboratory has validated a rodent model of LBP, the aging SPARC-null mouse, which displays axial and radiating pain that parallels LBP in humans and is pharmacologically reversible. We therefore aimed to demonstrate that habitual running exercise will delay disc degeneration and decrease pain behavior in the aging SPARC-null mouse. After two months with free access to running wheels, SPARC-null mice show significantly reduced cold sensitivity in the hindpaw compared to baseline (p&lt;.05) and control group  (p&lt;.05), indicating reduced radiating LBP. Axial LBP was unaffected, suggesting the effect was specific to radiating pain. In older animals, cold sensitivity was significantly reduced compared to control group after four months (p&lt;.05), suggesting exercise is still beneficial in animals with more advanced disc degeneration. If running wheels are withdrawn from the home cage, SPARC-null mice continue to show reduced cold sensitivity for two months (p&lt;.01). Only after three months without wheel access do they return to baseline behaviour. X-ray analysis showed that both young and older SPARC-null animals display significant improvement in lumbar disc height after habitual exercise (p&lt;.01). However, exercise had no effect on the severity of disc degeneration in SPARC-null mice by histological analysis using the FAST staining method. Immunohistochemical staining of sensory nerve fibers in the IVD revealed that running exercise reduces the number and total length of CGRP-positive nerve fibers in the outer IVD in older SPARC-null mice (p&lt;.05). The number of CGRP-positive nerve fibers in the outer IVD correlated both with disc height and with cold hypersensitivity in the hindpaw in SPARC-null mice, suggesting that IVD nerve ingrowth may mediate the relationship between disc degeneration and radiating low back pain behaviour in mice. Overall, we see that voluntary running exercise specifically reduces radiating LBP and improves disc height, but does not improve axial LBP or histological signs of disc degeneration. Running exercise may reduce IVD sensory nerve ingrowth, which could help explain the relationship between disc health and low back pain behaviour. Improving our understanding of this relationship will hopefully lead to improved therapies and preventions for the LBP patient.</description><description>La douleur chronique du bas du dos (lombalgie) affecte plus de 10% des Canadiens et diminue gravement la qualité de vie. Le disque intervertébral (DIV) peut dégénérer avec l'âge, ce qui peut contribuer à la lombalgie. L'activité physique peut influencer la physiologie du DIV, et des études chez l'animal montrent que le chargement cyclique augmente la synthèse des protéoglycans dans le disque, ce qui suggère un rôle pour l'exercice dans la réparation du DIV. Notre laboratoire a validé un modèle expérimental de la lombalgie, la souris SPARC-nulle âgée, qui démontre de la douleur axiale et sciatique qui ressemble la lombalgie chez l'humain et est pharmacologiquement réversible. Nous avons donc cherché à démontrer que l'exercice habituel de la course retardera la dégénérescence du DIV et diminuera le comportement indiquant la lombalgie chez la souris SPARC-nulle âgée. Après deux mois en accès libre à des roues tournantes dans leurs cages domestiques, les souris SPARC-nulles montrent une réduction de leur hypersensibilité au froid sur la patte arrière par rapport à leur seuil de départ (p &lt;.05) et au groupe de contrôle sans roues tournantes (p &lt;.05), indiquant une réduction de douleur sciatique. La douleur axiale n'a pas été affectée, ce qui suggère que l'effet était spécifique à la douleur sciatique. Chez les animaux âgés, la sensibilité au froid a été réduite par rapport au groupe de contrôle après quatre mois (p &lt;.05). Si les roues sont retirées des cages, les souris SPARC-nulles continuent à montrer une sensibilité au froid réduite pendant deux mois (p &lt;.01). C'est seulement après trois mois sans accès aux roues qu'ils reviennent au comportement de base. L'analyse radiographique a montré que les souris SPARC-nulles (jeunes et vieux) avec des roues tournantes démontrent une amélioration significative de la hauteur discale lombaire (p &lt;.01). Toutefois, l'exercice n'a eu aucun effet sur la gravité de la dégénérescence discale par l'analyse histologique. La détection immunohistochimique des fibres nerveuses sensorielles dans le DIV a montré que l'exercice habituel réduit le nombre et la longueur totale des fibres nerveuses marquées au CGRP dans le DIV chez les souris SPARC-nulles âgés (p &lt;.05). Le nombre de nerfs dans la DIV corrèle avec la hauteur du disque et aussi avec l'hypersensibilité au froid dans la patte arrière chez la souris SPARC-nulle, ce qui suggère que la croissance des nerfs dans la DIV peut influer la relation entre la dégénérescence discale et la lombalgie chez la souris. En conclusion, nous voyons que l'exercice de course volontaire améliore la douleur sciatique et la hauteur de la DIV, mais n'améliore pas la douleur axiale ou les signes histologiques de dégénérescence de la DIV. L'exercice de course volontaire réduit possiblement la croissance des nerfs dans le DIV, ce qui pourrait aider à expliquer la relation entre la santé du disque et le comportement douloureux chez la souris. Une meilleure compréhension de cette relation devrait mener à l'amélioration des traitements et de la prévention pour le patient lombalgique.</description><creator>Danco, Alexander</creator><contributor>Laura Stone (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Beneficial effects of running exercise on intervertebral disc degeneration and low back pain in mice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731737c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t549n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3n2042495</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'initialisation de la vapeur d'eau et de la température est, depuis longtemps, un sujet de préoccupation pour les prévisions météorologiques à la méso-échelle, où de petites erreurs dans ces champs produisent souvent des erreurs significatives dans le modèle concernant la caractérisation des processus à la méso-échelle, telles que l'initiation de la convection. Afin de répondre à cette question, un radiomètre micro-ondes à « méso-échelle » a été conçu et construit à l'Université McGill dans le but exclusif de fournir avec précision, ou au moins de contraindre, les champs de vapeur d'eau en trois dimensions. Une évaluation de la capacité d'un radiomètre micro-ondes pour recouvrer la vapeur d'eau et température sur un vaste domaine (250x250x10km) en deux et trois dimensions est présentée. Le contenu de l'information d'un radiomètre micro-ondes à balayage en élévation et en azimut est évalué dans un cadre de régression statistique. Il est démontré qu'un balayage radiomètre micro-ondes est, en effet, capable de fournir jusqu'à 3.9 contraintes sur la vapeur d'eau à proximité de l'instrument diminuant à environ 0.5 contraint à des distances de ~150km , tandis que les informations de température est en grande partie limitée à entre 1.2 et 0.3 contraintes dans les régions plus proche que 50 km. La quantité d'information inhérente au système est également évaluée; on y constate que, dans le but de contraindre la vapeur d'eau avec un précision de 0.5g/kg pour une section 2D à travers l'atmosphère, nous avons besoin de 63.2 contraintes indépendantes en juillet et seulement 3.2 en janvier, distribuées principalement entre 500 et 4000m d'altitude.Basé sur ces résultats, nous proposons d'éventuelles modifications du système radiomètre pour faciliter sa capacité à fournir des informations précises sur la vapeur d'eau à des résolutions méso-échelle dans un domaine tridimensionnel.</description><description>The initialization of water vapour and temperature fields has long been a concern in mesoscale weather forecasting, where small errors in these fields often produce significant errors in the model characterization of mesoscale processes, such as convective initiation. In order to address this issue, a scanning "Mesoscale" Microwave Radiometer has been designed and built at McGill University with the exclusive goal of accurately providing, or at least constraining, three dimensional water vapour fields. An assessment of a scanning microwave radiometer's capability for retrieving water vapour and temperature fields over large (250x250x10km) two- and three-dimensional domains is presented. The information content of an elevation and azimuthal scanning microwave radiometer is assessed using a statistical regression framework. It is shown that a scanning microwave radiometer is, indeed, capable of providing up to 3.9 constraints on water vapour near the instrument decreasing to roughly 0.5 constrains at distances of ~150km, while temperature information is largely restricted to between 1.2 and 0.3 constraints in regions within 50km.  The amount of information inherent in the system is also assessed, where it is found that, in order to constrain water vapour to 0.5g/kg throughout a 2D cross-section through the atmosphere, we require 63.2 independent constraints during July and only 3.2 in January, largely distributed between 500 and 4000m altitude.  Based on these results, we propose possible modifications to the radiometer system to further facilitate its ability to provide accurate water vapour information at mesoscale resolutions within a three dimensional domain.</description><creator>Themens, David</creator><contributor>Frederic Fabry (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Atmospheric Sciences</subject><title>The quest for accurate three-dimensional water vapour and temperature fields: a theoretical examination of the capabilities of a mesoscale microwave radiometer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935624d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n2042495</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q761k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Accelerated eutrophication of freshwater ecosystems led by agricultural activities has raised concerns in Southern Quebec and other industrialized locales. Phosphorus being the main culprit, effort has been made to rationalize application and curtail exports of this nutrient with agricultural best management practices. Still, concentrations of phosphorus and nitrogen in typical tile drainage return flow wastewater exceeds the eutrophication-prevention criterion set by the Quebec Ministry of Environment (0.030 mg TP ∙L-1) and the ecosystem safeguard criterion suggested in the literature (1.10 mg TN ∙L-1), with cumulative loads becoming a major contributor to the poor quality of downstream aquatic ecosystems, especially when poorly diluted, as is the case with heavily drained agriculture-dominated watersheds.As a third line of defense in a best management practices package, constructed wetlands (CWs) for the interception of phosphorus are proposed. These wetlands can also mitigate nitrogen and contribute other ancillary benefits. They can be implemented at the mouth of tile drainage or at the confluence of a few outlets, i.e. drainage ditches or first order streams.The main phosphorus removal mechanisms in a CW are adsorption and precipitation with positively charged ions contained in the substrate (e.g., Ca2+, Fe3+, Al3+). Physico-chemical conditions prevailing in the system – especially redox potential – are major factors influencing these reactions. A sub-surface vertical up-flow system seems most appropriate, as it maximizes potential interaction of pollutant-charged water with the substrate constituents, allowing full radial contact and deterring preferential flow. These wetlands also are efficient longer into the cold season, given the underground nature of the flow. An experiment was conducted on McGill's CW research site, situated in Ste-Anne-de-Bellevue, Québec, so as to ascertain the efficiency of a vertical up-flow constructed wetland in treating tile drainage return flow wastewater. During 14 weeks, the capacity to remove the different forms of phosphorus was evaluated, as was the removal of nitrogen compounds. The effluent quality was also compared to the criteria. The wetland had a dimension of 9.15 m2 and the target flow rate was 1 L∙min-1, which is representative of a drainage system serving a 3 ha field in typical Southern Quebec conditions (wetland:watershed ratio: 0.03%; hydraulic loading rate: 0.16 m∙d-1; hydraulic retention time: 2.99 days). The target influent concentrations were 0.300 mg TP ∙L-1, and 10.00 mg TN ∙L-1, which – again – is typical of Southern Quebec tile drainage return flow. The wetland was efficient at removing 84% TP and 86% TN, but the treated wastewater was still above the criteria in 76% and 69% of the cases for TP and TN, respectively.Recommendation is made to supplement the wetland with a dedicated phosphorus-removal substrate so as to further enhance its performance, and to increase the wetland:watershed surface ratio to abate more nitrogen compounds. Community support is key to the implementation of agricultural best management practices. Hence, suggestion is made to include constructed wetlands in the set of initiatives that are financially aided through governmental programs, such as Prime-Vert of Québec.</description><description>L'eutrophisation accélérée des écosystèmes aquatiques dû aux activités agricoles donne lieu à des inquiétudes tant dans le Québec méridional que dans d'autres pays industrialisés. Le phosphore étant le principal coupable, des efforts importants ont été consentis à la réduction des exportations de ce nutriment, avec l'instauration de pratiques de gestion agricole optimales. Néanmoins, les concentrations de phosphore et d'azote dans les eaux usées de retour de drainage agricole typiques sont encore au-dessus des critères pour la prévention de l'eutrophisation (0.030 mg TP ∙L-1) et de maintien de la santé des écosystèmes aquatiques (1.10 mg TN ∙L-1), la charge cumulative étant un contributeur majeur à la piètre qualité des écosystèmes aquatiques situés en aval, en particulier lorsque peu diluée, comme c'est le cas par exemple dans les bassins versants à dominante agricole où le drainage est fortement présent. À titre de troisième ligne de défense dans la série de pratiques de gestion agricole optimales, les marais filtrants ciblant l'interception du phosphore sont proposés. Ces marais peuvent également atténuer l'azote et apporter des bénéfices collatéraux. Ils peuvent être installés à l'embouchure de drains agricoles, ou bien à la confluence de plusieurs sorties, comme par exemple dans un fossé agricole ou un cours d'eau d'ordre un. Les deux principaux mécanismes d'enlèvement du phosphore sont l'adsorption et la précipitation avec des ions à charge positive qui sont contenus dans le substrat (e.g., Ca2+, Fe3+, Al3+). Les conditions physico-chimiques qui règnent dans le système – en particulier le potentiel d'oxydo-réduction – sont des facteurs importants pouvant influencer ces réactions. Le système à flux vertical ascendant sous-surfacique est celui qui semble le plus approprié, puisqu'il maximise les interactions entre l'eau chargée de polluants avec les constituants du substrat, permettant un plein contact radial et prévenant les flux préférentiels. Ce type de marais est aussi efficace plus longtemps pendant la saison froide, étant donné la nature sous-surfacique du flux. Une expérience a été menée au site de recherche de l'Université McGill, situé à Sainte-Anne-de-Bellevue, au Québec, afin de vérifier l'efficacité d'un marais à flux vertical ascendant pour traiter les eaux usées de retour de drainage agricole. Pendant quatorze semaines, la capacité d'enlèvement du phosphore sous ses différentes formes a été évaluée, de même que l'enlèvement des composés azotés. La qualité de l'effluent traité a aussi été comparée aux critères de qualité. Le marais avait une surface de 9.15 m2 et le débit cible était de 1 L ∙min-1, ce qui est représentatif d'un système de drainage desservant un champ de 3 ha dans les conditions typiques du Québec méridional (ratio bassin versant:marais filtrant : 0.03%; charge hydraulique : 0.16 m∙d-1; temps de rétention hydraulique : 2.99 jours). Les concentrations cibles dans l'affluent étaient de 0.300 mg TP ∙L-1 et 10.00 mg TN ∙L-1, ce qui – encore là – correspond à un retour de drainage agricole dans les conditions du Québec méridional. L'efficacité du marais est telle qu'un enlèvement de 84% du phosphore total et 86% de l'azote total a été observé, mais l'effluent traité outrepassait encore les critères dans 76% et 69% des cas pour ce qui est du phosphore total et de l'azote total, respectivement. Il est recommandé d'ajouter au marais un substrat dédié à l'enlèvement du phosphore, afin de renforcer la performance, ainsi que d'augmenter le ratio surfacique marais filtrant:bassin versant, afin de diminuer davantage les composés azotés. Le support par la communauté est un élément clé dans l'instauration de pratiques de gestion agricole optimales. Ainsi donc, il est suggéré d'inclure les marais filtrants dans l'ensemble d'initiatives qui sont financièrement appuyées par les programmes gouvernementaux, tels le programme Prime-Vert au Québec.</description><creator>Duteau, Michel</creator><contributor>Shiv Prasher (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Grant Clark (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</subject><title>Phosphorus removal in a vertical up-flow constructed wetland</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752m26b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q761k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cx56t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Hypothalamic-Pituitary-Somatic (HPS) axis is the endogenous system through which our body secretes Growth Hormone (GH) in a regulated manner. The HPS axis has many levels of feedback; GH -Releasing Hormone (GHRH) and Somatostatin (SOM) not only regulate GH secretion, but also modulate each other. For example, GHRH neurons in the arcuate nucleus (ARC) display high expression of SOM receptor subtype 1 (sst1). Radio-labeled SOM has been shown to bind to the ARC in a rhythmic manner as well. Furthermore, we have previously shown that sst1 alters its association with post-synapses on neurons of the ARC in a rhythmic manner depending on the endogenous GH cycle. After a GH trough, characterized by low SOM concentration in the blood, there is an increased association of sst1 receptors with post-synaptic specializations, and after a GH peak, characterized by higher SOM concentrations in the blood, there is a decrease in sst1 association with synapses. Hence, we hypothesize that intracerebroventricular injection of SOM receptor agonists should also lead to a redistribution of sst1 receptor association with post-synaptic densities. To test our hypothesis, we injected 0.5 pmol of CH-275 (n=3), an sst1-seletive agonist, [D-Trp8]-somatostatin-14 (n=3), a non-selective SOM receptor agonist, and artificial cerebrospinal fluid (ACSF) (n=4), as a negative control, into the lateral ventricles of adult male Sprague Dawley rats. This procedure was followed by pre-embedding silver-enhanced immunogold electron microscopy to determine sst1 localization within the arcuate nucleus of agonist injected rats. Quantitative analysis revealed that only 20% of sst1 receptors are located at the plasma membrane and 80% intracellularly. SOM agonist injections did not have any significant effect on sst1 plasma membrane association. Overall, sst1 maintained constant cell surface receptor levels while the majority of sst1 immunoreactivity was found intracellularly. Upon SOM agonist injection, sst1 decreased its association with post-synaptic densities, when compared with vehicle injected rats. Furthermore, in the neuropil region of the ARC, over 40% of sst1 receptors were found within axonal terminals. This percentage did not change between vehicle-injected and agonist-injected rats. The sizeable portion of sst1 receptors found within terminals posits the claim that sst1, in addition to mediating postsynaptic SOM effects, may be acting as an auto-receptor in SOM-containing terminals within the ARC.</description><description>L'axe hypothalamo-hypophyso-surrénalien (HHS) est un système endogène par lequel notre organisme sécrète l'hormone de croissance (GH) de manière régulée. L'axe HHS possède plusieurs niveaux de régulation; l'hormone de libération de la GH (GHRH) et la Somatostatine (SOM), non seulement régulent la sécrétion de GH mais se modulent mutuellement. Par exemple, les neurones GHRH du noyau arqué (ARC) expriment fortement des récepteurs de sous-type SOM1 (sst1). Il a été également démontré que la SOM marquée-radioactive se lie au noyau arqué de façon rythmique. Par ailleurs, nous avons déjà montré que sst1 modifie son association avec les post-synapses des neurones du noyau arqué de façon rythmique selon le cycle endogène de GH. Après une diminution de l'hormone GH, caractérisée par une faible concentration de SOM dans le sang, il se produit une association accrue des récepteurs sst1 avec des spécialisations post-synaptiques, et après un pic de GH, caractérisé par des concentrations élevées de SOM dans le sang, il y a une diminution de la liaison sst1 avec des synapses. Par conséquent, nous émettons l'hypothèse que l'injection intracérébrale d'agonistes des récepteurs SOM devrait également conduire à une redistribution de l'association du récepteur sst1 avec des densités post-synaptiques. Pour vérifier notre hypothèse, nous avons injecté 0.5 pmole de CH-275 (n=3), un agoniste sélectif de sst1, [D-Trp8] somatostatine-14 (n=3), un agoniste non sélectif des récepteurs SOM, et du liquide céphalo-rachidien artificiel (LCR) (n=4), un contrôle négatif, dans les ventricules latéraux de rats Sprague Dawley adultes. Cette procédure a été suivie par un pré-enrobage pour déterminer la localisation de sst1 dans le noyau arqué des rats injectés avec l'agoniste. L'analyse quantitative a révélé que 20% seulement des récepteurs sst1 sont situés à la membrane plasmique et que 80% sont intracellulaires. Les injections d'agonistes SOM n'ont pas eu d'effet significatif sur l'association sst1 à la membrane plasmique. Dans l'ensemble, sst1 a maintenu des niveaux constants de récepteurs de surface cellulaire alors que la majorité des sst1 immunoréactifs est intracellulaire. Lors de l'injection de l'agoniste SOM, l'association de sst1 avec des densités post-synaptiques a diminué en comparaison avec les rats contrôles injectés avec le LCR. En outre, dans la région neuropile du noyau arqué, plus de 40% des récepteurs sst1 ont été trouvés dans les terminaisons axonales. Ce pourcentage n'a pas changé entre les rats injectés avec le LCR et ceux injectés avec les deux agonistes. La quantité importante de récepteurs sst1 trouvés dans les terminaisons axonales indique que sst1, en plus de produire des effets post-synaptiques SOM, peut agir comme auto-récepteur dans les terminaison SOM du noyau arqué.</description><creator>Umar, Rehan</creator><contributor>Thomas Stroh (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Subcellular distribution of somatostatin receptor subtype 1 in the arcuate nucleus of agonist injected rats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rh73j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cx56t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zc77st36q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction: Dans les années 1994 à 1997, le Centre Hospitalier de Kateri Memorial en collaboration avec le Centre de l'Education de Kahnawake ont développé un cursus de la prévention de diabète pour les écoles élémentaire. L'intervention vise à augmenter les connaissances et changer l'environnement physique et les normes sociales des écoles et de la communauté par la promotion de l'alimentation de bonne santé et la mode actif de vie avec l'objectif de longue durée de prévenir l'obésité et le diabète chez la population de Kanien'kehá:ka. Le programme consiste de trois unités: la nutrition, le fitness et les modes de vie, et le diabète, divisé de cours en 10 et 45 minutes pour chaque classe de 1 à 6. Le projet de prévention du diabète de Kahnawake a été impliqué dans un des plus anciens programmes de prévention du diabète en milieu scolaire; il a été mis en œuvre dans les écoles élémentaire de Kahnawake pour 15 ans. Objectifs: D'évaluer la mise en œuvre du programme d'éducation à la santé de l'hôpital de Kateri Memorial dans les années 2010/2011 et 2011/2012, et d'explorer les obstacles et les facilitateurs de la programme du point de vue des enseignants, des parents, des auteurs du programme et les administrateurs scolaires. Objets et méthodes: Cette étude adopte une approche communautaire participative. La population cible de cette étude est sélectionné parmi les trois sous-groupes de personnes dont les enseignants, les parents, les auteurs du programme et les administrateurs scolaires. Le design de cette étude était descriptive qualitative combinée avec une enquête transversale. Les questionnaires ont été distribués aux enseignants d'écoles élémentaires à Kahnawake. La partie qualitative a été menée à l'aide des cercles de discussion avec les parents, les auteurs et les enseignants. Les entrevues semi-structurées ont été réalisées avec les administrateurs des écoles pour mieux comprendre les enjeux actuels avec le programme d'études et d'élaborer des recommandations pour des futurs changements. Les statistiques descriptives ont été appliquées pour analyser les résultats du questionnaire, comme le nombre de leçons du programme enseigné, le nombre d'enseignants qui a implémenté le programme et le nombre d'étudiants qui ont reçu le curriculum. Les cercles de discussion et les entrevues semi-structurées ont été audio-enregistrées et transcrites textuellement. L'analyse textuelle thématique a été réalisée afin d'identifier les thèmes émergents. Résultats: Les résultats ont démontré que les participants perçoivent le programme d'éducation à la santé important pour les enfants à accroître les connaissances sur les comportements de santé pour prévenir le diabète de type 2. Les points forts du programme comprenaient des facteurs impliquant un environnement scolaire positif et certains aspects de la prestation et le contenu du programme. Faiblesses comprenaient le manque de soutien administratif, le temps d'enseignement et les problèmes de gestion du temps, un manque de représentation culturelle Mohawk, et des ressources obsolètes ou manquantes. Recommandations adressées contenu du programme l'intégration culturelle, le développement de la méthodologie et de soutien administratif afin de revitaliser le programme et sa livraison.Conclusion: À notre connaissance, ce projet a été la première étude à explorer les obstacles et les facilitateurs de ce programme de 15 ans de prévention du diabète. Les résultats obtenus à partir de ce projet apportent des connaissances sur les défis et les atouts face à un programme d'éducation sanitaire à partir de perspectives différentes. Les résultats serviront à formuler des recommandations pour la révision ou l'élaboration d'un nouveau programme d'éducation sanitaire.</description><description>Introduction: In years 1994 to 1997, the Kateri Memorial Hospital Center in conjunction with the Kahnawake Education Center, and the Kahnawake Schools Diabetes Prevention Project developed an elementary school diabetes prevention curriculum. The curriculum aimed to increase knowledge of type 2 diabetes, healthy eating and active lifestyles of the children with the long term goal of preventing obesity and diabetes among the Kanien'kehá:ka (Mohawk) population of Kahnawake, Quebec. The curriculum consisted of three units: nutrition, fitness, and lifestyles and diabetes, divided into 10, 45-minute lessons for grades 1 through 6. The Kahnawake Diabetes Prevention Project has been involved with one of the longest diabetes prevention school based curricula; it has been implemented in Kahnawake elementary schools for 15 years. Objectives: To evaluate the implementation of the Kateri Memorial Hospital Center health education curriculum in the years 2010/2011 and 2011/2012, and to further explore the barriers and the facilitators of the health education curriculum from the perspectives of teachers, parents, curriculum authors and school administrators. Subjects and Methods: This study adopted a community-based participatory approach. The participants of this study were selected from four groups of people including teachers, parents, curriculum authors and school administrators. The design of this study was qualitative descriptive combined with a cross-sectional survey. Questionnaires were distributed to classroom teachers in the Kahnawake elementary schools. The qualitative portion was undertaken using talking circles with parents, curriculum authors and teachers. Semi-structured interviews were conducted with school principals to understand current issues with the curriculum and to develop recommendations for future changes and implementation. Descriptive statistics were applied to analyze the questionnaire results such as the number of curriculum lessons taught, the number of teachers who implemented the curriculum and the number of students who received the curriculum. The talking circles and the semi-structured interviews were audio-recorded, and transcribed verbatim. Thematic textual analysis was performed to identify emerging themes. Results: The findings showed that participants perceived the health education curriculum as important to the children to increase knowledge regarding health behaviours to prevent Type 2 diabetes. The strengths of the curriculum included factors involving a positive school environment and certain aspects of delivery and curriculum content. Weaknesses included lack of administrative support, instructional time and time management issues, a lack of Mohawk cultural representation, and outdated or missing resource materials. Recommendations addressed curriculum content, cultural integration, methodology development and administrative support to revitalize the curriculum and its delivery. Conclusion: To our knowledge, this project was the first study exploring the barriers and facilitators of this 15-year-old diabetes prevention curriculum. The results obtained from this project provide knowledge on the challenges and the strengths faced with a health education curriculum from different perspectives. The findings will be used to make recommendations for revision, development and implementation of a new health education curriculum. </description><creator>Khayyat Kholghi, Maedeh</creator><contributor>Ann Macaulay (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Gillian Bartlett-Esquilant (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health Sciences - Education</subject><title>The barriers and facilitators of the Kateri Memorial Hospital Center health education curriculum: Kahnawake Schools Diabetes Prevention Project</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qn17v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77st36q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qb98mj812</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La vitamine D est un modulateur clé de l'homéostasie des minéraux. La forme active de la vitamine D est la 1,25-(OH)2D synthétisée au niveau du rein par l'action de l'enzyme CYP27B1 sur le précurseur 25-(OH)D. L'enzyme CYP24A1 initie la voie d'oxydation C24 qui conduit à la dégradation de la forme hormonale de la vitamine D, mais est également responsable de la synthèse de 24,25-(OH)2D. L'activité biologique de la 24,25-(OH)2D demeure controversée, mais il a été constaté qu'à la suite de fractures du tibia chez les poussins, les niveaux d'activité  de la CYP24A1 et les niveaux sériques de 24,25-(OH)2D sont stimulés. Notre laboratoire a mis au point une lignée de souris déficientes pour le gène Cyp24a1 afin d'étudier le rôle de la 24,25-(OH)2D, et a identifié une molécule qui pourrait agir comme récepteur membranaire pour la 24,25-(OH)2D (FAM57B2). Dans cette étude, nous avons évalué les propriétés biomécaniques (rigidité et la force maximale pour rompre) des os réparés chez des souris mutantes et de type sauvage, suite à un traitement en présence ou absence de 24,25-(OH)2D exogène. Nous avons également évalué l'expression de l'ARNm et de la protéine du récepteur putatif dans différents organes chez les souris sauvage. Méthodes: les souris de type sauvage ou déficiente pour le gène Cyp24a1 ont été soumise à une ostéotomie ouverte modifiée du tibia avec insertion d'un clou médullaire, suivie d'un traitement sous-cutané avec le véhicule (propylène glycol) ou avec 6,7 g/kg de 24,25-(OH)2D. Les tibias ont été prélevés aux jours 18 et 28 suivant la chirurgie, et les propriétés biomécaniques ont été testées en utilisant un test de flexion à trois points. Pour évaluer l'ARNm et l'expression de la protéine de Fam57bv2 dans différents tissus, une amplification par PCR quantitative, l'immunobuvardage et l'immunohistofluorescence ont été utilisés. Résultats: au jour 18, nous avons observé que les paramètres biomécaniques sont nettement inférieurs chez les souris mutantes mâles et femelles injectées avec le véhicule par rapport aux animaux de type sauvage. Ces différences disparaissent suite à l'administration de 24,25-(OH)2D exogène. Aucune différence statistiquement significative n'a été mesurée au jour 28. L'analyse qRT-PCR a montré une expression elevée de l'ARNm de Fam57bv2 dans la peau et le cartilage, tandis que l'analyse par immunobuvardage a montré que FAM57B (toutes les isoformes) est exprimée dans tous les tissus étudiés. L'immunohistofluorescence a permis de détecter FAM57B dans des coupes en paraffine de cerveau et dans des cryosections de rein et de tibia. Conclusion: Les résultats de cette étude confirment le retard de la guérison des fractures chez les souris déficientes en Cyp24a1 et soutiennent un rôle de la 24,25-(OH)2D à optimiser la guérison des fractures. Nos résultats concernant l'expression de FAM57B montrent que le récepteur potentiel de la 24,25-(OH)2D, FAM57Bv2, est exprimé à des niveaux élevés dans les chondrocytes, ce qui appuie une contribution mécanistique au cours de la guérison des fractures.</description><description>Vitamin D is a key modulator and regulator of mineral and bone homeostasis. The main active form of vitamin D in the body is the 1,25-(OH)2D metabolite that is formed in the kidney from 25-(OH)D by the enzyme CYP27B1. The enzyme CYP24A1 initiates the C24-oxidation pathway that leads to degradation of the hormonal form of vitamin D, but is also responsible for the synthesis of 24,25-(OH)2D. The putative biological activity of 24,25-(OH)2D remains unclear, but it has been found that following tibial fractures in chicks, the levels of CYP24A1 activity and serum 24,25-(OH)2D are both elevated. Our laboratory has engineered a mouse deficient for the Cyp24a1 gene to study the role of 24,25-(OH)2D, and has identified a putative membrane receptor (FAM57Bv2) to 24,25-(OH)2D. In this study we assessed the biomechanical properties (stiffness and force needed to break) of the repaired bones of mutant and wild-type mice at different intervals in the presence or absence of treatment with exogenous 24,25-(OH)2D. We also assessed the mRNA and protein expression of the putative receptor in different organ tissues of wild-type mice. Methods: wild-type and Cyp24a1-deficient mice were subjected to a modified open osteotomy with subsequent intramedullary nailing of the tibia, followed by subcutaneous treatment with vehicle (propylene glycol) or 6.7 µg/kg of 24,25-(OH)2D. Tibiae were collected on days 18 and 28 post operatively, and the biomechanical properties were tested using a three point bending testing machine. To assess the mRNA and protein expression of Fam5bv2 in different tissues, qRT-PCR, western blot analysis and immunohistofluorescence were performed. Results: at day 18, we observed significantly inferior biomechanical parameters in the male and female mutant mice injected with vehicle compared to their wild-type littermates. These differences were rescued by exogenous administration of 24,25-(OH)2D. No statistically significant differences were measured at day 28. qRT-PCR analysis showed high mRNA expression of Fam57bv2 in skin and cartilage, while western blot analysis showed FAM57B (all isoforms) to be expressed in all tissues studied. Immunohistofluorescence studies showed detection of FAM57B in brain paraffin sections, and kidney and tibial cryosections. Conclusion: The results of this study confirm the delay of fracture healing in Cyp24a1-deficient mice and support a role for 24,25-(OH)2D in optimizing fracture healing. Our expression monitoring results show that the putative receptor for 24,25-(OH)2D, FAM57Bv2, is broadly expressed with enrichment in chondrocytes, which may contribute to improved fracture healing.</description><creator>Hamade, Bachar</creator><contributor>Rene St-Arnaud (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Physiology</subject><title>Fracture repair in Cyp24a1 deficient mice: biomechanical properties of repaired bones and contribution to mechanisms involved</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698c046.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mj812</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rx92j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Optical transmission measurements were made through samples of CuInSe2 at room temperature, in the wavelength range 1300 to 1600 nm, beyond the energy gap absorption edge. The samples used were polished wafers about 1 mm thick, obtained from Bridgman ingots of monocrystals of the compound,  grown from melts containing from 0 to 11 atomic % of elemental sodium (Na), plus excess over stoichiometry, x of selenium, corresponding to the formula CuInSe_(2+x), where x varied from 0 to 0.4. From the measured transmission, thickness and an assumed reflectivity value, absorption coefficient values (α) were obtained, which were found to decrease to low values with increasing wavelength. However, the most noteworthy feature was a strong increase of α with Na content in the melt, at a fixed wavelength. Thus, for a sample with 11 atomic % Na in the melt, α at 1600 nm was two orders of magnitude greater than its value for a sample without any added Na. The increased absorption is attributed to increased optical scattering by Se vacancies, created by the added Na. A large increase of α was also found in a sample from an ingot having a Se deficiency, with a melt composition CuInSe_1.8. In the case of samples with no added Na but excess Se, α was also found to increase with x, although it was less pronounced. While previously published research has indicated sensitivity of α in CuInSe_2 samples, prepared in different ways, to annealing, the present samples, from ingots Bridgman-grown in this laboratory, have only exhibited a relatively small change with heat treatment in argon at 500 °C.</description><description>Mesures de transmission optique ont été réalisés pour des échantillons de CuInSe_2, à température ambiante, dans une longueur d'onde entre 1300 à 1600 nm, au-delà de la limite d'absorption d'énergie écart. Les échantillons utilisés sont des tranches polies d'environ 1 mm d'épaisseur, obtenues à partir de lingots monocristaux du composé fait part le procédé Bridgman, issues d'une masse fondue contenant de 0 à 11% en atomes de sodium élémentaire (Na), ainsi que de l'excès du sélénium x, correspondant à la formule CuInSe_(2 + x), où x varie de 0 à 0,4. À partir des mesures de transmission, l'épaisseur des tranches, la valeur de réflectivité et les valeurs de coefficient d'absorption (α) ont été obtenus, qui ont été trouvées à diminuer avec l'augmentation de longueur d'onde. Cependant, la caractéristique la plus remarquable a été une forte augmentation de α avec l'ajout de Na à la masse fondu, à une longueur d'onde fixe. Ainsi, pour un échantillon de 11% atomique de Na dans la masse fondue, α à 1600 nm est de deux ordres de grandeur supérieure à sa valeur d'un échantillon sans Na ajouté. L'augmentation de l'absorption est attribuée à l'augmentation de dispersion optique due à des lacunes de Se, créés par l'ajout de Na. Une forte augmentation de α a également été trouvé dans un échantillon provenant d'un lingot ayant une déficience Se avec une composition CuInSe_1.8. Dans le cas des échantillons sans Na mais avec excès de Se, α a également été trouvé à augmenter avec x, même si elle a été moins prononcée. Alors que les recherches précédemment publiées indiquent une sensibilité de α dans les échantillons CuInSe_2 à un recuit, les échantillons présents, à partir de lingots de Bridgman-développé dans ce laboratoire, ont seulement montré une variation relativement faible avec un traitement thermique sous argon à 500 °C.</description><creator>Jin, An Qi</creator><contributor>Ishiang Shih (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Absorption coefficient measurements in the wavelength range 1.3 to 1.6 microns in Bridgman-grown copper indium diselenide with added sodium</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zr82b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rx92j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j440j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Candidate materials for low-loss optical waveguides based on poly(glycidyl methacrylate-ran-pentafluostyrene) (P(GMA-ran-PFS)) copolymers were synthesized by nitroxide mediated polymerization (NMP) initiated with BlocBuilder® (N-(2-methylpropyl)-N-(1-diethlphosphono-2,2-dimethylpropyl)-O-(2-carboxylprop-2-yl) hydroxylamine) bearing a succinimidyl ester group (NHS-BlocBuilder) at 90 oC in 1,4 dioxane. The copolymerizations yielded copolymers with low dispersity  between 1.2-1.4. The core structure of single-mode channel waveguides was fabricated by direct UV lithographic patterning.  The copolymers with low resulted in line width roughness (LWR) of about 0.16 μm, whereas LWR of copolymers with  ~ 3.5 but similar compositions was about 0.5 μm. The improvement in microstructural control allotted by NMP permitted finer pattern replication for copolymers desired for optical waveguides, as suggested for photoresist polymers.</description><description>Les matériaux candidats pour des guides d'ondes optiques à faible perte à base de copolymères poly(méthacrylate de glycidyle-ran-pentafluostyrene) (poly(GMA-ran-SSP)) ont été synthétisés par la polymérisation médiée par nitroxyde (NMP) initiée avec BlocBuilder® (N-(2-méthylpropyl)-N-(1-diethlphosphono-2,2-diméthylpropyl)-O-(2-carboxylprop-2-yl) hydroxylamine) portant un groupe d'ester de succinimidyle (NHS-BlocBuilder) à 90 ° C dans du 1,4-dioxane. Les copolymérisations ont donné des copolymères à faible dispersité ( ) entre 1,2-1,4. La structure de base des guides d'ondes canaux monomodes a été fabriqué à l'aide de motifs lithographique par UV directe. Les copolymères de faible ont donné une rugosité à la largeur de ligne (LWR) d'environ 0,16 μm tandis que la LWR des copolymères avec  ~3.5 mais de compositions similaires était d'environ 0,5 μm. L'amélioration du contrôle de microstructure attribué par NMP a permis la réplication des motifs plus fins pour les copolymères dont l'utilisation est souhaitée dans les guides d'ondes optiques, tel que suggéré pour les polymères photosensibles.</description><creator>Wang, Zi Jun</creator><contributor>Milan Maric (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Chemistry - Polymer</subject><title>Nitroxide mediated synthesis of well defined random copolymers for low loss optical waveguides</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cv03m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j440j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xd07gx06c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Neuronal growth and synaptic function are key determinants of nervous system behaviour. Understanding the molecular mechanisms that regulate these processes is central to comprehending nervous system function, both in health and during disease states. My thesis has focused on trying to better understand the mechanisms controlling glutamatergic neuronal growth, synaptic function and synaptic plasticity using the Drosophila melanogaster larval neuromuscular junction (NMJ) as a model system. This work has concentrated on the role that protein synthesis regulators play in modulating NMJ function and plasticity, and has revealed important roles for multiple regulators of cap-dependent translation in these processes. Importantly, genetic manipulations predicted to enhance cap-dependent translation in postsynaptic muscle can induce retrograde enhancements in synaptic function. In each case, these manipulations are without effect on neuronal growth, the number of synaptic sites or glutamate receptor levels. Instead, enhanced postsynaptic cap-dependent translation leads to increased presynaptic release probability. This retrograde pathway plays a key role in the expression of homeostatic synaptic plasticity at NMJ synapses. Glutamate receptor subunit IIA (GluRIIA) mutants exhibit reduced postsynaptic receptor function which is compensated for by enhanced presynaptic release; cap-dependent translation, under control of the TOR (target of rapamycin) pathway, is essential for this retrograde homeostatic response. Furthermore, we find that Parkinson's disease related protein LRRK2 (leucine rich repeat kinase 2), and its Drosophila orthologue dLRRK, can regulate synaptic function at the NMJ via cap-dependent translation. Importantly, however, mutant forms of LRRK2 are defective in their ability to regulate synaptic strength.  Together, these findings further our understanding of the molecular mechanisms regulating glutamatergic synaptic function and plasticity. </description><description>La croissance neuronale et la fonction synaptique sont des constituants clés dans le comportement du système nerveux. Il est donc essentiel de comprendre les mécanismes moléculaires régulant ces processus à l'état normal ainsi qu'à l'état pathologique. Ma thèse a pour objectif une meilleure compréhension des mécanismes contrôlant la croissance neuronale, ainsi que la fonction et la plasticité synaptiques engendrés par la transmission glutamatergique, en utilisant comme modèle la jonction neuromusculaire (JNM) de la drosophile, Drosophila melanogaster. Cet ouvrage porte spécifiquement sur l'impact de régulateurs de la synthèse protéique sur la fonction et la plasticité synaptiques dans la JNM, et a identifié des rôles importants pour de multiples régulateurs de traduction coiffe-dépendante dans ces processus. Des manipulations génétiques menant à une augmentation de la traduction coiffe-dépendante dans le muscle post-synaptique induisent une augmentation rétrograde de la fonction synaptique. Dans chaque cas, ces manipulations n'affectent ni la croissance neuronale, ni le nombre de synapses, ni le niveau de récepteurs glutamatergiques. Plutôt, une traduction coiffe-dépendante post-synaptique conduit vers une augmentation de la probabilité de relâche pré-synaptique. Cette voie signalétique joue un rôle important dans l'expression de la plasticité homéostatique des synapses neuromusculaires. Des mutants du récepteur glutamatergique IIA (GluRIIA) montrent une réduction dans la fonction post-synaptique, qui est compensée par une augmentation de la probabilité de relâche pré-synaptique. La traduction coiffe-dépendante, sous le contrôle de la voie signalétique TOR (target of rapamycin), est essentielle pour cette réponse homéostatique rétrograde. De plus, la protéine reliée à la maladie de Parkinson, LRRK2 (leucine rich repeat kinase 2), ainsi que son orthologue chez la drosophile, dLRRK, peuvent réguler la fonction synaptique de la JNM via la traduction coiffe-dépendante. Cependant, les formes mutantes de LRRK2 sont défectueuses dans leur habileté à réguler la fonction synaptique. Globalement, ces trouvailles nous aident à comprendre les mécanismes moléculaires régulant la fonction et la plasticité synaptiques glutamatergiques.</description><creator>Penney, Jay</creator><contributor>Ali Haghighi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Retrograde regulation of synaptic function at «Drosophila» neuromuscular junctions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hq37vr91j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gx06c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q811kp05z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background: Human papillomavirus (HPV) infection is recognized as an independent risk factor for squamous cell carcinomas (SCCs) of the head and neck, and the presence of HPV DNA is associated with a better prognosis. Recent evidence indicates a broader role for erythropoietin via binding and activation of its receptor (EpoR), which is present in many neoplastic non-hematopoietic cells. The expression of EpoR in cancer may represent a selection process that permits cancer cells to survive in an unfavorable microenvironment and may indicate aggressive cancer cell behavior. EpoR is variably expressed in head and neck cancer cells and could independently predict a poorer treatment response. Objectives: 1. To determine HPV status and the frequency of EpoR expression in archived biopsy specimens obtained from patients with oropharyngeal SCCs.  2. To evaluate whether the EpoR status affects survival and whether this putative effect is influenced by HPV status. Methods: A retrospective cohort study was conducted by reviewing the charts of 97 patients with oropharyngeal SCCs treated with primary curative intent radiation therapy at the McGill University Health Center, from 2000 to 2009. Eligible patients had to have archived tissue samples available for HPV and EpoR analysis. HPV DNA testing and typing was done using a standard polymerase chain reaction (PCR) protocol. EpoR status was determined by immunohistochemistry using rabbit polyclonal anti-EpoR staining. Stained sections were analyzed by 2 independent examiners by conventional light microscopy. A score product of 0-300 was determined for each patient by multiplying the percentage of neoplastic cells staining for EpoR (0-100%) and the intensity of the EpoR staining expressed from 0 to 3. Results: The median age was 62 years (range: 43–83). HPV status was positive in 74% of patients and this was significantly higher in patients aged ≤65 years, p=0.023. Patients with a significant smoking history (&gt;10 pack-years) and drinking history (&gt;4 drinks/week) were significantly more likely to be HPV negative, p= 0.041 and 0.0001 respectively. On Cox regression analysis, HPV positivity was associated with a 29% reduction in risk of death (Hazard Ratio (HR)=0.71; 95% Confidence Interval (CI): 0.34-1.49), albeit non-significantly. EpoR status was positive in 27% of patients and was associated with a non-significant 23% increase in risk of death (HR=1.23; 95%CI: 0.59-2.56). Patients who were HPV positive and EpoR negative had a non-significant 33% reduction in risk of death (HR=0.67; 95%CI: 0.29-1.56).Conclusion: This study demonstrates a trend indicating that HPV and EpoR status correlate with survival. This trend persists when patients are divided into low, intermediate and high-risk groups based on their HPV/EpoR status. The lowest risk group appears to consist of patients, which are HPV positive and EpoR negative. To the best of our knowledge this is the first study to discuss the relation of EpoR and survival in head and neck cancer.</description><description>Contexte: Le virus du papillome humain (VPH) est reconnu comme un facteur de risque indépendant pour les carcinomes épidermoïdes (CE) de la tête et du cou. De plus, la présence de l'ADN du VPH est associée à un meilleur pronostic. Des recherches récentes indiquent un plus grand rôle de l'érythropoïétine via une une activation de son récepteur (EpoR), qui est présent dans de nombreuses cellules non-hématopoïétiques néoplasiques. L'expression de EpoR dans un cancer peut représenter un processus de sélection qui permet aux cellules cancéreuses de survivre dans un environnement défavorable et peut aussi indiquer un comportement agressif des cellules cancéreuses. EpoR est variablement exprimé dans les cancers de la tête et du cou et pourrait prédire de façon indépendante une réponse plus faible aux traitements offerts aux patients. Objectifs: 1. Pour déterminer le statut VPH des cellules et la fréquence de l'expression du récepteur EpoR dans des biopsies obtenues de patients atteints du cancer  épidermoïde oropharyngé. 2. Pour évaluer si la présence d'EpoR affecte la survie et si cet effet négatif est influencé par le statut VPH des cellules. Méthodes: Une étude rétrospective a été menée en examinant les dossiers de 97 patients atteints du cancer épidermoïde oropharyngé traités par radiothérapie comme intention curative au Centre universitaire de santé McGill, de 2000 à 2009. Les patients éligibles devaient avoir archivé des échantillons de tissus disponibles pour l'analyse VPH et EpoR. L'analyse de la présence du VPH a été effectuée en utilisant une réaction standard en chaîne par polymérase (PCR). La présence du récepteur EpoR a été déterminée par immunohistochimie en utilisant des marqueurs polyclonaux colorants anti-EpoR obtenus chez les lapins. Les sections de pathologie ont été analysées par 2 examinateurs indépendants par la microscopie optique conventionnelle. Un score de 0 à 300 a été déterminé pour chaque patient en multipliant le pourcentage de cellules néoplasiques contenant l'EpoR (0 à 100%) et l'intensité de la coloration de l'EpoR exprimée de 0 à 3. Résultats: L'âge médian était de 62 ans (extrêmes: 43-83). Le statut VPH a été positif chez 74% des patients. Ceci était significativement plus élevé chez les patients âgés ≤ 65 ans, p = 0,023. Les patients ayant des antécédents de tabagisme importants (&gt; 10 paquet-années) et d'alcoolisme (&gt; 4 verres / semaine) étaient significativement plus susceptibles d'être VPH négatif, p = 0,041 et 0,0001 respectivement. En analyse de régression de Cox, la présence de VPH était associé à une réduction de 29% du risque de décès (Hazard Ratio (HR) = 0,71, Intervalle de confiance (IC) 95%: 0,34 à 1,49), mais de façon non significative (p &gt;0.05). Le statut EpoR était positif chez 27% des patients et a été associé à une augmentation non significative de 23% du risque de décès (RR = 1,23, IC 95%: 0,59 à 2,56). Les patients qui étaient positifs pour le VPH et négatifs pour l'EpoR avaient une réduction non significative de 33% du risque de décès (RR = 0,67, IC 95%: 0,29 à 1,56).Conclusion: Cette étude démontre une tendance qui indique que le VPH et le statut EpoR ont une corrélation avec la survie. Cette tendance persiste lorsque les patients sont divisés en sous-groupes (faible, intermédiaire et  haut risque) en fonction de leur statut VPH / EpoR. Le groupe avec le plus faible risque de décès sont les patients avec le statut de VPH positif et EpoR négatif. Au meilleur de nos connaissances, cette étude est la première à examiner la relation entre l'EpoR et la survie chez les patients avec le cancer de la tête et du cou.</description><creator>Almarzouki, Hani</creator><contributor>Karen Kost (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Eduardo L F Franco (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery </subject><title>Human Papillomavirus (HPV) infection and Erythropoietin Receptors (EPoR) expression as prognostic indicators in oropharyngeal cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579w62k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811kp05z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Otolaryngology - Head and Neck Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306t268j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les payements pour les services d'écosystème (PSE) sont largement utilisés pour la conservation de la biodiversité et le management des services environnementaux. Particulièrement en Afrique, les PSE sont supposés générer des revenus complémentaires pour la réduction de la pauvreté et l'amélioration des moyens de subsistance dans les zones rurales. Cependant, il y a très peu de PSE dans les zones arides et semi-arides (ZASA) qui impliquent les communautés pastorales et semi-nomades. Il y a peu d'évidences empiriques de l'impact des PSE sur la pauvreté. Cette thèse évalue les changements en biodiversité, les services environnementaux, la population humaine et la variation climatique dans les ZASA au Kenya. L'étude examine aussi les implications potentielles et réelles des PSE sur la pauvreté et les adaptations au changement climatique fondées sur les écosystèmes de deux communautés pastorales Maasai vivant à proximité des zones protégées de la faune sauvage dans le sud du Kenya. L'étude génère l'évidence des effets positifs des PSE sur les moyens de subsistance des familles participantes, particulièrement pendant une période d'extrême sécheresse quand les PSE servent comme un moyen de sécurité contre la mortalité élevée du bétail et la perte de revenus de l'élevage. Les PSE sont comme une source précieuse de diversification des revenus avec un effet de réduction de l'inégalité des revenus. Malgré ses aspects positifs, il est nécessaire d'évaluer et de contrôler les conséquences négatives potentielles de l'impact des PSE les non-participants et les familles sans terre. Les inquiétudes se posent sur les implications d'équité, et le manque de financement durable des programmes.</description><description>Payments for ecosystem services (PES) are widely being applied in the conservation of biodiversity and management of ecosystem services. In developing countries, particularly in Africa, PES mechanisms are expected to generate co-benefits of poverty reduction and improved livelihoods in rural areas. However, there are very few such schemes in the Arid and Semi-Arid Lands (ASAL) that involve pastoral and semi-nomadic communities. Furthermore, there is little empirical evidence of the impact of PES on poverty. This thesis assesses the changes in biodiversity (using wildlife populations as a proxy), ecosystem services (provisioning, habitat and cultural and amenity services), human population and climatic variability in Kenyan ASAL at the national, sub-national and local levels. It further examines the potential and actual implications of PES on poverty and ecosystem based adaptation (EBA) to climate change among two pastoral Maasai communities living adjacent to wildlife protected areas in southern Kenya. It generates evidence of the positive effects of PES on the livelihoods of participating families, particularly during a period of extreme drought when PES serves as a critical safety-net against high livestock mortality and loss of cash income derived from livestock. In addition, PES is found to be an invaluable source of income diversification and is the most equitable of all income sources among participating households. Despite some of its positive attributes, there is need to assess and mitigate the potential negative implications of PES impact on the non-participating households and the landless families. Concerns also arise with regard to the equity implications, leakages and the lack of financial sustainability in the PES programs analysed. </description><creator>Osano, Philip</creator><contributor>Peter Gilbert Brown (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>John Galaty (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Social Sciences - Geography </subject><title>Direct payments to promote biodiversity conservation and the implications for poverty reduction among pastoral communities in East African arid and semi-arid lands</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cf26v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t268j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v611h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'occurrence très fréquente d'efflorescences en eau douce constitue une importante menace à la santé humaine et environnementale. Les microcystines sont les cyanotoxines les plus communes et la caractérisation microscopique d'efflorescences toxigènes pose souvent un défi. Ce projet de recherche vise à développer et évaluer des approches axées sur l'amplification en chaîne par polymérase (ACP) pour améliorer le suivi des cyanobactéries toxigènes dans les lacs d'eau douce du Canada. Des études préliminaires évaluant l'utilité, dans la détection quantitative par ACP (qACP) de souches de Microcystis actives ou inactives en production de microcystine, d'une série de gènes codant pour les sous-unités de la microcystine synthétase (mcy), démontra que les tests visant l'identification d'une portion des gènes mcyA, mcyE, ou mcyG permit l'estimation de la quantité de souches de Microcystis toxigènes dans des échantillons d'eau de la Baie Missisquoi, Québec. Les équivalents en cellules de Microcystis toxigènes pour les gènes mcyA, mcyE, ou mcyG furent fortement associés (p&lt;0.05; R2&gt;0.90) au compte total de Microcystis obtenu par microscopie. De plus, les trois tests réussirent à quantifier les cellules de Microcystis ayant le potentiel d'être toxigènes dans des échantillons ayant une teneur en microcystine indétectable, laissant présager leur utilité potentielle dans un système d'alerte précoce pour les cyanobactéries toxigènes. Afin d'évaluer l'utilité des tests moléculaires élaborés pour estimer la teneur en Microcystis toxigènes, des études en laboratoire furent entreprises afin d'évaluer comment la teneur en gènes mcy et la biomasse de différents assemblages mixtes d'une espèce toxigène de Microcystis et d'une espèce non-toxigène d'Anabaena pourraient varier sous divers régimes d'azote, de phosphore, de température et de lumière. Les résultats démontrent une dépendance des taux de croissance, quotas en microcystine cellulaire et gène mcyE sur les nutriments et conditions de température et sur la présence de cyanobactéries compétitrices. Les changements dans le nombre de copies de mcyE furent souvent le reflet du taux de croissance de M. aeruginosa CPCC 299, ce qui implique un jumelage entre la production de mcyE et la croissance cellulaire.L'étude développa et adopta une approche qACP multiplexe pour la quantification simultanée des génotypes d'Anabaena, Microcystis, et Planktothrix produisant de la microcystine dans la Baie Missisquoi. En laboratoire, le test multiplex s'avéra très sensible et spécifique aux souches d'Anabaena, Microcystis, et Planktothrix portant le gène mcyE. Les valeurs de R2 pour la courbe d'étalonnage excédèrent 0.99, et les efficacités de réaction excédèrent 90%. L'analyse des échantillons souligna que Microcystis spp. était le principal présumé producteur de microcystine durant les périodes d'échantillonnage de 2010 et 2011. Enfin, les tests qACP développés servirent à l'étude de l'expression génique de mcyE dans Microcystis et Planktothrix, en parallèle au changement du nombre de copies de mcyE, la biomasse cyanobactérienne et les concentrations en microcystine, afin d'en dériver un indicateur fiable du risque associé à la microcystine. Les produits de transcription de mcyE furent généralement moins élevés dans les cultures mixtes (vs. monocultures), ce qui s'accorde avec la diminution du taux de croissance en cultures mixtes. Lorsque, en cultures maintenues en laboratoire, les concentrations en copies du gène mcyE, le nombre de cellules, et la teneur en chlorophylle a étaient significativement corrélés (p&lt;0.01) avec la teneur en microcystine, le niveau de transcriptions du gène mcyE s'avéra faiblement corrélé au niveau de microcystine. Dans les échantillons, le nombre de copies de mcyE montra une forte association à la teneur en microcystine, suggérant que le nombre de copies de mcyE pourrait être un meilleur indicateur du risque de contamination en microcystine.</description><description>Increased incidences of toxigenic cyanobacterial blooms in freshwater bodies pose significant threats to human and ecosystem health worldwide.  Microcystins (MCs), produced mostly by Microcystis, Anabaena, and Planktothrix spp., are amongst the most prevalent freshwater cyanotoxins. Characterization of toxigenic blooms by conventional microscopy is often challenging because of co-occurrence of morphologically indistinguishable toxic and non-toxic strains of cyanobacteria. This research project therefore sought to develop and evaluate polymerase chain reaction (PCR) approaches for improved monitoring of toxigenic cyanobacteria in Canadian freshwater lakes. Preliminary studies evaluating the utility of a suite of microcystin synthetase (mcy) genes for quantitative PCR-based detection of microcystin-producing Microcystis revealed that assays targeting portions of the mcyA, mcyE, and mcyG genes successfully estimated potential microcystin-producing Microcystis genotypes in  water samples collected from Baie Missisquoi (Missisquoi Bay), Quebec. The qPCR-based Microcystis mcyA, mcyE, or mcyG toxigenic cell equivalents showed significant associations (p&lt;0.05; R2&gt;0.90) with total Microcystis counts determined by microscopy. Furthermore, all three assays successfully quantified potentially toxic Microcystis cells in samples with undetectable microcystin concentrations, suggesting their potential usefulness in early warning systems for toxigenic cyanobacteria. To further ascertain the utility of developed molecular assays in estimating toxigenic Microcystis concentrations, laboratory studies were conducted to investigate how mcy gene concentrations and biomass of mixed assemblages of a toxic Microcystis sp. and non-toxic Anabaena sp. varied under different nitrogen, phosphorus, temperature, and light regimes. Results demonstrated dependence of growth rates, microcystin cellular and mcyE gene quotas not only on nutrients and temperature conditions, but also the presence of competing cyanobacteria. The fact that changes in mcyE copies often mirrored changes in M. aeruginosa CPCC 299 cellular growth rates implied possible coupling of mcyE production to cellular growth; thus validating use of mcyE gene concentrations as indicators of toxigenic Microcystis.The third phase of this study involved development and utilization of a multiplex qPCR approach for simultaneous quantification of microcystin-producing Anabaena, Microcystis, and Planktothrix genotypes in Missisquoi Bay.  Laboratory evaluation showed the multiplex assay to be highly sensitive and specific for mcyE-containing Anabaena, Microcystis, and Planktothrix genotypes, with assay standards achieving R2 values above 0.99 and reaction efficiencies greater than 90%. Analyses of water samples from Missisquoi Bay showed Microcystis spp. as the main putative microcystin producer, with patchy occurrence of toxigenic Anabaena and Planktothrix genotypes during the 2010 and 2011 sampling periods.Finally, the developed qPCR assays were utilized to study Microcystis and Planktothrix mcyE gene expression, concomitantly with changes in mcyE copies, cyanobacterial biomass and MC concentrations, in order to derive the most reliable indicator of microcystin risk. McyE transcripts were generally lower in mixed cultures relative to monocultures, in agreement with depressed growth recorded in the mixed cultures. Whereas concentrations of mcyE gene copies, cell counts, and chl-a correlated significantly (p&lt;0.01) with microcystins in laboratory cultures, McyE gene transcripts levels associated very poorly with MC. Furthermore, mcyE copies showed the strongest positive association with MCs in field samples, suggesting that mcyE copies are better indicators of MC risks rather than McyE transcripts or traditional biomass proxies.</description><creator>Felexce, Fru Ngwa</creator><contributor>Chandra A Madramootoo (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Engineering - Environmental</subject><title>Development and field evaluation of molecular techniques for monitoring toxigenic cyanobacteria in water</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zx59r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v611h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cm030</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>N-methyl-D-aspartate receptor (NMDAR) hypofunction has been hypothesized as a pathological change accounting for many of the symptoms of schizophrenia, including cognitive deficits. Although the etiology of schizophrenia is still not known, prenatal infection has been identified as an early-life environmental risk factor. While the onset of psychosis commonly occurs in early adulthood, cognitive deficits can be present earlier. Exposure to risk factors during adolescence, such as stress, is hypothesized to precipitate the onset of psychosis. Recent findings suggest stress may impact cognition through the modulation of NMDAR function and plasticity in the hippocampus, a vulnerable structure in schizophrenia. Therefore, prenatal infection may increase vulnerability to schizophrenia through the modulation of hippocampal NMDAR function. In order to examine this we utilized a rodent model of prenatal immune activation and investigated hippocampal NMDAR function using behavioral, electrophysiological and molecular techniques in both adolescent and adult offspringFor all of the experiments in this thesis, we examined the male offspring from pregnant rats administered lipopolysaccharide (LPS), a bacterial endotoxin, or saline control on gestational days 15 and 16. In Chapter 2 we investigated the effects of prenatal LPS exposure on hippocampal and NMDAR associated learning and memory in adolescent and adult offspring. Using NMDAR associated behavioral tasks we found alterations in adolescent, but not adult offspring. Specifically, adolescent prenatal LPS offspring had subtle long-term spatial memory impairment and enhanced spatial reversal learning; both tasks which are associated with hippocampal NMDAR-dependent synaptic plasticity, long-term depression (LTD). Next, in Chapter 3 we used electrophysiological techniques to investigate the effects of prenatal LPS exposure on in vitro hippocampal NMDAR synaptic function and LTD in adolescent offspring and tested if this may be differentially affected by exposure to stress. We found NMDAR-dependent LTD was abolished in prenatal LPS offspring, which was supported by a significant decrease in both field and whole cell measures of NMDAR synaptic function. However, restraint stress repaired the abolished LTD in prenatal LPS offspring, and treatment with the stress hormone corticosterone (CORT) augmented LTD in prenatal LPS offspring but not in controls. In Chapter 4, similar experiments were performed in adult offspring. However, hippocampal NMDAR synaptic function was not significantly altered in either basal or CORT conditions in adult prenatal LPS offspring compared to controls, suggesting the effects observed in adolescence are transiently expressed. Finally, in Chapter 5 we investigated the effects of prenatal LPS exposure on hippocampal reelin and glutamic acid decarboxylase 67 (GAD67) expression in juvenile and adolescent offspring. Both reelin and GAD67 expression are reduced in schizophrenia and preclinical studies suggest they could modulate NMDAR-mediated synaptic plasticity. Using immunohistochemistry, we found a decrease in reelin+ cells at postnatal day (P)14 and decrease in GAD67+ cells at P14 and P28 in the hippocampus of prenatal LPS offspring compared to controls. The results from this thesis demonstrate that prenatal exposure to LPS transiently alters NMDAR function in the hippocampus of rat offspring during adolescence. Prenatal LPS causes NMDAR hypofunction under basal conditions, but increased NMDAR function in response to stress during adolescence. Also, the decreased hippocampal expression of reelin and GAD67 in juvenile prenatal LPS offspring could impact normal NMDAR development. Therefore, prenatal infection could be increasing vulnerability to schizophrenia during adolescence at the level of the NMDAR and interacting with a second risk factor, stress. These results may provide insight into how prenatal infection could increase risk for schizophrenia.</description><description>L'hypofonctionnement des récepteurs au N-methyl-D-aspartate (NMDA) est une des principales hypothèses pour expliquer les symptômes de la schizophrénie, en particulier les déficits cognitifs. Bien que les causes de la schizophrénie soient méconnues, une infection durant la grossesse est un des facteurs de risque qui a été identifié. Alors que la maladie ne se manifeste qu'à l'âge adulte, les déficits cognitifs peuvent apparaitre avant. Des études suggèrent que le stress affecte les capacités cognitives via les récepteurs NMDA et la plasticité synaptique dans l'hippocampe. Par conséquent, l'infection prénatale pourrait augmenter la vulnérabilité à la schizophrénie par une modulation des récepteurs NMDA dans l'hippocampe, dont les conséquences seraient observables à l'adolescence et à l'âge adulte. Afin d'étudier cette hypothèse nous avons évalué la fonction des récepteurs NMDA dans l'hippocampe de rats adultes et adolescents suite à une infection prénatale. Nous avons utilisé un modèle d'activation du système immunitaire chez la rate gestant : une dose de lipopolysaccharide (LPS) est injectée à des rates à 15 et 16 jours de gestation et les effets sur la progéniture ont été étudiés. Les effets de cette exposition au LPS sur les fonctions cognitives sont présentés dans le chapitre 2. Les rats adolescents exposés au LPS ont montré des déficits de mémoire spatiale à long terme et une augmentation de la réversion de l'apprentissage spatial. Les rats adultes n'ont présenté aucun déficit. Ces deux tâches étant associées à la fonction des récepteurs NMDA dans la plasticité synaptique et à la dépression synaptique à long terme (LTD) dans l'hippocampe, nous avons dans le troisième chapitre étudié l'effet de l'exposition au LPS sur la transmission synaptique liée aux récepteurs NMDA et sur la LTD dans l'hippocampe des rats adolescents. De plus, nous avons étudié la relation entre le stress et l'exposition au LPS. Nous avons montré que l'exposition au LPS abolit la LTD. Cet effet est associé à une diminution de la fonction des récepteurs NMDA puisque les potentiels de champ dépendant des récepteurs NMDA ainsi que les courants NMDA furent diminués. Un stress de contention permet de rétablir les déficits de LTD observés dans le groupe exposé au LPS alors qu'un traitement à la corticostérone augmente la LTD seulement chez les animaux du groupe LPS. Aucune altération de la fonction des récepteurs NMDA et de la plasticité synaptique n'a été observée chez l'animal adulte (chapitre 4). Par conséquent une exposition au LPS affecte les fonctions des récepteurs NMDA hippocampiques de façon transitoire pendant l'adolescence.Dans le chapitre 5, nous avons étudié l'effet de l'exposition au LPS sur l'expression de la reelin et de la GAD 67 chez le rat juvénile et adolescent. L'expression de ces deux protéines est réduite chez les schizophrènes et des études suggèrent que cela affecte la plasticité synaptique en modulant les récepteurs NMDA. Nous avons observé une diminution du nombre de cellules exprimant la reelin et la GAD67 dans l'hippocampe à 14 et 28 jours chez les rats du groupe LPS. L'ensemble de nos résultats montrent que l'exposition prénatale au LPS cause des altérations de la fonction des récepteurs NMDA de l'hippocampe de façon transitoire durant l'adolescence. Elle induit un hypofonctionnement des récepteurs NMDA et augmente l'effet du stress sur leur fonction ainsi que sur la LTD pendant l'adolescence. De plus, la diminution de l'expression de la reelin et de la GAD67 observée dans l'hippocampe chez les rats juvéniles et adolescents exposés au LPS suggère que ces changements pourraient avoir un impact sur le développement des récepteurs NMDA. En conclusion, nos résultats soutiennent l'hypothèse que l'infection prénatale augmente la vulnérabilité à la schizophrénie à l'adolescence et élucident une partie des mécanismes par lesquels l'infection prénatale augmente les risques de développer la schizophrénie.</description><creator>Burt, Melissa</creator><contributor>Patricia J Boksa (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Tak Pan Wong (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Psychology - Psychobiology </subject><title>Investigating the effect of prenatal immune activation, a risk factor for Schizophrenia, on hippocampal n-methyl-d- aspartate receptor function in a rodent model</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xj156.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cm030</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rs201</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Gonadotoxic therapies including radiotherapy and chemotherapy used to treat cancers are extremely damaging to germinal epithelium inducing transient or permanent azoospermia. Spermatogonial stem cells (SSCs) are the foundation of spermatogenesis. They represent the basis of a male fertility restoration strategy after treatment. This work presented herein addressed two critical aspects in this strategy; markers to identify and isolate human SSCs, and the kinetics of SSC recovery after chemotherapy. In chapter 2, the expression of various rodent SSC markers by undifferentiated human spermatogonia, which include SSCs, was examined by immunohistochemistry, and CD9 expression was detected in the basal compartment of human seminiferous tubules. After immunological sorting, human CD9 positive male gem cells showed 3 to 4-folds enrichment when transplanted into immune-deficient nude mice testes, confirming that CD9 is expressed on human putative human SSCs and can be used to enrich for this population.  In chapter 3, I studied the contribution of SSC recovery to fertility recovery after chemotherapy in a mouse model, and provided functional evidence that the restoration kinetics of male fertility follows those of the SSC population after damage. I also addressed the question whether there is a critical SSC number to confer fertility and suggested a 30% of original SSC population as a threshold of the SSC population size required for the onset of male fertility restoration. Though the study did not identify a faithful physiological parameter related to male reproduction (sperm count, testis weight, testosterone level, Glial cell-derived neurotropic factor (GDNF) transcripts level in testes), which would allow for monitoring the degree of SSC recovery in a non-invasive manner, yet it paved the way for future efforts to predict the timing of male fertility restoration after chemotherapy. In conclusion, this work identified a new marker for human putative SSCs and proved it to be effective to enrich for this cell population. In addition, it provided functional evidence that restoration of male fertility results from that of SSC and identified for the first time a threshold level of SSC population size permitting recovery.</description><description>Les thérapies gonadotoxiques y compris la radiothérapie et de la chimiothérapie utilisées pour traiter les cancers sont extrêmement dommageable pour l' épithélium germinal, induisant l'azoospermie transitoire ou permanente. Les cellules souches germinales (CSG) sont à la base de la spermatogenèse. Elles représentent la base d'une stratégie de restauration de la fertilité masculine après traitement. Ce travail a porté sur deux aspects essentiels de cette stratégie; identifier des marqueurs pour isoler les CSG humains, et étudier la cinétique de la récupération des CSG après une chimiothérapie. Dans le chapitre 2, l'expression de différents marqueurs des CSG de rongeurs a été examinée dans les CSG humaine par immunohistochimie, et l'expression de CD9 a été détectée dans le compartiment basal des tubes séminifères de l'homme. Après un triage cellulaire immunologique, les cellules CD9 positives ont montré un enrichissement de trois à quatre lorsqu'elles sont transplantées dans les testicules des souris nude immunodéficientes, confirmant que CD9 est exprimé sur les CSG mâles et peut être utilisé pour enrichir cette population.Dans le chapitre 3, j'ai étudié la corrélation entre la cinétique de récupération des CSG et la restauration de la fertilité après une chimiothérapie chez un modèle de souris, et fourni une preuve fonctionnelle que la restauration de la fertilité masculine est parallèle à celui de la population CGS après l'insulte. J'ai également abordé la question de savoir si il y a un nombre critique de CSG pour récupérer la fertilité. Mes résultats suggèrent que 30% de la population d'origine CSG doit être seuil pour supporter la restauration de la fertilité masculine. Bien que l'étude n'a pas identifié un paramètre physiologique mesurable indicateur de la capacité reproductive des mâles pour l'apparition de la restauration de la fertilité masculine (nombre de spermatozoïdes, poids des testicules, niveau de testostérone, niveau de transcription du facteur neurotrope dérivé des cellules gliales (GDNF) dans les testicules), qui permettrait de surveiller le degré de récupération de la CSG, mais il a ouvert la voie à de futurs efforts. En conclusion, ce travail a identifié un nouveau marqueur des CSG humaines et il s'est avéré être efficace pour enrichir cette population cellulaire. En outre, il a fourni des preuves que la restauration fonctionnelle de la fertilité masculine est le résultat de la récupération des CSG,  et a identifié pour la première fois un seuil de taille de la population CSG permettant la récupération de fertilité masculine.</description><creator>Zohni, Khaled</creator><contributor>Makoto Nagano (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Peter Chan (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health Sciences - Obstetrics and Gynecology</subject><title>Spermatogonial stem cells (SSCs): study of recovery kinetics and potential role in restoration of male fertility after cytotoxic treatment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010t40d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rs201</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074z401</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le cancer de la peau est le plus fréquent dans le monde avec presque trois millions de cas par an. Les mélanomes cutanés sont les cancers de la peau les plus mortels, puisqu'ils sont responsables de 75 pour cent des morts liées aux cancers cutanés. Au cours des cinquante dernières années, le taux d'incidence des mélanomes dans les pays développés a augmenté plus vite que pour les autres cancers. Bien que la plupart des patients présentent une tumeur localisée au moment du diagnostic et sont soignés par excision de la tumeur primaire, les mélanomes cutanés peuvent former des métastases dans presque n'importe quel autre organe. Le diagnostic à un stade avancé est alors associé à un prognostic faible : la survie à 15 ans n'est alors que de 5 pour cent. Ainsi, il est crucial d'élucider les mécanismes sous-jacents à la progression des mélanomes cutanés. La famille des facteurs de croissance TGFb (Transforming Growth Factor beta) représente un vaste groupe de polypeptides plurifonctionnels qui contribuent à l'orchestration et la modulation du développement, à la croissance, à la différentiation, ainsi qu'à l'homéostasie de presque tous les types cellulaires et tissulaires. Le TGFb et ses récepteurs sont exprimés par tous les tissus et il joue un rôle important dans les maladies humaines. Dans les cancers chez l'humain, le TGFb joue généralement un double rôle. Dans les stades normaux et pré-malins, il maintient l'homéostasie des tissus et agit comme un suppresseur de tumeur. Cependant, ces effets sont perdus au cours de la tumorigenèse à cause d'altérations dans les molécules de la voie de signalisation, donnant alors lieu à des réponses qui favorisent la progression tumorale. Il semble néanmoins que ces effets soient spécifiques à chaque type tissulaire. Dans les mélanomes cutanés, ils sont encore mal caractérisés et sont controversés. Ce travail de doctorat avait pour but d'élucider le rôle du TGFb dans la progression des mélanomes cutanés. Le premier objectif était de déterminer les effets du TGFb sur de multiples lignées cellulaires de mélanome aux origines cliniques très variées. Cette étude a tout d'abord montré que le TGFb inhibe la croissance des cellules de mélanome à différents degrés et a mis en évidence que ces effets sont dus à l'induction de l'arrêt du cycle cellulaire en phase G1 et à l'induction de l'apoptose. Ensuite, de manière surprenante, ce travail a démontré que le TGFb inhibe les propriétés migratoires et invasives des cellules de mélanome, agissant ainsi comme un facteur anti-métastatique. Le second objectif était d'identifier des molécules en aval du TGFb qui transmettent ses effets. Ainsi, ce travail a mis en lumière une nouvelle voie suppressive de tumeur dans les mélanomes, dans laquelle le TGFb régule l'expression de l'inhibiteur du cycle cellulaire p21, par une cascade impliquant le facteur inhibiteur des leucémies (LIF) et son effecteur STAT3, et régulant l'arrêt du cycle cellulaire et l'apopose. Par ailleurs, l'inhibiteur de l'activateur du plasminogène (PAI-1) a été démontré comme étant un protagoniste important des effets anti-métastatiques du TGFb, son expression étant fortement augmentée par le TGFb, entraînant une diminution de la formation de la plasmine, une enzyme clé dans la migration et l'invasion. Enfin, le facteur de transcription pro-migratoire neurogenin2 (NGN2) a également été identifié comme un intermédiaire des effets inhibiteurs du TGFb sur la migration des cellules de mélanome, via la régulation de la réorganisation du cytosquelette d'actine. En conclusion, les résultats de ce doctorat ont clarifié les effets jusque-là mal connus du TGFb dans les mélanomes cutanés et ont montré que la voie de signalisation du TGFb agit comme un puissant suppresseur de tumeur dans les mélanomes cutanés, inhibant non seulement la croissance mais également la migration et l'invasion des cellules cancéreuses. En conséquence, favoriser les effets du TGFb serait une stratégie thérapeutique intéressante.</description><description>Skin cancer is the most common type of cancer worldwide, with an annual occurrence of almost 3 million cases. The most lethal skin cancer is cutaneous melanoma, which accounts for 75 percent of skin cancer related deaths. Over the past 50 years, the incidence of melanoma in most developed countries has increased faster than any other cancer. Although most patients have localized disease at the time of diagnosis and are cured by surgical excision of the primary tumor, melanoma can be highly malignant and form metastases to almost any organ of the body. Melanoma diagnosis at later stages of tumor progression is associated with a poor prognosis. Indeed, the fifteen-year survival for advanced melanoma is only 5 percent. It is therefore crucial to elucidate the molecular events underlying melanoma progression. The transforming growth factor beta (TGFb) family of growth factors represents a large group of plurifunctional polypeptides that contribute to the orchestration and modulation of the developmental program, growth, differentiation, and functional homeostasis of almost all cell types and tissues. TGFb and its receptors are expressed in all tissues and the regulatory role played by this growth factor is of central importance in human diseases. In human cancers, TGFb is generally considered to exert a dual role. In the normal and premalignant states, TGFb maintains tissue homeostasis and acts as a tumor suppressor. These activities can be lost during tumorigenesis because of alterations of the TGFb pathway molecules and other responses then prevail, favoring tumor progression and metastasis. However, these effects might be tissue-specific and they have not been well characterized in cutaneous melanoma, where they remain controversial. The present thesis aimed at elucidating the role of TGFb in cutaneous melanoma progression. The first goal of this work was to determine the effects of TGFb in multiple cutaneous melanoma cell lines originating from various clinical backgrounds. Firstly, this study showed that TGFb exerts variable growth inhibitory effects on melanoma cells, and specifically highlighted that this inhibition results from the induction of both cell cycle arrest in the G1 phase and apoptosis. In addition, this work surprisingly showed that TGFb inhibits both melanoma cell migration and invasion, thus acting as an anti-metastatic factor. The second objective was to identify downstream TGFb targets mediating these effects. As such, this work highlighted a novel tumor suppressive pathway in melanoma, in which TGFb regulates the cell cycle inhibitor p21, through a cascade involving the leukemia inhibitory factor (LIF) and the signal transducer and activator of transcription 3 (STAT3) to modulate cell cycle arrest and apoptosis. Also, the plasminogen activator inhibitor-1 (PAI-1) was shown to be an important protagonist in the anti-metastatic activities of TGFb, through its TGFb-mediated strong upregulation and the subsequent decrease in plasmin generation and activity, a key enzyme in the migratory and invasive processes. Finally, the pro-migratory transcription factor neurogenin2 (NGN2) was demonstrated to be a key player in the TGFb-induced inhibition of migration, through regulation of actin cytoskeleton reorganization. Together, the results in the present thesis shed some light on the so far controversial role of TGFb in cutaneous melanoma and indicate that TGFb signaling is a potent suppressive pathway in cutaneous melanoma, not only inhibiting cell growth but also altering cell migration and invasion. Thus, targeting this pathway to mimic its effects may provide insights into the development of new therapeutic tools.</description><creator>Humbert, Laure</creator><contributor>Jean Jacques Lebrun (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery </subject><title>Role of transforming growth factor beta in human cutaneous melanoma progression</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816q82s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074z401</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50h061f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La gravitation en 2+1 dimensions avec une constante cosmologique négative est une théorie topologique, sans degrés de liberté locaux. Lorsqu'elle est limitée à des univers compacts qui sont topologiquement un produit direct des surfaces de Riemann au genre g et du temps, son espace de phase classique est le fibré cotangent de l'espace des modules des surfaces de Riemann. Nous considérons la quantification de l'espace des modules lui-même, qui se produit comme la tranche zéro dynamique de cet espace de phase. Quand on ajoute un terme Chern-Simons, qui brise la parité, à l'action gravitationelle, une forme symplectique non triviale est induite sur cette tranche qui est un multiple de la forme Kähler de Weil-Petersson. En exigeant que cette forme symplectique doit intégrer à 2 pi fois h barre multiplié par un entier sur tous les cycles non triviaux de degré 2 dans l'espace des modules—condition nécessaire pour faire la quantification du système—nous trouvons une nouvelle condition de quantification pour k', le couplage Chern-Simons. Notre résultat suggère fortement que k' doit être un multiple entier de 24, afin de définir une théorie cohérente de la gravitation quantique.</description><description>(2+1)-dimensional gravity with a negative cosmological constant is a topological theory with no local degrees of freedom. When confined to compact universes which are topologically genus g Riemann surfaces times time, its classical phase space is the cotangent bundle of the moduli space of Riemann surfaces. We consider the quantization of moduli space itself, emerging as the zero-momentum slice of this phase space. When a parity-violating Chern-Simons term is added to the gravitational action, a nontrivial symplectic form is induced on this slice which is a multiple of the Weil-Petersson Kähler form. By demanding that this symplectic form integrate to 2 pi h-bar times an integer on every nontrivial two-cycle in moduli space—which is a necessary condition for the system to be quantizable—we find a new quantization condition on the Chern-Simons coupling k'. Our result strongly suggests that k' must be an integer multiple of 24 in order to define a self-consistent theory of quantum gravity.</description><creator>Blais, Timothy</creator><contributor>Alexander Maloney (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Physics - Theory</subject><title>A new quantization condition for parity-violating three-dimensional gravity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z856g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50h061f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zh80w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le facteur de transcription CUX1, et plus particulièrement ses isoformes courtes, sont impliquées dans différents processus associés au développement cancéreux dans des expériences de culture de tissus et dans des modèles de souris transgéniques. De plus, CUX1 est sur-exprimé dans de nombreux cancers humains. Les fonctions attribuées jusqu'à présent à CUX1 sont associées à son activité transcriptionelle. Cependant, il est possible que CUX1 joue un rôle non-transcriptionel dans la cellule. La purification par affinité en tandem, couplée à la spectrométrie de masse, a  permis d'identifier plusieurs partenaires d'interaction de CUX1. Le but de mes études a été de valider et caractériser les interactions de CUX1 avec certaines de ces protéines, plus précisément REV1, PARP1 et Ku70/Ku80. REV1 est une ADN polymérase de faible fidélité lors de la synthèse d'ADN impliqué dans le processus de synthèse à travers les lésions (translesion synthesis) et responsable de la plupart des mutations ponctuelles chez la levure, ainsi que chez les mammifères. Nous avons montré que l'interaction entre REV1 et CUX1 nécessitait le domaine BRCT de REV1 et que leur affinité respective augmentait suite à l'irradiation. J'ai montré que CUX1 était phosphorylé suite aux dommages à l'ADN. Mes résultats ont indiqué que ATM phosphorylait CUX1 et que les phosphorylations de CUX1 sur les serines 861, 868 et 1100 favorisaient son interaction avec REV1. Des expériences de localisation génomique par puce ont montré que REV1 était localisé de manière préférentielle dans des régions transcrites, que cette localisation augmentait suite à l'irradiation aux rayons gamma et que 12.9% des sites de localisation de REV1 se superposaient aux sites de localisation de CUX1.J'ai optimisé et j'ai caractérisé deux essais rapporteurs pour l'analyse des mutations ponctuelles (GFPstop et résistance à l'ouabain) et j'ai montré que la fréquence  des mutations ponctuelles corrélait, en partie, avec la capacité des promoteurs à recruter REV1. Une réduction de l'expression de REV1 a induit la réduction de l'expression des nombreux gènes. Nous suggérons que le rôle physiologique du recrutement de REV1 au sein de régions génomiques transcrites est de permettre la transcription efficace des gènes transcrits activement, en prévenant le blocage du passage du complexe transcriptionel normalement induit par les fourches de réplication arrêtées à cause du dommage à l'ADN. Ku et PARP1 sont des détecteurs du dommage à l'ADN et stimulent la réparation de l'ADN. J'ai validé l'interaction de CUX1 avec Ku et PARP1 et j'ai montré que, suite à l'expression des fragments de CUX1, Ku et PARP1 ne se localisaient plus sur certaines de leurs cibles génomiques. En utilisant différentes approches expérimentales, mes résultats ont indiqué que, en plus de son rôle transcriptionel, CUX1 pourrait jouer un rôle non-transcriptionel dans la réparation des cassures de l'ADN. </description><description>The short isoforms of the CUX1 transcription factor have been implicated in various cancer-related processes in tissues culture experiments and were found to contribute to tumorigenicity in transgenic mice. In addition, CUX1 is over-expressed in many human cancers. The functions attributed so far to CUX1 stem from its activity as a transcription factor. However, it is possible that CUX1 plays a non-transcriptional role in the cell. Tandem affinity purification, followed by mass spectrometry, identified numerous binding partners of CUX1. The aim of my studies was to validate and further characterize the interactions of CUX1 with some of these proteins: REV1, PARP1 and Ku70/Ku80. REV1 is an error-prone DNA polymerase involved in translesion synthesis and is responsible for most point mutations in yeast and mammalian cells.  We showed that the REV1-CUX1 interaction required the REV1 BRCT domain and was increased following irradiation. I have shown that CUX1 was phosphorylated following DNA damage. My results indicated that ATM phosphorylated CUX1 and that phosphorylation of CUX1 at serines 861, 868 and 1100 promoted its interaction with REV1.  ChIP-on-chip experiments showed that REV1 preferentially localized to transcribed regions, that the recruitment increased after gamma-irradiation and that 12.9% of REV1 binding sites overlapped CUX1 binding sites. I have optimized and characterized two reporter assays for point mutations (GFPstop and ouabain resistance) and showed that point mutation frequency correlated, at least in part, with the ability of a promoter to recruit REV1. Reduction in REV1 expression led to a decrease in expression of numerous genes. We propose that the physiological purpose for REV1 recruitment to transcribed regions is to enable efficient transcription of actively transcribed genes, by preventing stalled replication forks from blocking the passage of the transcription machinery. Ku and PARP1 are sensors of DNA damage and promote DNA damage repair. I have validated the interaction of CUX1 with Ku and PARP1 and showed that expression of CUX1 fragments led to their displacement from known promoter targets. Using various experimental approaches, my results indicated that in addition to its transcriptional role, CUX1 might play a non-transcriptional role in the repair of strand breaks. </description><creator>Hulea, Laura</creator><contributor>Alain Nepveu (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Multiple roles of CUX1 in the DNA damage response</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58ph30j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zh80w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n583xz426</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Comprendre la pathogenèse d'une maladie dégénérative du cerveau telle la maladie d'Alzheimer est d'une importance primordiale pour notre population vieillissante. Le cerveau est l'organe du corps humain avec le plus haut taux de cholestérol, et la neurophysiologie normale dépend fortement de ce stérol. La dysrégulation du stérol a été largement impliquée dans la pathogenèse de la neurodégénérescence, mais les efforts de recherche n'ont pas réussi à déterminer comment ces perturbations nécessaires causent la maladie. Les oxygénases hème sont des capteurs dynamiques de stress oxydatif cellulaire et des médiateurs probables de l'homéostasie redox tissulaire à travers le spectre phylogénétique. Toutefois, le processus catabolique hème s'est avéré être l'un des visages de janus! La surexpression de l'hème oxygénase-1 et le métabolisme du cholestérol altéré est caractéristique des tissues neurologiques affectés par la maladie d'Alzheimer. Notre laboratoire a précédemment démontré que la propension de HO-1 surexpression peut avoir un impacte sur l'homéostasie des stérols. Dans les présentes, nous enquêtons les mécanismes derrière ces interactions HO-1/sterol in vitro (astrocytes de rat en culture) et examinons cette relation dans le cerveau atteint d'Alzheimer post-mortem (Religious Order Study) et in vivo en comparant deux modèles de souris; 1) une souris HO-1 transgénique (GFAP.HMOX1) conçue pour faire ressortir de façon sélective de la HO-1 humain dans le compartiment astrocytic et 2) une souris transgénique triple d'Alzheimer (3xTg-AD), décrite précédemment. Les données résultantes de notre expérimentation indiquent que la HO-1 est un profond effecteur de la régulation des stérols dans le système nerveux central et suggère que, dans diverses conditions de stress cellulaire, la HO-1 impact de façon différentielle les modes des stérols et oxystérols du cerveau. Nous présentons un nouveau modèle de régulation neurosterol d'Alzheimer's à travers le spectre pathologique et délimitons l'importance de la HO-1 dans ce processus. Mauvais dynamiques HO-1/stérol semblables à celles examinées dans les présentes constitue une voie omniprésente du vieillissement pathologique et, par conséquent, une cible solide pour l'intervention thérapeutique de la maladie d'Alzheimer et de maladies dégénératives similaires.</description><description>As average life expectancy increases, understanding the pathogenesis of age related degenerative brain disease such as Alzheimer's is of paramount importance. The brain is the most cholesterol dense human organ and normal neurophysiology is highly dependant upon this sterol. Sterol dys-regulation has been widely implicated in the pathogenesis of neurodegeneration, yet investigative efforts have failed to determine how these essential disturbances drive disease progression. The heme oxygenases (HOs) are dynamic sensors of cellular oxidative stress and likely mediators of tissue redox homeostasis across the phylogenetic spectrum. However, the heme catabolic process has proven to be one of janus face! Up-regulation of heme oxygenase-1 and altered cholesterol metabolism are characteristic of Alzheimer-diseased (AD) neural tissues. Our lab has previously demonstrated the propensity for HO-1 overexpression to impact sterol homeostasis. Herein, we query the mechanisms behind these HO-1/sterol interactions in vitro (cultured rat astroglia) and examine this relationship in post-mortem human AD brain (Religious Orders Study) and in vivo by comparing two mouse models; 1) a novel HO-1 transgenic mouse (GFAP.HMOX1) engineered to selectively express human HO-1 in the astrocytic compartment and 2) the previously described triple transgenic AD mouse (3xTg-AD). Data garnered from our experimentation indicate that HO-1 is a profound effecter of sterol regulation in the central nervous system and suggests that, under various conditions of cellular stress, HO-1 differentially impacts patterns of brain sterols and oxysterols. We present a novel model of brain sterol regulation in AD across the pathological spectrum and delineate the importance of HO-1 in this process. Aberrancy of HO-1/sterol dynamics akin to those reviewed herein constitute a ubiquitous pathway of pathological aging and, hence, a robust target for therapeutic intervention in AD and similar degenerative diseases.</description><creator>Hascalovici, Jacob</creator><contributor>Hyman M Schipper (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Heme Oxygenase-1/sterol interactions in Alzheimer's disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q489z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xz426</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r872b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of this work was to examine the effects of chlorine (Cl2) gas inhalation on airway dysfunction in a mouse model of irritant-induced asthma. Cl2 inhalation induces airway hyperresponsiveness (AHR), bronchial epithelial cell damage, increased oxidative stress and airway inflammation, characterized by neutrophilia.  While the effects of Cl2 inhalation had been previously characterized, mechanisms driving airway injury induced by Cl2 remained elusive.  We hypothesized that oxidative stress following Cl2 was pivotally involved in mechanisms leading to airway injury.  First, using antioxidants we aimed to further characterize the effects of Cl2 inhalation by evaluating airway mechanics, pulmonary antioxidant activity, lung inflammatory profiles and bronchial epithelial cell proliferation. We established that administration of antioxidants post-Cl2 inhalation was effective at ameliorating AHR, oxidative stress, bronchial epithelial cell proliferation, and airway inflammation, suggesting indirect mechanisms were responsible for Cl2-induced airway damage. Next, we depleted several inflammatory cell types in an attempt to determine which cell type, if any, was contributing to the observed effects of Cl2. We depleted macrophages, eosinophils and neutrophils and found that only depletion of neutrophils was effective at reducing airway hyperresponsivness and prevented endogenous antioxidant activity as measured by nuclear factor (erythroid-derived 2)-like 2 (NRF2) nuclear translocation.  Concomitant experiments established Cl2 increased the pro-inflammatory lipid mediators cysteinyl-leukotrienes and mRNA levels of cysLT-related biosynthetic genes.  Given the role of cysLTs and their receptor cysLTr1 as established pro-asthma mediators, we chose to explore the role of cysLTr1 in our model by utilizing cysLTr1 deleted mice (cysLTr1-/-).  We found that deletion of cysLTr1 worsened measured outcomes following Cl2.  Compared to wild-type mice, cysLTr1-/- demonstrated increased AHR, airway neutrophilia and epithelial cell apoptosis.  In contrast to wild-type mice, we observed that cysLTr1-/- did not show nuclear translocation of NRF2 or increased antioxidant mRNA levels following Cl2 exposure.  At baseline levels, we observed that cysLTr1-/- mice had increased e-cadherin protein expression on bronchial epithelial cells compared to wild-type mice. We propose that deletion of cysLTr1 in mice results in an increased susceptibility to Cl2 induced airway damage and dysfunction and this damage is mediated via an aberrant endogenous antioxidant response.  This vulnerability to oxidant damage, likely due to increased neutrophil numbers and NRF2 idleness, may be due to an innate increase in e-cadherin, which is partially mediated via cysLTr1. Finally, we use in vitro studies to examine how exogenous cysteinyl-leukotriene D4 stimulates bronchial epithelial cells to release the neutrophil chemoattractant IL-8.  We found this pathway to be dependent on the activation of the epidermal growth factor receptor. These in vitro studies establish the basis for further examination of specific pathways that may be involved in how epithelial cells may be involved in neutrophil recruitment.  </description><description>L'objectif du travail présenté dans cette thèse était d'examiner les effets de l'inhalation de chlore gazeux (Cl2) sur la dysfonction des voies respiratoires chez la souris, un modèle d'asthme induit par un irritant. L'inhalation de Cl2 induit une hyperréactivité bronchique (HRB), des lésions des cellules épithéliales bronchiques, une augmentation du stress oxydatif et l'inflammation des voies aériennes qui se caractérise principalement par une neutrophilie. Même si les effets de l'inhalation de Cl2 sont bien caractérisés, en revanche, les mécanismes entraînant les lésions des voies aériennes induites par le Cl2 sont toujours méconnus. Nous émettons l'hypothèse que le stress oxydatif qui survient suite à une exposition au Cl2 joue un rôle clef dans l'apparition des lésions des voies aériennes. Tout d'abord, les effets de traitements antioxydants sur l'inhalation de Cl2 ont été caractérisés en évaluant les fonctions respiratoires, l'activité antioxydante et le profil inflammatoire pulmonaire ainsi que la prolifération des cellules épithéliales bronchiques. Nous avons établi que l'administration d'antioxydants à la suite d'une inhalation de Cl2 améliore l'HBR, le stress oxydatif, la prolifération des cellules épithéliales bronchiques et l'inflammation des voies respiratoires. Ces résultats suggèrent que des mécanismes indirects sont responsables des lésions des voies respiratoires induites par Cl2. Ensuite, afin de déterminer quel(s) type(s) de cellules contribuent, le cas échéant, aux effets du Cl2, nous avons effectué une déplétion de plusieurs types de cellules inflammatoires : macrophages, éosinophiles et neutrophiles. Nous avons constaté que seule la déplétion des neutrophiles permet de réduire l'hyperréactivité bronchique et de prévenir l'activation des facteurs antioxydants endogènes, telle que mesurée par la translocation nucléaire du facteur nucléaire (erythroid-derived 2)-like 2 (NRF2). L'exposition au Cl2 augmente le taux de médiateurs pro-inflammatoires lipidiques cystéinyl-leucotriènes (cysLTs) ainsi que la quantité d'ARNm liés à la biosynthèse de ces médiateurs, dans le poumon proximal. Étant donné que les cysLTs et leur récepteur cysLTr1 sont établis comme étant des médiateurs pro-asthmatiques, nous avons choisi d'explorer le rôle de cysLTr1 dans notre modèle en utilisant des souris mutées pour le gène cysLTr1 (cysLTr1-/-).  Nous avons constaté que la suppression de cysLTr1 aggrave les résultats obtenus suite à l'exposition au Cl2. Par rapport aux souris de type sauvage, les souris cysLTr1-/- montrent une augmentation de l'HBR, une neutrophilie des voies respiratoires et une apoptose des cellules épithéliales. Contrairement aux souris de type sauvage, nous avons observé que les souris cysLTr1-/- ne montrent pas de translocation nucléaire de NRF2 ni d'augmentation des niveaux d'ARNm anti-oxydantes après une exposition au Cl2. Nous avons observé que l'expression des protéines E-cadhérine dans les cellules épithéliales bronchiques des souris cysLTr1-/- est augmentée par rapport aux souris de type sauvage. Nous proposons que la suppression de cysLTr1 chez la souris cause une sensibilité accrue aux lésions et aux dysfonctionnements des voies respiratoires induites par le Cl2. Nous pensons qu'une réponse aberrante des antioxydants endogènes est à l'origine de ces dommages. Cette vulnérabilité aux dommages oxydatifs, probablement causée par l'augmentation du nombre de neutrophiles et l'absence de translocation NRF2, peut s'expliquer par une augmentation innée de l'e-cadhérine, partiellement contrôlée par cysLTr1. Contrairement à une carence chronique en cysLTr1, une exposition aiguë à LTD4 des cellules épithéliales respiratoires humaines provoque une cascade d'événements conduisant à la libération d'HB-EGF, l'activation du récepteur d'EGF et la libération IL-8. À la fois protecteurs et pro-inflammatoires/régénérateurs, les leucotriènes s'avèrent jouer un rôle complexe dans la réponse de l'hôte à une exposition au Cl2.</description><creator>McGovern, Toby</creator><contributor>James G Martin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Biology - General</subject><title>Oxidative stress and chorine induced airway dysfunction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741v947.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r872b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kf05b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:09:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Histories of North American feminist, queer, and queer feminist art can be traced in relation to a history of the institutions, organizations, and structures that have helped to secure and legitimize feminist and queer art practices. My dissertation provides a queer feminist historiographical analysis of key feminist and queer alternative art spaces in three North American cities, in an effort to both affirm their enduring historical significance and to delineate the ways by which the present day histories of past queer and feminist practices support or challenge the dominant narrative lens through which the histories have come to be read. With focus on the 1970s feminist art movement in Los Angeles, the underground queer art communities formed in New York City in the 1980s and continuing into the mid-2000s, and the burgeoning queer feminist cultural communities working in the present day in Montreal, I show how the socio-political conditions of each place have resulted in divergent paths among the institutions. Putting each history into dialogue with contemporary queer feminist initiatives and interventions, I demonstrate how queer feminism can work, in the present day, both to secure the historical significance of these spaces and to critically engage histories of exclusion as integral to their continued relevance.</description><description>On peut retracer l'histoire de l'art féministe, de l'art queer ainsi que de l'art queer et féministe en Amérique du Nord à travers une histoire des institutions, des organisations et des structures qui ont contribué à garantir et légitimer les pratiques d'art queer et féministe. Ma thèse offre une analyse historiographique queer et féministe des espaces d'art alternatifs, féministes et queer clés dans trois villes nord-américaines, de manière à affirmer leur portée historique tout en délimitant les façons par lesquelles l'histoire actuelle des pratiques queer et féministes du passé soutient ou remet en question l'optique du discours dominant à travers laquelle cette histoire en est venue à être lue. En me concentrant sur le mouvement artistique féministe des années 1970 à Los Angeles, sur les communautés underground d'art queer formées à New York dans les années 1980 jusqu'à la première moitié des années 2000 et sur les communautés culturelles queer et féministes émergeantes aujourd'hui à Montréal, je démontre comment les conditions socio-politiques présentes dans chaque ville ont mené les institutions dans des trajectoires divergentes. En engageant chaque histoire dans un dialogue avec des initiatives et interventions féministes et queer contemporaines, je démontre comment le féminisme queer peut présentement participer tant à assurer l'importance historique de ces espaces qu'à aborder, de façon critique, les histoires d'exclusion comme étant une partie intégrante de leur pertinence continue.</description><creator>Silver, Erin</creator><contributor>Jones, Amelia (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2013</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Art History</subject><title>Sites unseen and scenes unsighted: histories of feminist and queer alternative art spaces, ca. 1970-2012</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236566b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kf05b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):13475</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>