<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:44:11Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40275" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306t1052</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nickel constitutes the major impurity encountered during copper electrorefining (Cu ER) operations. Continuous nickel build-up in the electrolyte is controlled by withdrawing a fraction of solution from the tankhouse and separate nickel as crude NiSO4.2H2O via Evaporative Crystallisation . The energy required to evaporate water is high, increasing thus the operation costs; moreover, the product thus obtained is of poor quality in terms of purity and crystal size. As part of an ongoing research project launched at McGill University, the Solvent Displacement Crystallisation (SDC) technique is investigated as an attractive alternative to the conventional method. SDC involves the addition of low-boiling point, watermiscible organic solvents (MOs) to aqueous solutions to cause salt precipitation based on the "salting out" effect. The crystals are separated by filtration whereas the solvent is subsequently recovered for reuse by low-temperature distillation. The present work describes the successful application of SDC method to the precipitation of NiSO4.6H2O from Cu ER spent electrolytes. Tests have been performed on synthetic and industrial electrolytes (courtesy of Canadian Copper Refineries), using Isopropanol as precipitant. By maintaining a low supersaturation (i.e. controlled addition of the solvent to the electrolyte) and heterogeneous crystallisation conditions (use of seed/product recycling), crystal growth is favoured while impurity uptake/contamination is minimised.</description><creator>Moldoveanu, Georgiana A.</creator><contributor>Demopoulos, George P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Precipitation of nickel sulphate from decopperised acid solution by solvent displacement crystallisation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698940n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t1052</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53wx69t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There is a need for two dimensional parallel optical interconnects for large bandwidth transfer of data over a distance ranging from tens of centimeters to a few meters. Optical transmission of data through "free-space" using imaging or diffractive elements would fulfil this need for very large bandwidth and high throughput density, but is not yet a practical approach. A commercially viable approach in the shorter term is to use optical fiber technologies as the communication medium. Fiber image-guides can be mass produced and are easy to align with the source but have insertion losses of the order of -3 dB. Ordered fiber arrays can be constructed using the same technology as fiber image-guides, and can have lower insertion losses but at the cost of reduced alignment tolerances. We present a model for the numerical calculation of the insertion loss in ordered fiber arrays when coupling light from an array of VCSELs of equal dimensions. We then apply this model to study the impact of alignment on insertion losses as a function of the different fiber array parameters: core radius and of the individual fiber elements, and the dimensions of the array. We conclude that the alignment tolerances for multimode ordered fiber arrays should be compatible with present-day connector technology.</description><creator>Mathieu, Frédérick.</creator><contributor>Kirk, Andrew (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Alignment tolerance study between VCSEL arrays and a new kind of ordered fiber array technology considered for two dimensional parallel optical interconnects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418q05w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53wx69t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rw360</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Parallel Optical Data Links (PODLs) have the potential to solve interconnection bottlenecks which are currently being experienced in high-speed communication and information processing systems. Such links often require a large number of channels and two-dimensional arrays of active optoelectronic devices are being developed. In order to interconnect these devices, fiber image guide technology consisting of a bundle of several thousand equally spaced optical fibers is being proposed to alleviate the need for dedicated fibers. This thesis examines the implementation of a two-dimensional parallel optical interconnect consisting of an array of Vertical-Cavity Surface-Emitting Lasers (VCSELs), a 1.35m Fiber Image Guide (FIG) and a Metal-Semiconductor-Metal (MSM) receiver array. Coupling issues associated with image guides are analysed and discussed as well as general image guide properties and transmission characteristics. The design, construction and integration aspects of the data link, including optics, electronics and optomechanics are summarised. Characterization results are presented and a transmission rate of 250 Mbit/s per channel is demonstrated with an optical crosstalk of less than -27 dB and a total optical loss of -3dB.</description><creator>Maj, Tomasz.</creator><contributor>Kirk, Andrew (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Interconnection of a 2D vertical-cavity surface-emitting laser array to a receiver array via a fiber image guide</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fb228.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rw360</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j6731581h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The punching shear behaviour of interior slab-column connections in flat plates is investigated. The response of six two-way slab specimens, which were designed such that they would fail in punching shear, are presented. The parameter introduced in the experimental program is member depth. The effects of this parameter on the punching shear capacity of slab elements are investigated. The results show a strong "size effect", with deeper members having a smaller shear stresses at failure than shallow ones. Test results obtained from this experimental program are compared with the punching shear predictions of the Canadian CSA A23.3-94 Standard, the American ACI 318-95 Code, the British BS 8110-85 Standard and the European CEB-FIP 1990 Model Code. Predictions were also made using computer program "Response 2000", assuming an equivalent beam analogy to represent the slab. It is concluded that the shear design of slabs, according to the current Canadian and American codes, can be unconservative under certain conditions, particularity for thick slabs. It is recommended that the punching shear expressions of the CSA Standard and the ACI Code be modified to take into account the "size effect" on the punching shear strength of slabs.</description><creator>Li, Kevin Ka Lun, 1975-</creator><contributor>Mitchell, Denis (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Influence of size on punching shear strength of concrete slabs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j300c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j6731581h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977w93c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Along with the essential importance of the metallurgical sector, one must recognise that it is also one of the largest sources of environmental pollution. In particular, the problem of electric arc furnace (EAF) dusts is of a growing concern due to the increase in popularity of EAF steelmaking. This dust is classified as a hazardous product due to the elevated content of toxic metals (e.g., Cr). Studies on the properties of EAF dusts are sparse. Experiments were performed in order to determine the chemical and physical characteristics of the dust. It was determined that EAF dust is constituted of randomly distributed agglomerations of homogeneously nucleated particles and entrained particles. The main elements present within the particular dust were iron and chromium, the latter due to the fact that the dust used was formed within a stainless steel mini-mill. The main phases present within the dust were Fe2O3/Fe 3O4 and Cr2O3. Thermal remediation experiments were then carried out in a computer controlled thermogravimetric system. The parameters studied during the tests included temperature, residence time and heating rate. In addition, the behaviour of the EAF dust during remediation was studied; in terms of weight and volume loss, gas evolution, particle morphology and resulting leachability of the treated product. Furthermore, it was observed that at temperatures greater than 1200°C metal leachability decreased significantly due to a decrease in toxic metal concentration within the treated product and the formation of a resistant, dense, plate-like morphology. At 1600°C, no toxic metals leached out of the remediated EAF dust and volume reduction was significant, resulting in a product that would be safe and more economical to landfill.</description><creator>D'Souza, Neil S.</creator><contributor>Szpunar, J. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Kozinski, J. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Thermal remediation of stainless steel electric arc furnace (EAF) dust</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j38608818.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977w93c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75df442</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis presents the analysis, based on velocity singularities, of the upswept finite span wings of various planforms and distributions of incidence. The method of velocity singularities has been first introduced by Mateescu for the analysis of the flow past airfoils, based on the singular behaviour of the fluid velocity near the leading edge and ridges. In this work, the method of velocity singularities is extended to determine the solution of the flow in the Trefftz plane normal to the uniform stream. Velocity singularities are used to obtain directly the complex expression of the perturbation velocity in the cross-flow coordinates. The spanwise variation of the circulation is obtained by integrating the real part of the complex conjugate velocity in the Trefftz plane, and then is related to the local intensity of the circulation on the wing. Two methods of solutions were developed, one applicable only for wings with symmetrical distribution of incidence, and a more general one applicable for both symmetrical and non-symmetrical distribution of incidence. Both methods have been validated by comparison with Carafoli's solutions for symmetrical wings. Then the more general method has been used to obtain solutions for various wings with non-symmetrical distribution of incidence, such as the case of wings with anti-symmetrically deflected ailerons. The method was proven to be more efficient and accurate than the comparable methods that are currently employed.</description><creator>Dziubinschi, Alexandru.</creator><contributor>Mateescu, Dan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><title>Analysis of finite span wings based on velocity singularities</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xb46s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75df442</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q6069</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work gathers theoretical and experimental evidence showing the feasibility of a computer vision system aimed at performing view-based recognition under space-variant conditions. An artificial retina preserving the essence of space-variant sensing while passing around some of its intrinsic difficulties is described and baptised the square-zone retina. A new bottom-up attentional scheme, the generic attentional scheme, is tailored to the properties of the square-zone retina. The attentional strategy is designed to assist visual learning tasks under uncontrolled illumination conditions. Recognition theories are the focus of a review describing the progressive emergence of the view-based concept. The basic idea of that concept is adapted to show experimentally the interpolation properties of new object representation. A review on trans-saccadic memory and integration, as well as insights gained experimentally, have guided the selection of the nature of the image features extracted to construct the object representation. Finally, (i) the square-zone retina, (ii) the generic attentional scheme, (iii) the adaptation of the view-based concept, and (iv) the object representation are bound together to demonstrate the feasibility of view-based recognition under space-variant conditions.</description><creator>Domercq, Alain.</creator><contributor>Clark, J. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>View-based recognition under space-variant conditions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h368g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q6069</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8s45qb71m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The behaviour of 10 spirally reinforced concrete columns and 5 plain concrete columns subjected to a concentric compressive load is investigated. The reinforced concrete columns were designed using the CSA A23.3-94 Standard. The experimental specimens were made of concretes with compressive strengths ranging from 35 MPa to 125 MPa. Two types of steel spiral reinforcement, Grade 400 and Grade 500, were used to investigate the ability of a higher yield strength steel to confine the concrete core. The response of the reinforced specimens is compared to predictions using a stress-strain model for confined concrete. The determination of the predicted response is based on the computation of a load-strain response using the effective confining stresses in the concrete core. The effects of the concrete compressive strength and the steel spiral tensile strength on the load-strain response are investigated. The peak loads of the spirally reinforced circular concrete columns are compared to the peak loads predicted by our current codes of practice. The response of the plain concrete columns with a wide range of specified compressive strengths are investigated. The peak loads of the plain concrete columns are predicted using various concrete stress-block factors provided by different codes.</description><creator>Da Silva, Pedro.</creator><contributor>Mitchell, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Effect of concrete strength on axial load response of circular columns</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w668p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qb71m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:12579v13f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The field of cultural studies is founded upon the belief that there are no essential (ahistorical or transhistorical) limits separating theory from practice. Thus, it rejects out of hand a central principle of the West's premodern tradition of thought, which held that political theory must always be tempered by a practical awareness of human nature. The move away from this older belief in natural limits is largely carried out in the name of diversity, a sincere wish to promote openness and tolerance toward the various ends that humans may choose to pursue. Unfortunately, this ground-clearing exercise runs into certain contradictions when it is realized that absolute tolerance can provide no consistent argument against its opposite, extreme intolerance. A more subtle effect of this tolerance, however---and one that I will argue is in evidence in much cultural studies research today---is the inability to ground important political decisions. This inability leads to what Stuart Hall has called a "formalization" of the field: unwilling to commit to a particular practical vision, theory becomes locked within a self-referential sphere, or limits itself to "low risk" practical discussions (e.g., the cultural implications of record collecting). This trend towards political ineffectuality, I argue, can only be moderated by subjecting cultural studies' deepest assumptions concerning human nature to philosophical doubt. Following the argument of Leo Strauss, I propose that the most radical challenge to the mainstream of current thought is found in premodern writings. Thus, this thesis is at once a critique of the "present-mindedness" that I have witnessed in cultural studies and a limited defense of past thought.</description><creator>Staring, Scott Patrick.</creator><contributor>Szanto, George (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Culture -- Study and teaching.</subject><subject>Culture -- Philosophy.</subject><title>Cultural studies and the challenge of past thought</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354h17x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579v13f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r746h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The conflict between adat law and Islamic law is still a current issue in today's Indonesia. It is rendered even more controversial because it deals with the spheres of family law, marriage law and the inheritance system in particular. This is exacerbated by the fact that Indonesia is home to such a wide variety of social systems. Family structure patterns range from patriarchy to matriarchy and every shade between, with each system being supported by a nexus of indigenous or adat laws. To complete the confusion, there is the residual influence of Dutch policy. Of the many attempts that have been made to resolve the situation, the contribution of Hazairin (1906--1975) deserves particular attention. Realizing that fiqh or Islamic law is the product of another place and time, he sought to accommodate it more to the realities of Indonesian Muslim society. For him this meant abandoning the Dutch legacy of privileging adat law over Islamic law, and replacing it with what he called a "bilateral system," based primarily on the Qur'an and ḥadith. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Sugiono, Sukiati.</creator><contributor>Federspiel, Howard M. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Hallag, Wael B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Hazairin, 1906-1975.</subject><subject>Adat law -- Indonesia.</subject><subject>Islamic law -- Indonesia.</subject><title>Islamic legal reform in twentieth century Indonesia : a study of Hazairin's thought</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h369r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r746h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sj14k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study opens with an exploration of the philosophical theories of two recognized scholars in the field of religious education with a view to providing a basis or jumping-off-point from which to present what the author sees as a development of a more advanced and freeing procedure for the religious development of the young. Thomas Groome proposes a Shared Praxis Approach to Christian religious education. He emphasizes the need for appropriation, by the student, of that which he calls the Christian Story. Sam Keen's stance is then examined wherein he contends that the basic Christian Story might well be supplanted as a shaper of personal identity by a growing, developmental autobiography. The third and closing section of the thesis allows the writer to expose a personal proposal towards a more effective approach to religious education for the young, and this for a lifetime. The new proposal focuses on an examination of each student's personal experience with that which we call God, experiences within the framework of the child's initial orientation and then, progressively taking into account other major religious orientations. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Strain, Alexander.</creator><contributor>Francoeur, Thomas A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Religious education of children.</subject><title>The importance of personal experience in religious education /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43p009v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sj14k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s429d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the effects of television and entertainment culture on American fiction. Focusing primarily on the novels of Don DeLillo and David Foster Wallace, with a secondary focus on the films of American film director David Lynch, the thesis proposes that post-postmodern fiction, fiction in which the familiarizing trends of postmodern fiction are reversed, is a response to the powerful influence of television and other forms of electronic media on American culture.</description><creator>Stewart, Robert Earl.</creator><contributor>Ohlin, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Television -- Social aspects.</subject><subject>American fiction -- 20th century -- History and criticism.</subject><title>The catastrophe of entertainment : televisuality and post-postmodern American fiction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w932n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s429d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bw403</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores the thought of a prominent Indian Muslim thinker, Asghar Ali Engineer, on liberation theology and the status of women in Islam. In his elaboration of liberation theology, Engineer demonstrates that from its inception, Islam has sided with the oppressed and the weak. If it is interpreted from its theological as well as sociological context, he argues, Islam makes it clear that it promotes justice and equality. The juxtaposition of theological and sociological perspectives is crucial to any understanding of Engineer's thought on liberation theology. Such perspectives also inform Engineer's view of the status of women in Islam. Our discussion is limited to two of the topics addressed by Engineer: polygamy and the veil. The key to understand these issues, Engineer maintains, is by distinguishing between the 'normative' and 'contextual' statements of the Qur'anic text. The point of this distinction is to differentiate between those principles of the Qur'an which are universal in nature, i.e. values, which transcend beyond time and space, and the contextual ones which are only valid in particular situations and circumstances. In conclusion, Engineer's thought on liberation theology and women's issues are found to be liberal, critical and emancipative, successfully demonstrating that Islam sides with the weak and promotes justice and equality.</description><creator>Nuryatno, Muhammad Agus.</creator><contributor>Alvi, Sajida S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Muslim women.</subject><subject>Islam and justice.</subject><subject>Engineer, Asgharali, 1940-</subject><subject>Liberation theology.</subject><title>Asghar Ali Engineer's views on liberation theology and women's issues in Islam : an analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77ft31g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bw403</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52j9828</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Environmental education faces special challenges in areas of acute conflict over resource use. This thesis assesses the role of popular environmental education workshops carried out by an external non-governmental organization in a forest-based community in Morelos, Mexico. Factors investigated as possible influences on the impact of workshops included: the pedagogy employed; local perceptions of environmental problems; obstacles to participation; and motivations of participants. The research indicates that the potential role of environmental education for collective action is enhanced when workshops not only increase access to, and sharing of, relevant information, but encourage organizational capacity and inspiration through group work. Furthermore, environmental education must be relevant to major local concerns and forms of communication. Initial workshops on the forest have demonstrated local desire for community management to solve deforestation problems. A political ecology approach could be useful in workshops for in-depth analysis of the decision-making levels affecting the local environment.</description><creator>Oliver, Beatriz.</creator><contributor>Scott, Colin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Environmental education -- Mexico.</subject><title>Assessing participation in popular environmental education workshops : the case of Huitzilac, Morelos, Mexico</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j301n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j9828</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54kq04k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recent developments in environmental management (EM) in Trinidad and Tobago have produced several umbrella legislation and institutional reforms. Since their enactment in 1995, there are still questions about their efficacy and key issues of these are examined. A multi-variant, cross-comparison approach relates the new and existing EM strategies to recommended guidelines found in the literature and collected from local opinion. Environmental Impact Assessment (EIA) is used in tandem with EM, as it is the main tool of EM in Trinidad and Tobago. A case study of EIA application is used to assess the effectiveness of EIA and EM in Trinidad and Tobago. Recommendations for reform are made based on the analysis and the case study.</description><creator>Paddington, Luke.</creator><contributor>Meredith, Thomas (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Environmental management.</subject><title>An appraisal of environmental management in Trinidad and Tobago /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gf847.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kq04k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816p37r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The incest prohibition, though ostensibly "universal," has inspired a wide range of explanations and definitions both within and between cultures. Intense debate sprung up around the incest taboo during the matrimonially tumultuous reign of Henry VIII, leading to the great interest in this theme, which flourished on the Elizabethan and Jacobean stages. Although Shakespeare contributed a number of works to the incest canon, King Lear does not treat the incest motif overtly such that many critics have ignored its crucial role in that play. A synthetic theoretical approach is useful in exploring the wide-reaching implications of father-daughter love in Lear, which challenges the parameters of the incest prohibition. King Lear's effort to obstruct the marriage of Cordelia in the first scene constitutes a violation of the incest prohibition according to Levi-Strauss's notion of exogamy. To this violation, Cordelia contributes her belief that marriage requires only partial withdrawal of love from her father. Lear's unfulfilled love for his daughter Cordelia, whom he figures into wife and mother roles, exhibits oedipal traits and seeks gratification in Goneril and Regan. Lear experiences their "unnatural" refusal of his desires as emasculating sexual rejection, which manifests as the disease and guilt of transgression. He understands virtuous love as fatally tainted by sexual desire; the theme of love-as-death gains momentum. The tempest emerges as an agent of justice and punishment. Lear and Cordelia's reunion reasserts the themes of adulterous love and love-as-death, foreshadowing their shared death. Their subsequent capture introduces an expanded notion of the father-daughter relationship, including the possibility of conjugal love, which is consummated in their marriage in death.</description><creator>Hendricks, Shellee.</creator><contributor>Bristol, Michael D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Incest in literature.</subject><subject>Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616. King Lear.</subject><title>"The curiosity of nations" : King Lear and the incest prohibition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50gx98h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816p37r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wh896</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Return to my native land by Aime Cesaire is a poetic Notebook expressing the emotions of a West Indian coming back to his island. It is one of the founding texts of Negritude. The author is torn between two cultures, on one side his native Black land, Martinique, on the other the colonizer's, who gave him a French education, which predisposes him to a duality through his writing. Cesaire's writing is also influenced by different artistic movements that surround him. This thesis explores a subtle yet perceptible aspect, not normally apparent during one's reading of the Notebook: the voices. The land, the return, and the Negritude are three of the author's main preoccupations. These themes are expressed through voices in the text. After having explained this notion, the linear analysis will define their place in space and in time, coinciding with the chronology of the movements in the text. We will see the different modes of expression of the narrator, the fluctuation of tones, from cries, to anger, to tears, to exaltation which do not always belong to the oral domain. This work attempts to offer a new unrestrictive alternative to the reading of the Notebook.</description><creator>Horn, Michael Edward.</creator><contributor>Chapdelaine, Annik (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Césaire, Aimé. Cahier d'un retour au pays natal.</subject><title>La plurivocalité dans le "Cahier d'un retour au pays natal" d'Aimé Césaire /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612q549.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wh896</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591b24c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Purpose. The purpose was to examine venous PO2, transcutaneous tissue PO2 (PtcO 2), and VO2max in a normobaric environment following a single HBO2 treatment. Methods. Ten moderately trained (VO2max = 57.6 mL·kg-1·min -1) males volunteered for the study. Baseline testing included measures of VO2max, PtcO2, and anthropometry. Subjects received two HBO2 treatments, which consisted of breathing 95% oxygen at 2.5 ATA for 90 min. Following the first HBO2 treatment (6.0 +/- 1.0 min), subjects performed a VO2max test. Following the second HBO2 treatment, leg and chest PtcO2 and venous PO2 were monitored for 60 min. Results . VO2max, running time, and peak La were not altered (p &lt; 0.05) post-HBO2 treatment. Leg PtcO2 was lower (p &lt; 0.05) and chest PtcO2 was unchanged following the HBO2 treatment compared to baseline values. Venous PO2 was lower in the first 3 min post-HBO2 treatment than subsequent values, but no other differences were found (p &lt; 0.05). Conclusion. The results of this study show that a single HBO 2 treatment at 2.5 ATA for 90 min does not elevate venous PO2, PtcO2, or VO2max in a normobaric, normoxic environment.</description><creator>Hodges, Alastair N. H.</creator><contributor>Montgomery, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Exercise -- Physiological aspects.</subject><subject>Hyperbaric oxygenation.</subject><title>Effect of hyperbaric oxygen on venous PO2, transcutaneous PO2, and VO2max in a normobaric environment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sr89b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591b24c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s1784n54m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis highlights a new approach to the programs and agenda of the Shi`ite representative body in Lebanon known under the acronym AMAL. The period studied is from 1969--1984. Previous studies have drawn insufficient attention to the important and quintessentially Islamic relation between religion and politics for this particular community. This relation becomes a focal point for this thesis. Here, I study and tell the story of how a politically and socially marginalized sector of a society awakened unto itself and sought change in its political, social and economic position. This change involved a reaffirmation of specifically Shi`i doctrines, beliefs and motifs which helped this community assert themselves with a new identity during this fifteen year period.</description><creator>Herbert, Lise Jean.</creator><contributor>Boullata, Issa (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Lebanon -- Politics and government -- 1975-1990.</subject><subject>Shiites -- Lebanon -- Politics and government.</subject><subject>Islam and politics -- Lebanon.</subject><subject>Amal (Movement)</subject><title>From the supreme Islamic Shii council to AMAL : Shii politics in Lebanon from 1969-1984</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10ws213.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s1784n54m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d56zz46m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effects of sub-unit formation on adult listeners' ability to notice changes in a continuously changing timbre (with fixed fundamental frequency) were studied. In Experiment 1, reaction times were recorded when listeners were asked to detect a change in the timbre of a 5-sec sound with spectral content that gradually shifted across time producing a perceptual change from "dull" to "bright." Sixteen silences were inserted in some conditions to cause the formation of short units. Listeners noticed the change sooner in these conditions than when the transitions were unbroken or broken by loud noise bursts. Experiments 2 and 3 looked at the individual unit and considered two separate processes as possible explanations for the previous results. Process 1 accentuates stimulus properties present at moments of onset and offset. Process 2, instead, uses onsets and offsets to signal the beginnings and ends of units and reduces the change perceived within a unit. The former would imply that listeners made onset comparisons in a point-to-point manner, whereas the latter would imply that the onsets, which formed units, enabled a unit-to-unit comparison. In Experiments 2 and 3 listeners were asked to distinguish between 1-sec sounds that both started with Timbre 1 and ended with Timbre 2, but were different in their internal rates of timbral change. Listener's performance was significantly poorer when asked to distinguish between two sounds that had identical onset and offset information in comparison to their performance when asked to distinguish either the first halves or second halves of these, which would differ in onset or offset information. Evidence suggests the presence of both Process 1 and Process 2.</description><creator>Crum, Poppy.</creator><contributor>Bregman, Hilbert S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Audiometry.</subject><subject>Auditory perception.</subject><title>How does the formation of an auditory unit affect the perception of a changing timbre?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042v839.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zz46m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h415pc387</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Eye Movement Desensitization Reprocessing (EMDR) therapy has burst upon the psychotherapeutic scene as a time-limited, cost-contained, and efficacious treatment for anxiety, stress, and psychological trauma. Although this therapy has been pronounced as revolutionary by its inventor, Francine Shapiro, it has distinct historical precedents. The explanatory models of pathogenic memory and dissociation theory, and the reliance on mechanical inference for objectivity make EMDR therapy familiar and salient. Notions of suggestion and hypnosis, and the eye-movement component of therapy are presented as discontinuous with clinical and theoretical practice, in order to free them from the tainting associations of pseudo-science and quackery. By connecting the current EMDR movement with the conceptual and practical history of traumatic memory, dissociation, and suggestion, I argue that EMDR is not revolutionary. It is a powerful technology of the self, normalizing and valourizing certain ways of behaving and thinking. Shapiro's implicit assumptions that psychological suffering is pathological, and that early traumatic events are indelibly encoded, stored and dissociated in the brain are problematized. A brief commentary on the moral, political, and psychotherapeutic implications of EMDR therapy is provided.</description><creator>Cohen, Steven, 1973-</creator><contributor>Young, Allan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Eye movement desensitization and reprocessing.</subject><title>Eye movement desensitization and reprocessing (EMDR) : the making of a psychotherapy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dt989.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pc387</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zg428</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores twenty years of community based tourism policy and planning in the Baffin Region. This rise of local participation in tourism development is reviewed. Such an approach is seen as being potentially beneficial to marginalized aboriginal people in remote areas. This, combined with political support for Inuit self determination, formed the rationale behind community based tourism policy in Baffin. With its extensive community participation program, the planning process formed a strategy for sustainable tourism. Since then, the industry has grown but some of the strategy's goals have not been met. The number of Inuit involved in the industry initially increased, but is now beginning to decline and turnover is high. Interest in the industry, and initiatives such as training, need to arise from inside communities rather than the government. To complement traditional subsistence hunting, the tourism industry must support short term employment.</description><creator>Corless, Gillian.</creator><contributor>Wenzel, George (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Milne, Simon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Tourism -- Nunavut -- Baffin Island.</subject><subject>Ecotourism -- Nunavut -- Baffin Island.</subject><title>Community based tourism planning and policy : the case of the Baffin region, Nunavut</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s4305.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zg428</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pg15bg975</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The last years of the twentieth century have been characterized by an increased presence of women in Hispanic poetry, who inevitably brought forth a new poetic language. Typical of this new expression are the Spaniard Ana Rossetti and the Peruvian Rocio Silva Santisteban, who give free rein to their emotions and desires in their poetic texts, which reflect love as both eroticism and joyful sexuality. In their poetry the body becomes the instrument for the fulfillment of desire and the production of erotic states. Thus, love is despised almost innocently but through the use of Kitsch as pop songs and advertising slogans, love is rehabilitated and the pleasure-death relation is seen in multiple perspectives.</description><creator>Cossíos, Susana.</creator><contributor>Sibbald, K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Silva Santisteban, Rocío, 1963- -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Rossetti, Ana, 1950- -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Spanish poetry -- Women authors -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Kitsch in literature.</subject><title>El kitsch en la poesía femenina de los 90 : Ana Rossetti y Rocío Silva Santisteban</title><language>spa</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708z69r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bg975</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Hispanic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z708z71s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The amaNdzundza are a South African abaNtu people. This thesis sets forth to determine the role of their world (in the Heideggerian sense) as it impacts on their Architecture. First the evolutionary process of the amaNdzundza architecture is established. An infinite series of memes (much like genes) that function both on an intra- and inter-cultural level govern this process. Next, the cultural interaction of the amaNdzundza over a period of half a millenium are mapped (and a space-time matrix drawn up: ch.3), as to find the sources of introduction on an intercultural level. Finally, the architecture of the amaNdzundza milieu, both of their settlements and of the cultures with which they shared their environment, is analyzed and a sample of memes identified, which best illustrate the meme-exchange and evolution. This is done in a structure comprising the analysis of selected religious spatial incentives, and some aspects and elements of the settlement, the dwelling and the mural. A summary is given of the memes involved in the amaNdzundza architecture, and their evolutionary dynamics and origins. The researcher thus concludes that, rather than a singular factor such as the patronage of apartheid, the cultural 'memes' in the amaNdebele ya amaNdzundza milieu played the predominant role in the shaping of their existential, spatial and structural dwelling, through a process of 'loci meme' evolution.</description><creator>Fourie, Morne.</creator><contributor>Bhatt, Vikram (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Vernacular architecture -- Africa, Southern.</subject><subject>Memetics.</subject><subject>Ndebele (African people) -- Dwellings.</subject><title>Mêmes in amaNdzundza architecture</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655j50r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708z71s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p2676x575</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:02:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bamboo has been one of the most important housing materials for families of all income-levels for generations in many parts of the world. Through an analysis of methods of construction used for housing in the coffee region of Colombia, this thesis investigates the most important features of the use of bamboo in the traditional and modern techniques used to build walls, floors and structures. In conducting this research I collected extensive graphic material such as pictures, sketches, drawings and plans, from old and new town houses, rural houses, haciendas, and slums, in the three main regions of Colombia, where bamboo is the most important natural resource for construction. The first part of the study gives a general overview of construction systems for walls, floors and structures in housing using bamboo throughout the world, especially in Asia and America. The second part is a study of one of the three regions in Colombia where environment, its preservation, and its sustainability are the main issues, and it contains an analysis of the data collected from the three regions. The main part of the thesis classifies and analyses new techniques and systems that are applied in the construction of walls, floors and structures in the region of Old Caldas, Colombia.</description><creator>Gonzalez, Cesar O.</creator><contributor>Bhatt, Vikram (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Architecture -- Columbia -- Caldas (Dept.) -- Case studies.</subject><subject>Caldas (Columbia : Dept.) -- Buildings, structures, etc. -- Case studies.</subject><subject>Bamboo construction -- Columbia -- Caldas (Dept.) -- Case studies.</subject><title>The use of bamboo in architecture : case study : Old Caldas, Colombia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f785h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676x575</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40300</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>