<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:31:04Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):23350" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t281s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A laboratory threshing unit was constructed utilising a standard tangential feed ("conventional") combine cylinder, concave, beater and transition grate. This unit was used to study the phenomenon of corn cob break-up and its effect on the performance of the threshing unit. It was found that the degree of corn cob break-up was affected by cylinder peripheral speed, cylinder-concave clearance and hybrid cultivar. Within the hybrid cultivars used, increased cob break-up was associated with decreased shelling efficiency and concave separation efficiency. The possibility of reducing kernel damage and increasing concave separation efficiency by changing some of the concave design parameters was investigated. A mathematical model of the tangential feed threshing unit was developed and used to investigate the effect of the concave design parameters. Experimental data indicated that kernel damage may be reduced by at least 24 per cent and concave separation efficiency increased by at least 38 per cent.</description><creator>Wall, Gavin Lindsay.</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Combines (Agricultural machinery)</subject><subject>Threshing machines</subject><subject>Corncobs</subject><subject>Corn -- Shelling</subject><title>Performance of a tangential feed threshing cylinder as affected by corn cob break-up and concave design parameters.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s103w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t281s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gh22b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The genetics and epigenetics of cortisone-induced cleft palate in the mouse have been examined. The SW/Fr strain, in which 6% of newborns have a cleft palate in the absence of treatment, has the greatest reactivity to cortisone of any strain tested so far and closes it palate comparatively late in development. After cortisone treatment, the mean of the distribution on palate closure stage is shifted towards later gestational ages without changing the variance. The genetic basis for the DBA/2-C57BL/6 difference in susceptibility to cortisone-induced cleft palate is relatively simple. One dominant gene on chromosome 5 contributes predominantly to the strain difference in susceptibility, but the embryonic response appears also to be influenced by genes on the X chromosome. The H-2 haplotype does not affect the cortisone-induced cleft palate response in the two congenic strains C57BL/10 (B10) and B10.A by altering the stage of palate closure.</description><creator>Vekemans, Michael John Jacques.</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Cleft palate -- Genetic aspects.</subject><subject>Mice -- Genetics.</subject><title>Genetics and epigenetics of cortisone-induced cleft palate in the mouse</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g101b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gh22b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s336m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Using a photoplethysmograph, vaginal blood volume (VBV) and pulse pressure (VPP) responses of 53 women volunteers were compared and related to immediate self-reports of either sexual or genital arousal. The responses were examined across a sequence of experimental phases and, in one of these phases as a function of high or low erotic stimulus intensity. Results indicated that both physiological and subjective responses were specifically affected by the erotic stimuli. After these stimuli VPP and subjective responses returned to prestimulation levels whereas VBV did not. Intensity of erotic stimulus affected subjective responses but not the physiological responses. Correlations between the measures indicated that VBV and VPP were moderately well correlated at all times but became more so during the high intensity erotic stimulus and when physiological responses were strong. The correlation between physiological and subjective responses was also enhanced during the erotic stimulus phase as a function of both erotic stimulus intensity and strength of physiological response. Following the erotic stimuli, subjective reports of declining arousal were still strongly correlated with VPP but not with VBV. Results were discussed in terms of the nature of the haemodynamic system underlying changes in blood flow and the possible mechanism by which women detect such changes. Four factors shown to influence the correlation between physiological response and self-report (i.e. response change, physiological response strength, particular physiological response, and erotic stimulus intensity) were discussed in terms of this process, and in terms of cognitive variables which may affect subjective judgments of sexual arousal. Methodological and statistical implications of this research were examined, as well as implications for the clinical assessment of female sexual arousal.</description><creator>Harris, Ronald George.</creator><date>1980</date><subject>Women -- Sexual behavior.</subject><subject>Sexual excitement.</subject><title>Relationships among human vaginal blood volume, pulse pressure, and self-report of arousal as a function of erotic stimulation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33rx54v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s336m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gp154</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Spirit cults constitute an important element of Brazilian society. One of these, Umbanda, has in recent decades achieved prominence nationally. A historical survey of cult groups in Manaus shows that although they have always been in a state of change, they have recently been experiencing a period of accelerated transformation under the influence of Umbanda. This study documents the development of Umbanda in Manaus. This is done in two steps. First, by analyzing the history of Umbanda it becomes evident that it has not only amalgamated a number of religious traditions, but still today continues to encompass numerous regional cults. Several authors suggest that urbanization and industrialization have advanced the spread of Umbanda. This thesis shows that while this is indeed the case, the integration of Umbanda beliefs and practices into the cult life of the region is effected by a particular form of mediumistic trance. As a second step, an analysis of trance as a dynamic feature of Umbanda reveals how this occurs. The trance forms the pivotal point of communicative events in Umbanda; it gives rise to a special form of leadership based on the communications of the spirits and which functions through a medium's or leader's manipulation of "public" (generally accepted) and "private" (personal) elements of cult knowledge. Because it gives a central position to innovation and individual elaboration, the Umbanda trance form allows full freedom for the incorporation of practices from local cult groups. The resulting process of mutual assimilation between regional cults and Umbanda holds implications for cultists both as individuals and as members of a socio-economic group.</description><creator>Gabriel, Chester E.</creator><date>1980</date><subject>Cults -- Brazil -- Manaus.</subject><subject>Umbanda (Cult)</subject><title>Communications of the spirits : Umbanda, regional cults in Manaus and dynamics of mediumistic trance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qm85h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gp154</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:js956g80m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigated the immunological aspects of Entamoeba histolytica infection in Syrian hamsters. Immunization of hamsters by an intradermal injection with live axenic amoebae, conferred complete protection against amoebic liver abscess. Protection was achieved with homologous or heterologous strains of E. histolytica and was dose-dependent. Combination of thymectomy and anti T-cell serum treatment significantly increased the size of liver abscess and metastatic dissemination of the parasite. It was shown that a cell-mediated immune response controls the healing of skin ulcers in vaccinated animals and thus confers on them resistance to intrahepatic amoebic challenge infection. Resistance to hepatic infection with E. histolytica can be passively transferred to normal recipients with sensitized cells, but not with immune serum. Sensitized cells from vaccinated, protected or infected animal kill E. histolytica trophozoites in vitro. Splenectomy reduces the resistance of hamsters to amoebic infection. It is suggested that macrophages are required in the host defence against the establishment of amoebic abscess in the liver and dissemination of amoebae to other organs.</description><creator>Ghadirian, Esfandiar.</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Cellular immunity</subject><subject>Amebiasis -- Vaccination.</subject><subject>Amebiasis</subject><title>Studies on the protective immunity against hepatic amoebiasis in the hamster.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67js02k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956g80m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225b94v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The synthesis of novel nucleoside and nucleotide analogues in which the sugar moiety is replaced by an aliphatic chain is described. The acyclic analogue of adenosine was tested as both a substrate and an inhibitor of adenosine deaminase while the interaction of some dinucleoside monophosphate analogues with spleen and snake venom phosphodiesterase is reported. Some mention is made of the solution conformation of these acyclic derivatives. The utility of the methyl group as a phosphate protecting group in oligonucleotide synthesis was reinvestigated and the preparation of some interesting 2', 5' linked trinucleoside diphosphate analogues of adenosine, with the methyl moiety as phosphate masking group, was undertaken. A novel approach to the cleavage of phosphate methyl esters is discussed. A facile fluoride ion mediated preparation of alkylated nucleoside base fragments was discovered. This procedure led to high isolated yields of a variety of N-alkylated purines and pyrimidines.</description><creator>Gillen, Michael Francis.</creator><date>1980</date><subject>Nucleotides.</subject><subject>Nucleosides.</subject><title>Synthesis and properties of novel nucleoside and nucleotide analogues : a thesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603qz316.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225b94v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816n368</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The influence of 4, 5 and 6 generations of selection for duration of fertility of frozen-thawed chicken semen on fertility and hatchability of frozen-thawed semen, fertility of fresh semen, semen volume, concentration of spermatozoa, spermatozoal motility and on spermatozoa and seminal plasma cholesterol and phospholipid levels and their ratios (generations 5 and 6) as well as the genetic influence on these traits was studied. A selected line and an unselected control line of broiler chickens were used. All estimates of fertility of frozen-thawed and fresh semen were significantly (P 0.05). The heritabilities of fertility of frozen-thawed and fresh semen and semen characteristics were generally low and those for spermatozoa lipid levels and their ratios were generally medium. The positive phenotypic correlations between estimates of fertility within frozen-thawed and fresh semen were high but low between fertility of frozen-thawed and fresh semen. The phenotypic correlations between semen characteristics and fertility were inconsistent. The phenotypic correlations of spermatozoa and seminal plasma cholesterol with fertility of frozen-thawed semen were negative as were the phenotypic correlations of seminal plasma cholesterol with fertility of fresh semen. Genetic correlations were also calculated and were similar in direction to the phenotypic correlations but their magnitudes exceeded unity in many cases. The level of inbreeding was uncorrelated with either fertility, semen characteristics, spermatozoa and seminal plasma lipids or their ratios.</description><creator>Ansah, George Ackah</creator><date>1980</date><subject>Agriculture, Animal Culture and Nutrition.</subject><title>The influence of six generations of selection for fertility of frozen-thawed semen in the fowl on fertility, semen characteristics and semen cholesterol and phospholipid levels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vr732.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816n368</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75r874m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Some physicochemical properties of several series of transition metal chalcocarbonyls such as ((eta)('6)-C(,6)H(,6))Cr(CO)(,2)(CX) and Cr(CO)(,5)(CX) (X = O, S, Se) have been investigated. In particular, the infrared, ('13)C and ('17)O nuclear magnetic resonance and ultraviolet spectra have been examined. The results show that the order of (sigma)-donor and (pi)-acceptor capabilities of the ligands is CO CS. The M((pi)) (---&gt;) CX((pi)*) ultraviolet charge-transfer bands are shown to correlate with the respective (mu)'(,MCX) and ('13)C NMR data. Also, the ('13)C NMR chemical shifts and GQVFF force constants are found to be highly correlated. The ('17)O NMR spectra of the metal chalcocarbonyl complexes display chemical shifts in the opposite direction to the corresponding ('13)C ones. No correlation is found between the ('17)O shieldings and the other spectroscopic data. Reaction of Cr(CO)(,5)(CX) (X = S, Se) with halide ions (Y('-)) afforded mixtures of {Cr(CO)(,5)Y}('-) and trans-{Cr(CO)(,4)(CX)Y}('-) while Cr(CO)(,5)(CS) reacted with cyclohexylamine to give Cr(CO)(,5)(CNC(,6)H(,11)). The similarities and differences in the physicochemical behaviour of the metal chalcocarbonyls compared to related systems are discussed in the light of the different bonding patterns.</description><creator>Baibich, Ione Maluf.</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy.</subject><subject>Carbonyl compounds.</subject><subject>Ultraviolet spectroscopy.</subject><title>Infrared intensity and nuclear magnetic resonance studies of some group VIB metal chalcocarbonyl complexes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945r66r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75r874m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:05741s597</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The variations of soil mechanical properties, cohesion, c, internal friction angle, (phi), soil-rubber adhesion, c(,r)', soil-steel adhesion, c(,s)', soil-steel friction angle, (delta)(,s), soil-rubber friction angle, (delta)(,r), the sinkage moduli, kc, k(phi), and n, have been studied under field conditions for different soil depths of sandy loam and clay soils. Models to predict these parameters were developed in this study. These models were functions of soil moisture content, soil plastic limit or liquid limit and two constants which depend on the soil type and depth. Also, a model to estimate the soil moisture content by a simple and accurate method was developed using the data of daily precipitation and evaporation pan reading (class A) in southern Quebec. The soil mechanical properties models were used to study the traction characteristics of lugged tires. The investigation shows that lug design could have a significant role in improving the traction force for agricultural tires. The optimal lug angle was found for different soil types during the farming season in an average climatic year of southern Quebec.</description><creator>Ali Hassan, Omar Soliman.</creator><date>1980</date><subject>Engineering, Agricultural.</subject><title>Modelling of the soil mechanical properties to soil moisture conditions and their applications to study the traction developed by lugged tires</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278t93k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741s597</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60cx24z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation analyzes melodrama as a common mode of mid-nineteenth century cultural expression. The dissertation centres on the melodrama in Bulwer Lytton's novels, emphasizing Lytton's use of melodrama as a form of radical social criticism. The first novels expose contemporary social inequities, but employ melodramatic techniques sparingly. Later, Lytton shows complete understanding of the melodramatic method and the 'political' basis of melodrama, resulting in novels such as Paul Clifford and Night and Morning. Other novels, though, display, uneasiness with the one-sided analysis of life presented in melodrama, while Zanoni attacks the naivety of melodramatic social criticism. Most of the last novels condemn melodrama for its simple-mindedness, or falsification of human experiences. In addition, 'reactionary' novels such as The Parisians reject the radical social vision of melodrama as neither attainable nor desirable.</description><creator>Aviss, Julian Price.</creator><date>1980</date><subject>English drama -- 19th century -- Social aspects.</subject><subject>Melodrama -- History -- 19th century.</subject><subject>Lytton, Edward Bulwer Lytton, Baron, 1803-1873 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>The melodramatic mode, and melodrama as social criticism in the novels of Bulwer Lytton : from radical to conservative</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dq52b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cx24z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vc27c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A study of heat transfer to tubes in the freeboard region of a fluidized bed was conducted in a column of cross section 0.254 m x 0.432 m and height 3.00 m. The operating variables covered included superficial gas velocity (up to 1.7 m/s), average particle diameter (102, 470, and 890 (mu)m), height of the instrumented tube above the expanded bed surface (up to 0.6 m), horizontal tube spacing, position of tube within the tube bundle, and number of tubes. Silica sand particles were fluidized by air in all experimental runs. An instrumented oil-cooled tube of outer diameter 25.4 mm was used to collect heat transfer data. Heat transfer coefficients to tubes in the freeboard were found to be significantly influenced by the superficial gas velocity, average particle diameter, and height of the tube above the expanded bed surface. The heat transfer coefficient increased with increasing superficial gas velocity and decreasing distance between the tube and the bed surface due to increased impingement of particles on the tube. The heat transfer coefficient for a tube in the freeboard was found to increase with decreasing particle size as for immersed tubes. The effects of horizontal tube spacing and single tube versus bundle were found to be small, less than 20%, over the range of experimental conditions investigated. Values of heat transfer coefficients for a tube in the splash zone, in the immediate vicinity of the expanded bed, are nearly as favourable as for immersed tubes. The high rates of heat transfer are associated with impingement of particles on the heat transfer tube. The experimental results are in qualitative agreement with the few data available in the literature. The present experimental data were correlated in a form suitable for design purposes. The correlation approaches limits at low and high heights above the expanded bed surface. At the bed surface, heat transfer coefficients correspond to in-bed values. Heat transfer coefficients for tubes far removed from the bed surface correspond to dilute phase suspension or to air alone in cross flow, depending on particle size. The correlation fits the data obtained in this work to within (+OR-) 12%. Entrainment rates for the finest silica sand particles were measured with and without tubes in the freeboard. Under conditions of the present experimental work, entrainment rates were affected very little by the presence of tubes in the freeboard. The entrainment rates were compared with entrainment correlations available in the literature. There were substantial differences between data and almost all of the correlations. Fair agreement was obtained with the Zenz and Weil correlation for saturation carrying capacity. Hydrodynamics of bed and particles motion around tubes were also investigated visually, photographically and by means of pressure profiles. The information obtained was helpful in explaining the heat transfer results.</description><creator>George, Safa Edward</creator><date>1980</date><subject>Fluidization.</subject><subject>Heat -- Transmission.</subject><title>Heat transfer to tubes in the freeboard region of a fluidized bed</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rv36s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vc27c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j96021655</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Rb-Sr studies of the Sept Iles anorthosite complex show that it was emplaced during the Cambrian and that it is unrelated to the Grenville province. The age of this complex is very similar to that of other igneous rocks associated with the St. Lawrence graben system. Both the acidic and basic components of the complex have similar ages and originated from magmas with similar, low('87) Sr/('86) Sr initial ratios. There is no evidence that crustal contamination played an important role in the generation of the acidic magmas. The earliest rocks of the complex exposed at Sept Iles are now observed on the mainland. They consist of cumulates rich in oxide minerals, mafic minerals and plagioclase. These rocks are thought to have been formed at the base of the complex. Further south, across the fault that defines the St. Lawrence graben in this area, the top of the complex is exposed on six islands and Presque-Ile Marconi. This part of the complex is thought to have formed by multiple injection of the magma differentiating at depth in the main chamber into the already solidified roof of the complex. Plagioclase cumulates, the earliest rocks exposed here, are cut by later, more differentiated gabbros. Syenite commonly overlies the basic rocks and is in turn overlain by granite. Geochemical and petrographic evidence indicate that the syenite was intruded as a magma and was not formed by accumulation of perthite precipitated from the granite. Geochemical studies show that all the rocks exposed at Sept Iles could have been formed by differentiation of a single gabbroic magma.</description><creator>Higgins, Michael Denis.</creator><date>1979</date><subject>Anorthosite -- Québec (Province) -- Sept Iles.</subject><title>Age and origin of the Sept Iles anorthosite complex, Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf2686035.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j96021655</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074v97j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the extrusion blow molding process, the behaviour of the parison prior to inflation is of central importance. Properties of the finished article, such as wall thickness and thickness uniformity, are determined by the simultaneous phenomena of swell and sag. In the present study, an apparatus was built to study the behaviour of the extrudate from an annular die under isothermal conditions. First, sag was eliminated by extruding into an oil bath, and both thickness and diameter swell were determined as functions of time. Then, extruding into heated air, sag behaviour was observed. These procedures allowed the study of the individual contributions of swell and sag to the overall parison behaviour. Three high density polyethylene resins and a polypropylene resin were studied. The materials were thoroughly characterized to obtain the traditional rheological properties. In addition, an extensional rheometer was modified to measure the viscosity under uniaxial extension. A model to predict the total length of the parison at any given time is proposed. This model is expressed in terms of rheological properties of the materials and process variables only.</description><creator>García-Rejón, Andrés.</creator><date>1979</date><subject>Polymers.</subject><subject>Rheology.</subject><title>Behaviour of molten polyolefins extruded from an annular die</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k585f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074v97j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj4305673</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Interaction between rigid and flexible track-grouser systems with a clay soil is examined in order to obtain a better understanding of the manner in which energy is transferred and dissipated in the bearing soil substrate. Analytical framework is developed for the establishment of the kind of mechanisms involved in this interaction with a view to obtaining a rational prediction of track-soil performance. The method of visioplasticity is used to determine the specific participants contributing to the expenditure of energy at different soil levels beneath a simple representative multiple grouser element. Subsoil reponse behaviour and dissipated energy components are investigated for different grouser shapes, spacings, displacements, and flexibility boundary conditions. A predictive model is established for the off-road track performance prediction based on the principle of energy conservation for the entire track/grouser-soil system. This energetic model provides successful predictions which are in good agreement with the experimentally measured performance of a full track model at various degrees of slip.</description><creator>Elmamlouk, Hussein H.</creator><date>1980</date><subject>Soil mechanics.</subject><title>Energy analysis and prediction of track-soil interaction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gd86k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj4305673</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547s291</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Amba Dongar carbonatite complex, India is host to a large fluorite deposit. The complex consists of a small ring structure comprised of early carbonatite breccia, a large, outer lining of calcitite and a number of small ankeritic carbonatite plugs. Surrounding the carbonatite ring are numerous plugs of nephelinitic and phonolitic syenites. The complex was intruded into Late Cretaceous Bagh Sandstones and Late to Early Paleocene Deccan Volcanics. The hydrothermal history of the complex is extensive, consisting of two main systems, the first resulted in large amounts of fenitization, causing extensive K and Na metasomatism of the surrounding sandstones and the second, dealt with here, was responsible for the silicification of large amounts of the calcitite and the deposition of economic quantities of fluorite. The deposit consists of veins and vug fillings of blue, purple, white, yellow and colorless fluorite. The main ore zone, which is currently under production, and most other showings, are found near the carbonatite-sandstone contact. Chemical analyses and mass balance calculations show that the fluids responsible for silicification removed significant quantities of Ca from the rock while adding large amounts of Si, Al and F. Alteration associated with fluorite deposition involved the removal of Al from the rock and the addition of large quantities of F and Si. Fluid inclusions in fluorite point to a low temperature-low salinity ore fluid, which decreased in temperature and salinity with evolution. Crushing experiments performed on fluid inclusions in both fluorite and quartz reveal the presence of ${ approx0.08}$ m of dissolved CO$ sb2$ in solution while analyses of leachates and decrepitate residues from fluid inclusions show significant concentrations of Ca, Al, Na, Cl and S in their fluids. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Palmer, David A. S.</creator><contributor>Williams-Jones, A. E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Geology.</subject><subject>Geochemistry.</subject><title>Geology and Geochemistry of the Amba Dongar carbonatite-hosted fluorite deposit, India</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rp47t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547s291</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h415pb28s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of the present study was to identify the muscle and kinematic parameters associated with the emergence of a skilled organization of landing from a jump in boys 7 years to 13 years of age. Jumps were videotaped (60Hz) in the right sagittal plane. The digitized coordinates of six landmarks were used to calculate the angular position, velocity, and acceleration parameters for the hip, knee, and ankle joints. Surface EMG signals were recorded for six muscles (Tibialis Anterior, Lateral Gastrocnemius, Soleus, Vastus Lateralis, Rectus Femoris, Biceps Femoris) to obtain the pattern of muscle onsets in anticipation for landing and the modulation of the muscle activity during the impact phase. Subjects could be classified into three distinct groups based on the pattern of muscle onsets: the Proximal-distal group (PDS), the Transitional group (TS), and the Adult group (AS). The classification reflected a progression from a proximal-distal (PDS) to a distal-proximal (AS) organization of landing. At the muscular level, the progression was associated with: (1) an increased contribution of the ankle to the anticipatory control of landing; and (2) the modulation of muscle activity to reduce the impact ground reaction forces. The strongest kinematic correlates were associated with the increased ability: (1) to manage and organize motion-dependent torques; (2) to critically modulate the joint position in anticipation of landing, and (3) to utilize anticipatory muscle activity rather than biomechanical joint limits to manage the impact ground reaction forces.</description><creator>Pelland, Lucie</creator><contributor>McKinley, P. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><title>Control strategies for landing from a jump-down in boys 7 to 13 years of age : muscle and kinematic parameters which optimize postlanding stability</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r877f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pb28s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053g93z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to investigate the results of two long-term fertilization experiments on soil organic C, total N, and mineralizable N in the Jiangsu Province of People's Republic of China. The soil samples that received manure over the years contained more soil organic C, and total N than the inorganic fertilized samples. Soil organic C was closely correlated with total N and there were correlations between crop yields and soil organic C contents and between crop yields and soil total N contents. Plant-available N was estimated using biological and chemical tests. Mineralized N formed under anaerobic incubation was low except for those soil samples that received manure. Microbial biomass C and N were estimated using the chloroform fumigation-incubation method (CFIM) and fumigation-extraction procedures. Biomass measurements by CFIM were more precise and reliable than values obtained by fumigation-extraction. Treatment differences in biomass were not significant. Estimates of biomass C and N were influenced by the choice of the control soil and the period of incubation used by the CFIM. Unfumigated (10-20 d) control soils were found to be the best control for samples. Extraction of mineralized N using O.5M NaHCO$ sb3$ after incubation overestimated biomass N since this extraction was found to extract non-biomass N.</description><creator>Ouimet, Nicole</creator><contributor>MacKenzie, A. F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Fertilizers -- China -- Kiangsu Province</subject><subject>Soil microbiology -- China -- Kiangsu Province.</subject><subject>Manures -- China -- Kiangsu Province</subject><subject>Soils -- China -- Kianygsu Province</subject><subject>Soils -- Nitrogen content -- China -- Kiangsu Province</subject><title>Laboratory measurements of soil microbial biomass and nitrogen mineralization from two Chinese soils as influenced by long-term applications of manure and inorganic fertilizers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vh61x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053g93z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10wr12x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this study was to assess tree species influence on forest floor fertility in a mixed forest stand using Redundancy Analysis (RDA). Eighty microsites were located in a beech-hemlock-red maple forest. Forest floor was analyzed for thirteen variables; total N, P, K, Ca and Mg, extractable Ca, Mg and K, mineralizable N (NH$ sb{4+}$), basal microbial respiration (CO$ sb2$), pH, thickness and bulk density. The influence of seven tree species was calculated as a function of tree diameter and distance from each microsite. Spatial patterns were detected by using correlograms and incorporated in a variation-partitioning model with trend surface analysis. Tree species, microtopography, and spatial structure explained 53% of the total variation in forest floor data. The fraction explained by tree species alone (16%) was studied with a RDA ordination biplot. The main source of variation in the soil data was related mainly to the opposite effects of American beech and eastern hemlock on calcium while most of the other species had a beneficial effect on soil fertility. This study showed the potential of RDA as a tool for studying the role of tree species in mixed forests.</description><creator>Pelletier, Bernard, 1964-</creator><contributor>Fyles, James W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Forest litter.</subject><subject>Soil fertility</subject><subject>Forest soils.</subject><title>A multivariate analysis of tree species influence on forest floor fertility /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161711z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wr12x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:41687j348</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The NT/NN precursor molecule possesses four lysine-arginine dibasic residues which represent potential sites of cleavage by proteolytic maturation enzymes. The aim of the present study was to identify immunohistochemically the regional, cellular and subcellular localization of the various polypeptide intermediates resulting from the precursor's intraneuronal processing and to attempt to determine which enzymes are involved in this processing. We have used site specific antibodies directed against NT, against the exposed KLPLVL(K6L) and EKEEVI(E6I) sequences of the precursor as well as against the PC1 and PC2 maturation enzymes. E6I and K6L immunoreactivity was essentially confined to nerve cell bodies and terminals in areas displaying NT immunoreactivity. In the absence of colchicine pre-treatment, the NT and E6I immunostained perikarya remained sparse throughout, whereas those with K6L were virtually undetectable. By contrast, terminal immunostaining was intense for both NT and E6I in most regions examined, with K6L remaining consistently weaker except in the globus pallidus where both the E6I and the K6L immunoreactive arbors were more widespread than those of NT. In double labeling experiments, E6I and K6L antigens were found to be present in the same cells as NT, indicating that even if it is quantitatively different among brain regions, the basic pattern of NT/NN precursor processing remains qualitatively similar throughout the brain. At the subcellular level, a granular pattern of NT and E6I immunofluorescence was distributed throughout the cytoplasm of the perikarya and proximal dendrites. Comparative analysis of the distribution of PC1 and PC2 with that of NT revealed only a partial overlap of the three markers in the rat CNS. Immunoreactivity for both PC1 and PC2 was mainly concentrated in nerve cell bodies and dendritic processes. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Lafortune, Louise</creator><contributor>Beaudet, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Maturation of the neurotensinneuromedin N precursor in the central nervous system of the rat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rf467.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687j348</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n870zr60r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Time domain reflectometry (TDR) is becoming a widely used method to determine volumetric soil water content ($ theta$) and bulk soil electrical conductivity (EC$ sb{ rm a}$). It has been found that the $ theta$ and EC$ sb{ rm a}$ values obtained by this method, on certain soils, require calibration. The purpose of this study was to monitor the effects of soil texture (most particularly the clay type and clay content) on $ theta$ and EC$ sb{ rm a}$ estimated by TDR. Water content was measured, gravimetrically and by TDR, on packed columns of nine soil mixtures, composed of three clay types (Hydrite, Bentonite, and Ste. Rosalie clay) and coarse sand at three levels (8, 16, and 30% by weight) of these clay materials. Three replicates of each mixture (a total of 27 columns) were made to statistically establish the effect of the clay type and the clay content on $ theta$ and EC$ sb{ rm a}$ readings by TDR. It was found that the TDR overestimated $ theta$ for the Hydrite and Ste. Rosalie (Natural) materials but accurately predicted for the Bentonite materials, compared to gravimetric determinations. Bulk soil electrical conductivity was simultaneously measured by two independent techniques, TDR and 4-probe, on the same soils. It was found that the clay types and clay contents have almost equal effects on the EC$ sb{ rm a}$ as measured by TDR and 4-probe techniques. It was found that the estimated EC$ sb{ rm a}$ values obtained by TDR and 4-probe methods for the fine-textured Bentonite materials were lower than those for the Hydrite and Ste. Rosalie materials at equal $ theta$ and EC$ sb{ rm W}$ (electrical conductivity of soil water).</description><creator>Liaghat, Abdolmajid</creator><contributor>Broughton, B. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Clay.</subject><subject>Soils -- Electric properties.</subject><subject>Soil moisture.</subject><subject>Time-domain reflectometry.</subject><title>Effect of clay type and clay content on moisture content and bulk soil electrical conductivity as measured using time domain reflectometry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f430j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zr60r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gf06g360p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recently, there has been a dramatic increase in the use of scale invariance in the study of geophysical fields. However, very little attention has been paid to the anisotropy that is invariably present in these fields, in the form of stratification, differential rotation, texture and morphology. In order to account for scaling anisotropy, the formalism of Generalized Scale Invariance (GSI) was developed. Until now, only a single analysis technique has been developed which incorporates this formalism and which can be used to study the differential rotation of fields. Using a two-dimensional representation of the linear approximation to GSI, a new, greatly improved, technique for quantifying anisotropic scale invariance in geophysical fields is developed: the Scale Invariant Generator technique (SIG). The ability of the technique to yield valid estimates is tested by performing the analysis on multifractal (scale invariant) simulations. It was found that SIG yields reasonable estimates for fields with a diversity of anisotropic and statistical characteristics. The analysis is also performed on three satellite cloud radiances and three sea ice SAR reflectivities to test the applicability of the technique. SIG also produced reasonable estimates in these cases.</description><creator>Lewis, Gregory</creator><contributor>Lovejoy, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Geophysics.</subject><title>The scale invariant generator technique and scaling anisotropy in geophysics /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644s408.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g360p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j191d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A particular kind of gaseous particle detector, called resistive plate counter, has been built and tested with cosmic rays. It is composed of two parallel highly resistive electrode plates between which circulates an ionizing gas, and of capacitively coupled readout pads. The tests look at the pulse shape, efficiency, charge distribution, time delay, and time resolution of the counter. It is shown that these characteristics are dependent upon the voltage applied to the electrodes, the gas mixture ratio (argon/butane/freon), and the surface irregularities of the electrodes. The counter exhibits a 98% efficiency and a time resolution of approximately 1 ns. These results are consistent with published results for this type of counter.</description><creator>Laperle, Pierre</creator><contributor>Hanna, David S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>Construction and testing of a resistive plate counter</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p120s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j191d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227mq68g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Transcutaneous electrical nerve stimulation (TENS) has been employed for over 2 decades in pain management, however, definitive analgesic parameters have yet to be determined. The objective of this study was to determine the influence of 10, 30 and 60 min of TENS on the time course and magnitude of modulation on flexion reflex (FR) and on subjective pain estimates (visual analogue scale, VAS), as well as determining the relationship between FR responses and VAS scores following TENS of different durations. Ten (10) normal subjects received electrical stimuli of maximal tolerable intensity to the sole of their foot. Our results indicated that TENS could suppress the FR in 50% to 70% of subjects. However, longer durations (30 and 60 min) of TENS have a small, but discernible difference in the number of subjects that show inhibition of FR area and significant maximal FR suppression when compared to 10 min of TENS. Moreover, the 60 min of TENS generated significant depression of VAS scores in more subjects than 10 and 30 min of TENS and ensured that any increase in pain perception would not reach significance when compared to the shorter (10 and 30 min) durations of TENS. Our results suggested that longer durations of TENS could be applied to produce antinociceptive and analgesic effects. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Chin, Steven R. (Steven Richard)</creator><contributor>Hui-Chan, Christina (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><title>Transcutaneous electrical nerve stimulation (TENS) : effects of duration of stimulation on antinociception in man</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708x467.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mq68g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t2822</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bacterial species have been classified according to physiological, biochemical and immunological features. The sequencing of homologous genes present in various species can provide new insights for bacterial taxonomy and for the comprehension of molecular mechanisms involved in evolution. Recently, a new gene, called nlp (for Ner-like-protein), was discovered in E. coli and was shown to also be present in several other Enterobacteriaceae. The Nlp protein is highly homologous to the Ner repressors of transposable bacteriophages Mu and D108. In order to determine if the nucleotide sequence of the nlp gene was conserved in enteric bacteria, and also for studying the potential evolutionary relationship between bacteria and bacteriophages, the E. coli C nlp gene was cloned and sequenced. The resulting nucleotide sequence was compared to the nlp genes of E. coli W3110 and Shigella sonneii. Results showed that the coding region of the E. coli C nlp gene is identical to its E. coli W3110 counterpart. In S. sonneii, the nlp gene sequence revealed three nucleotide substitutions when compared to the two E. coli nlp sequences. Nevertheless, these variations were located in the third position of codons and had no effect on the primary structure of the Nlp protein.</description><creator>David, Jocelyn</creator><contributor>DuBow, Michael S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Characterization of the nlp gene family of Enterobacteriaceae</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708x45z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t2822</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860786f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:02:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An uncoupled, modified Hibler ice model has been applied to the Gulf of St. Lawrence for three different winters of varying severity, in order to examine interannual sea ice variability. The simulation was initialized with observed November sea surface temperatures, and forced by weekly geostrophic winds, monthly averaged meteorological data and model geostrophic surface currents. Results showed a general correlation with observations, reproducing differences in the sea ice cover between the years chosen. Neglecting oceanic effects caused excessive ice formation in the northwest Gulf and produced discrepancies between the observed and modelled ice edge. Sensitivity studies revealed a high sensitivity to variations in both the forcing fields and the model free parameters. Further modelling studies must include a coupled ocean component, and force the ice component with weekly meteorological data to improve the accuracy of the prediction.</description><creator>DeTracey, Brendan</creator><contributor>Ingram, R. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Physical Oceanography.</subject><title>Modelling interannual sea ice variability in the Gulf of St. Lawrence</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666533h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860786f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):23375</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>