<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:47:31Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):41050" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712m7309</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An analysis of migration patterns and migrant adjustment in peninsular Malaysia is presented, based on data from the Malaysian Family Life Survey. The analysis revealed that urban/rural residence, ethnicity, motivations underlying migration, and manner of securing employment are important determinants of the duration of the job search and of post-migration income. It was further noted that transferees form a distinct stream of migration. They differ from other migrants in age, education, employment, and post-migration income. In discussing the significance of these findings, attention is drawn to the impact of government policies on types of migration streams, and to the size of the public (or formal) sector as a determinant of work-related migration, or transfers.</description><creator>Menon, Ramdas</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Migration, Internal -- Malaysia</subject><subject>Malaysia -- Economic conditions</subject><subject>Working class -- Malaysia</subject><title>Migration patterns and migrant adjustment in peninsular Malaysia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365581k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m7309</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p537j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Several strategies outlining approaches to the synthesis of the heteroanthracyclinones 4-demethoxyxanthodaunomycinone and 4-demethoxyisoxanthodaunomycinone (7,8,9,10-tetrahydrobenzo(b)-6,7,9,11-tetrahydroxy-9-acetylxanthen-12 and 5-one) are described. The condensation of tetralin 2-acetyl-5,8-dimethoxy-1,2,3,4-tetrahydro-2-naphthol with o-methoxybenzoic acid was investigated and useful large-scale syntheses of important 1,4-dimethoxy-substituted xanthone intermediates were developed. Diels-Alder cycloaddition reaction between a xanthone-derived o-quinodimethane intermediate and an olefin afforded a low yield of adduct. On the other hand, excellent yields of isolable but labile adducts were obtained in the cycloaddition reaction between xanthoquinone (and also thioxanthoquinone) and Danishefsky's dienes. The formation of linear vs internal adducts was rationalized on the grounds of resonance and FMO theory. Efforts to induce unactivated dienes to cycloadd using catalysts as well as annulation studies on model compounds using the novel reagent (E)-N-vinylpyrrolidine-(beta)-(2-lithio-1,3-dithian-2-yl) (as a synthon of the (alpha),(beta)-dianion of acetaldehyde) are discussed. The synthesis of daunomycin and xanthodaunomycin analogs carrying a carbon substituent at position 7 were not accessible using the Diels-Alder cycloaddition reaction as diene 1-carbomethoxy-3-triethylsilyloxy-1,3-butadiene failed to react with either quinizarinquinone or xanthoquinone even at elevated temperatures. The compound 4-hydroxy-1- 2- (2-hydroxyethyl)amino ethyl amino xanthone and the 4-methoxy derivative were prepared and found to be inactive in the in vivo P-388 mouse leukemia model system.</description><creator>Mancini, Michael.</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Anthracyclines.</subject><subject>Antineoplastic agents.</subject><title>Approaches to the synthesis of xanthone analogs of the anthracycline class of anticancer agents</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q4741.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p537j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386k02m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis deals primarily with the problem of soft-error tolerance in digital machines. The possible sources of soft errors are reviewed. It is shown that the significance of ionizing radiation increases with the scaling down of MOS technologies. The characteristics of electromagnetic interference sources are also discussed. After presenting the conventional methods of dealing with soft errors, a new approach to this problem is suggested. The new approach, called Soft-Error Filtering (SEF), consists of filtering every output of the logic before latching it, in such a way that a transient injected into a machine does not change the final result of an operation. An analysis of the reduction in the error rate that is obtained by using SEF is presented. For example, this analysis demonstrates that the error rate due to alpha particles generated by the decay of radioactive elements becomes negligible. A great deal of attention is devoted to the design of filtering latches which is an essential component for implementing SEF machines. Three structures are considered and a CMOS implementation is proposed in each case. The double-filter latch is the best of the three implementations. It features a nearly optimum performance in the time domain and it is relatively insensitive to process fluctuations. An overhead analysis demonstrates that SEF usually results in a small overhead, both in area and in time simultaneously. In conclusion, SEF is the best approach to the problem of designing a machine tolerant to short transients.</description><creator>Savaria, Yvon, 1958-</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Integrated circuits -- Very large scale integration -- Reliability.</subject><subject>Electric filters.</subject><subject>Digital electronics.</subject><title>The design of digital machines tolerant of soft errors /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nv32z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386k02m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5h73pw81c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Brazil instituted a crawling peg (mini-devaluation) exchange rate system in 1968 as a long-term device to put into operation an "export oriented growth-cum-debt" model of economic development. The crawling peg was expected to serve diverse objectives by decreasing the variability in the exchange rate. In this study we have analyzed the degree to which this strategy succeeded in realizing the desired goals during the period from 1968 to 1980. Our findings verified that the implementation of the crawl was an important tool that protected and enhanced Brazil's competitive position in world markets. The demand for Brazilian products became more responsive both to changes in relative prices and to changes in world income. We further established the significance of the crawl in stabilizing import prices and flows in addition to its impact on foreign financing decisions.</description><creator>Omar, Jaber H. (Jaber Hussein), 1948-</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Capital -- Brazil.</subject><subject>Foreign trade promotion -- Brazil.</subject><subject>Foreign exchange administration -- Brazil.</subject><subject>Brazil -- Economic policy.</subject><title>The Brazilian crawl : its impact on trade and capital flows</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059c8317.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73pw81c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hm50ts33q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Analgesias induced by an interaction between restraint and morphine, an interaction between exposure to a novel environment and morphine, and by restraint alone were all shown to be dependent upon an increase in brain tryptophan uptake. Further investigation of the analgesia induced by an interaction between retraint and morphine revealed that the increase in brain tryptophan uptake was induced by sympathetic activity and that the nucleus raphe magnus, the nucleus raphe dorsalis, and the periaqueductal gray were critical to the analgesia. Examination of the endogenous opiod activity critical to analgesia induced by restraint alone revealed that the opioid activity was in the central nervous system and independent of tryptophan uptake. The findings reported in this thesis may be delineating a general mechanism for analgesia that involves stress, serotonin, and opioids.</description><creator>Kelly, Sandra, 1958-</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Analgesia.</subject><subject>Stress (Physiology)</subject><subject>Morphine -- Physiological effect.</subject><subject>Rats -- Behavior.</subject><title>Analgesia induced by morphine or stress : an analysis of mechanisms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870w64v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50ts33q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jd472x159</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The mechanisms of pain and hyperalgesia were examined in rats following cutaneous-heat and peripheral-nerve injury. Central mechanisms of hyperalgesia were indicated since a heat injury produced a decrease in foot-withdrawal latencies in the paw contralateral to the injury and an increase in autotomy of the injured paw following section of the sciatic and saphenous nerves. The reduced contralateral foot-withdrawal latencies were reversed by spinal anesthesia and subcutaneous guanethidine, but were unaffected by local anesthetics and capsaicin at the site of injury. The enhancement of autotomy produced by an injury was reduced by spinal anesthesia and a combination of intrathecal capsaicin and subcutaneous guanethidine. Both intrathecal substance P and systemic noradrenaline produced an increase in autotomy following nerve lesions; guanethidine, but neither capsaicin nor procaine, produced a decrease in autotomy. A reduction in inflammation and hyperalgesia within an injured paw was produced by local capsaicin, but not by guanethidine. The results suggest that central mechanisms, such as spinal hyperactivity, combined with peripheral neurogenic mechanisms are involved in the production of hyperalgesia following heat injury. Pain and hyperalgesia following nerve injury are proposed to be due to spinal cord plasticity resulting from deafferentation and abnormal sympathetic activity.</description><creator>Coderre, Terence J. (Terence James)</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Hyperalgesia.</subject><subject>Analgesia.</subject><subject>Autotomy.</subject><subject>Nervous system.</subject><subject>Pain -- Physiological aspects.</subject><subject>Rats -- Behavior.</subject><title>Peripheral and central mechanisms of pain and hyperalgesia : effects of adrenergic and sensory neuron blockade on autotomy and pain sensitivity following injury</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j3333002.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd472x159</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75r865n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Self-fertilization requires less energetic expenditures than cross-fertilization and benefits from a 50% advantage in its rate of gene transmission. Yet, no plant species is known that reproduces exclusively via self-fertilization, as all appear to maintain a certain outcrossing rate. I test the hypothesis that, under specific circumstances, cross-fertilization provides short-term advantages over self-fertilization in Corydalis sempervirens, a self-compatible winter annual. Some fitness components of selfed and crossed progeny were compared under different experimental conditions. Crossed progeny derived short-term advantages from both their higher mean individual heterozygosity and their greater genotypic diversity. Overall, they had higher mean fitnesses than selfed individuals (heterosis), especially in favorable environments. Crossed progeny also displayed greater constancy of yield under increasing densities. In all test-environments, the few individuals with highest fitness resulted from outcrossing. However, as a group, crossed offspring did not have higher fitness values than selfed offspring and not all crosses generated progeny with equally high fitness. The fittest individuals were produced in crosses between parents which shared an intermediate number of common ancestors.</description><creator>Cartier, Julie.</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Corydalis sempervirens.</subject><subject>Fertilization of plants.</subject><subject>Plant genetics.</subject><title>Short-term advantages of outcrossing in the autogamous wildflower Corydalis sempervirens</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515p112.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75r865n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kb53c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A series of experiments was carried out to clarify the effects of morphine (0.3 - 10 mg/kg) on intracranial self-stimulation (ICS) and to compare these with the effects of the stimulant amphetamine on this behavior. It was shown that the enhancement of ICS by morphine requires repeated drug exposure, is prevented by pre-exposure to the drug in a non-ICS context, is mimicked by administration of vehicle, and is not reliably reversed by naloxone. In contrast, facilitation of ICS by amphetamine was immediate and remained stable over repeated days of testing. It was concluded that ICS facilitation induced by morphine, but not by amphetamine, is largely the outcome of a learned association between the drug effect and the ICS procedure, and does not appear to be a direct, opiate receptor-mediated effect. Finally, 6-OHDA lesions of ventral tegmental dopamine neurons were shown to block the facilitation of ICS by morphine but not by amphetamine. These lesions were also shown to delay the development of tolerance to morphine-induced catalepsy.</description><creator>Hand, Timothy Henry.</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Amphetamines -- Physiological effect.</subject><subject>Rats -- Behavior.</subject><subject>Morphine -- Physiological effect.</subject><subject>Brain stimulation.</subject><title>Effects of morphine on intracranial self-stimulation : the involvement of associative factors and the role of ventral tegmental dopamine neurons</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42n877z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kb53c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b688c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Theoretical expressions essentially based on the Flory-Stockmayer statistics of gelation were experimentally examined for their applicability beyond the gel point. By studying the crosslinking process of a polyester network formed from 1,3,5-benzenetriacetic acid and 1,10-decamethylene glycol beyond the gel point, the validity of the expressions was quantitatively confirmed, and their limitations were delineated. On stepwise degradation of a similar network, increasingly large soluble fractions were obtained at each step, and their weight-average molecular weights increased as the degelation point was approached. The molecular weights and distributions of these fractions were in close quantitative agreement with theory, i.e., they represented a near-mirror image of the molecular weights of sol fractions obtained on crosslinking beyond the gel point. Similar results were obtained by degrading a network prepared by the random crosslinking of monodisperse primary chains of polystyrene. Experimental support was thus obtained for treating random network degradation by reversing the statistics of the Flory-Stockmayer theory of gelation.</description><creator>Argyropoulos, Dimitris S.</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Polymers -- Deterioration.</subject><title>Synthesis and degradation of model network polymers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f4209.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b688c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nh81w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Boltzmann's equation for binary chemical reactions has been solved by the modified moment method using the equivalent of the 13-moment approximations. It was found that the transport coefficients are nonlinear in the thermodynamic forces. This nonlinearity is at least quadratic. The rate coefficient also appears to be at least quadratic in fluxes. The stability of the solutions of two coupled equations of change for the current under the influence of an electric field is examined. These equations are deduced from the structure of dissipative terms calculated in the modified moment method. Two steady state branches in current are found to bifurcate from the primary steady state branch as a critical field value E(,c) = 4.35 V/cm is crossed. The results are in good qualitative agreement with experiment. The dynamical behaviour of the two coupled equations used above was also studied in order to establish the influence (if any) of the entropy production surface on the trajectory followed by the system. This aspect of the study proved to be difficult since the entropy production surface associated with the two equations used did not have sufficiently distinctive features. In order to continue studies on the relationship between dynamical behaviour and the topography of the entropy production surface, the two basic equations used before were slightly modified, and new parameters were introduced. At the critical field value E(,c) = 1.48 V/cm, no secondary steady states bifurcated out of the unstable primary steady state as in the previous model. Rather, stable oscillations in current of more or less constant amplitude occurred. This may account for some of the current fluctuations observed in experiment. The entropy production surface associated with this pair of model equations consists of two intersecting locii of minima. It turns out that the trajectory follows these minimal regions for most of the orbit, crossing from one locus of minima to another either through the intersection near to the origin or by crossing a ridge of high entropy production. The average energy dissipated over this cycle turns out to be smaller than if the system had remained with the unstable steady state. Out of the latter studies, the useful conjecture was made. Given the topography of the entropy production surface and the stability of the steady states, it is possible to qualitatively predict the dynamics of the system provided the entropy production surface has sufficiently distinctive features.</description><creator>Ali, Jaleel A.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Electric conductivity.</subject><subject>Chemical systems.</subject><subject>Chemical kinetics.</subject><subject>Kinetic theory of liquids.</subject><subject>Semiconductors.</subject><title>Some deductions from kinetic theory for chemically reacting systems and semiconductors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qm740.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nh81w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zb84h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>When high yield chemimechanical sulphite pulp fibres were suspended in water, both lignin and carbohydrate were leached out of the pulp. The rate of leaching fitted a theory developed previously for the diffusion of macromolecules through the water-swollen fibre wall. The average intrafibre diffusion coefficients for lignin and carbohydrate were several orders of magnitude lower than the free diffusion of these macromolecules in solution. Leaching over a long period indicated a polydispersity of diffusion coefficients. This was related to an increase with time in the molecular weights of macromolecules removed from the fibre. Although the rate of leaching increased markedly with temperature, the diffusion coefficient of lignin decreased, while that of carbohydrate increased by a factor higher than that predicted by the Stokes-Einstein equation. These contrasting results were interpreted in terms of the molecular weights of the diffusing species and hydrogen bonding of carbohydrate to the fibre wall. The rate of leaching decreased with an increase in pulp yield, increasing cationic strength and pH of the wash water, decreasing refining energy, pretreatment of pulp with formaldehyde, and the use of polyethyleneoxide/alum retention aid in the wash water. Decreasing pH of the cooking liquor and the use of anthraquinone in the pulping increased the leaching of lignin but did not affect the leaching of carbohydrate. The effects observed could be related either to swelling or degradation of the fibre wall.</description><creator>Willis, Jocelyn M.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Sulphite pulping process.</subject><subject>Leaching.</subject><subject>Lignin.</subject><title>The leaching of lignin and carbohydrate from high yield pulp fibres suspended in water /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182k96j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zb84h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d56zx33b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new method for the estimation of the EEG evoked potential (EP) is presented in this thesis. This method is based on a new model of the EEG response which is assumed to be the sum of the EP and independent correlated Gaussian noise representing the spontaneous EEG activity. The EP is assumed to vary in both shape and latency, with the shape variation represented by correlated Gaussian noise which is modulated by the EP. The latency of the EP is also assumed to vary over the ensemble of responses in a random manner governed by some unspecified probability density. No assumption on stationarity is needed for the noise. With the model described in state-space form, a Kalman filter is constructed, and the variance of the innovation process of the response measurements is derived. A maximum likelihood solution to the EP estimation problem is then obtained via this innovation process. Tests using simulated responses show that the method is effective in estimating the EP signal at signal-to-noise ratio as low as -6db. Other tests using real normal visual response data yield reasonably consistent EP estimates whose main components are narrower and larger than the ensemble average. In addition, the likelihood function obtained by our method can be used as a discriminant between normal and abnormal responses, and it requires smaller ensembles than other methods.</description><creator>Al-Nashi, Hamid Rasheed</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Evoked potentials (Electrophysiology)</subject><subject>Electroencephalography.</subject><title>A maximum likelihood method to estimate EEG evoked potentials /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247ds83g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zx33b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042t76p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A deterministic computer model was developed to continuously simulate the runoff from surface and subsurface-drained fields in the St. Lawrence lowlands. The model simulates all of the major hydrologic and hydraulic processes occurring both above and below the ground. Input data requirements include hourly rainfall, daily potential evapotranspiration, soil physical properties, field dimensions, open channel geometry and drainage system specifications. Events for the years 1978 to 1982 were simulated, to compare the runoff characteristics between 20 ha, clay loam, surface-drained and subsurface-drained fields. Further simulations were conducted to examine the hydrologic effects of wide-spaced, deep, parallel field ditches. Hydrographs for the one-in-200-year storm were also simulated. All of the simulations confirmed that the peak flow rate on the subsurface-drained field was less than that of the surface-drained field. Longer times to peak and lag times occurred on the subsurface-drained field.</description><creator>Madramootoo, Chandra Alastair, 1954-</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Drainage.</subject><subject>Drainage -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>An agricultural land drainage simulation model /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jx87w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042t76p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k3569528d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cell surface T antigen, detected by a radioimmune assay using ('125)I-labeled S. aureus protein A and antibodies against either authentic T antigen or D2 T antigen, was found in SV40-transformed and -infected cells and in Ad2('+)D2-infected cells. To determine how the target antigen of this assay is related to SV40 large T antigen and D2 T antigen and whether or not it is an integral membrane protein, plasma membranes from cell lines infected with SV40 or Ad2('+)D2 were purified. Protein blotting with polyclonal and monoclonal antibody overlay was used to identify a specific protein of 90 kd in membranes from SV40-transformed and lytically infected cells that was indistinguishable from nuclear T antigen. The blotting procedure and overlay with polyclonal anti-D2 T antibody showed that plasma membranes from HeLa cells infected with Ad2('+)D2 contained a 100 kd protein that was also indistinguishable from its nuclear counterpart. Unlike SV40 membrane T antigen, membrane D2 T antigen was produced in large quantities. Up to 40% of membrane D2 T antigen remained tightly associated with membranes under alkaline conditions (to pH 11.5). It could not be totally solubilized by treatment with ionic detergents or nonionic detergents or both. Contamination of membrane D2 T antigen by nuclear D2 T antigen in purified plasma membrane preparations was less than 5 percent as demonstrated by reconstitution experiments. Velocity sedimentation analysis showed that both nuclear and membrane D2 T antigen existed as heterogeneous molecules of predominantly 5 to 7 S with smaller amounts of 14 to 16 S and 23 S when centrifuged under low salt conditions. The higher S value forms could be dissociated to the 5 to 7 S forms when centrifuged in the presence of high salt concentrations. Sephacryl S-300 chromatography in high salt in the presence of Brij-99 showed that the nuclear form was dissociated to low molecular weight species while the membrane form eluted as a complex of high molecular weight. This indicates that the membrane form of D2 T antigen contains a hydrophobic region not present in the nuclear form and suggests a difference between the two not hitherto described.</description><creator>Ismail, Alnashir A.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><title>Comparison of membrane and nuclear T antigen ; a tumor antigen specified by the adenovirus 2-Simian virus hybrid, Ad2+D2</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053g83q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569528d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ms35t933r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The mixing mechanism of South African cumulus congestus clouds is investigated using a combined observational and modeling approach. The experimental data consists of aircraft measurements collected in developing cloud towers near Nelspruit on three case study days. The observations are analyzed to determine the source regions of the entrained air. The mixing processes are simulated using both axially and slab symmetric cumulus models with very high spatial and temporal resolutions. The simulated clouds have a structured organization with small scale features such as in-cloud downdrafts. The mixing processes are examined by analyzing the time variation of dynamic and thermodynamic quantities along computed parcel trajectories. Both observations and simulations indicate that most of the entrainment occurs at the cloud top. Evaporative cooling causes downdrafts that transport highly diluted air from the cloud top down to lower levels. The trajectory analysis shows that the penetrative downdrafts are also affected by pressure perturbations. In the presence of wind shear the downshear sides of the clouds become more diluted, cooler and have stronger downdrafts. The asymmetric organisation is attributed to turbulent exchange of horizontal momentum at the cloud top.</description><creator>Reuter, Gerhard Wilhelm.</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Cumulus.</subject><subject>Cloud physics.</subject><subject>Clouds -- South Africa.</subject><title>Observations and numerical simulations of mixing mechanisms in South African cumulus conqestus clouds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w066q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35t933r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kb55x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Data taken from the literature were used to develop and evaluate models predicting fish biomass and yield, crustacean zooplankton biomass, and profundal macrobenthos biomass in lakes. Total phosphorus concentration and macrobenthos biomass/mean depth were the best univariate predictors of fish biomass and yield. Phosphorus concentration was also the best predictor of zooplankton and macrobenthos biomass. In experiments testing for inter- and intraspecific competition, conducted in situ at densities based on measured natural fish densities, growth of yellow perch (Perca flavescens) and pumpkinseed (Lepomis gibbosus) reared alone was inversely related to density. Both species primarily ate macroinvertebrates when reared alone. When reared together: perch growth was significantly depressed compared to that of perch reared alone; pumpkinseed growth was equivalent to that of pumpkinseed reared alone; and the diet of perch changed to include food of inferior quality (microcrustaceans) in the presence of the superior competitor, pumpkinseed, whose diet did not change.</description><creator>Hanson, John Mark, 1955-</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Fish populations -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Competition (Biology)</subject><subject>Predation (Biology)</subject><subject>Freshwater animals.</subject><title>Patterns of animal abundance in lakes : the role of competition in the fish-macroinvertebrate relationship</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602150j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kb55x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn301203s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Nisku Formation in the Alberta subsurface consists of bank facies, reefal facies, and basinal/slope facies along the Outer Shelf. The bank facies was not previously recognized, and is here designated the Dismal Creek Member. Most buildups are coral-bearing mudmounds. The Nisku Formation was affected by more than twenty diagenetic processes, most notably by dolomitization and anhydritization. The buildups were partially lithified in shallow phreatic environments, and some were subaerially exposed. Dolomitization took place at depths of about 300 to 1000 m by fluids that were derived mainly from the underlying Ireton Formation. Most of the anhydrites formed during the last stages of and/or after dolomitization. After oil emplacement, thermochemical redox reactions between hydrocarbons and sulfates resulted in partial removal of anhydrite in the deepest buildups, and the formation of 'dead' oil, sour gas, replacive calcite, saddle dolomite, celestite, and native sulfur. Diagenetic changes after maximum burial were very minor.</description><creator>Machel, Hans-G. (Hans-Gerhard)</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Diagenesis -- Alberta.</subject><subject>Facies (Geology) -- Alberta.</subject><title>Facies and diagenesis of the Upper Devonian Nisku formation in the subsurface of central Alberta</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247ds869.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301203s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jm155</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Adrenocorticotropic hormone (ACTH) is synthesized in the pituitary gland as part of a larger precursor molecule. This precursor is characterized by the fact that it contains within its structure multiple chemical messengers with quite different biological activities. Among them are included the melanotropins (MSH), the beta-lipotropin ((beta)-LPH) and the endorphins. To account for the major biological activities of its components, the name pro-opiomelanocortin (POMC) has been proposed for this common precursor. Characterization of this molecule in pituitary tissues including both the anterior and intermediate lobes as well as the mouse anterior pituitary tumour cell line AtT-20/D16v, established its apparent molecular weight (Mr) to be around 30 000 Daltons with the presence of carbohydrate side chains attached to a peptide backbone. This latter aspect is considered partly responsible for the heterogeneity observed in both the molecular weight and the charge of the molecule. Nucleotide sequencing of the cDNA coding for POMC has predicted the whole primary structure. ACTH and (beta)-LPH together account for only half the size of the precursor, the other half being located on the amino-terminal side. This cryptic segment as ACTH and (beta)-LPH contains an MSH-like sequence called (gamma)-MSH. Pulse and pulse-chase experiments indicated that this cryptic segment of the POMC has an apparent molecular weight of 16 000 to 19 000 Daltons and that it is an important maturation product. In order to completely characterize this cryptic segment we dissected porcine pituitary glands in both the anterior and neurointermediate lobes. Our objective was to determine the molecular form of the amino terminal segment of the porcine POMC (pNT) in the anterior lobe using a chemical approach. We extracted the peptides from the anterior lobes and chromatographed them on various systems including molecular sieving, ion-exchange and high performance liquid chromatography. Complete primary structure of the pNT revealed that the major form is a glycopeptide of 80 amino acid residues with at least two glycosylation sites. Two other peptides of 107 and 61 amino acid residues were isolated. We proposed that they are members of the genealogic tree of the pNT, the 107 residue being the whole cryptic segment preceding ACTH and the amidated 61 residue being a maturation product of the major secretory form. We also isolated a peptide which links the 80 residue glycopeptide to the ACTH in the POMC; it will be called the joining peptide (pJP).</description><creator>Larivière, Normand.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Purification and characterization of the N-terminal peptides related to porcine pro-opiomelanocortin</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hw129.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jm155</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m039k576g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The cap structure m('7)GpppX(m)...at the 5' terminus of eucaryotic mRNAs facilitates ribosomes binding to mRNA via interaction with cap binding proteins (CBP). Polypeptides of 24, 50 and 80 kilodaltons in crude initiation factors can be specifically crosslinked to the cap structure of mRNA. Crosslinking of the 50 and 80 kilodalton polypeptides requires ATP hydrolysis, but shows reduced dependence on ATP if the mRNA has less secondary structure. Purification by m('7)GDP affinity chromatography yields the CBP complex, comprising polypeptides of 24, 50 and (TURN)220 kilodaltons. The CBP complex and eucaryotic initiation factor-4B (eIF-4B, 80 kilodaltons) are sufficient to allow a cap specific mRNA protein interaction between the 24 and 50 kilodalton polypeptides of the CBP complex, eIF-4B and mRNA. In relation to the cap specific polypeptides in crude initiation factors, the 50 kilodalton polypeptide is eucaryotic initiation factor-4A (eIF-4A) and the 80 kilodalton polypeptide is most probably eIF-4B. This suggests that the cap binding protein complex and possibly eIF-4B, denature mRNA. In poliovirus-infected cells, uncapped poliovirus RNA is translated when cellular (capped) mRNA translation is inhibited. The 220 kilodalton polypeptide of the CBP complex is proteolyzed in poliovirus-infected cells, correlating with a reduction in the crosslinking of the 24, 50 and 80 kilodalton polypeptides, thus probably explaining the inhibition of cellular mRNA translation. mRNAs with reduced secondary structure are less dependent on the fully active CBP complex for ribosome binding, consistent with the suggestion that the CBP complex can denature capped mRNAs. The data indicate an important role for the 220 kilodalton polypeptide in ribosome binding and, that mRNA secondary structure is a significant determinant in translation of capped mRNAs.</description><creator>Lee, Kevin A. W.</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><title>Role of eucaryotic mRNA cap binding proteins in protein synthesis and regulation in poliovirus infected HeLa cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cn69m4969.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k576g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn009z615</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This investigation examines cell proliferation in the pancreas of the Syrian golden hamster. Three main themes are pursued. First, normal pancreatic growth and development is reviewed. Emphasis is placed on histogenesis and trophic stimuli. Secondly, modulation of pancreatic growth is examined. A new method for producing partial pancreatic duct obstruction using a technique of cellophane wrapping is described. The histologic alterations induced by wrapping are the same as those associated with the early changes of chemical pancreatic carcinogenesis--duct epithelial hyperplasia, metaplasia and nesidioblastosis. Morphometric, immunocytochemical, autoradiographic and G.I. hormone analysis are also utilized to characterize this model. Importantly, experimental nesidioblastosis can result in islets which are functionally capable of reversing streptozocin-induced diabetes. Thirdly, aberrant pancreatic growth was investigated in relation to carcinogenesis. Clinical cancer epidemiology is reviewed with special reference to risk factors and postulated trophic influences. Experimentally, the trophic effects of diet, cholecystectomy and duct obstruction were investigated. Finally a new model for the induction of carcinoma of the head of the pancreas, using cellophane wrapping in association with a chemical carcinogen, is presented.</description><creator>Rosenberg, Lawrence.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Cell proliferation in the pancreas of the Syrian golden hamster</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m732v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn009z615</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214p883</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The primary grain in oat spikelets is larger than the secondary grain. Oat genotypes were grown to determine the effects of planting primary and secondary grains separately on vegetative and reproductive growth. Plants from primary seeds had higher yields than those from secondary seeds. The advantage was associated with earliness of heading. It was concluded that increased seed uniformity would be advantageous. Reductions in panicle size by removal of all primary grains and some secondary grains indicated that secondary grains have more growth potential than observed in untreated panicles. However, secondary grains in the treated panicles did not achieve weights equalling those of primary grains in the untreated panicles. Variation in primary:secondary seed weight ratios was found among experiments. The variability was attributed mainly to instability of secondary grain weight. The inheritance of secondary grain weight and of the primary:secondary seed weight ratio was studied at two locations. For both traits, additive and non-additive genetic effects were evident. Dominant gene action was relatively unimportant, suggesting good potential for improvement through pure-line breeding.</description><creator>Tibelius, Anne Christine Smith.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Seeds -- Quality.</subject><subject>Grain -- Weights and measures.</subject><subject>Oats -- Seeds -- Quality.</subject><title>Some aspects of secondary seed size and primary:secondary seed weight ratios in Avena sativa L.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j6428.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214p883</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988k715</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The availability of phosphorus from the anoxic hypolimnia of lakes to epilimnetic plankton was investigated by experimental studies on eight lakes in Ontario and Quebec. Availability was determined with a short-term bioassay based on the standardized retardation of planktonic uptake of phosphorus tracer in the presence of orthophosphate; availability was also estimated by SRP (soluble reactive phosphorus) analysis, since approximately 90% of SRP was available in anoxic waters. Iron concentrations were high in some hypolimnia, but should become diluted after mixing with surface water. When iron concentrations after mixing exceeded 0.20 mg/L, aeration lowered availability and SRP. Therefore, samples from anoxic hypolimnia were kept anoxic. The fate of hypolimnetic phosphorus at turnover was studied by construction of a budget for SRP, total phosphorus, particulate iron containing phosphorus and particulate biological phosphorus at fall turnover in Lake Magog. Despite high concentrations of hypolimnetic iron, only 30% of the upwelling hypolimnetic phosphorus combined with iron after complete mixing, 30% was incorporated into biomass and 38% stayed potentially available as SRP. In two lakes, hypolimnetic iron was undetectable hydrogen sulfide concentrations were high. H(,2)S interfered with the SRP analysis and poisoned plankton. After degassing, routine SRP analysis was possible, and availability was close to 100%. Iron and H(,2)S interference in the SRP analysis were circumvented by degassing or by maintaining anoxia. A simpler method, the analysis of TRP (total reactive phosphorus) after aeration, was developed which analyses SRP quantitatively in anoxic waters.</description><creator>Nürnberg, Gertrud.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Lake ecology.</subject><subject>Water -- Phosphorus content.</subject><subject>Freshwater plankton.</subject><title>The availability of phosphorus from anoxic hypolimnia to epilimnetic plankton /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613mz27v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988k715</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:08612p40r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Lower Devonian carbonate-clastic sequence of southwest Ellesmere Island accumulated in the Franklinian Basin at approximately 15(DEGREES)N latitude. A variety of depositional settings are represented, ranging from tidal flat to basinal environments. These environments can be recognized in Lower Devonian rocks across the Arctic Islands. Progradation of the carbonate sequence of southwest Ellesmere Island occurred in the Early Devonian, but was periodically interrupted in the Zlichovian/Dalejan by transgressive events. Upward movement in the newly named Inglefield Uplift occurred throughout the Devonian, and shed clastic sediments westward that, in Middle to Late Devonian time, finally overwhelmed the marine carbonates and resulted in fluvial deposition on southern Ellesmere Island. Certain formations in the Lower Devonian sequence are profusely fossiliferous, in particular the Blue Fiord Formation, which contains an abundant fauna including numerous species of coral and brachiopods. Both of these groups belong to the Old World Biogeographic Realm, and indicate a Zlichovian age for the lower Blue Fiord Formation of southern Ellesmere Island.</description><creator>Smith, Gary Parker.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Paleontology -- Canadian Arctic Archipelago (Nunavut and N.W.T.)</subject><subject>Paleontology -- Devonian</subject><subject>Paleontology -- Nunavut -- Ellesmere Island</subject><subject>Geology, Stratigraphic -- Devonian.</subject><title>Stratigraphy and paleontology of the lower Devonian sequence, southwest Ellesmere Island, Canadian Arctic Archipelago</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mg259.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612p40r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795852g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The idea of an operational category over A generalizes the notions of tripleable and equational category over A, and also the dual notions of cotripleable and coequational category. An operational category, U:D (---&gt;) A is given by a presentation ((theta),H) (UNFORMATTED TABLE FOLLOWS) D C('T) C('(theta)) A C('B) H*(TABLE ENDS) where (theta) is a functor bijective on objects and D is a specified pullback. R:Op(A) (---&gt;) Cat/A is defined as the category of operational categories (and functors) with given presentations. Another category, Op(,o)(A) over Cat/A of operational categories with standard presentations is also defined. There is a fixed theory (theta)(,o), employed in every standard presentation. Op(,o)(A) is a retract of Op(A) over Cat/A: (UNFORMATTED TABLE FOLLOWS) i Op(,o)(A) Op(A) s R(,o) R Cat/A(TABLE ENDS) i.e. every operational category (and functor) has a standard presentation (but not s(REVTURNST)i!). Also R(,o) has a left adjoint L(,o) and Op(,o)(A) is complete. Finally, there is a category of algebras, S(,*)-Alg over Cat/A such that Op(,o)(A) (DBLTURN) S(,*)-Alg over Cat/A. Thus, the operational categories can be determined by their internal structure, without reference to any presentation. Some properties of operational categories and some special cases are also examined.</description><creator>Jay, C. Barry.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Categories (Mathematics)</subject><title>Generalising the structure-semantics adjunction : operational categories</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n203z92n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795852g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv9353758</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Let (GAMMA) be a discrete group of hyperbolic isometries having a fundamental polygon with finitely many sides and no cusps. We show that the associated horocycle flow admits just one ergodic measure which is not concentrated on a single orbit. We use ergodicity of this measure to calculate the ratio set of the Patterson measure of (GAMMA).</description><creator>Kenny, Patrick J.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Measure theory.</subject><subject>Ergodic theory.</subject><title>Ergodic measures for a class of horocycle flows</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cx10m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv9353758</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):41075</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>