<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:18:36Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):7250" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r814f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Contexte: Les directives de meilleures pratiques pour l'AVC aigu recommandent un parcours de soins, en dépit des preuves limitées de l'impact sur les indicateurs de la fonction. Les parcours de soins existants manquent d'éléments visant directement l'amélioration de la fonction; ces éléments pourraient mieux orienter les soins vers des résultats fonctionnels. Objectif: L'objectif était de développer et de tester la faisabilité et l'impact d'un tableau de bord, centré sur le patient, suite à un AVC en phase aigue pour suivre les indicateurs de récupération fonctionnelle des patients post-AVC. Méthodes : Trois théories du transfert des connaissances ont été utilisées pour informer l'élaboration du tableau de bord. Les méthodes ont consisté d'une analyse des lacunes des pratiques de documentation pour 240 patients historiques. Un modèle a été construit reflétant le contenu axé sur les résultats actuels et nouveaux, testé de façon prospective sur 25 patients. Une version électronique a été développée de manière itérative, mise en œuvre et testée de manière prospective. Résultats :Pour l'étape A, la documentation collectée sur trois périodes de temps révèle une documentation cohérente pour seulement trois domaines fonctionnels : le contrôle de la vessie, la déglutition et la capacité de manger indépendamment. La capacité indépendante de mobilité et les activités de la vie quotidienne étaient rarement documentées, à l'exception de la capacité à marcher lorsque l'unité des soins suite à un AVC était en opération, ce qui augmente de 18% à 59%. Pour l'étape B, le contenu du tableau de bord a été établi à partir de l'information discutée lors des rencontres hebdomadaires avec l'unité des AVC. Les items ont été rédigés, classés et les choix de réponses sélectionnés. Des algorithmes ont été créés afin de calculer les scores totaux des indicateurs de récupération fonctionnelle. Douze  itérations ont été effectuées sur une période de 3 mois. Pour l'étape C, pendant le déploiement de la phase papier du tableau de bord, il était clair que ce format ne serait pas adopté par l'équipe, car il était inflexible et restait sur le dossier médical, dupliquant les rapports déjà requis. L'équipe de recherche a dû terminer la quasi-totalité du contenu. Une version électronique via une application a dû être développée sur des appareils mobiles distribués à chaque station d'infirmières. L'équipe de recherche a facilité la transition vers les dossiers électroniques auprès de l'équipe clinique. Pour l'étape D, l'application électronique a été déployée par le personnel de l'unité de soins suite à un AVC. Deux infirmières se sont portées volontaires afin de prendre en charge l'utilisation quotidienne du tableau de bord. Sur une période de 6 mois, 20 itérations du tableau de bord se sont produites pour combler les besoins émergents. Les données de 117 patients ont révélé que le contenu infirmier, environ 50 champs de données, a été complété auprès de plus de 90% des patients. Le contenu des autres membres de l'équipe était moins fréquemment complété : physiothérapeutes (10 champs) ont complété ~ 23%; ergothérapeutes et orthophonistes varient entre 5% et 13%.Conclusion :Ce tableau de bord a procuré de meilleures données systématiques sur la fonction que la tenue de dossier habituelle. Le processus de transmission des connaissances a été efficace pour engager les infirmières en chef et leurs assistantes dans le processus de créer un système de tenu de dossier électronique rencontrant les exigences énoncées par le Ministère de la santé du Québec pour les centres tertiaires suite à un AVC.</description><description>Background: Best-practice guidelines for acute stroke recommend a care pathway, despite limited evidence of impact on functional outcomes. Existing pathways lack elements directly targeting improvement in function; this content might better orient care towards functional outcomes. Objective: The aim was to develop and test the feasibility and impact of a patient-centered Acute Stroke Dashboard to track the functional recovery indicators of patients post-stroke. Methods: Three Knowledge Translation (KT) theories were used to inform development of the Dashboard.  The methods involved a gap analysis of documentation practices for 240 historical patients. A model was built reflecting current and new outcome-focused content, tested prospectively on 25 patients. An electronic version was developed iteratively, implemented and tested  prospectively. Results: For Phase A, documentation over three time periods, revealed consistent documentation of only three functional areas: bladder control, swallowing, and ability to eat independently. Capacity for independent mobility and activities of daily living were rarely documented except for walking capacity when the Stroke Unit was operational which increased from 18% to 59%.  For Phase B, the content for the Dashboard was established from information discussed at weekly Stroke Rounds, the items were worded, and ordering and response options selected. Algorithms were created to calculate total scores from the functional recovery indicators. Twelve iterations were carried out over 3 months. For Phase C, during the deployment of the paper-based Dashboard, it was evident that this format could not be adopted by the Stroke Team as it was inflexible and resided on the medical chart duplicating existing required reporting. The Research Team had to complete almost all content. An electronic APP version was developed on mobile devices distributed to each of the nursing stations. The research team facilitated transfer of the electronic charting to the clinical team.  For Step D, the APP version deployed by the Stroke Unit staff. Two Nurse Champions self-identified and took on the daily use of the APP Dashboard during daily huddles. Over a 6 month period, 20 iterations of the Dashboard occurred to cover emerging needs. Data from 117 patients revealed that nursing content, some 50 data fields, were completed in more than 90% of patients. Content for other team members was less often completed: PT (10 fields) range of completion ~23%; OT/SLP range 5% to 13%. Conclusions: This Dashboard provided better systematic data on function than routine charting. The Knowledge Translation process was effective to engage Nursing Managers and assistant Nurse Managers in the process of creating a viable electronic charting system to meet the requirements set out by the Ministry of Health in Quebec for designation as a Tertiary Stroke Center.</description><creator>Bakhshinategh, Behtash</creator><contributor>Nancy Mayo (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Physical &amp; Occupational Therapy</subject><title>Developing and implementation of an acute stroke dashboard to meet reporting requirements for status as a tertiary care stroke center</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892d71r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r814f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m613n124m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The innate immune system is the first line of defence against HIV, activated within minutes of transmission. HIV must replicate and diversify fast enough to overcome the harsh environment it faces within its target immune cells. The enormous selective pressure that the immune system exercises on replicating HIV species would favor certain phenotypes that permit HIV to replicate despite intrinsic immune factors. Importantly, drug resistance mutations have been shown to be archived and to re-emerge rapidly when failing treatments are re-initiated. It is widely established that resting memory CD4+ T-lymphocytes represent an important latent reservoir for HIV.  Monocytes and macrophage also contribute to the latent reservoir. In addition, monocytes can infiltrate and differentiate in tissues where they reside for decades. They can also penetrate into privileged drug sanctuary sites and they are largely resistant to the cytopathic effects of HIV infection. Wild type (WT) HIV-1 have difficulty infecting dendritic cells (DC), monocytes, macrophage and resting CD4+ T-cells in part because of an intrinsic immune factor called SAMHD1 that keeps dNTP pool low, thus limiting the availability of this substrate for HIV reverse transcription.  Previous work in our laboratory has demonstrated that HIV-1 reverse transcriptase (RT) enzyme harboring specific drug resistance mutations (DRMs) can overcome low dNTP compared to WT. This led us to hypothesis that such DRMs, specifically E138K, may help the virus to overcome SAMHD1 restriction and to replicate better in the above mentioned immune cells.The research I performed during my thesis is divided in 3 parts. First I studied PRMT6 and arginine methylation which we consider to be part of the intrinsic immune system. We had previously showed in the laboratory that PRMT6 is able to restrict HIV replication. My work centered on the regulation of PRMT6 through automethylation that I characterized and demonstrated that PRMT6 automethylation is crucial for its stability and anti-HIV activity. The second intrinsic immune factor I studied was SAMHD1 where I looked at the replication profile of different drug resistant mutants in primary immune cells and cell lines that express or not SAMHD1. I did in fact find that different drug resistant viruses grew differently in different cell types. Most remarkably, some of the single mutants replicate better in DC and resting CD4+ T-cells whereas E138K mutant replicate as well as the WT virus in macrophages.We extended our study to integrase drug resistant mutants given that selection studies in cord blood mononuclear cells indicated that cell types might influence the genotype that are selected for under the integrase inhibitor dolutegravir (DTG) pressure. We found that R263K- and H51Y/R263K-containing HIV replicated better than WT in resting CD4+ T-cells.  This showed both RT and IN drug resistant viruses have improved fitness in specific cells.  Drug resistant virus emerging from long-lived reservoir immune cells could also contribute to the chronic immune activation that is seen in some patients. </description><description>Le système immunitaire inné est la première ligne de défense contre le VIH. Le VIH doit se répliquer et se diversifier suffisamment rapidement pour surmonter l'environnement hostile auquel il fait face à l'intérieur de ses cellules immunitaires cibles. L'énorme pression sélective que le système immunitaire applique sur le virus pourrait paradoxalement favoriser certains phénotypes qui permettent la réplication du VIH en dépit des facteurs immunitaires intrinsèques. Les mutations de résistance aux médicaments sont ainsi archivées dans le réservoir et peuvent réapparaître rapidement lorsque les traitements défaillants sont ré-initiées. Il est largement établi que les lymphocytes CD4+ quiescent représentent un réservoir latent important pour le VIH. Les monocytes et les macrophages contribuent également au réservoir latent. De plus, les monocytes peuvent infiltrer et se différencier dans les tissus où ils résident pendant des décennies. Ils peuvent également pénétrer dans les sites sanctuaires qui sont peu accessibles aux médicaments et ils sont largement résistants aux effets cytopathogèniques du VIH. Le type sauvage du VIH-1 a de la difficulté à infecter les cellules dendritiques, les monocytes, les macrophages et les lymphocytes CD4+ quiescents, en partie à cause d'un facteur immunitaire intrinsèque appelé SAMHD1 qui maintient des concentrations de dNTP faibles, limitant ainsi la disponibilité de ce substrat pour la transcription inverse du VIH. Des travaux antérieurs dans notre laboratoire et d'autres ont démontré que le VIH-1 hébergeant des mutations spécifiques de résistance aux médicaments dans la transcriptase inverse (RT) peut surmonter les faibles concentrations de dNTP mieux que le type sauvage. Cela nous a conduit à l'hypothèse que ces mutations, spécifiquement E138K, peuvent aider le virus à surmonter l'effet négatif de SAMHD1 et à se répliquer mieux dans les cellules immunitaires susmentionnées.La recherche que j'effectué au cours de ma thèse est divisée en 3 parties. Tout d'abord, j'ai étudié PRMT6 et la méthylation de l'arginine que nous considérons comme faisant partie du système immunitaire intrinsèque. Il avait été montré précédemment dans le laboratoire que PRMT6 est en mesure de limiter la réplication du VIH. Mon travail a été centré sur la régulation de PRMT6 par automethylation que j'ai caractérisé et j'ai démontré que l'automethylation de PRMT6 est cruciale pour sa stabilité et son activité anti-VIH.Le deuxième facteur immunitaire intrinsèque que j'ai étudié est SAMHD1. J'ai mesuré le profil de réplication de différents mutants résistants aux médicaments dans les cellules immunitaires primaires et des lignées cellulaires qui expriment ou non SAMHD1. J'ai découvert que certains virus résistants aux médicaments se répliquent différemment dans différents types de cellules. De manière remarquable, certains de ces mutants simples répliquent mieux dans les cellules dendritiques et les lymphocytes CD4+ quiescents, tandis que le mutant E138K se réplique aussi bien que le virus de type sauvage dans les macrophages.Nous avons élargi notre étude à des mutants dans l'intégrase qui sont aussi résistants aux médicaments étant donné que les études de sélection dans les cellules mononucléées du sang de cordon ont indiquées que différents types de cellules peuvent influencer les génotypes qui sont sélectionnés en présence de l'inhibiteur d'intégrase dolutégravir (DTG). Nous avons constaté que les virus qui contiennent R263K et H51Y/R263K se répliquent mieux que le type sauvage dans les lymphocytes CD4+ quiescents. Cela montre que les virus résistants aux médicaments qui ont des mutations dans la RT ou dans intégrase peuvent dans les deux cas se répliquer efficacement dans des cellules spécifiques. La réplication persistante de certains de ces mutants résistants aux médicaments dans les cellules immunitaires réservoirs pourrait également contribuer à l'activation immunitaire chronique que l'on voit chez certains patients</description><creator>Singhroy, Diane</creator><contributor>Mark Wainberg (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Microbiology &amp; Immunology</subject><title>Host-virus interactions: innate immunity in wild-type and drug-resistant HIV-1 infections</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x407p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n124m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hm50tv245</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Appraisal of the impact of Bariatric surgery on health related quality of life and work productivity in morbidly obese patients Background: In the last decades, morbid obesity has emerged as an increasingly prevalent chronic metabolic disorder affecting populations located in both developed and emerging countries. Obesity is associated with increased morbidity, disability and premature mortality.  Given the impact of obesity on health status and its related economic burden, it is reasonable to anticipate that weight loss in obese patients will be associated with health and economic benefits. Bariatric surgery has emerged as a treatment of choice for this patient population. Significant reductions in mean percent excess weight loss and BMI percent change are observed as a consequence of Bariatric surgery. Several studies have established that obese individuals experience significant impairments in quality of life as a result of their condition.  Health related quality of life (HRQoL) represents a particularly important and relevant outcome when assessing the overall impact of chronic conditions such as obesity. The data published as of date reports a significant correlation between excess weight loss and improvement in weight specific and physical aspects of HRQoL. However, trends toward decreases in HRQoL associated with weight regain between the first and sixth year post surgery have also been reported. The evidence relating to change in HRQoL in obese patients following Bariatric surgery for weight loss is currently either of relatively low quality or mainly focussed on evaluating the short-term impact of the intervention on HRQoL. Often overlooked but equally important is the relationship between obesity and its outcome on work productivity.  Ample evidence underlining the correlation between obesity, increased work limitation and productivity loss may be found in the literature. The need for further evaluation of HRQoL and productivity loss outcomes over longer time horizons, following Bariatric surgery, has actually been identified as key areas of focus in this field of research, given the chronic nature of the disease and its considerable economic burden. Long-term outcomes data related to HRQoL and productivity loss following Bariatric surgery remains scarce in the Canadian setting.  Objective: To describe the impact of Bariatric surgery on HRQoL and work productivity in patients with morbid obesity. Methodology: A cross-sectional survey measuring health related quality of life and work productivity outcomes, using the SF-36, the EQ-5D and the WLQ, for morbidly obese patients sampled from a population of patients being treated at the McGill University Health Centre (MUHC). Results: We observed Improvements in HRQoL and WLQ outcomes over the follow-up time period following Bariatric surgery and that, for all outcome measures.  Conclusion: Following Bariatric surgery, patients may experience less physical disability and mental health issues and the perception of their health related quality of life state was reported to be significantly better than before the surgery. Per our findings, the initial positive impact of Bariatric surgery on HRQoL appeared to be sustained over time. Increases in physical disability, work limitations and decreases in patients' perception of their health status may be consequential to increments in BMI units and years of follow-up since the surgical intervention. Our findings further corroborated trends towards decreases in the occurrence of chronic comorbidities following Bariatric surgery.</description><description>Évaluation de l'impact de la chirurgie Bariatrique sur la qualité de vie liée à la santé et la productivité au travail chez les patients souffrant d'obésité morbide Contexte: Dernièrement, l'obésité morbide est apparue comme une des maladies métaboliques chroniques la plus répandue affectant les pays développés et émergents. L'obésité est associée à une augmentation de la morbidité, de l'incapacité physique et de la mortalité prématurée. Compte tenu de l'impact de l'obésité sur l'état de santé et son fardeau économique, il est raisonnable de prévoir que la perte de poids chez les patients obèses aurait un avantage sur la santé public et le plan économique. La chirurgie Bariatrique est apparue comme le traitement de choix pour cette population de patients. Des réductions significatives d'excès de poids et d'index de masse corporelle (IMC) sont observées suite à la chirurgie Bariatrique. Plusieurs études ont établi que les personnes obèses connaissent des déficiences importantes de qualité de vie liée à la santé. La qualité de vie liée à la santé (QVLS) représente une mesure particulièrement important et pertinent pour évaluer l'impact global des maladies chroniques telles que l'obésité. Les données présentement publiées rapportent une corrélation significative entre la perte de l'excès de poids et l'amélioration des aspects physiques spécifiques de la QVLS. Cependant, les tendances vers des baisses de QVLS associées à la reprise de poids entre la première et la sixième année après la chirurgie ont également été rapportés. Les éléments de preuve relatifs aux changements reliant la QVLS chez les patients obèses après la chirurgie Bariatrique sont actuellement soit de faibles qualités ou principalement axées sur l'évaluation de l'impact à court terme sur la QVLS, après l'intervention. Souvent négligée, mais tout aussi importante est la relation entre l'obésité et la productivité au travail. Les preuves présentement disponibles dans le domaine publique soulignent la corrélation entre l'obésité, l'augmentation des limitations au travail et la perte de productivité. La nécessité de poursuivre l'évaluation de la relation entre la QVLS et la perte de productivité au cours des horizons plus longs, après la chirurgie Bariatrique, a été identifié comme un point de recherche d'intérêt, étant donné la nature chronique de la maladie et son fardeau économique considérable. Les données résultant de l'évaluation à long terme de la relation entre la QVLS et la perte de productivité après la chirurgie Bariatrique demeurent rares dans le contexte canadien. But: Décrire l'impact de la chirurgie Bariatrique sur la QVLS et la productivité au travail chez les patients atteints d'obésité morbide. Méthodologie: Une enquête transversale mesurant la QVLS et de la productivité au travail, à l'aide du SF-36, l'EQ-5D et le WLQ, chez des patients souffrant d'obésité morbide échantillonnés à partir d'une population de patients traités au Centre universitaire de santé McGill (CUSM). Résultats: Nous avons observé des améliorations des résultats pour la QVLS et la productivité au travail au cours de la période de suivi après la chirurgie Bariatrique et ce, pour toutes les mesures évaluées. Conclusion: Après la chirurgie Bariatrique, les patients peuvent éprouver moins d'handicap physique et les problèmes de santé mentale, et la perception de leur état de santé liés à la qualité de vie a été signalé comme étant beaucoup améliorée suivant la chirurgie. D'après nos résultats, l'impact positif initial observé suite à la chirurgie Bariatrique sur la QVLS semble être soutenue au fil du temps. Une augmentation de l'invalidité, des limites physiques au travail et une diminution de la perception de l'état de santé peuvent être consécutifs à des augmentations d'unités d'IMC et des années de suivi après l'intervention chirurgicale. De plus, nos résultats corroborent les tendances vers une diminution de la présence de comorbidités chroniques après la chirurgie Bariatrique.</description><creator>Desrosiers, Nathalie</creator><contributor>John Sotirios Sampalis (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Surgery</subject><title>Appraisal of the impact of Bariatric surgery on health related quality of life and work productivity in morbidly obese patients</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870z71p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tv245</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n009w505s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La modélisation numérique des problèmes d'interaction sol-structure impliquant des inclusions géo-synthétiques flexibles ou souples et de grande déformation est reconnue pour sa complexité, surtout en présence de structures rigides à proximité. Cette thèse a pour objectif majeur l'élaboration d'un concept de modélisation numérique pour les problèmes d'interaction sol-géo synthétiques. Il fait état des résultats des analyse 2D et 3D avec la modélisation explicite de la géométrie et des détails des matériaux de la structure géosynthétique et le remblai environnant. Deux types de géo synthétiques qui sont couramment utilisés dans les projets géotechniques sont considérés en utilisant le cadre numérique proposée; géogrille et Polystyrèene expansé (PSE) Geofoam. Une procédure numérique de modélisation du comportement à court terme de Geofoam PSE soumis à une charge uni axiale de compression est d'abord développé et validé pour trois matériaux de Geofoam PSE différents. Pour examiner les performances de ce modèle dans l'analyse des problèmes d'interaction complexes, une expérience de laboratoire qui implique une structure rigide enterrée dans un matériau granulaire avec un ajout de Geofoam PSE est simulée par analyse 2D. Le rôle de la matière Geofoam PSE, les propriétés géométriques et la configuration sur la réduction des pressions de terre qui agissent sur les structures enterrées sont étudiés. Les résultats ont montré que l'introduction du bloc de Geofoam PSE immédiatement au-dessus de la structure a un effet important sur la distribution des pressions de contact en particulier sur la paroi supérieure de la structure. Le reste de la thèse est consacrée à l'introduction d'un cadre numérique adapté aux analyses en trois dimensions des applications impliquant l'interaction sol-géogrille. La réponse de géogrille est étudiée dans les deux environnements non confinés et des sols confinés en utilisant différentes conditions de chargement (par exemple vertical fondation chargement et retrait de chargement). L'approche proposée FE a prouvé son efficacité dans la capture la réponse 3D de la géogrille, le remblai environnant et la géogrille-remblayage interaction de contact.</description><description>Numerical modeling of soil-structure interaction problems involving flexible or soft geosynthetic inclusions and large deformation is known to be challenging, especially in the presence of nearby structures. This thesis is devoted to developing a numerical modeling framework for the analysis of soil-geosynthetic interaction problems. It reports the results of both 2D and 3D analyses with explicit modeling of the geometry and material behavior of geosynthetics and the surrounding backfill. The numerical results are validated using existing laboratory experimental data. Two types of geosynthetics that are commonly used in geotechnical engineering projects are considered using the proposed numerical framework; EPS geofoam and geogrid.  A numerical procedure for modeling the short-term response of EPS geofoam is first developed and validated for three different EPS geofoam materials. To examine the performance of such model in analyzing complex interaction problems, a laboratory experiment that involves a rigid structure buried in granular material with EPS geofoam inclusion is simulated using a series of 2D finite element analysis. The role of geofoam material, geometrical properties, and configuration on the reduction of earth loads acting on buried structures are investigated. Results showed that the introduction of EPS geofoam block immediately above the structure has a significant effect on the contact pressure distribution particularly on the upper wall of the structure. The rest of the thesis is devoted to introducing a numerical framework that is suitable for the three-dimensional analysis of applications involving soil-geogrid interaction. The geogrid response is investigated under both unconfined and soil-confined environments using different loading conditions (e.g. vertical foundation loading and pullout loading). The proposed FE approach has proven to be efficient in capturing the 3D response of the geogrid, the surrounding backfill, and the geogrid-backfill contact interaction. </description><creator>Hussein, Mahmoud</creator><contributor>Mohamed Meguid (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Civil Engineering &amp; Applied Mechanics</subject><title>Numerical modeling framework for soil-geosynthetics interaction problems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h220b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w505s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074x84w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Importance: Noise induced hearing loss is an increasingly worrisome problem. Although caffeine intake is common in people who are in noisy environments, the effect of caffeine on the recovery of hearing after a temporary threshold shift requires further understanding. Objectives: To determine whether caffeine impairs hearing recovery in guinea pigs exposed to acoustic overstimulation.  Design, Setting, Subjects: Twenty four female guinea pigs were divided into three groups. This study was approved by McGill University Ethics review board and the University animal care committee. The experiment took place at the McGill University Auditory Sciences Laboratory. Intervention: Group 1: received caffeine; Group 2: exposed to acoustic overstimulation events (AOSEs); Group 3: exposed to AOSEs and caffeine. Daily caffeine dose for groups 1 and 3 was 25 mg/kg administered intraperitoneally. AOSEs were administered on days 1 and 8 and consisted of a one hour of 110 dB SPL pure-tone sound. Serial auditory brain stem response tests (ABRs) were measured to determine the audiological threshold shift and recovery. Scanning Electron Microscopy (SEM) and Light Microscopic (LM) analysis were performed. Main Outcomes and Measures:ABRs at mid first week, one week mark, mid second week and two weeks mark. In addition to SEM and LM analysis of the cochlea Results: The 1 hour post acoustic overstimulation resulted in a similar threshold shift between all animals in groups 2 and 3 at all frequencies tested (8, 16, 20 and 25khz). Maximum threshold shift was at 16khz with a mean of 66 and 54 dB respectively. By day 8, group 2 threshold shift recovered completely in all frequency except at 20 kHz. Group 3 hearing impairment persisted in 3 frequencies (8, 16 and 25khz) with a threshold of 22, 28 and 26 dB respectively (p value 0.001). Following a second acoustic overstimulation at day 8, similar threshold shift and outcome was recorded on day 15, as compared to day 8. SEM &amp; light microscope showed more aggressive changes in the group that received AOSEs and caffeine (Group 3) compared to the group that was only exposed to AOSEs (Group 2).   The difference in ABR threshold recovery was in concordance with SEM and light microscopic findings of each group. Conclusion: A daily dose of caffeine was found to impair the recovery of hearing after an acoustic overstimulation event. </description><description>Importance: La perte d'audition due au bruit est un problème de plus en plus inquiétant. Bien que la consommation de caféine est fréquente chez les personnes impliquées dans des environnements bruyants, l'effet de la caféine sur la reprise de l'audition après un déplacement temporaire du seuil d'audibilité nécessite une meilleure compréhension. Objectifs: Déterminer si la caféine affecte la reprise d'audition chez les cochons d'Inde après une surstimulation acoustique. Sujets: Vingt-quatre cochons d'Inde femelles ont été divisés en trois groupes. Cette étude a été approuvée par le department d'éthique en recherche et du comité de protection des animaux de l'Université de McGill. L'expérience a eu lieu au Laboratoire des Sciences Auditives de l'Université de McGill. Interventions: Le groupe 1 a reçu de la caféine. Le groupe 2 a été exposés à des événements de surstimulation acoustiques (ESAs). Le groupe 3 a été exposée à des ESAs et à de la caféine. La dose de caféine par jour pour les groupes 1 et 3 était de 25 mg / kg, administrée par voie intrapéritonéale. Les ESAs ont été administrées aux jours 1 et 8 et consistait d'une heure de son pur de 110 dB. Des tests des potentiels évoqués auditifs du tronc cérébral (ABR) ont été mesurés pour déterminer le décalage du seuil d'audibilité et de sa récupération. Une analyse avec la microscopie électronique à balayage (MEB) et la microscopie optique (MO) ont été effectuées.Mesures principales:Des tests des potentiels évoqués auditifs du tronc cérébral (ABR) ont été mesurés au milieu de la première semaine, à une semaine, au milieu de la deuxième semaine et à deux semaines. En plus, une analyse de la cochlée a été faite avec la MEB et la MO.  Résultats: Une heure après une surstimulation acoustique, le déplacement du seuil d'audibilité etait similaire entre tous les animaux dans les groupes 2 et 3 dans les fréquences testées (8, 16, 20 et 25 kHz). Ce changement de seuil etait maximal à 16 kHz avec une moyenne de 66 et 54 dB, respectivement. Au jour 8, le changement s'est normalisé complètement dans toutes les fréquences sauf à 20 kHz. La déficience auditive a persisté dans le groupe 3 à trois fréquences (8, 16 et 25 kHz) avec un seuil de 22, 28 et 26 dB, respectivement (valeur p de 0,001). Après une deuxième surstimulation acoustique au jour 8, des résultats similaires ont été enregistrées au jour 15. La différence entre les deux groupes était en concordance avec les résultats de la MEB et de la MO. Conclusion: Une dose quotidienne de caféine a été trouvé à altérer la reprise de l'audition après un événement de surstimulation acoustique.</description><creator>Zawawi, Faisal</creator><contributor>Jamie M Rappaport (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Sam Joseph Daniel (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Otolaryngology - Head and Neck Surgery</subject><title>Association of caffeine and hearing recovery after acoustic overstimulation events in a guinea pig model</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644v30f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074x84w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Otolaryngology - Head and Neck Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860958p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study is concerned with the 2-D transient energy storage and energy recovery for arbitrary-shaped double pipe latent heat thermal energy storage (LHTES) units for the efficient utilization of the solar energy and industrial waste heat. The phase change material (PCM) which is selected here is commercially available paraffin wax which melts and freezes over a fixed temperature range of 8.7oC. The arbitrary nature of the computational domain is accounted for through the use of a non-orthogonal boundary-fitted coordinate (BFC) system on a staggered grid arrangement. An enthalpy-porosity scheme is used to model the various complex mushy region phase change problems. The continuum mixture model is implemented for tackling the above phase change problems. A control volume based finite-difference scheme is used to discretize the mixture model equations. A series of simulation runs is carried out to investigate the effects of inner tube wall temperature, varying from 69.9oC to 89.9oC, the duration of the melting time, the initial temperature of the solid PCM ranging from 41.2oC to 51.2oC, the shapes of inner and outer tubes, the orientations of the horizontal outer enclosure, the eccentricity/concentricity of the inner tube, and of the various thermal boundary conditions on the inner tube. Two orientations of the outer triangular tube are selected to utilize the attic space of a domestic dwelling more efficiently. The predicted results show that neither the change in the inner tube boundary conditions nor the configurations/orientations of the inner and outer tubes have resulted in the appreciable improvement of the performance of the units after an elapsed time period of 14.87 min. To overcome the above limitation, the effect of the high thermally conductive dispersed nanoparticles in the base PCM is modeled. It is observed that the cumulatively charged energy is greatly enhanced using the PCM with copper nanoparticles as compared to the base PCM for all studied geometries except for the right triangular enclosure with the concentric inner tubes. With the increase in volume fraction of nanoparticles, the energy storage capacity of the unit is decreased and it is true for all the three Rayleigh numbers studied.The numerical study is also carried out to investigate the effect of an alternate melting/freezing cycle. The results show that the net energy stored is greater than the net energy retrieved irrespective of the configuration of the LHTES devices. The study of an alternate melting/freezing cycle indicates that the cumulatively charged/discharged of thermal energy is the highest for the inverted triangular enclosure with an eccentric inner circular tube near the top of the outer tube among all the studied heat exchangers.</description><description>Cette étude est concernée avec de la 2-D de stockage d'énergie transitoire et récupération d'énergie pour en forme arbitraire du tuyau double stockage d'énergie thermique de la chaleur latente (LHTES) unités pour une utilisation efficace de l'énergie solaire et la chaleur des déchets industriels. Les matériaux à changement de phase (PCM) qui est sélectionné ici est commercialement disponible de la cire de paraffine qui fond et gèle sur une plage de température fixe de 8.7oC. Le caractère arbitraire du domaine de calcul sont comptabilisées par l'utilisation d'une non-orthogonale coordonnées ajustées aux limites des unités hors Siège (BFC) Système sur un arrangement de grille étagée. Une enthalpie-porosité schéma est utilisé pour modéliser l'écheveau complexe des divers région bourbeuse problèmes de changement de phase. Le continuum mélange modèle est implémenté pour aborder les problèmes de changement de phase ci-dessus. Un volume de contrôle fondée par différence finie schéma est utilisé afin de diviser les équations du modèle de mélange. Une série de simulations a été réalisée pour étudier les effets de la température de paroi du tube intérieur, variant de 69,9o C à 89,9o C, la durée de la temps de fusion, la température initiale du PCM solides allant de 41,2o C à 51,2o C, les formes des tubes intérieurs et extérieurs, les orientations de l'action horizontale le boîtier externe, de l'excentricité/concentricité du tube intérieur, et des diverses conditions limite thermique sur le tube intérieur. Deux orientations de l'extérieur sont sélectionnés pour tubes triangulaires à utiliser l'espace de grenier d'une habitation plus efficacement. Les résultats prédits montrent que ni les modifier dans le tube intérieur conditions limites ni les configurations/orientations du tubes intérieurs et extérieurs ont entraîné l'amélioration sensible de la performance des unités après une période de temps écoulée de 14,87 min. pour surmonter la limitation ci-dessus, l'effet de la forte dispersion thermoconducteur nanoparticules dans le PCM de base est modélisée. Il est observé que l'cumulativement est grandement améliorée de l'énergie chargée à l'aide du PCM avec des nanoparticules de cuivre par rapport à la base pour tous étudié géométries PCM sauf pour le droit triangulaire boîtier avec les tubes intérieurs concentriques. Avec l'augmentation de volume fraction des nanoparticules, la capacité de stockage de l'énergie de l'unité diminue et c'est vrai pour les trois numéros Rayleigh étudiés.L'étude numérique est également réalisée pour étudier l'effet d'un autre cycle de fusion/congélation. Les résultats montrent que l'énergie nette stockée est supérieur au montant net de l'énergie récupérée indépendamment de la configuration de l'LHTES périphériques. L'étude d'un autre cycle de fusion/congélation indique que la cumulativement chargé/déchargé de l'énergie thermique est la plus élevée pour l' inversion triangulaire à un excentrique du boîtier tube circulaire intérieur près du haut de la tube extérieur parmi tous les échangeurs de chaleur étudiés.</description><creator>Tabassum, Tonny</creator><contributor>Mainul Hasan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Mining and Materials</subject><title>Transient latent heat thermal energy storage in complex annuli</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602361g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860958p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5999n605v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La recherche en composition assistée par ordinateur (CAO) a pour but d'offrir aux compositeurs des langages de programmation et des interfaces spécialisés permettant de simuler des processus compositionnels dans un cadre interactif et basé sur la notion de modélisation. Bien que la disponibilité et le niveau de performance des ressources informatiques se soient développés depuis les dernières décennies et aient conduit à une prolifération de l'utilisation des technologies dans la pratique musicale, en particulier dans les domaines de l'audio spatialisé, du contrôle gestuel et de la synthèse sonore, ces développements sont demeurés relativement isolés du domaine de la CAO et n'ont donc pas été pris en compte dans les modèles et applications relatifs à celle-ci. Cette thèse propose un développement des systèmes de composition assistée par ordinateur en y intégrant des outils concernant les données d'ordre spatial, gestuel et sonore, dans l'objectif de rendre ces technologies disponibles et réactives dans le contexte de la composition écrite ou symbolique. Nous présentons la conception, le design et des applications d'une structure logicielle intégrée sous la forme de trois bibliothèques pour l'environnement de composition assistée par ordinateur OpenMusic. La bibliothèque "OM-Prisma" permet la spécification de processus de spatialisation de complexité arbitraire et les relie à d'autres processus et matériaux musicaux de haut niveau dans un environnement compositionnel. Nous introduisons un nouveau paradigme au-delà des concepts conventionnels, qui dépasse la spatialisation d'objets sonores individuels pour atteindre la microstructure du son et ainsi réaliser une "synthèse du son spatialisée". La bibliothèque "OM-Geste" propose des solutions pour intégrer les gestes physiques comme matériaux dans les formalisations musicales. La description, la représentation et le traitement des gestes en tant que signaux multidimensionnels y sont discutés et nos pistes de solutions y sont présentées. Un système est introduit et permet de concevoir le "mapping" comme un programme pour la création d'objets musicaux d'échelle et de résolutions arbitraires en utilisant des spécifications hybrides. En guise de validation, deux exemples complémentaires, incluant des enregistrements de gestes réels y sont décrits.La bibliothèque "OM-Pursuit" introduit un système d'analyse/synthèse fondé sur des dictionnaires qui fournit des représentations abstraites de son-cible qui sont susceptibles d'être intégrées et manipulées par des procédés compositionnels dans le domaine symbolique. Ce modèle constitue une contrepartie granulaire aux modèles sinusoïdaux dominants et permet le renouvellement des manières de concevoir le son et la composition. Une application professionnelle de ce logiciel dans le cadre de la composition d'une oeuvre pour piano contrôlé par ordinateur et dispositif électronique y est décrite.Les bibliothèques logicielles présentées dans cette thèse ont été conçues comme une structure cohérente à partir des mêmes concepts, interfaces et structures de données. Tous les développements exposés sont en accès libre ; ce sont des projets open-source et ils ont été validés au sein de productions artistiques professionnelles, de projets de recherche et font maintenant partie des programmes d'études de musique électronique dans différentes universités et institutions de recherche.Mots-clés : Composition assistée par ordinateur, spatialisation, geste, mapping, synthèse sonore.</description><description>Computer-Aided Composition (CAC) research aims to provide composers with specialized programming languages and interfaces to simulate processes of composition in an interactive approach referred to as "compositional modelling". Although the increased performance and availability of computer resources over the past decade has led to a widening of technologies used in musical practice, in particular in the fields of spatial audio, physical computing and sound synthesis, these developments have remained mostly isolated from the domain of CAC and are therefore not accounted for in the corresponding models and applications. This dissertation proposes a further evolution of CAC systems by integrating spatial-, sound-, and gesture-related data with the objective of making these technologies available and responsive to formal music composition. We present conception, design, and applications of an original software framework implemented as three libraries for the visual computer- aided composition environment OpenMusic. The library "OMPrisma" allows for the design of spatialization processes of arbitrary complexity and relate them to high-level musical processes and materials in a compositional framework. Beyond conventional concepts we introduce a novel paradigm which extends the notion of sound source spatialization from pre-existing sound objects to the spatial micro-structure of sound, referred to as spatial sound synthesis. The library "OM-Geste" proposes solutions for integrating physical gestures as materials into compositional formalisms. Coding, representation and processing of gestures as multi- dimensional signals are discussed and design guidelines are presented. A novel approach is introduced which allows to extend the scope of "mapping" to high-level programs for creating musical objects of arbitrary scales using hybrid specifications. Two complementary examples for validation with the use of real-world gesture recordings are described. The library "OM-Pursuit" introduces a dictionary-based analysis/synthesis system which provides abstract representations of sound targets that can be integrated and manipulated within symbolic compositional processes. This model constitutes a granular counterpart to the prevalent sinusoidal representations and allows for renewed conceptions of sound and compositional directions. A professional application of the software for a composition for computer-controlled piano and electronics is described. The presented software libraries have been designed as a coherent framework based on the same design concepts, interfaces and programming tools. All of the presented developments are free, open-source projects and have been validated in professional artistic productions, research projects, and are now part of computer music curricula in different universities and research institutions.Keywords: Computer-Aided Composition, Spatialization, Gesture, Mapping, Sound Representation</description><creator>Schumacher, Mario Marlon</creator><contributor>Sean Alastair Ferguson (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Marcelo Wanderley (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Music</subject><title>A framework for computer-aided composition of space, gesture, and sound. Conception, design, and applications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117r63d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n605v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gq97t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Proprotein convertases (PCs) are serine proteases that cleave secretory proteins after specific residues, resulting in final active or inactive forms. In mammals, the family of PCs comprises nine members, PC1/3, PC2, furin, PC4, PC5/6, PACE4, PC7, SKI-1/S1P, and PCSK9.  While the first seven cleave after basic residues with the motif (K/R)-2X-(K/R)↓ (X=0-3 residues), SKI-1/S1P cleaves after small amino acids (aa) at the motif R-X-(L/V/I)-X↓, and PCSK9 only cleaves itself at the sequence VFAQ↓. Among them, the closely related furin, PC5/6, PACE4, and PC7, so called furin-like PCs, are widely expressed, and share many in vitro/ex vivo substrate hormones, receptors, viral proteins, and growth factors. Although recent research showed their consensus sequence and in vitro/ex vivo substrates, we are far from fully understanding the consequences of their physiological actions and identifying substrates in vivo. Their redundant functions are probable considering the similarity in their target aa sequences. However, recent evidences prove that, in vivo, PCs process specific substrates in ways that result in unique, complementary, or opposite physiological consequences. My research aimed to unravel these specific in vivo functions of PCs, partners, and target substrates. First, I studied a unique role of furin by generating its endothelial cell-specific knockout mice. Newborns die shortly after birth, and magnetic resonance images (MRI) revealed that knockout embryos exhibit ventricular septal defects and/or valve malformations, owing to defective processing of endothelin-1, adrenomedullin, TGFβ-1, and BMP4. Secondly, I studied the roles of furin-like PCs in HIV-associated neurocognitive disorder (HAND). I showed the abundance of PC mRNAs in postmortem brains of individuals exhibiting HAND, driven by neuroinflammation with increased expression of proteinase-activated receptor 1 (PAR1), an inflammation-associated receptor, which I proved to be inactivated by the soluble PACE4 and PC5/6A. Unexpectedly, PAR1 was not cleaved by, but inhibited, the membrane-bound basic aa-specific furin, PC5B and PC7. This data revealed a PC-PAR1-interaction network, which offsets the effects of HIV-induced neuroinflammation, viral infection, and development of HAND. The following report presents the fascinating biology of these phylogenetically ancient proteases, in hopes of leading to their translational trajectory "from bench to bedside". </description><description>Les proprotéines convertases (PC) sont des protéases à sérine qui clivent les protéines sécrétoires après des résidus spécifiques, produisant ainsi des formes actives ou inactives. Chez les mammifères, la famille des PC est composée de neuf membres : PC1/3, PC2, furine, PC4, PC5/6, PACE4, PC7, SKI-1/S1P et PCSK9. Alors que les sept premiers clivent après des résidus basiques selon le motif (K/R)-2X-(K/R), dans lequel X = 0 à 3 résidus, SKI-1/S1P clive après de petits acides aminés au motif R-X-(L/V/I)-X↓ et PCSK9 ne peut que s'autocliver à la séquence VFAQ↓. Les enzymes furine, PC5/6, PACE4 et PC7 sont très similaires, et ont été dénommées "enzymes du type furine". Elles sont largement exprimées et partagent un grand nombre de substrats in vitro/ex vivo : hormones, récepteurs, protéines virales, facteurs croissance, etc. Nous sommes cependant loin de comprendre leur rôle physiologique. L'existence d'une redondance in vivo est probable, étant donnée la grande similitude de leurs motifs de clivage. Toutefois, des études montrent qu'elles exercent des fonctions physiologiques uniques, complémentaires ou opposés. C'est sur l'élucidation de ces fonctions que mes recherches ont porté via l'identification de substrats spécifiques in vivo et de possibles partenaires. J'ai tout d'abord révélé un rôle unique de la furine. J'ai produit des souris déficientes en furine, spécifiquement dans les cellules endothéliales. Les nouveaux nés meurent peu après la naissance à cause de défauts du septum ventriculaire et/ou des valves que nous avons identifiés par résonance magnétique (MRI). J'ai pu montrer que ces défauts étaient associés à une maturation déficiente de l'endothéline-1, de l'adrénomédulline, du TGFβ-1, et du BMP4. J'ai ensuite étudié les rôles des PC du type furine dans la maladie neurocognitive associée au VIH (HAND). J'ai observé une augmentation des ARNm des PC dans le cerveau post-mortem des patients en réponse à une neuroinflammation caractérisée par une expression accrue du proteinase-activated receptor 1 (PAR1). PAR1 un récepteur associé à l'inflammation, et activé par clivage de sa région N-terminale. J'ai démontré que PACE4 et PC5/6A solubles inactivaient PAR1 et, de façon inattendue, que les PC furine, PC5/6B et PC7 (toutes trois ancrées dans la membrane) inhibaient PAR1. Ces interactions PC-PAR1 compensent donc les effets de la neuroinflammation liée au HIV et le développement de HAND. Le rapport qui suit présente la biologie fascinante de ces protéases phylogénétiquement anciennes, dans l'espoir que la modulation de leur activité mène à des applications "de la paillasse au chevet du patient".</description><creator>Kim, WooJin</creator><contributor>Nabil G Seidah (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>The multifaceted Furin-like proprotein convertases: defining their «in vivo» roles in physiological models</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hf895.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gq97t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6q182n799</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Une approche biocatalytique basée sur la réaction de transfructosylation de saccharose catalysé par endo-inulinase dans un milieu non-conventionnel a été étudiée pour la synthèse de fructooligosaccharides bien définies. Endo-inulinase d'Aspergillus niger a été purifiée par une chromatographie d'échange d'anion. Les réactions de transfructosylation ont été effectuées dans un milieu biphasique composé d'une phase organique/tampon (3: 1, v: v) à 35/40°C sous une agitation de 150 trs par minute. L'heptane, l'heptanone, le cyclohexane, l'acétate de butyle et l'acétate d'éthyle ont été utilisés comme solvants organique dans le milieu biphasique. Les composantes de la réaction ont été analysées par la chromatographie d'échange d'anions à haute performance équipée d'un détecteur ampérométrique pulsée. La vitesse initiale la plus élevée de 1500.00 μmol/ml.min a été obtenue dans le milieu biphasique composé d'heptane/tampon, suivie d'une vitesse initiale de 1000.67 μmol/ml.min qui a été observée dans le milieu biphasique composé d'acétate de butyle/tampon. Tandis que l'utilisation d'un milieu biphasique composé d'hexane/tampon a conduit à une vitesse initiale la plus faible de 69.62 μmol/ml.min. Bien que le milieu biphasique composé d'acétate de butyle/tampon a conduit à la bioconversion la plus élevée de 93.94%, la réaction de transfructosylation dans ce milieu ne représentait que 43.33% par rapport à celle d'hydrolyse. La proportion relative de la réaction du transfructosylation la plus élevée de 79.34% a été estimée dans le milieu biphasique contenant l'heptane. Le milieu biphasique composé de l'acétate de butyle/tampon a permis l'obtention d'un rendement de bioconversion des fructooligosaccharides le plus élevé de 60.24%. 1-kestose était le plus abondant fructooligosaccharides suivi par nystose et fructosyl-nystose.Les effets de l'unité enzymatique, la proportion du solvant acétate de butyle et le temps réactionnel sur la synthèse de fructooligosaccharides (réponses : concentrations de kestose, nystose et fructosyl nystose et le rendement de bioconversion) ont été évalués en utilisant la méthode de surface de réponse (RSM). L'analyse RSM a démontré que la variable la plus significative dépendait des réponses. L'unité enzymatique a montré un effet linéaire très significatif dans le model prédictive de la concentration kestose, tandis que dans les autres modèles prédictifs de la concentration de nystose et du rendement de bioconversion, le temps de réaction et la proportion de solvant étaient les variables les plus déterminantes, respectivement. Toutefois, pour la réponse de concentration de fructosyl nystose, tous les termes linéaires des variables étaient significatifs dans son model.La production de fructooligosaccharides par l'endo-inulinase dans un milieu biphasique contenant des sirops d'érable ayant des Brix sélectionnées (15º, 30º, 60º) a été investiguée sur une période de réaction de 16 à 80h. Parmi ces trois sirops d'érable, celui ayant 66°Bx a conduit au rendement de bioconversion le plus élevé de 52,53% après 80h de réaction. La production de kestose la plus élevée a été obtenue dans le sirop d'érable de 15º Bx tandis que le taux le plus élevé de nystose et fructosyl nystose ont été obtenus avec le sirop d'érable de 66 ° Bx. L'étude avec l'approche biocatalytique a démontré un grand potentiel pour la synthèse de fructooligosaccharides comme ingrédients fonctionnels et aussi dans le développement de nouvelles applications pour le sirop d'érable.</description><description>A biocatalytic approach based on endo-inulinase-catalyzed transfructosylation reaction in non-conventional media using sucrose as substrate was investigated for the synthesis of well-defined fructooligosaccharides. Endo-Inulinase from Aspergillus niger was purified by anion exchange chromatography. The transfructosylation reactions were carried out in selected organic/buffer biphasic systems (3:1, v/v) at 35/40°C and 150 rpm. Heptane, heptanone, cyclohexane, butyl acetate and ethyl acetate were the investigated organic solvents. The reaction components were analyzed by high performance anion exchange chromatography equipped with pulsed amperometric detector. The highest initial velocity of 1,500.0 μmol/ml.min was observed in the heptane/buffer biphasic system followed by the butyl acetate /buffer biphasic system with an initial velocity of 1,000.7 μmol/ml.min. However, the lowest initial velocity of 69.6 μmol/ml.min was obtained in the hexane/buffer biphasic system. Although the butyl acetate/buffer system resulted in the highest sucrose conversion of 93.94%, the relative proportion of the transfructosylation reaction was only 43.33%. The highest transfructosylation relative proportions of 79.34% was reported in the heptane/buffer biphasic systems. The highest fructooligosaccharides bioconversion yield of 60.24% was obtained in the butyl acetate/buffer biphasic system after 48 h of reaction, with nystose as the main end-product. 1-kestose was the most abundant fructooligosaccharides produced followed by nystose and fructosyl-nystose. The effects of enzyme unit, proportion of butyl acetate solvent and reaction time on the kestose, nystose and fructosyl-nystose concentrations as well as the bioconversion yield of fructooligosaccharides were studied, using a response surface methodology (RSM). The RSM analysis showed that the most significant variable was different for the various responses. The linear term of the enzyme unit exhibited the most significant effect on the kestose concentration, whereas for the nystose concentration and fructooligosaccharides bioconversion yield responses, the reaction time and the proportion of solvent were the most significant variables, respectively. However, for the fructosyl-nystose concentration response, all linear terms were found to be significant. Among the interactive effects, the one between the reaction time and the proportion of solvent had the most significant effect on kestose and nystose concentrations and on the bioconversion yield of fructooligosaccharides.An investigation in the production of fructooligosaccharides by endo-inulinase catalysed transfructosylation reaction in maple syrup-based biphasic media was carried out using selected maple syrups with different Brix (Bx) values (15º, 30º, 60º). The synthesis was performed over a time course of 16 to 80 h to assess the transfructosylation products obtained by endo-inulinase in a butyl acetate/maple syrup based biphasic system. Among the three maple syrups, the one with 66°Bx at 80 h of reaction resulted in the highest fructooligosaccharide bioconversion yield of 52.53%. As for the end product profile, the highest production of kestose was obtained with the use of maple syrup15°Bx, whereas the maple syrup 66°Bx resulted in the highest productions of nystose and fructosyl nystose. The biocatalytic approach of the study showed a great potential in synthesizing well defined fructooligosaccharides as functional ingredients in food industry and the development of new applications with maple syrup. </description><creator>Appanah, Neeyal</creator><contributor>Salwa Karboune (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</subject><title>Enzymatic synthesis of fructooligosaccharides from sucrose by endo-inulinase-catalyzed transfructosylation reaction in a non-conventional media</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88ck220.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182n799</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x346d6982</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sustainability of rural rice processing will ensure self-sufficiency and food security in sub-Saharan Africa.   Research, appropriate technology, and education (RATE) was used as a tool to effectively develop methods on how to increase sustainability of rice processing in the region.  Utilization of rice husk waste from the predominant Engelberg and Milltop rice mills as biofuel feedstock was found to increase the sustainability of the process:  considering the social, economic, and, environmental criteria.  Process parameters including binder type and ratio, moisture content, and die pressure were found to affect the quality of densified rice husk. Rice husks from these two mills were characterized to investigate their viability as biofuel feedstock based on physical, chemical and thermochemical analyses. Physical analysis of the rice husk showed that the Engelberg rice husk is significantly different from the multistage Milltop rice husk (P&lt;0.05). Particle size analysis of the Engelberg and Milltop produced rice husks showed that the Milltop husks have significantly higher geometric diameter with 95% of the samples by weight, retained by Standard sieve #20 (0.850 mm). The Engelberg rice husks were much smaller with 95% of the particles retained by sieve #100 (0.150 mm). The Engelberg rice husks were much finer with higher bulk and particle densities than the Milltop rice husk samples. Particle size analysis, microstructural analysis using SEM, and statistical analysis showed that the most important components of the Engelberg rice husk samples were immature paddies and broken kernels, while the most important components of the Milltop were unbroken Lemma and Palea with small broken kernels and bran present within the samples.  The Engelberg and the Milltop rice husks form two significant groups of rice husks that will require two completely different design parameters to be utilized as biofuel, and it was found that even within the two groups there can be differences that are significant between the samples that could be due to rice ecology, variety, harvesting and other postharvest handling processes other than milling.  However, this should not hinder the design of a versatile biofuel production system that will utilize the two as specific groups of rice husks based on their physical characterization.   Chemical analysis of the Engelberg and Milltop rice husks showed that the Milltop samples have lower amounts of proximate starch, protein, and fat compared with the Engelberg samples.  The FT-IR results also showed that the Engelberg and Milltop rice husks spectra have unique characteristics that define them as separate groups; with key differences being the quantity of the proximate components that confirmed what was observed during the starch, protein, and fat analyses of the samples.  The FT-IR analysis also distinguished the samples with higher immature grains from the rest of the rice husk samples.Thermochemical characteristics of the Engelberg and the Milltop milled rice husks including proximate composition and higher heating value (HHV) were studied.  An effective method for determination of the HHV of rice husk using oxygen bomb calorimeter coupled with comparative analysis of bomb calorimeter residuals, proximate ash, and densified pellet impact resistance was developed.  HHV prediction models for the rice husks of the two milling machines were developed. Higher HHV values of the Engelberg milled rice husk samples compared to the Milltop samples were found to be consistent with their respective higher volatile proximate components.  FT-IR and SEM analyses showed that there were no significant differences between the physico-chemical composition of the Engelberg and Milltop rice husk ash samples.   </description><description>.La pérennité de la transformation du riz en Afrique sub-Saharienne est l'un des aspects les plus importants pour assurer la sécurité alimentaire et l'autosuffisance dans cette région, tout en prenant en considération les critères sociaux, économiques, et environnementaux des processus.  Le thème proposé (recherche, technologie appropriée, et de l'éducation (RTAE)), est un outil efficace pour augmenter la pérennité de la transformation de riz dans les régions rurales de l'Afrique sub-saharienne. Les écorces de l'Engelberg et de la Milltop sont les plus abondantes en termes de sous-produits les plus sous-utilisés de la transformation dans la région. Les écorces de ces deux ont été caractérisées pour étudier leur viabilité en tant que matière première de biocarburants basée sur L'analyses physique, chimique, et  thermochimique. L'analyse physique des écorces de riz a montré une différence significative entre les deux moulins Engelberg et Milltop (P&lt;0.05).  L'analyse granulométrique a montré que le diamètre géométrique de la Milltop est significativement plus élevé avec 95% des échantillons en poids étant retenu par le tamis Standard #20 (0,850 mm). Les écorces Engelberg étaient beaucoup plus petites avec 95% des particules en poids retenu par un tamis Standard #100 (0,150 mm). Les écorces de riz Engelberg étaient plus fines et avaient une densité apparente plus élevée en comparaison avec l'écorce de riz Milltop. Les analyses statistiques de la granulométrie et de la microstructure ont montré que le principal composant de l'Engelberg contenait à la fois les composants internes et externes des grains de riz. Tandis que, les écorces de riz Milltop sont composées principalement de la coque extérieure. L'analyse chimique des écorces de riz Engelberg et Milltop ont montré que les échantillons Milltop avaient une plus petite quantité d'amidon, de protéines et de matières grasses en comparaison avec les échantillons Engelberg. Les résultats de l'analyse FTIR ont également montré que les deux écorces de riz ont des caractéristiques uniques qui les définissent comme groupes; avec les principales différences étant la quantité des composants chimiques qui ont confirmé ce que l'on a observé au cours des analyses de l'amidon, des protéines et des graisses. L'analyse thermochimique des écorces de riz Engelberg et Milltop impliquant les analyses immédiates et la détermination du pouvoir calorifique supérieur (HHV) a développé une méthode utilisant une bombe calorimétrique. Des modèles prédictifs pour la détermination du HHV des échantillons des écorces de riz ont été développés.  Les analyses FTIR et de microscopie SEM ont montrés qu'il n'y avait pas de différences significatives physico-chimiques entre les cendres Engelberg et Milltop.     </description><creator>Bakari, Mohammed</creator><contributor>Valerie Orsat (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Bioresource Engineering</subject><title>Characterization of rice husks as a biofuel feedstock towards sustainable rural rice processing in Sub-Saharan Africa</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pw41p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d6982</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pr76f624t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La maladie d'Alzheimer (MA) constitue la première cause de démence au monde et aucun traitement efficace n'existe à ce jour. Dans la MA, l'accumulation de peptides béta-amyloïde (Aβ) peut survenir 10 à 15 ans avant les troubles cognitifs et progresse d'un stade intracellulaire vers un stade de plaques extracellulaires. Cependant et à ce jour, le mécanisme précis par lequel l'accumulation précoce de peptides Aβ entraine les troubles cognitifs reste inconnue. En utilisant un rat transgénique modélisant la MA, ce travail de thèse a pour but de répondre aux questions en suspens ayant trait à l'impact de l'accumulation précoce d'Aβ sur la cognition ainsi que d'évaluer les résultats d'un traitement par le lithium, une molécule à cibles multiples.Le premier Chapitre de cette thèse est une revue des caractéristiques physiopathologiques et des facteurs de risque génétique associés à la MA. S'en suit un aperçu des multiples cascades de signalisation cellulaire qui sont déréglées dans la MA. Ce Chapitre inclue un résumé des récents efforts d'identification des phases précliniques de la maladie. Ce Chapitre traite également de la découverte des effets cliniques du lithium et examine quelques-uns des mécanismes d'action connus  de cette molécule à cibles multiples. Enfin, ce Chapitre s'achève sur un résumé des Buts et Hypothèse de cette Thèse. Le Chapitre 2 traite de l'impact de l'accumulation précoce d'Aβ sur le dysfonctionnement des lobes temporaux et frontaux. La performance des rats Alzheimer McGill-R-Thy1-APP dans une tache de discrimination visuelle est comparée à celle des rats contrôles sauvages en utilisant un dispositif « touchscreen operant platform ». La présence intraneuronale d'Aβ entraine un déficit sévère d'apprentissage associé chez le rat Alzheimer, qui coïncide avec une réduction de la translocation nucléaire et de l'occupation génomique du co-activateur du facteur CREB, CRTC1, ainsi qu'avec une réduction dans la production de messagers Arc, c-fos, Egr1 et Bdnf associés à la plasticité synaptique. Ainsi, le blocage de l'expression de gènes dépendant du CRTC1 au cours de la phase précoce pré-plaque de la pathologie amyloïde Alzheimer offre une base moléculaire pour expliquer les déficits cognitifs si proéminents dans la MA précoce. Le Chapitre 3 décrit l'utilisation d'une formulation du lithium à faible dose pour le traitement de la pathologie amyloïde liée à la MA. Il a été démontré que le lithium peut réduire l'activité de BACE1 et la production d'Aβ, promouvoir l'expression de gènes dépendant du CRTC1 et rétablir la cognition. Ce Chapitre présente des résultats démontrant que le traitement par le NP03 annule les déficits cognitifs chez le rat Alzheimer. Des résultats supplémentaires montrent que le NP03 réduit de façon significative le niveau d'Aβ toxique, l'hyperactivité de BACE1 et rétablit l'occupation génomique du promoteur CRTC1 au niveau de gènes requis pour l'apprentissage et la mémoire. Le Chapitre 4 traite des propriétés anti-stress oxidatif et anti-inflammatoires du NP03 et présente des résultats démontrant que le traitement au NP03 diminue de façon significative l'expression d'un sous-groupe de cytokines pro-inflammatoires, tout en réduisant le recrutement de microglies vers les neurones contenant Aβ dans l'hippocampe. NP03 rétablit également la neurogenèse adulte dans le gyrus denté de l'hippocampe des rats Alzheimer. Le Chapitre 5 est une discussion générale. Les thérapies expérimentales actuellement mises en œuvre contre la MA sont abordées, ainsi qu'une explication des raisons pour lesquelles les thérapies combinées seront nécessaires pour traiter la MA. Enfin, ce Chapitre conclue en suggérant que CRTC1 est une cible potentielle dans le traitement de la MA et identifie le NP03 comme un candidat thérapeutique pour la phase précoce de la MA.</description><description>Alzheimer's disease (AD) is the leading cause of dementia worldwide and currently no effective treatment exists. In AD, accumulation of amyloid beta (Aβ) begins decades before cognitive symptoms, progressing from intraneuronal material to extracellular plaque. However, the precise mechanism by which the early buildup of Aβ peptides leads to cognitive dysfunction remains unknown. Using a rat transgenic model of AD, this thesis aims to resolve outstanding issues surrounding the impact of early Aβ accumulation on cognition and evaluate the result of potential therapy using the multi-target drug lithium.  Chapter 1 of this thesis serves as a review of the pathophysiological characteristics and genetic risk factors associated with AD. What follows is an overview of the multiple cellular signaling cascades that are dysregulated in AD. The Chapter includes a summary of recent efforts to identify the preclinical phases of the disease. The Chapter discusses the discovery of the clinical effects of lithium, and examines some of the known mechanisms of action of this multi-target drug. Finally, the Chapter ends by summarizing the Aims and Hypotheses of this thesis. In Chapter 2, the impact of the early Aβ accumulation on temporal and frontal lobe dysfunction is investigated. The performance of McGill-R-Thy1-APP transgenic AD rats was compared with wild-type littermate controls on a visual discrimination task using a touchscreen operant platform. The presence of intraneuronal Aβ caused a severe associative learning deficit in the AD rats that coincided with reduced nuclear translocation and genomic occupancy of the CREB co-activator, CRTC1, and decreased production of synaptic plasticity-associated transcripts Arc, c-fos, Egr1, and Bdnf. Thus, blockade of CRTC1-dependent gene expression in the early, pre-plaque phase of AD-like pathology provides a molecular basis for the cognitive deficits that figure so prominently in early AD. Chapter 3 describes the application of a microdose lithium formulation, coded NP03, for the treatment of AD-like Aβ pathology. Lithium has been shown to reduce BACE1 activity, Aβ production, and to promote CRTC1-dependent gene expression and restore cognition. This Chapter presents data showing that NP03 treatment reversed cognitive deficits in Alzheimer transgenic rats, as measured by standard rodent cognitive tasks. Additional data are presented showing that NP03 also significantly reduced the level of toxic Aβ and reduced BACE1 hyperactivity, and restored CRTC1 promoter occupancy in genes required for learning and memory. The anti-oxidative stress and anti-inflammatory properties of NP03 are studied in Chapter 4, where data are presented showing that NP03 treatment significantly reduces the expression of a subset of oxidative stress and pro-inflammatory cytokines, along with reducing microglia recruitment to Aβ-neurons in the hippocampus. It is also demonstrated that NP03 restored adult hippocampal neurogenesis in the dentate gyrus in AD rats. This Chapter ends with the presentation of a hypothetical model that may account for the beneficial effects of NP03 by halting oxidative stress/neuroinflammation contributing to self-perpetuating neurotoxicity. Chapter 5 serves as a general discussion, and as such, situates the findings of this thesis in the broader context of current literature and puts forth a theoretical model for the action of lithium in Alzheimer's disease brains. Also discussed are the experimental therapeutics currently being explored for AD, and an explanation as to why combination therapies will likely be required for the treatment of AD. Finally, the Chapter concludes by suggesting CRTC1 as a potential target for AD therapy and identifies NP03 as a therapeutic candidate for the treatment of early stage Alzheimer's disease. </description><creator>Wilson, Edward</creator><contributor>Claudio Cuello (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Neuroscience</subject><title>Experimental therapy and cognitive outcomes in a rat transgenic model of Alzheimer disease-like amyloid beta neuropathology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qc413.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f624t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h711v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In acidic soils, aluminum (Al) and manganese (Mn) availability can be high and have a negative effect on plant growth and nutrition. Silicon (Si) has been studied for its ability to alleviate Al and Mn toxicity in agricultural crops. Despite its importance, only a few studies have examined Si uptake and interactions in trees. In this study, I first investigated Si, Al, Mn and Calcium (Ca) accumulation in leaves of sugar maple and American beech over a five-month period. Si uptake was found to be continuous for both species before reaching a plateau (Si concentration &gt; 1%) at the end of the growing season. Si uptake is likely associated with the sum of evapotranspiration in sugar maple and American beech (r = 0.991 for A. beech and 0.998 for sugar maple). Both species can therefore be considered passive accumulators of Si. In the second part of the study, sugar and silver maple were grown with different concentrations of Al and Mn in hydroponic systems with and without Si. Most of the effects observed were restricted to the root system. The negative Al effect was less pronounced for root dry weight and length of silver maple with the addition of Si with a concentration of AlCl3 between 100-2,000 uM and Na2SiO3 of 2,000 uM. As for sugar maple, root dry weight increased with the addition of Si suggesting that Al toxicity was not achieved for sugar maple and that it is better adapted to high Al availability than silver maple. Finally, I investigated the capacity of different species to accumulate Si and assessed the species interaction on Si uptake in a young plantation on the Macdonald Campus. Leaves of 16 tree species were analyzed for their Si content. On average, leaf Si concentration was almost six times higher in hardwoods (6.01±0.34 mg g-1) than in conifers (0.98±0.36 mg g-1), and sugar maple had the highest leaf Si concentration amongst maples (9.86 mg g-1). When grown in mixed plantations, sugar maple had a higher leaf Si concentration than in the monoculture, the likely result of reduced Si uptake by the companion species that are Si excluders (Si &lt; 1 %).</description><description>Les sols acides contiennent des concentrations élevées d'aluminium (Al) et de manganèse (Mn), ce qui a des effets négatifs sur la pousse et la nutrition des plantes. Des études sur les plantes agricoles ont démontré que la silicone (Si) a des propriétés qui permettent d'atténuer la toxicité causée par l'Al et le Mn. Malgré son importance, peu d'études ont examiné l'accumulation et l'interaction de la Si chez les arbres. Dans cette thèse, j'ai examiné en premier lieu l'accumulation de la Si, de l'Al, du Mn et du Calcium (Ca) dans les feuilles d'érables à sucre et de hêtres d'Amérique sur une période de cinq mois. L'absorption de la Si était continuelle pour les deux espèces et a atteint un plateau (concentration de Si &gt; 1%) à la fin de la saison de pousse. L'absorption de la Si est probablement associée à l'évapotranspiration chez le hêtre d'Amérique et l'érable à sucre (r = 0,991 pour le hêtre d'Amérique et 0,998 pour l'érable à sucre). Ainsi, les deux espèces peuvent être considérées comme des accumulateurs passifs de Si. Dans la seconde étude, la croissance de l'érable argenté et de l'érable à sucre a été étudiée dans un système hydroponique sous différentes concentrations d'Al et de Mn avec et sans ajout de Si. La majorité des effets ont été observés parmi les racines. Pour l'érable argenté, les effets toxiques de l'Al ont été moindres sur la masse des racines et la longueur des feuilles lors de l'addition de Si alors que la concentration d'AlC3 variait entre 100-2 000 uM et celle de Na2SiO3 était de 2 000 uM. Pour l'érable à sucre, la masse des racines a augmenté avec l'addition de Si ; la toxicité de l'Al n'a pas été atteinte durant l'expérience. Ceci démontre que l'érable à sucre est mieux adapté que l'érable argenté à l'Al dans les sols acides. Dans la troisième et dernière étude, j'ai comparé l'habileté de différentes espèces d'arbre à accumuler la Si et j'ai analysé l'interaction entre les espèces lors de l'accumulation de Si parmi les jeunes pousses au campus Macdonald. Les feuilles de 16 espèces d'arbres différentes ont été analysées afin de déterminer les concentrations de Si. En moyenne, la concentration de Si des feuillus (6,01±0,34 mg g-1) était presque six fois plus élevée que celles des conifères (0,98±0,36 mg g-1) et l'érable à sucre avait la concentration la plus élevée parmi les érables (9,86 mg g-1). Lorsque l'érable à sucre était planté avec d'autres espèces, il avait une concentration de Si plus élevée qu'en monoculture. Le résultat obtenu est probablement causé par le fait que les autres espèces excluent la Si (Si &lt; 1%) et, ainsi, ont absorbé une concentration moindre que l'érable.</description><creator>Tikasz, Peter</creator><contributor>Benoit Cote (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Natural Resource Sciences</subject><title>Silicate dynamics in common hardwoods of southern Quebec with a focus on its role on Al and Mn toxicity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386n153.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h711v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h702q889z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sequencing familial cases of cancer has repeatedly proven useful in identifying new predisposition genes for rare cancers that can arise in familial settings. One group of such cancers are non-epithelial ovarian cancers. These are classified into sex cord-stromal tumours, germ cell tumours, and miscellaneous ovarian tumours that include small cell carcinoma of the ovary, hypercalcemic type (SCCOHT), and soft tissue tumours not specific to the ovary, such as malignant rhabdoid tumours. The focus of this thesis was to search for predisposition genes to forms of non-epithelial ovarian cancer that can arise in families. Whole exome sequencing on DNA from a woman and her daughter who were both diagnosed with immature teratomas, a type of germ cell tumour, revealed deleterious mutations in the chromatin remodelling gene, SMARCA4. The lack of mutations in the validation cohort of 106 sporadic germ cell tumours, as well as two reports describing that germline mutations in SMARCA4 cause rhabdoid tumours (usually caused by SMARCB1 mutations), prompted a review of the daughter's tumour and mother's pathology reports, allowing us to recognize that the tumours were indeed rhabdoid tumours. We similarly sequenced members of three familial cases of SCCOHT that, along with validation in non-familial cases, also revealed germline and somatic mutations in SMARCA4. These mutations were accompanied by loss of the SMARCA4 protein in the tumours. Meticulous histological and clinical review of 45 familial and non-familial cases led to us promoting the idea that SCCOHT should be re-classified as a malignant rhabdoid tumour of the ovary. The histological and genetic similarity between SCCOHT and rhabdoid tumours prompted us perform exome sequencing and methylation analyses to compare SCCOHT and the intracranial variant of rhabdoid tumours, called atypical teratoid/rhabdoid tumours (ATRTs). We found that on both genomic and epigenomic levels, SCCOHT and ATRTs were more similar to each other than each were to other types of tumours from their respective tissues of origin. We further assessed the similarity of SCCOHT and ATRT on a clinical level. Therapies used to treat ATRT, particularly high dose chemotherapy with autologous stem cell rescue (HDC-aSCR), have been shown to be beneficial in treating SCCOHT. Cox regression and Kapan-Meier analyses on 257 SCCOHT cases revealed that patients who received HDC-aSCR had a significantly better outcome than those who received standard chemotherapy alone. Additionally, SCCOHT patients who carried germline SMARCA4 mutations were diagnosed at a significantly younger age than those with somatic mutations only. Together, our work demonstrates the value of whole exome sequencing in discovering predisposition genes and in potential reclassification of familial cancers. We show how this can subsequently have implications on diagnosis and treatment.</description><description>Le séquençage de cas de cancer familiaux s'est révélé utile à maintes reprises dans l'identification de nouveaux gènes de prédisposition aux cancers rares pour lesquels aucun allèle à haute pénétrance n'a encore été identifié, comme par exemple pour les cancers de l'ovaire non-épithéliaux. Les cancers de l'ovaire non-épithéliaux sont classés en plusieurs groupes : les tumeurs du stroma-cordons sexuels, les tumeurs des cellules germinales et les tumeurs de l'ovaire divers, qui incluent entre autres le carcinome à petites cellules de l'ovaire, du type hypercalcémie (SCCOHT) et les tumeurs des tissus mous non-spécifique à l'ovaire, comme les tumeurs malignes rhabdoïdes. L'objectif de cette thèse était de rechercher des gènes de prédisposition à des formes de cancer de l'ovaire non-épithéliales qui peuvent survenir dans les familles. Le séquençage des exomes d'ADN d'une femme et de sa fille, toutes deux diagnostiquées avec des tératomes immatures, une sorte des tumeurs des cellules germinales, a révélé des mutations délétères dans le gène de remodelage de la chromatine, SMARCA4. L'absence des mutations dans la cohorte de validation de 106 tumeurs germinales sporadiques, ainsi que deux rapports qui décrivent que des mutations germinales dans SMARCA4 causent les tumeurs rhabdoïdes (généralement causées par mutations dans SMARCB1), ont suscité une réévaluation de la tumeur de la fille et des rapports de pathologie de la mère, ce qui nous a permis de reconnaître que les tumeurs étaient en effet des tumeurs rhabdoïdes. Nous avons similairement séquencé les membres de trois cas familiaux de SCCOHT et avons observé des mutations germinales et des mutations somatiques dans le gène SMARCA4.  Ces mutations étaient accompagnées par la perte de la protéine SMARCA4 dans les tumeurs. Une réévaluation histologique et clinique minutieuse de 45 cas familiaux et sporadiques a entraîné une reclassification de ces tumeurs en tant que les tumeurs rhabdoïdes. Les similarités histologiques et génétiques entre SCCOHT et MRT nous ont conduit à effectuer des comparaisons de séquençage d'exomes et d'analyses de méthylation entre SCCOHT et la variante intracrânienne des tumeurs rhabdoïdes, appelés les tumeurs rhabdoïdes/tératoïdes atypiques (ATRTs). Nous avons trouvé qu'aux niveaux génomiques et épigénomiques, SCCOHTs et ATRTs partageaient plus de similarités entres elles qu'avec des types de tumeurs différents de leur tissu d'origine respectif. Nous avons également évalué la similitude des SCCOHT et ATRTs au niveau clinique. Les thérapies utilisées pour traiter ATRT, en particulier la chimiothérapie à haute dose avec la transplantation des cellules souches autologues (HDC-aSCR), se sont révélées être bénéfiques dans le traitement de SCCOHT. Les analyses Cox et Kapan-Meier sur 257 cas de SCCOHT ont révélé que les patients qui ont reçu l'HDC-aSCR ont eu un résultat significativement meilleur que ceux qui ont reçu la chimiothérapie seule. En outre, les patients souffrant de SCCOHT qui portaient des mutations SMARCA4 germinales furent diagnostiqués à un âge significativement plus jeune que ceux ayant seulement des mutations somatiques. Dans l'ensemble, notre travail démontre la valeur du séquençage d'exomes pour la découverte des gènes de prédisposition mais aussi pour le reclassement potentiel des cancers familiaux. Nous démontrons aussi que ces découvertes peuvent avoir des répercussions sur le diagnostic et le traitement de certains cancers. </description><creator>Witkowski, Leora</creator><contributor>William Foulkes (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Human Genetics</subject><title>Reclassifying non-epithelial ovarian cancer, one family at a time</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qs34t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q889z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88ck238</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Myc-interacting zinc finger protein-1 (Miz-1) is a ubiquitously expressed but poorly studied transcriptional transactivator that can bind to the proto-oncoprotein c-Myc, which is the main driver of a large number of different cancer types. In my thesis, I use murine T cell development as well as mouse models of T cell leukemia to broaden our biochemical understanding of the functions of Miz-1. At the beginning of my Ph.D., our lab had reported that Miz-1 plays an essential role during early stages of T cell development in the thymus, specifically at the β-selection checkpoint, which has important implications for T cell leukemia. At this checkpoint, Miz-1 deficiency causes apoptosis and a developmental block in cells undergoing β-selection. However, the exact role of Miz-1 during β-selection remained unclear. The work presented here is a compilation of two studies that highlight the important role of Miz-1 during T cell development and transformation and ultimately furthers our understanding of Miz-1 in the context of leukemia research.In the first study, presented in Chapter II, I found that the increased apoptosis in Miz-1-deficient cells is due to deregulated signaling via p53, and this deregulation could be rescued following deletion of p53. Furthermore, I identified a Miz-1 binding site in the promoter of Rpl22, which regulates the synthesis of p53 during β-selection, as well as Miz-1-dependent activation of gene transcription. I also found that Miz-1 deficiency increases p53 translation due to the direct binding of Rpl22 to the mRNA of p53. These findings suggest that Miz-1, via the activation of Rpl22, regulates the translation of p53 at the β-selection checkpoint, when DNA damage occurs. Because I found that Miz-1 regulates the translation of a prominent tumor suppressor in Chapter II specifically at the stage where T cell transformation is thought to occur, in Chapter IIIxI investigated whether loss of Miz-1 affects the development of T cell leukemia. Using the ICN1 model of T-ALL induction, I showed that a strong counter selection occurs during T cell leukemogenesis against the loss of Miz-1, since Miz-1-deficient mice succumb to the disease with a significantly longer latency period than WT animals. Finally, I showed that Miz-1 also regulates p53 activity in this context, since mice deficient for both Miz-1 and p53 develop T-ALL at a rate similar to p53-deficient mice. These findings suggest that Miz-1 is required for the efficient development of T-ALL, and acts as a repressor of p53.Thus, I demonstrate that loss of Miz-1 significantly hinders both normal T cell development and induction of T-ALL in part through the inability of these cells to repress p53 activity and signaling.</description><description>La protéine Miz-1 (Myc-interacting zinc finger protein-1) est un facteur de transcription exprimé de façon ubiquitaire, interagissant avec la protéine oncogènique c-Myc, impliquée dans le développement de plusieurs cancers. Pendant ma thèse, j'ai étudié les fonctions biochimiques et moléculaires de Miz-1 dans le développement des cellules T ainsi que son rôle dans différents modèles de leucémies aigues T (T-ALL). Au début de ma thèse, notre équipe a montré que Miz-1 est impliqué dans le développement des cellules T en particulier lors de la β-sélection qui est une étape clé dans l'initiation des leucémies T. En effet, au cours de la β-sélection, l'expression exclusive d'une forme tronquée de Miz-1 (dans les souris Miz-1ΔPOZ) induit l'apoptose et cause un défaut de différenciation des lymphocytes T. Cependant, le rôle exact joué par Miz-1 lors de la β-sélection n'est pas clair, ainsi que son impact sur l'initiation et le développement des leucémies T. Le travail présenté ici comprend ainsi deux études qui soulignent l'importance de Miz-1 durant le développement et la transformation des cellules T et améliorent nos connaissances quant à l'implication de Miz-1 dans le domaine de la recherche sur les leucémies T. Dans notre première étude, présentée dans le deuxième chapitre de cette thèse, j'ai déterminé que l'induction de l'apoptose dans les cellules Miz-1ΔPOZ que nous avions préalablement observée, est causée par une dérégulation de la voie de signalisation de p53. En effet, j'ai montré que Miz-1 se lie au promoteur et active l'expression de Rpl22, qui régule la synthèse de p53 durant la β-sélection. Rpl22 peut ainsi se lier à l'ARN messager de p53. Cette liaison favorise une augmentation de la traduction de p53 ainsi qu'une augmentation d'expression de p53 dans les cellules T lors de la β-sélection, augmentant alors l'apoptosexiimédiée par p53. Ces résultats suggèrent une régulation de la traduction de p53 par Miz-1, via l'activation de Rpl22, durant la β-sélection des cellules T. Puisque Miz-1 régule la traduction d'un suppresseur de tumeur important au stade du développement des cellules T où la transformation maligne peut se produire dans les T-ALL, j'ai décidé d'étudier l'effet de la perte de fonction de Miz-1 dans le développement de ces mêmes tumeurs. En utilisant le modèle de surexpression de Notch1 de T-ALL, j'ai montré que les souris exprimant la forme tronquée de Miz-1 ont un meilleur taux de survie par rapport aux souris contrôles, suggérant que Miz-1 est nécessaire pour l'induction des leucémies T. Finalement, j'ai montré que Miz-1 régule aussi l'activité de p53 dans le contexte tumoral, puisque les souris Miz-1ΔPOZ n'exprimant pas p53 développent des T-ALL avec la même rapidité que les souris p53-/- exprimant normalement Miz-1. Ces résultats suggèrent un rôle important de Miz-1 dans le développement des leucémies aigues T en réprimant p53.En conclusion, je démontre que la perte de fonction de Miz-1 inhibe le développement normal des cellules T ainsi que l'induction des leucémies T en favorisant l'expression de la protéine p53, médiateur important de l'apoptose.</description><creator>Rashkovan, Marissa</creator><contributor>Tarik Möröy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>The role of myc-interacting zinc finger protein-1 (miz-1) in T cell development and leukemogenesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d260k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88ck238</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s4655k24b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Self-critical (SC) perfectionism, the more maladaptive dimension of perfectionism, has been associated with depression, anxiety, stress and various other difficulties. The overall purpose of the current doctoral thesis was to identify important explanatory mechanisms that help to clarify the relationship between SC perfectionism and negative outcomes over time in both community as well as clinical samples with the goal of identifying important targets for future interventions. More specifically, the goal of my dissertation was to examine the role of emotional reactivity (i.e. daily fluctuations in negative mood in response to daily fluctuations in stress appraisals) as an important explanatory variable in the relationship between SC perfectionism and psychosocial maladjustment. Article 1 examined the role of heightened stress reactivity in a sample of 150 community adults in the relationship between SC perfectionism and depressive and anxious symptoms over a period of four years. In order to measure stress reactivity, daily dairies measuring daily stress and affect for 14 consecutive days were collected at both Month 6 and Year 3. Results demonstrated that SC perfectionism predicted daily stress–sadness reactivity (i.e., greater increases in sadness in response to increases in stress) across Month 6 and Year 3, which in turn mediated the relationship between higher SC perfectionism and general depressive and anxious symptoms and anhedonic depressive symptoms four years later, controlling for baseline symptoms. Article 2 examined the role of heightened interpersonal sensitivity (daily increases in negative mood in response to increases in negative social interactions) in a sample of 145 community adults in the relationship between SC perfectionism and interpersonal stress generation four years later. Interpersonal sensitivity was measured at both Month 6 and Year 3 using 14 days of daily diaries measuring daily negative interpersonal interactions and affect. Findings showed that interpersonal-sadness sensitivity mediated the relationship between SC perfectionism and interpersonal stress generation four years later, controlling for the effects of depressive symptoms. Article 3 evaluated whether stress-sadness reactivity and cortisol activity moderated the relationship between SC perfectionism and depressive symptoms in a sample of 43 depressed patients over a one-year period. Stress-sadness reactivity was measured using seven days of daily dairies examining daily stress and affect. High levels of SC perfectionism in combination with high levels of both daily stress-sadness reactivity and the cortisol awakening response (CAR) predicted less depression improvement relative to other patients one year later. Low SC perfectionism in combination with higher levels of stress-sadness reactivity/CAR predicted the lowest levels of depression over time.  Taken together, the empirical findings from the current thesis demonstrate that emotional reactivity serves as an important explanatory variable in the relationship between SC perfectionism and a host of negative outcomes. </description><description>Le perfectionnisme autocritique, la dimension plus inadapté du perfectionnisme, a été associée à la dépression, à l'anxiété, au stress et à diverses autres difficultés. L'objectif général de cette thèse de doctorat était d'identifier d'importants mécanismes explicatifs qui aident à clarifier la relation entre le perfectionnisme autocritique et les conséquences négatives au fil du temps auprès d'échantillons communautaires et cliniques, dans le but d'identifier des cibles importantes pour les interventions futures. Plus précisément, l'objectif de ma thèse était d'examiner le rôle de la réactivité émotionnelle comme une importante variable explicative de la relation entre le perfectionnisme autocritique et l'inadaptation psychosociale. Dans un échantillon de 150 adultes de la communauté, l'Article 1 a examiné le rôle de la réactivité accrue face au stress dans la relation entre le perfectionnisme autocritique et les symptômes dépressifs et anxieux sur une période de quatre ans. Afin de mesurer la réactivité au stress, des journaux quotidiens mesurant le stress et l'affect (par exemple, la tristesse et l'affect négatif) ont été collectées pendant 14 jours consécutifs au Mois 6 et à l'Année 3. Les résultats démontraient que le perfectionnisme autocritique prédisait la réactivité stress-tristesse quotidienne à travers le Mois 6 et l'Année 3, laquelle agissait à son tour comme médiateur dans la relation entre le perfectionnisme autocritique élevé et les symptômes général de dépression et d'anxiété, ainsi que les symptômes anhédoniques de la dépression quatre ans plus tard, après avoir contrôlé les symptômes de base.  Dans un échantillons de 145 adultes de la communauté, l'Article 2 a examiné le rôle de la sensibilité interpersonnelle élevée dans la relation entre le perfectionnisme autocritique et la génération du stress interpersonnel quatre ans plus tard. La sensibilité interpersonnelle a été mesurée au Mois 6 et à l'Année 3 en utilisant 14 jours de journaux quotidiens mesurant les interactions interpersonnelles négatives et l'affect au quotidien. Les résultats démontraient que la sensibilité interpersonnelle-tristesse agissait comme médiateur dans la relation entre le perfectionnisme autocritique élevée et de plus importantes création de stress interpersonnel quatre ans plus tard, après avoir contrôlé l'effet des symptômes dépressif. L'Article 3 a évalué si la réactivité stress-tristesse et l'activité cortisolique ont modéré la relation entre le perfectionnisme autocritique et les symptômes dépressifs dans un échantillon de 43 patients souffrant de dépression sur une durée d'un an. La réactivité stress-tristesse a été mesurée en utilisant 7 jours de journaux quotidiens mesurant leur stress et leur affect au quotidien. Cortisolique salivaire ont été recueillies sur deux jours distincts. Les patients ayant un niveau élevé de perfectionnisme autocritique, combiné à un niveau élevé de réactivité stress-tristesse quotidienne et à l'augmentation cortisolique au réveil, montraient moins d'amélioration des symptômes de dépression comparé aux autres patients un an plus tard. Un niveaux plus bas du perfectionnisme autocritique, combiné à un niveau élevé de réactivité stress-tristesse/ augmentation cortisolique au réveil, prédisait un niveau inférieur de dépression au fil du temps. Dans l'ensemble, les résultats empiriques de cette thèse démontrent que la réactivité émotionnelle sert d'importante variable explicative de la relation entre le perfectionnisme autocritique et toute une série de conséquences négatives. </description><creator>Mandel, Tobey</creator><contributor>David Michael Dunkley (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Psychology</subject><title>Self-critical perfectionism, daily emotional reactivity, and psychosocial maladjustment: three multi-wave longitudinal studies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010s79d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655k24b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:np193c536</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background: The World Health Organization identifies women of reproductive age as a high risk group for soil-transmitted helminth infections because these infections cause blood loss, iron deficiency anemia, and nutritional impairment. Deworming is a central component of control efforts aimed at reducing the burden of disease in endemic areas. The postpartum period offers a unique opportunity to reach women periodically throughout their reproductive lifespans. To date, no study has investigated the effect of maternal postpartum deworming on infant or maternal health outcomes. Objectives: The objectives of this study were to determine the effectiveness of maternal postpartum deworming on the following infant and maternal health outcomes: 1) infant growth and morbidity; 2) maternal soil-transmitted helminth infection and intensity, anemia, and fatigue; and 3) breast milk quality indicators. Methods: A double-blind, randomized, placebo-controlled trial was carried out in Iquitos, Peru. Mother-infant pairs were enrolled into the trial following delivery at Hospital Iquitos "Cesar Garayar Garcia". Prior to hospital discharge women were randomized to receive either a single-dose 400 mg albendazole tablet (i.e., deworming) or identical placebo, based on a pre-specified randomization schedule. Mother-infant pairs were visited in their homes at 1 and 6 months postpartum for outcome ascertainment. The primary outcome was mean infant weight gain between birth and 6 months of age. Continuous outcomes were compared between intervention groups using linear regression models and dichotomous outcomes were compared using log-binomial regression models. Analyses followed an intention-to-treat approach. Adjusted, complete-case, and per-protocol analyses were also performed.Results: Between February and August 2014, 1010 mother-infant pairs were enrolled into the trial. A total of 999 (98.9%) and 970 (96.0%) mother-infant pairs completed their 1 and 6-month study visits, respectively. Infant weight gain between birth and 6 months of age was similar between intervention groups (4.3 kg ±0.04 vs. 4.4 kg ±0.04), as were secondary growth indices. The single-dose deworming intervention also did not have a differential effect on the occurrence of hospitalizations, nor on the incidence of diarrhea, respiratory illness, fever, or ear infections in infants. Over the 6-month postpartum period, deworming significantly reduced the prevalence (RR: 0.5; 95% CI: 0.4, 0.6) and intensity of maternal helminth infections but had no demonstrable effect on maternal anemia (RR: 1.0; 95% CI: 0.9, 1.1) or fatigue score (mean difference: -0.4; 95% CI: -1.1, 0.3). Additionally, the mean concentration of vitamins and minerals in breast milk was similar between intervention groups.Conclusions: Overall, while single-dose deworming did reduce maternal helminth infections, no statistically significant benefit was detected on infant growth or morbidity outcomes in the first 6 months of life. Maternal postpartum deworming also had no effect on the prevalence of maternal anemia, fatigue, and breast milk composition. The benefits of deworming may be more apparent in areas of higher prevalence and intensity of soil-transmitted helminth infection, over longer periods of follow-up, and with repeated administration. This first trial on maternal postpartum deworming contributes essential empirical evidence to inform World Health Organization policy and guidelines towards eliminating soil-transmitted helminthiasis as a public health problem.</description><description>Contexte: L'Organisation mondiale de la santé considère les femmes en âge de procréer comme un groupe à haut risque d'infection par les géohelminthes parce que ces infections causent des pertes sanguines, l'anémie ferriprive et une détérioration de l'état nutritionnel. Le déparasitage est un élément essentiel des efforts de réduction du fardeau de la maladie dans les régions où les géohelminthes sont endémiques. Toutefois, l'effet du déparasitage postpartum sur la santé maternelle et infantile n'a jamais été étudié à ce jour. Objectifs: Les objectifs de cette étude étaient de mesurer l'efficacité du déparasitage maternel postpartum sur les issues suivantes: 1) la croissance et la morbidité infantiles: 2) la prévalence et l'intensité des géohelminthiases, l'anémie et la fatigue chez les mères; et 3) les indicateurs de la qualité du lait maternel. Méthodes: Un essai à double insu contrôlé par placebo a été effectué à Iquitos, au Pérou. Des dyades mère-enfant ont été enrôlées dans l'étude après la naissance des enfants à l'Hôpital 'Cesar Garayar Garcia' d'Iquitos. Avant leur congé de l'hôpital, les femmes ont été désignées aléatoirement pour recevoir, soit une capsule unique de 400 mg d'albendazole (déparasitage), soit un placebo, selon un protocole préétabli. Mères et nourrissons ont été visités à domicile à la fin des premier et sixième mois de vie du nourrisson. Le principal résultat à l'étude était le gain pondéral des nourrissons durant leurs six premiers mois de vie. Les résultats continus ont été comparés entre les groupes d'intervention au moyen de régressions linéaires et les résultats dichotomiques ont été comparés au moyen de régressions log-binomiales. Les analyses suivaient l'approche de l'intention de traiter. Des analyses ajustées, des analyses complètes de cas et selon le protocole ont également été effectuées.Résultats : De février à août 2014, 1010 dyades ont été enrôlées dans l'étude. En tout, 999 (98,9%) dyades ont complété la visite à un mois, et 970 (96,0%) ont complété celle à six mois. Le gain pondéral des nourrissons des deux groupes d'intervention durant leurs six premiers mois de vie étaient similaires (4,3 kg ±0.04 vs. 4,4 kg ±0.04), tout comme les indicateurs secondaires de la croissance. L'intervention de déparasitage à dose unique n'a eu aucun effet sur l'occurrence des hospitalisations, ni sur l'incidence de la diarrhée, de la toux, de la fièvre ou de l'otite chez les nourrissons. Durant les six mois postpartum, le déparasitage a réduit significativement la prévalence (RR: 0,5; IC à 95% : 0,4; 0,6) et l'intensité des infections à géohelminthes chez les mères mais n'a eu aucun effet démontrable sur l'anémie (RR : 1,0; IC à 95% : 0,9; 1,1) ou le score de fatigue (différence des moyennes : -0,4; IC à 95% : -1,1; 0,3) chez les mères. De plus, les concentrations moyennes de vitamines et de minéraux dans le lait maternel des deux groupes d'intervention étaient similaires. .Conclusions : Bien que l'intervention de déparasitage à dose unique ait réduit significativement les infections à géohelminthes chez les mères, aucun effet bénéfique statistiquement significatif n'a été détecté sur la croissance ou la morbidité des nourrissons durant leurs six premiers mois de vie. Le déparasitage postpartum n'a eu non plus aucun effet sur la prévalence de l'anémie et de la fatigue chez les mères, ni sur la composition du lait maternel. Les effets bénéfiques du déparasitage pourraient être plus apparents dans des zones où la prévalence et l'intensité des infections à géohelminthes sont plus élevées, après de plus longues périodes de suivi ou après des traitements répétés. Ce premier essai de déparasitage maternel postpartum apporte une preuve empirique essentielle qui informera les politiques et les lignes directrices de l'Organisation mondiale de la santé en vue de l'élimination des géohelminthiases comme problème de santé publique.</description><creator>Mofid, Layla</creator><contributor>Theresia Gyorkos (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Epidemiology and Biostatistics</subject><title>Maternal postpartum deworming: a novel strategy to reduce infant and maternal morbidity in low-and-middle-income countries</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451m32w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193c536</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4f16c5279</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The design of subsurface structures associated with transportation and other underground facilities, such as buried pipes and culverts, requires an understanding of soil-structure interaction. These structures are usually subjected to heavy loads from the backfill material in addition to substantial traffic loads, particularly when the structure is buried at shallow depth below ground surface. The soil-structure interaction of these systems depend on several factors including the method of construction and the relative stiffness between the structure and the surrounding backfill material. To reduce earth pressure acting on buried structures, different techniques have been proposed by researchers including the installation of geosynthetic material above the structure to either reinforce the backfill soil (using geotextile or geogrid sheets) and distribute the earth loads away from the structure or to mobilize shear strength of the soil above the buried structure by installing a compressible material (e.g. EPS geofoam) immediately above the structure. This thesis is devoted to investigate the behavior of these composite soil-geosynthetic-structure systems using laboratory experiments focusing on buried rigid structures. The experimental results are compared with some of the available theoretical solutions, typically used in design. The investigations involved designing and building a test chamber and utilizing the tactile sensing technology to measure the changes in earth pressure distribution on the walls of the buried structures. The research results have been published and submitted for publication in refereed journals and conference proceedings amounting to three journal and two conference papers. The papers are compiled to produce six chapters and one appendix presented in this thesis. The role of geogrid in reducing earth loads on circular pipes buried at shallow depth and subjected to a strip load is first investigated to illustrate that this installation method can be effective only if sufficient surface movement is allowed to mobilize geogrid resistance. The rest of the thesis is devoted to study the effect of placing EPS geofoam blocks above buried conduits of circular and square shapes on the magnitude and distribution of earth pressures acting on the walls of the structure. Significant reduction in pressure was found for the case of shallow circular pipes installed with EPS geofoam inclusion and subjected to repeated surface loading. This is attributed to the compressibility of the geofoam material compared to the surrounding backfill that leads to differential ground movement and the generation of upward shear stresses above the EPS material. Lastly, The behavior of a square shaped structure overlain by geofoam material under deep burial condition is also examined and the changes in pressure as well as the drag forces developed along the sides of the box section are evaluated. A comparative study is then performed between the experimental results and the existing theoretical solutions to evaluate the validity of these solutions in designing buried conduits under different conditions.</description><description>La conception des ouvrages et installations souterrainnes en lien avec les transports, tel que les conduites enfouies et caniveaux, nécessite une compréhension avancée des interactions sol-structure. Ce type de structure est habituellement exposé à de lourdes charges provenant des matériaux de remblais en plus d'importantes charges de trafic, plus particulièrement lorsque la structure est enfouie de façon superficielle. L'interaction sol-structure de ces systèmes dépend directement de nombreux facteurs, incluant la méthode de construction de l'ouvrage ainsi que la rigidité relative de la structure par rapport au matériel de remblayage employé. Pour réduire la pression de la terre agissant sur les structures enterrées, différentes techniques ont été proposées par des chercheurs, incluant l'installation de matières géo synthétiques au-dessus de la structure, à la fois pour renforcer le sol de remblai (en utilisant des géotextiles ou des feuilles géogrilles) et répartir les charges de terre loin de la structure ou déplacer la résistance au cisaillement du sol  au dessus de la structure enterrée en installant un matériau compressible (par exemple Geofoam EPS) directement au-dessus de la structure. Cette thèse est consacrée à l'étude détaillée du comportement d'un système composite avec une structure sol-geosynthétique à l'aide de d'expériences de laboratoire effectuées sur des structures rigides enfouies. Les résultats expérimentaux sont comparés avec quelques solutions analytiques disponibles, généralement utilisées dans la conception. Les enquêtes comprenaient la conception et la construction d'une chambre d'essai et l'implantation de la technologie de senseurs tactiles pour enregistrer les variations dans la distribution de la pression des terres sur les parois de la structure enfouie. Les résultats de la recherche ont été publiés et soumis pour publication dans des revues arbitrées et actes de conférence, pour un total de trois papiers et deux documents de conférence. Les documents sont compilés pour produire six chapitres et une annexe présentée dans cette thèse.Le rôle des géogrilles dans la réduction des pressions des terres sur des conduites circulaires enfouies peu profondément et assujetties à une charge linéaire est tout d'abord étudié afin d'illustrer que cette méthode d'installation n'est efficace seulement lorsqu'un déplacement suffisant pour mobiliser la résistance du géogrille est possible.La seconde partie de ce mémoire est consacrée à l'effet que peut avoir l'installation de blocs de géofoam en polystyrène expansé au-dessus de conduites de forme circulaire et carré sur l'amplitude et la distribution des pressions des terres agissant sur la structure. Une réduction significative de la pression a été constatée pour le cas de conduites circulaires à faible profondeur installées avec des inclusions en Geofoam PSE et exposées à des charges de surface répétitives. Ceci est attribué à la compressibilité du matériau Geofoam par rapport au remblai qui mène un mouvement différentiel de masse ainsi que la génération des forces de cisaillement ascendantes au-dessus du matériau PSE. Le comportement d'une structure de forme carrée recouverte par un matériau Geofoam, sous condition d'enfouissement profond, est également examiné ainsi que les changements de pression et les forces de traînée développées le long des côtés de la section de la boîte sont évalués. Une étude comparative est ensuite effectuée entre les résultats expérimentaux et les solutions analytiques existantes pour évaluer la validité de ces solutions dans la conception de conduits enterrés dans des conditions différentes.</description><creator>Ahmed, Mahmoud</creator><contributor>Mohamed Meguid (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Civil Engineering &amp; Applied Mechanics</subject><title>Experimental investigations into the role of geosynthetic inclusions on the earth pressure acting on buried structures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv9355602.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c5279</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289m61r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the upper house problem in the United Kingdom and Canada, asking why the types of reform sought by institutional reformers have proven to be so elusive.  It is the intention of this work to account for a government's success or failure in achieving their desired objectives, and not simply in passing reform legislation.  Distinguishing between reform which is technically successful but does not achieve the outcomes intended by reformers, and change which achieves their objectives, defined as meaningful reform, this work examines each instance of credibly attempted significant upper house reform in either country since the start of the twentieth century.  It argues that there are two factors which are necessary for reform to be of the meaningful variety: elites must have a correct understanding of both the written and unwritten rules for reform, and they must have a contextualised understanding of the institution they are reforming, including proper identification of causal links between their planned changes and desired outcomes. This study includes six cases from the United Kingdom, and two from Canada.  In the United Kingdom, this includes the 1911 and 1949 Parliament Acts, the 1958 Life Peerages Act, the 1963 Peerage Act, the 1968-69 Parliament (no. 2) Bill, and the 1999 House of Lords Act.  In Canada, this includes the 1980-92 era of megaconstitutional politics, and the 2006-14 attempts at unilateral reform by the federal government.  In all but two of the eight cases, one or both of the necessary factors for meaningful reform were absent, even though five of the eight cases resulted in some sort of significant change.  Only the 1958 and 1963 reforms were both technically successful and produced the desired results, while in 1911, 1949, and 1999, changes actually produced results which were contrary to reformers' objectives.  Most of the time, reformers are good at identifying the written and unwritten rules for reform, but are less capable of identifying what they need to change to produce their desired outcomes. </description><description>Cette thèse est une étude du problème des sénats au Royaume-Uni et Canada, et se demande pourquoi la réforme de type significatif est tellement difficile à achever.  Il n'est pas l'intente de cette étude pour rendre compte de la réussite ou l'échec  d'un gouvernement d'adopter une loi de réforme, mais plutôt dans la réalisation de leurs objectifs souhaités.  Avec une distinction entre la réforme qui est techniquement un succès mais n'achève pas les objectifs des réformateurs, et le changement qui achève ces objectifs, dite la réforme significatif, cette œuvre scrute chaque fois qu'il y avait un essai à réformer le sénat dans chaque pays depuis le début du vingtième siècle.  Je propose qu'il y a deux éléments nécessaires pour la réforme de type significatif : les politiciens en charge doivent bien comprendre les règlements de réforme écrites et non-écrites, et doivent aussi avoir une compréhension contextualisée de l'institution, y compris l'identification correcte des liens de causalité entre les changements prévus et les résultats souhaités. Cette étude comprend six cas du Royaume-Uni, et deux du Canada.  Au Royaume-Uni, ça inclut les Parliament Acts de 1911 and 1949, le Life Peerages Act de 1958, le Peerage Act de 1963, le Parliament (no. 2) Bill de 1968-69, et le House of Lords Act de 1999.  Au Canada, ça inclut l'ère mégaconstitutionel entre 1980 et 1992, et les tentatives de réformer le sénat unilatéralement entre 2006 et 2014.  Au total, deux des huit cas manquent l'une ou l'autre des éléments nécessaires étaient absents, tandis que cinq cas ont donné lieu à une sorte de changement formelle.  Seules les réformes de 1958 et 1963 étaient à la fois techniquement une réussite, et ont produits les résultats escomptés, alors qu'en 1911, 1949, et 1999, les changements produits étaient effectivement contraires aux objectifs de réformateurs.  La plupart du temps, les réformateurs peuvent identifier les règlements écrites et non-écrites avec succès, mais sont moins capables d'identifier ce qu'ils doivent changer pour produire les résultats souhaités.</description><creator>Hughson, Heather</creator><contributor>Richard Schultz (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Political Science</subject><title>Senates and sensibility: an analysis of upper house reform attempts in the United Kingdom and Canada, 1906-2014</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w237p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289m61r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289m621</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'acte de dire un mensonge reflète la maturité des capacités cognitives d'un enfant.  L'enfant doit comprendre les états mentaux et les comportements d'un autre tout en contrôlant ses propres pensées et comportements.  Étant donné l'importance d'obtenir et d'évaluer la véracité des déclarations des enfants, il est nécessaire de trouver une procédure d'entrevue qui tient compte du niveau développemental de l'enfant.  Cette thèse est composée de trois manuscrits qui contribuent collectivement à la littérature en documentant : (1) l'habileté des enfants à maintenir un rapport à propos d'un événement; (2) le taux de détection, par des adultes, de la véracité d'un témoignage honnête ou faux d'un enfant; et (3) les facteurs cognitifs individuels des enfants qui permettent de prédire la détection de la véracité du témoignage lors d'un contre-interrogatoire avec une charge cognitive très taxante.  Cette thèse examine les vrais et faux témoignages des enfants qui subissent un contre-interrogatoire avec une charge cognitive, sans questions suggestives.  C'est-à-dire, un questionnement à l'ordre inversé.  Le premier manuscrit examine la capacité des enfants  de 9 à 12 ans (Mâge en mois = 131.00, SD = 14.77) à maintenir un témoignage vrai ou faux lors de quatre types de questions : de sonde non-suggestives, de clarification, à séquence inversée et à séquence chronologique.  Les résultats de cette étude indiquent que plus de 69% des enfants, peu-importe de la véracité de leur témoignage, étaient capable de maintenir leur condition à travers les questions.  Les enfants ont eu de la difficulté avec toutes les questions séquentielles.  Le deuxième manuscrit décrit l'habileté de l'adulte à identifier la véracité et la crédibilité d'un témoignage véridique ou déceptif lors du contre-interrogatoire avec une charge cognitive élevée. Les taux de détection des adultes (Mâge = 20.43, SD = 1.45) étaient semblables au niveau de chance pour l'interrogatoire principal (49.40%) et le contre-interrogatoire (52.30%).  En ce qui concerne les jugements de véracité de témoignages non-véridiques, il y a eu une amélioration après le contre-interrogatoire.  Le troisième manuscrit explore les facteurs cognitifs qui peuvent prédire les taux d'identification de véracité du témoignage des enfants.  Le contrôle inhibitoire, mesuré par le Stroop, était le seul qui pouvait prédire les jugements après l'interrogatoire principal.  Par contre, peu-importe la véracité du témoignage, la théorie de l'esprit, la planification et le mémoire de travail sont les facteurs cognitifs qui peuvent prédire les jugements après le contre-interrogatoire.  En bref, les résultats de ces trois études contribuent à nos connaissances sur la façon d'évaluer les rapports d'enfants témoins et comment d'interroger les enfants dans les milieux judiciaires.  Plus précisément, ce programme d'étude présente une alternative de questionnement à la salle d'audience et lors des procédures d'entrevue judiciaire.  Les implications pour psychologues qui travaillent avec des enfants, qui peuvent révéler un abus, sont également discutées.</description><description>Lie-telling reflects a child's emerging cognitive maturity, as the child begins to understand others' mental states and behaviours, while simultaneously learning to control his or her own.  Given the importance of obtaining and assessing the veracity of children's reports, there is a need for developmentally appropriate interview procedures for children.  This dissertation is comprised of three manuscripts that collectively contribute to the literature by documenting: (1) children's ability to maintain the veracity of their reports about an event; (2) adults' ability to detect deception in children's true and false reports of the event; and (3) the individual cognitive factors of children that predict detection rates while undergoing a highly taxing cognitive load cross-examination procedure.  The current research examines children's true and false reports during cross-examination procedures that are non-suggestive and non-leading but tax cognitive load (i.e., reverse order questioning).  The three manuscripts are unique as they include children reporting true denials, true assertions, false denials or false assertions.  The first manuscript reports on 9 to 12 year old (Mage in months = 131.00, SD = 14.77) children's ability to maintain a true or false statement across four question types including open-ended, prompted, reverse and chronological sequencing questions.  Results of the first study indicate that overall, 69% of children were able to maintain their reports.  However, truth-tellers demonstrated greater ease at maintaining their condition across all questions.  Regardless of question type (reverse-order or chronological order), children had difficulty recalling information sequentially.  The second manuscript reports on adults' ability to accurately identify the veracity of children's statements, as well as to rate perceived credibility and believability of the child undergoing the aforementioned cross-examination procedure.  Adults (Mage in years = 20.43, SD = 1.45) detection rates hovered at chance levels for both direct- (49.40%) and cross-examination (52.30%).  In comparison to accuracy judgments after direct-examination, when children were reporting a false event, accuracy judgments increased after cross-examination.  The third manuscript explored which cognitive factors are predictive of detection rates.  Inhibitory control, as measured by the Stroop task, was the only measure that predicted accuracy judgments during the direct-examination.  Theory of mind, planning, and working memory predicted accuracy rates, regardless of the veracity of the child's statement, during the cross-examination.  Taken together, findings from these three studies provide insight into how to interview children and assess their eye-witness reports in forensic settings.  Specifically, the current study proposes that high cognitive load questions are used as an alternative to the current courtroom and forensic interviewing procedures.  Also discussed are the implications of this research for school psychologists who work with children who may disclose abuse. </description><creator>Saykaly, Christine</creator><contributor>Victoria Talwar (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Educational and Counselling Psychology</subject><title>Assessing the veracity of children's reports: the influence of cognitive load and cross-examination questioning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gw36w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289m621</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p8418q927</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Visualizing and simulating the real world by means of three-dimensional (3D) models is important for many fields of science, technology, engineering and medicine (STEM). Exploiting the human senses, such as the sense of sight with head-mounted displays (HMDs) and the sense of touch with haptic devices, has helped in creating immersive virtual-reality (VR) experiences. However, HMDs and haptics have seldom been combined in STEM applications, and recently the technology has been advancing rapidly in both areas. The objective of this research was to develop a VR system which combines both a consumer-level HMD and a mid-level haptic device using a game-development platform. A proof-of-concept system was developed using the Oculus Rift HMD and the Phantom Premium 1.5 High Force haptic device. The system was implemented using the Unity 3D game engine and was tested with two 3D human anatomical models, a heart and part of a skull. The technical performance of the system was evaluated, and a small preliminary user evaluation was performed. Particular challenges and limitations of currently available hardware and software are also discussed. The combination of HMDs and haptics promises to be beneficial for educational, training and rehabilitation purposes. Future work should include more in-depth evaluation, as well as extension of the system beyond 3D model visualizations and simple haptic interactions to include more complex features such as material deformation and cutting, which are useful for many applications in STEM and beyond.</description><description>Simuler et visualiser le monde par des modèles en trois dimensions (3-D) est primordial pour de nombreux domaines de la science, la technologie, l'ingénierie et la médecine (STIM). Solliciter les différents sens de l'être humain à travers des appareils divers, comme par exemple les visiocasques pour solliciter le sens de la vue et les appareils haptiques pour solliciter le sens du toucher, a permis de susciter le sentiment d'immersion dans un environnement virtuel. De nos jours, la technologie derrière les visiocasques et les appareils haptiques a évolué très rapidement mais les deux sont rarement combinés pour servir dans des applications STIM. L'objectif de cette recherche était de développer un système de réalité virtuelle qui combine à la fois un visiocasque pour consommateurs et un appareil haptique de niveau intermédiaire en utilisant un moteur de jeu. Un système de preuve de concept a été développé en utilisant le visiocasque Oculus Rift et l'appareil haptique Phantom Premium 1.5 High Force. Ce système a été développé en utilisant le moteur de jeu Unity 3D et testé avec deux modèles anatomiques du corps humain, un coeur et une partie d'un crâne. L'évaluation de la performance technique du système a été établie et une petite évaluation préliminaire de l'utilisateur a été effectuée. Les défis et limites des matériels et logiciels informatiques disponibles sont également discutés.La combinaison des visiocasques et des appareils haptiques promet d'être bénéfique pour des fins éducatives, d'entraînement et de réhabilitation. Les travaux futures doivent inclure une évaluation plus approfondie ainsi qu'une extension du système au-delà des visualisations des modèles 3D et des simples interactions haptiques pour inclure des fonctions plus complexes telles que la déformation de la matière et la coupe, utiles pour de nombreuses applications STIM et au-delà.</description><creator>Saad, Elie</creator><contributor>Paul Kry (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>W Robert J Funnell (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Biomedical Engineering</subject><title>A virtual-reality system for interacting with three-dimensional models using a haptic device and a head-mounted display</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd4730033.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p8418q927</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343v667</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>RÉSUMÉUn ascenseur spatial pourrait être une alternative aux fusées pour effectuer l'accès humain à l'espace. La construction d'un ascenseur spatial exige un matériau ayant une résistance à la traction élevée et une faible densité de masse. Un aspect important à considérer avant d'entamer la construction de l'ascenseur spatial est la dynamique de l'ascenseur spatial. Dans cette thèse, une partie importante de la dynamique – c'est-à-dire, les oscillations longitudinales du ruban de l'ascenseur spatial - est étudiée. Contrairement à des travaux antérieurs, une station spatiale située à l'altitude géosynchrone a été prise en considération. En utilisant la discrétisation par la méthode de modes hypothétiques et l'approche Lagrange, les équations de mouvement pour l'ascenseur spatial dans la direction longitudinale sont dérivées. Ces équations sont non- dimensionalisées et puis résolues en utilisant MATLAB. Sur la base de la solution de ces équations, l'effet de la masse de la station spatiale sur la durée et l'amplitude des oscillations longitudinales est examiné. On démontre que, si la masse de la station spatiale augmente, l'amplitude et la durée de ses oscillations augmentent aussi. De plus, l'effet de la variation de la masse du contrepoids sur l'amplitude des oscillations est étudié. On remarque que l'oscillation de la station spatiale dépend fortement de la masse du contrepoids. Il a été constaté que toute augmentation de la masse du contrepoids, même par un petit pourcentage, se traduira par des oscillations de la station spatiale et l'amplitude des oscillations augmente. D'autre part, toute diminution de la masse du contrepoids, même par un petit pourcentage se traduira par des oscillations de la station spatiale vers la terre, et l'amplitude des oscillations augmente. Finalement, l'effet de la masse de l'ascenseur et sa position sur les oscillations longitudinales du ruban sont étudiés, et les ajustements nécessaires dans la masse du contrepoids sont présentés. On a constaté que l'ascenseur comme une masse ponctuelle peut augmenter l'amplitude des oscillations de la station spatiale, et l'amplitude de ces oscillations dépend de la masse et de la distance de l'ascenseur vis-à-vis l'altitude géostationnaire. Il est également suggéré que les ascenseurs pourraient finalement faire partie du contrepoids ou de la station spatiale pour fournir de tels ajustements dans la masse du contrepoids ou de la station spatiale.</description><description>AbstractA space elevator could be an alternative to rockets for human access to space. Construction of a space elevator requires a material with a high tensile strength, and a low bulk density. An important aspect to consider before construction of the space elevator is the dynamics of space elevator. In this thesis, an important part of the dynamics - the longitudinal oscillations of the space elevator ribbon - is studied. Unlike previous works, a space station located at the geosynchronous altitude has been taken into account. Using discretization by assumed modes method and Lagrange approach, the equations of motion for the space elevator in the longitudinal direction are derived. These equations are nondimensionalized and then solved using MATLAB. Based on the solution of these equations, the effect of the mass of the space station on the period and amplitude of the longitudinal oscillations is examined. It is shown that if the mass of the space station increases, both the amplitude and the period of its oscillations increase. Also the effect of the change in the mass of the counterweight on the amplitude of the oscillations is studied. It is observed that the oscillation of the space station depends strongly on the mass of the counterweight. It was found that any increase in the mass of the counterweight, even by a small percentage, will result in oscillations of the space station and the amplitude of the oscillations increases. On the other hand, any decrease in the mass of the counterweight even by a small percentage will result in oscillations of the space station toward the earth, and the amplitude of the oscillations increase.  Finally, the effect of the mass of the climber and its position on the longitudinal oscillations of the ribbon is studied, and the needed adjustments in the mass of the counterweight are presented. It was found that the climber as a point mass can increase the amplitude of the space station oscillations, and the amplitude of these oscillations depends on the mass and the distance of the climber from the geostationary altitude. It is also suggested that the climbers finally could become part of the counterweight or space station to provide such adjustments in the mass of the counterweight or the space station.</description><creator>Fardad, Keivan</creator><contributor>Arun K Misra (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering</subject><title>Longitudinal oscillations of the space elevator ribbon</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fb97b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343v667</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb397b94k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cancer is one of the leading causes of death worldwide. Genetic and epigenetic alterations in cells lead to dysregulated expression and activity of two main categories of genes, tumor suppressors and oncogenes, which results in aberrant cell signaling, proliferation and tumor formation. One of the highly expressed oncogenes in many cancer types is the c-Myc transcription factor. c-Myc drives tumor initiation and progression as well as tumor maintenance. MXD1, another transcription factor, antagonizes c-Myc activity. c-Myc/MXD1 network are regulated by changes in protein expression and turnover, which determines whether a cell proliferates or remains in quiescent state. Increasing evidence has revealed that vitamin D has anti-proliferative and pro-differentiating effects. Epidemiological data strongly suggest that vitamin D acts as a cancer chemopreventive agent, and its levels are inversely correlated with cancer risk, however the underlying mechanisms have not been fully elucidated. In this study, we have investigated the effect of hormonal 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D (1,25D) on the expression and activity of c-Myc and MXD1 transcription factors. This work has uncovered new molecular mechanisms of cancer chemopreventive effects of vitamin D through cooperation with the FBW7 E3 ubiquitin ligase, a key regulator of c-Myc and MXD1 turnover. FBW7 is a tumor suppressor that regulates the turnover over several drivers of cell proliferation and tumorigenesis. We have shown through in vitro and in vivo studies that the 1,25D-bound vitamin D receptor (VDR) profoundly alters the balance in function of c-Myc and its antagonist MXD1 through multiple mechanisms. 1,25D inhibited transcription of c-Myc-regulated genes in vitro, and topical 1,25D application to mouse skin suppressed expression of c-Myc and its target gene Setd8. In contrast, MXD1 levels were elevated in vitro and after topical application of 1,25D to mice skin. 1,25D also accelerated c-Myc protein turnover, but enhanced MXD1 expression and stability, which resulted in a profound alteration in the ratios of recruited c-Myc and MXD1 to the promoters of target genes. In addition, c-Myc expression increased upon VDR knockdown. This effect was abolished following knockdown of β-catenin (CTNNB1), an activator of MYC gene transcription. Consistent with these findings, c-Myc expression was widely elevated in Vdr-/- mouse tissues. This included intestinal epithelia, where enhanced proliferation has been reported, and skin epithelia, where phenotypes of VDR-deficient mice are similar to those overexpressing epidermal c-Myc.  Unexpectedly, we found that the E3-ubiquitin ligase FBW7 not only regulates the stability of c-Myc, the oncogenic arm of the c-Myc/MXD1 push-pull network, but also regulates the turnover of the tumor suppressor arm, MXD1. FBW7 ablation attenuated 1,25D regulation of c-Myc and MXD1 turnover. FBW7 interacted with c-Myc, MXD1 and VDR in coimmunoprecipitation assays. The association of FBW7 with c-Myc was enhanced and that of MXD1 was inhibited in the presence of 1,25D, consistent with the effects of 1,25D on their turnover. Furthermore, FBW7 was recruited to the promoter of c-Myc target genes in association with c-Myc, MXD1 and VDR. The recruitment of FBW7 to the promoter of c-Myc target genes was not altered following treatment of the cells with 1,25D, however, its association with c-Myc was enhanced, in agreement with the elevated c-Myc degradation. In contrast, association of FBW7 with DNA-bound MXD1 declined in the presence of 1,25D.Remarkably, Analysis of VDR expression suggested that FBW7 increases the turnover of VDR protein in the presence of 1,25D, without having any effect on its mRNA expression. These results reveal that VDR and FBW7 regulate each other's function. They also provide a novel molecular basis for cancer preventive actions of vitamin D, as well as insights into the mechanisms by which 1,25D signaling regulates cell proliferation.</description><description>Le cancer est une des principales causes de mortalité à travers le monde. Des modifications génétiques et épigénétiques entrainent des dérégulations d'expression et d'activité de deux grandes catégories de gènes, les gènes suppresseurs de tumeur et les oncogènes, entraînant à leur tour des dérégulations de voie métaboliques allant de la prolifération et la formation de tumeurs. Un des oncogènes le plus exprimé est le facteur de transcription c-Myc qui déclenche l'initiation, la progression et le maintien de la tumeur. MXD1, un autre facteur de transcription, antagonise l'activité c-Myc. Les deux branches du réseau c-Myc/MXD1 sont régulées par des changements du niveau d'expression et le renouvellement de protéines, ce qui détermine si la cellule prolifère ou reste quiescente. Des preuves grandissantes ont révélé que la vitamine D a un effet anti-prolifératif et entraine la differentiation cellulaire.  Des données épidémiologiques suggèrent que la vitamine D protège chimiquement du cancer, et que ses niveaux sont inversement corrélés au risque de cancer. Les mécanismes de ce phénomene ne sont toutefois pas élucidés.Dans cette etude, nous avons étudié l'effet hormonal de 1,25-dihydroxyvitamine D (1,25D) sur l'expression et l'activité des facteurs de transcription c-Myc et de MXD1. Ce travail a révélé de nouveaux mécanismes moléculaires dans la chimioprotection liée a la vitamin D à travers une coopération avec l'ubiquitine ligase FBW7 E3, un régulateur clé du renouvellement de c-Myc et MXD1. FBW7 est un suppresseur de tumeur qui régule le renouvellement de plusieurs agents de la prolifération cellulaire et de la tumorigenèse. Nous avons montré avec des études in vitro et in vivo que le récepteur de la vitamine D (VDR) couplé à 1,25D change profondément l'équilibre et la function de c-Myc et antagonise MXD1 à travers divers mécanismes. 1,25D inhibe la transcription de gènes sous le contrôle de c-Myc. L'application locale de 1,25D sur la peau murine diminue l'expression de c-Myc et de son gène cible Setd8. Par contre, les niveaux de MXD1 sont élevés in vitro et après application de 1,25D sur la peau murine. 1,25D accélère également le renouvellement de c-Myc alors que MXD1 en augmente l'expression et la stabilité, ce qui entraine un changement majeur du recrutement de c-Myc et de MXD1 au niveau des promoteurs de leurs gènes cibles. De plus, l'expression de c-Myc augmente suite a la diminution d'expression de VDR. Cet effet est bloqué si béta-caténine, un activateur du gène MYC, est préalablement inhibée. En accord avec ces découvertes, l'expression de c-Myc était largement augmentée dans les tissus de souris Vdr-/-. Ceci tant au niveau de l'épithelium intestinal, ou une prolifération accrue a été rapportée, qu'au niveau de la peau, ou les phénotypes de souris VDR-déficientes sont similaires a ceux de souris surexprimant c-Myc. Nous avons été surpris de trouver que E3-ubiquitine ligase FBW7 régule non seulement la stabilité de c-Myc, l'aspect oncogénique de l'équilibre dynamique c-Myc/MXD1, mais également le renouvellement du suppresseur de tumeur MXD1. La perte de FBW7 atténue la régulation de c-Myc par 1,25D ainsi que le renouvellement de MXD1. FBW7 interagit avec c-Myc, MXD1 et VDR dans des expériences de co-immunoprécipitations. L'association de FBW7 avec c-Myc est facilitée et celle avec MXD1 est inhibée en présence de 1,25D, ce qui va de pair avec l'effet de 1,25D sur leur renouvellement. De façon intéressante, Une analyse d'expression de VDR suggère que FBW7 augmente le taux de nouvellement protéique de VDR en présence de 1,25D sans aucun effet sur les niveaux de transcrits. Ces résultats montrent que VDR et FBW7 régulent leurs fonctions respectives et apportent un nouveau mécanisme moléculaire par lequel la vitamine D prévient du cancer ainsi que des pistes de mécanismes par lesquels 1,25D agit sur la prolifération cellulaire.</description><creator>Salehi Tabar, Reyhaneh</creator><contributor>John H White (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Medicine</subject><title>The hormone-bound vitamin D receptor regulates turnover of target proteins of the SCFFBW7 E3 ligase</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gn670.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397b94k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jp18d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigates the properties of flexible epoxy adhesives and their applicability in the design of hybrid bolted/bonded joints. There is increasing interest in using flexible adhesives for joint design, due to their ductility that enables significant elongation before failure. Generally, the behaviour of ductile adhesive involves considerable nonlinearities including large deformation, nonlinear material properties and plasticity. Analysis of flexible adhesives is more challenging than that of stiff adhesives, which is sufficiently described by linear elasticity and infinitesimal strain theory. The present study experimentally characterizes EA9361, selected as the representative material for flexible epoxy adhesives. The tensile tests, based on ASTM D638, generate stress/strain relation and also measure the evolution of Poisson's ratio throughout the strain until failure. From the stress/strain curve of the tensile tests, distinct yielding is observed. Therefore, in order to further understand the yielding nature of the epoxy adhesive, biaxial tests are then performed using a custom-designed Arcan fixture. While the biaxial tests try to capture yield stresses at different levels of biaxial loading, sharp stress concentrations are developed in the adhesive due to the constraint effects caused by high Poisson's ratio. Consequently, the values of the measured yield stresses are severely underestimated except for the pure shear case. From the pure shear case, the shear stress/strain relation is presented.  Also tested is the adhesive under tension-tension cyclic loading in order to investigate the evolution of material properties through repeated cycles of plastic deformation. The results show that the material response converges in the presence of yielding and significant viscous effects. In addition to the above material characterizations, hybrid bolted/bonded joints are tested under cyclic loading in order to simulate in-situ application of a flexible adhesive. The results of the joint testing show that, despite the complex adhesive's response due to yielding and viscous effects, proper use of flexible epoxy adhesives could help design hybrid joints that operate at higher efficiency. Additionally, a new methodology to measure adhesive strain for a very thin adhesive bondline is proposed, and the custom-designed testing and manufacturing devices are introduced.</description><description>Cette étude porte sur les propriétés d'un adhésif flexible et son applicabilité dans la conception du joint hybrides boulonnés/collés pour structures aérospatiales. En raison de sa ductilité qui permet un allongement significatif avant l'échec, l'utilisation d'adhésif flexible pour la conception des joints suscite un intérêt croissant. En général, le comportement de l'adhésif ductile est considérablement non-linéaire : ceci inclut de grande déformation, des propriétés de matériaux non-linéaires et la plasticité. L'analyse d'un adhésif flexible est plus difficile que celle d'un adhésif rigide, qui est suffisamment décrit par élasticité linéaire et la théorie de déformation infinitésimale. La présente étude caractérise expérimentalement des adhésifs époxy flexibles, en utilisant EA9361 comme matériau représentatif. Les essais de traction, selon ASTM D638, génèrent des relations entre la contrainte et la déformation et mesurent également l'évolution du coefficient de Poisson au long du processus de contrainte jusqu'à la rupture. De l'écoulement plastique distincte est observé par des tests de traction. Ensuite, afin de définir la transition entre l'élasticité et la plasticité, des tests bi-axiaux sont effectués en utilisant un montage Arcan conçu sur mesure. Alors que les tests bi-axiaux tentent de mesurer des limites d'écoulements à différents niveaux de chargement bi-axial, des concentrations de contraintes sont développées dans l'adhésif en raison des effets de contraintes causées par le coefficient de Poisson élevé. Par conséquent, les valeurs de la limite d'écoulement sont gravement sous-estimées, sauf pour le cas de cisaillement pur. Dans le cas de cisaillement pur, la relation entre la déformation de cisaillement et la contrainte est notée. On a également testé l'adhésif sous une charge cyclique tension-tension, afin d'étudier l'évolution de la réponse du matériau par des cycles répétés de déformation plastique. Les résultats montrent que la réponse du matériau converge en présence d'écoulement et d'effets visqueux. En outre des caractérisations des matériaux ci-dessus, joints hybrides boulonnés / collés sont testés sous une charge cyclique afin de simuler l'application in-situ d'un adhésif flexible. Les résultats des tests de joints montrent que, en dépit de la complexité en raison de plasticité et les effets visqueux d'adhésifs ductiles, leur utilisation appropriée pourrait aider à la conception des articulations hybrides d'une plus grande efficacité. En plus, une nouvelle méthodologie pour mesurer un allongement adhésif pour un collage très mince est proposée, et des appareils d'essai et de fabrication sur mesure sont introduits.</description><creator>Lim, Gyu-hyeong</creator><contributor>Larry Lessard (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering</subject><title>Mechanical characterization of flexible adhesive and its influence on hybrid joint design</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687k913.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jp18d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65vb33j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'objectif de cette thèse de doctorat était d'étudier le développement des valeurs intrinsèques et extrinsèques ainsi que l'impact qu'ont les différences individuelles au niveau des valeurs sur le fonctionnement adaptatif au fil du temps. Les aspirations de richesse, beauté et célébrité sont promues par les médias dans les sociétés occidentales. Toutefois, des données de plus en plus nombreuses démontrent que de telles aspirations peuvent être néfastes pour le bien-être. Les chercheurs Kasser et Ryan (1993; 1996), étudiant la théorie de l'auto-détermination, ont différencié deux formes de valeurs de vie: les aspirations intrinsèques (croissance personnelle, contribution communautaire, et formation de relations étroites) et les aspirations extrinsèques (richesse, popularité/célébrité, et apparence physique). Des études antérieures ont révélé que les individus qui accordent davantage d'importance aux aspirations intrinsèques, par rapport aux aspirations extrinsèques, ont tendance à ressentir un plus grand bien-être et moins de symptômes liés à la dépression et l'anxiété. Cependant, de récentes analyses de ce champ de recherche (Koestner &amp; Hope, 2014; Dittmar, Bond, Hurst, &amp; Kasser, 2014) ont démontré un manque de recherches longitudinales nécessaires à l'étude des trajectoires développementales des aspirations et de l'impact des aspirations sur le bien-être futur. En l'absence d'études longitudinales rigoureuses, la relation entre la mise en priorité des aspirations intrinsèques, par rapport aux aspirations extrinsèques, et le bien-être demeure inconnue. Ainsi, la présente thèse examine les antécédents et les conséquences de la mise en priorité relative des aspirations intrinsèques chez les jeunes adultes dans trois études longitudinales. L'Article 1 étudie l'influence des changements survenant au cours d'une année scolaire dans les valeurs des jeunes adultes (aspirations intrinsèques par rapport à extrinsèques) sur les changements au niveau du bien-être et du développement psychosocial. En suivant 196 étudiants de septembre à avril, j'ai trouvé qu'une plus grande mise en priorité des valeurs intrinsèques au cours de l'année, par rapport aux valeurs extrinsèques, mène à un développement supérieur de l'identité et de l'intimité. L'Article 2 continue sur le thème de l'étude longitudinale des conséquences associées aux aspirations intrinsèques, par rapport aux aspirations extrinsèques. Par contre, plutôt que de se concentrer uniquement sur les aspirations intrinsèques et extrinsèques au niveau de l'individu, L'Article 2 examine également l'impact des différences en terme d'ambition et de motivation au niveau des objectifs. Plus précisément, L'Article 2 étudie l'impact de la poursuite d'objectifs personnels associés aux valeurs intrinsèques, par rapport aux valeurs extrinsèques, sur la progression de l'objectif et l'état émotionnel lié à l'objectif chez les jeunes adultes. J'ai trouvé que les individus font davantage de progrès et ressentent davantage de vitalité en poursuivant leurs objectifs personnels les plus intrinsèques. Dans mon étude doctorale finale, L'Article 3, j'ai élucidé les trajectoires de développement des valeurs chez les jeunes adultes, examinant les influences du contexte social et de la personnalité des proches (ex. le perfectionnisme) sur la mise en priorité des aspirations intrinsèques par rapport aux aspirations extrinsèques. Dans cette longitudinale à informateurs multiples effectuée auprès de 341 étudiants, de leurs amis et des membres de leur famille, j'ai trouvé que le niveau de perfectionnisme chez les amis prédit une augmentation des aspirations extrinsèques avec le temps. D'une autre part, lorsque les étudiants mettent en priorité des aspirations extrinsèques, par rapport aux aspirations intrinsèques, leur bien-être diminue et ils deviennent davantage contrôlés et moins autonomes dans leur motivation à poursuivre leurs objectifs personnels.</description><description>The aim of this doctoral thesis was to investigate the development of intrinsic relative to extrinsic values priorities, and the impact of individual differences in values priorities on adaptive functioning over time. Life aspirations of affluence, beauty, and fame are promoted by the mass media in Western society, yet mounting evidence has revealed that such aspirations may be detrimental to well-being. Self-determination theory researchers Kasser and Ryan (1993; 1996) have distinguished two forms of life values, intrinsic aspirations (personal growth, community contribution, and building close relationships) and extrinsic aspirations (wealth, popularity/fame, and physical attractiveness). Previous research has revealed that individuals who tend to prioritize intrinsic aspirations over extrinsic aspirations tend to experience greater well-being, and fewer symptoms of anxiety and depression. However, recent reviews of this body of research (Koestner &amp; Hope, 2014; Dittmar, Bond, Hurst, &amp; Kasser, 2014) have found a lack of longitudinal studies necessary for examining both the developmental trajectory of aspirations and the impact of aspirations on future well-being. Without rigorous longitudinal investigations directionality in the relationship between prioritization of intrinsic relative to extrinsic aspirations and well-being remains unknown. Therefore, the present thesis examined the antecedents and consequences of the relative prioritization of intrinsic aspirations for young adults in three longitudinal investigations. Article 1 examines the influence of change in young adults' values over an academic year on their changes in well-being and their psychosocial development. Following 196 students from September to April, I found that found that increased prioritization of intrinsic relative to extrinsic values over the year led to greater identity and intimacy development. Article 2 continues on the theme of longitudinally examining the consequences of intrinsic relative to extrinsic aspirations. However, instead of focusing on intrinsic relative to extrinsic aspirations exclusively at the level of the person, Article 2 also considers the impact of differences in aspirations at the level of the goal. Specifically, Article 2 examines the impact of pursuing personal goals connected to intrinsic relative to extrinsic aspirations on young adults' goal progress and goal-related affect. I found that individuals make greater goal progress and experience greater vitality from pursuing their more intrinsic personal goals. In my final doctoral investigation, Article 3, I elucidated pathways to development of young adults' values, examining the influence of social context and close others' personality (e.g., trait perfectionism) on individuals' prioritization of intrinsic relative to extrinsic aspirations. In this multi-informant longitudinal study of 341 students and their friends and family members, I found that friends' level of perfectionism predicted an increase in the students' extrinsic aspirations over time. In turn, as students' prioritized extrinsic over intrinsic aspirations, their well-being decreased, and they became more controlled and less autonomous in their motivation for their personal goals.Overall, the empirical evidence collected for the present work suggests a positive impact of prioritizing intrinsic aspirations over time. In the conclusion, I review the following empirical contributions of the present work: 1) young adults who prioritize intrinsic relative to extrinsic aspirations more highly tend to experience increased well-being over time, compared to those who are lower on prioritization of intrinsic aspirations 2) prioritizing intrinsic aspirations and pursuing personal goals connected to intrinsic aspirations leads to greater goal progress and vitality for goals, and 3) close friends' perfectionism influences young adults' values priorities, predicting greater prioritization of extrinsic aspirations. </description><creator>Hope, Nora</creator><contributor>Richard Koestner (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Psychology</subject><title>Antecedents and consequences of life aspirations: implications for well-being and self-regulation in three longitudinal investigations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/000002746.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65vb33j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gf06g538k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T14:45:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le dioxyde de carbone est l'un des principaux gaz à effet de serre, et contribue au réchauffement climatique. L'une des sources anthropiques majeures de CO2 est la combustion des carburants fossiles, d'où l'importance de l'application de techniques de mitigation sur les processus de combustion, afin de capturer le CO2 et réduire les émissions dans l'atmosphère. Les photo-bioréacteurs avec des micro-algues ont démontré un potentiel pour la fixation de CO2. Toutefois, ils présentent plusieurs désavantages donc la formation de sous-produits ou des particules aériennes (aérosols). Ceux-ci peuvent avoir un impact négatif sur le climat et la santé humaine s'ils sont relâchés dans l'atmosphère. Je présente le développement d'un système de photo-bioréacteur avec des algues couplé avec des interfaces de nano- et microparticules naturels contenant des oxydes de fer et d'aluminium, ce qui a le potentiel de remédier aux sous-produits gazeux à la source tout en réduisant les émissions de CO2. Le système utilise des nanoparticules recyclables et peut fonctionner à l'énergie solaire. De plus, afin de gérer les déchets algaux du photo-bioréacteur, des tests d'absorption préliminaires ont été effectués qui démontrent le potentiel des algues dans le rôle de biosorbent pour remédier au mercure gazeux, un polluant aussi présent dans les émissions de gaz de combustion. Une étude de faisabilité a aussi été effectuée afin d'étudier la viabilité économique de l'installation ainsi que son potentiel de mise à échelle pour l'associer à des installations industrielles.</description><description>Carbon dioxide is one of the main greenhouse gases, known to contribute to global warming. A major source of anthropogenic CO2 is from the combustion of fossil fuels, hence the application of mitigation techniques on combustion processes to capture CO2 are of great importance to reduce emissions being released to the atmosphere. Photo-bioreactors with microalgae have demonstrated a potential for CO2 fixation. However, they can present several drawbacks including the formation of side products or airborne particles (aerosols). These can have a negative impact on the climate and human health, if released to the atmosphere. I present the development of an algal photo-bioreactor system coupled with natural nano- and micro-particle interfaces containing iron oxides and alumina, which has the potential to remediate gaseous by-products at the source while reducing CO2 emissions. The system uses recyclable nanoparticles, and can be operable using solar energy. Furthermore, to manage the algal waste produced from the photo-bioreactor, preliminary absorption tests were performed which demonstrated the potential of algae to serve as a biosorbent for remediation of gaseous mercury, a pollutant also present in flue gas emissions. A feasibility cost analysis was also performed to analyze the cost-effectiveness of the set-up and its up-scaling potential to couple it to existing industrial setups. </description><creator>Rocha, Andrea</creator><contributor>Parisa A Ariya (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2016</date><subject>Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</subject><title>Development of a hybrid photo-bioreactor coupled with nano-and micro-interfaces for air pollution remediation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935561b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g538k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):7275</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>