<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:34:28Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11700" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1c18dj79j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An essential measurement far the exact comprehension of the physical properties of macromolecular substances, as well as far the study of the rules through whi eh their polymerization reactions occur, is the determination of the molecular weight. A theoretically unquestionable method far the determination of the molecular weight of high polymers, in the ranges between 104 and 106, is the application of osmotic pressure measurements, or measure~nts of the sedimentation equilibrium (1) using a Svedberg ultracentrifuge. The importance of these methods depends upon the fact that in the case of their evaluation, only the gas constant R is assumed (2}. Besides these methods, because of its extreme simplicity, the viscometric determination of the molecular weight has been used extensively, particularly in industry. However, the inherent uncertainty associated with the interpretation of the results limits its value considerably. In the present work viscosity and osmotic measurements have been undertaken. [...]</description><creator>Sirianni, Aurele Frederick.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946. </date><subject>Chemistry. </subject><title>Molecular weight measurements of macromolecules with an improved osmometer.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wg89j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dj79j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zw12z835q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although the reaction between cellulose nitrates and alkali has been frequently studied, the conditions used invariably brought about severe degradation and produced low molecular products. Nevertheless, the nitrate groups in the second, third and sixth positions of the glucose residues constituting cellulose almost certainly differ in reactivity. Proper experimental conditions should therefore make it possible to remove one nitrate group selectively without substantially affecting the rest. The discovery of such conditions was the initial object of the present research, which forms part of the confidential N.R.C. war project XR-74 on the thermal and alkaline stability of nitrated celluloses.</description><creator>Segall, Gordon Hart.</creator><contributor>Purves, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946. </date><subject>Chemistry. </subject><title>The selective denitration of cellulose nitrates.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698b881.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z835q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773z80d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Formaldehyde, which is prepared by the oxidation of methyl alcohol, was available only in limited quantities prior to 1923. In that year, however, a commercial method for the production of synthetic methyl alcohol by the catalytic reduction of carbon monoxide was discovered (1). This in turn made formaldehyde more plentiful, as a result of which it became possible to produce hexamine in large quantity by the evaporation of an aqueous solution of formaldehyde and ammonia. Before World War II, hexamine was produced commercially for use in industry as a special form of anhydrous formaldehyde, for example, in the manufacture of synthetic resins. To a smaller extent, it was used in the preparation of certain pharmaceutical products. The production of hexamine and the study of its chemistry attained national importance, however, by its use as the starting material in the production of the explosive, RDX.[...]</description><creator>Polley, John Richard.</creator><contributor>Nicholls, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Chemistry. </subject><title>Studies on the formation of hexamine from formaldehyde and ammonium salts in aqueous solution.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kx03q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773z80d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pg15bj10q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>(1) This research is part of N.R.C. project XR-79,a search for desirable stabilizers for guncotton. Three substituted ureas, N,N'-diethyl-N,N'-bis-(3,4-dimethoxyphenyl)· urea, N-ethyl-N,N'-bis-(3,4-dimethoxyphenyl)-urea, and N,N'-bis-{3,4-dimethoxyphenyl)-urea were synthesized. These compounds are analogues of the co~mon stabilizer, centralite. Tho first two were new compounds, and were characterized; the third was synthesized by a new method. (2) The necessary intermediate, 4-athylwAinoveratrola, was synthesized in four ways, and characterized by derivatives. The benzenesulfonyl and acetyl derivatives were also employed in the purification of the compound. Practical methods of hydrolyzing these derivatives were discovered. {3) In addition to those already mentioned, the following new compounds ware prepared in pure form and analyzed: 4-bromoacetylguaiacol, N-benzenesulfonyl-3,4-dimethoxyaniline, N-ethyl-N-benzenesulfonyl-3,4-dimethoxyanilina, N-othyl-3,4- dimethoxyacetanilide, and N-ethyl• N-3,4-dimethoxyphenylcarbamyl chloride.</description><creator>Moir, Robert Young.</creator><contributor>Purves, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946. </date><subject>Chemistry. </subject><title>Synthesis of a substituted centralite.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w551w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bj10q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tq16g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The first difficulty is concerned with the differences that exist between the sediments and their source rocks. Sedimentary rocks are formed from the destruction of igneous and metamorphic rocks, or from earlier sediments. Features which may have been distinctive of the source rocks are likely to be submerged during the processes of weathering, transportation, and deposition. Sediments of very diverse origins may look very much alike after a long period of transportation, since only certain kinds of material can withstand continued attrition or adverse climatic environment. Conversely within narrow limits the same source rocks can give derived sediments of more or less widely varying characteristics under differing conditions. A sediment is not an equilibrium product. A tendency towards equilibrium is exhibited by the various component minerals at the temperatures, pressures and other physical conditions existing on, or close to, the surface of the earth. Certain minerals are very unstable under these conditions, and are altered to other minerals which are stable. A granite is very stable at the temperature and pressure under which it was formed beneath the crust of the earth. If these temperatures and pressures, and other attendant physical conditions, are maintained, it is conceivable that the granite could exist indefinitely without any changes. Should this granite be exposed at the surface of the earth, it is no longer at equilibrium.[...]</description><creator>McPherson, William John.</creator><contributor>Clark, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Geological Sciences.</subject><title>Critical review of criteria used in the nomenclature and classification of sandstones.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dg83z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tq16g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb397c45v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>[...] The first section of this thesis describes the studies which led to a satisfactory process for recovering acetic acid. The latter two sections, although of much less importance to large scale manufacture of RDX, contributed to the knowledge of the intricate mechanism of the Bachmann Process. The combined efforts of numerous research workers, each making his small contribution in this way, have provided a very considerable knowledge of polymethylene nitramine chemistry.</description><creator>MacHutchin, John George. </creator><contributor>Winkler, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946. </date><subject>Chemistry. </subject><title>The recovery of glacial acetic acid from the residual liquors of the Bachmann process. : 2. The rate of disappearance of hexamine in Bachmann type mixtures and the discovery of L-DPT. 3. The kinetics of BSX formation.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn107225b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397c45v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nx82k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A method was developed for the accurate estimation of the acetyl content of trityl cellulose acetates. Monotrityl cellulose diacetate (I) waB prepared and fully characterized. The nitration of I, to yield a 11cellttlose-6-nitrate diacetate11 , was found to be accompanied by considerable deacetylation. The nature of this deacetylation was studied. The replacement by iodine of tosyloxy and nitrate groups in the cellulose molecule was studied. At least 0.52 of the nitrate groups in a 'bellulose-6-nitrate'' were definitely shown to occupy the primary position. Some of the results indicate that application of the 110ldham - Rutherford Rule" to cellulose mey prove misleading.[...]</description><creator>Lemieux, Raymond U.</creator><contributor>Purves, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946. </date><subject>Chemistry. </subject><title>Hindrance effects' in cellulose substitution reactions.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kk463.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nx82k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80hz77j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>When the work of designing and building a null detector was undertaken as a thesis, the initial research was broken up into two phases. The first phase consisted of analyzing the conditions necessary for balancing impedance bridges of various types. The second phase consisted of analyzing the properties necessary for the functioning of a null detector. The bridge is essentially a comparator and its basic property is to attain two equipotential points to compare the bridge arms to each other. The customary types of null detectors used in balancing impedance bridges may be classified under the following headings-, :- (1) Headphones with or without amplification; (2) Tuned vibration galvanometers; (3) A.C. galvanometers of the dynamometer type; (k) D.C. galvanometers of the d’Arsonval type, preceded by suitable rectification; (5) Electronic visual indicators of the cathode-ray oscillograph type. A more detailed discussion of the various types of detectors will be discussed in the following paragraph. Literature on as many types of commercial null detectors as possible was studied. The reasons for the various limitations of these units were studied. The purpose of this thesis was to try to incorporate the best qualities of all of these units into a single unit. An effort was made to overcome these limitations.[...]</description><creator>Merson, Lawrence Nelson.</creator><contributor>Howes, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Electrical Engineering.</subject><title>The Analysis, design and construction of a null detector for a-c impedance bridges.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b657m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hz77j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bg257j053</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis breaks away from the usual procedure in that it uses newspapers for historical sources, something that has all too infrequently been done in works on Canadian History. In fact, the regrettable lack of other studies along the same lines made for considerable difficulty in its preparation. The reader will notice the extensive, I will not say disproportionate, use made of Montreal papers such as the Gazette, the Herald, the Courier, the Pilot, the Witness, La Minerve. Le Moniteur Canadien, and L’Avenir. I will not say disproportionate, because Montreal was really the seat of the movement, and although it thrived in the Eastern Townships, it was still largely inspired and directed by the Central Annexation Association in Montreal. This city was where the annexation movement began, it was the acknowledged leader, and many of its wealthy citizens were the movement’s chief supporters. For that reason Montreal papers naturally have a greater importance than Quebec ones. Because of this, and the tendency of the Quebec papers to report the agitation through the eyes of the Montreal press, the newspapers of this latter city should and do occupy the dominant position.</description><creator>Mills, G. H. Stanley (George Hampden Stanley)</creator><contributor>Cooper, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Canada -- Annexation to the United States.</subject><title>The annexation movement of 1849-50 as seen through Lower Canadian press.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d570087c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bg257j053</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451m87g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study on the Confederation of Catholic Workers of Canada has been undertaken in view of the fact that there is little material of an organized and comprehensive nature available on this subject. It traces, in a general manner, the causes for the establishment of an organization of an exclusive character for the French Canadian Catholic worker out of the peculiar problems or the industrialization of Quebec and a complication of this process by the ethnic differences between the initiators of industrialization and the workers destined to be employed in production. Following an account of the growth and development of the organization, there is an examination of the philosophy and ideology of the Catholic labor movement in order to point out the differences which exist betweent these and the non-sectarian labor unions of Canada. The latter part of the thesis is devoted to a study of the attitude of the Catholic Syndicates towards the general labor movement (T.L.C. and C.C.L.) and its effectiveness as a union organization in performing the function and achieving the aims of unionism.</description><creator>Mindes, Evelyn.</creator><contributor>Woods, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Economics.</subject><title>Confederation of Catholic workers of Canada.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sn00b1906.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451m87g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j4202</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Few living political thinkers are better known than Professor Harold Laski. Educated at Oxford, he came to this continent during world war I and taught first at McGill and afterwards at Harvard. At both universities he promptly got into hot water with the authorities for publicly expressing (to them) objectionable opinions. Receiving an appointment as lecturer at the London School of Economics, Laski returned to England in 1920. A prolific writer, he has built up a solid and enviable reputation for exact scholarship (all who have met or heard Laski testify to his phenomenal memory) brilliant rhetoric and complete sincerity. A forceful and eloquent speaker, he has received this century's most positive accolade of fame - his speeches are reported. Today, the chairman and influential spokesman, he is also sometimes referred to as the one-man brain trust of the British Labour Party.[...]</description><creator>Layton, Irving.</creator><contributor>Tuck, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946. </date><subject>Laski, Harold Joseph, 1893-1950 -- Political and social views.</subject><subject>Socialism.</subject><title>A critical examination of Laski’s political doctrines.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pd838.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j4202</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hj692</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this experiment, rats were fed a series of baked diets containing three different shortenings, ( Lard, Covo and Rapeseed ) incorporated at 0, 8, 18 and 36 percent by weight. The protein level for half the diets was maintained at 17 percent of the calories,while the remaining half contained 15 percent protein by weight. Lard and Covo were of equal nutritional value but the Rapeseed diets were less palatable and produced significantly lower gains at 38 and 36 percent levels. It was concluded that high levels of Rapeseed decreased the efficiency of utilization of the diet. Variations in gain were not explainable by differences in digestibility. When the protein calories remained constant, increasing the fat level produced increased gains for Lard and Covo, but not for Rapeseed. However, when the protein level was constant by weight, gains on Lard and Covo diets showed no significant difference between fat levels, while gains on Rapeseed diets decreased significantly.</description><creator>Millar, M. J.</creator><contributor>Crampton, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Nutrition.</subject><title>A study on the utilization of different kinds and levels of fat in baked diets.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x6955.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hj692</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x696f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The composition of the top few inches of the soil, with which the agriculturist is mainly concerned, consists of a mineral framework of inorganic particles varying in degree of subdivision and in chemical composition. These particles are coated with a hygroscopic layer of organic matter in the colloidal state, in various stages of decomposition, the whole in close association with inorganic aggregates in a similar state. The spaces between the particles are occupied by the soil atmosphere and the soil solution. The soil is biologically very active and provides the habitat for an extensive microbial population, comprising bacteria, actinomycetes, fungi, algae, and protozoa, for which the organic-inorganic colloid complex serves as a supply of energy and nutrition. Bacteria predominate, both in numbers and in variety of activities, over all the others and it is with this group that the present study is concerned.[...]</description><creator>Rouatt, James Wilbert.</creator><contributor>Gray, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Agricultural Bacteriology.</subject><title>The effects of adding inorganic fertilizers and glucose on the morphological and physiological groups of bacteria in soil.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579w48r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x696f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Bacteriology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227mt05t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The commercial importance of the Yellowtail Flounder (Limanda ferruginea Storer) in recent years has greatly increased, partly because of the greater use of otter trawlers in North American waters, and also as a response to the unprecedented demand for fish products during the war. This is particularly true in the case of Canada where, until recently, the traditional method of fishing was line trawling, a method which prevented the capture of yellowtails since its mouth is so small that one is rarely caught on the large hooks used for cod, haddock, and pollock. These factors have led to an extensive exploitation of the yellowtail fisheries, especially in New England waters where, in 1942, more than 65,000,000 pounds of yellowtails were landed. Since then yellowtail landings in New England have steadily decreased, although the fishing intensity has increased, and there are indications that this decrease may be the result of over-fishing. The position of the yellowtail upon the Canadian market, although much less important, is becoming increasingly significant. [...]</description><creator>Scott, David Maxwell.</creator><contributor>Berrill, N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Flatfishes.</subject><title>The biology of the Yellowtail flounder (Limanda fervuginea - Storer).</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f6805.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mt05t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Zoology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712mb049</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The chief purpose of this investigation was to study the influence of quinine and atabrine on the parasympathetic (vagal) innervation of the gastric glands in the dog, both in acute form of experimentation and in a dog with a permanent gastric fistula. The problem arose as a sequel to previous work with quinine done in this laboratory. Repeating the old experiments of R. Heidenhain ' 1 \ who was the first to observe the effect of quinine on the parasympathetic nervous system in 1868, Stavraky (1933) ^2' found that quinine hydrochloride, administered intravenously to the dog, paralyzed the secretory fibres in the chorda tympani (for the submaxillary gland) and in the auriculo-temporal nerve (for the parotid gland).[...]</description><creator>Karp, Dorothy.</creator><contributor>Babkin, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946. </date><subject>Stomach -- Secretions.</subject><subject>Quinine.</subject><subject>Quinacrine.</subject><subject>Dogs -- Physiology.</subject><title>The effect of quinine and atabrine on gastric secretory function in the dog.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s806b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712mb049</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54kr248</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the investigation of the properties of nitrodicyandiamidine, a flashless propellant component, it was found that the substance is a weak acid since a number of stable metal salts could be isolated. Salt formation of nitrodicyandiamidine may be used as a basis for its quantitative estimation. Similar to other urea and guanidine derivatives it couples with aryldiazotates to yield arylazo substituted nitrodioyandiamidine, reacts with hydrazine hydrate to form N (1,1 bishydrazino) methyl N1 nitrourea, and decomposes when formaldehyde is added to its aqueous alkaline solution. Also at elevated temperatures it undergoes rearrangement reactions. The formation of the N (1,1 bishydrazino} methyl Nl nitrourea can be used for the identification of nitrodiayandiamidine. In one of a series of attempts to prove the structure of nitrodicyandiamidine by synthetic methods, the phenyl substituted nitrodioyandiamidine was prepared. [...]</description><creator>Hugill, John Templeton.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The production and study of compounds of sulfur and fluorine for use in chemical warfare : with special reference to disulfur decafluoride, and Physical properties of disulfur decafluoride.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wd3760906.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kr248</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g158bm556</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Of the gases occurring naturally in the earthfs atmosphere carbon dioxide and water vapour are the only ones which absorb infra red light. [...] Interest, therefore, attaches to a simpler infra red total absorption method of measuring carbon dioxide in small concentrations, developed in England by Dingle and Pryce [...] The purpose of the work presented in this thesis was thus twofold: first, to improve the method of Dingle and Pryce, and second, to illustrate as strikingly as possible its applications and place in the study of plant physiology. Due to the somewhat unusual nature of the problem, the standard form of presentation is precluded. It has seemed best to divide the thesis into two parts, the first dealing with the development and description of the apparatus as it is now in use, together with suggestions for its further improvement, and the second with its applications including such discussion of the literature as is pertinent to the physiological experiments performed. These experiments, varied in kind to illustrate the peculiar value of the apparatus in following rapid independent changes as well as the time courses of photosynthesis and transpiration over long periods of time under the various conditions employed, must be regarded as largely exploratory in nature, pointing the way to further, more refined experimentation. In themselves they are united by a common theme - the relation between photosynthesis, transpiration, stomatal opening and the water balance.</description><creator>Shaw, Michael.</creator><contributor>Gibbs, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Plant Pathology &amp; Botany.</subject><title>Applications of the infra red absorption technique of measuring gas exchange in plants, to the study of plants exposed to normal and harmful conditions.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524js05q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bm556</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Pathology and Botany</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k643b424z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Arthritis is usually one manifestation of a generalized disease of the body. Though there are a few forms of arthritis, like the traumatic and the infectious, that are localized in the joint, it is not primarily a joint disease. This interpretation of the arthritio syndrome was adopted by the American Committee for the Control of Rheumatism foimed in 1928 (302). The etiology of a few forms of arthritis is recognized, but the majority of the arthritides and the rheumatic disturbances are not fully understood. Relatively little inquiry has been made into the nature of the generalized processes involved in rheumatism until recently. [...]</description><creator>Hall, Octavia.</creator><contributor>Selye, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946. </date><subject>Arthritis.</subject><subject>Hormones.</subject><title>Hormonal production of arthritis.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dn39x453s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b424z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k0698b899</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The pre-eminent role of hypertension and cardiovascular-renal disease in human pathology has resulted in intensive research into the underlying etiology. In spite of this fact the progress of elucidation has not been commensurate with the vigor and diligence with which the investigations have been conducted. This is, perhaps, largely due to the involvement of so many apparently unrelated factors. Notwithstanding the uniformity of the symptomatology and pathology evoked by different clinical and experimental conditions various groups of investigators have, according to their predilections, implicated the nervous system, the kidneys, dietary influences, primary disease of the blood vessels of unknown etiology and a host of other agencies.[...]</description><creator>Hall, Charles Eric.</creator><contributor>Selye, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946. </date><subject>Cardiovascular system -- Abnormalities.</subject><subject>Hormones.</subject><title>The hormonal production of cardiovascular lesions.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gp21k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698b899</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:np193d079</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since 1939 the value of readily available whole blood, plasma and serum has received widespread and deserved recognition. For most purposes whole blood may be considered the ideal material for replacing lost blood, yet certain conditions, such as burns, in which hemoconcentration is to be combatted, call primarily for replacement of circulating fluid. In such cases plasma or serum may be the materials of choice. The chief advantage of plasma and serum, however, lies in their stability over long periods which makes possible the accumulation of large stores without wastage. The problem of maintaining such plasma or serum in the best possible condition for long periods of time thus assumes considerable importance.[...]</description><creator>Gurd, F.R.N.</creator><contributor>Denstedt, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946. </date><subject>Biochemistry. </subject><title>Changes in the lipoproteins of human blood serum during processing.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b658w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193d079</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr1721368</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This paper is a presentation of the more important aspects of power system stability. The power-angle curve is derived, and the criterion of equal areas used to show the effects on stability of faults, switching and sudden load increases. Those synchronous machine constants which are involved in stability studies are discussed, and an outline, illustrated by experimental results, given of methods of determining them. A short chapter is included on transmission line and transformer impedances. The paper shows how these various constants are used to determine whether a system will retain stability under certain conditions. The step-by-step procedure for calculating swing curves is described in detail, and an actual stability calculation is performed to illustrate it and to show the beneficial effect of clearing faults quickly. Finally, various factors are reviewed to show how power system stability can be improved.</description><creator>Slader, Geoffrey Henry Yorke.</creator><contributor>Christie, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Electrical Engineering.</subject><title>The Stability of high voltage power systems.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35tc47h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr1721368</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:765374182</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two specially synthesized cellulose nitrates are subjected to thermal decomposition, for the purpose of gaining information regarding the reaction mechanism. For these studies, an all-glass apparatus was constructed which recovered the reaction products quantitatively, and with which it was possible to work at fairly low pressures and at a variety of temperatures. This equipment was designed to accentuate the primary decomposition reaction. Analytical methods are adapted for estimating the composition of the reaction products, both volatile and non-volatile. The analytical data are tabulated, and certain generalizations are apparent on the basis of this data. In conclusion, an attempt is made to explain the results of this investigation on theoretical grounds.</description><creator>Grassie, Vernon Robert.</creator><contributor>Purves, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946. </date><subject>Chemistry. </subject><title>Possible mechanisms for the thermal decomposition of nitrocellulose.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182p299.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/765374182</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042x30p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An attempt...</description><creator>Glegg, Ronald Edward.</creator><contributor>Purves, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946. </date><subject>Chemistry. </subject><title>Studies on the accessible fraction of cellulose.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236546v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042x30p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603r1853</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The light sources chosen for special study were arc tubes through which a condenser was discharged. The discharge was initiated by an external control electrode. Tubes were made of Pyrex or quartz and had cathodes of mercury or nickel. Work was first done with mercury tubes at low pressures. Later, tubes were made having nickel cathodes and filled with argon. Tubes were tested to see at what voltage they discharged spontaneously one hence if they could be used with the 20,000 V power supply available. A 2500 V power supply was obtained for use with low voltage tubes. An integrating light output meter was constructed for measuring the light output of the tubes. Using this meter relative readings of the light output of tubes used under different conditions were obtained. Fine fibres were set up and illuminated in a manner reproducing conditions of cloud tracks in an expansion chamber. The fibres were then photographed to get an indication of whether the light sources would be practically useful, and of their effects on a photographic emulsion. Emperimental results indicate that low pressure arc tubes are not a practical means of obtaining high voltage operation, Mercury cathodes were shown to be little better than nickel ones in all types of tubes studied; and have the disadvantage of becoming dirty. In gas filled tubes having pressures of the order of a few centimeters of mercury, the light output is greatest when the bore of the tube is small.[...]</description><creator>Tate, Parr Allen.</creator><contributor>Terroux, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>A study of high intensity light sources for use in the photography of effects observable in an expansion chamber.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73q028n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r1853</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z709098k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:08:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>McLean's description of the syndrome in 1864, is possibly one of the first attempts to correlate active military life with Neurocirculatory Asthenia (117). He believed that the disease was limited to soldiers and that a definite pathological change in the heart occurred in this syndrome. The following excerpts from McLean18 article epitomizes his views on the subject. "And, f i r s t are diseases of the heart and great vessels more prevalent in the army than in civil life? I think so." McLean's description of a heart, typical of Neurocirculatory Asthenia is suggestive that his pathological exhibits were those of organic heart disease - possibly coronary artery disease.[...]</description><creator>Gertler, Menard Max.</creator><contributor>Hoff, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946. </date><subject>Asthenia.</subject><title>The physiological basis of neurocirculatory asthenia.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w2949.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z709098k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11725</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>