<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:25:00Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34000" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77ft18x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This paper examines the impact of the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights (TRIPS Agreement) on domestic control. The paper explains why intellectual property became part of the global trade agenda. The author considers arguments both for and against stronger global protection for intellectual property rights. Through analysis of the World Trade Organization (WTO) cases on the TRIPS Agreement, the author argues that the TRIPS Agreement has effectively removed from WTO Member states control over their intellectual property regimes. The author focuses on the negative impact that a rigid application of the TRIPS Agreement is likely to have on developing countries.</description><creator>Osei-Tutu, Julia J.</creator><contributor>de Mestral, Armand (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>Trips and domestic control : implications for developing countries</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c2307.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77ft18x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zc77sr74q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Determining whether or not a gold gravity circuit should be installed in a gold plant requires a prediction of how much gold will be recovered. This has always been a difficult task because recovery takes place from the grinding circulating load, in which gold's behavior must be described. A population-balance model (PBM) to predict gold gravity recovery was developed at McGill University in 1994 (Laplante et al, 1995). The objective of this research was to make this PBM user friendly. This was achieved in two different ways. First, the behavior of gravity recoverable gold (GRG) in secondary ball mills and hydrocyclones was described by two parameters, tau and R-25mum, and these parameters were linked to the circulating load of ore and the fineness of the grinding circuit product, for easy estimation. Second, the database of simulations produced by the PBM was represented by two multilinear regressions (one for coarse GRG, the other for fine GRG) linking the predicted GRG recovery to the natural logarithm of tau, R-25mum , the size distribution of the GRG and the recovery effort (Re ), defined as the proportion, in %, of the GRG in the circulating load recovered by gravity. Re was found to be the most significant parameter, tau the least. The GRG size distribution, represented either by two (coarse GRG) or three (fine GRG) points on the cumulative passing curve, has a significant impact on recovery. A total of twenty different GRG size distributions were used to generate the simulation database. The multilinear regressions were tested on four case studies, and found to predict GRG recovery well within the precision with which the GRG content can be measured, a relative 5%. Whenever size-by-size recovery data are available, the PBM itself would be used; if not, the simpler regressions would be preferred.</description><creator>Xiao, Zhixian, 1970-</creator><contributor>Laplante, A. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Mineralogy.</subject><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Developing simple regressions for predicting gold gravity recovery in grinding circuit</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v722p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77sr74q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514nn11s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Due to the continual development of the CMOS IC technology, there is a corresponding strong demand for faster and more accurate methods to compute the delay, which is a critical parameter in CAD tools for timing analysis. Several delay models have been developed for the basic CMOS inverter circuit. These models have also been used in some approaches to the analysis of delay in general CMOS gates. This involves the reduction of the gate to an equivalent inverter. Most gates consist of series and/or parallel combinations of MOSFET transistors. The greatest challenge in the reduction process is presented by the series-connected MOSFET structure (SCMS). In this thesis we examine existing techniques for reducing a SCMS and its input signals to an equivalent transistor with its equivalent input signal. In the process we propose some significant simplifications and improvements to these techniques. We examine, in particular, the SCMS reduction techniques presented in [5] and [6], both of which use a two-step process consisting of (i) mapping the input signals to a single equivalent one and, (ii) mapping the SCMS transistors to a single MOSFET. The authors of [6] claim that their model is superior to the simpler one used in [5]. Our analysis, based on a 0.35 micron technology, shows that the same accuracy claimed in [6] can be achieved by replacing their Step (ii) by a much simpler one based on the more empirical implementation used on [5]. We also show that the weighting coefficients used by [6] in Step (i) to compute the equivalent input signal, are functions of the input signal transition time, unlike the claim made in [6] that they are constant. We also conclude that, in the final analysis, the accuracy of our modified model as well as the one in [6] is limited by the empirical formula used to determine the equivalent input transition time.</description><creator>Wang, Yujun, 1968 March 4-</creator><contributor>Rumin, Nicholas (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Delay modeling of CMOS transistor chains</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fb06w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nn11s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65v961h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Carbonaceous mesophases are discotic nematic liquid crystals that are spun into high performance carbon fibers using the melt spinning process. The spinning process produces a wide range of fiber textures and cross-sectional shapes. The circular planar polar (PP), circular planar radial (PR), ribbon planar radial (RPR), and ribbon planar line (RPL) textures are the most frequently observed in industrial fiber making. This thesis presents, solves, and validates models of mesophase fiber texture formation based on the classical Landau-de Gennes theory of liquid crystals, adapted here to carbonaceous mesophases. The model captures the microstructure and the formation of the four (PP, PR, RPR, RPL) textures. In cylindrical fibers, the computed PP and PR textures phase diagram, given in terms of temperature and fiber radius, establishes the processing conditions and geometric factors that lead to the selection of these textures. The influence of elastic anisotropy to the textures' formation and structure is thoroughly characterized. The multi-stage formation process of the PP texture is reproduced, including defect nucleation, defect migration, and overall texture geometry. The mechanisms that control the PP texture geometry are characterized using analytical methods. The role of elasticity and flow-induced orientation on texture selection mechanism in ribbon-shaped mesophase fibers are characterized using an anisotropic viscoelastic model. The model is able to predict the formation of the commonly observed line defect in the RPL texture, and the fine structure of the line is reproduced and explained in terms of classical liquid crystal defect physics. The results of this thesis provide new knowledge on how to optimize and control mesophase fiber textures.</description><creator>Yan, Jun, 1974-</creator><contributor>Rey, A. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Theory and simulation of texture formation in mesophase carbon fibers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j729x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65v961h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hq37vq29v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis we use a novel refinement-based technique to formally verify data transfer in an asynchronous timing framework. Novel data transfer models are proposed to represent the implicit relationship between clock and data validity events. We construct comprehensive implementation models for a previously published GALS architecture for on-chip systems [MVK+99]. Applying our techniques on this claimed to be hazard-free architecture, we find several hazards, and other dangers, together with additional delay constraints to avoid some of the detected dangers. We further exam re-design issues of an existing GALS system as compact design, internal structure optimization and reduced power consumption. Exhaustive verifications are applied to re-designed asynchronous wrapper circuits using our proposed refinement-based technique to ensure hazard-free operation. We explore a strategy to resolve relative timing conflicts by implementing detected chain constraints as new circuit components to be integrated with the original design. This method is applied on two design cases to demonstrate its benefits and tradeoffs.</description><creator>Ying, Weidong Larry, 1968-</creator><contributor>Negulescu, Radu (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Verification and re-design of communication interfaces with heterogeneous timing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612q38x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vq29v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qf85nc88t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The degradation of plasticizers by the yeast Rhodotorula rubra J-96-1 (ATCC 9449) was studied in the presence of a water-soluble substrate (glucose). The plasticizers studied included bis 2-ethylhexyl adipate (B(EH)A), dioctyl phthalate (DOP) and terephthalate (DOTP), which are in widespread use. In addition, the degradation of two less common plasticizers, di-propylene glycol dibenzoate (D(PG)DB) and di-ethylene glycol dibenzoate (D(EG)DB), were studied. It has been proposed that the latter plasticizers be used as alternatives to the commonly used plasticizers, which have been associated with negative environmental impacts. The degradation of D(PG)DB or D(EG)DB led to a significant increase in solution toxicity. This increase in toxicity was associated with the production of metabolites resulting from the incomplete breakdown of the original plasticizers. The metabolites responsible for the acute toxicity in the D(PG)DB system were identified as isomers of di-propylene glycol monobenzoate. A mechanism for the formation of this metabolite was proposed. Although the metabolite observed when D(EG)DB was being degraded was not isolated, it was tentatively identified as di-ethylene glycol monobenzoate by analogy to the D(PG)DB system. This same metabolite was observed when D(EG)DB was degraded by the fungus, Aspergillus niger ATCC 9642-U. In contrast, there were no observable metabolites nor increases in toxicity in the media during the degradation of B(EH)A, DOP, or DOTP by R. rubra. These observations also differ from those of earlier work in which it was reported that the degradation of all three of these plasticizers by bacteria resulted in the production of toxic metabolites. Collectively, these results do not support the use of D(PG)DB and D(EG)DB as environmentally safe alternatives to B(EH)A, DOP or DOTP.</description><creator>Gartshore, James.</creator><contributor>Cooper, D. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Biodegradation of plasticizers by rhodotorula rubra</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jq51d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nc88t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wf53z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Log-domain filters have emerged in recent years as a new and important class of continuous-time filter. The attractive features of these filters include their compact structure, their potential to run at high frequencies while operating from low power supplies, and their electronic tunability. At the heart of the log-domain filtering technique is the logarithmic/exponential relationship between voltage and current in a transistor. In this work, the development of log-domain filters in CMOS technology will be investigated. The lateral bipolar transistor, inherent to CMOS processes, will be used for this purpose. A SPICE compatible model for a lateral PNP transistor, fabricated in 0.35mu CMOS technology, is presented. A log-domain integrator, which makes use of both lateral PNP transistors and MOSFET transistors operating in strong inversion, as well as a biquadratic low-pass log-domain filter and a third order elliptic low-pass log-domain filter, have each been designed and characterized in 0.35mu CMOS technology. Experimental results indicate that these filters are capable of operation at frequencies up to 10 MHz. For the elliptic filter operating at a bias current of 10 muA, the experimentally measured total harmonic distortion is -39.6 dB for an input current of 5 muA (a 50% current modulation index), the dynamic range is -34.1 dB, and the total power consumption is 183 muW/pole from a 2.5 V supply. These filters are capable of operating at significantly higher frequencies than CMOS log-domain filters described in the literature which make use of MOSFET transistors operating in weak inversion.</description><creator>Duerden, Geoffrey.</creator><contributor>Roberts, Gordon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>The development of bipolar log-domain filters in a standard CMOS process /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zj55g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wf53z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hq37vq30m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Space-time coding is an important research topic in wireless telecommunications systems. A novel framework for multi-dimensional multi-transmit antenna space-time coding systems is presented that includes Aggregate Transmit Antenna (ATA) systems and Orthogonal Transmit Antenna (OTA) systems. The former is a generalization of Tarokh, Seshadri, Calderbank's (TSC) approach where there is total sharing of dimensions among transmit antennas and the latter is a generalization of many traditional diversity schemes, where there is no sharing of dimensions between transmit antennas. This framework naturally accommodates cellular downlink OCDMA and models and derivations for this particular application and for cellular downlink slow fading Rician channels are presented. Analysis shows that the main effects of transmit-correlation and spatially-correlated multi-access-interference on space-time codes are a degradation in the coding gain and a raising of the SNR at which asymptotic coding and diversity gains are obtained. Simulation results for known and new 2 transmit (Tx) space-time codes and new 4Tx space-time codes support these analytical results for transmit correlation. In transmit correlated fading channels, there is the potential in ATA systems of obtaining beamforming-like gain. A new code, 4Tx POTARep, which combines repetition coding and space-time coding, simultaneously obtains diversity, coding and beamforming gain.</description><creator>Godbout, Michael.</creator><contributor>Leib, Harry (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>A framework for multi-dimensional space-time coded systems with applications to OCDMA Rayleigh block fading channels /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296x0804.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vq30m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30pv406</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis considers a combination of iterative decoding with space-time coding, known as space-time-turbo coding. Parallel and serial concatenated codes are considered for transmission using different bandwidth allocation schemes. The analysis of space-time-turbo codes is then performed in this thesis, resulting in the derivation of code design rules and of performance bounds. In particular, epsilon-capacity curves (based on the outage probability) are seen to provide a visually attractive method for the evaluation of the bandwidth-efficiency/performance tradeoff achieved by different codes. Computer simulations are then used to evaluate the performance of the proposed space-time-turbo codes over the spatially-uncorrelated block Rayleigh fading channel. It is then seen that certain space-time-turbo codes can outperform other recently proposed space-time codes. Finally, in light of simulation results, a low-complexity serial concatenated code is presented. This scheme, making use of a Wyner-Ash outer code and an inner recursive convolutional code achieving full-diversity, is shown to provide a good tradeoff between bandwidth-efficiency and error rate performance over the spatially-uncorrelated quasi-static Rayleigh fading channel.</description><creator>Goulet, Laurent.</creator><contributor>Leib, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Turbo decoding for transmit diversity communication systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gm657.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pv406</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dp13p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Sami people have struggled for centuries to maintain their culture in spite of pressures against it from colonialism. The formal education systems of Norway and Finland have acted in discord with Sami decision-making since their inception. In response to this lack of decision-making power, there is a dynamic internal process at work; Sami people have begun to take control of their own schooling. This thesis qualitatively examines the processes of curriculum development and implementation for wood handicraft programs at the Sami colleges in Guovdageaidnu, Norway and in Anar, Finland, and details the most significant educational and political factors involved in the transmission and production of indigenous knowledge associated with Sami handicraft. Factors associated with the teaching of Sami handicraft in the form of increasing commercialization, generalization and mechanization in formal duodji education and the stereotyping of Sami cultural imagery pose potential risks to appropriate transfer of Sami cultural knowledge. This thesis will show that the teaching of Sami handicraft (duodji) is an educational and political tool that helps develop and define modern Sami culture. Accordingly, attempts by the Sami colleges to incorporate greater indigenous knowledge have resulted in the implementation of modern indigenous curriculum that promotes cultural knowledge through the teaching of Sami handicraft.</description><creator>Stevenson, Charles Blair.</creator><contributor>Muller-Wille, Ludger (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Sami (European people) -- Education (Higher) -- Norway.</subject><subject>Folk art, Sami -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Finland.</subject><subject>Handicraft -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Norway.</subject><subject>Sami (European people) -- Education (Higher) -- Finland.</subject><subject>Handicraft -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Finland.</subject><subject>Folk art, Sami -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Norway.</subject><title>Modern indigenous curriculum : teaching indigenous knowledge of handicraft at Sami colleges in Finland and Norway = Oddaaigasaš eamialbmoga oahppoplanat : arbevealuš diedu oahpaheapmis duoddji oahpaheapmi Sami allaskuvlaiid</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483k98p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dp13p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290c283</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examined the effectiveness and acceptability of conjoint behavioral consultation (CBC) and videotape therapy (VT) in the remediation of behavior problems in children. Further, this investigation sought to examine changes in parental practices such as levels of involvement, limit setting, and autonomy granting, following participation in either CBC or VT. An A/B design was used and participants included six boys between the ages of three and nine, and their parents. Based on parental observations in the home, children in both conditions evidenced a reduction in their target behaviors from baseline to treatment (effect sizes = -0.10 to -3.27). Parental perceptions of treatment acceptability of both interventions were high at pretest ( M = 62.57, SD = 3.95) and at posttest (M = 63.37, SD = 5.09) for the entire sample. Overall, parents perceived themselves as involved in their children's lives, as well as able to set limits for them and promote their autonomy. The theoretical and practical implications of these findings, limitations of the study, and future research directions are discussed.</description><creator>Sinai, Daniela.</creator><contributor>Sladeczek, Ingrid (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Parenting.</subject><subject>Child psychotherapy -- Parent participation.</subject><subject>Behavior disorders in children -- Treatment.</subject><subject>Family psychotherapy.</subject><title>Parenting practices and treatment acceptability of conjoint behavioral consultation and videotape therapy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752j55c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290c283</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547t254</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is an examination of the concept and the term "superflat" as it is elaborated by the Japanese artist Murakami Takashi in his writings, in the exhibition he curated under the same name, and in his own art. Its aim is to contextualize Murakami's project on one hand in terms of a similar attempt to define a Japanese national aesthetic in the early 20 th century, and on the other in terms of the 1990's tendency to return to Edo Japan to find the "origins" of Japan's postmodernity. Murakami's own art is then turned to in order to both elaborate on and test the aesthetic of Japanese art he calls the superflat. This examination of Murakami's art permits the formulation of an aesthetics of Japanese contemporary art and animation even as it will afford an understanding of the "cultural logic" of the digital age that informs Murakami's argument. Questions important to this project are: Is the articulation of a local aesthetics possible in this globalizing age? What are the aesthetic traits of the digital age? How should the superflat---as both idea and project---be interpreted?</description><creator>Steinberg, Marc A.</creator><contributor>Lamarre, Thomas (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Art, Japanese.</subject><subject>Aesthetic movement (Art)</subject><subject>Murakami, Takashi.</subject><title>Emerging from flatness : Murakami Takashi and superflat aesthetics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fn55k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547t254</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of East Asian Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q585r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Social change strategies grounded in theory help change agents to be more effective in their efforts. This study attempts to make explicit the links between public education efforts and the social change goals of non-profit organizations through an examination of both radical humanist thought and various social change theories. This thesis maintains that public education is an essential component of lasting change, serving eleven identifiable roles in the social change process. Of particular note, education can serve to challenge the dominant corporate paradigm and to develop an informed, critical, and more active citizenry. Education can also help create an environment conducive to achieving systemic changes. It is argued that civil society organizations are well situated to play a leading role in the creation of a more just and healthy society. Public education is proposed here as an approach that shows considerable promise to move us in that direction.</description><creator>Stephens, Michael, 1964-</creator><contributor>McDonough, Kevin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Education -- Social aspects.</subject><subject>Social problems.</subject><subject>Educational socology.</subject><title>The interface between education and social change efforts in civil society agencies /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m8411.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q585r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s161803g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le medianoche amoureux is a collection of short narratives by Michel Tournier that was published in 1989. Being introduced as a collection of "Contes et nouvelles" and being compared with Boccacio's Decameron, Le medianoche amoureux has raised many questions. Some of its traits, however, were not explored: is the Medianoche amoureux a "recueil-ensemble"? If so, can it be classified as a "recueil a recit cadre", just like the Decameron? These are the questions this thesis tries to answer. After the characteristics of the different types of short narratives collections have been established, Le medianoche amoureux is confronted to it. In the same vein, it is compared to short narratives collections belonging to the Decameron 's tradition. This analysis' results do not allow to conclude that Le medianoche amoureux has enough resemblance with the Decameron and other collections of the same type to be included in this tradition. However, some traits that are unique to it, for example the progression from "nouvelles" to "contes" and the interactive structure, suggest that it should be seen as a "recueil a recit cadre" as well as being recognized as original in its construction. Le medianoche amoureux hence opens the way to a new generation of collections. This thesis' "creation" part is trying to construct that type of collection. Le second banquet can be seen as a progression from "nouvelle" to "conte" and it has an interactive structure. One must search the same kind of progression that is found in Le medianoche amoureux and see that the opening and closing texts establish an interactive structure, for the reader will have to reconstruct the context in which the narratives appear.</description><creator>Saint-Mleux, Julie.</creator><contributor>Boucher, Jean-Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Tournier, Michel. Médianoche amoureux.</subject><subject>Frame-stories.</subject><title>Fonction du récit cadre dans Le médianoche amoureux ; partie création, Le second banquet</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gm66h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161803g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429c01d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nicolas Poussin's two Self-Portraits, painted in 1649 and 1650, have been the subject of countless art-historical investigations, but remain only incompletely understood. This study attempts to draw the meanings of the self-images into clearer focus. To this end, the relationships between Poussin and the eventual recipients of the two portraits, Jean Pointel and Paul Freart, Sieur de Chantelou, are examined more probingly and are positioned centrally in the analysis of the works. A careful exploration of the web of associations among the three men reveals that Poussin's caution in dealing with Chantelou, his often jealous and emotional patron, was a factor of great consequence to the development of the Self-Portraits. Bearing this in mind, both Poussin's letters and the scholarly accounts which accept his written statements at face value, may be approached with a more critical eye. This practice, in turn, leads to a broadened range of possibilities for the interpretation of the two Self-Portraits, and to a greater appreciation of the extent to which Poussin's creations were affected by human dynamics.</description><creator>Prevost, Roberta.</creator><contributor>Glen, Thomas L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Self-portraits, French -- 17th century</subject><subject>Poussin, Nicolas, 1594?-1665 -- Friends and associates</subject><subject>Poussin, Nicolas, 1594?-1665 -- Self-portraits</subject><title>Nicolas Poussin's Self-portraits for Pointel and Chantelou</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cm74f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429c01d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nw393</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the 20th century, political communications have evolved at a tremendous pace. In its present version, as can be encountered everywhere in the Western world, this type of communication increasingly makes use of marketing-related techniques. These techniques, coupled with the naturally affective characteristics of modern media have influenced political campaigning into featuring more and more emotional messages. This tendency has decisively affected the quality of the information that political actors (politicians, parties, etc.) contribute to the public sphere, thus impeding on citizens' capacity to construct rational opinion on a variety of political matters. This thesis sets out to explore two examples from Quebec's history to show how this increasing use of emotional messages in political communications has found its way into the province's social environment.</description><creator>Pouilot, Simon-Pierre.</creator><contributor>Straw, William (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Québec (Province) -- Politics and government -- 1994-</subject><subject>Political psychology.</subject><subject>Communication in politics.</subject><subject>Communication -- Political aspects.</subject><title>Politics and emotions : making sense of the emotional component in political communications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zg30g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nw393</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dt86h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this thesis comes from a desire to ponder on the role played by Benito Perez Galdos' novels. As a prolific Spanish journalist, novelist and "historian," his work offers a deep insight into the second half of the nineteenth-century society for it depicts historical situations of that particular moment. Through the evolution of the author's artistic representation, we will assess the values he seeks to impart. Moreover, in conjunction with this artistic evolution, there is our perception of the various political changes and turmoils, that is, we shall try to understand these historial events, not so much in a rational manner, but rather according to the author's philosophical perception.</description><creator>Remillard-Belanger, Judith</creator><contributor>Perez-Magallon, Jesus (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Pérez Galdós, Benito, 1843-1920 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>Galdós, o la novela como lectura de la historia</title><language>spa</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719n981.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dt86h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Hispanic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rg277</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The ideology of jihad as propounded by the Islamic Resistance Movement of Palestine (H&amp;dotbelow;amas) is the subject of this thesis. It examines what this organization specifically means by jihad. To properly ascertain this meaning, the ideology of jihad from two different time periods has been examined. In the first period, the "classical" age, the ideology of several jurists concerning jihad is introduced. It can be seen that during this period jihad was applicable to both the expansion and protection of Islamic social/political hegemony. In the second, or modern period, the interpretations of jihad by four thinkers commonly known as "Islamic revivalists" are presented. The definitions of jihad in this era were mostly responses of defending and liberating land from colonialism and imperialism; however, in some cases it was also understood as a means to implement the shari'a in Muslim societies. The jihad of H&amp;dotbelow;amas can, for its part, be seen as an amalgam of these ideologies, in that it is largely connected to liberating the land of Palestine from Israeli rule, establishing an Islamic state, and continuing to assist in struggles in other areas beyond the borders of Palestine.</description><creator>Bordenkircher, Eric.</creator><contributor>Hallaq, Wael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Arab-Israeli conflict.</subject><subject>Ḥarakat al-Muqāwamah al-Islāmīyah.</subject><subject>Islamic fundamentalism -- Gaza Strip.</subject><subject>Islamic fundamentalism -- West Bank.</subject><subject>Jihad.</subject><title>An analysis of Jihad in the context of the Islamic resistance movement of Palestine /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s1618069.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rg277</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d504rn09h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main scope of this study consists in analyzing how the poetic and ideologic universe of Dante is implanted and transformed in the Russian culture of the late XIXth---early XXth century. Particular emphasis is made on the role of Dante's heritage in the philosophy and poetry of the first Russian philosopher and symbolist poet---Vladimir Soloviov, as well as on the further impact of dantesche images on some major representatives of the Russian Symbolist movement. This analysis will be done through a demonstration of major point of interference between Soloviov and Dante: these can be examples of direct influence (as is the case with Theocracy) of appearance of the same archetypes (as is the case with Sofiology and theory of love). Despite the clear and definite presence of dantesque motifs in Soloviov's heritage, no systematic analysis of the parallels between the two has been made up to date.</description><creator>Bogoiavlenskaia, Anna.</creator><contributor>Predelli, Maria (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Dante Alighieri, 1265-1321 -- Influence</subject><subject>Solovyov, Vladimir Sergeyevich, 1853-1900 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>Symbolism (Literary movement) -- Russia.</subject><subject>Dante Alighieri, 1265-1321 -- Appreciation -- Russia</subject><title>Suggestioni dantesche nel sistema poetico, teologico e politico di Vladimir Soloviov</title><language>ita</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cg08v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rn09h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Italian</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289k811</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The works of Lewis Carroll show an abiding interest on the part of the author in the relationship between education, language and authority. In particular, the Alices are the story of a young girl who must learn to deal with a variety of characters in dream-worlds where the power of language reigns. It is therefore necessary for Alice to learn how language is used for authoritarian purposes and to discover ways of defending herself against it. It is the purpose of this thesis to investigate, in many cases for the first time, the ways in which Alice is able to find "spaces" in language where authority breaks down, places where the fundamental nature of language is unable to support authoritarian use. In this way, "space" will become both a metaphor and a figurative model for Alice's growing knowledge of and resistance to authority.</description><creator>Bourgeois, David C. C.</creator><contributor>Conway, C. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Carroll, Lewis, 1832-1898. Through the looking-glass.</subject><subject>Space and time in literature.</subject><subject>Language and languages in literature.</subject><subject>Carroll, Lewis, 1832-1898. Alice's adventures in Wonderland.</subject><title>Making space : the subversion of authoritarian language in Lewis Carroll's Alice books</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sx65z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289k811</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977w809</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There are two parts to this thesis; one is a critical study, the other comprises two literary texts. In the first part, I speak of the links between fiction and autobiography. Having defined these two terms, I then look at the ways they are present in several works by Janine Boissard, a French writer. I try to understand the techniques that are needed to write fiction and autobiography. The second part of the thesis contains an autobiographical story and a short story that uses some autobiographical elements. It shows how an event is modified by memory, in the case of the autobiographical text, and by imagination, in the case of the short story. Finally, in a brief essay, I discuss the difficulties I encountered in writing each of these texts.</description><creator>Bertrand, Juliane.</creator><contributor>Everett, Jane (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Boucher, Jean-Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Boissard, Janine.</subject><subject>Autobiography in literature.</subject><title>Fiction et autobiographie chez J. Boissard ; une histoire, deux récits</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440v41m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977w809</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290c29c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Awareness of movement onset was studied in a series of three experiments. It was defined as the ability to detect computer-generated delays between the movement onset of the subject's hand and a visually displayed hand. This was accomplished by employing a Cyber Glove that rendered a computer-generated image of a hand on a computer screen. In the pilot study, an estimate of the average detection threshold of movement onset delays was obtained in 17 normal control subjects (9 females, 8 males). Peripheral view of the hands was blocked. No significant differences in detection thresholds between men and women, between left and right hands, and across types of movement (all-fingers, index-finger, index-middle-finger extension) were found. In the second study, data on detection thresholds in the absence of proprioceptive input was gathered from a patient diagnosed with sensory neuropathy of the left hand. No significant differences in detection thresholds between the affected and unaffected hand were recorded. Proprioception does not appear to be critical for awareness of movement onset delays. In the third study, 33 normal control subjects (31 females and 2 males) performed four experimental movement conditions, two passive and two active. During the passive conditions, a lever device moved the subject's finger while their hand was either visible (PF) or hidden (PH) from view. In the active condition the subject moved their own finger while their hand was either visible (AF) or hidden (AH) from view. Detection thresholds were significantly lower during the active than the passive conditions (p &lt; 0.01). No significant main effect of view was present. It appears that internal feedback loops, as opposed to visual feedback loops, may play a critical role in awareness of movement onset. Taken together, data from all three studies suggest that the efferent copy plays an important role compared to visual or proprioceptive cues in the detection of movement onset delays.</description><creator>Velikonja, Katherine.</creator><contributor>Paus, Tomas (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Psychology, Physiological.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Awareness of self-initiated movement</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903171v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290c29c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977w81k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this research was to examine the effects of sitosterol and sitostanol supplementation on plasma cholesterol levels and cholesterol metabolism in hypercholesterolemic subjects consuming a fixed foods diet in a four-phase crossover design. It was hypothesized that addition of either phytosterols, phytostenols, or a 50:50 mixture of sterols and stanols to butter would reduce circulating cholesterol levels, despite butter's hypercholesterolemic effect, through actions involving cholesterol absorption, synthesis, and turnover rates. The data obtained indicate that in their free, unesterified form, plant sterols and stanols lower plasma LDL cholesterol equivalently in hypercholesterolemic subjects. Results of this study provide new data that phytosterols and stanols function by suppressing cholesterol absorption while increasing cholesterol synthesis, however, the de-suppression in synthesis cannot fully compensate for the decrease in absorption making the treatment effective, thus may assist in the development of a food which offers health-promoting advantages related to the prevention of cardiovascular disease.</description><creator>Vanstone, Catherine A.</creator><contributor>Jones, Peter J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Hypercholesteremia -- Treatment.</subject><subject>Sterols -- Physiological effect.</subject><subject>Phytosterols.</subject><subject>Blood lipids.</subject><subject>Cholesterol -- Metabolism.</subject><title>Influence of phytosterols versus phytostanols on plasma lipid levels and cholesterol metabolism in hypercholesterolemic humans</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n2040921.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977w81k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj139379r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Several classes of genes determine the lifespan of the nematode Caenorhabditis elegans. Our laboratory is particularly interested in the clk class of genes that is composed of clk-1, clk-2, clk-3 , and gro-1. Mutations in these genes have been shown to extend lifespan and to deregulate several developmental and behavioural processes such as pharyngeal pumping and defecation cycle length. clk-1 encodes a 187 amino acid mitochondrial protein that is composed of two homologous TRC domains (TRC for T̲andemly R̲epeated in C̲LK-1). Interestingly, the yeast homologue of clk-1, COQ7, has been implicated in ubiquinone biosynthesis. clk-1 (e2519) lesion is a point mutation that changes a conserved amino acid (E148K) in the second TRC domain. A structural model proposed that clk-1 is a di-iron carboxylate protein. We found that mutations in the di-iron binding center abolish CLK-1 activity and modify the subcellular distribution of CLK-1 in clk-1( qm30) null mutants.</description><creator>Ubach, Antonio.</creator><contributor>Hekimi, Siegfried (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Caenorhabditis elegans -- Genetics.</subject><title>Mitochondrial import and localization of CLK-1 in Caenorhabditis elegans</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b286j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139379r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dj52w6575</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:42:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>State explosion problem is an essential impediment in practical applications of formal languages such as SDL, Specification and Description Language. In the context of validation and testing, one of the possible solutions is to abstract a constructed formal specification by removing certain, unimportant from some viewpoint, variables. The resulting system could be more tractable by existing validation and testing tools. In this thesis, we first elaborate methods for abstracting variables in the Extended FSM model and then methods to treat SDL specifications that are based on the EFSM model. The methods are implemented in a tool that is successfully tested on a real life SDL specification.</description><creator>Wang, Xiaoyu, 1968-</creator><contributor>Ratzer, Gerald (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Variables abstraction in SDL</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128c66n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w6575</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34025</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>