<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:55:02Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):1050" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p0969218</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:14:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Contained within the parameters of postmodern thought, particularly feminist critical perspectives on western epistemology, this thesis proceeds from the following arguments: that knowledge is political: that it possesses a reflexive and dialectical nature and that it is based upon interpretations of reality which are in potential, indeterminate in range. Within these boundaries, knowledge is viewed as a phenomenon subject to influence from social power structures. And western culture is observed to breed situations of epistemological inequality where knowers may become unjustly privileged or oppressed. Focusing on arguments expounded by Lorraine Code, Patti Lather and Catherine Walsh, this thesis aims to explore how western culture may be observed to impose on consciousness and thereby lead to restriction of interpretive outcomes. Following this line of reasoning, the goal of this thesis is to consider how applications in deconstructionism may be used to emancipate the position of the oppressed knower.</description><creator>Tucker, Jasmin</creator><contributor>Nemiroff, Stanley (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Education -- Philosophy</subject><subject>Cultural relativism</subject><subject>Knowledge, Sociology of</subject><title>Accommodating multiple perspectives on reality within western academic settings : some postmodern considerations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sx92v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p0969218</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207tr376</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:14:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The writings of Edmond Jabes pose a formidable task to their reader. Their irrecoverable strangeness, which makes their categorization difficult, is at once frightening and seductive. This is particularly true of those works associated with what one might describe as the author's "second manner", inaugurated by Le Livre des Questions. This thesis attempts to re-read the works of Jabes (in particular Le Livre des Ressemblances) from the standpoint of the fragment, presupposing that this form is not simply an effect secondary to a particular literary conception, but that it becomes the essence of Jabes' poetics, its very organizing principle. The works of Jabes then appear in a new light, as an everchanging locus of thoroughfares, telling of the impossibility of the Book, of the author, and of literature itself.</description><creator>Trudel, Eric</creator><contributor>Rivard, Yvon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Jabès, Edmond. Livre des ressemblances</subject><subject>Jabès, Edmond -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>Edmond Jabès et l'écriture du fragment</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v753p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tr376</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085n393</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:14:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines representations of nation, race and gender in three postcolonial texts: Salman Rushdie's Midnight's Children; Meena Alexander's autobiographical memoirs Fault Lines; and Bengali writer Mahasweta Devi's collection of short stories entitled Imaginary Maps. All three texts reconfigure conventional accounts of nationhood by positing fictions based on what I am calling the poetics of displacement. The diasporic perspective provides Salman Rushdie's novel with the ability to suggest hybrid identities arising from the experience of cultural migration. In Meena Alexander's autobiography, displacement is figured in terms of both a diasporic and feminist vision that allows for the deconstruction of masculinist narratives of identity and nation. Mahasweta Devi's short stories, by contrast, represent displacement in terms of the violences and dislocations suffered by the Indian subaltern as a result of ecological degradation and cultural uprootment. In looking at these differential articulations of displacement, this thesis thus attempts to illustrate that what is often seen as an unified body of postcolonial literature emerges from a heterogeneous set of textual practices which are the products of varying social, cultural, political and economic contexts. In this way, this thesis rethinks the categories of nation, race and gender in order to consider the bases upon which people make claims to identity along with the boundaries of inclusion or exclusion often invoked by such claims.</description><creator>Tagore, Proma</creator><contributor>Cope, Karin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Identity (Philosophical concept) in literature.</subject><subject>Gender identity in literature</subject><subject>Race in literature</subject><title>The poetics of displacement : rethinking nation, race and gender</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qr607.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085n393</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603r0466</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:02:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Samuel Johnson's Dictionary has long been regarded as an epoch-making book, as great a scholarly achievement as the dictionaries of the Italian, French and Spanish academies, yet more enlightened in its pretensions and its politics. For Johnson does not claim to have fixed the language; his authority is not backed by the state; his decisions as to currency, propriety, meaning, and spelling are based on a jumble of general custom, literary precedent, and reason. I argue that the intellectual origins of Johnsonian standard English lie in Sir Edward Coke's early seventeenth-century restatement of common law doctrine and terms. Salient issues are common law's need to give an account of its antiquated, medieval vocabulary and its place in the constitutional conflict of the seventeenth century. I give an account of other possible influences on Johnson--Latin and English grammars, pedagogy, philosophical speculation on the nature of language, English prose styles, and proposals for an English academy or similar reform--but cannot find in any of them a sufficiently close conceptual parallel.</description><creator>Stone, John, 1967-</creator><contributor>Hensley, David C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>English language -- Lexicography</subject><subject>Johnson, Samuel, 1709-1784. Dictionary of the English language</subject><title>The common-law model for standard English in Johnson's dictionary</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cc90g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r0466</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p096922j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:02:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the context of the contemporary rebirth of interest in contemplative prayer in the Christian tradition, many people, e.g., Laurence Freeman (1995), Eileen O'Hea (1990), Bede Griffiths (1991), have begun to examine the writings of John Main. This thesis presents John Main's understanding of Christian Meditation, in particular, his recovery from the Desert monks of the 4th century, of the practice of 'pure prayer' (silent meditation using a prayer word or mantra). Main recovered the use of a mantra as a way of meditation within the tradition of the Christian church. The thesis also discusses some aspects of the Christian life and themes which are relevant to his teaching and finally, articulates some implications for contemporary religious/spirituality education. Comparisons are made between Main's pedagogical approach and that of several other contemporary Christian educators.</description><creator>Romandini, Doreen Jane</creator><contributor>Lawlor, William (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Christian life</subject><subject>Monks -- Religious life</subject><subject>Main, John, O.S.B.</subject><subject>Meditation -- Christianity</subject><title>John Main as religious educator</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708z93t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p096922j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wj086</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:02:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis discusses the impact of the snowmobile on the Inuit society in northern Canada and more specifically in Kangiqsualujjuaq (Nunavik). By drawing the portrait of traditional and modern habits of mobility, it is possible to understand the influence of the snowmobile--considered as micro-technology--on the fundamental structures of the Inuit society. More generally, the research illustrates the evolution of the means of transportion starting from the pre-contact period to the 1990's. Westernization of the Inuit society is not the consequence of only one item but the combination of many. Even if it is difficult to evaluate the influence of a particular technology on a cultural system, snowmobile has had an important impact on the social, cultural and economic values of the Inuit society. The results of the introduction of this vehicle are not only the consolidation of the westernization way of living, because the snowmobile also gives to the Inuit society, the technology needed to practice traditional activities in a contemporary context.</description><creator>St-Onge, Paul</creator><contributor>Muller-Wille, Ludger (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Inuit -- Québec (Province) -- Kangiqsualujjuaq</subject><subject>Transportation -- Québec (Province) -- Kangiqsualujjuaq -- History</subject><subject>Transportation -- Arctic regions -- History</subject><subject>Snowmobiles -- Québec (Province) -- Kangiqsualujjuaq</subject><title>Transport et mobilité des résidants du village de Kangiqsualujjuaq (Nunavik) : le cas de la motoneige</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mk94s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wj086</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930c029c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:02:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to explore perceived physical competence and participation in physical activity of children with physical awkwardness. Children with physical awkwardness are those without known neuromuscular problems but who have difficulty in learning and performing motor skills. Participants were 135 children, 31 with physical awkwardness and 104 without any motor deficiency. The age ranged from 5 to 11 years. It was hypothesized that children with physical awkwardness would have lower levels of perceived physical competence and would participate less in physical activity than their nonawkward peers. Finally, a positive relationship between motor performance and perceived physical competence was expected. There were no significant differences found in perceived physical competence between the two groups. However, nonawkward children participated significantly more in community sports and were significantly more active during free play than children with physical awkwardness. The results also indicated that the relationship between motor performance and perceived physical competence was very low in both groups. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Sopiadou, Anna</creator><contributor>Reid, Greg (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Clumsiness in children</subject><subject>Motor ability in children -- Psychological aspects</subject><subject>Exercise</subject><title>Perceived physical competence and participation in physical activity of children with developmental coordination disorder</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xd75c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930c029c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gg05s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:02:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The selective success of women in traditionally male dominated fields is identified as a paradox whose explanation will have implications for the issue of the under representation of women in science and engineering programs. Trends in degree attainment by sex science and engineering are examined in the context of degree attainment in all traditionally male dominated degree programs in order to generate empirically based hypotheses. Because research designs in use for quantitative data in sociology are much better designed to test hypotheses than to generate new ones, an important aspect of this study is its development of a new analytical strategy. In order to effectively explore the available data, the existing statistics for degree attainment in traditionally male dominated fields for both sexes over the 1962-1989 period are converted to graphical display and analysed visually. The organization of the graphical displays developed is consistent with basic aspects of the comparative, exploratory research strategy advocated by Glaser and Strauss and graphical display techniques of Tufte. Findings show that the largest gains in representation in traditionally male dominated disciplines have been in those where the associated professions or occupations are typically autonomous self-employed professions rather than positions in large organizations. These findings further suggest processes that may be contributing the continued under representation of women in the physical sciences and engineering.</description><creator>Salonius, Annalisa</creator><contributor>Krohn, Roger (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Degrees, Academic -- Canada -- Statistics</subject><subject>Women in science</subject><subject>Women in engineering</subject><subject>Sociology -- Methodology</subject><title>Contextualizing the under representation of women in science and engineering : a graphical analysis of trends in Canadian degree attainment statistics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182n27j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gg05s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97ks467</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:02:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents a case study conducted in 1994 concerning the effects of fishery management regulations on the Native village of Old Harbor, Alaska. Access to the traditional livelihood of harvesting marine resources has profound implications for the sustainability of the economy of Alaska's rural Native villages. The institution of the limited entry system in 1975 caused the transfer of commercial salmon fishing rights away from some Native fishermen and a reduction in local fishing jobs. Although the alternatives may have had similar or worse effects on the village, limited entry is perceived as a major cause of economic and social dysfunction. One of many factors that has integrated remote villages into the global market economy, it has exacerbated the uneven distribution of wealth in the community and contributed to a growing gulf between fishing as a business and a lifestyle.</description><creator>Robinson, Deborah Butterworth</creator><contributor>Muller-Wille, Ludger (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Salmon fisheries -- Alaska -- Old Harbor</subject><subject>Fishers -- Alaska -- Old Harbour -- Social conditions -- Case studies</subject><title>Changing relationships to marine resources : the commercial salmon fishery in Old Harbor, Alaska</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w4405.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97ks467</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d206s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:02:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis proposes that Yeats found in certain conventions of the Noh drama a realization and defense of his idea of unity of culture, which his Noh-like Four Plays for Dancers illustrates. Yeats' use of recurrent imagery in the dance plays expresses his belief in a unity of culture defined and evoked by an image and stems in part from the pattern of images he discovered in the Pound-Fenollosa translations of the Noh. The imagery of the poetic text reappears in symbolic visual designs or is coordinated with music and dance in the production of the plays. The importance of the spoken word above all determined the basis of the association of arts with which Yeats characterized unity of culture and shaped his adaptation and occasional misconception of the staging techniques of the Noh. A common love of vivid, allusive words joined the audience for whom the dance plays were written. When Yeats stated that they were modelled on the audience of the Noh, his perception was colored, as usual, by his own priorities and experience.</description><creator>Peter, Denise</creator><contributor>Ronsley, Joseph (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Yeats, W. B. (William Butler), 1865-1939. Four plays for dancers</subject><title>W.B. Yeats' Four Plays for Dancers : the search for unity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t406n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d206s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z903195f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:02:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines and assesses the Gleichschaltung of the Germandom organizations from 1933 to 1939. The first chapter outlines the Peace Treaties of Versailles, Trianon and St. Germain and their effect upon the increased German minority in Europe. This body of Germans in countries outside Germany, Austria and Switzerland are referred to as the Volksdeutsche. The policies of the Weimar Government towards the German minorities in Europe are then examined. The second chapter outlines the minority policy of the National Socialist Party and various prominent National Socialist leaders. Chapter three outlines the major non-National Socialist and National Socialist Germandom organizations. Particular emphasis is given to the Verein fur Deutschtum im Ausland or the VDA, the Volksdeutscher Rat or the VR, Auslandsorganisation der NSDAP or AO, the Buro Kursell and the Volksdeutsche Mittelstelle or VoMi. Chapters four through six deal with the events that lead to the Gleichschaltung of the Germandom organizations. Although the non-National Socialist Germandom organizations maintained a degree of independence from Nazi influence from 1933 until 2 July 1938, there was never any doubt that eventually the National Socialist Germandom organizations would gain ascendancy over them. In late 1936, the National Socialist Germandom organizations began to achieve lasting power and influence. By 1938, the non-National Socialist Germandom organizations were virtually impotent. The Gleichschaltung of the Germandom organizations, therefore, mirrors the Gleichschaltung that occurred on all levels of society in Germany following Adolf Hitler's appointment as Chancellor on 30 January 1933.</description><creator>Osborne, Thomas W. (Thomas William)</creator><contributor>Hoffmann, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Germany -- History -- 1933-1945</subject><subject>Germans -- Foreign countries -- Societies, etc.</subject><title>The Gleichschaltung of the Germandom organizations : 1933-1939</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m8828.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903195f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9880vs97v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:02:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis will critically examine the project on globalization as articulated by the Association of Theological Schools in the United States and Canada (ATS) in an effort to uncover the presuppositions and motivations that underlie the project, and to situate them historically and with reference to current North American trends in education and politics. It will argue that the project, as it has been described and defined, comes out of the ethos of Protestant liberalism, particularly as this is embodied in missiology and the 19th century Social Gospel Movement, and that this liberal foundation has been influenced since the 1960's in North America by the Civil Rights Movement, the Women's Movement and the more recent concern related to minorities and North American pluralism. Although lip service is paid to evangelism, ecumenism and interreligious dialogue, the globalization agenda is expressed in terms of social ethics, predominantly justice or liberation theology.</description><creator>O'Rourke, James Colin Daly</creator><contributor>Young, Katherine K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Theology -- Study and teaching -- United States</subject><subject>Theology -- Study and teaching -- Canada</subject><subject>Missions -- Theory -- History of doctrines -- 20th century</subject><subject>Association of Theological Schools in the United States and Canada</subject><title>Globalization or liberation theology? : an examination of the presuppositions and motives underlying the efforts toward globalization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s449w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vs97v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jd472z43p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:02:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In recent years, with the development of DNA tests and genetic knowledge, there has been a growth of genetic counseling services and research in Canada and Japan. Although the uniqueness of genetic services in medicine lies in the preliminary assessment of the entire family rather than a single patient, few attempts have been made by social scientists to examine the technical and social construction of family trees and medical pedigrees. The purpose of this thesis is to analyze how the family data taken by genetic counselors are transcribed as medical pedigrees and used by associated health care workers in different cultural settings. The comparative analysis was based on an ethnographic approach that included participant-observation in genetic counseling sessions, interviews with clinical workers, and content-analysis of medical textbooks. The findings include three major points: (1) cultural views of the family are taken for granted by genetic counselors; (2) the process of documenting family data consists of four stages: primary transcription, secondary transcriptions, combination and publications; (3) the clinical workers' use of medical pedigrees results in the construction of family history as part of the present family illness.</description><creator>Nukaga, Yoshio</creator><contributor>Cambrosio, Alberto (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Genetic counseling -- Cross-cultural studies.</subject><subject>Medical history taking -- Cross-cultural studies.</subject><title>The visual transcription of "family disease" : a comparison of the use of medical pedigrees in genetic counseling practices in Canada and Japan</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79408019c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd472z43p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn1071033</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:02:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, we investigate several processes affecting coronals and velars in Tamil and Malayalam, two Dravidian languages spoken in southern India. We begin by discussing two assimilation processes which apply adjacent to front vowels, Palatalization, where anterior coronals become palatoalveolar, and Coronalization, where velars are fronted to palatoalveolar. We compare and contrast the feature geometries proposed by Sagey (1986) and Hume (1992) in their ability to adequately express these processes. In Sagey's model, front vowels are argued to be Dorsal. It is thus impossible to express either Palatalization or Coronalization as spreading. In Hume's model, where front vowels are Coronal, both processes involve spreading. However, the model does not formally distinguish between these two processes across languages; thus, it fails to capture the fact that Palatalization is widely attested but Coronalization seems to be restricted to diachronic alternations. In order to express this asymmetry, we adopt the model advanced by Goad &amp; Narasimhan (1994), a revision of Goad (1993), where Palatalization involves spreading but Coronalization is a two-step process, spreading followed by reanalysis. In this model, a single feature (front), defined as "front of articulator", is doubly dependent on both Dorsal and Coronal nodes. Its interpretation is thus partly determined by the node to which it links; it marks apicality in coronals and front of tongue body in dorsals. In Chapter 3, we demonstrate how this model allows us to capture the fact that in Malayalam, only a subset of the anterior coronal consonants, the apicals, form a natural class with front vowels. In Chapter 4, we provide support for the model from languages other than Tamil and Malayalam, both Dravidian and non-Dravidian.</description><creator>Narasimhan Kidambi, Rama</creator><contributor>Goad, Heather (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Tamil language -- Phonology.</subject><subject>Assimilation (Phonetics)</subject><subject>Coronals (Phonetics)</subject><subject>Malayalam language -- Phonology.</subject><subject>Velars (Phonetics)</subject><title>Coronals, velars and front vowels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nt06n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn1071033</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bk128c953</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:02:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis is a short novel, Adam's Navel, followed by a critical afterword. The narrator, Sam Meir, a first year medical student at McGill University, recounts the events of the unsuccessful road trip from Montreal to Seattle that he made in the summer before his last year of undergraduate study. Sam attempts the trip with his girlfriend, but his increasing obsession with historical, and mythical figures disrupts their relationship and their travel plans. As the two travel deeper into the middle of America, Sam realizes he cannot leave his family or his past behind him. Thematically, Adam's Navel is a contemplation of the meaning of family, tradition, and the intense sense of gravity that results from an historical awareness. The critical afterword explores the function of repetition in the transcendental narrative strategies of certain quasi-mythological heroes of the American canon, Huckleberry Finn and Nick Carraway. As is required, Sam's narration is included in the discussion.</description><creator>Mitnick, Howard</creator><contributor>Reichertz, Ron (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Literature, Canadian (English).</subject><title>Adam's navel</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w441f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128c953</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26z0454</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:02:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is an exposition on the British traveller Mary Edith Durham and her various activities in the Balkans from 1900 to 1914. Durham earned a reputation as an ethnographer, traveller, reporter, political activist and relief worker. First, the thesis documents her experiences between 1900-1908 as a traveller in the Balkans. In this period Durham developed a keen interest for the history and cultures of the peoples of the Balkans. She also gained a solid knowledge of Balkan politics and became a familiar face in Montenegro and the Albanian territories of the Ottoman Empire. The study then describes her relief work in Albania and her efforts to lobby for the Albanian cause from 1910 to 1914, when she returned to England. The research consists of both published works and unpublished sources, some of which have not been used for studying Durham. These include Durham's personal manuscripts, correspondence from other personal papers, and documents from the British Foreign Office archives. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Medawar, Christian</creator><contributor>Longworth, Phillip (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Durham, M. E. (Mary Edith), 1863-1944 -- Journeys -- Balkan Peninsula</subject><subject>Balkan Peninsula -- Description and travel</subject><title>Mary Edith Durham and the Balkans, 1900-1914</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053j17j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z0454</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752j87n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:02:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>William of Ockham's (1285-1349) influence on medieval philosophy has been generally acknowledged. Little, however, has been written on the possibility that his work had an effect on the arts. His radical reversal of traditional epistemology and ontology raised new questions which had great implications for poetry. This study seeks to establish the extent of his influence on one poet, Geoffrey Chaucer (c. 1345-1400), by examining Chaucer's engagement with Jean de Meun (c. 1232-1305) on the theme of language and morality.</description><creator>McKergow, Ian</creator><contributor>Conway, C. Abbott (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>William, of Ockham, ca. 1285-ca. 1349 -- Influence</subject><subject>Chaucer, Geoffrey, d. 1400 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>Jean, de Meun, d. 1305? -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Language and morality after Ockham : a study of Chaucer's engagement with themes in Jean de Meun</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128c96c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752j87n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gm98s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:02:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This paper considers two major issues in the evolution of the European Union, the Single Market and the Single Currency. The first chapter deals with the projected effects of the 1992 Programme, and the second chapter deals with the collapse of the Exchange Rate Mechanism of the European Monetary System and examines the prospects for European Monetary Union given this collapse. The third chapter revolves around the concept of Central Banking under Monetary Union and focuses on the European Monetary Institute and the European System of Central Banks. Chapter four presents data regarding the progress of the European Union towards the target of the Single Currency, as well as other macroeconomic indicators.</description><creator>Mavrikiou, Petros Andreas</creator><contributor>Frankman, Myron (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>European Union</subject><subject>Monetary unions -- European Union countries.</subject><title>Aspects of European economic integration : the single market and the single currency</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m3911.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gm98s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rk189</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Considering the specific experiences of Chile and Argentina, this study undertakes the analysis of economic liberalization policies from a "credibility constraint" perspective. Building on the assumption that, in a context interdependence, one of the essential conditions for economic development is the attraction of foreign capital, it suggests that confidence-seeking is a major concern constraining the rest of the government's activities. From these premises, the thesis addresses the socio-political consequences of this quest for credibility and provides an analysis of these criteria's compatibility with democratic and authoritarian rule. In this endeavor, the project relies on a comparative observation of four case studies to establish that notwithstanding regime type, the success of economic liberalization depends primarily on the satisfaction of the socio-political requirements for credibility. The results are clear: both types of regimes are in a position to fulfill these requirements although this may have considerable consequences on the economic well-being of substantial sections of the population.</description><creator>Margherita, Michelangelo</creator><contributor>Oxhorn, Philip (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Argentina -- Economic policy</subject><subject>Chile -- Economic policy</subject><title>Southern cone economic liberalization policies and the credibility constraint</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mr96v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rk189</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30pv72g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The object of this thesis is to present a comprehensive analysis of the phrase structure and the properties of the subject in spoken French and Japanese. Consulting histories, grammars, and a corpus of transcribed speech from each language, a comparative examination of the oral codes of both languages is conducted, which highlights not only the significant distinctions between the two but also the similarities. These distinctions are not just the result of structural differences between the two languages, but are more that of a distinct classification of our experiences. By pointing out the distinguishing characteristics of the oral codes of the two languages, this study attempts to bring us to a better understanding of the two languages and equally of the cultures from which they are inseparable.</description><creator>Fukuda, Suzy E.</creator><contributor>Hasegawa, Sumi (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Bouchard, Chantal (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Japanese language -- Spoken Japanese</subject><subject>French language -- Grammar, Comparative -- Japanese</subject><subject>Japanese language -- Grammar, Comparative -- French</subject><subject>French language -- Spoken French</subject><title>Grammaire comparée du français et du japonais parlés : phrase et sujet</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s686v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pv72g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x346d622q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Evgenii Zamiatin's Islanders (Ostrovitiane 1917) is a novella that has largely been ignored, overshadowed by the writer's best known dystopian novel We (My 1920-21). Yet the novella reveals a wealth of themes, stylistic and linguistic innovations, that were to reach full fruition in We. Thus, it appears to be appropriate and profitable for a broadening of Zamiatin research to conduct a chronotopic analysis of Islanders, which enables a comprehensive investigation, incorporating thematic, stylistic, and linguistic facets of the novella. Chapter One reviews Zamiatin's opposition between the urban and the natural worlds, based on M. Bakhtin's concept of the chronotope, supplemented by Iu. Lotman's category of mobility and immobility. Chapters Two and Three will examine both worlds in turn, as embodied by their respective characters. Finally, Chapter Four will explore the characters' dynamic interaction and resulting metamorphosis. This first full-length study of Islanders hopes to bring a new focus on Zamiatin's oeuvre at large.</description><creator>Frenette, Véronique</creator><contributor>Beraha, Laura (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Zami︠a︡tin, Evgeniĭ Ivanovich, 1884-1937. Ostroviti︠a︡e</subject><title>A chronotopic study of Evgenii Zamiatin's Islanders</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z2989.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d622q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Russian and Slavic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf2687180</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The strict divisions of city spaces created by physical urban planning disintegrated under transformations of capitalism and its accompanying crises of overaccumulation, social urban planning was elaborated to more effectively control the capitalist city and to reintegrate the increasingly blighted areas of the once popular amusements into the economy. This disciplined reintegration, unsuccessfully attempted in New York City's Times Square since the late 1920s. is finally being realized by the redevelopment forces that began shaping the city's spatial practices in the wake of the fiscal crisis of 1975. The development projects undertaken in midtown Manhattan following the recovery from the fiscal crisis are transforming the renowned Times Square theater district into a strikingly different urban environment. The new politics of redevelopment under the regime of flexible accumulation are almost exclusively oriented towards economic development that is equated with speculative property investments, rebuilding Times Square to promote the global city's finance monopoly. Denying the existence of the public realm and celebrating free market laissez-faire policy, the 42nd Street Development Project, under the guise of removing blight, is eliminating the undesirable and underprivileged from the new image of the Bright Lights District. Times Square as a center of the local popular culture of Broadway theaters, cinemas, restaurants, billboard spectaculars, and public celebrations, has been lost as a public space. In the redevelopment projects now imaging the Crossroads of the World, the lost city of the past is recreated through the commodification of its collective memory, fashioning a Disneyfied spectacle for the global urban center. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Filipcevic, Vojislava</creator><contributor>Szanto, George (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Urban renewal -- New York (State) -- New York -- History -- 20th century</subject><subject>City planning -- New York (State) -- New York -- History -- 20th century</subject><subject>Times Square (New York, N.Y.) -- History.</subject><title>Bright lights, blighted city : urban renewal at the crossroads of the world</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c247dv19v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf2687180</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hf232</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dark House is a creative writing thesis. In the story, Ben Sandler, a twenty-five year old graduate student in English, retreats to his great uncle's home in rural Ontario to write his Master's thesis. The text is presented in alternating chapters. Chapters 1, 3, 5, 7 and 9 are first person accounts of Ben's experiences. Chapters 2, 4, 6 and 8 are annotated selections from his writings. The required critical afterword is in two parts. The first section deals with innovative and experimental approaches to literary criticism. In the second section, I consider some issues of epistemology, orienting my discussion around the work of Martha Nussbaum and Stanley Cavell.</description><creator>Fanning, Simon</creator><contributor>Ohlin, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Literature, Canadian (English).</subject><title>Dark house : a trailer park pastoral</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w442q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hf232</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:05741t827</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dene women are leading and directing efforts toward "healing" themselves, their families, and their communities. Employing a modality of montage and storytelling, this thesis explores this enigmatic concept of "healing" among Dene, and its gendered dimensions, in the community of Fort Good Hope, Northwest Territories. This account challenges the limitations of a resistance-hegemony paradigm often used to describe Aboriginal actions as embedded within colonial relations, and endeavours toward a more nuanced analysis which explores Dene "healing" beyond the colonial space. "Healing" is emerging as a vehicle for the assertion and celebration of Dene identity, Dene tradition and "Dene ways". This thesis further explores how many Dene women in Fort Good Hope are mobilizing the power of tradition, such as -aet'sechi/ (practices associated with "becoming woman"), as a means of "healing" social/health concerns, and influencing gender and power relations in the community.</description><creator>Fajber, Elizabeth</creator><contributor>Lock, Margaret (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Tinne Indians -- Medicine</subject><subject>Tinne women -- Northwest Territories -- Fort Good Hope</subject><title>The power of medicine : "healing" and "tradition" among Dene women in Fort Good Hope, Northwest Territories</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c472x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741t827</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s4655j65c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:03:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is made up of two distinct parts. The first part is a translation of Valeria Narbikova's text B sc HOHMOCTb Hac. The second is a commentary constituted of a presentation of the author, of her work and of the characteristics distinctive of her work and of the characteristics distinctive of her writing, as well of a reflection on the process of translation. The approach developed for this translation of literary translation is presented; it is inspired mainly by the conception of two authors: Antoine Berman and Henri Meschonnic. The concepts of openness and respect of the source language and source culture are two fundamental aspects of this approach. The approach is illustrated through the examination of the problem of cultural references. A classification of the references found in Valeria Narbikova's text and a discussion of the different methods used to translate them is also presented.</description><creator>Dussault, Annie Pénélope</creator><contributor>Berama, Laura (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Sakayan, Dora (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Narbikova, Valerii︠a︡ -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>L' apparence de nous de Valeria Narbikova ; suivi de, La traduction, une ouverture à l'Autre</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cm96g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655j65c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Russian and Slavic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):1075</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>