<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:22:10Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33350" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:02870x60z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The dissertation treats of Paul Natorp's and Martin Heidegger's interpretations of Plato. My goal is twofold: sympathetically to expound each of these interpretations in its own right, and to contrast them against each other as emblematic of the conflict between neo-Kantianism (Natorp) and Phenomenology (Heidegger). The philosophical controversy centers on the relation of thinking and being, a controversy which in this specific context may ultimately be traced back to Kant. Natorp and Heidegger both, for different reasons, return to the Platonic "theory of forms" in order to ground their respective conceptions of thinking and being. Accordingly, I discuss in Chapter One the role of the Platonic forms in Kant's own philosophy. In Chapter Two, I examine the central doctrine of neo-Kantianism and its roots in post-Kantian German philosophy. In Chapter Three, I show how this doctrine is embodied in Natorp's analysis of several of Plato's dialogues. In Chapter Four, I lay out the principal points of Phenomenology's dispute with neo-Kantianism, as well as Heidegger's understanding of that dispute. Finally, in Chapter Five, I show how Heidegger's fundamental ontology is expressed in his interpretations of several key passages of Plato.</description><creator>Kim, Alan, 1968-</creator><contributor>Deslauriers, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Menn, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Buckley, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Plato -- Influence.</subject><subject>Heidegger, Martin, 1889-1976.</subject><subject>Natorp, Paul, 1854-1924.</subject><title>Original fracture : Plato in the philosophies of Paul Natorp and Martin Heidegger</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m829r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02870x60z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Philosophy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tn61w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation is an economic investigation into the persistency of Canadian unemployment. It examines whether this persistence is caused by sectoral shifts. Empirically, we test for persistence using the Cochrane Variance ratio and the modified rescaled range test statistics. We estimate unemployment persistence using Bayesian ARFIMA class of models. To understand employment sectoral dynamics, the thesis uses data-driven Vector Autoregression models with emphasis on Classical and Bayesian estimation techniques. At the theoretical level, two structural Real Business Cycle models are proposed to explain how aggregate unemployment persistence emerges from sectoral labour mobility. The main difference between these two models is the impetus of the shock. One model uses relative sectoral technology shocks and the other uses relative sectoral taste shocks. We show that sectoral phenomena are important in accounting for aggregate unemployment fluctuations.</description><creator>Mikhail, Ossama.</creator><date>2001</date><subject>Labor mobility -- Canada.</subject><subject>Unemployment -- Canada.</subject><title>The persistence of unemployment in Canada and sectoral labour mobility /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322f950.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tn61w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:73666619w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Great Famine (1845--1852) was not only a catastrophic moment in Irish history, it was and remains an important source of textual production, particularly in regard to literature and drama. These cultural products carry a powerful discourse used to communicate various social and political agendas. From the beginning, Irish novelists, poets and dramatists have confronted the question of the Famine's meaning then and now. At each historical moment, they have interrogated the Famine and have employed various discursive strategies to communicate to their readers and audiences. This dissertation makes four primary claims: (a) The historical Irish Famine has remained a source of discursive activity by Irish writers, and so constitutes a phenomenon that merits communication research; (b) This discursive content constructs the Famine in ways that communicate its meaning for contemporary readers in successive historical periods; (c) The multiple discursive meanings of the Famine are often contradictory, and demonstrate the conflicting socio-cultural and political goals of both writers and their readerships; and (d) The emergence and evolution of Famine discourse, which consistently recruits pre-existing discourses, provides an important site for examination of the communicational function of imaginative literature and drama. A survey of Famine literature and drama reveals inconsistent patterns of textual production and discursive content. By determining the historical periods of Famine literary and dramatic production, and by analyzing the contextual dimensions and textual features of representative works, the reasons behind periods of high and low output, the purposes of discursive maintenance and manipulation and the relationship between literary and dramatic discourse and readerships can be approached. To undertake this analysis, five central tropes---land, national identity, religion, gender and agency---are employed. These themes are multi-layered and mutually implicated both on the level of textual production and consumption, that is, in their writing and in their reading/viewing. These tropes have been employed in and through the communicational perspectives of several thinkers, notably Pierre Bourdieu and Teun van Dijk. Termed an Gorta Mor in the Irish language, the Famine dramatically altered Ireland's social, economic and political fabric, triggered massive emigration to America, Britain and Canada, and etched itself into the Irish psyche as an enduring, if frequently repressed, moment of trauma. As such, a study of its role in communication, in human meaning-making, can illuminate not only Irish experience but the human capacity to tell a bitter, painful story, for specific ends, by remembering and manipulating its elements and to use that story as tool in achieving social and political goals, and in obtaining or maintaining power.</description><creator>Day, Jerome Joseph.</creator><contributor>Robinson, Gertrude Joch (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Ireland -- History -- Famine, 1845-1852.</subject><subject>Famines in literature.</subject><title>An analysis of Irish famine texts, 1845-2000 : the discursive uses of hunger</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042v58z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666619w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vd66w140s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Neurofilaments are the major type of intermediate filaments found in the adult nervous system of mammalians. Abnormalities of the neurofilament network constitute a common finding of many neurological disorders. For instance depositions of neurofilament aggregates in the perikarya and axons of motor neurons are observed in most amyotrophic lateral sclerosis (ALS) cases, sporadic and familial. The impact of such accumulation of neurofilaments on the course of motor neuron disease remains to be fully elucidated. In order to investigate the role of neurofilaments in motor neuron disease, transgenic mice expressing a mutant form of the Cu,Zn superoxide dismutase (SOD1) were used as an animal model of familial ALS. Increasing the perikaryal neurofilament content in these mutant SOD1 mice slowed down the motor neuron disease progression and increased their life span by up to 65%. To date, this approach constitutes the most efficient way to increase the life span of mutant SOD1 mice. Moreover, increasing the axonal neurofilament content in mutant SOD1 mice by human neurofilament-light subunit (hNF-L) overexpression demonstrated that axonal neurofilaments do not constitute an exacerbating factor in the neurodegeneration caused by mutant SOD1. The pathogenicity of human neurofilament-heavy (hNF-H) proteins expressed in transgenic mice was also investigated. Two alleles of the NF-H gene are present in the normal human population. Expression of both alleles in transgenic mice provoked motor neuron dysfunction. The adverse property of NF-H overexpression is the result of an improper stoichiometry between the NF-L and the NF-H subunits. Restoration of an adequate stoichiometry, via the co-expression of NF-L and NF-H subunits, rescued mice from the motor neuron dysfunction. Finally, expression of the allele called NFH43, bearing less phosphorylation sites than the other allele called NFH44, was shown to be more pathogenic in transgenic mice.</description><creator>Couillard-Despres, Sebastien.</creator><contributor>Julien, Jean-Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Transgenic mouse models to study the role of neurofilaments in motor neuron disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j3860858g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w140s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pp64k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recent developments in string theory have led to the understanding that many physical systems posses multiple equivalent, or dual, descriptions which are distinguished by their usefulness in differing regions of parameter space. Dualities of this type often relate theories which exist in different numbers of space-time dimensions and it is the purpose of this thesis to examine several examples of this phenomenon. It is well known that the low energy dynamics of D3-branes is well described by N = 4 super-Yang-Mills theory in 3 + 1 dimensions. In the first part of this thesis it will be shown how the physics of magnetic monopole solutions of this theory is often best described by a 1 + 1 dimensional quantum field theory. In particular it is found that near the core of the monopole the most appropriate description of the physics is in terms of a particular version of non-commutative geometry arising from the non-abelian nature of the 1 + 1 dimensional field theory. The second part of this thesis discusses the duality between Anti de-Sitter Space and Conformal Field Theory (the AdS/CFT correspondence) which states that at strong coupling N = 4 Super-Yang-Mills theory is actually best described by type IIB superstring theory in 9 + 1 dimensions. The implications of this conjecture as applied to non-supersymmetric field theories are explored and it is found that many properties of quantum-chromo-dynamics (QCD) such as confinement and mass gaps can effectively be studied using string theory techniques. It is also shown how the mass spectra of glueballs in QCD-like theories can be computed. These techniques are then turned around to deduce from the field theory a perturbative proof of a positive energy conjecture for asymptotically AdS spaces.</description><creator>Constable, Neil R.</creator><contributor>Myers, Robert C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>Dirichlet branes and the connections between quantum field theory and gravity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wr94d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pp64k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gf669</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The scientific aim of computational neuroanatomy using magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) is to quantify inter- and intra-subject morphological variabilities. A unified statistical framework for analyzing temporally varying brain morphology is presented. Based on the mathematical framework of differential geometry, the deformation of the brain is modeled and key morphological descriptors such as length, area, volume dilatation and curvature change are computed. To increase the signal-to-noise ratio, Gaussian kernel smoothing is applied to 3D images. For 2D curved cortical surface, diffusion smoothing, which generalizes Gaussian kernel smoothing, has been developed. Afterwards, statistical inference is based on the excursion probability of random fields defined on manifolds. This method has been applied in localizing the regions of brain tissue growth and loss in a group of 28 normal children and adolescents. It is shown that children's brains change dramatically in localized areas even after age 12.</description><creator>Chung, Moo K., 1969-</creator><contributor>Ramsay, J. O. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Worsley, K. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Statistics.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Human Development.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Anatomy.</subject><title>Statistical morphometry in Neuroanatomy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n280v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gf669</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cv66n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Living organisms must monitor and respond to a diverse array of environmental stimuli. These responses, many of which are genetically-programmed, allow the organisms to obtain nutrients as well as cope with toxins. To identify such responses in Escherichia coli, a chromosomal luxAB gene fusion library was constructed. By screening this library with metals and monitoring for increases in luminescence, two metal-inducible clones were identified. Luminescence of clone LF20110 increases with increasing concentrations of added aluminum, iron, indium, gallium and vanadium, but not added calcium, magnesium or nickel. Luminescence of clone TBT1 increases with increasing concentrations of added tributyltin, triethyltin, tri-n-propyltin and carbonyl cyanide m-chlorophenyl hydrazone, but not added dibutyltin or tetrabutyltin. Analysis of clone TBT1 revealed a luxAB fusion to the uhpT gene, which encodes a hexose-6-phosphate transport protein. Transcriptional regulation of uhpT by glucose-6-phosphate has been well characterized. However, it had not been previously demonstrated that addition of tributyltin could induce transcription of uhpT. This effect on uhpT is associated with the uncoupling of oxidative phosphorylation. Isolation and sequencing of the luxAB gene fusion from clone LF20110 uncovered a previously uncharacterized gene, which we call ais (a̲luminum and i̲ron s̲timulated). The ais gene has been sequenced, the transcriptional start site has been identified, and the 22 kDa Ais protein has been overexpressed in vivo. Mutation of the basS gene abrogates metal-induced transcription of ais. However, expression of the BasR-BasS two-component regulatory system, in trans, restores the metal-inducible response. The E. coli BasR-BasS regulon is poorly characterized. To identify genes regulated by this two-component system, a MudI (lac Ap) gene fusion library was constructed and screened Gene fusions to blc, glmUS, iap, and ygjlJK exhibited increased beta-galactosidase activity upon overexpression of BasR-BasS, while expression of a dsdXA fusion decreased. By searching the E. coli genome database for putative BasR binding sequences, four additional genes, seiC, yibD, yhhT and yaf were identified. Of these nine genes, four have not yet been characterized. The other five are associated with cell membrane functions or sugar metabolism.</description><creator>Alexander, David Charles.</creator><contributor>DuBow, Michael S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Characterization of generically-programmed responses of Escherichia coli to heavy metal stress</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w3763868g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cv66n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v692t794b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A rodent model was developed to assess the osteogenic potential of continuous capacitive electrical stimulation on bone healing around titanium (Ti) implants. Adult male rats were fitted subcutaneously with electrical leads, that were placed around Ti implants inserted in the tibia. One electrical lead was attached directly to the extraosseous component of the implant, and the other was anchored to the adjacent subcutaneous tissues. Bone healing around the Ti implant was assessed histologically after 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 14 and 21 days of continuous capacitive electrical stimulation as compared to controls and sacrificed immediately. Other groups of animals were given 7 days of continuous capacitive electrical stimulation but sacrificed at day 14 or 21 post-implantation. Histomorphometric analysis of the bone-Ti interface revealed that animals given 5--7 days of continuous capacitive electrical stimulation demonstrated more bone at the surface of the Ti implant than in controls. Radioautographic analyses of bone formation was carried out in rats injected with tritiated (3H)-proline 4 days prior to sacrifice at days 7, 14 and 21. These results showed increased 3H-proline deposition at day 7, corresponding to increased bone formation as shown by morphometric findings. Biomechanical 'pull-out' tests demonstrated that the force required to remove the Ti implants from the tibiae was significantly greater in electrically stimulated animals compared to controls at day 7. Bone densitometric measurements revealed a statistically significant increase in bone density in the electrically-stimulated animals by days 5--7 compared to controls. In summary, an animal model was developed to evaluate the effects of continuous capacitive electrical stimulation on bone healing around Ti implants placed in tibiae of rats. Significant bone growth was demonstrated by days 5--7 postimplantation as in all parameters tested. These findings suggest that continuous capacitive electrical stimula</description><creator>Abd-Ul-Salam, Hani.</creator><contributor>Gornitsky, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Dentistry.</subject><title>The effects of continuous capacitive electrical stimulation on bone healing around titanium implants with an appendix on the effects of gallium-aluminum-arsenic low energy laser on bone healing around titanium implants /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343t77j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t794b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn1070818</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recently, various proteoglycans (PGs) have been identified in the lung. The first objective of this thesis was to test the hypothesis that matrix glycosaminoglycans contribute to lung tissue viscoelasticity. Lung parenchymal strips were exposed to specific glycosaminoglycans-degradating enzymes to determine whether the mechanical properties of the tissue were affected. The degradation of heparan sulphate and chondroitin/dermatan sulphate glycosaminoglycans caused significant increases in energy dissipation and dynamic resistance relative to control strips. Hyaluronidase treatment did not alter any of the dynamic or static measures. Since PGs were found to be part of the stress bearing structure, the second part of the thesis aimed at examining whether subjecting the lung to excessive mechanical force can cause alteration in PG composition so as to adapt to the altered stress bearing requirement. To address this hypothesis, the effect of different ventilation regimes on lung tissue mechanics and PGs was examined in an in vivo rat model. After 2 h of mechanical ventilation, lung tissue elastance and resistance were significantly increased in rats ventilated with tidal volume of 30 ml/kg at 0 positive end-expiratory pressure (Vt30PEEP0) as compared to controls (Vt8PEEP1.5). Versican, a basement membrane heparan sulphate PG and biglycan, were all increased in rat lungs ventilated with Vt30PEEP0 as compared to control. These data demonstrated that alterations in lung tissue mechanics with excessive mechanical ventilation are accompanied by changes in all classes of ECM PGs. However, whether the alteration seen in PG composition resulted from excessive mechanical ventilation directly was unclear. In addition the cellular source of these PGs was not determined. Therefore, the aim of the third part of the thesis was to investigate and characterize the effect of mechanical strain on lung fibroblast PG production in vitro. We found cell layer associated versican protein in</description><creator>Al-Jamal, Rehab.</creator><contributor>Ludwig, Mara S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>The interaction between dynamic lung physiology, the extracellular matrix and mechanical strain /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j716v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn1070818</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227mr54b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this dissertation is to examine the effect of recent trade policy changes on trade and economic growth for southern Africa. This is accomplished by using a dynamic panel data modeling approach to examine the effect of openness on economic growth during the 1990s. The gravity model and Tobit maximum likelihood estimation are used to examine the effect of trade policy changes and two types of spatial separation on the likelihood of trade. The two types of spatial separation are distance and preferential trading arrangements. This study uses sophisticated econometric techniques and a more complete sample of countries than previous studies on southern Africa. The results show that distance impedes the likelihood of trade. Trade policy changes and the preferential trading arrangements, SADC and COMESA, enhanced trade in southern Africa during the 1990s. The trade stimulating effect was larger for SADC membership. However, some members benefited much more from the existence of preferential relations than other members. The study results indicate that openness affects economic growth.</description><creator>Agama, Laurie-Ann Cecilia.</creator><contributor>Iton, John (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Grimard, Franque (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Africa, Southern -- Economic conditions.</subject><subject>Africa, Southern -- Commercial policy.</subject><title>Trade and economic growth : an econometric investigation of southern Africa</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn107082j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mr54b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3484zj40v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Caulobacter crescentus divides asymmetrically to produce two different progeny, a swarmer progeny that is replication incompetent, and a stalked cell progeny that is replication competent. Upon cell division, a cell cycle regulator protein (CtrA) was identified only in the swarmer cells, and additional circumstantial evidence links this protein to being a repressor of chromosome replication. For example, this response regulator protein binds to five specific sites in the replication origin (Cori) designated [a-e]. We carefully studied the binding characteristics of both phosphorylated (CtrA~P) and unphosphorylated forms of the protein to the five binding sites [a-e] in the replication origin (Chapter 2) and upstream of the ctrA gene (Chapter 3). We showed that phosphorylation significantly enhances binding affinity in the replication origin (Chapter 2) but not upstream of ctrA (Chapter 3). In addition a "pseudo-active" protein form (CtrA D51E) that resembles the phosphorylated form in vivo did not improve the binding characteristics (Chapter 3). These results suggest that enhanced binding on phosphorylation is not the only signal achieved on phosphorylation. In fact, CtrA half-site mutation binding studies shows that phosphorylation stimulates protein/protein interaction and cooperative binding between sites [a] and [b] in the replication origin (Chapter 2). We show that CtrA binding site [b] is the major contributor in the cooperative CtrA binding between [a] and [b] (Chapter 4). We demonstrate that cooperative binding of CtrA~P to sites [a] and [b] repress transcription from a strong promoter (Ps), which in turn blocks plasmid replication. In addition, mutating site [b] to block CtrA binding to [a] and [b] has a deleterious effect on chromosome replication (Chapter 4). This cooperative CtrA binding at [a] and [b] is independent from the upstream binding sites [c-e] (Chapter 2). CtrA~P binding in the origin is altered in the presence of the histone-like protein (IHF) that also binds and overlaps CtrA binding site [c] (Chapter 5). In-fact, IHF binds and overlaps binding site [c] (Chapter 5). We propose a replication model in the stalked cell were IHF binding hinders active CtrA binding in the replication origin and regulates cooperative transcription that coincides with replication initiation.</description><creator>Siam, Rania.</creator><contributor>Marczynski, G. T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Mechanisms of C. crescentus regulation of chromosome replication by a cell cycle regulator protein</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dr276.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zj40v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wh69q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Morphogenesis of the dsDNA phages is a highly regulated process that utilizes multicomponent pathways to assemble precursors of heads and tails. These mechanisms have been extensively investigated in many phage systems but have yet to be well characterized for the transposable phages. To investigate morphogenesis in these systems, we have cloned and sequenced 4.5 kb the of the DNA of phage Mu immediately downstream of the first late promoter P lys; expressed the associated proteins; examined phage development in thin section; and refined our existing in vitro packaging assay. Previous amber mutant analysis had located the lytic and maturation genes of Mu in the Plys transcript. Sequence data were derived from this region and were analyzed with various computer algorithms, to characterize all potential open reading frames (ORFs), and to assign function to some ORFs based on homology to previously characterized genes. Sequencing of lys, D and E amber mutants was used to assign these genes to specific ORFs. Cloning and expression of the region proximal to the Plys promoter resulted in the production of protein extracts that specifically recognize the phage-encoded packaging signal, characteristic of phage maturation enzymes. Additionally, the growth characteristics of strains expressing these late gene constructs show that lysis of the cultures is induced as a result of the presence of one or more phage-specific proteins expressed from this region. Our studies indicate a deviation from existing phage lysis paradigms. Thin section electron micrographs show that the development of the structures from induced prophages occurs relatively late in the lytic cycle. Sucrose gradient fractions highly enriched for proheads are associated with pac-specific DNA recognition functions. A specific DNA substrate can be packaged, in vitro, into these active proheads. Packaging of the DNA substrate may be improved by the inclusion of purified, E. coli HU or IHF.</description><creator>Siboo, Ian Russell.</creator><contributor>DuBow, M. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Characterization of morphogenetic functions of transposable bacteriophages Mu, D108 and D3112</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811km340.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wh69q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3484zj393</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>DNA methylation is vital in genome functions as diverse as parental imprinting, X chromosome inactivation, regulation of gene expression and precipitation of inactive chromatin structures. A growing line of evidence suggests that aberrations in proper homeostatic regulation of genomic methylation status are causal in oncogenic processes. Recent evidence has also revealed novel roles of the DNA Methyltransferase (DNMT1), the enzyme believed to be largely responsible for maintenance of the DNA methylation pattern, in replication and in direct regulation of chromatin structure which may help to explain its role in cancer. Despite the importance of DNMT1 in the regulation in many critical genome functions, little has been done to clearly elucidate its regulation of expression. Chapters 1--3 of this thesis describe three intriguing mechanisms employed in the regulation of dnmt1 gene expression which further implicate this protein as an important player in cellular transformation and tumorigenesis. Chapter 1 describes dnmt1 as a novel downstream effector of the commonly studied T Antigen oncogenic signaling pathway and points to a novel mechanism by which DNMT1 inhibitors might target tumorigenesis. dnmt1 has also been previously characterized as an effector of the Ras-jun oncogenic signaling pathway and Chapter 2 describes how the c-jun proto-oncogene can recruit and synergize with the tumor suppressor Rb to transactivate dnmt1. Chapter 3 describes a novel and unique mechanism by which dnmt1 can feedback regulate its own expression via methylation of its own promoter. The discovery of active demethylation activity in transformed cell types has also changed our understanding of genomic methylation as a means of epigenetic control and suggests the possibility that aberrant regulation of a demethylase gene may also contribute to cellular transformation and tumorigenesis. Chapter 4, therefore, describes the upregulation of Mbd2/Demethylase in various human tumors and the</description><creator>Slack, Andrew.</creator><contributor>Szyf, Moshe (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Roles of the DNA methylation machinery in cellular transformation and tumorigenesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d826x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zj393</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h415pc10j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Magnetization transfer (MT) imaging is a relatively new magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) technique that generates contrast dependent upon the phenomenon of magnetization exchange between semi-solid macromolecular protons and water protons. This technique has the ability to indirectly image semi-solids, such as protein matrices and cell membranes, whose magnetization dies away too quickly to be imaged directly. Preliminary in vitro and in vivo results suggest that MT quantification may allow improved characterization of the pathologically heterogeneous lesions of multiple sclerosis (MS) by providing a measure of demyelination. However, MT imaging, as currently applied, is only a semi-quantitative technique that reflects a complex combination of tissue and experimental parameters in addition to MT. In this thesis a novel quantitative imaging technique is described that yields all of the observable properties of the binary spin bath model for MT. Based on a new model of the steady-state behavior of the magnetization during a pulsed MT weighted imaging sequence, as well as new methodological developments in MRI relaxometry, this approach yields parametric images of the fractional size of the restricted pool, the magnetization exchange rate, the T2 of the restricted pool and the relaxation times in the free pool. Validated experimentally on agar gels and samples of uncooked beef, the method is demonstrated in studies of two normal subjects and a patient with multiple sclerosis.</description><creator>Sled, John G.</creator><contributor>Pike, G. Bruce (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Quantitative imaging of magnetization transfer parameters in vivo using MRI</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj4306415.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pc10j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cn69m570c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the nervous system of the marine mollusk Aplysia , protein kinase C plays important roles in plasticity and learning. Aplysia PKCs are differentially regulated in sensory neurons of the nervous system. The facilitating neurotransmitter serotonin activates the Ca2+-dependent PKC Apl I but not the Ca2+-independent PKC Apl II. The mechanisms underlying this differential PKC activation still remain unclear. To better understand putative mechanisms regulating PKC activity we sought to characterize Aplysia PKC structural domains. This thesis has explored the characteristics of C1 and C2 domains from Aplysia PKC Apl I and PKC Apl II and whether differences in PKC activation can be attributed to differences in these domains. First, we demonstrate that the presence of the C2 domain of PKC Apl II lowers the affinity of the C1 domain for the protein kinase C activator, phorbol ester. This C2 domain mediated inhibition of activator binding can be overcome by elevating phosphatidylserine concentrations. Further, phosphatidic acid is much more potent than phosphatidylserine in reducing C2 domain mediated inhibition. Second, we present a comparison of the C1 and C2 domains of PKC Apl I and PKC Apl II. The C2 domain of PKC Apl I binds to lipids constitutively, while the C2 domain of PKC Apl II does not. In contrast, the C1 domains of PKC Apl I and PKC Apl II exhibit only small differences in lipid interactions. This suggests that while the C2 domain of PKC Apl I assists lipid mediated activation that of PKC Apl II hinders activation. Finally, we show that there are two primary autophosphorylation sites in the C2 domain of PKC Apl II. These sites map to residues serine 2 and serine 36 located in loop 1 of the C2 domain. In vitro, phosphorylation of serine 36 increased binding of the C2 domain to phosphatidylserine membranes. In vivo, the PKC activator phorbol ester stimulated PKC Apl II phosphorylation at serine 36 and PKC phosphorylated at this residue translocated more efficiently to membranes. Moreover, mutation of serine 36 to alanine significantly reduced membrane translocation of PKC Apl II. As a whole, these data suggest a phosphorylation dependent mechanism regulating C2 domain membrane binding of Ca2+-independent PKCs. This mechanism of Ca2+-independent PKC plasma membrane localization may play a role in generating persistent PKC activity and the eventual modulation of synaptic plasticity in the nervous system of Aplysia.</description><creator>Pepio, Anthony M.</creator><contributor>Sossin, Wayne S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>The role of the C2 domain of protein kinase C APl II in the nervous system of Aplysia californica /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913r542.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m570c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vj39m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effect of management practices used by smallholder farmers to improve soil quality and increase maize yield was examined in an 80 ha. micro-watershed of central Malawi. Because of the complexity inherent in smallholder farming systems, this research proposed the combination of participatory methods with analytical techniques developed in field ecology, such as multivariate and spatial analysis. During a Participatory Rural Appraisal (PRA), farmers identified factors potentially influencing soil quality and maize yield. One hundred and seventy-six (176) plots were located in twenty-nine (29) fields and characterized for management practices and biophysical characteristics. Soil samples were collected at each plot and analysed for a suite of properties. The maize yield was measured for both 1996--97 and 1997--98 seasons. A formal survey was used to gather information on household characteristics. Results showed that management practices that were promoted by a previous extension project, such as alley cropping and the planting of grass on contour ridges, were strongly correlated and found mainly in fields located closer to house compounds. Farmers with a higher proportion of their land under wetland gardens tended to use less agroforestry. Food security was associated with households that were able to purchase inorganic fertilizers, had larger landholding size, and owned livestock and woodlots. The effect of management practices on maize yield and soil quality was partially confounded with characteristics of the plot, such as slope, degradation level, number of years under cultivation or pest damage. Higher maize yield was observed in plots that were better managed, as expressed by the combination of different management practices, lower pest incidence, fewer erosion signs and higher soil fertility. Some positive effects of alley cropping on soil quality were observed in plots that were cultivated for a longer period and located on flatter land. This study demo</description><creator>Pelletier, Bernard, 1964-</creator><contributor>Fyles, J. W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Corn -- Soils -- Malawi.</subject><subject>Corn -- Yields -- Malawi.</subject><subject>Agricultural productivity -- Malawi.</subject><subject>Sustainable agriculture -- Malawi.</subject><title>Management practices, soil quality and maize yield in smallholder farming systems of central Malawi</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rw13p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vj39m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d504rm986</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of the research described in this thesis is to further our understanding of the motor control strategies that are available to the child when learning to produce meaningful interactions with environmental surfaces. The principal aim is to explore the analytical techniques that could be used to evaluate the range of neuromechanical responses for the lower limb that would provide stability at the limb/environment interface during growth and development. Five studies are presented that provide both experimental data and theoretical perspectives that were coalesced in the formulation of a general model for the control of stability at the limb/environment interface. The first study presents an analytical technique that was devised to classify the spatial-temporal organization of the surface myoelectric activity into one of three distinct patterns: Burst, Tonic, and Tonic Burst. This classification permits the matching between the pattern of muscle activity and the kinematic and kinetic control of the ground contact phase of landing. In the second, and companion paper, different distributions of the Burst, Tonic, and Tonic Burst patterns across the muscles of the lower limb were associated with three mechanical responses of the limb to ground contact. Mechanically, the three limb responses show a progression toward an effective control of stability at the limb/environment interface and it was therefore proposed that the distribution of activity patterns could reflect the priorities of system at different stages of growth and development. The results support our hypothesis that more complex movements can be executed when the limits of stability are maximized. Study three presents a formal model for the control of stability at the limb/environment interface. The model was further applied to propose new theoretical approaches that could be used in the clinical milieu, shifting the focus of the evaluation to the range of feasible movements that would be available</description><creator>Pelland, Lucie.</creator><contributor>McKinley, Patricia (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Human Development.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Strategies for motor control analysis in children</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q3192.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rm986</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xt36h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We investigate both directed and elliptic flow and linear momentum transfer in intermediate energy heavy ion collisions. The model that we have adapted for this work is the BUU transport equation solved with a momentum-dependent lattice Hamiltonian algorithm. We introduce an extension of this transport model that consistently takes into account the momentum-dependent in-medium modification of the nucleon-nucleon collision cross section. Comparison with linear momentum transfer data favours a soft momentum-dependent nuclear mean field of compressibility K = 215 MeV. Analysis of higher energy elliptic flow data favours a momentum-dependent over that of a momentum-independent nuclear mean field. Furthermore, we find that both the linear momentum transfer and elliptic flow data favour an in-medium nucleon-nucleon cross section over the free space cross section.</description><creator>Persram, Declan.</creator><contributor>Gale, Charles (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Physics, Nuclear.</subject><title>A momentum-dependent lattice Hamiltonian model for simulations of heavy ion collisions /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b494b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xt36h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8049g669h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There is accumulating evidence that cysteine proteinase activity plays an important role in cancer cell invasion and metastasis. Extracellular cysteine proteases, in particular cathepsin B, have been implicated in a variety of pathological processes involving tissue remodeling states, such as inflammation, parasite infection, and tumor metastasis, by degradation of extracellular matrix components. As such, increasing efforts are directed toward the development of inhibitors that are specific to the enzyme cathepsin B in order to both dissect out the role of the enzyme in these pathological processes and as potential therapeutic agents. Unlike other members of the papain superfamily of enzymes, cathepsin B has a unique 18-residue insertion loop termed the "occluding loop" which sits over the primed subsites of the enzyme. It has now been well established that this loop is responsible for cathepsin B's unique dipeptidylcarboxypeptidase activity due to the presence of two positively charged residues, His110 and His111, that anchor the C-terminus of peptide substrates and allow the enzyme to carry out its carboxypeptidase activity. It has been demonstrated that this loop is a flexible segment that can move up and out of the way in order to accommodate binding of larger molecules such as the propeptide. Close examination of the x-ray crystal structure of the mature enzyme indicates the presence of an electrostatic interaction between the side chain of the main chain residue Asp22 and the imidazole ring of the occluding loop residue His110. This salt bridge acts as latch between the loop "open" and loop "closed" conformations of the enzyme. It has been postulated that the development of inhibitors which interact with the "occluding loop" might provide highly selective inhibitors for cathepsin B and in fact cathepsin B-specific epoxysuccinyl inhibitors have been made which exploit the interaction of between a negatively charged carboxylate at P2' and the two positively charged histidine residues of the occluding loop. Using site-directed mutagenesis, we have dissected out the individual contributions of the two occluding loop histidine residues (His110 and His111). The effect of pH on these interactions has also been evaluated and it has been shown that increasing pH results in increased loop flexibility and diminished inhibitor potency. Further structure-activity relationships for epoxysuccinyl inhibitors were also established by varying our inhibitor design template both in the P1' and P2' positions using known substrate specificities in these positions. Extension of the inhibitor template into the unprimed subsite region yielded the most potent epoxysuccinyl inhibitor to cathepsin B reported to date (BzlNH-Phe-NH-(2 S,3S)-tEps-Leu-Pro-OH: k2/Ki 2 900 000 +/- 300 000 M-1s-1).</description><creator>Michaud, Stephanie.</creator><contributor>Chan, Tak Hang (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Gour, Barbara J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Exploring cathepsin B selectivity using epoxysuccinyl inhibitors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p199z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g669h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913r55b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines why and how art is collected and used by modern corporations. Primarily, the study is focused on Alcan Aluminium Ltd., but for purposes of comparison and illumination, substantial attention is paid to Martineau Walker, Loto-Quebec and the Banque Nationale du Canada, all Montreal-based companies that have collected art for at least twenty years. An historical introduction outlining the relationship between the arts and business---from the Renaissance in Europe to its place of greatest expansion in the nineteenth and twentieth centuries; in the U.S.A. as well as in Canada---begins the discussion. An attempt is made to position the activities of modern corporate art collecting between two poles---that of the individual collector and that of the institutional art museum. Motives for collecting include, among many, the search for distinction and the desire to create a perception in the community of humanitarian standards guiding the corporation. The ways in which corporate motives contribute to the creation of a positive external corporate art identity, and thus a productive business environment, are examined and developed, as are the principal objections of their chief public detractor, artist-writer Hans Haacke. In three of the four corporations studied, original research on the behavioural and emotional reactions of employees to the corporate art surrounding them has allowed an in-depth analysis of the internal effects of art on employees. Foremost among these are feelings of pride, well-being and the enhancement of self-identity. Finally, a brief discussion of the role of mediators is offered, in particular that of the corporate curator in the modern art world.</description><creator>Meade, JoAnn.</creator><contributor>Glen, Tom (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Lamarche, Lise (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Corporations -- Art collections -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Art patronage -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Alcan Aluminium Limited -- Art collections.</subject><title>Forging the corporate identity with art : four Montreal corporations : Alcan Aluminium Limited, Martineau Walker, Banque Nationale du Canada, Loto-Quebec with a focus on Alcan</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nw261.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913r55b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cr56n283p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present literary production in France indicates the return of the subject, which has been proclaimed dead since the New Novel. With the proliferation of autobiographical texts in the nineteen-eighties, a generalized movement towards an aesthetic genre valuing this particularity was noticed. This proliferation renders the scope of this literary form immense. It covers a range from strictly historical texts, including autobiographies, memoirs and intimate journals to semi-referential texts, qualified as autobiographical fictions, "autofictions" or again "factual fictions". Midway between the autobiography and the novel, autofiction, this little studied literary practice, inaugurates a new writing form which we believe constitutes one of the boldest modern incarnations of the writing of the self. This thesis considers the possibility of a correlation existing in the problematics of autofiction and those of Jewishness in writing. Already off-centered, the Jewish writer, can be seen as the emblematic figure of the writer himself. Drawing on a corpus of four writers (Serge Doubrovsky, Marcel Benabou, Regine Robin and Patrick Modiano), we examine the structure, as well as its functionning rules, woven through texts sharing Jewish authorship. These writers pose, each from his own specific perspective, the problem of Jewishness in writing. This correlation brings to light the exemplary nature of these texts with regards to the more generalized and thus far unprecedented strategy that is autofiction. The intersection of these historically marked problems, autofiction and Jewishness in writing, leads us inevitably to further reflection upon the tragedy of modernity, the Shoah and its omnipresent shadow in the works of our corpus.</description><creator>Molkou, Elizabeth.</creator><contributor>Rivard, Yvon (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Robin, Regine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>French literature -- 20th century -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Autobiography in literature.</subject><subject>French literature -- Jewish authors.</subject><subject>Self in literature.</subject><title>Contributions d'ecrivains juifs a la problematique de l'autofiction</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr171z86w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n283p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xt37s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study explores the concept of sainthood in the medieval Islamic tradition. A close reading of the unexplored writings of two 14th C. mystical thinkers, Muh&amp;dotbelow;ammad and `Ali Wafa', shows the presence of at least three distinct currents of thought regarding sainthood. One has been adopted from the Sufi order of the Shadhiliyya, one from the writings of a 9th C. central Asian mystic al-Tirmidhi, and one from the controversial 13th C. thinker Ibn `Arabi. Our study analyses how our Egyptian writers, Muh&amp;dotbelow;ammad and `Ali Wafa', synthesized and elaborated upon these currents to develop a distinct doctrine of sainthood. Although our writers are to be located firmly within the Sunni tradition, it is significant that they felt free to draw on Shi'ite ideas for the construction of their own theory of the final great saint.</description><creator>McGregor, Richard J. A.</creator><contributor>Landolt, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Religion, Philosophy of.</subject><subject>Religion, General.</subject><title>A study of sainthood in medieval Islamic Egypt : Muhammad and Ali Wafa</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214q74z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xt37s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tq57ns586</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This comprehensive analysis of T. S. Eliot's literary-critical corpus provides both a long-overdue reassessment of the nature and extent of his commitment to notions of aesthetic autonomy, and an Eliotic critique of the hypostatization of art that characterizes both philosophical postmodernism and its literary-theoretical derivatives. The broader context for these two primary objectives is the "ancient quarrel" between the poets and the philosophers and its various manifestations in the work of a number of prominent post- and anti-Enlightenment thinkers. Accordingly, I begin by highlighting several fundamental but much-neglected (or misunderstood) features of Eliot's critical canon that testify to his life-long preoccupation with this still resonant issue. Specifically, I demonstrate that there is a logical connection between his sustained opposition to those who seek in literature a substitute for religious faith or at least philosophic belief, his critique of various more or less sophisticated forms of generic confusion, and his robust defence of the integrity of different discursive forms, social practices, and disciplinary domains. In anticipation of my Eliotic critique of philosophical and literary-theoretical postmodernism, I then locate Eliot's account of these characteristic features of "the modern mind" within the context of Jurgen Habermas remarkably congenial The Philosophical Discourse of Modernity. In successive chapters, I next provide detailed analyses of Eliot's account of the discursive and functional integrity of art, literature, poetry, and criticism. By way of providing additional support for the concept of "integrity," and indicating its relevance to contemporary debates about the relationship between literature, criticism, and philosophy, I advert to the work of a number of other contemporary philosophers, John Searle, Goran Hermeren, Monroe Beardsley, Peter Lamarque, Paisley Livingston, and Richard Shusterman chief among them. I then demonstrate that Eliot's critique of the hypostatizing and levelling tendencies of many of his predecessors and contemporaries can itself legitimately be brought to bear on the similar practices of contemporary postmoderns such as Jacques Derrida and Richard Rorty. I conclude by suggesting that a return to Eliot's literary critical corpus is both timely and instructive, for it provides a much-needed corrective to some late twentieth-century trends in literary studies, and, in particular, to the influence of philosophical postmodernism upon it.</description><creator>Laver, Sue, 1961-</creator><contributor>Hjort, Mette (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Criticism.</subject><subject>Postmodernism (Literature)</subject><subject>Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1888-1965 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Poets, philosophers, and priests : T.S. Eliot, postmodernism, and the social authority of art</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xt382.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57ns586</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v4644</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Everything about fascism is aesthetic: this is what our thesis aims to demonstrate, based on the example of interwar French Fascism (1919--1939). It studies both discourses, symbolic practices, and literary texts, in order to show the multiple aspects of fascism's aesthetic dimension. Two theories, discourse analysis and sociocriticism, have guided us and permitted us to explain the interaction between aesthetics and ideology. Our thesis is divided in three parts, each one devoted to one of fascism's central themes: the leader, the youth, and the group. In our first chapter, we examine the charismatic leader's many faces, among which are the poet and the warrior. We then show that fascism's discourse on heroism makes of the epic hero an ideological model and that, in its turn, this ideological hero greatly influenced Pierre Drieu la Rochelle's representation of the hero. But, as we indicate, Drieu's novels reveal that the cult of the hero is both a glorification of the self and a self-hatred. In our second chapter we examine fascism's cult of youth such as it was in Italy and Germany, after which we have demonstrated that, in a way, French fascism was an extreme radicalization of the contemporary French discourse on youth. Then, we analyse one of Robert Brasillach's novels which brings to the fore the dark side of fascism's cult of youth: its death drive. In our last chapter, we unearth the aesthetic principles underlying fascism's political spectacle, principles that we also find at the heart of Drieu's texts. We consequently state that Drieu has adopted fascism's aesthetic years before he realized he had fascist ideas. Going a little further yet, we stipulate that Drieu thus reveals that the aesthetic was one of the main roads towards fascism. We then establish, in our final conclusion, a synthetic description of fascist aesthetics: an aesthetics of pathos, exhibition, sublime, violence, and death.</description><creator>Lacroix, Michel, 1969-</creator><contributor>Angenot, Marc (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Fascism -- France.</subject><subject>Drieu La Rochelle, Pierre, 1893-1945 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Fascism and art -- France.</subject><subject>Aesthetics, French -- 20th century.</subject><title>La beaute comme violence : la dimension esthetique du fascisme francais, 1919-1939</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w032466s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v4644</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859h272</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:38:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The focus of this dissertation is on the dynamics of sensorial pleasure and the relationship between its intensity and subsequent behavior. The aim is to challenge the assumption that the relationship between pleasure intensity and approach behavior remains stable over time and across contexts. Two experiments were performed to test the proposition, consistent with opponent process theory, that different levels of initial pleasure intensity change at different rates over time and produce behavioral manifestations unpredicted by traditional approach-avoidance models. The objectives of Experiment 1 were to model the changes in online ratings (pleasure and desire to consume) associated with pleasures of different intensity, and to study the relationship between pleasure intensity and consumption. Testing was conducted in a naturalistic context and stimuli consisted of different flavors of dark chocolate selected on an idiosyncratic basis to produce a range of pleasure intensity. On separate days, 22 subjects ate at their discretion a different flavor out of a known quantity. Results revealed that online ratings possessed a Markov quality, and that increases in initial pleasure intensity were associated with diminishing marginal pleasure and desire overall. When accounting for contextual and individual-level factors, consumption did not reflect any influence of pleasure intensity. In Experiment 2, contextual variables were manipulated on a between-subject basis to test the possibility of influencing pleasure intensity and its behavioral manifestations. In a controlled environment, prior to consumption, 85 subjects read a booklet containing either the history of chocolate or a vocabulary of its sensory properties, and during consumption their attentional focus was directed toward either their sensations or a word puzzle. Subjects ate a piece of cinnamon-flavored milk chocolate at regular intervals while rating their sensorial pleasure, desire to eat the next piece, an</description><creator>Le Bel, Jordan Lachance.</creator><contributor>Dube, Laurette (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Pleasure.</subject><subject>Food consumption.</subject><title>Investigation into the experience of pleasure : intensity, its relationship to consumption behavior, and moderators thereof</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57ns57x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859h272</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33375</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>