<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:50:03Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):41675" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074v90m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Anaerobes belonging to the genera Propionibacterium, Bacteroides, Peptococcus, Peptostreptococcus, Eubacterium, Streptococcus and Lactobacillus, which are commonly isolated from the human urogenital flora, were tested for their ability to inhibit the in vitro growth of Neisseria gonorrhoeae strains. The antigonococcal effect of the anaerobic bacterial strains tested was found not to be due to nutrient depletion and pH change of the media which had supported their growth. This inhibition was not an all-or-none phenomenon since an inhibitory strain did not necessarily interfere with all the gonococcal strains tested. All the 23 lactobacilli strains tested were found to inhibit the in vitro growth of N. gonorrhoeae. This inhibition was found to be dependent on the composition of the culture medium. In comparison to the gonococcus (GC) and dextrose starch agar (DSA) media, a modified deMan, Rogosa et Sharpe (MRS) medium was more appropriate to support both the growth of lactobacilli and the production of their antigonococcal activity. For the other 32 anaerobic bacterial strains tested, six were selected for their large antigonococcal spectrum of activity. These strains were Peptostreptococcus anaerobius (Pc9,Ps11B,Ps11C), Bacteroides fragilis (B1A), Bacteroides ovatus (B24) and Eubacterium limosum (Ps11A). The antigonococcal activity produced by these six strains appeared to be specific to the gonococcus since a variety of anaerobes and aerobes were not generally inhibited. E. limosum and B. fragilis strains were further selected to evaluate the production of their antigonococcal activity in liquid medium. E. limosum Ps11A strain produced its inhibitory activity in prereduced brain heart infusion (BHI) broth during the mid-logarithmic phase of growth, when no inhibitory concentration of short-chain fatty acids was detected in the culture medium. Furthermore, when the amounts of short-chain fatty acids produced by E. limosum increased, its antigonococcal activity decreased. Based on these results and on the individual amount of short-chain fatty acids excreted by E. limosum strains, it was concluded that the observed antigonococcal activity was not due to the presence of these acids. However, B. fragilis strains excreted propionic acid in the amount reported to be inhibitory to the gonococcus. Preliminary characterization of the antigonococcal produced by E. limosum PsiiA strain indicated that it is heat and PH resistant and not susceptible to proteases, lipase and amylases. Our results suggested that this inhibitory activity is composed of more than one amino compound having molecular weights ranging from 1000 to 2500.</description><creator>Morin, André</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Anaerobic bacteria.</subject><subject>Neisseria gonorrhoeae.</subject><title>In vitro inhibition of Neisseria gonorrhoeae growth by anaerobes and isolation of the inhibitory activity produced by Eubacterium limosum</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cx11w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074v90m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306sz98g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study is to investigate the possibility of using the Bleached Kraft wastewater sludges as a sealant to a permeable soil structure which could contain these liquids. The sludges used are either self-contained in wastewater, produced from treatment processes, or from the addition of chemical coagulant to the wastewater. The mechanisms of the sludge sealing phenomena which were investigated individually are divided into physical, physico-chemical, biophysical and bio-physico-chemical types of seals. Coarse sand #24 was found suitable for this sealing study as a particle size cut. Among the types of sealings studied, the bio-physical type of seals is the most effective. The physico-chemical type of seals is effective in the initial stage of sealing. The coefficient of the permeability is reduced from an average of 6.4 x 10('-2) cm/sec to 1.0 x 10('-6) cm/sec in a period of 24 hours, with a risk of leakage of less than 1% of the total effluent. A long-term stability of using sludges as a liner to the wastewater pond has become a substantial issue. Alum was originally chosen as an effective coagulant for forming a layer of sludge for physico-chemical types of sealing. However, after the stability analyses, one finds that alum sludge is not a stable material under commonly-found hydrostatic pressures and high pH ranges. The results of the research shows that one of the alumino-silicate sludges is much more stable than that of alum sludge. The relatively stable alumino-silicate sludge was obtained from one of the coprecipitations of sodium-silicate and sodium aluminate in a BKME solution. The economic impact of using alumino-silicate sludge is significant. The cost comparison study shows a cost ratio in the range of up to 1:10 as compared to conventional lining material. The results can be used for the implementation of field work in sludge sealing practice. In addition, this investigation could form an excellent foundation for further studies on other effluents with different parameters.</description><creator>Chen, Michael Ching-li.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Sewage sludge.</subject><subject>Sealing (Technology)</subject><subject>Sewage lagoons.</subject><title>Study of sealing mechanisms in aerated stabilization basins for bleached kraft wastewater sludges</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580n352.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306sz98g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q524jp452</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Anatomically, the stomach-proper of the adult mouse is composed of two parts, the corpus and pyloric antrum. By serially sectioning entire stomachs, and histologically reconstructing the stomach-proper, it has been shown that both areas contain numerous finger-like, epithelial infoldings or gastric units. Special attention was given to the units of the antrum, which by three-dimensional reconstruction appeared as tubes, generally having a single pit, a gland and connecting these an isthmus. Using light and electron microscopy, with or without ('3)H-thymidine radioautography, the renewal of gland cells was investigated. The mucous cells, making up about 82% of the gland cells were produced by the division of cells in the isthmus and upper gland, and displayed immature features. With time, mucous gland cells migrated toward the base of the gland, and began to assume the features of differentiated cells. Not all mucous gland cells, however, reached the gland base. Some were lost by cell death and phagocytosed by neighbouring cells, at various levels of the gland. While some mucous gland cells had a fairly short lifespan of several or more days, a few lived in excess of 60 days.</description><creator>Lee, Eunice R.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Biology, Anatomy.</subject><title>A description of the mucosal lining in the adult mouse stomach with emphasis on the antrum and the renewal of epithelial cells therein /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268595p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jp452</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9g54xj433</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Methyl 4-trimethylsilyl-3-dialkylaminocrotonate is synthesized by the silylation of methyl 3-dialkylaminocrotonate. It reacts with carbonyl electrophiles at its (gamma)-position. The unusual regiochemistry of this reaction is studied and rationalized. It reacts with enamines derived from acyclic ketones or cycloketones of large ring size (of 12 and 15 membered rings) to give aromatic compounds in a 3C + 3C combination and with enamines derived from cycloketones of 5-8 membered rings to give aromatic compounds in a 4C + 2C combination. The mechanism of this cycloaromatization reaction is investigated. meta-Cyclophanes with a morpholino substituent are synthesized by the above cycloaromatization reaction. These meta-cyclophanes possess planar chirality and are successfully resolved. A number of metacyclophanes with alkyl substituents at the intraannular position are synthesized. Depending on the ring size and the steric size of the alkyl group, some of them are also resolved. The rotation process of meta-cyclophane is studied through their temperature dependent ('1)H NMR.</description><creator>Kang, Guo-jun.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Aromatic compounds -- Synthesis.</subject><subject>Enamines.</subject><title>Cycloaromatization reactions of enamines</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zb87b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xj433</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547w65h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Na,K-ATPase, or Na+ pump is an integral membrane protein found in the cells of virtually all higher eukaryotes and is one of the most important systems in cellular energy transduction. Na,K-ATPase catalyzes the electrogenic exchange of three intracellular Na+ for two extracellular K+ ions coupled to the hydrolysis of one molecule of ATP. The research described in this thesis concerns the regulation of the Na,K-ATPase by FXYD 2, a member of the FXYD family of small single transmembrane proteins. FXYD 2, commonly known as the gamma modulator, is located primarily in the kidney and has a role in modulating the enzyme's apparent affinities for ligands. This study has addressed several aspects of gamma structure and function, namely its function in intact cells, the function of the gamma transmembrane domain, and delineation of regions of the enzyme's catalytic alpha subunit with which gamma interacts. Transport assays using intact transfected HeLa cells showed that the two gamma variants, gammaa and gammab, cause (i) an increase in K+/Na+ antagonism, seen as an increase in K'Na at high K+ concentration, and (ii) an increase in apparent ATP affinity seen as an increase in ouabain-sensitive K+ influx as a function of ATP concentration. These results are consistent with those obtained earlier with unsided membrane preparations. The present study also showed a gamma-mediated increase in steady-state intracellular Na+ concentration and, in contrast to assays using permeabilized membranes, a gamma-mediated increase in apparent affinity for extracellular K+. Experiments with synthetic gamma transmembrane (gamma-TM) peptides provided insight into the role of the TM region such that incubation of these peptides with membranes containing alphabeta pumps modulated K'Na similarly to transfected full-length gamma, indicating that the TM domain alone can cause an increase in K'Na at high K+ concentration. Results with gamma-TM bearing the Gly41→Arg missense mutation associated with familial renal hypomagnesemia provided direct evidence that this mutation prevents gamma association with alphabeta pumps. In a study aimed to identify regions of alpha critical for the functional effects of gamma, interactions of alpha1/alpha2 (and the reverse alpha2/alpha1) chimeras with gamma showed the importance of the carboxy terminus, particularly TM 9. The chimera data also indicate that interactions of transmembrane regions of the catalytic alpha subunit with FXYD proteins are not necessarily the sole determinants of the kinetic effects of gamma on Na+ affinity since the extramembranous L7/8 loop of a appears to modulate intramembranous alpha-gamma interactions that mediated the increase in K+/Na+ antagonism.</description><creator>Zouzoulas, Athina.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Regulation of the sodium potassium adenosine triphosphatase (Na,K-ATPPase) by FXYD 2</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Athina Zouzoulas, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rq462.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547w65h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vn133</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In anesthesia practice, consciousness is often equated with the waking state and with the ability to respond to stimuli in the integrated manner. The reversible loss of consciousness is induced by the general anesthetic, which have a wide range of molecular structure and physicochemical characteristics. The mechanisms of unconsciousness induced by anesthetic agents are not well understood. The studies I have conducted for my Ph.D. have focused on how anesthetic drugs produce unconsciousness in human subjects. In two separate PET studies, receptor imaging and regional CBF analysis were used to examine the unconsciousness induced by propofol, a popular general anesthetic. The first study evaluated kinetic analysis methods for estimation of the receptor availability of the muscarinic receptor using dynamic positron emission tomography (PET) studies with [N-11C-methyl]-benztropine. The study also investigated the effect of propofol on central muscarinic receptor availability during general anesthesia. The results of this study suggested the propofol-related reductions in muscarinic receptor availability. The second study identified the brain function changes specifically linked to the difference in levels of consciousness. We used physostigmine (an anticholinestherase) to restore consciousness in the subjects anesthetized with a constant concentration of propofol. The results revealed that the thalamus and precuneus/cuneus jointly play a critical role in controlling the changes in the level of consciousness during general anesthesia. Together, these two studies support a hypothesis that the joint deactivations of a Common Midline Core, which includes the medial thalamus, midline precuneus/cuneus, prefrontal cortex and other related cortical areas, contribute to the unconsciousness induced by general anesthetics. These deactivations are mediated, at least partially, by a reduction in the central cholinergic transmission.</description><creator>Xie, Guoming, 1963-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Exploration of the mechanisms of unconsciousness induced by propofol with positron emission tomography (PET) functional brain imaging</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Guoming Xie, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pj133.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vn133</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f545p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation explores the interaction between literati and various social forces in east China in the mid-seventeenth century by focusing on their military performance. Based on a wide range of sources, the study focuses on about twenty literati, most of whom have never been previously researched from a military history perspective. It examines the diversity and complexity of Chinese literati as they pursued power over and within local society, paying special attention to the interrelation between them (literati and society). It argues that Chinese literati in this time period had much less aptitude in changing China than has been previously thought. Both individual and group case studies show that they mainly focused on the realization of an ideal goal, but were unwilling or ill-equipped to adapt themselves to changing conditions as well as environments. This study also indicates that the local military forces as well as ordinary peasants generally played a more crucial role than the literati; the latter's superior position could only be realized in times of peace. That civil and military officials affected each other in fact is an expression of a larger relationship between the central government and its own military forces or with certain local forces. Finally, this study concludes that Chinese literati as a whole had no idea how to integrate and lead the other social forces to reach an ideal goal in that specific time period.</description><creator>Zhang, Yimin, 1961 Oct. 19-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>China -- History, Military.</subject><subject>China -- History -- Shunzhi, 1644-1661.</subject><subject>China -- History -- Li Zicheng Rebellion, 1628-1645.</subject><subject>Intellectuals -- China -- History -- 17th century.</subject><title>The role of literati in military action during the Ming-Qing transition period /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Yimin Zhang, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386p75r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f545p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445cj59r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Muscular dystrophies are a group of diseases that are often caused by loss-of-function mutations affecting the dystrophin glycoprotein complex (DGC). The common feature of the diseases is muscle degeneration, which is often associated with mental retardation and various retinal defects, including ones of synaptic transmission. However, the mechanisms of the disease remain largely unknown, especially those in the central nervous system. I have focused on dystroglycan (DG), the transmembrane protein in the DGC that links the cytoskeleton to the extracellular matrix and is essential for muscle survival and brain development. I have used proteomics and Drosophila genetics to study DG function in the brain and retina. Using proteomics I found that beta-DG is directly associated with the GTPase dynamin 1 in the retina and in the brain together with alpha-DG and Grb2, and immunohistochemically beta-DG was colocalized with dynamin 1 in the outer plexiform layer where photoreceptor terminals are localized. Moreover, loss of DG in differentiated DG-null embryonic stem cells significantly increases dynamin-mediated transferrin-uptake and re-expression of DG in null cells by infection with an adenovirus containing DG reduced transferrin uptake to levels seen in wild-type cells. This result implies that one of mechanisms in muscular dystrophy might be the altered synaptic vesicle endocytosis, especially in the retina where synaptic transmission defect has been known for decades. Muscular dystrophies show not only impaired retinal synaptic transmission and several DG-related congenital muscular dystrophies also display retinal structural defects. To further understand the roles of DG in the retina, I used Drosophila eye as a model and demonstrated for the first time that DG is required cell-autonomously for photoreceptor morphogenesis in the developing visual system. Deficiency of DG in the eye causes severe disruption of retinal structure, aberrant lens formation and abolition of electroretinogram in the adult fly eye. These adult defects appear derived from autonomous photoreceptor cell (PRC) defects in the early pupa including size arrest, loss of polarity and progressive degeneration. All defects in the eye, however, can be reversed by re-expression of wild type DG in DG-deficient PRCs, suggesting DG functions cell-autonomously in PRCs and non-autonomously for lens. In the 3rd instar larvae DG is present in the apical tips and the basal membranes of PRCs, two polarized locations opposing the extracellular matrix. At the pupal stage it continues to mainly distribute at the apical rhabdomere and basal membrane of PRCs. Over-expression of DG leads to larger ommatidia but the PRC number remains unchanged, suggesting that DG is both necessary for and sufficient to promote PRC expansion. By rescue experiments, I demonstrated that the extracellular DG alone could not rescue DG-deficient eye defects, whereas the intracellular DG can substantially ameliorate PRC degeneration and structural defects while some PRCs remain disorganized, a sign of disrupted PRC planar polarity in absence of the extracellular DG. Therefore, our data suggest that the degeneration and planar polarity disruption in DG-deficient PRCs are two independent processes that appear to require the respective function of intracellular and extracellular DG. In summary, our experiments demonstrated several novel findings and provided the basis for future investigations on DG function and the molecular mechanisms of nervous system defects in muscular dystrophies.</description><creator>Zhan, Yougen, 1968-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Proteomics and genetic studies of dystroglycan function in the nervous system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Yougen Zhan, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429f63t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cj59r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:73666903m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An Electron Microscopy Proteomic Organellar Preparation (EMPOP) robot was developed as a tool for high-throughput preparation of subcellular fraction samples for electron microscopic identification. It will provide a means for validation of subcellular sample purity and confirmation of protein localization needed for organellar proteomics. The device automates all chemical and mechanical manipulations required to prepare organelles for electron microscopic examination. It has a modular, integrated design that supports automated filtration, chemical processing, delivery and embedding of up to 96 subcellular fraction samples in parallel. Subcellular fraction specimens are extremely fragile. Consequently, the system was designed as a single unit to minimize mechanical stress on the samples by integrating a core mechanism, composed of four modular plates, and seven support subsystems for: (1) cooling, (2-3) fluid handling, (4-7) positioning. Furthermore, control software was developed specifically for the system to provide standardized, reproducible sample processing while maintaining flexibility for adjustment and recall of operational parameters. Development of the automated process progressed from initial validation experiments and process screening to define operational parameters for preservation of sample integrity and establish a basic starting point for successful sample preparation. A series of successive modifications to seal the local environment of the samples and minimize the effect of fluidic perturbations further increased process performance. Subsequent testing of the robot's full sample preparation capacity used these refinements to generate 96 samples in approximately 16 hours; reducing the time and labor requirement of equivalent manual preparation by up to 1,000 fold. These results provide a basis for a structured approach toward process optimization and subsequent utilization the device for massive, parallel preparation of subcellular fraction samples for electron microscopic screening and quantitative analysis of subcellular and protein targets necessary for high-throughput proteomics.</description><creator>Waterbury, Raymond.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Robotics.</subject><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>The electron microscopy proteomic organellar preparation robot /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Raymond Waterbury, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505474h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666903m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zj757</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Financing water infrastructure has been increasingly identified as a constraint to reaching the Millennium Development Goals for developing countries' water sectors and a significant area in which potential exists to develop sustainable financing is through the design of appropriate tariff policies. This thesis examines in detail the demand for water service improvements by analysing the willingness to pay for such improvements in Trinidad and Tobago. The basis for the work is a household sample survey conducted in 2003 which assessed the current quality of service and attitudes towards changing the status quo situation. The survey of 1419 households showed that services are poorer than officially stated, and that in response many households have opted for private coping solutions to mitigate the poor service levels of the utility. Choice experiments, which have only limited previous application in the sector, are employed to develop attribute based utility models describing the welfare effects of service level changes, in addition to the more commonly used contingent valuation method. A rigorous comparison of the two methods is developed. It provides evidence that the choice experiment methodology has benefits for policy analysis around the willingness to pay for service changes in the water sector. An analysis of proposed marginal cost based tariffs in Trinidad, as a part of wider sector reforms, is used as a case study for the policy applications of the choice experiment based willingness to pay data. Consumers are willing to pay for investments in water infrastructure, provided that they impact upon the actual service received. Marginal cost based tariffs might be socially unacceptable given that whilst significant, the willingness to pay, given likely service changes associated with planned investments by the Trinidadian water utility, for service changes is not sufficient to cover this economically efficient level of tariff.</description><creator>Virjee, Kameel.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Sanitary and Municipal.</subject><title>Willingness to pay for change : the use of contingent valuation and choice experiments in the Trinidad and Tobago water services sector</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Kameel Virjee, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns064993m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zj757</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d504rq47b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents methods and practical implementations for compensating or suppressing signal distortions induced by fiber nonlinearity in long-distance transmissions. Our methods take advantage of the availability and already wide deployment of dispersion-compensating fibers with various choices of dispersions and dispersion slopes. The basic principle behind the methods is to choose suitable fibers and to arrange them properly into transmission lines manifesting scaled symmetries. Based on the nonlinear Schrodinger equation which describes the nonlinear and dispersive signal propagation in optical fibers, we have shown analytically that a scaled symmetry renders the nonlinear signal distortion by the first part of a transmission line to be largely undone by the second part, when an optical phase conjugator is installed in the middle of the line. Without a phase conjugator, the most detrimental nonlinear interactions among pulses within a wavelength channel may be significantly suppressed in a scaled symmetric line. We have identified two types of scaled symmetries: mirror and translation. Although mirror-symmetric systems have been discussed by other authors before, our own proposals and designs using high-dispersion fibers in conjunction with distributive Raman or erbium-doped amplification could make practical transmission systems manifesting nearly perfect mirror symmetries in the scaled sense and hence excellent nonlinear compensations. Firstly noted and investigated thoroughly by us, the concept of scaled translation symmetries in transmission lines may well spur the adoption of nonlinear compensation methods in practical transmission systems, since distributive amplifiers are no longer necessary for translation symmetries. To support our mathematical analyses, extensive computer simulations have been carried out to validate the effectiveness of our proposed systems, most of which assume practical system setups and parameters and could therefore serve as paradigms for real system designs.</description><creator>Wei, Haiqing, 1970-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Symmetry &amp; nonlinear compensation in fiber-optic transmissions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Haiqing Wei, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zn03b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rq47b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90f043b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In China, higher vocational education (HVE) is a specific educational form in terms of its the educational goals, management structure, and close relationship with the economy. During the past quarter century, China has experienced not only a substantial increase in economic progress, but also the influence of globalization on its political, socio-economic, and educational development. This thesis examines how HVE has changed since the emergence of a socialist market economy (SME) in 1992. It interprets the relationship between globalization and HVE in terms of actual changes that have occurred at the Vocational College of Shanghai Jiaotong University (VCSJTU). The thesis is significant for three reasons. First, it generates useful insights into the process of HVE policy implementation in China since its economic transformation in the early 1990s, and interprets the relationship between globalization, SME, and HVE. The case study also generates insights which can contribute to understanding HVE policy on learning in relation to the context of the economic situation within China and the impact of globalization. Second, the thesis puts special emphasis on analyzing the culture and value changes in VCSJTU since its foundation and explores the deep roots between different values and their implications for people's understanding and appreciation of globalization in the school context. Third, the academic contributions of this case study include theoretical frames of reference on culture, education, and economic globalization. In particular, the study outlines and analyzes (with reflections) the experience gained during the internal economic transformations within China---an analysis which contributes to the international sociology of education, to an understanding of the values within education in relation to the impact of globalization.</description><creator>Wang, Molin, 1975-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>China -- Economic conditions -- 2000-</subject><subject>Vocational education -- China.</subject><subject>Education, Higher -- China.</subject><subject>Globalization.</subject><subject>China -- Economic conditions -- 1976-2000.</subject><title>Globalization and higher vocational education (HVE) in China : a case study in Shanghai</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Molin Wang, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712mc09w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90f043b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70n0508</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since the late 19th century, scientists and clinicians have generated an astonishing array of meters, scales, experimental designs, and questionnaires to quantify pain with more precision, accuracy, and objectivity. In this thesis, I follow the development and implementation of pain-measuring technologies in the United States until the mid-1970s. Focussing on how these technologies work, I analyse the relationship between practices of objectification; the social, material and technical resources on which these practices depend; and changing conceptions of pain, subjectivity and objectivity. Surprisingly, as efforts to objectify pain were intensified, pain was increasingly conceptualised as a subjective experience, that is, as a phenomenon inextricably tied to the unique emotional, psychological, and social condition of the experiencing self. I argue that this transformation was not solely due to the development of new theoretical models of pain, but also, importantly, enabled by the implementation of new technologies that could measure pain as an individual and psychological phenomenon. I also argue that the successful implementation of these technologies depended on the availability of specific social, material, and technical resources, and examine the social settings in which these resources were made available. The main motivation for the direct investment of new resources towards pain-measuring technologies was a desire to make analgesic drug testing more objective. Beginning in the late 1930s, professional, industrial and public health interests in drug addiction, opiate pharmacology, new drug development and therapeutic testing converged on the goal of better pain-measurement. By the 1950s, the organisation and funding of analgesic testing made it possible to implement and validate the analgesic clinical trial, a technology that determined analgesic efficacy by measuring collective pain and its relief. The validity of the clinical was based on procedural and statistical control of data collection and analysis, rather than on the standardisation of individual experiences and evaluations of pain. It became possible to think of pain relief as an inevitably idiosyncratic experience, open to multiple sources of psychological variation, and yet still measure it consistently and objectively on a collective level. Keywords. pain; measurement; objectivity; subjectivity, clinical trials; analgesics: psychophysics; psychosomatics; history of medicine; history of science.</description><creator>Tousignant, Noémi R.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Technology -- United States -- History.</subject><subject>Pain -- Measurement -- United States -- History.</subject><title>Pain and the pursuit of objectivity : pain-measuring technologies in the United States, c1890-1975</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Noémi R. Tousignant, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xx186.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70n0508</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149t82x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Audio signal processing systems for converting two-channel (stereo) recordings to four or five channels are increasingly relevant. These audio upmixers can be used with conventional stereo sound recordings and reproduced with multichannel home theatre or automotive loudspeaker audio systems to create a more engaging and natural-sounding listening experience. This dissertation discusses existing approaches to audio upmixing for recordings of musical performances and presents specific design criteria for a system to enhance spatial sound quality. A new upmixing system is proposed and evaluated according to these criteria and a theoretical model for its behavior is validated using empirical measurements. The new system removes short-term correlated components from two electronic audio signals using a pair of adaptive filters, updated according to a frequency domain implementation of the normalized-least-means-square algorithm. The major difference of the new system with all extant audio upmixers is that unsupervised time-alignment of the input signals (typically, by up to +/-10 ms) as a function of frequency (typically, using a 1024-band equalizer) is accomplished due to the non-minimum phase adaptive filter. Two new signals are created from the weighted difference of the inputs, and are then radiated with two loudspeakers behind the listener. According to the consensus in the literature on the effect of interaural correlation on auditory image formation, the self-orthogonalizing properties of the algorithm ensure minimal distortion of the frontal source imagery and natural-sounding, enveloping reverberance (ambiance) imagery. Performance evaluation of the new upmix system was accomplished in two ways: Firstly, using empirical electroacoustic measurements which validate a theoretical model of the system; and secondly, with formal listening tests which investigated auditory spatial imagery with a graphical mapping tool and a preference experiment. Both electroacoustic and subjective methods investigated system performance with a variety of test stimuli for solo musical performances reproduced using a loudspeaker in an orchestral concert-hall and recorded using different microphone techniques. The objective and subjective evaluations combined with a comparative study with two commercial systems demonstrate that the proposed system provides a new, computationally practical, high sound quality solution to upmixing.</description><creator>Usher, John S.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Surround-sound systems.</subject><subject>Sound -- Recording and producing.</subject><subject>Music -- Acoustics and physics.</subject><subject>Acoustical engineering.</subject><title>Subjective evaluation and electroacoustic theoretical validation of a new approach to audio upmixing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© John S. Usher, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vw193.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149t82x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440x86c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Metalloproteinases (MPs) include the families of matrix metalloproteinases (MMPs) and metalloproteinase-disintegrins (ADAMS). MPs are implicated in multiple sclerosis (MS) and experimental autoimmune encephalomyelitis (EAE), an animal model of MS. Both MS and EAE involve central nervous system (CNS) infiltration, microglial activation, and expression of chemokines and cytokines including CC chemokine ligand 2 (CCL2) and interferon-gamma (IFNgamma). MPs mediate cellular infiltration of the CNS parenchyma and regulate activity of chemokines and cytokines. This thesis describes studies of MPs in EAE and other animal models of neuroinflammation. Gene expression of the majority of MPs was upregulated in the CNS of mice with EAE. In contrast, four of the six membrane-bound MMPs (MT-MMPs) were downregulated. MMP-8, MMP-10, MMP-12, ADAM-12, TIMP-1, and all MT-MMPs were selected for further analysis. Macrophages were identified as a major source of MMP-12 and the tissue inhibitor of MPs-1 (TIMP-1), and granulocytes as a major source of MMP-8. ADAM-12 was expressed primarily by T cells. All but one of the MT-MMPs were expressed by microglia, and three MT-MMPs were downregulated by microglia in EAE. Five of the MT-MMPs were downregulated in transgenic mice overexpressing IFNgamma specifically in the CNS. MPs were also regulated in non-immune models of CNS infiltration that did not involve production of IFNgamma. After entorhinal cortex stab lesion, which results in prominent influx of leukocytes to the injured area, three MT-MMPs were significantly downregulated. In transgenic (Tg) mice that overexpress CCL2 specifically in the CNS, leukocytes spontaneously cross the endothelial basement membrane of the blood-brain barrier (BBB) and accumulate in the perivascular space surrounding CNS vessels, but the mice do not show clinical symptoms. Pertussis toxin (PTx) given intraperitoneally induced encephalopathy and weight loss in CCL2 Tg mice. This involved leukocyte migration across the glia limitans into the brain parenchyma. PTx induced expression of TIMP-1, ADAM-12 and MMPs 8 and 10 in brains of CCL2 Tg mice, whereas there was no significant change in expression of MT-MMPs. Weight loss and parenchymal infiltration induced by PTx were significantly inhibited by the broad-spectrum MP inhibitor BB-94/Batimastat. These studies identify cellular sources of MPs in neuroinflammation and links stages of cellular CNS infiltration to distinct MP profiles.</description><creator>Toft-Hansen, Henrik.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Metalloproteinases in neuroinflammation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Henrik Toft-Hansen, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s4451.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440x86c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54ks25r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this dissertation I develop and theorize an approach to Shakespearean character. I focus on the ways in which characters talk about knowing others and being known; in other words, this is an approach to characters who are themselves approaching characters. The plays I treat in detail are Coriolanus and Hamlet. The words characters in these plays use when they explain their decisions, avoid explaining their decisions, talk about others' decisions, or try to expose others' secrets, are often position-and-movement words. I argue that characters use for these purposes words related by wordplay to the postures and gestures involved in crucial rituals (the "custom of request" in Coriolanus, the fencing match in Hamlet). At the same time, this is a metacritical project: I deal with approaches and attitudes of Shakespeare interpreters. How do we stand in relation to each other? How do editors and critics echo and transform the characters' postural/gestural language, and what are the implications of these echoes and transformations? Why is it worthwhile to work toward awareness of these echoes and transformations? In an extensive introductory section I theorize the kind of reading practiced here as an ethical practice-a practice intended to modify what Michel Foucault calls the rapport a soi. The project's main original contribution is its way of re-conceiving the relationships among several currents in Shakespeare studies. My discussion engages with recent work in textual studies. Examples include work by Leah Marcus and Paul Werstine. It also engages with historically informed treatments of wordplay. Examples include work by Margreta de Grazia and Patricia Parker. And it addresses work that could be said to be part of a move in the field toward "ethical criticism." Examples include work by Stanley Cavell and John Guillory. As well, my discussion engages with psychoanalytic criticism by Marjorie Garber, Coppelia Kahn, and others. While I do not consider myself a psychoanalytic critic, the affinity my approach has with psychoanalysis has to do with my interest in making explicit some of the implications of unreflectively chosen metaphors, word associations, etc. The implications that concern me most are those that have to do with the ways interpreters relate to each other.</description><creator>Travis, Keira.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616 -- Characters.</subject><subject>Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Infinite gesture : an approach to Shakespearean character</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Keira Travis, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c6712.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54ks25r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8p58pj14c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Milk proteins represent an important source of protein ingredients due to their distinctive physico-chemical, nutritional, technological and functional properties. Casein content of milk represents about 80% of milk proteins. The distinguishing property of phosphorylation provides important properties to caseins. The objectives of this research were to investigate enzymatic dephosphorylation of caseins, to characterize products of dephosphorylation and to examine the effects of dephosphorylation on biological properties of caseins. Bovine whole casein, alpha-casein and beta-casein were dephosphorylated with potato acid phosphatase; optimum dephosphorylation conditions were 37°C, pH 5.8 for 6 h. The extents of dephosphorylation accounted for 71.6, 89.2 and 73.7% for whole casein, alpha-casein and beta-casein, respectively. The apparent Vmax and apparent K m for dephosphorylation of whole casein were 0.283 mumol P/mg casein min and 9.951 mg casein/l, respectively. SDS-alphaPAGE, urea-PAGE, RP-HPLC and ESI-MS demonstrated effects of dephosphorylation on the caseins. Urea-PAGE and ESI-MS confirmed the identities of the individual fractions. ESI-MS established (a) the molecular weight for alpha-casein and beta-casein as 23, 612 and 24, 017 Da, respectively; (b) random removal of 1, 2, 4, 6, 7 and 8 phosphate groups from alpha-casein and 1, 2, 3, 4 and 5 phosphate groups from beta-casein and (c) effects of incubation conditions. The effects of dephosphorylation of alpha-casein and beta-casein on the action of pepsin and trypsin were evaluated. Peptide mapping by RP-HPLC indicated that both proteases generated a complex mixture of peptides, with dephosphorylated peptides showing an increase in retention time. LC-ESI-MS and MS/MS in conjunction with the use of advanced bioinformatics software resulted in the identification of the peptides generated. Dephosphorylated alpha-casein and beta-casein showed the presence of peptides in which phosphate groups were removed, and were not observed in peptides from the corresponding native protein. Several of the peptides identified contained sequences that have been reported to be biologically active. Residual allergenicity of dephosphorylated whole casein, alpha-casein and beta-casein as well as peptic and tryptic products of these caseins was determined by an ELISA technique. The results demonstrated that removal of phosphate groups from whole casein, alpha-casein and beta-casein reduced allergenicity by 33, 31.2 and 24.4%, respectively. Proteolysis and dephosphorylation resulted in a significantly (p &lt; 0.05) higher reduction in the antigen-antibody binding capacity compared to non-hydrolyzed and non-dephosphorylated caseins, particularly in the highly allergenic alpha-casein.</description><creator>Tezcucano Molino, Aline C.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Casein.</subject><title>Effects of enzymatic dephosphorylation on properties of bovine casein</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Aline C. Tezcucano Molino, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80j082s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pj14c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b765h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Air-Assisted Solvent Extraction (AASX) is a novel concept that uses a solvent-coated bubble to contact the organic and aqueous phases. The advantages over conventional solvent extraction (SX) are high solvent to aqueous contact area with reduced solvent volume and ease of phase separation due to the buoyancy imparted by the air core. This opens the way to treat dilute solutions (&lt;1 g/L), such as effluents. The novel contribution in this thesis is the production of solvent-coated bubbles by exploiting foaming properties of kerosene-based solvents. The basic set-up is a chamber to generate foam which is injected through a capillary (orifice diameter 2.5 mm) to produce solvent-coated bubbles (ca. 4.4 mm) which release into the aqueous phase. This generates a solvent specific surface area of ca. 3000 cm-1, equivalent to solvent droplets of ca. 20 mum. Demonstrating the process on dilute Cu solutions (down to 25 mg/L), high aqueous/organic ratios (ca. 75:1) and extractions are achieved. The solvent readily disengages to accumulate at the surface of the aqueous solution. The LIX family of extractants imparts some foaming to kerosene based solvents but D2EHPA does not. An extensive experimental program determined that 1.5 ppm silicone oil provided the necessary foaming action without affecting extraction or stripping efficiency, greatly expanding the range of solvents that can be used in AASX. To complement the foam study, films on bubbles blown in solvent were examined by interferometry (film thickness) and infra-red spectroscopy (film composition). A "bound" solvent layer was identified with an initial thickness of ca. 2 - 4 mum, comparable to that determined indirectly (by counting bubbles in an AASX trial and measuring solvent consumption). The film composition appeared to be independent of film thickness as it decreased with time. As a start to scaling up, the single bubble generation system was adapted by installing up to 8 horizontal capillaries. The bubbles generated were ca. 3.4 mm. Trials showed the multi-bubble set up was a simple replication of the individual bubble case. Preliminary analysis of kinetic data shows a fit to a first-order model.</description><creator>Tarkan, Haci Mustafa.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Air-assisted solvent extraction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Haci Mustafa Tarkan, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cz50c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b765h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53x1141</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The swelling behavior of thin polyelectrolyte multilayers assembled from poly(allylamine hydrochloride) (PAH) and poly(acrylic acid) (PAA) under various pH and environmental conditions was characterized in real time by in situ single wavelength ellipsometry. Both the rates and extent of swelling were found to be independent of the solution environment, yet they depended strongly on the solution pH under which the layers were fabricated. The ambient humidity strongly influenced the rate of swelling, where a change by as little as 20% prior to swelling with bulk solution lead to a variation from seconds to tens of minutes to reach the final swollen thickness. Neutron reflectivity studies revealed that water is distributed asymmetrically within the multilayer, and preferentially localizes at the polymer surface, and explains the unusual effect of humidity on the swelling kinetics. The effect of solution pH and salt ions on the water distribution in the multilayer was also investigated by neutron reflectivity. Exposure to both pH and salt solutions increased water content in the film. These studies indicate that the water localizes asymmetrically in the film and predominantly segregates near the substrate when exposed to salt solutions and the distribution of salt ions also increases near the substrate region. Finally, the light-induced expansion of thin films of polymers containing azobenzene chromophores and copolymers of PAA was characterized in real time by single wavelength ellipsometry. An initial expansion of the azo polymer films was found to be irreversible and with repeated irradiation cycles the expansion becomes reversible. Modulating either the pump beam power or the duration of irradiation gave control over the extent of the reversible expansion. This represents the first discovery of the photo-mechanical effect in azobenzene polymers, and in principle now allows these materials to be developed as reversible photo-actuation systems.</description><creator>Tanchak, Oleh.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Swelling and photo-expansion of polyelectrolyte thin films</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Oleh Tanchak, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128g226.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53x1141</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj430894m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Declarative learning entails the internalization of facts and events. This type of learning depends on the integrity of the hippocampal system. In rodents, spatial learning is studied as a model of declarative learning. In this thesis, electrophysiological and behavioral experiments assessed the role of NMDA receptors in synaptic plasticity and rats' spatial learning and memory. Primed burst potentiation (PBP), a form of synaptic strengthening, was studied in freely-behaving rats treated with NMDA receptor antagonists. The impairments caused by the antagonists correlated with those observed in behavioral studies. The results support the idea that NMDA receptors in the hippocampal system mediate the internalization of the contents and organization of new environmental information, and show that the receptors are not relevant for spatial working memory or performance once a representation of the environment is stable. The results also suggest that stable spatial representations resemble multiple relations of events and do not correspond to topographical maps of an environment. As learning proceeds, representations are activated by smaller subsets of environmental cues, which eventually become sufficient for effective navigation. The representations thus are encoded as relationships of stimuli that share similarities or that are unique to a particular event. The organization of novel information is given through NMDA receptor-mediated synaptic plasticity. This plasticity mechanism could resemble a process similar to the synaptic changes observed during PBP.</description><creator>Tirado Santiago, Giovanni.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Methyl aspartate.</subject><subject>Rats -- Physiology.</subject><subject>Learning -- Physiological aspects.</subject><title>An investigation of the role of hippocampal NMDA receptors in spatial learning /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Giovanni Tirado Santiago, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246x20s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430894m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qw98d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this study I investigate the influence and reception of Paulo Freire in Indonesia with a specific question in mind: To what extent has Freire influenced educational thought and practice in the country? This study shows that Paulo Freire has been known in Indonesia since the early 1970s, although he was at first familiar only to certain groups. In the 1980s, the discourse and practice of Freirean education was more extensive than in the 1970s, with both domains (discourse and practice) equally balanced. The trend in the 1990s up to 2005 shifted: there was a more extensive discussion of Freire than implementation of his theory and methodology in practice. This study shows that Paulo Freire has left a considerable intellectual legacy to Indonesian educational scholars and practitioners. In fact, his cultural and educational philosophies have become subjects of discussion amongst social activists, educational practitioners and scholars concerned with educational issues. It is no wonder that many articles, books and theses by and on Freire are available in the Indonesian. I would venture to say that no other foreign educational thinker has gained such acceptance in Indonesia. The study explores as well the attempts to connect Freire to Islam---the faith of a majority of Indonesian---demonstrated by the publication of many articles and theses that tried to compare and connect the two. This is, to the best of my knowledge, a new feature in Freirean scholarship. My contention is, however, that any attempt to compare Islam and Freire is likely to fall into apologetic, in the sense that this would only confirm that Islam also insists on the idea of liberation, as Freire did, without trying to analyze why such an idea has never developed in Islamic education. The fact that Islam, since its appearance, has concerned itself with liberation and taking the side of the poor cannot be denied. However, using this fact to legitimate Freire's educational philosophy and practice is less productive, because it does not make a substantive contribution to re-developing and re-structuring Islamic education, which is essentially conservative. Freire in Indonesia is not only influential in the realm of discourse, but in that of practice as well. In this study I investigate the experiences of Indonesian educational practitioners in applying Freire's educational philosophy and methodology to certain discrete groups within the society, namely, villagers in Papua, the rural poor in Maluku Tenggara, workers, peasants, street children, university students, and NGO activists. From my investigation, became clear that it was not Freire's concept of literacy that found favor with Indonesian educational practitioners; rather, it was his vision of education as a means of improving critical capacities within learners and of driving social transformation. No evidence could be found of any group or individuals in Indonesia applying Freire's approach in a systematic way and as a whole; most, rather, mixed this with other concepts, such as community organizing and community development. The positive reception of Freire in Indonesia does not necessarily mean that his thought is accepted blindly or without critique. Several criticisms offered by Indonesian educators of the theories of Paulo Freire are highlighted in this study, although few of them have not been raised before.</description><creator>Nuryatno, Muhammad Agus.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Freire, Paulo, 1921-1997.</subject><subject>Islamic education -- Indonesia.</subject><subject>Education -- Indonesia.</subject><title>Education and social transformation : investigating the influence and reception of Paulo Freire in Indonesia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Muhammad Agus Nuryatno, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jw31n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qw98d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Curriculum and Instruction</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290f78q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>GH acts through its specific receptor, GHR. In the human liver, more than twelve hGHR mRNAs are transcribed from unique TUTR exons, seven of which are found in two small clusters: module A (V2,V9,V3) and module B (V7,V1,V4,V8). While module A mRNAs are ubiquitously expressed, module B transcripts are restricted to normal postnatal liver, suggesting developmental- and liver-specific regulation of the hGHR gene. To begin characterising the elements regulating module B mRNA expression, I studied the promoter region of the V1 exon, the most abundantly expressing variant in liver. A 1.8 kb region upstream of the V1 transcriptional start site (TSS) was actively repressed in transient transfection assays (TTAs). However, T or 3' deletions relieved the suppression, suggesting the presence of multiple negative and positive regulatory elements. Two sites for growth factor independence-1 (Gfi-1) and Gfi-1b and a GAGA element were identified in the most 3' 300 by regulatory region. Gfi-1 was detected by western blot in human foetal and postnatal liver. Gfi-1 and Gfi-lb strongly repressed while the Drosophila GAGA factor (GAF) stimulated V1 transcription through their specific sites, as determined by TTAs and site-directed mutagenesis (SDM). Six putative sites for hepatic nuclear factor-4 (HNF-4) were also identified in the 1.8 kb region. HNF-4alpha is developmentally regulated in human liver: HNF-4alpha,2 and alpha8 proteins are expressed in foetal hepatocytes but only HNF-4alpha2 is detected postnatally. TTAs and SDM demonstrated that HNF-4alpha2 and HNF-4alpha8 have a similar dual effect on V1 transcription: activation via site #1 in the proximal promoter and repression through site #6, ~1.7 kb upstream of the TSS. Results from EMSA/EMSSA/ChIP analyses suggest these sites are bound by HNF-4alpha. Thus, V1 transcriptional activity is repressed by Gfi-1/Gfi-1b, stimulated through a GAGA element by GAF, and repressed or stimulated by HNF-4alpha. (2+8) depending on the site. Similar sites are present in homologous regions of the bovine, ovine and mouse GHR genes suggesting that their regulatory roles are conserved. However, none of these factors individually appear to be responsible for the postnatal hepatic-specific expression of V1 mRNA. To define the specific regulatory mechanisms, future studies should examine their interactions with additional liverenriched factors (e.g. C/EBPalpha).</description><creator>Osafo, Joy Kwakyewaa.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Regulation of the V1 mRNA variant of the human growth hormone receptor gene by Gfi-1, Gfi-1b, a GAGA element and the liver enriched transcription factor, HNF-4[alpha]</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Joy Kwakyewaa Osafo, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386p761.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290f78q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483p43q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis we present a unified framework for planar location-allocation problems with dense demand. Emergence of such information technologies as Geographical Information Systems (GIS) has enabled access to detailed demand information. This proliferation of demand data brings about serious computational challenges for traditional approaches which are based on discrete demand representation. Furthermore, traditional approaches model the problem in location variable space and decide on the allocation decisions optimally given the locations. This is equivalent to prioritizing location decisions. However, when allocation decisions are more decisive or choice of exact locations is a later stage decision, then we need to prioritize allocation decisions. Motivated by these trends and challenges, we herein adopt a modeling and solution approach in the allocation variable space. Our approach has two fundamental characteristics: Demand representation in the form of continuous density functions and allocation decisions in the form of service regions. Accordingly, our framework is based on continuous optimization models and solution methods. On a plane, service regions (allocation decisions) assume different shapes depending on the metric chosen. Hence, this thesis presents separate approaches for two-dimensional Euclidean-metric and Manhattan-metric based distance measures. Further, we can classify the solution approaches of this thesis as constructive and improvement-based procedures. We show that constructive solution approach, namely the shooting algorithm, is an efficient procedure for solving both the single dimensional n-facility and planar 2-facility problems. While constructive solution approach is analogous for both metric cases, improvement approach differs due to the shapes of the service regions. In the Euclidean-metric case, a pair of service regions is separated by a straight line, however, in the Manhattan metric, separation takes place in the shape of three (at most) line segments. For planar 2-facility Euclidean-metric problems, we show that shape preserving transformations (rotation and translation) of a line allows us to design improvement-based solution approaches. Furthermore, we extend this shape preserving transformation concept to n-facility case via vertex-iteration based improvement approach and design first-order and second-order solution methods. In the case of planar 2-facility Manhattan-metric problems, we adopt translation as the shape-preserving transformation for each line segment and develop an improvement-based solution approach. For n-facility case, we provide a hybrid algorithm. Lastly, we provide results of a computational study and complexity results of our vertex-based algorithm.</description><creator>Murat, Ekrem Alper.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Industrial location -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>An allocation based modeling and solution framework for location problems with dense demand /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Ekrem Alper Murat, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xn903.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483p43q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:79408230s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new thermal analysis technique was developed and tested. It makes use of the improvements in heat transfer characteristics associated with recent advances in heat pipe technology. Heat is extracted from a liquid sample of a melt taken in-situ from within a vessel or furnace. The rate of heat extraction is such as to cause the sample to solidify. The technique was tested both in the laboratory and on an industrial scale (Grenville Castings, Perth, Ontario). Aluminum alloys including 356, 319, Al-xSi, Al-Si-Cu-xMg, and 6063 were subjected to various melt treatments and were used to carry out the tests. Classical thermal analysis was also carried out simultaneously under the same melt conditions using a preheated graphite cup. The comparison showed that the new technique has great potential over classical thermal analysis. The major advantages of the new method are that it conducts the analysis inside the melt (since it is no longer necessary for a physical sample to be removed from the melt itself), it consumes less time and the cooling rate can be precisely controlled during the solidification process. Moreover, it produces curves of greater detail and of better resolution than conventional techniques. In fact, the detail is of such resolution that, in some cases, the cooling curves may be used to infer the chemical composition of certain components of the melt, a fact which equates to a form of rapid chemical analysis. The peaks in the signal which refer to intermetallic formation are of better resolution and more identifiable when the new technique is used. The size of the peaks obtained using the new probe is about three times greater than that obtained by the classical method. With this new technique it becomes possible to correlate the area below the intermetallic peak to the concentration of iron or copper in the melt. This is a feature which makes the new thermal analysis probe act as a rapid chemical analyzer for selected constituents.</description><creator>Musmar, Sa'ed Awni.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>In-situ thermal analysis probe</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Sa'ed Awni Musmar, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x7986.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/79408230s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dj52w8879</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:11:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Defects in the cytoskeletal protein dystrophin have been implicated in the pathogenesis of both genetic and acquired forms of cardiomyopathies. In Duchenne muscular dystrophy (DMD), dystrophin-deficiency results in dilated cardiomyopathy, which represents a major cause of mortality in patients with DMD. So far, the role of dystrophin in the heart remains unclear. A better understanding of the mechanisms by which abnormalities in dystrophin integrity induce cardiac dysfunction appears warranted for the effective management and therapy of DMD and other dystrophin-related cardiomyopathies. While gene therapy and the recently documented cardioprotective effects of a membrane sealant in DMD offer new promising therapeutic avenues, the feasibility of these interventions remains to be demonstrated. This project was aimed at better defining the role of dystrophin in the heart. Specifically, it tested the hypothesis that dystrophin plays a crucial role in regulation of cardiac energy metabolism. This hypothesis was formulated on the following basis. First, increasing evidence indicates that metabolic perturbations occur early in the progression of several types of cardiomyopathies, and contribute to disease progression. Second, dystrophin-deficient hearts display perturbations in calcium handling and nitric oxide (NO) signaling, two factors that play a crucial role in the concerted regulation of energy substrate metabolism and contractile function. Finally, pathways that are central to substrate oxidation, such as the mitochondrial citric acid cycle, have been shown to be dependent on cytoskeletal organization. Given the availability of a mouse model for dystrophin deficiency, namely the mdx mouse, our first objective was to setup an experimental methodology allowing dynamic measurements of cardiac substrate energy metabolism using ex vivo perfusions in the working mode and a carbon 13-labeling strategy. We then used this study model to conduct a detailed functional and metabolic phenotyping of the dystrophin-deficient mdx mouse heart at an age, during which no major histological or echocardiographic abnormalities were reported. Our findings highlight the presence of early "sub-clinical" alterations in the energy substrate metabolism of the dystrophin-deficient heart, which could play a role in the subsequent progression to overt myocardial dysfunction and cardiomyocyte damage. Moreover, the pattern of metabolic alterations was suggestive of an altered NO/cGMP pathway. Therefore, the final aim of this thesis project was to evaluate the potential benefits of an intervention that targets this pathway. We show that pharmacological enhancement of the NO/cGMP pathway in the dystrophy-deficient heart mitigates cardiac remodeling and improves the resistance of cardiomyocytes to mechanical injury. This study provides basis for a therapy that could potentially improve cardiac function in patients suffering from Duchenne and Becker muscular dystrophy.</description><creator>Khairallah, Maya.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Myocardial dystrophin-deficiency and its impact on metabolic and nutrient signaling pathways</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Maya Khairallah, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354k49m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w8879</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):41700</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>