<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:45:49Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40625" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77fr63b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis analyses the Mexican legal framework and the public policies implemented by the Mexican government regarding female labour from an international perspective. The position to be argued throughout the thesis is that the Mexican government has not fulfilled its international obligations derived from the treaties and international conventions that directly or indirectly provide for women's labour rights. The thesis proposes a number of legal reforms and public policies that once properly enforced and implemented by the Mexican government would provide for gender equality in the Mexican labour market.</description><creator>Guzmán Lozano, Luz María.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Women -- Employment -- Mexico.</subject><subject>Labor laws and legislation -- North America.</subject><subject>Labor laws and legislation -- Mexico.</subject><subject>Women -- Employment -- North America.</subject><title>Female labour in Mexico : a legal analysis comparing international and domestic law</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Luz María Guzmán Lozano, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w3763703f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fr63b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:00000025v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tumbling mills describe a class of mechanical systems defined by a cylindrical chamber filled with balls and/or rocks that rotate around their own longitudinal axis. Due to the action of charges, the lifters/liners wear significantly and their shape will be changed which will influence the efficiency of the mill. Liner bolts are the mill components which connect the mill interior with the exterior environment. With this property, bolts have been paid more and more attention. The first part of the thesis covers the structural analysis of the lifter/liner bolts, and the possibility for on-line charge motion measurement with the aid of bolts is discussed by comparing the strain distributions at the bolt areas where the bolts occupy different mill circumferential positions. In order to measure the lifter/liner wear, a real-time, on-line wear sensor was developed by the Comminution Dynamics Laboratory. However, the positioning of the sensor/sensors affects the strength of the mill is unknown. The second part of the project provides detailed research on this issue by FEA analysis so as to provide a basis for the practical application of this kind of sensors. Finally, during the grinding process of tumbling mills, some mills can vibrate greatly at some ranges of mill rotating speeds and as a result the mills cannot work properly because of this vibration or resonance. With six different mill models, the final part of the thesis investigates the mill natural frequencies and their modes by FEA and furthermore, explores the effect of mill diameter, length on these frequencies and modes.</description><creator>Quan, Yuyun, 1973-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Finite element analysis of tumbling mill design and operating effects on liner bolt stresses, liner stresses and mill resonance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Yuyun Quan, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676v912.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000025v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05fb905</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Physical and mathematical modelling of fluid flow phenomena play an important role in studies of steel quality associated with the various steps in steelmaking and steel processing operations. In the continuous casting process, the tundish not only serves as an intermediate buffer, but with increasing demands for high quality steel, it has also evolved into a useful reactor for liquid steel refining. It is now a proven fact that a modern tundish is designed to carry out different metallurgical operations such as inclusion separation and floatation, alloy trimming, superheat control, calcium doped inclusion modification, thermal and particulate homogenization. To carry out those operations effectively, certain parameters like Residence Time Distribution (RTD), Residual Ratio of Inclusions (RRI), Slag Entrainment and Vortex formation phenomena are generally studied and optimized using various tundish designs, and flow modification devices. These are usually specific to a given plant practice and to a targeted grade of steel. A full scale physical model of a delta shaped, four strand tundish using water as the simulating fluid for liquid steel was used to study the fluid flow behavior of a 12 t tundish producing aluminium-killed steel billets., The above mentioned parameters were studied to predict the performance of the tundish using two different types of flow modification systems.</description><creator>Ray, Shamik Kumar.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Water modelling studies to predict steel quality in a 4 strand delta-shaped tundish</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Shamik Kumar Ray, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720d06q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fb905</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fx719m704</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A switching strategy mediated by brainstem omni-directional pause neurons (OPNs) is proposed to fuse slow and fast phases of orienting eye and head movements in a model of gaze control. It is implemented in the anatomically based model developed by Galiana and Guitton (1992) where slow and fast components of gaze are represented as two different operating modalities of the same neural circuit. No comprehensive mechanism for alternating between the two modes of operation yet exists; it is in fact one of the least understood aspects of oculomotor control. Switching strategies that are implemented in existing models are usually designed artificially just to obtain a desired system response. The mechanism presented in this thesis employs a linear weighted sum of three anatomically relevant inputs to OPNs; gaze motor error, head velocity and eye velocity. It is designed to accurately decide when one phase should be ended and the other initiated in all types of behaviorally observed gaze movements. Simulated performance reveals that the implemented switching mechanism compels the model to respond appropriately to both visual and vestibular stimuli.</description><creator>Prsa, Mario.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Fusing slow and fast phases in a model of combined eye and head movements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Mario Prsa, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q1750.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719m704</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj430494s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Electron microscopy (EM) is an important tool in organellar proteomics, where it is used to validate sample purity and to confirm protein presence. Current sample preparation techniques are manual, labor-intensive and time-consuming. To overcome these problems, an electron microscopy proteomic organellar preparation (EMPOP) robot is being developed for parallel preparation of up to 96 subcellular fraction samples in an efficient, repeatable and standardized manner. This thesis describes the development and validation of the software that controls the EMPOP robot. The software was organized in two coordinated levels consisting of a: (1) human-machine interface (HMI), and (2) low-level real-time control routines. The HMI was designed to be 'friendly and flexible', and to enable the operator to modify system parameters on-the-fly. Contrarily, the low-level control routines are responsible for controlling all EMPOP system processes. Pilot studies using the EMPOP system prove that the robot and software function predictably and consistently to generate high quality subcellular sample fractions.</description><creator>Punwani, Karishma.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Automated control of the electron microscopy proteomic organellar preparation robot</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Karishma Punwani, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w0093.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430494s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dv821</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Earlier work with the dibenzoate plasticizers, di(propylene-glycol) dibenzoate (D(PG)DB) and di(ethylene-glycol) dibenzoate (D(EG)DB), had shown that one yeast could hydrolyze one of the ester bonds of these compounds resulting in an accumulation of the monoesters, di(propylene-glycol) monobenzoate or di(ethylene-glycol) monobenzoate, respectively. These monoesters exhibited an acute toxicity greater than that of the parent compounds and greater than the metabolites of the widely used phthalate and adipate plasticizers. In the present study, it was shown that the degradation of dibenzoate plasticizers is a common phenomenon among soil microorganisms. In most examples, the degradation was incomplete leading to the accumulation of the expected monoesters. However, the biodegradation of these monoesters was shown to be possible even if the rates of biodegradation were much slower than the rates of hydrolysis of the parent compounds. In addition, it was found that di(ethylene-glycol) monobenzoate was easier to biodegrade than di(propylene-glycol) monobenzoate. This difference was attributed to the methyl substituents on the di(propylene-glycol) monobenzoate. The very fast rates of degradation of simpler benzoate esters such as methyl and ethyl benzoate confirmed that steric effects could be important. The rate of biodegradation of 1,6-hexanediol dibenzoate was much faster than that of either of the dibenzoate plasticizers. From this, it was hypothesized that the stability of the monoesters of the plasticizers was due to the presence of an ether function. It was also shown that the presence of the monoester of D(PG)DB was shown to increase the rate of hydrolysis of the parent di-ester. This was attributed to the ability of the monoester to enhance the bioavailability di-ester. Collectively, these results do not support the use of dibenzoate plasticizers as environmentally friendly alternatives to phthalate and adipate plasticizers.</description><creator>Lahdou, Gilbert.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Microbial degradation of dibenzoate plasticizers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Gilbert Lahdou, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sd09f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dv821</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:js956g116</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Lactococcus lactis are intensely being studied for the oral delivery of vaccines and other therapeutics to the mucosa of the gastrointesintal tract (GIT). In this thesis, we explore a new development by applying microencapsulation technology. A comparative study of the viability and protein secretion of free and alginate-poly-l-lysine-alginate (APA) encapsulated engineered L. lactis has demonstrated the effectiveness of this new system. The viability of microcapsules in in vitro culture conditions and simulated gastrointestinal (SGI) environments was also investigated. The latter condition exhibited inferior survival, and the attributing factors were identified. Subsequently, a novel system for the sustained delivery of a single-chain variable fragment (scFv) antibody targeting the human pathogen Helicobacter pylori has been developed using microencapsulated genetically engineered L. lactis cells. Studies herein demonstrate the sustained viability and protein secretion of the system showing the therapeutic potential to this approach. Additional studies are required, specifically, in vivo evaluation in experimental animals.</description><creator>Lawuyi, Olabisi.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>A novel approach to oral therapy : preparation and in vitro analysis of microencapsulated engineered Lactococcus lactis cells secreting heterologous proteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Olabisi Lawuyi, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jx28q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956g116</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t205z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This investigation was focused on the in vitro metabolism of DEHA, DEHP and other common plasticizers by mammalian cell lines. The metabolic products and cell viability of hepatocytes (mouse and human) and human umbilical endothelial cells exposed to plasticizers was investigated in static culture. Gas chromatography and mass spectrometry showed that all of the plasticizers investigated were partially degraded, but at differing rates, depending on the plasticizer and cell line. Solubility and stearic effects were found to play important roles in determining the rate of hydrolysis. The only metabolic product observed was 2-ethyl hexanol, which accumulated in culture. This was due to the lack of alcohol dehydrogenase production in the human hepatocyte cell line used. Hepatocyte cell viability was not significantly affected at 4 days of exposure to DEHA. By 12 days, only 50% of the cells remained viable when compared to control experiments. These results suggest that the accumulation of plasticizers metabolites, specifically 2-ethyl hexanol, may have potentially toxic effects.</description><creator>Korsieporn, Pira.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Interaction of plasticizers with mammalian cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Pira Korsieporn, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qm316.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t205z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xp68kg53w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The development of a new angioplasty balloon from a new material can be a long and arduous process that may take months. These balloons must meet some very stringent requirements such as high rated burst pressure with minimal wall thickness. The purpose of this thesis is to help reduce the amount of time invested in the experimental development stages of these medical balloons. This can be achieved with the aid of a cycle-to-cycle controller. The controller presented here may be simplistic, but it has shown that with further testing and modeling, it has the potential to completely replace the trial-and-error method of balloon development in use today.</description><creator>Lalli, Dominic.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Cycle-to-cycle control of the angioplasty balloon fabrication process</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Dominic Lalli, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55mc356.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kg53w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085k27w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis reports on research, performed at McGill University, on the experimental responses of four deep beams forming part of a larger research program involving eight deep beams. The other four beams are reported by BouSaleh (2006). The beams reported in this thesis were tested in an attempt to obtain crushing at the support nodal zones through the provisions of inadequate bearing area for beams with different tension tie anchorage details. In order to study the influence of different anchorages of the main tension tie, the beams were designed with the same strut-and-tie model in accordance with the CSA Standard (2004). The four full-scale simply supported deep beams had similar dimensions of 1000 mm in height, 350 mm in thickness, and a span of 2000 mm centre-to-centre between the supports. The four beams contained two layers of five 15M reinforcement. However, the length of each specimen varied according to the different anchorage details. The tension tie reinforcement anchored by straight bar embedment resulted in the longest beam. Identical overall lengths were provided for the specimens anchored using 90° standard hooks and friction-welded headed bars of head size 1.5 in. (38 mm). Finally, the shortest beam was anchored using friction welded headed bars of 2 in. (50 mm) head size. The beam containing hooked anchorages performed better than the beam with straight bar embedment, with higher capacity and ductility. The reduced head size friction-welded headed bars, further anchored with a lead-in length, resulted in a higher nodal zone bearing stresses, better confinement for the concrete and higher ductility compared to the straight bar embedment and the hooked anchorage. The friction-welded headed bars having heads with an area equal to ten times the bar area not only reduced the length of the beam significantly and were capable of developing the full yield strength of the bar at the inner side of the head. The beam with full size heads achieved a higher capacity than the beam with the straight bar embedment and reached about the same capacity as the beam with hooked end anchorage. This research also demonstrates the beneficial effect of the confining transverse pressure provided at the support nodal zones by the support reactions, in improving the bond. This effect resulted in higher bar stresses than those predicted using the CSA and ACI code development length expressions.</description><creator>El-Jorf, Rula Refat.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Study of support bearing details on response of deep beams</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Rula Refat El-Jorf, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s1616474.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085k27w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386j43n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Glass Fibre Reinforced Plastic (GFRP) composite structures are increasingly used in waterfront and marine environments due to their corrosion resistance. While the GFRP materials have demonstrated excellent tensile capacities, they also present quite low elastic moduli compared to steel. Consequently, local buckling and excessive deflection are always performance-limiting factors in design of thin-walled composite structures that use low-tech FRP. The research reported herein is focused on the buckling and deformation analysis of a pultruded sheet pile wall subjected to uniformly distributed load and harsh environmental exposures. Prior to structural analysis, material properties of the composite sheet pile were determined by coupon tests. A finite element ABAQUS model was introduced and validated by comparison with full-scale experimental test data. The prebuckling, buckling and postbuckling behaviour were evaluated and the failure mode identified. In order to enhance the load bearing capacity and reduce the deflection of the sheet pile panel, new profiles were proposed: the purpose was to increase the local buckling load and enhance the stiffness. Adding stiffeners at the junctions between the different section plates appeared to be efficient. In order to study the durability of the FRP sheet piles under different service conditions, the effects of five environmental exposures on the structural performances were studied: they were freezing, freezing/thawing, wet environment, wet and freezing and wet and freezing/thawing conditions. The elastic moduli were found to be unaffected whereas reductions in the strength were observed. As a result, there was no noticeable change in the buckling load and deflection but significant decrease in ultimate failure load. Maximum loss in load capacity due to moisture uptake and freeze/thaw cycles was found to be about 23%.</description><creator>Darchis, Fabien.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Finite element analysis of composite sheet piles subjected to uniform load and harsh environments</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Fabien Darchis, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr171x534.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386j43n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8p58pd21z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Hearing loss is the third leading chronic disability after arthritis and hypertension, and the most frequent birth defect. Non-invasive diagnoses and middle-ear prostheses are often unsatisfactory, partly because of a lack of understanding of middle-ear mechanics. The focus of this thesis is to develop a 3-D finite-element model to quantify the mechanics of the gerbil middle ear. An MRM dataset with a voxel size of 45 µm, and an x-ray micro-CT dataset with a voxel size of 5 um, supplemented by histological images, are the basis for 3-D reconstruction and finite-element mesh generation. The eardrum model is based on moire shape measurements. The material properties of all the structures in the model are based on a priori estimates from the literature. The behaviour of the finite-element model in response to a static pressure of 1 Pa is analyzed. Overall, the model demonstrates good agreement with low-frequency experimental data. For example, (1) the ossicular ratio is found to be about 3.5; (2) maximum footplate displacements are about 34.2 run +/- 0.04 nm; (3) the motion of the stapes is predominantly piston-like; (4) the displacement pattern of the eardrum shows two points of maximum displacements, one in the posterior region and one in the anterior region. The results also include a series of sensitivity tests to evaluate the significance of the different parameters in the finite-element model. Finally, in an attempt to understand how the overall middle-ear mechanics is influenced by the anterior mallear ligament and the posterior incudal ligament, results are shown for cutting or stiffening the ligaments.</description><creator>Elkhouri, Nidal.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Finite-element modelling of the gerbil middle ear</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Nidal Elkhouri, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892b079.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pd21z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cb10b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tissue engineering requires diagnostic tools for in-vitro monitoring of cell proliferation in three-dimensional scaffolds. Current methods are inaccurate, prohibitively expensive, or compromise sample integrity. This work presents a nondestructive system for the on-line measurement of cell concentration in micro-porous polymer scaffolds. The system is based on measuring the reflection coefficient of the sample with an open-ended coaxial probe over a frequency range of 10-200 MHz. An aperture admittance model is used to extract the complex permittivity from the reflection measurement. Then, effective medium approximation is used to relate the complex permittivity to the cell properties and concentration of the sample. The system detected the relative cell concentration differences between micro-porous polymer scaffolds seeded with progressively greater number of pre-osteoblast cells. Proliferation of pre-ostoblasts over 14 days was measured within 56 scaffolds by the system and a concurrent DNA assay. The recorded cell proliferation data corresponded well to each other and those found in literature. Thus, the system can be applied for on-line monitoring of cell proliferation within micro-porous polymer scaffolds.</description><creator>Dziong, Dariusz.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>Nondestructive on-line measurement system for in-vitro cell proliferation in microporous polymer scaffolds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Dariusz Dziong, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784m11m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cb10b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289j75p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The role of nerve growth factor (NGF), a neurotrophic molecule, and its high-affinity receptor in intact and injured adult rat lumbar sensory neurons was examined at a cellular level using quantitative receptor radioautography to localize the NGF high-affinity receptor-positive subpopulation, in conjunction with histochemistry on adjacent sections. The 40-50% of sensory neurons displaying NGF receptors were characterized. Virtually all neurons containing substance P or CGRP were NGF receptor-positive, but not those with somatostatin or thiamine monophosphatase activity. The ability of a neuron to bind NGF with high-affinity correlates positively with growth-associated protein (GAP43) expression but not with neurofilament (NFM) expression. Following injury, sensory neurons atrophy, lose NGF receptors, decrease NFM expression, while GAP43 expression is elevated in all neurons irrespective of their ability to bind NGF. Infusion of NGF for 1 week, at the time of injury or 3 weeks following injury counteracts NGF receptor loss, cell atrophy, and decreased NFM expression, but only in those neurons bearing NGF receptors. GAP43 expression remained high in all neurons despite infusion. NGF's function in normal sensory neurons appears to be modulatory, permitting regulation of intrinsic properties. Injury disrupts this permissive state, which can be restored with exogenous NGF.</description><creator>Verge, Valerie Mary Kathleen</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Properties of intact and injured sensory neurons with nerve growth factor receptors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117p57v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289j75p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gk562</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Duplan strain of Radiation Leukemia Virus (RadLV) induces an AIDS-like syndrome when injected intraperitoneally into adult C57BL/6 mice. The mice develop T cell depletion, polyclonal B cell proliferation (lymphadenopathy, splenomegaly), hypergammaglobulinemia, and immune deficiency. This syndrome has recently been designated MAIDS (murine acquired immunodeficiency syndrome). This virus preparation, passaged in vivo, is crude and known to contain different strains of retroviruses. To identify the etiologic agent of this disease, we first infected fibroblasts in vitro with this crude virus mixture. Supernatants of these cultures induced disease. Unintegrated viral DNA from fibroblasts newly-infected with this virus preparation was extracted by the Hirt supernatant method and analysed with various viral probes: 8.8 and 4.8 kb DNA species were detected and molecularly cloned in pUC 18 (clones Du9S and Du5H, respectively). An unique DNA sequence derived from the gag region of the defective Du5H genome did not hybridize to various other retroviral DNA's (Moloney MuLV, N-Cl-35 or Du9S). The restriction of Du9S is similar to the map of other RadLV's. The defective Du5H DNA was transfected into fibroblasts in the presence of the neomycin resistance gene and rescued with the non-leukemogenic ecotropic RadLV (G6T2). This virus complex, as well as the ecotropic virus alone, were inoculated into C57BL/6 mice to test their pathogenic potential. The rescued cloned defective virus caused MAIDS, whereas the helper virus (G6T2) alone did not cause disease. Sequence data shows that the defective virus has large deletions in pol and env, and that the gag region is conserved and harbors a novel p12 sequence. This mouse model may help in understanding some important mechanisms underlying the biology of retrovirus-induced immunodeficiency syndromes, such as AIDS.</description><creator>Aziz, Douglas C.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Molecular studies on murine acquired immune deficiency syndrome (MAIDS)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gh09s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gk562</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hq36p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Atrial natriuretic factor (ANF), a 28 amino acid peptide hormone, is the major secretory product of the heart. Because of its diuretic, natriuretic and vasodilating activities, this peptide may be involved in the maintenance of proper fluid and electrolyte balance and blood pressure control. In order to study the transcriptional regulation of ANF, we have isolated the rat ANF gene and we have established a system of cardiocytes in primary cell culture for studies on the hormonal, tissue-specific and developmental regulation of the ANF gene. Using this in vitro system, as have demonstrated that thyroid hormone increases ANF mRNA levels about 2- to 4-fold in atrial and ventricular cells in primary cardiocyte cell cultures, respectively. Similarly, glucocorticoids augment by about 3-fold both atrial and ventricular ANF mRNA levels in cardiac cells in culture. Glucocorticoids exert this effect at the transcriptional level probably via the binding of glucocorticoid receptor to a DNA element in the distal 5$ sp prime$-flanking sequences of the gene as suggested by DNA-mediated transfection studies in cardiocyte cultures. In order to better understand the mechanisms governing the cardiac-specific as well as developmental expression of the ANF gene, we have analyzed ANF promoter sequences by transient transfection studies in primary cardiocyte cultures. Our data show that the ANF promoter is active only in cells of cardiac origin. Moreover, up to $-$1.6 kb of 5$ sp prime$ upstream sequences are necessary for full expression of the ANF gene in cardiac cells. Within these sequences, two particular elements, a proximal and a distal, are necessary for full ANF transcriptional activity. The proximal element can confer cardiac specificity to an otherwise non tissue-specific heterologous promoter. Further upstream sequences, between $-$2.5 and $-$1.6 kb appear to be implicated in the developmental control of ANF gene expression, as assessed by differential activity in 1 and 4 d</description><creator>Argentin, Stefania</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>Transcriptional regulation of the rat atrial natriuretic factor gene</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tc73v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hq36p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4x51hj821</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The time-varying survival rates of the carrot weevil, Listronotus oregonensis, were estimated by a new method. This method precluded the possibility of negative simulation survival rates. Analysis of carrot weevil population dynamics indicated that the egg mortality was density dependent with Anaphes sordidatus, an egg parasitoid, as a major density dependent factor. Larval mortality was less density dependent. Based on the mortality information, a simulation model for carrot weevil population dynamics was established. The simulation precision, evaluated by comparing simulated and observed egg and larval population dynamics, was satisfactory. Sensitivity analysis indicated that A. sordidatus had a large influence on carrot weevil population dynamics. The economic threshold for carrot weevil control in early carrots was 5 eggs/100 carrots at the peak population density. It ranged from 3.8 to 5.3 eggs/100 carrots in mid-season carrots depending on the selling price. A decision model showed that the best sowing date was after June 5 when risks were not considered. For risk aversion growers, sowing carrots between May 20 and May 31 was the best choice.</description><creator>Zhao, Dingxin</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Insect populations -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Carrot weevil -- Integrated control</subject><subject>Carrots -- Diseases and pests -- Integrated control.</subject><title>Mathematical models for the population dynamics and management of the carrot weevil, Listronotus oregonensis (LeConte) (Coleoptera:Curculionidae)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f4188.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hj821</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m039k567h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A family of four low molecular weight peptides, that are rich in arginine and cysteine and which have the ability to inhibit ACTH stimulated adrenocortical steroidogenesis have been purified from rabbit lung and neutrophil extracts and sequenced. They are called corticostatin I (CSI), II (CSII), III (CSIII), and IV (CSIV) respectively. Among them CSI is the most potent with ED$ sb{50}$ of 25 nM against a concentration of 150 pg/ml ACTH stimulation. The mechanism of action of CSI has been studied extensively. CSI shows a high degree of specificity in that it does not inhibit the action of angiotensin II in the adrenal cortex. CSI does not inhibit dbcAMP induced steroidogenesis, however it does inhibit the accumulation of cAMP in response to ACTH in the rat adrenal cell suspension. CSI acts by competing with the basic--Gly$ sb{14}$-Lys$ sb{15}$-Lys$ sb{16}$-Arg$ sb{17}$-Arg$ sb {18}$--sequence of ACTH for its binding site.</description><creator>Zhu, Qinzhang</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Purification, characterization, and biological action of corticostatic peptides</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n203z814.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k567h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sd395</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sesame (Sesamum indicum L.) is a tropical oilseed found growing in the mid-altitude ($&lt;$1700 m.a.s.l.) regions of Ethiopia. Recently, there has been an attempt by settler farmers from the Ethiopian plateau to expand sesame cultivation in the low altitude areas ($&lt;$800 m.a.s.l.). A genotype-environment interaction study on sesame lines developed through progeny selection originating from a bulk of landraces was carried out at six environments in Ethiopia. The environments selected were believed to provide a wide variation in temperature (altitude), moisture and soil. The objective of the study was, therefore, to select a line or lines widely adaptable over these environments for variables seed yield, oil and protein content as well as fatty acid composition. Two statistical methods, namely, the regression model and the procedural approach of superiority measure were used to estimate line adaptability. Several lines were identified which were adapted over the six environments while others were specifically adapted to low- or high-yielding environments. Lines showing wide adaptation for one variable were not always widely adapted for others. In addition, the two parametric statistics used to analyze the data did not always agree for each variable.</description><creator>Woldemariam, Yebio</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Sesame -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Sesame -- Ethiopia -- Climatic factors.</subject><title>Genotype-environment interaction study on sesame (Sesamum indicum L.)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qq288.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sd395</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54kn843</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Treatment of chick myoblasts with the glucosidase inhibitors bromoconduritol (BCD) or N-methyl-1-deoxynojirimycin (MDJN), but not the mannosidase I inhibitor 1-deoxymannojirimycin (ManDJN), decreased the rate of cell-adhesion to fibronectin and laminin and increased the rate of adhesion to collagen. The adhesion of chick myoblasts is predominantly mediated by integrin(s), as judged by inhibition of adhesion by an anti-integrin antibody (JG22). The effects of BCD, MDJN and ManDJN on myoblast integrin detectable at the myoblast cell surface with JG22 antibody correlated well with their effects on adhesion to fibronectin and laminin, and paralleled the previously reported effects of these agents on myogenesis. Interaction of integrin with the extracellular matrix appears critical for terminal differentiation. Mn$ sp{2+}$ ions increased myoblast adhesion to ECM proteins, and antagonized the effect of BCD and MDJN on myoblast differentiation. Finally BCD and MDJN were found to act at an early stage in myoblast differentiation, down regulating the expression of both myogenin and muscle $ alpha$-actin mRNA in L$ sb6$ myoblasts.</description><creator>Trudel, Geralyn C.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Human Development.</subject><title>A study of myoblast integrin, adhesion and differentiation /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tc744.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kn843</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:th83m009p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The swelling and exclusion behavior of crosslinked hydrogels were determined in aqueous solutions of electrolytes and in aqueous solutions of proteins and enzymes. The gels were ionic copolymers of acrylamide, ionic copolymers of N-isopropylacrylamide (NIPA) and homopolymers of NIPA. Both anionic (weak acid and strong acid) and cationic (strong base) monomers were used. The following new gels were synthesized: (a) copolymer of acrylamide and 2-acrylamido-2-methyl-1-propanesulfonic acid (R-SO$ sbsp{3}{-}$H$ sp+).$ (b) copolymer of NIPA and R-SO$ sbsp{3}{-}$H$ sp+.$ (c) copolymer of NIPA and sodium vinylsulfonate. The gel structure was varied by changing the following variables at gel preparation: total monomer concentration, fraction of ionizable monomer and proportion of crosslinker. The swelling behavior of the gels at equilibrium was interpreted through a thermodynamic model developed from Flory's theory and an additivity rule for the osmotic pressure of polyelectrolyte-salt solutions. The kinetics of gel swelling were Fickian for NIPA-based gels, but non-Fickian for acrylamide-based gels. The rate of one-dimensional swelling or collapse was described by a mathematical model which used a material coordinate and a chemical potential driving force. Deformed copolymer gels of acrylamide and sodium acrylate exhibited a volume overshoot during swelling. Extensive exclusion measurements were made for NIPA-based gels using uncharged solutes (polyethylene glycol and dextran), ionic solutes (sodium polyvinyl-sulfonate and dextran sulfate), proteins (ovalbumin, bovine albumin, lactoglobulin and cytochrome C) and enzymes (lipase, $ alpha$-amylase and $ beta$-galactosidase). Exclusion is primarily by size and net charge although some proteins adsorbed onto the surfaces of hydrogels having the same charge.</description><creator>Vasheghani-Farahani, Ebrahim</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Swelling and exclusion behavior of hydrogels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79407x975.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m009p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s092k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The testing of printed circuit board (PCB) interconnects is a complex task that requires enormous amount of resources. With the increasing use of new technologies like surface mounting technology (SMT), testing PCB interconnects using the available techniques, like in-circuit testing and functional testing, is becoming very difficult. To make testing manageable, it must be considered earlier in the design process. This is known as 'design for testability' (DFT). A hierarchical DFT approach known as boundary scan architecture has recently become an increasingly attractive solution for PCB interconnect testing problems. This framework provides a scan path for electronic access to the interconnect test points, thus removing the need for accessibility through electro-mechanical contacts known as 'bed of nails'. In the recent past, several researchers have proposed different schemes for PCB interconnect testing based on the boundary scan architecture. In this dissertation, a new approach, based on the concept of built-in self-test (BIST), is developed using the boundary scan architecture for PCB interconnect testing. BIST, at the component level, generally consists of incorporating additional circuitry on the chip to generate test patterns and to compact the response of the circuit under test into a reference signature. For the PCB level BIST, the board is considered as the unit under test. A family of BIST schemes are developed for board interconnect testing utilizing the properties of the boundary scan architecture. The BIST approach has removed the dependence on automatic test equipment (ATE) for generation of test vector sets and analysis of output data sets. Techniques are developed for the generation of test vector sets which require very simple test generation hardware. Test vector sets are shown to be independent of the order of the input/output (I/O) scan cells in the boundary scan chain and of the structural complexity of the interconnects under test. Response compaction techniques proposed in the schemes are such that fault detection and diagnosis can be done independent of the topological information about the interconnects. These response compaction techniques can be implemented within each boundary scan cell or outside the boundary scan chain, providing a trade-off in terms of test time and hardware complexity. The various uses of the boundary scan architecture make the proposed schemes more attractive and advantageous than the existing approaches for board interconnect testing. Moreover, a family of interconnect testing schemes is proposed for a partial boundary scan environment. Partial boundary scan environment refers to a board with a mix of boundary scan and non-boundary scan components. Such an environment is more complex compared to a complete boundary scan environment. The proposed schemes are BIST-able despite the inherently complex test environment. However, fault coverage is limited because of the reduced accessibility of the partial boundary scan environment.</description><creator>Hassan, Abu S. M. (Abu Saleem Mahmudul)</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Testing of board interconnects using boundary scan architecture</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rm02c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s092k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hg16m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The influence of boron distribution on the precipitation of Nb(C,N) and on austenite recrystallization was studied by means of a stress relaxation technique. A plain carbon steel containing 0.026% C, used as the reference material, and three other steels alloyed with 0.003% B, 0.055% Nb and 0.003% B + 0.055% Nb were employed. The microstructural evolution during relaxation was interpreted in terms of the pinning effect of precipitates on mobile dislocations. C-shaped precipitation-time-temperature diagrams were determined for both the Nb + B and Nb steels. The presence of boron accelerates precipitation so that it begins at higher temperatures and after shorter times. Also, the combined addition of Nb and boron delays the recrystallization start time at 1000$ sp circ$C and suppresses the partial recrystallization of austenite observed at 950$ sp circ$C. Samples were quenched or control cooled at different stages of the tests and the evolution of precipitation and the location of boron and boron compounds were studied by various microanalytical techniques. The occurrence of the non-equilibrium segregation of boron after deformation and during recrystallization at austenite grain boundaries was revealed in this way. The observations are interpreted in terms of the interaction between vacancies and boron atoms. The strong retardation of recrystallization and the acceleration of precipitation observed when both Nb and boron are present is explained in terms of the formation of Nb-B complexes and the increase in the effective concentration of precipitate forming interstitials. At deformation temperatures of 950$ sp circ$C and above, boron appears to increase the solute drag effect of Nb, leading to greater delays in recrystallization. At lower temperatures, boron plays its role in accelerating the nucleation stage of precipitation. Finally, changes in the size distribution of the precipitates as a function of composition, temperature and time were measured. These data are employed in the framework of the diffusion controlled nucleation and particle growth theory. Expressions for the Nb(C,N) precipitation start times and for the diffusion of Nb in austenite were obtained which are in accord with the values reported in the literature.</description><creator>Djahazi, Mohammad</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Influence of boron distribution on precipitation and recrystallization in hot worked austenite</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s5533.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hg16m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4x51hj839</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Order-disorder phase transitions in solid cyclopentene, cyclohexene, tetramethylene sulfoxide, pentamethylene sulfide, cycloheptane, cycloheptene, 1,3-cycloheptadiene and 1,3,5-cycloheptatriene, were studied by various combinations of differential scanning calorimetry, proton spin-lattice relaxation time measurements, and variable temperature infrared and Raman spectroscopy. Possible unit cell symmetries have been proposed for the low temperature phases of several of these compounds, based on splitting observed in the vibrational spectra. The high temperature phases of cyclopentene, cyclohexene and 1,3-cycloheptadiene, for which the flexibility of the ring is reduced relative to the saturated analogues due to the presence of one or more double bonds, were found to be characterized by anisotropic molecular reorientation, as opposed to the other compounds, in which isotropic reorientation occurred. The ring puckering vibrations, when observed, were found to undergo significant frequency shifts at the order-disorder transitions. "Glassy crystals" were readily formed from cyclohexene, cycloheptane, cycloheptene, and 1,3-cycloheptadiene, the spectra of which confirmed the presence of static disorder related to the disorder present in their respective high temperature phases. Phase transitions in cyclohexane and cyclohexane-d$ sb{12}$ at high pressure were investigated by infrared and Raman spectroscopy using diamond anvil cells. Two phase transitions were observed in cyclohexane at 5.1 and 9.6 kbar, respectively. The vibrational spectra indicated that the change in unit cell symmetry was from O$ sb{ rm h}$ to D$ sb{ rm 2h}$ at the first transition, and then to C$ sb{ rm 2h}$ at the second transition. A study of the C-H oscillators of cyclohexane-d$ sb{11}$, dilute in cyclohexane-d$ sb{12}$, confirmed these changes in unit cell symmetry.</description><creator>Haines, Julian</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>An investigation of order-disorder phase transitions in several monocyclic organic compounds /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gp00h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hj839</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97kr18v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:04:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Under intensive farming, soil structure degradation and soil erosion are primarily associated with losses of organic matter. Restoration of soil structure may depend on the amount and nature of the organic amendment added. The effect of the addition of humic and fibric materials, and beeswax, a naturally occurring source of long-chain aliphatics comparable to those present in humic materials, on microbial activity and the structural properties of a waterlogged silty clay low in organic carbon was investigated. The incorporation of the fibric material increased the microbial activity in proportion to the amount of material added, whereas the humic and beeswax materials had the opposite effect. All organic materials added increased the cohesion of aggregates due to non water-dispersible cements. The fibric material was predominantly composed of polysaccharides and large quantities were required to produce a positive effect. The humic material was mainly lipids and the effect was associated with the time of incubation rather than the amount of material added. Principal-component analysis showed that the humic material was more effective at stabilizing soil aggregates than the fibric material, although the fibric material had a greater effect on the resistance of aggregates to slaking forces. Further testing with beeswax showed that the clay-associated lipids increased by 3.5-4.0 times the resistance of soil aggregates to the slaking forces, whereas the effect of hydrophobic "free" lipids was transient and accessory by coating and embedding soil aggregates.</description><creator>Dinel, H. (Henri), 1950-</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Soil structure.</subject><subject>Humus</subject><subject>Clay soils.</subject><subject>Soil conservation.</subject><title>The influence of soil organic matter components on the aggregation and structural stability of a lacustrine silty clay /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591917r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kr18v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Renewable Resources</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40650</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>