<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T00:51:38Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):12775" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860b110</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:22:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dans la tradition juridique, les actes délictuels et les crimes ont été conçus, étudiés et traités comme étant des catégories distinctes d'infractions légales. Toutefois, dans ces deux catégories les mécanismes indépendants de résolution de conflit -  Mode Alternatif de Résolution des Conflits et Justice réparatrice – ont parallèlement proposé des questionnements procéduraux et normatifs à la compréhension juridique de l'infraction. Ce mémoire propose d'unir ces développements indépendants afin d'établir un discours  unique et créatif défiant l'État de droit en tant qu'intermédiaire au conflit. Conséquemment, ce mémoire étudie l'émergence ainsi que les implications relatives à ce discours à travers lequel les infractions juridiques de nature civiles et pénales sont repensées en tant que conflits subjectifs soustraits aux différenciations juridiques conventionnelles. Ce mémoire cherche à étudier, clarifier et situer ce discours comme étant celui avec lequel la justice conventionnelle a négocié sur le plan politique.  S'appuyant sur la conception de « conflit en tant qu'immobilisation » de Nils Christie, ce mémoire encadre la négociation des revendications à la propriété, tant publiques que privées, plutôt que le conflit même et sa résolution. Conséquemment, un concept clarifié de propriété du conflit est établi, contenant à la fois les dimensions morales et juridiques et caractérisée par une dimension constitutionnelle, avec l'intention d'interpréter et de critiquer son état. À la lumière des défis offerts par le discours émergent ce mémoire réévalue la relation entre l'État et les particuliers puisque cette dernière a pris forme à travers cette négociation. Ce faisant, l'auteur note un changement dans l'évaluation morale à la propriété, et demande, sur cette base, que les différenciations traditionnelles soient réévaluées.</description><description>In the legal tradition, torts and crimes have been conceived of, studied, and addressed as distinct categories of legal wrongs. In both of these categories however, independent movements in dispute resolution – Alternative Dispute Resolution (ADR) and Restorative Justice – have offered parallel procedural and normative challenges to the legal understanding of wrongs. This thesis takes these independent developments as together comprising a single re-imaginative discourse that challenges state-based law as the intermediary of disputes. Accordingly, this thesis explores the emergence and implications of this discourse in which legal wrongs of both civil and criminal designation are re-imagined as subjective conflict and removed from conventional legal categorization. It seeks to survey, clarify, and situate this discourse as one with which the conventional legal discourse has been negotiating politically. Building on Nils Christie's conception of 'conflicts as property,' the thesis frames this negotiation in terms of public and private claims to ownership over conflict and its resolution. Accordingly, a clarified notion of ownership of conflict – containing both moral and legal dimensions and characterized as a constitutional issue – is developed in order to interpret and critique its state. In light of the challenges offered by the emergent discourse, the thesis re-assesses the relationship between the state and private individuals as it has emerged through that negotiation. In doing so, the author notes a shift in the moral assessment of ownership, and calls for the traditional categorizations to be re-assessed on that basis.</description><creator>Kennedy, Jeffrey</creator><contributor>Frederic Bachand (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>Exploring 'ownership' of conflict: legal wrongs in a new world order</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w3763b164.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860b110</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72pb680</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:22:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Alors que de nombreux gouvernements et entités commerciales prévoient d'ambitieuses expéditions dans l'espace extra-atmosphérique et dans les corps célestes, le patrimoine de l'humanité dans l'espace est menacé. Cette thèse examine les protections actuellement disponibles pour les objets et sites qui représentent les grandes réalisations de l'humanité concernant l'utilisation et l'exploration de l'espace, avec une attention particulière portée sur la Base de la Tranquillité, le site d'atterrissage d'Apollo 11. Les protections existantes sont analysées en vertu du droit du patrimoine culturel et du droit de l'espace, et se concentrent principalement sur le langage des traités en ces domaines. Il y a eu plusieurs tentatives menées aux États-Unis pour protéger les sites d'atterrissage d'Apollo, en particulier concernant la Base de la Tranquillité. Ces mesures sont examinées dans les développements de la thèse afin d'évaluer leur pertinence et leur efficacité. Les recommandations pour optimiser la protection du patrimoine de l'espace dans le futur sont ensuite présentées. Cette thèse conclut que l'approche la plus efficace, qui est également la plus susceptible de réussir, consiste en un processus en plusieurs étapes, comprenant des mesures unilatérales, des traités bilatéraux et une solution multilatérale de soft law, aboutissant idéalement à un traité multilatéral, et pouvant éventuellement conduire à la formation de droit international coutumier. Fondamentalement, la coopération et la bonne foi sont les pierres angulaires de toute solution à ce problème de droit international. Il est important que les règles juridiques régissant l'interaction et la préservation de ces objets et de ces sites soient clairement déterminées, afin d'éviter que des dommages irréversibles ne soient causés à une ressource unique et irremplaçable. </description><description>As numerous governments and commercial entities plan ambitious expeditions into outer space and to celestial bodies, humanity's heritage in space is threatened. This Thesis examines the protections currently available to those objects and sites that represent the great achievements of humankind in using and exploring space, with a focus on Tranquility Base, the Apollo 11 landing site. Existing protections are analyzed under both cultural heritage law and space law, focusing primarily on the language of relevant treaties in these fields. There have been several endeavors undertaken in the United States to protect the Apollo landing sites in general and Tranquility Base in particular. These actions are reviewed herein for appropriateness and efficacy. Recommendations to optimize the protection of space heritage in the future are then presented.  This Thesis concludes that the most effective approach, which is also likely to succeed, consists of a multi-step process including unilateral actions, bilateral treaties, and a multilateral soft law solution, ideally culminating in a multilateral treaty, and possibly leading to the formation of customary international law. Fundamentally, cooperation and good faith are the cornerstones of any solution to this issue of international law. It is important that the legal rules governing interaction with and preservation of these objects and sites be clearly determined to avoid irreversible damage to a unique and irreplaceable resource. </description><creator>DiPaolo, Andrea</creator><contributor>Ram S Jakhu (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>Space law and the protection of cultural heritage: the uncertain fate of humanity's heritage in space</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jq030.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72pb680</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x346d7393</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:22:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Space has become highly commercialized and satellites are treated as transferable goods, even while they are on orbit. Although the existing international space law regime allows such transfers, it also raises some serious questions especially with regards to registration and liability. The insufficiency of the present legal framework is rooted in the cause that the space treaties were drafted decades ago, and it was not possible to contemplate on-orbit transfers at that time. Under present regime of space law, in case of an inter-State on-orbit transfer of satellite, there may be a State having de jure jurisdiction and control over a space object, for which it is liable, while another State has de facto control over the space object and is responsible, as it is that State's national activity. In this context, finding a pragmatic solution, while keeping in mind the interests of the victims, the transferor and the transferee, is imperative. Consequently, it is important to analyze whether the current framework of law is competent to deal with the issue, or whether the existing law needs to be amended. Because on-orbit transfers are happening now and will increase in the future, the topic is an extremely significant one and addresses a practical problem.</description><description>L'espace s'est fortement commercialisé et les satellites sont traités comme des biens aliénables, même lorsqu'ils sont déjà placés en orbite. Bien que le droit spatial international autorise déjà de tels transferts, certaines questions demeurent, notamment en ce qui concerne la responsabilité et l'immatriculation des satellites. Les lacunes du présent régime sont dues au fait que les conventions concernées ont été adoptées il y a plusieurs décennies. A cette époque, les transferts de satellites n'avaient pas été prévus. Le cadre légal actuel prévoit qu'un Etat peut avoir le contrôle légal d'un satellite alors même qu'il n'en a pas le contrôle effectif, et qu'un autre Etat peut en être responsable, si l'un de ses nationaux l'opère. Dans ce contexte, une solution pratique prenant en compte les intérêts des victimes, du cédant et du cessionnaire doit impérativement être adoptée. De ce fait, l'analyse du cadre légal actuel est importante pour savoir si un amendement est nécessaire. Etant donné que le phénomène de transfert de satellites placés en orbite a déjà lieu de nos jours et prendra de plus en plus d'importance dans le futur, ce sujet concerne un problème prégnant.</description><creator>Dasgupta, Upasana</creator><contributor>Ram S Jakhu (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>On-orbit transfer of satellites between states: legal issues with special emphasis on liability and registration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sg923.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d7393</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:05741v82f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse propose d'apprécier le phénomène de falsification des prix de transaction depuis un point de vue juridique. Plus particulièrement, ce projet de recherche envisage l'étude de la falsification comme étant une pratique commerciale effectuée dans le cadre des échanges internationaux de biens et services. L'apport principal de la recherche porte sur la question de savoir si la falsification des prix de transaction est admissible dans la sphère commerciale. Pour cela, la question est posée de savoir si cette notion n'est pas légalement mal interprétée, c'est-à-dire, qu'elle semblerait impliquer un comportement criminel, et qu'ainsi, il faille approcher la notion d'une manière alternative afin de proposer une solution efficace pour dissuader ce genre de pratique.Cette thèse propose d'analyser plusieurs scénarios hypothétiques, afin d'illustrer la mise à exécution de la falsification des prix, puis d'argumenter si cette pratique peut être conceptualisée comme étant un crime. Pour cela, l'étude impliquera premièrement la revue des travaux académiques précédemment effectués sur le sujet, afin d'évaluer la conceptualisation de ce phénomène. Par la suite, la thèse proposera une explication sur l'hypothèse de réalisation de la falsification des prix de transaction. Cet exemple illustrera, non seulement ce que la falsification des prix sur les exportations implique, mais également la falsification des taux de transport, en tant qu'accessoire à la transaction. L'analyse de ces exemples révélera que la falsification des prix de transaction, en tant que pratique commerciale, est préjudiciable à l'intérêt public. Ainsi, cette thèse décrira les effets négatifs de la falsification des prix de transaction, qui ont été, jusqu'à maintenant, excessivement ignorés par la doctrine juridique. La difficulté pour détecter et contrôler la falsification des prix de transaction a probablement été à l'origine de l'absence d'étude juridique sur le sujet. Cependant, la pertinence d'une telle étude ne doit pas être laissée à l'abandon, spécialement du point de vue du droit pénal. Cette thèse démontrera à quel point le problème de falsification des prix de transaction est complexe et actuel à la fois. Elle démontrera à quel point il est important d'examiner ce problème sérieusement.Enfin, cette thèse mesure les conséquences de la falsification des prix de transaction en matière d'évasion fiscale, de fraude, de parjure et de blanchiment d'argent. Ces multiples idées doivent être examinées minutieusement. En effet, pour le moment, la majorité des études effectuées sur la falsification des prix de transaction s'est orientée sur les effets économiques de cette pratique, ainsi que les méthodes pour la quantifier, mais aucune ne porte sur une conceptualisation de cette pratique depuis un point de vue juridique.</description><description>This thesis evaluates the phenomenon of trade mispricing from a criminal law perspective. In particular, this research explores trade mispricing as a business practice performed within the international exchange of goods and services. The main contribution is to understand whether trade mispricing is a plausible phenomenon in the world of business; then, to discover whether it has been legally categorized incorrectly, that is, whether trade mispricing could involve criminal conduct and, consequently, a need for a different approach to propose an effective solution to deter this practice. The thesis proposes the analysis of hypothetical scenarios to illustrate how trade mispricing can be carried out and to discuss whether it can be conceptualized as a crime. The evaluation will, first, involve reviewing the previous academic work on the topic to assess the conceptualization of the phenomenon. Then, the thesis will explain how trade mispricing can hypothetically be done. This example will illustrate not only what mispricing exports involves, but also how transportation rates, as an accessory transaction, can be mispriced. The analysis of these examples will reveal trade mispricing as a business practice that causes harm to the public interest. Therefore, the thesis will describe the negative effects of trade mispricing, which may have been, thus far, unduly ignored in legal scholarship. The difficulties to monitor or control trade mispricing may have shifted attention away from its legal considerations. However, the relevance of this study cannot be neglected, especially regarding the criminal law perspective. This thesis illustrates how complex but current the issue of trade mispricing is and, by doing so, demonstrates why is important to consider it seriously. This thesis assesses the implications that trade mispricing has in the fields of tax evasion, fraud, perjury and money laundering. These multiple perspectives need to be scrutinized, since most of the work already done on trade mispricing focuses on the economic effects or the way to measure trade mispricing, but there has been no legal conceptualization of trade mispricing.</description><creator>Argibay Molina, Juan Agustin</creator><contributor>Allison Christians (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>The phenomenon of trade mispricing: untying the knot for a legal analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p3605.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741v82f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8910jx77z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Entrapment, as a behavior of abusing of the power by the police, should be prohibited by the law. However, in China, entrapment is read as legal and appropriate detective measure and the police or agent use it universally while recent legal regulation has begun to restrict its application. There are three reasons which contribute to its existence: firstly, insufficient understanding of the relationship between the human nature and entrapment; secondly, lacking the awareness of protecting the human rights and lastly overemphasizing on national accusatorial function. In terms of legal system, there is defectiveness in it. Specifically speaking, the defectiveness includes the law acquiesces in using entrapment by the police or agent; there is no regulations about whether the Judge could exclude the evidence that obtained because of entrapment and other procedural remedies for the accused are incomplete and ineffective. By comparing with the Canadian theory and legal system, the Chinese legal system in regulating entrapment might be improved to an extent. </description><description>La provocation policière, un abus du pouvoir de la police devrait être interdit par la loi. Cependant, estimée légale et comme une mesure détective approprié, cette pratique est universellement procédée par la police et son agent en Chine. Toutefois, la régulation légale est récemment venue restreindre de plus en plus son application dans la société. Trois raisons contribuent à son existence : une compréhension insuffisante du rapport entre la nature humaine et la provocation policière ; un manquement de conscience pour la protection des droits de l'homme ; et une importance exagérée accordée à la fonction accusatoire nationale. Par rapport au système juridique, il y en a des défectuosités qui, précisément, incluent l'acquiescement tacite de la loi sur la provocation par la police ou l'agent, l'absence des règlements en vertu desquels le juge pourrait exclure la preuve provenant de la provocation policière et, l'imperfection et l'inefficacité des autres remèdes procéduraux pour l'accusé. En comparaison avec la théorie et le système juridique du Canada, le système juridique chinois portant sur la provocation policière pourrait être amélioré dans une certaine mesure. </description><creator>Zhou, Sijia</creator><contributor>Mark Antaki (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>Research on entrapment in China--with reference to the experience in Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74ct954.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jx77z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445ch56q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bien que l'on ait observé que la rétroaction corrective (RC) s'avère un moyen efficace d'améliorer la prononciation dans la production orale en langue seconde (L2), il existe peu d'études empiriques portant sur ses effets sur la perception de la parole en L2. La présente étude a été conçue pour explorer (a) dans quelle mesure un enseignement avec et sans RC influe sur l'exactitude de la perception chez les apprenants de L2 par et (b) les raisons des effets des traitements différents. Trente-deux participants coréens, répartis en deux groupes, l'un avec enseignement sans RC et le second avec RC, ont suivi cinq cours de prononciation de 60 minutes qui attiraient leur attention sur le contraste phonémique /i/-/ɪ/ en anglais alors que seuls les membres du second groupe recevaient une rétroaction pertinente. Les participants ont eu à effectuer des tâches d'identification forcée dans le cadre d'un pré-test, d'un post-test immédiat et d'un post-test différé. Les membres des deux groupes ont amélioré leur rendement relatif à /i/ naturel et à /i/ synthétisé d'une durée modifiée, tandis que seuls ceux du groupe avec RC ont accru l'exactitude de leur perception de /ɪ/. Les participants des deux groupes ont maintenu les connaissances acquises après deux semaines, mais seuls ceux du groupe avec RC étaient en mesure de les transférer à des mots nouveaux. L'analyse de ces résultats montre le rôle essentiel de la RC dans le développement de l'exactitude de la perception de la parole en L2.</description><description>Corrective feedback (CF) has been identified as an effective means for improving pronunciation in second language (L2) speech production, but there has been a general lack of relevant empirical studies regarding its effects on L2 speech perception. The current study was designed to investigate (a) the extent to which the perceptual accuracy of L2 learners is influenced by instruction with and without CF, and (b) the reasons for differential treatment effects. Thirty-two Korean participants comprising Instruction-only and Instruction + CF groups were exposed to five one-hour pronunciation lessons that drew their attention to the English phonemic contrast /i/-/ɪ/, while only the Instruction + CF group was given relevant feedback. Forced identification tasks were provided to participants in a pretest, an immediate posttest, and a delayed posttest. Both groups showed improvement on natural and duration-synthesized /i/, while only the Instruction + CF group showed an increase in perceptual accuracy vis-à-vis /ɪ/. Both groups retained the acquired knowledge after two weeks, but only the feedback group was able to transfer it to new words. These findings are discussed in terms of the pivotal role played by CF in developing accuracy in L2 speech perception. </description><creator>Lee, Andrew</creator><contributor>Roy Lyster (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Education - Language and Literature </subject><title>Effects of corrective feedback on L2 speech perception: perceptual decisions, linguistic hypotheses, and negative evidence</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qw07z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445ch56q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tz440</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La base: Les accidents cérébro-vasculaires (ACV) sont une cause de morbidité dans les adultes avec des malformations cardiaque congénitales (AMCC). L'incidence et les prédicteurs de ACV ne sont investigés guère dans les AMCC. Les objéctives: L'éstimation du risque cumulatif et de l'incidence de ACV dans les AMCC et l'évaluation de la rôle des différentes catégories de lésion et des comorbidités comme prédicteurs de ACV. Les méthodes:  C'était une étude rétrospective basé sur des donnée groupée administratives de 28,465 AMCC patients âgé 18 à 64 ans en Québec entre 1998 et 2010. Les lésions étaient categorisées comme sévère si elles auraient une haute probabilité de cyanose où de chirurgie, comme shunt si elles causent une mixture du sang oxygéné et désoxygéné. Le reste était dividé en raison de la latéralisation en droit et gauche. Le risque cumulatif de ACV (ischémique et hémorrhagique combinés) était ajusté pour le risque competitif de la morte. Les incidences obtenues étaient standardisées à l'âge et le sexe selon des populations de référence. Les incidences de ACV rapportés auparavant pour la population générale de Québéc étaient 11 par 100,000 pour les femmes agées 15 à 54 ans et 82 par 100,000 pour les 55 à 64 ans en 2002; pour les hommes il y avait 18 ACV par 100,000 (15 à 54 d'ans) et 142 par 100,000 (55 à 64 d'ans). L'effet independent des catégories de lésion était evalué en utilisant des modèles de Cox avec âge comme unité de temps et ajustées pour les facteurs de risque classiques. L'importance des facteurs de risque différents était examinée par une étude cas-témoins en appliquant une combination de séléction "stepwise" et Bayesian model averaging (BMA). Finalement le risque d'une ACV dans les patients avec une nouvelle diagnose d`insuffisance cardiaque était comparé avec des contrôles en utilisant "propensity score matching". Les résultats: Le risque cumulatif de subir une ACV au cours de la vie jusqu'à l'âge 64 pour un patient AMCC agé 18 ans était 8.7% (95%-intervalle de confiance: 7.8 -9.5%). Pour les hommes, les lésions sévères amènaient le risque plus haut avec 16.2% (10.3-21.2%), pour les femmes les lésions gauches (11.9% (9.0-14.7%). Les femmes ont eu un risque élevé par 27% pour cent en comparaison aux hommes (incidence rate ratio: 0.73 (0.60-0.88)). Pour les femmes l'incidence standardisée à la population de Québéc de 2002 était 11 par 100,000 pour les 20 à 54 d`âge et 82 par 100,000 pour les 55 à 64; pour les hommes l'incidence était 18 (agé 20 à 54 ans) et 142 par 100,000 (agé 55 à 64 ans). En reference aux lésions shunt, le hazard ratio (HR) de ACV était 3.10 (2.05-4.51)) pour les patients agées 18 à 44 ans et 1.29 (0.80-2.01) pour les 45 à 64 d'ans; pour les lésions gauches les HR étaient 2.24 (1.51-3.30) et 1.29 (0.98-1.69) respectivement. L`insuffisance cardiaque, le diabète, l'insuffisance rénales chronique et les catègories de lésion sont sorties comme prédicteurs de ACV plus fortes de l'analyse de BMA. Les AMCC qui ont recu une première diagnose d'insuffisance cardiaque auraient un risque absolu de 6.7% (4.4-10.2%) de subir une ACV au course de 10 ans à l'encontre des contrôles qui on eu un risque de 3.1% (95%-CI: 2.0 - 4.9%) (stratified log-rank test: p-value = 0.01); toutfois le risque élevé était concentré dans les deux premières années.  Les conclusions: Au dessous de l'âge 55, ACV était environ 10 fois plus fréquent dans la population des AMCC par rapport à la population générale; au dessus de l'âge 55 ACV était 2.5 à 4.5 fois plus fréquént. Les lesions sévères et gauches étaient les catégories de lésion comportant le plus haut  risque d'une ACV, surtout dans les jeunes adultes. L'insuffisance cardiaque, le diabète et l`insuffisance rénale chronique étaient les comorbidités avec une valeur plus prédictive. La recherche future doit montrer si une modification de ces prédicteurs peut réduire l'incidence de ACV dans la population des AMCC. </description><description>Background: Stroke is an important cause of morbidity in adults with congenital heart disease (ACHD). However there is a lack of comprehensive data on the incidence and predictors of stroke in ACHD. Objective: To estimate the cumulative risk and incidence of stroke in ACHD, evaluate the role of different lesion categories and determine the most important predictors of stroke and their impact in ACHD. Methods: This retrospective study of 28,465 ACHD Quebec patients aged 18 to 64 years between 1998 and 2010 was based on aggregated province-wide administrative data. Lesions were classified as severe if they had a high probability of being associated with cyanosis or requiring early surgical intervention and as shunt lesions if defects primarily led to a mixture of oxygenated and deoxygenated blood; the remaining were categorized as right- and left-sided according to lateralization. In this dynamic cohort the cumulative incidence of stroke (ischemic and hemorrhagic combined) was adjusted for the competing risk of death and incidence rates were age- and sex-standardized to reference populations. Previously reported stroke-rates for women in the general population of Quebec in 2002 were 11 per 100,000 population for age-group 15-54 and 82 per 100,000 for age-group 55-64; corresponding rates for men were 18 per 100,000 (age-group 15-54) and 142 per 100,000 (age-group 55-64). By means of Cox proportional hazard (CPH) models with age as the time-scale and adjusted for classic cardiovascular risk factors the independent effect of different lesion categories was evaluated. The relevance of potential predictors was assessed in a nested case-control subcohort by a combination of stepwise model selection and Bayesian model averaging. To focus in on the absolute effect of newly diagnosed heart failure a propensity score matched cohort was created. The potential for information and selection bias was addressed by means of sensitivity analysis. Results: For an 18 year old patient the estimated overall cumulative risk of experiencing a stroke up to age 64 was 8.7% (95%-confidence interval (7.8 -9.5%). In males severe lesions accounted for the highest cumulative incidence with 16.2% (95%-CI: 10.3-21.2%), in females the left-sided lesions with 11.9% (95%-CI: 9.0-14.7%). Women had a 27% lower age-standardized stroke rate than men (incidence rate ratio: 0.73 (95%-CI: 0.60-0.88)). For females incidence rates age-standardized to the mid-year 2002 Quebec population were 11 per 100,000 population in age-group 20-54 and 82 per 100,000 in age-group 55-64; in males rates were 18 (age-group 20-54) and 142 per 100,000 (age-group 55-64) respectively. Contrasting severe to shunt lesions the hazard ratio (HR) of stroke was 3.10 (95%-CI: 2.05-4.51) for patients 18 to 44 years of age and 1.29 (0.80-2.01) for the 45 to 64 years old; for left-sided lesions HRs were 2.24 (1.51, 3.30) and 1.29 (0.98-1.69). Heart failure, diabetes, chronic kidney disease and lesion category emerged as the strongest predictors for stroke from Bayesian model averaging. Patients receiving their first diagnosis of heart failure had an absolute stroke risk of 6.7% (95%-CI 4.4-10.2%) over ten years of follow up compared to a risk of 3.1% (95%-CI: 2.0 – 4.9%) in non-heart failure patients (stratified log-rank test: p-value = 0.01); however CPH-analysis showed that the elevated risk was mainly contained in the first two years of follow-up.Conclusion: Stroke is 10 times more common in ACHD-patients than in the general population below age 55 and 2.5-4.5 times more common in patients aged 55 to 64. Severe and left-sided lesions are the lesion categories conveying the highest risk of stroke, in particular at younger age. Heart failure, diabetes and chronic kidney disease are the comorbidities with the strongest predictive ability for stroke. Further research is required to see if early detection and modifications of these risk factors may reduce the stroke rate in the ACHD population.</description><creator>Lanz, Jonas</creator><contributor>James Brophy (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Ariane Marelli (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</subject><title>Stroke in adults with congenital heart disease: Incidence and predictors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vp263.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tz440</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s4655k74j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les nanomatériaux de basses dimensions aux propriétés électroniques accordables sont appelés à jouer un rôle essentiel dans la conception de dispositifs nanoélectroniques de nouvelle génération. Dans la présente étude, trois méthodes de contrôle des états électroniques ont été étudiées, à savoir la régulation des défauts cristallins, le contrôle des contraintes mécaniques ainsi que  la conception d'hétérostructures. La théorie de la fonctionnelle de la densité (DFT), alliée à la méthode NEB, a été utilisée pour scruter les propriétés électroniques et la dynamique des défauts dans ces nanomatériaux bidimensionnels. Les défauts cristallins dans les nanomatériaux bidimensionnels peuvent être à l'origine de niveaux accepteurs ou donneurs externes et de pièges électroniques. Nous avons étudiés l'impact de lacunes dans le graphène et dans une monocouche de Nitrure de Bore (h-Bn) hexagonal sur les états électroniques et magnétiques, et en avons conclu que la présence de liaisons pendantes est la cause principale des conditions de dopage et des propriétés magnétiques de ces matériaux.  Concernant les contraintes mécaniques, nous avons trouvé que l'application d'une contrainte extérieure pouvait induire un déplacement des sous-bandes d'énergie ainsi qu'une modification des conditions de liaison locales. Par exemple, notre étude a montré qu'une contrainte bi-axiale  pouvait induire un basculement des états magnétiques dans une couche de nitrure de bore présentant des lacunes, du fait de la rupture et de la formation de nouvelles liaisons. En plus des deux méthodes mentionnées ci-dessus, nous nous sommes aussi intéressés à la conception d'hétérostructures, notamment à celle d'une structure hybride de graphène et de nitrure de bore. Nous avons concentré nos efforts en particulier sur le rôle des interfaces dans de telles hétérostructures. Notre étude a montré que les lacunes du réseau ont tendance à diffuser vers ces interfaces pour y être captées.Pour conclure, la présente étude a démontré que les états électroniques dans les nanomatériaux bidimensionnels peuvent être ajustés en contrôlant la densité et la nature des défauts cristallins, en exerçant des contraintes sur le matériaux ou en concevant des hétérostructures.</description><description>Low-dimensional nanomaterials with tunable electronic states play a key role in the design of next-generation nanoelectronic devices. In this thesis, three methods of engineering electronic states in two-dimensional (2D) nanomaterials have been investigated, i.e., defects control, strain engineering and heterostructure design. Density functional theory calculations together with nudged elastic band method are employed to examine the electronic properties and defect dynamics in 2D nanomaterials respectively. For the means of defect control, we note that the existence of defects in 2D nanomaterials can provide external donor or acceptor carriers and might also act as trapping states. We studied the contributions of vacancies in graphene and hexagonal boron nitride (h-BN) monolayer to the electronic/magnetic states, and concluded that the presence of dangling bonds is the main origin of doping conditionsand magnetism in these materials. For the means of strain engineering, we found that the external strain can induce shift of energy sub bands as well as modify local bonding conditions. For instance, our studies show that the biaxial strain canlead to switching of magnetic states in vacancy-decorated h-BN monolayer due to breaking and forming of bonds. Besides the above two methods of engineering electronic states, we also examined the route of heterostructure design, specifically the hybrid 2D graphene h-BN structure. In particular we focus on the role of interfaces in such heterostructures. Our studies show that the interface can act as a sink for vacancy segregation to achieve pinned electronic states. In conclusion, our current studies have demonstrated that the electronic states in 2D nanomaterials can be tuned by defect control, strain engineering and architecting heterostructures.</description><creator>Ouyang, Bin</creator><contributor>Jun Song (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Materials Science</subject><title>Tunable electronic states in defective 2D nanomaterials</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150n26c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655k74j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ws859j86f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>AbstractOver the past few decades, commercial communication satellites have improved the lives of people all over the world. They have fundamentally transformed the way people communicate, how business is conducted, and the manner in which militaries operate, fight and win wars. This dependence, however, has revealed that commercial communication satellites are increasingly vulnerable to disruptions, but also that these disruptions can pose significant risks to users everywhere. Such risks are especially concerning given the likelihood that satellite signal interference will be employed during future armed conflicts to disrupt the communications of adversaries. The implications of this new political, technical and military reality challenge the normative frameworks under international telecommunications law, international space law and international humanitarian law. This thesis addresses these and related issues in four chapters. Chapter One explores the extent to which satellite signal interference is becoming a serious threat to global users. Chapter Two discusses the technical application of interference and the normative regimes governing or relating to satellite transmissions and satellite communications. Chapter Three examines circumstances under which satellite signal interference can constitute an unlawful use of force or amount to an armed attack pursuant to the UN Charter. Chapter Four outlines the range of responses available to States suffering the effects of satellite signal interference.</description><description>RésuméAu cours des dernières décennies, les satellites de télécommunication ont amélioré la qualité de vie de millions d'humains, et ont profondément transformé leur manière de communiquer. De la même manière, le monde des affaires et les armées ont considérablement changé leur manière d'opérer. Cependant, cette nouvelle dépendance a mis en évidence la vulnérabilité croissante des satellites de télécommunications aux incidents et les risques que ces derniers présentent aux usagers de toute la planète. De tels risques sont préoccupants, étant donnée la probabilité que de futurs belligérants provoquent des interférences avec les signaux satellitaires lors de conflits armés. L'existence de cette nouvelle réalité politique, technique et militaire remet en cause le cadre normatif formé par le droit international des télécommunications, le droit spatial et le droit humanitaire. La présente thèse aborde ces difficultés et les problèmes adjacents. Le premier chapitre explore la portée de la menace réelle que représentent les interférences avec les signaux satellitaires pour les usagers du monde entier. Le deuxième chapitre étudie les applications techniques de ces interférences, ainsi que les normes qui régissent les transmissions par satellite. Le troisième chapitre examine les conditions dans lesquelles les interférences sont constitutives d'un usage illégal de la force ou s'apparentent à une agression armée au sens de la Charte des Nations Unies. Le dernier chapitre s'attarde sur les moyens dont disposent les Etats contre les interférences avec les signaux satellitaires.</description><creator>Mountin, Sarah</creator><contributor>Rene Provost (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Social Sciences - Law</subject><title>The legality and implications of intentional interference with commercial communication satellite signals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956k24w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ws859j86f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qb98mj73c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The possibility of using aluminum as a substrate for dye-sensitized solar cells (DSCs) was studied. In order to do so aluminum coupons were anodized in oxalic acid and sputtered with a conductive thin layer of either titanium, molybdenum or indium-tin oxide (ITO). The titanium-coated substrates were used as anodes or cathodes in DSCs in pair with conductive glass electrodes. In turn the molybdenum and ITO-coated substrates were only used as cathodes. The efficiency of the DSCs and their stability were measured by irradiating them using a solar simulator calibrated to reproduce the irradiation of the sun at the Earth's surface. The maximum values of efficiency measured were 6.4%, 4.5% and 2.1% for titanium, molybdenum and ITO cells respectively. The high resistivity of the ITO sputtered film was found to be responsible for the low efficiency of these DSCs. The degradation of the overall conversion efficiency of titanium-based DSCs was studied over 10 days. It was found that the efficiency decreased with time partly due to the reaction of the electrolyte with the metallic electrode. The evaporation of the volatile electrolyte due to sealant limitations was also found responsible for part of the decrease in the efficiency. </description><description>La possibilité d'utiliser l'aluminium comme substrat de cellules solaires à pigments photosensibles (DSCs) a été étudiée lors de ce projet de maîtrise.  Pour ce faire des coupons d'aluminium ont d'abord été anodisés dans l'acide oxalique puis de minces films conducteurs de titane, de molybdène ou d'oxyde d'indium-étain (ITO) ont été déposés par pulvérisation cathodique. Les substrats de titane ont été utilisés en tant qu'anodes et en tant que cathodes dans des DSCs en pair avec des électrodes de verre conducteur. Les substrats de molybdène et de ITO quant à eux n'ont été utilisés que comme cathodes. L'efficacité de ces DSCs ainsi que leur résistance ont été mesurées en les irradiant à l'aide d'un simulateur solaire calibré pour reproduire l'irradiation du soleil à la surface de la Terre. L'efficacité maximale mesurée pour les cellules de titane, de molybdène et de ITO était de 6,4%, 4,5% et 2,1% respectivement. Il a été montré que la grande résistivité des films de ITO est responsable pour leur faible efficacité. La dégradation de l'efficacité des cellules à base de titane a été étudiée sur une période de 10 jours. Il a été montré que l'efficacité diminuait avec le temps, entre autre à cause de la réaction de l'électrolyte avec le substrat métallique. Une partie de cette diminution de l'efficacité est aussi attribuée à l'évaporation de l'électrolyte volatile.</description><creator>Côté, Marie-Pier</creator><contributor>Mathieu Brochu (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>George Demopoulos (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Materials Science</subject><title>Thin conductive films sputtered on anodized aluminum substrates for dye-sensitized solar cell fabrication</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63t0249.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qb98mj73c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f1881q36b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The use of high strength steel has become more frequent in modern steel construction due to the increasing demand for taller buildings and longer spans. High strength stocky steel columns are often used as part of a building's primary lateral load resisting system. During the fabrication of welded steel subassemblies that utilize high strength columns, there exists the potential for crack initiation related to the welding process. The likelihood of cracking necessitates the evaluation of current welding guidelines and techniques used in practice related to welding performed on high strength steel so that failures occurring during or soon after fabrication can be avoided.This research focuses on the development of an advanced 2D finite element model that can accurately simulate multi-pass welding processes and provide a good estimate for crack initiation, occurring during or soon after fabrication. A specific case study was used involving a prequalified beam-to-column connection with welded thick doubler plates on a high strength steel column. When columns of this type are used as part of prequalified beam-to-column connections, thick doubler plates are typically welded to the column web in order to provide sufficient panel zone shear strength to prevent excessive yielding during an earthquake. The necessity to simulate the welding procedures performed in the panel zone area became evident after cracks were discovered post fabrication in the flanges of the case study column near the k-area. The FE model was relied on to simulate the complete joint penetration flare bevel groove welds on the web of an A913 Gr. 65 W-shape using a multi-pass flux cored arc welding process with CO2 gas shield. The results are presented for the heat transfer and stress analyses that replicate the welding sequence that is currently used in practice. High residual stress values are illustrated in the affected flange regions due to the welding. Additionally, an extended testing program for material characterization was employed involving tensile testing, Charpy V-Notch testing and scanning electron microscopy. It is demonstrated that the material exhibited good behaviour, suggesting that the cracking of the high strength steel column occurred due to the welding process. The measured material properties of the steel column were subsequently used in the finite element simulation. Through the use of linear elastic fracture mechanics crack propagation due to the welding was investigated, the quality of the W-shape material and the weld was evaluated and conclusions were drawn regarding the cause of the observed cracks during fabrication.</description><description>Les aciers à haute résistance sont de plus en plus usités dans les constructions modernes en raison de la demande croissante pour des bâtiments plus grands et des portées plus longues. Les colonnes trapues à haute résistance sont souvent utilisées dans le système principal de résistance aux efforts latéraux. Lors de la fabrication de sous-ensembles en acier soudé utilisant des colonnes à haute résistance, il peut y avoir apparition de fissures à cause du procédé de soudage. La fissuration potentielle impose une évaluation des procédés et des directives actuelles de soudage pour les aciers à haute résistance afin que les défaillances survenant pendant ou peu de temps après fabrication puissent être évitées.Cette recherche se concentre sur le développement d'un modèle avancé d'éléments finis 2D simulant de manière précise le soudage multi-passage et fournissant une bonne estimation pour la formation de fissure survenant pendant ou peu de temps après fabrication. Une étude de cas spécifique a été utilisée impliquant un assemblage poutre -colonne pré-qualifié avec d'épaisses plaques de renfort soudées sur une colonne en acier à haute résistance. Lorsque des colonnes de ce type sont utilisées dans le cadre de connexions poutre-colonne pré-qualifiées, les épaisses plaques de renfort sont généralement soudées à l'âme de la colonne afin de fournir une résistance en cisaillement suffisante au niveau de la "panel zone" pour éviter des déformations plastiques excessives durant les séismes. La nécessité de modéliser le procédé de soudage effectué dans la "panel zone" est devenu évidente lorsque des fissures ont été découvertes, après fabrication, dans les semelles de la colonne étudiée près de la zone k. Le modèle EF a été utilisé pour modéliser la pénétration complète de la soudure sur chanfrein sur l'âme d'un profilé W A913 Gr.65 effectuée par un processus de soudage à l'arc à file fourré avec un enrobage en CO2 avec multi-passage. Les résultats sont présentés pour le transfert de chaleur et l'analyse de contraintes qui reproduisent la séquence de soudage qui est actuellement utilisée. Des valeurs de contraintes résiduelles élevées dues à la soudure sont présentées dans les zones où les semelles sont affectées. De plus, un programme d'essais pour la caractérisation des matériaux a été employé impliquant essai de traction, essai Charpy V- Notch et microscopie électronique à balayage. Il est démontré que le matériau présente de bonnes caractéristiques, ce qui implique que la fissuration de la colonne en acier haute résistance a lieu en raison du procédé de soudage. Les propriétés du matériau de la colonne en acier obtenues par mesures ont ensuite été utilisées dans la simulation par éléments finis. La propagation des fissures dues au soudage a été étudiée selon la théorie des fissures mécaniques élastiques linéaires. Les qualités du matériau du profilé W et du soudage sont évaluées et des conclusions sont tirées concernant les causes des fissures observées pendant la fabrication.</description><creator>Nikolaidou, Violetta</creator><contributor>Dimitrios Lignos (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Colin Andrew Rogers (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Civil</subject><title>Finite element modelling and evaluation of welding procedures in high strength (450 Mpa : 65 Ksi) W - shape column assemblies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/41687m502.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881q36b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43p1491</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dynamic ankle joint stiffness defines the relationship between the position of the ankle and the torque acting about it and can be separated into intrinsic and reflex components. Under stationary conditions, intrinsic stiffness can be described by a linear second order system while reflex stiffness is described by a Hammerstein system whose input is delayed velocity. Given that reflex and intrinsic torque cannot be measured separately, there has been much interest in the development of system identification techniques to separate them analytically. To date, most methods have been nonparametric and as a result there is no direct link between the estimated parameters and those of the stiffness model. This thesis demonstrates that the ankle stiffness model can be approximated by a discrete-time, multiple input, single output linear transfer function model and introduces a novel algorithm for the identification of this class of models. As the algorithm is novel, proofs of the convergence and the existence of the solution are provided.  Through simulations we show that the algorithm gives unbiased results even in the presence of large non-white noise. Application of the method to experimental data demonstrates that it produces results consistent with previous findings.</description><description>La raideur dynamique de la cheville définit la relation entre la position de la cheville et le couple exercé à ce sujet et pouvant  être séparé en composants intrinsèques et réflexe.  En régime stationnaire, la raideur intrinsèque peut être décrit par un système linéaire du second ordre tandis raideur réflexe est décrit par un système Hammerstein dont l'entrée est retardé vélocité.  Étant donné que le couple réflexe et intrinsèque ne peut être mesurée séparément, il y'a eu beaucoup d'intérêt dans le développement de techniques d'identification de système pour les séparer analytiquement. A ce jour, la plupart des m´méthodes ont été non paramétrique et par conséquent il n'y a pas de lien direct entre les paramètres estimés et ceux du modèle de rigidité. Cette thèse d´démontre que le modèle de la raideur de la cheville peut être approché par une modèle de fonction de transfert linéaire avec entrée multiple et une unique sortie à temps discret et introduit un nouvel algorithme pour l'identification de cette classe de modèles. Comme l'algorithme est nouveau, les preuves de la convergence et de l'existence de la solution sont fournies. Grâce à des simulations, nous montrons que l'algorithme donne des résultats non biaises, même en présence d'un grand bruit non blanc. L'application de la m´méthode aux données expérimentales d´démontrent qu'il produit des résultats cohérents avec les résultats présentes dans la littérature.</description><creator>Guarin Lopez, Diego</creator><contributor>Kearney, Robert E. (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Biomedical</subject><title>Identification of multiple-input, single-output, discrete transfer function models. Application to ankle stiffness.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451m94w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43p1491</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jd473072h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The tundish plays an important role to produce refined steel as well as acting in its traditional role as a steel distribution vessel. Presently, a tundish fitted with different flow control devices, such as an impact pad, dams, weirs, baffles, etc. is used to provide the maximum opportunity for carrying out various metallurgical operations such as inclusion separation, superheat control, reduced slag entrapment and to provide thermal and particulate homogenization. Modelling has shown that a correctly designed impact pad in a continuous casting tundish can significantly reduce the amounts of slag entrained into individual moulds during ladle change operations. It can also minimize non-metallic inclusions reporting to the final product by improving inclusion flotation efficiency. Water can be used for the physical simulation, because the kinematic viscosities of liquid steel (at 1600°C) and water (at 20°C) are equivalent. In this one third scale water modeling work, the effects of an optimized impact pad on molten steel quality was evaluated in terms of "slag" entrainment during a ladle change, together with tracer dispersion studies and residence time distribution (RTD) analyses for isothermal and non-isothermal cases (temperature differences in between incoming fluid and existing fluid within the tundish) so as to visualize flow patterns developing within the tundish. Furthermore, the effect of increasing the molten steel capacity within the tundish by raising the liquid level, on the degree of slag entrainment during ladle changing operations, was also demonstrated.</description><description>Le Tundish joue un rôle important dans la production de l'acier raffiné ainsi que d'agir dans son rôle traditionnel d'un récipient de la distribution d'acier. Actuellement, un Tundish équipé de divers dispositifs de commande d'écoulement tels comme amortisseur d'impact, barrage, déversoirs, baffles, etc. est utilisé pour fournir le maximum de chances pour la réalisation de diverses opérations métallurgiques tels que la séparation d'inclusions, alliage rognage, réglage de la surchauffe, réduit piégeage de scories et pour fournir une homogénéisation thermique et de particules. La modélisation a montré que la conception d'un approprié amortisseur d'impact dans un Tundish de coulée continue permet de réduire de façon significativement les quantités de scories piégeage dans des moules individuels pendant les opérations de changement de louche.  Cela réduit également les inclusions non métalliques et améliore le produit final en raison d'une plus grande efficacité de la flottation.L'eau peut être utilisée pour la simulation physique, parce que la viscosité cinématique de l'acier liquide (1600°C) et de l'eau (20°C) sont équivalentes. A une échelle 1/3 du travail de modélisation, l'effet d'un optimale amortisseur d'impact sur la qualité d'acier fondu a été évaluée en termes de piégeage de scorie pendant le changement de "ladle", cette avec l'étude de la dispersion de traceurs et les analyses de la distribution des temps de séjour (RTD) pour les cas isothermique et non-isothermique (différence de température entre les flux de liquide d'entrée et sortie du Tundish) pour visualiser flux dans le Tundish. En plus l'affect d'augmenter la capacité d'acier fondue dans le Tundish par l'élévation du niveau du liquide, sur le grade du piégeage de scorie pendant les opérations de changement de louche ont aussi été démontre.       </description><creator>Hamid, Ahmed</creator><contributor>Roderick I L Guthrie (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Mihaiela Isac (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Metallurgy</subject><title>Effect of an optimised impact pad on molten steel quality in a 4 strand delta-shaped tundish</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547v730.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jd473072h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924f954</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse propose une méthodologie décentralisée pour la planification et la coordination des activités de charge et décharge des véhicules électriques (VEs) au sein des réseaux intelligents. La formulation d'optimisation est ensuite étendue vers une approche hybride qui peut  être considérée comme un compromis entre l'approche centralisée et l'approche décentralisée. La fonction objectif des différents mécanismes de coordination proposés maximise l'écrê tage de pointe du point de vue de l'opérateur du système électrique. Les algorithmes proposés sont examinés de façon multidisciplinaire par moyen d'analyse et de co-simulation de la puissance électrique et de communication intelligente, sur une infrastructure de communications basées sur des technologies convergentes haut-débit optique et sans-fil. L'objectif principal de cette thèse est de réaliser une étude comparative entre les méthodes centralisée, décentralisée et hybride. La comparaison des méthodes proposées avec un algorithme de référence centralisé révèle le compromis de performances entre les trois approches. La comparaison tient compte de plusieurs métriques du réseau, telles que la demande de puissance, les pertes, les amplitudes de tension nodale, et, du point de vue des communications, la largeur de bande requise et le délai. L'adoption d'un algorithme parmi les trois proposés dépend de plusieurs facteurs, cependant le nombre de VEs semble être le facteur principal. Les algorithmes centralisés démontrent des performances optimales pour des taux relativement faibles de pénétration des VEs, alors que les systèmes décentralisés sont nécessaires lorsqu'il y a un nombre croissant de VEs. D'autre part, les systèmes hybrides sont capables de répondre aux pics de demandes successives résultant de systèmes décentralisés avec des taux de pénétration très élevés.</description><description>This thesis proposes a decentralized methodology for the planning and scheduling of the charging/discharging activities of plug-in electric vehicles (PEVs) within the smart grids framework. The optimization formulation is then extended to a hybrid approach that can be seen as a compromise between the centralized and decentralized solutions. The optimization objective of the different proposed coordination schemes addresses peak load reduction from the system operator's perspective. The performance of the suggested algorithms is examined by means of analysis and powerful co-simulation of both power and communications perspectives, over a converged broadband fiber-wireless communication infrastructure. A comparison of the proposed decentralized and hybrid schemes to a centralized benchmark algorithm is conducted to identify the performance trade-offs between the three methods. This comparative study examines several performance metrics, such as power demand, losses, and nodal voltage magnitudes, and from the communications perspective, the required channel bandwidth and delay. The adoption of any of the three proposed algorithms depends on many factors; however the size of the fleet seems to be the main impact factor. Centralized algorithms demonstrate optimal performance for relatively low penetration levels, Whereas decentralized schemes become a necessity with increasing PEV fleets. Hybrid schemes, on the other hand, can resolve the successive demand peaks resulting from decentralized schemes with very high penetration levels.</description><creator>Mansour, Samah</creator><contributor>Geza Joos (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Performance optimization of hybrid, centralized, and decentralized adaptive charging/discharging schemes for plug-in electric vehicles</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sk60w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924f954</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rm54c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mise en Contexte: Malgré sa faible incidence, le cancer de l'ovaire est associé avec de très mauvais pronostique et c'est de notoriété publique dans la population générale. Les connaissances sont limitées sur les niveaux d'anxiété et de dépression chez les femmes qui subissent des tests de diagnostic pour la suspicion du cancer de l'ovaire. Cette étude a été menée dans le cadre de l'essai clinique DOvE (Diagnostic du cancer de l'ovaire précoce), un projet en cours fournissant le test de l'antigène du cancer (CA125) et l'échographie trans-vaginale (ÉTV) dans les centres  de diagnostics spécialisés à Montréal, pour les femmes présentant des symptômes qui ont été considérés associée à un cancer de l'ovaire. Objectifs: Notre objectif était d'examiner si la participation à ce programme a eu un impact sur la dépression et l'anxiété initiale ; nous avons voulu évaluer en particulier si un test faussement positif a eu un effet persistant, définie comme une durée de 4 mois ou plus, après que les femmes ont été  informées que le test a été  négatif. Méthodes: 706 femmes symptomatiques, ayant 50 ans ou plus, qui ont participé à DOvE entre juillet 2010 et septembre 2012 ont été invitées à remplir des questionnaires psychologiques, le Beck Anxiety Inventory (BAI), le Beck Depression Inventory-II (BDI-II) en deux points clés dans le processus de diagnostic: à la clinique, immédiatement avant l'évaluation et à la visite de suivi, 4 mois plus tard. Résultats: Bien que les taux d'anxiété et les scores étaient similaires lors de l'évaluation initiale et la visite de suivi, nous avons vu une diminution du taux et du niveau de dépression dans le temps (p &lt;.001). Il n'y avait pas de différence significative sur les variables démographiques et les scores d'anxiété / dépression entre les patientes testées positives dans l'absence de la maladie (faux positifs) et celles avec des résultats négatifs correctement diagnostiqués (vrais négatifs). Les femmes qui avaient de vrais résultats négatifs (77%) avaient un score significativement plus faible de la dépression au suivi qu'au début du programme (p &lt;.001).Conclusions: Globalement, faire partie du DOvE ne semble pas affecter négativement au moyen terme les scores d'anxiété et de dépression des femmes. En outre, les participants ont semblé bénéficier de l'assurance fournie par un résultat négatif, ce qui donne de la pertinence dans le contexte d'une maladie de faible incidence avec une réputation de mauvais résultats.</description><description>Background: Despite its low incidence, ovarian cancer is associated with very poor prognosis and this is common knowledge in the general population. There is limited knowledge about the levels of anxiety and depression in women who undergo diagnostic testing for suspected ovarian cancer. The setting of this study was the DOvE (Diagnosing Ovarian cancer Early) project, an ongoing study providing cancer antigen (CA125) testing and trans-vaginal ultrasound (TVUS) at dedicated diagnostic centres in Montreal for women with symptoms that have been found to be associated with ovarian cancer. Objectives: Our aim was to examine whether taking part in this program had an impact on depression and anxiety from baseline; in particular, we wanted to assess whether a false positive test had a persistent effect, defined as lasting 4 months or more, after women had been informed that the test was negative. Methods: 706 symptomatic women, 50 years or older, who took part in DOvE between July 2010 and September 2012, completed psychological questionnaires, the Beck Anxiety Inventory (BAI) and the Beck Depression Inventory-II (BDI-II) at two key points in the diagnostic process: at the clinic immediately before evaluation, and at follow-up (FU) visit, 4 months later. Results: While anxiety rates and scores were similar at initial assessment and follow-up visit, we saw a decrease in depression rates and scores over time (p&lt;.001). There were no significant differences on demographic variables and anxiety/depression scores between the patients testing positive in the absence of disease (false positives) and those with negative results correctly diagnosed (true negatives). Women who had true negative results (77%) had a significantly lower score for depression at FU than at the beginning of the program (p&lt;.001). Conclusions: Overall, taking part in DOvE did not appear to negatively affect women's medium term anxiety and depression scores. Moreover, participants appeared to benefit from the reassurance provided by negative result, which is of relevance in the context of a low incidence disease with a reputation for poor outcome.</description><creator>Grigorie, Maria Simona</creator><contributor>Lucy Gilbert (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Olga Basso (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery </subject><title>Anxiety and depression among participants in an early ovarian cancer diagnosis program</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t435gh157.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rm54c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8910jx787</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The mouse Flk-1 gene encodes for vascular endothelial growth factor receptor 2 (VEGFR-2), the receptor for vascular endothelial growth factor A (VEGF-A). This gene is essential for the development of the vascular system. In the early embryo, Flk-1 expression marks angioblasts and subsequent endothelial cells. Flk-1-/- embryos die at E8.5-9.5 and fail to develop the blood island, endocardium, dorsal aortae, intersomitic vessels, and capillaries. This gene product is required for endothelial cell development as well as for primitive and definitive erythrocyte differentiation. Flk-1-/- cells locate to the amnion, where it is not normally expressed. It is accepted that FLK-1 positive cells contribute to the formation of the endocardium as well as the embryonic vasculature and the extraembryonic yolk sac vasculature; however, the origins of these individual populations remain unknown. We hypothesize FLK-1 positive cells contributing to different lineages originate from different areas and behave differently; therefore, the aim of this project is to identify the origins of endothelial progenitors and study their behavior during their contribution to the cardiovascular system.Live-imaging microscopy analysis allows temporal and spatial observation of natural processes. Using the Flk-1-GFP mouse reporter line, heterozygous and homozygous embryos were used to live-image embryos from E7.5 to E8.5. The origins of endothelial cells forming the cardiovascular system were retrospectively identified with the use of software programs. The process of formation was then compared to that of Flk-1GFP/GFP mutant embryos.Live-imaging analysis of embryos during the streak stages showed the appearance of Flk-1- GFP+ cells laterally to the primitive streak. These cells then expanded embryonically and extraembryonically. During the head-fold stages, embryos showed a small population of Flk-1-GFP positive cells actively migrating from the embryonic-extraembryonic boundary into the embryonic region to form the dorsal aortae. During the migration, the cells aggregated and luminal structures were formed. The embryonic dorsal aortae form as these small luminal structures aggregated, lined laterally to the embryo midline. We also identified that endocardium progenitors originate from a region more anterior than dorsal aortae angioblasts. The majority of Flk-1-GFP+ cells in the extraembryonic region become part of the yolk sac vasculature. Flk-1GFP/GFP embryos appeared normal during the streak stages; however, during the head-fold stages, Flk-1-GFP+ cells showed lack of migration and failed to form vascular structures. The cells were located within the amnion, the base of the allantois, the cardiac mesoderm, and the extraembryonic region. The heart tube formed although the endocardium was absent. These data show the origins and contribution of Flk-1-GFP cells during gastrulation. Moreover, Flk-1 was found to be dispensable for the migration of mesodermal cell from the primitive streak and essential for angioblast migration</description><description>Le gène murin Flk-1 code pour le récepteur 2 du facteur de croissance endothélial vasculaire (VEGFR-2), récepteur au facteur de croissance endothélial vasculaire A (VEGF-A). Ce gène est essentiel au développement du syolk sactème cardiovasculaire. Au stade initial du développement de l'embryon, Flk-1 est exprimé sur les angioblastes, et sur les cellules endothéliales qui en sont issues. Chez les embryons Flk1-/- on constate la mort à E8.5-9.5, et l'absence de développement des îlots vasculaires, de l'endocarde, de l'aorte dorsale, des vaisseaux intersomitiques et des capillaires. Le produit de ce gène est nécessaire au développement des cellules endothéliales, ainsi qu'à la différenciation primitive et définitive des érythrocytes. Les cellules Flk1-/- sont localisées, de manière normale, dans l'amnios. Il est admis que les cellules exprimant Flk-1 contribuent à la formation de l'endocarde, ainsi qu'à la vascularisation de l'embryon et de la vésicule vitelline; cependent, les origines de ces populations cellulaires individuelles restent inconnues. L'hypothèse émise est que les cellules exprimant Flk-1, à l'origine de différentes lignées cellulaires, proviennent de différentes régions et ont un comportement différent; le but de ce projet est donc d'identifier l'origine des progéniteurs endothéliaux et d'étudier leur comportement contributif au développement du système cardiovasculaire. L'analyse en videomicroscopie permet une observation temporelle et spatiale de processus naturels. Des embryons issus de la lignée murine Flk-1-GFP, hétérozygotes ou homozygotes, ont été observés en videomicroscopie de E7.5 à E8.5 pour visualiser la formation du système cardiovasculaire. Les origines des cellules endothéliales formant le système cardiovasculaire ont été rétrospectivement identifiées à l'aide de logiciels. Le processus de formation a été comparé à celui d'embryons mutés Flk-1GFP/GFP. L'analyse en videomicroscopie des embryons durant les étapes séquentielles du développement a montré que les cellules Flk-1-GFP+ apparaissent latéralement sur la ligne primitive.  Ces cellules se répartissent ensuite dans les régions embryonnaires et extra-embryonnaires. Au cours de "head-fold stage" on a observé l'apparition d'une petite population de cellules Flk-1-GFP+, migrant de la frontière entre les régions embryonnaire et extra-embryonnaire dans la région embryonnaire pour former l'aorte dorsale. Durant cette migration, les cellules s'agrègent et initient la formation luminale. L'aorte dorsale embryonnaire se forme à mesure que ces petites structures luminales s'agrègent et s'alignent dans la région embryonnaire, formant une structure tubulaire distincte. Nous avons également pu identifier que les progéniteurs endocardiaux sont localisés dans une zone plus antérieure que les angioblastes de l'aorte dorsale. La majorité des cellules Flk-1-GFP+ de la région extra-embryonnaire forme la vascularisation de la vésicule vitelline. Les embryons Flk-1GFP/GFP sont apparus normaux au cours des étapes séquentielles, cependant, durant les étapes "head-fold", ni la migration ni les structures vasculaires n'ont été observées. Les cellules ont été localisées à l'intérieur de l'amnios, de l'allantoïde, du mésoderme cardiaque et de la région extra-embryonnaire. Le tube cardiaque s'est formé malgré l'absence de l'endocarde. Ces données montrent les origines des cellules exprimant Flk-1-GFP et leur contribution dans la gastrulation; de plus, il a été montré que Flk-1 est indispensable à la migration des cellules du mésoderme de la ligne primitive ainsi qu'à la migration des angioblastes. </description><creator>Sanchez Gonzalez, Veronica</creator><contributor>Yojiro Yamanaka (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>Development of the cardiovascular system through the «in-vivo» imaging of FLK-1-GFP positive cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m5175.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jx787</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h4931</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Contexte. Le Trouble Déficitaire de l'Attention et de l'Hyperactivité (TDAH) est caractérisé par l'impulsivité, l'hyperactivité, et l'inattention. Le TDAH se produit dans 5-10% des enfants scolaires. Le traitement de première ligne pour le TDAH sont les stimulants. Les stimulants augmentent les niveaux de dopamine (DA) et de norépinephrine (NE). Ces médicaments sont hautement efficaces, mais ne sont pas tolérés par tous les enfants. Les effets indésirables, comme l'insomnie, sont souvent reportés  pour ces stimulants. Par contre, leurs effets sont habituellement, mais pas toujours, bénins et transitoires. En général, les enfants souffrant d'insomnie sévère cessent le traitment. La faible tolérance peut limiter l'efficacité en compromettant la possibilité de prescrire des doses plus efficaces. Peu d'études ont mesuré l'efficacité comparative du methylphenidate á action prolongée et de l'amphétamine á action prolongée chez les enfants avec un TDAH. De plus,  il n'est pas clair s'il y a un effet différentiel de médicament et/ou de dose sur le sommeil. Les MAS augmentent les niveaux de NE et DA plus que les d-MPH, et donc pourraient avoir une incidence sur le sommeil d'une manière différente. Objectifs. Nous cherchons à déterminer s'il existe des différences  significatives dans les effets de dose-réponse des d-MPH et MAS á actions prolongées sur des mesures objectives du sommeil. Méthodes. Les enfants, âgés 10-17 (n=37), ont participé dans une étude croisée à double insu  comparant trois doses (10, 20, et 30mg) de d-MPH ou MAS au placebo. Chaque séance de traitement a duré une semaine, pour une durée totale de protocole de huit semaines.  Le sommeil a été mesuré dans toutes les conditions avec actimétrie et questionnaires. Résultats. Les mesures d'horaire du sommeil ont montré un effet significatif de dose à l'heure de début de sommeil (F(1,36)=6.284, p&lt;0.05); les enfants recevant 20mg ou 30mg on débuté leur sommeil significativement plus tard que ceux qui ont reçu le placebo  (p&lt;0.05). Un effet significatif de dose sur la durée réelle du sommeil (F(1,36)=8.112, p&lt;0.05) a été découverte, avec une durée de sommeil plus courte quand les sujets ont reçu 30 mg comparé au placebo (p&lt;0.05). Aucune différence entre les deux médicaments n'a été trouvée. Conclusion. Des doses plus élevées réduisent la durée du sommeil et conduisent à dormir plus tard, indépendamment de médicaments. </description><description>Background. Attention-Deficit/Hyperactivity Disorder (ADHD) is characterized by impulsivity, hyperactivity, and inattention, which affects 5-10% of school-age children. The first-line treatment for ADHD is stimulant medication, which increase levels dopamine (DA) and norepinephrine (NE). These medications are highly effective, but not always tolerated. Sleep side effects, such as insomnia, are reported for both stimulant classes and are usually, but not always, mild and transitory, which can lead to treatment discontinuation. Poor tolerability may limit efficacy by compromising the ability to prescribe effective doses. Few studies have assessed the comparative effectiveness of long-acting methylphenidate and amphetamine formulations in youth with ADHD, and it is unclear if there are differential effects of drug and/or dose on sleep. MAS increase NE and DA levels more than d-MPH and hence could be affecting sleep differently. Objectives. We sought to determine if there are significant differences in the dose-response effects of ER D-MPH and ER MAS on objective measures of sleep. Methods.  Children, aged 10-17 (n=37), participated in a double-blind crossover study comparing two stimulants (extended release DMPH, MAS) at three doses (10, 20, 30 mg) and placebo. Each treatment session lasted one week, for a total protocol duration of eight weeks. Sleep was assessed in all conditions using actigraphy and questionnaires. Results. Sleep schedule measures showed a significant effect for dosage on sleep start time (F(1,36)=6.284, p&lt;0.05), with a significantly later sleep start time when children were on 20mg or 30mg dosages, compared to placebo (p&lt;0.05). Sleep duration revealed a significant dose effect on actual sleep duration (F(1,36)=8.112, p&lt;0.05), with significantly shorter actual sleep duration for subjects receiving 30mg compared to those on placebo (p&lt;0.05). There were no significant differences between medications. Conclusion. Higher dosages reduce sleep duration and lead to later sleep start times, regardless of medication.</description><creator>Santisteban Lopez, Jose</creator><contributor>Reut Gruber (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health Sciences - Mental Health</subject><title>Dose response of extended release dexmethylphenidate and mixed amphetamine salts on sleep of youth with attention deficit/hyperactivity disorder</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773z91x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h4931</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b924f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette étude se propose de faire une lecture croisée entre la mémoire et le déplacement dans trois romans de Milan Kundera dont les personnages sont des exilés (Le livre du rire et de l'oubli, L'insoutenable légèreté de l'être et L'Ignorance). Notre hypothèse est que le déplacement s'accompagne chez les exilés d'un changement dans leur façon de se souvenir du passé : ne pouvant plus compter sur la mémoire linéaire (propre au régime moderne d'historicité) pour conserver un lien avec un passé dont ils sont spatialement séparés, ils recourent à ce que nous proposons de définir comme un nouveau type de mémoire: la mémoire variationnelle. Afin de définir ce terme, l'intertexte homérique nous servira de clef interprétative : la figure d'Ulysse, convoquée par le narrateur de L'Ignorance à propos du thème de l'exil et de la nostalgie, permet de voir comment la mémoire variationnelle (mémoire par retour de motifs) se construit en réponse aussi bien à l'impossibilité de la mémoire épique (mémoire idéale d'un passé parfaitement conservé) qu'à l'échec de la mémoire linéaire (mémoire par définition toujours falsifiable). </description><description>This study suggests a combined reading, between memory and displacement, of three different Milan Kundera novels where characters are exiled (The Book of Laughter and Forgetting, The Unbearable Lightness of Being and Ignorance). Our hypothesis is that the displacement comes with a change in the way that the exiles remember the past: since they cannot count on linear memory (related to the modern regime of historicity) to conserve a link with a past from which they are spatially separated, they resort to a new kind of memory that we propose to define as variational memory. To define this term, the Homeric intertext will serve as an interpretive key: the figure of Ulysses, called upon by the narrator of Ignorance concerning the theme of exile and nostalgia, gives the opportunity to see how variational memory (memory by return of motifs) is built like an answer to the impossibility of epic memory (idealistic memory of a perfectly conserved past) and the failure of linear memory (which is always falsifiable). </description><creator>Noël, Alex</creator><contributor>Isabelle Daunais (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Literature - Modern</subject><title>Le déplacement de la mémoire dans l'oeuvre romanesque de Milan Kundera</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418r56k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b924f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860b128</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le déclin des capacités perceptuelles est un aspect presqu'universel du vieillissement naturel qui reste en grande partie à élucider. Dans les voies auditives, ces déclins perceptuels se traduisent le plus souvent par des difficultés à identifier les détails temporels et spectraux subtils d'un son, de même que par une réduction de la capacité à comprendre le langage dans un environnement bruyant. Plusieurs anomalies du traitement de l'information auditive ont été décrites au niveau du cortex auditif primaire (A1) qui sert de canal principal à l'information auditive entre le tronc cérébral et les régions corticales cérébrales. Nombre de ces déficits ont été identifiés chez le rat âgé, un modèle qui gagne en popularité dans les études du déclin auditif lié à l'âge. Ils incluent une faible sélectivité de la mise au point par fréquence, une désynchronisation neurale et une diminution de la capacité à contraster les sons peu probables en présence de distracteurs. Puisque beaucoup de ces déficits du traitement auditif liés à l'âge apparaissant avec l'âge peuvent être partiellement inversés par l'entraînement auditif, il apparaît que ces changements ne sont pas entièrement dégénératifs mais représentent plutôt des ajustements plastiques « négatifs » en réponse à un changement des conditions cérébrales internes ou externes. Sur la base d'évidences indirectes obtenues lors d'études précédentes, nous avons émis l'hypothèse qu'une réduction de la clarté des motifs auditifs parvenant au cerveau causée par la dégénération des organes sensoriels périphériques pourrait entraîner ces changements. Pour tester cette hypothèse, j'ai exposé de jeunes rats adultes (5-6 mois) à du bruit continu peu défini à haut débit pendant 8 semaines utilisant un paradigme expérimental connu pour produire des profils du cortex auditif similaires à ceux rencontrés chez des rats âgés. J'ai comparé plusieurs aspects de la fonction, structure et connectivité d'A1 à ceux de rats âgés (21-26 mois). Il en est ressorti que l'effet de l'exposition au bruit sur les propriétés temporales et spectrales de A1 était presqu'identique à celui du vieillissement naturel sur A1. De plus,  mes résultats montrent que ces changements fonctionnels ont eu lieu parallèlement à une réduction de la population d'interneurones inhibiteurs et de la myéline intra-corticale, toutes les deux  amoindries par le vieillissement normal. Toutefois, la plupart de ces changements ont été inversés après avoir replacé les rats dans un environnement sans bruit. Finalement, des rats âgés (21 mois) placés dans un environnement enrichi de stimuli auditifs aux motifs complexes pendant deux semaines ont montrés de nombreuses améliorations dans le traitement des aspects temporel et spectral. Ces résultats suggèrent que les changements liés à l'âge dans A1 ont une composante fortement dépendante de l'activité et indiquent que la présence ou l'absence de motifs auditifs entrant clairs parvenant au cortex semblent jouer un rôle important dans le maintient des fonctions normales d'A1 chez l'adulte.Des changements de la connectivité entre A1 et le reste du cerveau pourraient jouer un rôle important dans l'émergence des déficits du traitement auditif liés à l'âge. La plupart des procédés d'A1 nécessitent l'intégration continuelle d'influences « ascendantes » et « descendantes ». La capacité à supprimer de façon sélective les données auditives distrayantes, l'une des faiblesses auditives les plus couramment rapportées par des adultes âgés, dépend fortement de cette intégration. Dans la deuxième partie de cette thèse, j'ai examiné le rôle de la statistique des données sensorielles, et en particulier l'impact de la présence du bruit auditif sur la connectivité entre A1 et plusieurs régions corticales « de haut niveau » impliquées dans le traitement auditif. </description><description>Perceptual decline is an almost universal aspect of natural aging that remains poorly understood.  In auditory pathways, these perpetual deficits most often result in difficulties identifying minute spectral and temporal details of stimuli, as well as a reduced ability to understand speech in noisy environments.  Several processing abnormalities have been described at the level of the primary auditory cortex (A1), the main conduit of auditory information between the brainstem and cerebral cortical fields. Many of these impairments have been identified in the aging rat, a model gaining popularity to study age-related auditory decline. These include poor frequency tuning selectivity, neural desynchronization, and a reduced ability to increase the contrast of low-probability sounds in the presence of distractors. Since many of these age-related auditory processing deficits can be partially reversed with auditory training, it appears that these changes are not be purely degenerative but rather represent “negative” plastic adjustments in response to some sort of change in external or internal brain conditions. Based on indirect evidence from previous studies, I speculate that a driver for these changes could be a reduction in the clarity of auditory pattern reaching the brain due to degenerating peripheral sensory organs. To test this hypothesis, I exposed young adult rats (5-6 m.o) to low-grade continuous broadband noise for 8 weeks, a paradigm previously shown to produce auditory cortex profiles similar to those seen in aged rats. Several aspects of A1 function, structure and connectivity were compared to aged rats (21-26 m.o). I found the impact of noise exposure on A1 spectral and temporal properties to be almost indistinguishable from the effect of natural aging on A1. In addition, I found that these functional changes were paralleled by a reduction in inhibitory interneuron population and of intra-cortical myelin, which are both negatively affected by normal aging. However, most of these changes were recovered after I returned the rats to a noise-free environment. Finally, aged rats (21 m.o) placed in an enriched environment containing highly patterned auditory stimuli for two weeks showed improvements in many aspects of temporal, and spectral processing. These results suggest that age-related changes in A1 have a strong activity-dependent component and indicate that the presence or absence of clear auditory input patterns reaching the cortex appear to play an important role in the maintenance of normal adult A1 function. Changes in connectivity between A1 and the rest of the brain could play an important role in the emergence of age-related auditory processing deficits. Most A1 processes require continuous integration of "bottom- up" and "top-down" influences. The ability to selectively suppress distracting auditory inputs, one of the most commonly reported auditory impairment in healthy older adults is highly dependent on this integration. In the second part of this thesis, I examined the role of sensory input statistics, more specifically the impact of auditory noise on the connectivity between A1 and a number of "high-order" cortical field involved in auditory processing. This was done using a combination of simultaneous electrophysiological recordings and tracer studies in young adult rats previously exposed to low-grade noise as in part one of the thesis and aged naive rats for comparison.  Noise exposure was found to reduce the anatomical and functional connectivity of A1 to downstream cortical fields, as was evident by a decrease in the amplitude and an increase in latency of the responses following electrical stimulation in A1. Furthermore, I found a decrease in synaptic bouton density of A1 afferents reaching the frontal cortical fields. These results suggest that "bottom-up" processes (noise exposure) might have the capacity to induce changes in cortical fields involved in "top-down" modulation. </description><creator>Kamal, Barishna</creator><contributor>Etienne De Villers-Sidani (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Central auditory decline: degeneration or negative plasticity?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qq46f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860b128</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860b13j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>D'abord, l'article [8] est situé dans son contexte et les points d'intérêt decet article sont soulevés. Il en découle une étude approfondie, où les démarchesde cet article sont suivies, en se référant à d'autres articles (des mêmes auteursou non). L'obtention du système d'Einstein-Dirac dans [8] est décrite. Puis,les résultats exposés sur la séparation de l'équation de Dirac sur la sphère dedimension trois dans [9] et qui sont détaillés en annexe, sont utilisés. L'utilisationde ces résultats avec l'expression classique du tenseur d'énergie-impulsion,dont la nullité de la divergence est démontrée, permet de réduire le systèmed'Einstein-Dirac en un système de deux EDO couplées avec une condition denormalisation.Pour étudier ce système, le formalisme de Bloch est brièvement introduit.Il est ensuite utilisé de façon a simplifier l'étude et la résolution de ce système.Les solutions du système résultant sont tirées de [8] et analysées de façon essentiellementqualitative. La solution approchée déterminée dans [7] est décriteet utilisé pour poser une borne inférieure approximative sur la probabilité quele Big-Bang soit évité.</description><description>Article [8] is first placed in its historical context and the points of interestsof this article are mentioned. It follows from them a deep study in which thesteps described in this article are followed, with occasional references to otherarticles (of the same authors or not). The way the Einstein-Dirac system isobtained is described. Then, results given by [9] on the separation of the Diracequation on the three-sphere and detailed in appendix are used. These resultsalong with the classical expression for the energy-momentum tensor, for whichthe vanishing of the divergence is proved, allow the reducing of the Einstein-Dirac system to a system of coupled ODE with a normalization condition.To study this system, the Bloch formalism is briefly introduced. It is thenused to simplify the study and the resolution of this system. The resultingsystem's solutions are taken from [8] and analysed in an essentially qualitativeway. The approximate solution determined in [7] is then described and usedto find an approximate lower bound on the probability that the Big-Bang isavoided.</description><creator>Morris, Christophe</creator><contributor>Niky Kamran (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics </subject><title>Le système d'Einstein-Dirac d'un univers homogène et isotrope</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365843s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860b13j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227mt17m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'émail dentaire est un matériau composite, constitué d'une partie organique (2-4% de l'émail) et d'une partie inorganique (96-98% de l'émail) qui protègent les couches profondes de la dent (dentine et la pulpe dentaire). L'émail dentaire est le tissu le plus dur chez les mammifères, et l'un des plus résistants. Cependant, l'émail est continuellement exposé à une agression d'origine mécanique, qui pourrait le fissurer, créant un environnement favorable à la croissance des bactéries qui pourraient provoquer la sensibilité dentaire ou la fracture de la dent. Aussi, l'incorporation des ions dans la structure de l'émail dentaire peut affecter les propriétés cristallographiques, mécaniques et physiques de ce tissu dentaire important. L'objectif de cette étude est de découvrir la relation entre la cristallographie, les propriétés physiques et chimiques de l'émail dentaire et sa résistance contre la propagation de fractures. La contribution possible des traces d'oligo-éléments dans la structure de l'émail, avec ses aspects cristallographiques et  ses propriétés chimiques et physiques, a aussi été examinée.     Des dents adultes ont été extraites dans la clinique dentaire d'étudiants de premier cycle de l'Université McGill.  La longueur de fissure de l'émail, la dureté, la cristallographie (i.e., la taille des cristaux, la structure cristalline; le long des axes a et c), la composition  chimique, la teinte et les traces des oligo-éléments ont été obtenues par microscope électronique à balayage, microdureté de Vickers, spectroscopie infrarouge à transformation de Fourier, ombre spectrophotométrie et de spectrométrie de masse à plasma inductif. Le niveau de signification statistique a été déterminé pour une valeur de P &lt;0.05. Dans cette étude, nous avons remarqué que la longueur moyenne de la fissure et la longueur moyenne des fissures perpendiculaires à la jonction émail-dentine, émanent des indentations induites sur l'émail, ont été corrélés aux dimensions de cristal de l'émail le long de l'axe c.  Selon ce rapport, nous avons proposé un nouveau modèle basé sur la théorie de Hall-Petch, qui prédit avec précision la propagation des fissures dans l'émail. La concentration de Ti dans l'émail des dents semble positivement associée à la dureté de l'émail, à la légèreté et à la taille des cristaux le long de l'axe c. En outre, nous avons constaté que la présence de Fe est associée à la formation de carbonate de type A, tandis que la concentration de Co et Ni montre une corrélation avec la formation de Type B. Cette substitution dans l'émail des dents est associée avec des paramètres de réseau cellulaire le long des axes a et c. D'autre part, Cr et Ni montent une corrélation négative avec les paramètres de la maille de cellules le long de l'axe c. La présence de Pb, Ti et Mn a un lien avec la taille des cristaux de l'émail des dents le long de l'axe c.Nos résultats montrent pourquoi les personnes âgées souffrent d'une fracture de la dent plus souvent que les plus jeunes, et comment la nanostructure de l'émail empêche une défaillance mécanique catastrophique. De plus, cette étude montre comment la présence d'oligo-éléments peut affecter les propriétés physico-chimiques de l'émail des dents.</description><description>Tooth enamel is a composite material, made of an organic phase (2-4% of enamel) and an inorganic phase (96-98% of enamel) that protects the tooth layers underneath (dentin and dental pulp). Tooth enamel is the hardest and one of the toughest materials in mammals. However, enamel suffers from continuous mechanical stress that might cause cracks, creating a favourable environment for bacteria growth and leading to tooth sensitivity or fracture. Also the incorporation of ions in tooth enamel structure can affect the crystallographic, mechanical and physical properties. This study was designed to find out the relative contribution of tooth enamel's crystallography, physical and chemical characteristics to its resistance to crack propagation. The possible contribution of tooth enamel trace elemental composition on its crystallography, chemical and physical properties was investigated, as well. Extracted sound teeth were gathered from patients attending McGill Undergraduate Dental Clinic. Tooth enamel's crack length, hardness, crystallography (i.e. crystallite size, unit cell parameters of the crystal; a and c), chemical composition, tooth shade and trace elements were obtained by Scanning Electron Microscope, Vickers microhardness, X-Ray Diffraction, Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy, shade spectrophotometry and inductively-coupled plasma mass spectrometry. The statistical significance was set at P &lt;0.05. In this study, I found that the average crack length and average length of cracks perpendicular to dentin-enamel junction that emanated from indentations induced on enamel were correlated to enamel's crystallite dimensions along c-axis. According to this finding, I proposed a new model based on Hall-Petch theory that accurately predicts crack propagation in enamel. The concentration of Ti in tooth enamel was positively associated with enamel's hardness, lightness and crystallite size along c-axis. Also, I found that the presence of Fe was associated with the formation of carbonate type A, while the concentration of Co and Ni were correlated with the formation of carbonate type B. Se substitution in tooth enamel was positively associated with unit cell parameters along a and c, on the other hand Cr and Ni had a negative correlation with unit cell parameters along c. It was shown that the presence of Pb, Ti and Mn had an association with tooth enamel's crystallite size along c-axis.Our findings show why older people suffer from tooth fracture more often than younger ones, and how the nanostructure of enamel prevents catastrophic mechanical failure. Also this study shows how the presence of trace elements can affect the physical-chemical properties of tooth enamel.</description><creator>Ghadimi, Elnaz</creator><contributor>Faleh Tamimi Marino (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Hojatollah Vali (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health Sciences - Dentistry</subject><title>Crystal shape and composition of enamel affect its mechanical properties</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sd77w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mt17m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720h12g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Poultry and liquid swine manure are major sources of bioactive levels of natural steroidal sex hormones, including 17β-estradiol, estrone, testosterone and progesterone. Although several detailed studies have investigated the environmental pathways and ecotoxicology of high-toxicity-at-low-concentrations of sex hormones in soil and water media, there is a lack of knowledge with respect to the fate and transport of steroid hormones in the soil matrix and aquatic media. Three separate studies were performed with the objective of developing effective on-field remediation techniques in order to reduce the environmental and biological hormonal pollution from agricultural sources. In the first study, the sorption retention and desorption resistance of two types of biochars (fast and slow pyrolysis) for three female sex hormones (17β-estradiol, estrone, progesterone) was evaluated in batch equilibrium experiments. Slow-pyrolysis biochar demonstrated a stronger remediation capability than the fast-pyrolysis biochar in this study. In the second study, the retention potency of slow pyrolysis biochar was assessed as a topsoil amendment on the fate and transport of the three sex hormones in a sandy soil over a 45-day period where poultry and liquid swine manure were applied as fertilizer to outdoor lysimeters, irrigated with different levels of simulated rainfall. A significant difference (p&lt;0.05) was observed between the spatial-temporal stratification of three hormones in lysimeteres with soil and soil-biochar treatments. The significant lower mass of hormones quantified at different depths of the soil profile and the measured concentration of all three hormones in collected leachate samples over time in the lysimeters amended with 1% slow pyrolysis biochar, potentially confirmed the hypothesis of this study, confirmed the highly effective retention capability of biochar as a soil-amendment for reducing manure-borne hormonal pollution in soil and water.</description><description>Les lisiers de volaille et de porc sont les principales sources, à des niveaux bioactifs, d'hormones sexuelles stéroïdiennes naturelles tel le 17β-estradiol, l'estrone, la testostérone et la progestérone. Quoique plusieurs études détaillées aient enquêté sur les chaînes de pénétration dans l'environnement et l'écotoxicologie de haute-toxicité-à-faible-concentration des hormones sexuelles dans la matrice du sol et dans les milieux aquatiques, il demeure des lacunes en ce qui concerne le devenir et le transport des hormones stéroïdes dans ces milieux. Trois études distinctes furent réalisées ayant pour objectif de développer des techniques d'assainissement sur le terrain qui permettraient de réduire la pollution hormonale liée aux sources agricoles et ses effets néfastes sur l'environnement et les biotes. Dans la première expérience, la rétention par sorption et la résistance à la désorption de trois hormones sexuelles féminines (17β-estradiol, estrone, progestérone) en présence de deux types de biochars (pyrolyse lente ou rapide) fut évalué par lots d'échantillons sous conditions d'équilibre. Le biochar produit par pyrolyse lente démontra une plus grande capacité d'assainissement que celui produit par pyrolyse rapide. Dans une seconde étude, entreprise à l'extérieur en lysimètres, le potentiel de rétention d'un biochar produit par pyrolyse lente et servant comme amendement à la couche arable d'un sol sablonneux, fut évalué, sur une période de 45 jours, quant à son effet sur le sort et le transport des trois hormones sexuelles féminines. Chacun des lysimètres reçurent du lisier de volaille ou de porc comme engrais, et fut irrigué avec un niveaux particulier de précipitation simulée. Entre le sols ayant ou n'ayant pas reçu d'addition de biochar, une différence significative (p &lt; 0.05) dans la stratification spatio-temporelle des trois hormones dans le sol fut évidente. Pour la duré de l'expérience, les teneurs des trois hormones à différentes profondeurs du profil du sol et dans le lixiviat furent sensiblement moins élevés dans les lysimètres dont le sol avait reçu un amendement de biochar à pyrolyse lente (à 1%), que ceux n'ayant pas reçu d'amendement. Ces résultats confirmèrent l'hypothèse de l'étude qui voudrait que le biochar utilisé comme amendement au sol confère une excellente capacité de rétention, dans le sol et dans l'eau, des polluants hormonaux provenant de lisiers.</description><creator>Alizadeh, Sanaz</creator><contributor>Shiv Prasher (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</subject><title>Use of biochar for reducing female sex hormonal pollution in agricultural areas</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612r85h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720h12g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v8383815</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Alors que le déclin de la population amphibienne mondiale est de plus en plus préoccupant, il est primordial d'identifier les facteurs qui en sont la cause. Puisqu'une certaine fluctuation de population est normale, il est difficile de déterminer si une variation donnée est naturelle ou symptomatique d'un déclin réel. Une meilleure compréhension des fluctuations de la population amphibienne pourrait servir à distinguer entre les facteurs naturels de variation et une altération de dynamique associée à un déclin. Voilà l'idée directrice de cette étude d'une espèce à risque, le crapaud de Fowler (Anaxyrus [=Bufo] fowleri) de Long Point en Ontario, dont la population semble diminuer graduellement. À partir de l'information recueillie sur deux décennies de marquage-recapture, j'ai examiné les facteurs, internes et externes, de variation de leur population. Au cours de la période, leur habitat de reproduction a été considérablement détérioré par la présence d'une espèce envahissante de roseau commun, le Phragmites australis. J'explore le lien entre cette altération de dynamique et le déclin progressif des crapauds de Fowler. Avant 2002, leur population était régulée par des facteurs internes comme la croissance en fonction de la densité et la mortalité hivernale. Depuis, les roseaux communs ont éliminé la plupart de l'habitat en eau libre des crapauds de Fowler, dont la population ne répond plus qu'à des facteurs externes d'influence, en particulier le niveau de l'eau du lac Érié. Ensuite, je cherche à voir si la présence de l'espèce envahissante a influencé, non seulement la quantité d'habitat de reproduction du crapaud de Fowler, mais aussi la qualité de ce qui reste, par la production de composés secondaires. L'hypothèse explorée est que les composés secondaires nuisibles aux branchies, produits autant par l'espèce envahissante Phragmites que par l'espèce native Typha, réduisent les chances de survie, la croissance et le développement des crapauds de Fowler, qui respirent nécessairement par leurs branchies. En toute logique, l'espèce sympatrique grenouille léopard du Nord (Lithobates [=Rana] pipiens), qui respire par ses branchies de façon facultative, devrait être affectée de façon similaire. Cependant, ce n'est pas le cas ; j'ai remarqué que les têtards de crapauds de Fowler n'étaient pas affectés par la présence de composés secondaires. De plus, c'est l'espèce native Typha qui semblait nuire à la croissance des crapauds de Fowler, plutôt que l'espèce envahissante Phragmites. J'en conclus que l'expansion de cette dernière peut influencer plusieurs espèces par une réduction de l'habitat disponible, mais pas par la détérioration de la qualité de son habitat larvaire. En étudiant le déclin amphibien à partir de la dynamique de population, nous pouvons améliorer notre capacité à établir des liens entre le déclin de populations d'espèces et les mécanismes qui y contribuent.</description><description>With concern rising over the global decline of amphibian populations, identifying the onset of declines and the factors driving them is paramount. Amphibian populations are naturally characterized by large fluctuations in abundance, which makes separating natural fluctuations from true declines very difficult. By improving our understanding of the natural dynamics of amphibian populations, we can separate normal fluctuations from altered dynamics associated with decline. I apply this principle to an endangered population of Fowler's toads (Anaxyrus [=Bufo] fowleri) in Long Point, Ontario which appears to have gradually declined in abundance. With over two decades of mark-recapture data, I investigate what factors, intrinsic and extrinsic, drive growth in this population. Over this same period, there have been considerable changes to the toads' habitat, as an invasive strain of the common reed, Phragmites australis, has overtaken the wetlands used by toads for breeding. I show that the expansion of this reed has altered the dynamics of the toad population, causing progressive decline due to breeding habitat loss. Prior to 2002, the population of toads was driven by density-dependent growth and overwinter mortality. After 2002, at which point the reeds had eliminated most of the open water habitat, the population of toads responded only to extrinsic factors, particularly the water level of Lake Erie. I then ask whether the expansion of invasive Phragmites has changed not just the quantity of larval habitat, but also its quality, through the release of secondary compounds. I hypothesize that Fowler's toad larvae, as obligate gill breathers, will experience reduced survival, growth, and development in the presence of gill damaging secondary compounds from the invasive Phragmites and native Typha. In contrast, the sympatric Northern leopard frog (Lithobates [=Rana] pipiens) should exhibit similar performance as tadpoles in the presence of secondary compounds, as a facultative gill breather. Contrary to my expectations, I found that Fowler's toad tadpoles had a similar performance across treatments, despite the presence of secondary compounds. Furthermore, the native plant, Typha, but not the invasive Phragmites, appeared to impede growth in Leopard frog tadpoles. Based on these results, I conclude that the expansion of invasive Phragmites has the potential to impact species through changes to available habitat, but not by reducing larval habitat quality. By incorporating population dynamics into the study of amphibian declines we can improve our ability to infer causal links between population declines and the mechanisms that drive them.</description><creator>Greenberg, Daniel</creator><contributor>David M Green (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Ecology</subject><title>Population dynamics of a declining amphibian</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924f96d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v8383815</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gh16h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD) is characterized by severe lung inflammation and progressive airflow limitation. Systemic manifestations of COPD, including exercise intolerance and skeletal muscle dysfunction, contribute to disease severity and mortality. Chronic oxidative stress has been implicated as a major contributor to the development of these co-morbid conditions. Oxidized proteins and lipids have been described in COPD skeletal muscle, however oxidatively damaged DNA has not been previously investigated. To assess the integrity of nuclear (nDNA) and mitochondrial DNA (mtDNA), we obtained muscle biopsies from 29 moderate-to-severe COPD patients (FEV1 = 48 ± 15% predicted) and 19 age-matched, healthy controls. Using a competitive ELISA assay, we found that COPD patients have significantly higher levels of oxidized DNA (387 ± 41 pg/mL) compared to controls (258 ± 21 pg/mL, p = 0.03). We also detected a higher prevalence of mtDNA deletions (74% in COPD and 15% in controls, p &lt; 0.01) and incidence of Electron Transport Chain (ETC) abnormalities (8.0 ± 2.1% in COPD and 1.5 ± 0.42% in controls, p &lt; 0.05). COPD patients with mtDNA deletions had significantly higher levels of oxidized DNA (457 ± 46 pg/mL) than patients with wild-type mtDNA (197 ± 29 pg/mL, p &lt; 0.05). These results implicate ROS-mediated formation of mtDNA deletions and ETC dysfunction as novel systemic manifestations of COPD.</description><description>La maladie pulmonaire obstructive chronique (MPOC) est caractérisée par une inflammation sévère des poumons et une obstruction progressive des voies respiratoires. Les manifestations systémiques de la MPOC, incluant l'intolérance à l'effort et le dysfonctionnement des muscles squelettiques, contribuent à la gravité de la maladie et au risque de mortalité. Le stress oxydatif chronique a été identifié comme contributeur majeur au développement de ces comorbidités. Les processus d'oxydation des protéines et des lipides dans le muscle squelettique chez les personnes atteints de MPOC ont été décrits dans la littérature, néanmoins les dommages oxydatifs causé à l'ADN n'ont jamais été préalablement étudiés.Pour évaluer l'intégrité de l'ADN nucléaire (ADNn) et de l'ADN mitochondrial (ADNmt), nous avons collecté des échantillons de biopsies musculaires chez 29 patients atteints de MPOC de niveau modérée à sévère (VEMS 1 = 48 ± 15% des valeurs prédites) et 19 sujets témoins sains du même âge.Les résultats du test ELISA concurrent nous ont permis de constaté que les patients atteints de MPOC présentaient des niveaux significativement plus élevés d'ADN oxydée (387 ± 41 pg / mL) par rapport aux sujets témoins (258 ± 21 pg / ml, p = 0,03). Nous avons également détecté une prévalence plus élevée de délétions dans l'ADN mitochondriale (74% chez les patients MPOC vs. 15% chez les sujets témoins, p &lt; 0,01) et une incidence plus élevée d'anomalie dans la chaîne de transport des électrons (CTE) (8,0 ± 2,1% chez les patients MPOC vs. 1,5 ± 0,42% chez les témoins, p &lt;0,05). Les patients atteints de MPOC ayant des délétions dans l'ADN mitochondriale présentaient une concentration significativement plus élevée d'ADN oxydée (457 ± 46 pg / mL) comparativement aux patients ayant un ADN mitochondrial intacts (197 ± 29 pg / ml, p &lt;0,05).Nos résultats suggèrent la formation de stress oxydatif, induite par la présence de délétions dans l'ADN mitochondriale et l'augmentation de l'incidence d'anomalie dans la CTE, comme nouvelle manifestation systémiques de la MPOC.</description><creator>Konokhova, Yana</creator><contributor>Tanja Taivassalo (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Russell Hepple (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - General</subject><title>Mitochondrial DNA deletions correspond to high levels of oxidative DNA damage in skeletal muscle of patients with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5q47rs14w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gh16h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k643b432n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:23:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>E138K, a G→A mutation in the human immunodeficiency virus type 1 (HIV-1) reverse transcriptase (RT), is preferentially selected by etravirine (ETR) and rilpivirine (RPV) over other substitutions at position E138 that offer greater drug resistance. We hypothesized that there was a mutational bias for the E138K substitution and designed an allele-specific PCR to monitor the emergence of E138A/G/K/Q/R/V during ETR or RPV selection experiments. E138K, as well as E138G, consistently emerged first during selection experiments, followed by E138A, E138Q and E138R. Surprisingly, E138K was identified as a minority in 23% of drug-naïve subtype B patients, and was not further enriched in patients with the M184I substitution. The high prevalence of E138K minority species could reflect a low fitness cost of E138K; however, E138K was one of the least fit substitutions at codon E138, even after taking into account the dNTP pools of the cells used in competition experiments. Ultra-deep sequencing analysis revealed other minority species in a pattern consistent with the mutational bias of HIV-1 RT. These results confirm the mutational bias of HIV-1 in patients and highlight the importance of G→A mutations in HIV-1 drug resistance evolution.This G→A bias reflects enriched adenosine in HIV-1 codons, a feature that is mysteriously targeted by the anti-HIV-1 restriction factor, Schlafen family protein 11 (SLFN11). Our in silico modeling of SLFN11 suggested putative structure-function relationships and a relation to Ski2-family RNA helicases.</description><description>E138K, une mutation G → A dans l'immunodéficience humaine de type virus humain 1 (VIH-1) et dans la transcriptase inverse (TI), est de préférence choisie par l'étravirine (ETR) et rilpivirine (RPV) plutôt que d'autres substitutions à la position E138 qui offrent une plus grande résistance. Nous avons supposé qu'il y avait un biais mutationnel pour la substitution E138K et conçu une PCR allèle spécifique pour surveiller l'émergence de E138A/G/K/Q/R/V lors d'expériences de sélection avec ETR ou RPV. E138K, ainsi que E138G, constamment apparue au cours d'expériences de sélection, suivi d'E138A, E138Q et E138R. Étonnamment, E138K a été identifiée comme une infime minorité dans 23% des cas de sous-type B de patients naïfs aux médicaments, et n'a pas augmenté chez les patients atteints de la substitution M184I. La prévalence élevée des espèces minoritaires de E138K pourrait refléter un faible coût de remise en forme de E138K, mais E138K était l'un des substitutions moins performants au niveau du codon E138, même après avoir pris en compte la concentration de dNTP dans cellules utilisées dans des expériences de compétition. Une analyse de séquençage en profondeure a révélé d'autres espèces minoritaires dans un modèle cohérent avec le biais mutationnel du VIH-1 TI. Ces résultats soulignent l'importance de G → A mutations du VIH-1 dans l'évolution de la résistance aux médicaments.Ce G → A biais a enrichi l'adénosine dans le codons VIH-1, une fonctionnalité qui est mystérieusement ciblé par le facteur anti-VIH-1 restriction, Schlafen protéine de la famille 11 (SLFN11). Notre modélisation in silico de SLFN11 suggère des relations structure/fonction présumée et une relation à l'hélicase ARN de famille Ski2.</description><creator>McCallum, Matthew</creator><contributor>Mark Wainberg (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Virology</subject><title>Mutational bias and emergence of drug resistance in the human immunodeficiency virus type 1</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wh246w292.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b432n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):12800</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>