<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:43:43Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40150" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128ng49h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description> Une analyse de la co-variabilité entre la température de                l'air au sol (SAT) ainsi que les précipitations en Amérique du Nord et la température                de l'océan Pacifique à la surface (SST), a été faite en utilisant la méthode SVD. Le                mode dominant de la SVD a révélé une relation forte entre les anomalies de la SST du                mois de novembre et celles de la SAT et des précipitations hivernales. Ce lien est                beaucoup plus faible en été. Le modèle GCM3 reproduit assez bien la réponse au                forçage de la SST, particulièrement sur les patrons de la SAT, mais sa réponse est                beaucoup moins précise en été. Les prévisions mensuelles et saisonnières de GCM3 ont                aussi été analysées. Les capacités de GCM3 à prévoir les précipitations sont faibles,                surtout en été où le forçage de la SST est aussi faible. De plus, le modèle ne                possède pas d'habiletés notables à prédire les sécheresses dans les prairies                Canadiennes. Par contre, les capacités prévisionnelles du modèle concernant la SAT et                le géopotentiel à 500 hPa sont généralement assez élevées, particulièrement en                hivers. Les habiletés de GCM3 sont concentrées dans le premier mois de la période de                prévision, puis déclinent lorsque le délai d'émission est prolongé.</description><description> An analysis of the co-variability of surface air temperature and                precipitation over North America and Pacific SST is conducted using an SVD analysis.                The leading SVD mode revealed a strong link between November SST anomalies and winter                surface air temperature (SAT) and precipitation anomalies. In summer this                relationship is much weaker. In winter GCM3 captured well the Pacific SST forcing and                its response, particularly on the SAT pattern, but its response is less accurate in                the summer. The monthly and seasonal forecasts using GCM3 are also analyzed.                Precipitation forecasts showed little skill, especially in the warm season where the                SST forcing is weak. Furthermore, GCM3 has low seasonal predictive skill in                forecasting drought events over the Canadian prairies. However, the model has                generally good predictive skill for 500 hPa heights and SAT, with higher scores in                the winter. The skill is concentrated in the first month of the prediction period and                decreases as the lead time is extended to one month.</description><creator>Aider, Rabah</creator><contributor>Jacques F Derome (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Charles A Lin (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Atmospheric Sciences</subject><title>Skill of monthly and seasonal forecasts using a Canadian general circulation model</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892c69h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128ng49h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hm50tt44f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Raising Fathers, Raising Boys: Informal Education and                Enculturation in Britain, 1880-1914 est une étude des préoccupations populaires                vis-à-vis la masculinité [manliness], de l'enfance et l'adolescence masculines et de                la paternité, situés dans un contexte contemporain caractérisé par une inquiétude                régnante face à l'efficacité nationale, le vice public et la moralité privée. Cette                thèse démontre l'existence d'un consensus de plus en plus marqué parmi les éditeurs                de la littérature populaire pour les enfants, (particulièrement pour garçons) sur le                fait que l'éducation formelle que recevaient leurs jeunes lecteurs (que ce soit dans                des écoles élite, ou, après la loi de 1870, dans les nouvelles institutions                d'éducation de masse) leur faisait défaut, et, de plus, que les parents de la nation                étaient inaptes à leur transmettre certains impératifs moraux, et ce, peu importe                leurs origines géographiques ou sociales. En insistant sur la continuité de                l'influence religieuse dans la vie quotidienne des enfants de l'époque (contestant                donc la thèse de sécularisation défendue par plusieurs historiens), cette thèse met                en évidence la mise en accord de groupes hétéroclites sur l'importance d'une                dissémination des valeurs chrétiennes au sein d'une éducation visant à créer des                hommes à la fois domestiques et véritablement mâles, et de bons pères. L'accent mis                ici sur la vie familiale est crucial, car il permet d'élargir les courants                historiographiques focalisant sur les implications impérialistes de l'éducation des                élites et la tendance des classes moyennes à « fuire la sphère domestique » qu'on a                appelé « flight from domesti</description><description>Raising Fathers, Raising Boys: Informal Education and Enculturation in                Britain, 1880-1914 is primarily focused on popular preoccupations surrounding                masculinity (manliness), boyhood, adolescence, and fatherhood, in the context of                widespread concerns about national efficiency, public vice, and private morals at the                fin de siècle. This thesis reveals the growing consensus amongst the publishers of                juvenile literature that children (especially boys) of all areas and social                backgrounds were being failed by the various institutions of formal education (be                they the elite public schools or the new schools springing up since the Education Act                of 1870), and that certain moral imperatives were being inadequately met by the                nation's parents. Stressing the continuity of religious influence in the everyday                experience of children throughout the late-Victorian and Edwardian period (and                thereby challenging the secularization thesis put forward by some scholars), this                study charts the agreement established between disparate groups on the importance of                disseminating Christian values for the task of raising the nation's boys into manly,                domesticated men and good fathers. This emphasis on family life is crucial, since it                broadens the current historiographical focus on the imperial connotations of elite                education and the supposed middle-class "flight from domesticity." By showing that                masculinity was not only about patriarchal or imperial outlooks, the work explicates                the meaning of fatherhood in the period, stressing the continuing importance and                validation of men as fathers and of the boy "as father to the man." The major sources                for the thesis arise out of a variety of religious organi</description><creator>Olsen, Stephanie</creator><contributor>J Elizabeth Elbourne (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Brian D A Lewis (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>History - Modern</subject><title>Raising fathers, raising boys: informal education and enculturation in Britain, 1880-1914</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dx25t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tt44f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zw29t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recent efforts in microprocessor development tend to the coexistence of                several Central Processing Units (CPUs) on a single chip. The Cell Broadband Engine                (CBE), the fruit of collaboration between Sony, Toshiba and IBM, integrates IBM's                legacy PowerPC CPU with a new set of simple cores, all of which communicate through a                high speed bus. The multiple cores on the CBE allow users to exploit the parallel                nature of their programs. However, it is often difficult to effciently extract the                parallelism from an application and to distribute tasks in a suitable fashion. We                propose a dataﬂow approach to CBE computing where the compiler is in charge of task                partitioning and of the infrastructure for runtime distribution of tasks. In this                work, we present the NCC programming language, Squid compiler and runtime                environment. NCC is a strict functional dataﬂow language that forces explicit                variable dependencies, in order to exploit parallelism in the application. NCC code                is thus written by the user without specifying parallelism explicitly. The Squid                Compiler draws a virtual data ﬂow graph from the NCC source. This graph is then                partitionned according to implementation specific criteria into tasks and supertasks.                The individual tasks are then translated to ANSI-C, and supertasks are analyzed and                transformed into scheduling structures. All tasks are executed by the CBE's simple                cores. The Squid Runtime Environment (SRE) interacts with the generated scheduler to                order tasks' execution, running the supertasks' scheduling, and managing garbage                collection. The SRE runs on the CBE's PowerPC core as a separate thread to implement                a host-device paradigm, and as resident code on the s</description><description>Les récents efforts en développement de microprocesseurs                tendent à une coexistence entre plusieurs Unités Centrales (UC) sur une seule puce.                Le Cell Broadband Engine (CBE), le fruit d'une collaboration entre Sony, Toshiba et                IBM, intègre le CU patrimonial d'IBM PowerPC, avec un nouvel ensemble d'unités                simples, communiquant entre elles avec un bus de haute vitesse. Les nombreueses                unités présentes dans le CBE permettent aux utilisateurs d'exploiter la nature                parallèle de leurs programmes. Cependant, il est souvent difficile d'extraire le                parallélisme d'une application et de distribuer des tâches de façon appropriée. Nous                proposons donc d'approcher la programmation du CBE sous une perspective de ﬂux de                données où le compilateur est chargé de partitionner les tâches et de                l'infrastructure de la distribution des tâches. Dans ce travail, nous présentons la                langue de programmation NCC, le compilateur et l'environnement d'exécution Squid. NCC                est un langage fonctionnel stricte de ﬂux, qui force les entre variables à être                explicites, aﬁn d'exploiter le parallelisme d'une application. Le code NCC est donc                rédigé par l'utilsateur sans spéciﬁer le parallelisme explicitement. Le compilateur                Squid dessine un graphe de ﬂux de données virtuel issu du code NCC. Ce graphe est                partitionné selon des critères particuliers à l'implémentation en tâches et                supertâches. Chaque tâche est ensuite traduite en ANSI-C, et les supertâches sont                analysées et transformées en structures d'ordonnançement. Toutes les tâches sont                exécutées par les untiés simples du CBE. L'Environnement d'Exécution Squid (EES)                interagit avec l'ordonnanceur pour ordonner$</description><creator>Azuelos, Nathaniel</creator><contributor>Warren Gross (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Zeljko Zilic (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>An integrated functional solution for multi-core programming on the cell broadband engine</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pf79k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zw29t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gm746</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Coatomer proteins 1 (COPI) are recruited to Golgi membranes in an ADP                ribosylation factor 1(ARF1)-dependent manner that couples protein sorting to vesicle                formation. Using a modified intra-Golgi transport assay with highly purified COPI                vesicles, we demonstrate that fusion of retrograde-directed vesicles with Golgi                membranes requires phosphatidylinositol 4,5-bisphosphate (PI(4,5)P2). The dependency                on PI(4,5)P2 appears to be COPI vesicle associated since pre-treatment of the                vesicles with either a specific 5'phosphatase or a 5'kinase resulted in inhibition or                gain of fusion, respectively. In contrast, corresponding pre-treatment of Lec1 Golgi                target membranes had no effect on the efficiency or extent of COPI vesicle fusion                with the Lec1 Golgi membranes. We continued our investigation in order to determine                the identity of the protein(s) recruited by PI(4,5)P2 which enable the fusion                process. Using Protease K (PK) treatment of both vesicles and target Lec1 Golgi to                investigate the cytoplasmic protein requirements, we detected a marked asymmetry                between the target Golgi and COPI vesicles, as PK treated vesicles were still able to                fuse with limited cytoplasmic proteins while target Golgi rapidly lost all                fusogenicity. Kinetic evaluation of vesicles treated as such observed a decrease in                the binding constant, however we observe little or no effect on the actual fusion                constant. Furthermore, we were able to identify a Protease K resistant core of                Golgin-84 whose location was limited to fusogenic COPI vesicles. Investigation of a                potential link between Golgin-84 and PI(4,5)P2 was unsuccessful. We were also able to                determine that while the Golgin-84 resistant core was necessar</description><description>Les protéines de coatomer de type 1 (COPI) sont recrutées                par l'appareil de Golgi sous l'action de l'activité de la protéine ADP-Ribolysation                factor 1 (ARF1), ce qui permet d'associer la formation de vésicules et                l'incorporation spécifique des protéines et lipides qui forment ces vésicules. Avec                l'aide d'un protocole expérimental mesurant le transport intra-Golgien, nous avons                démontré que la fusion de vésicules COPI rétrograde est dépendante de la présence de                phosphatidylinositol 4,5-bisphosphates (PI(4,5)P2). Cette dépendance apparaît                associée aux vésicules COPI étant donné que leur prétraitement en présence de                5'kinase ou 5'phosphatase spécifique résulte en une activation ou inhibition                respective. De façon contrastante, le même prétraitement des membranes de Golgi                cibles issues de cellules CHO Lec1 n'affecte pas la fusion entre les vésicules et les                membranes de Golgi. Nous avons continué notre investigation pour déterminer                l'identité des protéines recrutées par PI(4,5)P2 qui permettent la fusion. Avec                l'aide de l'enzyme protéase K (PK), nous avons détecté une asymétrie entre les                vésicules COPI ainsi que les membranes de l'appareil de Golgi : tandis que les                vésicules étaient en grande partie résistantes au traitement avec PK, les membranes                de Golgi se montraient très susceptibles et perdaient toute fusogenicité. Une                évaluation cinétique des vésicules soumis à ce traitement a permis de détecter une                diminution du rythme d'association des vésicules mais aucun ou très peu de changement                significatif du rythme de fusion ne fut détecté. De plus, nous avons identifié un                noyau de la protéine Golgin-84 résistant au traite</description><creator>Laporte, Frederic</creator><contributor>John J M Bergeron (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Cell</subject><title>Characterization of the fusogenic properties of COPl vesicles: a role for Pl(4,5)P2</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33rz46c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gm746</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rf55z963t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Visual-spatial cognition was examined in typically developing children.                Fifty-six children between 3- to 10-years-old completed a comprehensive battery of                cognitive tasks that tapped 8 components of visual-spatial functioning. Results                demonstrate that task complexity and age interact across the majority of                visual-spatial sub-domains, with visual-spatial competencies increasing linearly with                age. Examination of acquisition rates showed that after 8 years of age children are                capable of performing each measure significantly better than chance.                Gender-age-related findings suggest males demonstrate superior visual-spatial mental                rotation skills only until 9-10 years of age, than females begin to surpass males.                Visual-spatial cognition and mathematical performance was also investigated in                typical children. Children's visual-spatial mental rotation and manipulation and                visual-spatial directionality abilities were positively correlated with mathematical                performance.</description><description>Visual-cognition spatiale a été examinée dans le                développement général des enfants. Cinquante-six enfants âgés de 3 - à 10 ans, mené à                bien une batterie de tâches cognitives qui écoute 8 composantes de l'espace visuel                fonctionnement. Les résultats démontrent la complexité de cette tâche et de l'âge                d'interagir à travers la majorité de l'espace visuel sous-domaines, avec des                compétences visuo-spatiales croissant linéairement avec l'âge. L'examen des taux                d'acquisition a montré que, après 8 ans d'âge, les enfants sont capables d'effectuer                des chaque mesure nettement mieux que la chance. Entre les sexes liées à l'âge                résultats suggèrent hommes démontrer supérieure visuelle-spatiale mental rotation                compétences que jusqu'à 9-10 ans, que les femmes commencent à dépasser les hommes.                Visual-cognition spatiale et de mathématiques de performance a également été étudiée                dans le type d'enfants. Children's visuelle-spatiale de rotation et de la                manipulation mentale et visuelle-spatiale directionalité capacités ont été                positivement corrélé avec la performance mathématique.</description><creator>Williamson, Meagan</creator><contributor>Kim Cornish (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Education - Psychology</subject><title>Deconstructing visual-spatial cognition in typically developing children</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268698q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55z963t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xg714</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During recent years, application of light metals has greatly increased                in various industries. Magnesium, the lightest of structural metals, and its alloys                have gained special attention, and, therefore, the interest in modeling the behavior                of these alloys has increased. In many studies, the goal has been finding ways to                improve the low formability of Mg alloys. In this thesis, the effect of slip system                activity on Mg alloy behavior in both the pre- and post-localization zones is                examined. An available crystal plasticity model, that takes into account the initial                texture of the material and its evolution with deformation, is modified for the case                of HCP materials, and, then, implemented into the commercial finite element software                ABAQUS. Employing the crystal plasticity finite element (CPFE) method, the link                between micro-deformation on the slip systems in Mg alloys and the macro-scale                response of these metals is established. The model is verified for the case of Mg                single crystals which are highly anisotropic. The minimum required size of the                representative volume element (RVE), i.e. the minimum number of grains and the degree                of inhomogeneity in each grain required in the CPFE modeling of Mg alloys is                determined. Next, the role of different slip systems present in Mg alloys is studied.                The effects of strain-rate sensitivity on the micro- and macro-scale behavior of the                material and the link between them are also discussed. Using the observed trends for                the slip resistances and strain-rate sensitivity factor, new relations are proposed                for the change in these values over the range of warm temperatures (75-250°C). The                mechanical response of samples cut from hot-rolled</description><description>Au cours des dernières années, l'application de métaux                légers a augmenté dans diverses industries. Le magnésium, le plus léger des métaux                structuraux, et ses alliages ont acquis une attention particulière et, par                conséquent, l'intérêt pour la modélisation du comportement de ces métaux a augmenté.                Dans des nombreuses études, l'objectif a été de trouver les moyens d'améliorer la                formabilité des alliages de Mg. Dans cette thèse, l'effet de l'activité du système de                glissage sur le comportement de l'alliage de Mg dans les zones de pré- et                post-localisation est examiné. Un modèle de plasticité cristalline disponible, qui                prend en compte la texture initiale du matériau et de son évolution avec la                déformation, est modifié pour le cas des matériaux à structure hexagonale compacte,                et, ensuite, mis en œuvre dans le programme de calculs d'éléments finis, ABAQUS.                Employant la méthode des éléments finis à plasticité cristalline (EFPC), le lien                entre la microdéformation sur les systèmes de glissages des alliages du Mg et la                réponse à l'échelle macroscopique de ces métaux est établie. Le modèle est vérifié                pour le cas des monocristaux de Mg qui sont fortement anisotropes. La taille minimale                prescrite de l'élément volumique représentatif (EVR), c'est-à-dire le nombre minimal                de grains et le degré d'hétérogénéité dans chaque grain requis dans la modélisation                EFPC des alliages du Mg, est déterminée. Ensuite, le rôle des différents systèmes de                glissage dans les alliages Mg est étudié. Les effets de la sensibilité à la vitesse                de déformation sur le comportement du matériau aux échelles micro- et macroscopique                et le$</description><creator>Shahi, Mohsen</creator><contributor>Stephen Yue (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>James Nemes (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical</subject><title>Crystal plasticity finite element modeling of slip system activity and post-localization behavior in magnesium alloys</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s201j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xg714</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26z024c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Leishmania peroxin 7 (LmPEX7 or LdPEX7) is the receptor that                translocates PTS2 signal-containing proteins into the glycosome. This microbody is                unique to and crucial for the survival of trypanosomatids which include Leishmania                and Trypanosoma, the causative agents of leishmaniasis and African sleeping sickness,                respectively. Proteins are imported into the glycosome via two pathways, PTS1 and                PTS2, which involves the formation of a PTS-receptor complex in the cytosol, docking                of the complex on a translocation apparatus on the glycosomal membrane, and                subsequent release of the cargo protein into the lumen. However, the precise steps in                glycosome protein trafficking are not well-defined and to understand the function of                these organelles and prove their potential as chemotherapeutic targets, the mechanism                of glycosome biogenesis needs to be fully elucidated. Not much is known about the                mechanism of PTS2 import pathway in glycosomes as studies on PEX7 have been hampered                by the difficulty in expressing a soluble recombinant form of this receptor. To                dissect the PTS2 import pathway and to determine the role of PEX7 in Leishmania, this                protein was cloned and characterized. LmPEX7 is a ~41 kDa protein containing six                conserved WD40 motifs that displays limited sequence similarity to PEX7 homologues                involved in the biogenesis of evolutionarily-related peroxisomes found in other                eukaryotes. LmPEX7 interacts with PTS2 proteins, the PTS1 receptor LdPEX5, and the                membrane-associated docking protein LdPEX14. These interactions, characterized                through various biochemical techniques, were mediated by specific binding domains,                formation of stable protein-protein complexes, and conform</description><description>La péroxine Leishmania 7 (LmPEX7 ou LdPEX7) est un                récepteur qui transloque les protéines qui contiennent le signal PTS2 dans le                glycosome. Ce glycosome est unique et critique aux trypanosomes, tels que Leishmania                et Trypanosoma, les agents causant la leishmaniose et la maladie Africaine du                sommeil. Les protéines sont importées vers le glycosome par deux voies, PTS1 et PTS2,                qui nécessitent la formation d'un complexe PTS dans le cytosol, l'amarrage du                complexe sur un appareil de translocation sur la membrane du glycosome, et permet la                liberation de la charge protéique dans le lumen. Par contre, les étapes précises dans                l'acheminement de protéines glycosomales ne sont pas bien définies et pour comprendre                les fonctions de ces organelles et prouver qu'elles être des cibles                chimiothérapiques, les mécanismes impliqués dans la biogenèse doivent être très bien                élucidés. Pour disséquer le mécanisme d'importation et pour déterminer le rôle de                PEX7 chez Leishmania, cette protéine a été clonée à partir de l'ADN génomique de L.                major et a été caractérisée. LmPEX7 est une protéine d'environ 41 kDa qui démontre                une homologie limitée aux PEX7 impliqués dans la biogenèse des peroxysomes chez                autres eucaryotes. LmPEX7 interagit avec les protéines PTS2, le récepteur PTS1                LdPEX5, ainsi que la protéine LdPEX14 qui est associée à la membrane du glycosome.                Ces intéractions, décrites en utilisant des techniques biochimiques variées, sont                arbitrés par des domaines d'interactions situés sur LdPEX5 et LdPEX14, la formation                de complexes protéiques stables, et associée à divers changements conformationnels.                Des études de localisation subcellula</description><creator>Pilar, Ana Victoria</creator><contributor>Armando Jardim (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Parasitology</subject><title>Biochemical and molecular characterization of the glycosomal PTS2 import receptor peroxin 7 in «Leishmania donovani»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397b04d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z024c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913r66v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Approximately 70% of the total sensory receptors in the human body                reside in the eye and they provide 80% of the acquired information during life. The                initial stage of activating these sensory receptors is the light interaction with                photoreceptors, which are the cells covering the retinal surface at the back of the                eye. Photoreceptors are different in physical dimension and also in chemical                composition, which defines their role in vision. While the absorption of the light is                governed by the chemical composition inside the outer-segment of photoreceptors, due                to the wave guiding nature of the photoreceptor, the shape and dimensions of                outer-segment may also affect the absorbed spectrum. To the best of our knowledge,                this thesis is the first comprehensive numerical study of the light interaction with                the human retinal photoreceptor to understand the role of diversity in the physical                dimensions of the photoreceptor. Due to the inherent complexity of experimental                studies, the well known finite-difference time-domain (FDTD) method has been adopted                to investigate the optical characteristics of the human photoreceptor. Previous                numerical studies of the photoreceptor were limited to 2-dimensional (2-D) FDTD                analysis due to the higher computational complexity of 3-dimensional (3-D)                simulations. This limitation can affect the number of identified electromagnetic                modes propagating inside the outer-segment. Consequently, although 2-D models offer                valuable insight, they lack in accuracy of physical representation. In this thesis,                we conduct a 3-D FDTD study of the light interaction with the human retinal                outer-segment in order to fully assess its optical properties. Our results, wh</description><description>Environ 70% de tous les récepteurs sensoriels dans le                corps humain résident dans l'oeil et ils fournissent 80% d'informations acquises                pendant la vie. L'étape initiale d'activer ces récepteurs sensoriels est                l'interaction de la lumière avec les photorécepteurs qui sont des cellules qui                couvrent la surface rétinienne au fond de l'œil. Les photorécepteurs sont différents                dans les dimensions physiques et également en composition chimiques, qui définit leur                rôle dans la vision. Tandis que l'absorption de la lumière est régie par la                composition chimique à l'intérieur du segment externe, dû à la nature du guidage des                ondes électromagnétiques dans le photorécepteur, la forme et les dimensions du                segment externe peuvent également affecter le spectre de la lumière absorbé. Au                meilleur de notre connaissance, cette thèse est la première étude numérique complète                de l'interaction de la lumière avec le photorécepteur humain pour comprendre le rôle                de la diversité dans les dimensions physiques du photorécepteur. En raison de la                complexité inhérente des études expérimentales, la méthode bien connue des                différences finies dans le domaine temporel (FDTD) a été adoptée pour étudier les                caractéristiques optiques du photorécepteur humain. Précédemment, les études                numériques du photorécepteur ont été limitées à des analyses FDTD en deux dimensions                (2-D) due à une complexité plus élevé des codes de calculs en trois dimensions (3-D).                Cette limitation peut affecter le nombre de modes électromagnétiques identifiés                propageant à l'intérieur du segment externe du photorécepteur. En conséquence, bien                que les modèles 2-D offrent la$</description><creator>Haji Aboli, Amir</creator><contributor>Milica Popovich (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Biomedical</subject><title>Light interaction with the human retinal photoreceptor: finite-difference time-domain analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b296s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913r66v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h702q8091</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Agnes Laut (Ontario, 1871 – New York, 1936) was a Canadian journalist,                novelist, financial advisor, and a farmer who became closely involved with United                States-Mexico relations during the Mexican Revolution (1910-1921). This research                analyses Agnes Laut's editorial work, travels, and publications about Mexico and its                social strife. Furthermore, it explores her role as coordinator among US civic and                religious associations aiming to relieve Mexico's social troubles through                humanitarian aide. This thesis is a first approach to the study of the impact of                foreign civic society and philanthropic organizations in revolutionary Mexico.</description><description>Agnes Laut (Ontario, 1871 – New York, 1936) était une                journaliste canadienne, romancière, conseillère financière et une fermière qui était                étroitement engagé dans les relations entre les États-Unis et le Mexique pendant la                Révolution mexicaine (1910-1921). Cette investigation analyse les travaux éditoriaux,                les voyages et les articles publiés d'Agnes Laut sur la problématique de Mexique. En                plus, cette recherche étudie son rôle comme liaison entre les organisations civiques                et religieuses des États-Unis et son but de améliorer la situation troublé de la                population au Mexique à travers de la philanthropie. Cette thèse est un premier                effort pour étudier l'effet des organisations civiques étrangères dans le Mexique                révolutionnaire au début du XXème siècle.</description><creator>Ortega Jimenez, Grisell</creator><contributor>Catherine C LeGrand (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>History - Latin American</subject><title>A Canadian woman takes an interest in troubled Mexico: Agnes C. Laut's journalistic and philanthropic work in revolutionary Mexico, 1913-1921</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t101z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h702q8091</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x346d607m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since there exist drawbacks for linear models such as those based on regression techniques, which have been the basis of traditional statistical forecasting models, neural networks are used in this thesis to train and test the input data. This thesis presents a feedforward backpropagation neural network approach to univariate time series analysis. Real world observations of foreign exchange rates in twenty currencies against U.S. dollars have been applied as a study in this experiment. Feedforward connectionist networks have been designed to model daily exchange rates over the period from January 4, 1999 to October 20, 2000. The values of the root mean square error (RMSE) is used as the criterion of selecting the parameters of the training set, testing set, the numbers of the hidden nodes and epochs, the momentum terms and the learning rates. The models obtained in this study by using this method can be used to forecast the movement of these exchange rates. Before analyzing neural network techniques, data preprocessing and correlation analysis are presented. It is found there exist three correlation situations: the currencies between member countries in European Economic Community (EEC) have very strong correlation relationship; the correlations between Chinese Renminbi and the other currencies are very weak; and the correlations between the other currencies are variable with the change of the time period. They are related to the different finance policy, economic situation and the other factors of each country with the different time period.</description><creator>Wu, Qionglin, 1964-</creator><contributor>Newborn, Monty (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Information Science.</subject><subject>Economics, General.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><subject>Artificial Intelligence.</subject><title>Data mining and knowledge discovery in financial research : empirical investigations into currency</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75df42h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d607m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d504rn14c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Schneiderian papillomas (SP) are tumors arising from the surface epithelium (Schneiderian epithelium) of the nasal cavity and paranasal sinuses. Evidence points towards a viral etiology, specifically Human papillomavirus (HPV). Although substantial data indicates HPV as a likely etiology, little is known about the role of HPV in benign nasal pathologies or in normal nasal mucosa. Objective. To characterize the role of HPV in SP, chronic sinusitis (CS) and its prevalence in normal nasal mucosa. A case controlled study was undertaken, matching patients with SP to patients with chronic sinusitis (CS). Patients with normal nasal mucosa served as a control group. All patients had their tissues analyzed for the presence of various HPV types using polymerase chain reaction (PCR) coupled with a line blot assay. Results. A total of 168 patients were identified (74 SP, 74 CS, 20 control). Of these, 70 (41.7%) had detectable DNA, and 9/70 (12.9%) had detectable HPV of types 6, 11, and 16. None had detectable HPV type 18. Significant differences were detected in the presence of HPV in CS, SP and control groups, as well as in the presence of low risk versus high-risk types amongst investigation and control groups. Conclusions. Significant differences exist in the distribution of HPV between SP, benign nasal pathologies such as CS and normal nasal mucosa. HPV may play an important role, at least as cofactor, in the development of SP, with types 6, 11 and 16 more pivotal than other types. Line blot assay may provide a useful technique in identifying HPV in SP.</description><creator>Yoskovitch, Adi.</creator><contributor>Frenkiel, Saul (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Franco, Eduardo (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Analysis of human papillomavirus in Schneiderian papillomas as compared to chronic sinusitis and normal nasal mucosa</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rv042v76w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rn14c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Otolaryngology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xg72d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>To further our understanding of the complex pathophysiology of human sickle cell disease (SCD) and to develop better therapies, three transgenic mouse lines have been produced that survive on mostly human hemoglobin (Hb). These lines have been generated by crossing HbSAD (SAD) transgenic mice with other mice carrying a null deletion of the endogenous globin genes (alpha or beta), SAD/homozygous alpha-globin null (SADalpha -/-) mice display a SCD-like phenotype and have a dramatically reduced mean lifespan; therefore, this line provides a novel model for assessment of anti-sickling protocols or identifying epistatic modifiers genes. Intriguingly, SAD/heterozygous alpha-globin null (SADalpha+/-) mice have a mild phenotype compared to SAD mice. In stark contrast, the highest cellular HbSAD fraction and degree of in vivo sickling was obtained in SAD/compound heterozygous alpha- and beta-globin null (SADalpha +/-beta+/-) mice. These SADalpha +/-beta+/- mice display chronic anemia and delayed growth indicative of a severe phenotype, similar to the human HbSS phenotype.</description><creator>Wright, Adrian C.</creator><contributor>Trudel, Marie (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>Three transgenic hemoglobin SAD (S-Antilles, -Punjab), partial-"knockout" murine models of human sickle cell disease : the generation and phenotypic analysis of SAD mice with (1) heterozygous-null deletion of the murine a-globin genes, (2) homozygous-null deletion of the murine a-globin genes, and (3) heterozygous null deletions of the murine a- and b-globin genes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pc35d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xg72d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r288t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>E-commerce is a new way of doing business. It is becoming increasingly important to everybody. The objective of this thesis is to compare various design approaches and to find out the best solution for small businesses. Some commonly used technologies in developing e-commerce systems are introduced in the first three chapters. The topics covered are from Web standards and protocols to Web planning and design, from Web servers to server side programming, and most importantly, Java technology and IBM's WebSphere. Based on these technologies, two solutions are presented: building from scratch with Java servlets and building with IBM's WebSphere. We develop an online store with each of the solutions. The last part of the thesis is a comprehensive comparison. Time, complexity, performance and cost are evaluated in this comparison. A simple conclusion is drawn afterwards with our suggestions to small businesses regarding which solution they should choose.</description><creator>Yu, Xing, 1974-</creator><contributor>Newborn, Monty (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Business Administration, Marketing.</subject><subject>Mass Communications.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Comparing electronic commerce solutions for small businesses</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h144q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r288t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m039k6922</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Folate deficiency, a prevalent vitamin deficiency in America, can stem from environmental and/or genetic causes. The most common inborn error of folate metabolism is deficiency of methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase (MTHFR), which catalyzes the reduction of 5,10-methylenetetrahydrofolate to 5-methyltetrahydrofolate. Severe MTHFR deficiency results in hyperhomocysteinemia and homocystinuria; patients present with developmental delay, and various neurological and vascular disorders. This thesis describes three mutations identified in the MTHFR locus in patients with severe deficiency: 1025T→C (M→T), 1027T→G (W→G), and 1768G→A (E→K). Genotype-phenotype correlations are described, along with biochemical characterization of three mutations (983A→G (N→S), 1025T→C, 1027T→G). All three mutations exert their effect by decreasing Vmax without changing the enzyme's affinity for its substrate, 5-methyltetrahydrofolate. The 983A→G variant also conferred decreased affinity for FAD, a cofactor. The more common and mild deficiency observed in the general healthy population is probably due in part to insufficient dietary intake of folate. Folate deficiency has been associated with increased risk for colon cancer. In a pilot study presented here, the impact of altered folate intake on tumor multiplicity in the Min mouse, a model for multiple intestinal neoplasia, was assessed. Folate deficient diets did not produce a consistent change in tumor numbers. However, a linear correlation between S-adenosylmethionine and S-adenosylhomocysteine content of preneoplastic tissue and tumor multiplicity was identified. This thesis contributes to our understanding of the impact of genetic- and/or dietary-induced folate deficiency on cellular and organismal functions.</description><creator>Sibani, Sahar.</creator><contributor>Rozen, Rima (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Colon (Anatomy) -- Cancer -- Pathogenesis.</subject><subject>Methylenetetrahydrofolate reductase</subject><subject>Homocysteine -- Metabolism.</subject><subject>Homocystinuria -- etiology.</subject><subject>Folic acid -- Metabolism -- Disorders -- Genetic aspects.</subject><subject>Folic acid deficiency.</subject><title>Genetic and nutritional folate deficiency : implications for homocystinuria and intestinal neoplasia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732db79v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k6922</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:73666639c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Habitat selection by, ecological energetics of, and the effects of changes in white pine (Pinus strobus L.) forests on Red Crossbills (Loxia curvirostra) were studied in Algonquin Provincial Park, Ontario. Birds were surveyed in several forest habitats and daily activities were observed during the breeding season in the autumn of 1998, a good year for white pine seed production. During the autumn of 1997 and summer of 1998, surveys of white pine stumps from trees harvested in the mid-late 1800s were conducted. Breeding birds foraged in stands with a minimum of 40% white pine, and appeared to prefer stands, both mixed deciduous-coniferous (40--70% white pine) and pine (&gt;70% white pine) along roads. Possible reasons for this were: (1) seeds from trees along the road were more available to birds; (2) open-grown trees along the road had larger crowns with more seeds; and (3) the road provided grit and was adjacent to a favorite foraging area. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Simard, Julie H.</creator><contributor>Titman, Rodger (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Thompson, Ian D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Habitat selection.</subject><subject>Red crossbill -- Habitat -- Ontario -- Algonquin Provincial Park.</subject><subject>White pine -- Ontario -- Algonquin Provincial Park.</subject><subject>Red crossbill -- Ontario -- Algonquin Provincial Park -- Reproduction.</subject><title>Habitat selection, ecological energetics, and the effects of changes in white pine forests on breeding red crossbills (Loxia curvirostra) in Algonquin Provincial Park, Ontario</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xw849.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666639c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8s45qb66r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study was conducted to understand the interactions between irrigation water management and water quality (agro-ecological interactions). The Uda Walawe basin, in Southern Sri Lanka was chosen as the study area. Fluctuations in water quality, especially microbiological water quality, affect human health. Since the source of domestic water (drinking and washing) in this region is from the irrigation system, there is a concern for the human health effects. All the potential water sources and the water use habits of the community were identified. The water quality of these sources was then monitored for a period of 5 months (August--December 2000). Second, the water management of the Uda Walawe irrigation system was linked to the differences in water quality. The best quality water was found to come from the shallow wells (seepage water from the irrigation system). Both quantity and quality of the water were shown to fluctuate with canal construction (earthen or concrete) and irrigation water management.</description><creator>Shortt, Rebecca L.</creator><contributor>Madramootoo, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Waterborne infection -- Sri Lanka.</subject><subject>Irrigation -- Sri Lanka -- Management.</subject><subject>Water quality -- Sri Lanka.</subject><title>Water quality and health : implications for irrigation management in southern Sri Lanka</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pc36p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qb66r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75r960g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explored the association between maternal use of medication during pregnancy and risk of childhood acute lymphocytic leukemia (ALL); specifically, whether use of antibiotics, analgesics, anti-nauseas and/or illicit drugs were associated with an increased risk of ALL in the offspring. All cases of ALL, aged 0--14, diagnosed in Quebec during the period 1994--1997 were identified and matched to population-based controls by age and sex. With an overall response rate of 87%, this resulted in nearly 160 case-control pairs. Information was obtained from parents via telephone interviews, and analyzed using conditional logistic regression. Overall use of medication did not increase risk of childhood ALL (OR = 1.15, 95% CI = 0.66--1.99). Increased risks were observed for illicit drug use in the year prior to birth (OR = 2.44, 95% CI = 0.66--9.00), and for the offspring of women who used pain medication during delivery (OR = 1.88, 95% CI = 1.05--3.31); however, the latter increase was seen for male children only (OR = 3.43, 95% CI = 1.45--8.10).</description><creator>Shaw, Amanda K.</creator><contributor>Infante-Rivard, Claire (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Maternal use of medication and childhood leukemia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278w09g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75r960g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mx35k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Our objective was to study the effect of GLN supplementation on whole body protein turnover, somatic growth and gastrointestinal tolerance to enteral feeding in neonates following surgical stress. We hypothesized that GLN in total parenteral nutrition (TPN) would (1) favor retention of lean body mass by reducing protein breakdown (PB) during the acute phase after surgery, (2) promote somatic growth, (3) decrease length of time to achieve full feeds. Protein turnover was measured in a double-blind randomized trial involving neonates admitted to the Neonatal Intensive Care Unit after major surgery. L-GLN (n = 6) was added to TPN at a dose of 200 mg/g of protein intake. Controls (n = 7) were isonitrogenous. Isotope studies were performed on Day 4 of TPN. Subjects were given a 4-hour primed constant intravenous infusion of L-[1-13C]-leucine and [15N2]-urea. In the GLN group, a 15% reduction in PB was measured (unpaired t-test, p &lt; 0.05). There was a trend towards improved net protein balance which was statistically different from zero in the GLN group. There were no differences in somatic growth during TPN course and in the length of time to achieve full enteral feeds. Results suggest that early TPN supplemented with GLN has a beneficial sparing effect on protein metabolism in critically ill neonates after major surgical stress.</description><creator>Nolin, France.</creator><contributor>Beaumier, Louis (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Postoperative care -- Nutritional aspects.</subject><subject>Glutamine.</subject><subject>Parenteral feeding.</subject><subject>Newborn infants -- Nutrition.</subject><title>Parenteral glutamine supplementation in neonates following surgical stress</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708z65n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mx35k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7m01bn55v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Na+/H+ exchanger (NHE) is a major contributor in controlling intracellular pH. The activity of this protein is allosterically modified by intracellular H+. Histidine residues of the NHE that face the cytoplasm may be involved in determining the intracellular pH set point, with their state of protonation influencing the rate of Na +/H+ exchange. To test this hypothesis, histidine residues in the ubiquitously expressed NHE isoform (NHE1) that are relatively conserved amongst members of the NHE gene family were substituted by site-directed mutagenesis and the mutants were stably transfected into mammalian cells that are deficient in endogenous Na+/H + exchange activity. The pHi sensitivity of each mutant was evaluated by measuring the rate of 22Na + influx as a function of the intracellular H+ concentration. Mutation of the histidines located at the putative cytoplasmic face of the N-terminal transmembraneous domain of NHE1 did not show any significant effect on the pHi sensitivity of the protein. By contrast, substitution of histidines located in the C-terminal cytoplasmic tail activated the exchanger by increasing its sensitivity to H+. These mutants were no longer activated in response to protein kinase C, when compared to wild type. Taken together, these data support the hypothesis that some of the relatively conserved histidine residues in the C-terminal cytoplasmic tail of NHE1 may be involved in determining the pHi "threshold" or "set point" of the transporter.</description><creator>Pazooki, Babak.</creator><contributor>Orlowski, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>The role of histidine residues in the pHı sensitivity of the Na+/H+ exchanger /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237ht604.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bn55v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hf00r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Over the past years, considerable attention has focused on the synthesis of small complexes that can bind and react at specific DNA sequences. This understanding of how to target DNA sites with specificity becomes important for nucleotide probing and novel chemotherapeutics. Inert and stable transition-metal complexes are already being used for this purpose. Square planar platinum (II) complexes containing an aromatic heterocyclic ligand can insert and stack between the double helix base pairs. Two known ligands, DPPZ and phi, do intercalate DNA when chelating ruthenium, rhodium, or osmium. Here are presented the syntheses of [Pt(NH3)2DPPZ](CF 3SO3)2, [Pt(en)DPPZ](CF3SO3) 2, [Pt(phen)DPPZ](CF3SO3)2, [Pt(Me 2bpy)DPPZ](CF3SO3)2, and [Pt(phendione)DPPZ](CF 3SO3)2, and the attempted syntheses of [Pt(en)phi](PF 6)2 and [Pt(phen)phi](PF6)2. The binding constants of [Pt(NH3)2DPPZ](CF3SO3) 2 and [Pt(en)DPPZ](CF3SO3)2 to calf thymus DNA have been determined. The knowledge coming from the synthetic strategy to obtain monomers has allowed the synthesis of a platinum-based dimer, [(DPPZ)Pt{DPPZ(11-11 ')DPPZ}Pt(DPPZ)](CF3SO3)4, having two intercalative DPPZ ends. We hope that this bis-intercalator will bring into close proximity two DNA strands.</description><creator>Paradis, Michel, 1976-</creator><contributor>Sleiman, Hanadi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Inorganic.</subject><title>The design and synthessis of platinum-based DNA intercalators /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096903b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hf00r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3f462728q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents a new approach to generating nonlinear optical side-chain polymers. By functionalizing olefins with nonlinear optical (NLO) chromophores and using late transition metal insertion catalysts of the form (bipy)Pd(CH 3)+ X- (X = OTf or BArF- ), a series of NLO materials were synthesized. These novel NLO polyketones were produced in modest yields with excellent polydispersities and good thermal stabilities via the alternating insertion of CO and NLO-tethered olefin into the palladium-carbon bond of the catalyst. A variety of NLO insertion monomers were examined during this study, beginning with a series of allylic-based monomers and progressing to a number of styrene derivatives. A detailed investigation of the copolymerizations and attempted copolymerizations is presented.</description><creator>Oliver, Andrew, 1975-</creator><contributor>Kakkar, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Arndtsen, B. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>The sequential insertion of carbon monoxide and non-linear optical chromophores into palladium-carbon bonds : a novel route to non-linear optical polyketones</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752j66w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f462728q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429c08b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Carbon dioxide (CO2) and methane (CH4) fluxes from the soil surface, and concentrations within the soil profile, were measured between June 1998 and Sept. 1999 at four adjacent forest plantations and an old field in Nepean, Ontario. The objectives of this study were to quantify seasonal CO2 and CH4 fluxes from the soil surface and within the soil profile to determine the effect of soil moisture and temperature, and forest age and species on the exchange, and establish a chronosequence of organic carbon accumulation in the forest plantations and the old field soils. Dynamic and static chamber techniques were used to measure surface fluxes of CO2 and CH4, respectively, and soil gas concentrations were sampled with probes. In the old field and forest plantations, surface soil CO2 flux ranged from 2.9 to 27 g CO2 m-2 d-1 and 2.0 to 39 g CO2 m -2 d-1 respectively. Significant differences due to age and species of plantation were observed. Seasonal variations in CO2 efflux from the soil surface and within the soil profile were related to variation in soil temperature and moisture. Uptake of CH4 was observed at all sites and there was no significant differences in flux due to vegetation type or age. Maximum rate of CH4 consumption was 6.3 mg CH4 m-2 d-1. Methane uptake was positively related to soil moisture conditions. The carbon content of the soil increased in all sites following the establishment of vegetation on sandy parent material. Carbon content was greatest in the upper soil profile. Rates of carbon accumulation ranged from 109 to 426 g m-2 y-1. Soil carbon increased with increasing age of plantation during the first 30 years following the establishment of vegetation on parent material, but declined as the forest plantation matured.</description><creator>Lysyshyn, Kathleen E.</creator><contributor>Roulet, Nigel T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Atmospheric methane -- Ontario -- Nepean.</subject><subject>Forest soils -- Ontario -- Nepean.</subject><subject>Carbon cycle (Biogeochemistry) -- Ontario -- Nepean.</subject><subject>Atmospheric carbon dioxide -- Ontario -- Nepean.</subject><title>Carbon dioxide and methane fluxes and organic carbon accumulation in old field and northern temperate forest plantation soils</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579v079.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429c08b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65v965m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tubers of Russet Burbank were surface disinfested and 3 mm diameter by 3 mm deep wounds were made with cork borer. The holes were inoculated with 20muL of 104 macroconidia/ml suspension of (Fusarium sambucinum) or 20muL of 104 sporangia/ml suspension (Pythium ultimum) and incubated under mist. For infection studies, the inoculated tubers were exposed to 0--48 h of mist at 4--20ºC, dried and stored at 16ºC and 95% RH in growth chamber with forced air for 15 d (F. sambucinum), whereas stored at 12ºC and 95% RH for 30 d (P. ultimum). For lesion expansion studies tubers exposed to 24 h wet at 16ºC were stored in growth chambers at 4, 8, 12, and 16ºC for 15--90 d. At the end of storage tubers were cut and the volume of diseased area was measured. Models explained 94.2% of the variation in infection and 99.7% in lesion expansion for F. sambucinum . Whereas, models explained 96.7% of the variation in infection and 99.6% lesion expansion for P. ultimum. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Lui, Leung Hong, 1952-</creator><contributor>Kushalappa, A. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Pythium ultimum.</subject><subject>Potatoes -- Storage -- Diseases and injuries.</subject><subject>Fusarium diseases of plants.</subject><title>Factors influencing disease development and volatile production by Fusarium sambucinum and Pythium ultimum in stored potatoes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jd12x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65v965m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945s70j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The technique of functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) is rapidly developing from one of technical interest to wide clinical application. fMRI exploits the fact that brain neural activity produces a change in blood oxygenation level dependent (BOLD) response which is recorded at each point in the brain. In a typical experiment, a subject is given a stimulus or cognitive task, and the statistical question is to relate it to the BOLD response, usually via a linear model. The BOLD response is not instantaneous; it is delayed and smoothed by about 6 seconds. In this thesis we propose a rapid method of estimating and making inference about this delay. Our method is compared to other alternatives, and validated on an fMRI data set from an experiment in pain perception.</description><creator>Liao, Chuanhong, 1964-</creator><contributor>Worsley, Keith J. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Chaubey, Y. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><subject>Statistics.</subject><title>Estimating the delay of the hemodynamic response in fMRI data</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sc11k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945s70j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p096905w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:01:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Let V be a vector space equipped with a norm ∥·∥, φ be a symmetric multilinear n-form and Φ be the associated homogeneous polynomial of degree n. Define ∥φ∥ := sup | φ(x1,x2,..., xn)| with the supremum taken over x1,...,xn unit vectors in V and ∥Φ∥ := sup∥x∥=1 | Φ (x)|. Clearly, we have ∥Φ∥ ≤ ∥φ∥. On the other hand, we can always find a constant α &lt; infinity with ∥φ∥≤ α∥Φ∥. Such an α is called a polarization constant. An upper bound for α is nⁿ/n!, this follows from polarization. In the case V = L infinity and n = 2 (i.e., bilinear forms), the tighter 3√3/4 is an upper bound. We provide an example where it appears that the equality ∥φ∥ = 3√3/4∥Φ∥ holds, suggesting that the constant is in fact optimal.</description><creator>Loisel, Sébastien.</creator><contributor>Drury, S. W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Polarization constants for symmetric multilinear forms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430659m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p096905w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40175</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>