<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:07:19Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):29600" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m613mz75h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, I attempt to provide a linguistic solution to the problem of failure of substitutivity in intensional contexts, with specific emphasis on sentences containing verbs of propositional attitude, for example, "believe", "say", "think", "realize", etc. Many solutions to this problem have been proposed in the philosophical literature (the major ones will be reviewed in this thesis) and most of the linguistic analyses to date have been based upon the logical concepts invoked in the former. Using the pragmatic notion of "point of view" as defined by Reinhart (1975), I provide an alternate solution that takes into account the intuitions of speakers of natural language. My solution is based on the fact that different points of view can result in different referents for an expression, and that this difference is essential to the semantic interpretation and truth value of intensional sentences. I also discuss so-called identity statements of the form 'a = b' (where 'a' and 'b' stand for coreferential expressions), arguing that there is both semantic and syntactic evidence for the claim that natural language utterances of this form do not express identity.</description><creator>Mitchell, Alison</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Grammar, Comparative and general -- Substitution</subject><subject>Context (Linguistics)</subject><title>Failure of substitutivity in intensional contexts : a linguistic solution</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544bq53f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613mz75h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m613mz747</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Standard therapy for abdominal aortic graft infection involving resection of the graft and extranatomic bypass, carries significant morbidity and mortality due to aortic stump rupture and limb loss. This thesis evaluates the feasibility of combining in situ graft replacement with a highly vascular tissue flap as an alternative approach to this problem. In sixty-nine pigs, a segment of a polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE) graft was interposed in the infrarenal abdominal aorta. Staphylococcus aureus was then used to infect the graft. One week later the animals were divided into six treatment groups where two different types of pedicled muscle flaps were used to treat the infection. The flaps were designed from the rectus abdominis and the seromuscularis of the jejunum. The results showed that graft infection could be controlled if either of the muscle flaps were used. Graft thrombosis did not occur if the infected graft was changed with a new PTFE graft. Vascularized tissue flaps avoid thus potentially fatal aortic stump rupture and may improve limb salvage in this difficult clinical problem.</description><creator>Mehran, Reza John</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Evaluation of muscle flaps in the treatment of infected abdominal aortic grafts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vh872.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613mz747</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nc580n77k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study was an attempt to combine both the psychological and lifestyles approaches and use qualitative research techniques in order to explore how young anglophones living in Montreal adapted to prolonged periods of unemployment. I examined how these young people felt their well-being was influenced by the experience of unemployment, what factors distinguished those who coped well with unemployment from those whose well-being declined, and how the mental health of respondents influenced their ability to adapt their lifestyle to accommodate prolonged periods of unemployment. This study provides detailed data about young people's subjective experience of unemployment and indicates the means by which three variables, social support, attributed cause of unemployment, and commitment to securing employment, interact to influence a person's mental health status. Also, this research highlights how adopting either an active lifestyle or becoming involved in the informal economy can influence a person's ability to cope with prolonged periods of unemployment.</description><creator>Foley, Kathleen</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Unemployed -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal</subject><subject>Unemployed -- Mental health</subject><title>Adaptation of anglophone Montreal youth to prolonged periods of unemployment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43nz29z.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580n77k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42n9201</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dietary carbohydrate during pregnancy is essential but whether this requirement is specific to glucose or if fructose could substitute for glucose in the diet of pregnant rat dams was investigated. It was concluded that the carbohydrate requirement for the rat during pregnancy is not specific to glucose and the level, not the type, of carbohydrate was critical. The potential toxicity of high fructose diets was also investigated. Dams fed high fructose had significantly higher liver weights than dams fed high glucose while other toxic indicators were not affected. A third aspect was the comparison of isocaloric, low carbohydrate diets containing different sources of 4% glucose equivalents: glucose, fructose or lipid-glycerol. Fructose and lipid-glycerol were not adequate substitutes for glucose. The measurement of amniotic fluid glucose, which increased as either dietary glucose or fructose increased in the maternal diet may be a new, accessible nutritional indicator of carbohydrate status.</description><creator>Fergusson, Marjorie</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Pregnancy -- Nutritional aspects.</subject><subject>Rats.</subject><subject>Fructose.</subject><subject>Glucose.</subject><title>Comparison of dietary fructose versus glucose during pregnancy on fetal growth and development</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mn379.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42n9201</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cr56n230n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Octahedral cobalt complexes of the type cis- ((N$ sb4)$Co(OH)(OH$ sb2)$) $ sp{2+}$ where N$ sb4$ represents a tetraamine ligand, are highly efficient at hydrolyzing phosphate diesters. Furthermore the reactivity of the cobalt complexes is very sensitive to the tetraamine ligand structure. In the first part of this work, crystal structures of some key cobalt complexes have been determined. Close examination reveals an interesting structure-reactivity relationship. In the second part of this work, existing MMX force field is evaluated for predicting the structures of cobalt complexes. A modification of the force field was necessary in order to obtain good correlation between the calculated structures and the X-ray structures.</description><creator>Drouin, Marc</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Relationship between structure and reactivity of Co(III) complexes by X-ray analysis and molecular mechanics calculations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rf71k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n230n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h5636</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents an implementation of supervised learning performed with a stochastic neural net, as applied to a classification of business firms based on financial statements and ratios. The general Boltzmann Machine Algorithm is presented in detail, as well as the specific version designed for this application. We describe in detail several classifications that we attempted to reproduce, and some of the different possible ways of encoding the data issued from the income statements and the balance sheet. The results are shown to depend on the chosen encoding. We also confirm that the neural net behaves better when it is trained on the most difficult cases.</description><creator>Fays, Gérard</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Artificial Intelligence.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><subject>Economics, Finance.</subject><title>Boltzmann machine applied to financial ratio analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n870zr964.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h5636</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hq37vp75r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An earthquake of magnitude 5.7 occurred in the Saguenay region of the province of Quebec, Canada, on November 25, 1988. Although no loss of life or severe structural damages were caused by this earthquake the poor performance of unreinforced masonry and structures with 'tension-only' cross-bracing were reported by a site visit team. This thesis presents some of the important engineering characteristics of the 1988 Saguenay earthquake. Comparisons are made in terms of elastic and inelastic response spectra for the lateral forces to be considered for the seismic response analysis of short-period structural systems. In particular, the seismic response of a low-rise braced steel building designed according to the National Building Code of Canada is investigated in both the elastic and inelastic range. The code-suggested equivalent lateral force method for short-period structures with a substantial strength-reduction factor does not provide a rational control of structural damage that can be expected from seismic excitation in Eastern Canada. The use of a period-dependent strength reduction factor applied to the elastic strength demand for short-period structures is proposed to take advantage of the inelastic energy dissipation capacity for this type of system on a more rational basis.</description><creator>Romano, Angelo</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Seismic response analysis of low-rise buildings designed according to the NBCC 1990</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mw46w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hq37vp75r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rj158</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study examined the patterns and effectiveness of counterpart training by Canadian cooperants involved in development projects. The traditional one-on-one apprenticeship model of counterpart training was used. Success of the training was analysed by comparing results against the principles of effective training in industry. A group of 40 Canadian cooperants returned from postings in Africa participated in the study. All of the cooperants were participants in a major study on cross cultural effectiveness sponsored by the Canadian International Development Agency. Results of the study indicate that the counterpart training system is not very effective as a means of transferring knowledge and expertise. The problem appeared to lie in the process itself. Training was generally secondary to completion of the project on time and on budget, and tended to evolve as the need arose and as time permitted. Few of the cooperants had any experience in designing training interventions, and so devised their own tools and methods with few identifiable measures of success. There were no formal evaluations of either the cooperant or the counterpart, nor of program success upon completion of the training.</description><creator>Pritchard, Pamela J. (Pamela Jayne)</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Technology transfer.</subject><subject>Employees -- Training of</subject><subject>Exchange of persons programs</subject><subject>Technical assistance</subject><title>Canadian cooperants in counterpart training : patterns and effectiveness</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qd31s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rj158</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gm02z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effects of short range order on the structural and transport properties of the $ rm Cu sb{1-x}Ni sb{x}Zr sb2$ amorphous metallic alloy system are studied. Depending on composition, these amorphous alloys crystallize into different structures. CuZr$ sb2$ has the I4/mmm (C11) structure and NiZr$ sb2$ has the I4/mcm (C16) structure. It is believed that the short range order in the amorphous phase is related to the final crystalline phase. A careful study (using differential scanning calorimetry, X-ray diffraction on as made and crystallized states, room temperature magnetic susceptibility and resistivity, and a determination of the superconducting transition temperature of as-made and annealed states) has been done to see what transport properties are affected. It is observed that there is a linear increase in the values of the susceptibility, resistivity, and superconducting transition temperature of the system from CuZr$ sb2$ to NiZr$ sb2.$ This is attributed to an increase of the electronic density of states as the concentration of Ni increases. There is little or no influence on transport properties due to topological short range order.</description><creator>Pavlenyi, Marc</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Effects of short range order on structural and transport properties of Cu-Ni-Zr amorphous alloys</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88ch85v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gm02z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n583xw20r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Tang dynasty (618-907) is often referred to as a golden age of Buddhism in China. This research, concentrated on the first half of the dynasty (618-755), shows that Buddhism's impact on Tang aristocratic society has been overestimated. Looking at models of the familial and social order that one can extract from the Tang Code as well as from some literary works of the period, the picture emerging is that Tang society was a highly stratified one, and based on Confucian values. Buddhism, in order to establish and maintain itself in China, had to compromise with those values. However, its efforts to conciliate its doctrine with some Confucian precepts did not suffice to prevent its decline. Ultimately, Confucian values were reaffirmed as the sole basis of Chinese society, and remained so until the end of the Qing dynasty, in 1911.</description><creator>Piquet, Hélène</creator><date>1990</date><subject>China -- History -- Tang dynasty, 618-907.</subject><subject>Tʻang family.</subject><subject>China -- Civilization -- Buddhist influences</subject><title>Modèles de l'ordre familial et de l'ordre social dans la première moitié de la dynastie Tang (618-755)</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w5986.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xw20r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451j73q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study explores the political impact of the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms on the Supreme Court of Canada. This influence is contrasted with the judiciary's historic reluctance to recognize civil liberties, commencing with the position taken by the Judicial Committee of the Privy Council and the cautious reaction of the Supreme Court to the Diefenbaker Bill of Rights. The treatment of civil liberties under the Charter is considered through a survey of some of the Charter cases addressed by the Supreme Court of Canada. The political consequences of the Court's decisions are examined. Alternative possibilities for the Court's role in Canadian society are considered, including the prospects for entrenchment under the Meech Lake Accord and other recently proposed reforms. The criticism that too much power is being vested in the "least democratic branch" is addressed and the suggestion that the Charter should be located in the "communitarian tradition of Canadian politics" is appraised. This study reflects upon the theoretical assumptions which underlie the existence of the Charter, as it evaluates the political theory behind differing conceptions of judicial interpretation. This thesis concludes by determining that the Supreme Court has made a positive political contribution to Canadian society.</description><creator>Romano, Domenic</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Civil rights -- Canada</subject><subject>Canada. Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms</subject><subject>Canada. Supreme Court</subject><title>The political impact of the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms on the Supreme Court of Canada /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773w89g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451j73q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602203c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the yeast Saccharomyces cerevisiae, HEM13 codes for coproporphyrinogen oxidase which catalyses the sixth enzymatic step in the heme biosynthetic pathway. Coproporphyrinogen oxidase synthesis has been shown to be regulated negatively by heme and oxygen at the transcriptional level. We are interested in defining the HEM13 cis-acting upstream sequences that mediate regulation by heme. HEM13-lacZ and HEM13-CYC1-lacZ hybrid fusions were made and expression of the resulting $ beta$-galactosidase activity was determined in vivo, under conditions of varying levels of heme. Deletion analysis of the HEM13 promoter revealed the existence of 3 upstream regulatory elements designated as UAS1, UAS2, and URS that span a region of 365 pb from nucleotides $-$640 to $-$275 with respect to the most upstream HEM13 transcriptional start site. The trans-acting factor HAP1 previously identified to activate expression of CYC1 and CTT1 genes in the presence of heme and oxygen, was found to be involved in the regulation of HEM13 expression. Measurements of HEM13-CYC1-lacZ fusions in a hap1 mutant strain indicated that HAP1 was required to fully induce and repress expression of the fusions under heme-deficient and heme-sufficient conditions respectively.</description><creator>Richard, Catherine</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Deletion analysis of the sequences that regulate HEM13 expression</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wh208.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602203c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526d62k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since the beginning of the sixties, coastal trapped waves have been one of the most popular subjects in physical oceanography. Initially, we discuss their characteristics in the Southeast Hudson Bay, using the Brink and Chapman model. Then we compare the normal modes obtained with the observations made in Kuujjuarapik (Hudson Bay) in 1986 using the technique of Freeland et al (1986). This area is difficult to model because of rapid changes of stratification in the water column during the ice break-up period. The best fit was found for two topographic waves both having a period of three days with phase speeds of 70 cm/s and 13 cm/s. In this work it has been shown that the response function of the system due to atmospheric pressure gradients has a maximum at a period corresponding to the period of the topographic waves.</description><creator>Reynaud, Thierry</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Physical Oceanography.</subject><title>Propagation d'ondes côtières piégees sous la couverture de glace dans la Baie d'Hudson</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qd33b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526d62k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:79407z45m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Field trials were conducted to evaluate the effect of quizalofop-ethyl on quackgrass plants in a potato cropping sequence. Fall and summer applications were compared for their quackgrass control potential. Season-long quackgrass control was obtained with quizalofop-ethyl at 96 g/ha following summer application. An increase in the rate of quizalofop-ethyl did not further improve control. Yields with quizalofop-ethyl at 96 g/ha were similar to standard treatments sethoxydim and fluazifop-butyl at recommended rates. Quackgrass control following a summer application was not maintained through to the following season. Fall applications did not result in adequate control of quackgrass the following season at any of the quizalofop-ethyl rates tested.</description><creator>Poliquin, Bernard</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Weeds -- Control.</subject><subject>Potatoes -- Weed control.</subject><subject>Quitch-grass -- Control.</subject><subject>Herbicides.</subject><title>Quackgrass [Agropyron repens (L.) Beauv.] control in potatoes with quizalofop-ethyl</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977w22d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/79407z45m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf2686370</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this Thesis is to present a modern critical edition of the Missa Assumpta est Maria (H. 11) and the Elevation a 5, sans dessus de violon (H. 251) of Marc-Antoine Charpentier (c. 1634-1704). The Thesis is divided into three chapters. The first chapter provides an introductory biography of the composer and a general overview of his works. The second chapter deals specifically with the Missa Assumpta est Maria and the Elevation a 5, offering first an investigation of the historical background to these works. This discussion continues with stylistic analyses and is followed by an examination into questions of performance practice that are raised by the music. The chapter is completed with a declaration of editorial principles, critical notes, texts and translations, and a conclusion. The final chapter of the Thesis is comprised of the edited transcriptions of the Missa Assumpta est Maria and the Elevation a 5, sans dessus de violon. Endnotes and bibliography are inserted at the end of chapter two.</description><creator>Couse, Andrew Jerome</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Charpentier, Marc-Antoine, 1643-1704. Elevation à 5 sans dessus de violon</subject><subject>Masses -- Scores</subject><subject>Motets</subject><subject>Charpentier, Marc-Antoine, 1643-1704. Missa Assumpta est Maria</subject><title>The Missa Assumpta est Maria of Marc-Antoine Charpentier /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708x866.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf2686370</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hd34c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effect of spin fluctuations on the resistivities of 14 different $Fe sb{x}Ni sb{1-x}Zr sb2$ metallic glasses were analyzed in the temperature range from 4.2K to 80K. The corrections to the resistivity due to the superconductivity and quantum interference effects at very low temperatures were performed to obtain the spin fluctuation resistivity, $ rho sb{sf}$, as a function of temperature and composition. It is found that, $ rho sb{sf}$ varies as $T sp2$ at very low temperatures, i.e. below around 20K, and as T at higher temperatures. This confirms the predictions of the two-band model of Kaiser and Doniach and the one-band model of Rivier and Zlatic. The spin fluctuation temperatures for all the compositions, were determined from both models. $T sb{sf}$ calculated from the one-band model were about 30% higher than those calculated from the two-band model. The spin fluctuation temperature is lowest when the system is closest to the magnetic transition and it increases when the amount of magnetic species is reduced in the alloy, i.e. for x = 1, $T sb{sf}$ = 10K (15K) and for x = 0.4, $T sb{sf}$ = 64K (96K) for the two-band (one-band) model.</description><creator>Dantu, Srilakshmi V.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Spin fluctuation resistivities of Fe-Ni-Zr metallic glasses</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gm037.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hd34c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603qz694</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Layer thickness measurements are used to investigate polymer adsorption and possible conformations of adsorbed polymer. In a first step, photon correlation spectroscopy (PCS) is used to monitor the layer thickness at different ratios of polyethylene oxide (PEO) per polystyrene (PS) latex spheres. Comparison of the polymer concentration at which the equilibrium layer thickness was attained with the concentration where the adsorption isotherm reached its plateau leads to a proposed three step adsorption process. Kinetic studies of the layer thickness build-up also support this mechanism. Polymer polydispersity and the effect of anchored end groups on layer thickness are found to be in agreement with theoretical predictions. In a second step, a rheological investigation of PEO coated polystyrene-butadiene (PSB) latex spheres was performed. The influence of coating on the second virial coefficient was determined. Comparison of the layer thickness as measured by viscosity and PCS shows the relative importance of the latex polydispersity for the two methods.</description><creator>Couture, Lorraine</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>Adsorption of polyethylene oxide on latex particles</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892c03d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603qz694</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p158q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This report examines the mortality of the James Bay Cree of northern Quebec during the period 1982-1986. Life expectancy at birth is higher in this population than among most other North American Indians. Infant mortality remains high, due to high death rates in the postneonatal period. Genetic diseases, infections, and accidents take a heavy toll among Cree infants and children. The Cree continue to experience lower mortality rates than Canada as a whole from cancer and cardiovascular diseases. The rate of drownings remains ten times the Canadian rate, but the Cree are still relatively exempt from the high incidence of accidental and violent deaths which effect many North American Indian groups.</description><creator>Courteau, Jean-Pierre</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><subject>Sociology, Demography.</subject><title>Mortality among the James Bay Cree of northern Quebec 1982-1986</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rv657.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p158q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wd940</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis investigates the phenomenon of for-to complements in several dialects, focusing primarily on Appalachian English, though Belfast English and Ottawa Valley English are also examined. Following Chomsky's Government and Binding theory, we develop an analysis of for-to that predicts the distribution of for-to complements based on the requirements of Case, and the varieties of licit movement of features allowed by each dialect. To do this, we propose a Revised Case Filter which requires functional categories bearing Case features to discharge Case. We also show that the features of functional categories can move either by head movement (allowing movement of to into for) or by feature transmission (allowing for to move into to). Each of these mechanisms generates a specific range of well-formed for-to complements; the distribution of these complements can be predicted by the ways in which the dialects allow features to move. Appalachian English and Ottawa Valley English allow head movement of features only, while Belfast English allows features to move via head movement and feature transmission. Thus for-to complements are more wide-spread in Belfast English than in the other for-to dialects. Standard English, which does not allow features to move unless they are accompanied by lexical material, does not exhibit for-to complements at all.</description><creator>Wade-Woolley, Lesly A. (Lesly Ann)</creator><date>1989</date><subject>English language -- Ottawa River Valley (Québec and Ont.) -- Grammar</subject><subject>English language -- Northern Ireland -- Belfast -- Grammar</subject><subject>English language -- Complement</subject><subject>English language -- Appalachian Region -- Grammar</subject><subject>English language -- Dialects</subject><title>For-to complements in Appalachian English</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fc92x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wd940</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s361z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main objective of this study was to examine the effects of intraspecific competition on the growth and reproduction of yellow nutsedge. A field experiment was conducted to examine twelve tuber densities of yellow nutsedge, ranging from 1 to 1000 tubers/m$ sp2$. Results indicate that spring tuber populations of 100 tubers/m$ sp2$ and lower require close to 100% control of the infestation in order to prevent the yellow nutsedge population from increasing. Yellow nutsedge spring tuber population does not appear to influence tuber distribution in the soil profile. All tuber densities examined produced the greatest proportion of tubers in the top 20 cm of the soil profile. Tuber and shoot production increased as initial yellow nutsedge tuber populations increased from 1 to 1000 tubers/m$ sp2$, as did tuber and shoot biomass. Consequently, intraspecific competition does not appear to come into effect at tuber populations of 1000 tubers/m$ sp2$ and less. Predictions were made to determine the spread of yellow nutsedge based on an infestation of a single tuber. A single yellow nutsedge tuber could grow to infest an area of 50 m$ sp2$ in 5 years. Information concerning the effect of spring tuber density on the reproduction and spread of yellow nutsedge should be used in formulating control strategies for this weed.</description><creator>Sterkenburg, Neilda Jane</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Weeds.</subject><subject>Chufa.</subject><subject>Competition (Biology)</subject><title>Intraspecific competition in yellow nutsedge (Cyperus esculentus L.)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074w34g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s361z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xp68kh59r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Both the counterculture and its music will be examined using the concepts of heteronomy, autonomy, and theonomy and their dialectical relationship according to Paul Tillich's theory of religion and culture. The main themes beneath the emergence of the counterculture will be outlined, and the ways in which the dominant culture of the time may be considered what Tillich describes as a heteronomous phenomenon will be presented. The historical significance of the counterculture will then be demonstrated in terms of Tillich's concept of kairos. Through examination of the lyrics of some of the most popular songs between 1965 and 1970, the years during which the movement was at its height, the ways in which the counterculture may be seen as autonomous protest will be discussed. This will be followed by an examination of theonomous elements apparent in the song lyrics and an evaluation of the movement in terms of the Tillichian dialectic.</description><creator>Thompson, Pamela J.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Religion and culture</subject><subject>Rock music -- Religious aspects</subject><subject>Social history -- 1960-1970</subject><title>Rock and roll and the counterculture : the search for alternative values and a new spirituality</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jc62x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kh59r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290b67k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work is a study on software tools for the diagnosis of electrical equipment. It covers conventional and expert system methods, of which the latter are found to be more appropriate for the task. The interest in expert systems is directed towards those based on deep knowledge, meaning the structural and functional description of devices. A well-known approach for reasoning on complex structural knowledge consists of using qualitative models. The thesis explores the principal works in this domain and applies them to the diagnosis of electrical equipment in order to evaluate their limitations. Another approach is also considered, based on causal networks, which exploits an important element of diagnosis and complements qualitative models: causality. Finally, a global diagnostic methodology is presented for each approach.</description><creator>Tiffou, Benoît</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Etude des outils informatiques d'aide au diagnostic d'appareils électriques</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50gx357.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290b67k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gh93h0747</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Beniak, Edouard, 1952-</creator><date>1981</date><subject>French language -- Verb -- Study and teaching.</subject><subject>French language -- Canada -- Study and teaching.</subject><subject>French language -- Study and teaching (Elementary) -- English speakers.</subject><subject>French language -- Ability testing.</subject><title>Aspects of the acquisition of the French verb system by young speakers of English and French in Quebec and Ontario</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bj39d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h0747</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042v112</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Brierley, Jane, 1935-</creator><date>1982</date><subject>Québec (Province) -- Social life and customs.</subject><subject>Aubert de Gaspé, Philippe, 1786-1871</subject><subject>Authors, French-Canadian -- Québec (Province) -- 19th century -- Biography.</subject><title>Memoirs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cf50n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042v112</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fx719n54z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:13:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Mahadeo, Satish Kumar.</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Creole dialects, French -- Mauritius.</subject><title>Decreolization in Mauritian Creole : sociolinguistic and linguistic evidence</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z203r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719n54z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):29625</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>