<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:53:48Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):26175" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k0698779f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the Drosophila CNS, neurons and glia communicate to regulate cell survival, gene expression and differentiation, although the precise mechanisms remain unclear. I have genetic evidence to indicate that the glycosyltransferase Fringe (fng) is required for both glial cell differentiation and neuronal axon guidance in the embryonic ventral nerve cord (VNC). fng activity is known to modify signaling through the Notch (N) receptor, and fng-dependent glycosylation of N changes the affinity of the receptor for its two known ligands, Serrate (Ser) and Delta (Dl). I found that N is widely expressed in both neurons and glia during axon outgrowth stages while Ser and Dl are restricted to unique subsets of neurons. fng is expressed in a subset of glia in the VNC and is necessary for the correct glial specific expression of the transcription factor Prospero. Prospero expression can be induced by axon-derived N ligands or by activation of the N pathway specifically in glia. Conversely, inhibition of N signaling in glia abolishes Prospero expression. I have also found that fng activity is required for axon patterning and speculate that this function is also dependant on glia-specific expression of the gene. My work suggests that fng-dependent activation of the N pathway is important for axon-glia interactions during the development of the embryonic nervous system.</description><creator>Thomas, Graham, 1979-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>The glycosyltransferase fringe regulates glial cell differentiation and axon patterning in the drosophila CNS /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Graham Thomas, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz8060020.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698779f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483j61t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The frequency-following response (FFR) is a scalp-recorded evoked potential which faithfully mimics an auditory stimulus waveform. Some research has attempted to relate the FFR to pitch perception based on FFR spectral peaks which correspond to the perceived pitch of the evoking stimulus, but these explanations are not definitive because the pitch of the evoking stimulus is often equal to the waveform envelope frequency or nonlinear distortion products also represented in the FFR. The experiments herein attempt to clarify the relevance of the FFR to pitch perception and as an assay of nonlinear distortion in the auditory system. Using harmonic and inharmonic "missing fundamental" complex tone stimuli, it is demonstrated that: (a) missing fundamental pitch is not represented as a spectral peak in the FFR, (b) the FFR contains energy at the stimulus envelope frequency, primary tone frequencies, and nonlinear distortion product frequencies, and (c) human pitch perception can be predicted by a weighted average of envelope-locked and phase-locked neural activity in the FFR. The origin and properties of nonlinear distortion products measured in the FFR are also investigated.</description><creator>Wile, Daryl J.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Auditory perception.</subject><subject>Musical pitch.</subject><title>On the electrophysiological correlates of missing fundamental pitch perception and nonlinear distortion in the frequency-following response</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Daryl J. Wile, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fr622.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483j61t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82k7573</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Agriculture remains a dominant economic sector in many developing countries. Rice constitutes a staple food for more than half of the world's population and is the main meal of all Lao people (FAO, 2005). However, rice production faces many problems, including the effects of floods, drought and poor soil quality. These challenges combine to reduce rice productivity below what might be possible. However, before new agricultural policies are put in place, it is important to identify the factors associated with rice production efficiency. This thesis analyses technical and socio-economic factors that influence rice production and estimates the level of technical efficiency of individual rice farmers in Ban Home, Laos. Survey data were collected in the region in 2003, for both wet season and dry season rice production. Using these data, a Cobb-Douglas frontier production function was estimated for each season using two approaches, deterministic and stochastic. During the wet season, several factors were statistically significant and positive in their effect on rice yield: area in rice production, level of fertilizer use, total labour, the use of a modern variety, sandy soil and contact with a professional agricultural advisor. During the dry season, only area in rice production and fertilizer were significant. Based on the frontier production functions, it is possible to conclude that the average technical efficiency of farmers is higher during the dry season than the wet season, for both the deterministic and stochastic approaches. However, socio-economic factors were unable to explain the level of technical efficiency among farmers, when evaluated using a standard regression approach. By using a simple t-test to compare the mean level of efficiency of different groups of farmers, some significant differences emerged. Farmers who used credit were found to be more efficient than those who did not. Moreover, experienced farmers were more efficient than less experienced farmers. Also, farmers with less than 7 years of education were more efficient than more educated farmers.</description><creator>Hem Inthavong, Khamla.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Rice -- Yields -- Laos.</subject><title>Factors influencing rice production efficiency in Ban Home, Laos</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Khamla Hem Inthavong, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vb585.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k7573</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8s45q918w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of this thesis is to obtain the most precise radius measurement of the neutron star in Aql X-1. In order to measure the radius, nine new observations have been analyzed along with four previously analyzed observations. Two of the new observations were taken with XMM-Newton. During the times of the XMM-Newton observations Aql X-1 was found not to be in quiescence and so cannot be used for radius measurements. This state of active accretion of Aql X-1 is characterized by basic spectral analysis. Spectral lines from Aql X-1 were investigated using the Reflection Grating Spectrometer (RGS) on XMM-Newton. There was no visual evidence of spectral lines from Aql X-1 observed. The seven new Chandra observations along with four others all caught Aql X-1 in quiescence. These observations were taken over two quiescent periods with an intervening outburst. Joint spectral fitting of the 11 observations revealed significant variability in the high energy (&gt;2keV) emission but that the thermal emission---which emerges from the neutron star atmosphere---was constant, as expected from theory. The high energy component was parameterized with a varying power-law, with the thermal component held constant. The best fit from jointly fitting the observations was Rinfinity= 11.6+0.4-0.1 (D/5kpc)km and LogTeff(K)= 6.49+0.01-0.02 , where D is the distance to Aql X-1. This is the most precise measurement of the neutron star radius for this source, with the dominant uncertainty (not included in the statistical uncertainty) now in the source distance. Finally, a new class of neutron stars, RRATs, have recently been introduced. One of the RRATs includes Aql X-1 in its error circle. A search was performed of the Chandra and XMM-Newton observations for candidate counterparts. A fading X-ray source, CXOU J191121.4+003844, was found to lie within the error circle of the RRAT, which is put forth as a candidate X-ray counterpart.</description><creator>Hoffman, Kelsey L.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Physics, Astronomy and Astrophysics.</subject><title>A study of X-ray observations of Aquila X-1 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Kelsey L. Hoffman, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613mx830.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45q918w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207tp61v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The general circulation of the ocean acts as an energy reservoir. This means that the external forcing (primarily by the wind field) is balanced by dissipation. However, the dissipation is not well understood because energy does not easily cascade forward to small scales where dissipation is active. Approximate geostrophic balance holds over much of the ocean because the advective timescale is typically long compared to the Coriolis timescale. The resulting geostrophic turbulence behaves similarly to 2D turbulence in the sense that energy is not cascaded forward to small scales. In fact, there is an inverse cascade of energy toward large scales for these "balanced" flows. One possible mechanism for dissipation of the balanced flow is nonlinear interactions with unbalanced flow. In this thesis we made an analogy between balanced flow and 2D flow for the unstratified case. We numerically integrated the hydrostatic, barotropic vorticity equation using a pseudo-spectral, triply-periodic model varying the rate of rotation and the level of 3D (corresponding to unbalanced) energy via a 3D forcing. We analysed the energetics of the 2D flow to determine the impact of rotation and the 3D energy level. We found that there is a critical Rossby number between 0.1 and 1 above which there is 2D energy drain and below which there is 2D energy gain. We found that the magnitude of the drain/gain at large scales increases with forcing up to a limiting value. A review of ocean energetics and turbulent 2D-3D interactions is also presented.</description><creator>Gertz, Aaron Blake Rollinson.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Physical Oceanography.</subject><title>2D-3D interactions in a thin rotating fluid : implications for the energetics of ocean circulation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Aaron Blake Rollinson Gertz, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rb68xc135.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207tp61v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn009z04j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Infections caused by resistant pathogens fail to respond to treatment, resulting in increased costs due to prolonged illness and hospitalization. Determining the extent of resistance in animal populations is thus of great importance to public health. In this work, we first showed that asymptomatic populations of Salmonella in pigs present greater genotypic and phenotypic diversity than disease-associated populations. Second, we identified a clonal population structure associated with asymptomatic Salmonella found in the Canadian swine industry and we confirmed that food-producing pigs are a significant reservoir of Salmonella enterica, more particularly the clinically important serotype Typhimurium DT104. Finally, we identified the possible independent evolution of multidrug-resistance in serotypes Typhimurium, Derby and Heidelberg. Our work on asymptomatic Salmonella enterica stresses the importance of linking ecology and evolutionary biology to public health in order to understand and predict the response of pathogenic bacteria to selective pressure imposed by host immunity, whether naturally or artificially induced.</description><creator>Guimond-Peron, Gabriel.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Drug resistance in microorganisms -- Canada.</subject><subject>Salmonella infections in animals -- Canada.</subject><subject>Swine -- Diseases -- Canada.</subject><subject>Salmonella -- Canada.</subject><title>The ecology and evolution of antimicrobial resistance in asymptomatic Salmonella enterica /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Gabriel Guimond-Peron, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff365548j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn009z04j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f615m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Article 17 in the Warsaw Convention 1929, the core provision to all liability for passenger injury and death, has been the most litigated Article of the Warsaw Convention. The main reason for this is that the Warsaw Convention, the axis of private international air law, unfortunately did not provide clear definitions regarding "accident" and "bodily injury" in the Article 17. Its amendments, the Hague Protocol 1955 and the Guatemala Protocol 1971, did not succeed in clarifying the meanings. Although the Montreal Conference 1999 witnessed strong debates regarding the amendment of Article 17, the Montreal Convention 1999 did not succeed in changing Article 17. Since the Warsaw System did not provide definitions of "accident" and "bodily injury", each State has interpreted the two terms individually. Inconsistency in interpreting "accident" and "bodily injury" has emerged, since every State has a different jurisprudence. This phenomenon has created confusion in the international air transport community. In order to clear up the confusion, the International Civil Aviation Organization should amend Article 17 to specify and clarify the terms: "accident" and "bodily injury", while balancing the interests of all parties in the international air transport community.</description><creator>Lee, Jae Woon, 1979-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Law and legislation.</subject><subject>Liability for aircraft accidents.</subject><title>The concepts of &amp;quot;accident &amp;quot; and &amp;quot;bodily injury&amp;quot; in private international air law /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Jae Woon Lee, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580m92g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f615m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c077q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new legal phenomenon has emerged in recent years, as plaintiffs from developing countries have begun to initiate civil proceedings against multinational corporations in the courts where these companies have their headquarters. These suits have typically claimed damages for personal injuries arising from the multinationals' activities in a developing country. While the doctrine of forum non conveniens blocked many of the earlier attempts by plaintiffs to seek justice overseas, courts are increasingly refusing to dismiss these cases to ensure the interests of justice are served. The purpose of this thesis will be to compare the application of forum non conveniens to these cases in Canada, with the approaches in the U.K., the U.S. and Australia. The thesis concludes that Canadian courts have the jurisdiction to consider civil claims against a resident for extraterritorial harm and that this jurisdiction can be appropriately exercised where the foreign plaintiff is not likely to receive justice in the alternative forum. Precedents from the U.K., the U.S. and Australia, where courts have already accepted such jurisdiction, will also be examined for their relevance in Canada.</description><creator>Karmali, Karima.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Forum non conveniens.</subject><subject>Forum non conveniens -- Canada.</subject><title>The evolution of Canada's doctrine of forum non conveniens : in the interests of justice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Karima Karmali, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d217qp877.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c077q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fx719m69c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The existing air navigation services have many shortcomings and a reform was necessary. The new systems (CNS/ATM systems) will be largely dependent on Global Navigation Satellite Systems (GNSS) which can bring significant benefits to air navigation in terms of safety, efficiency, capacity, and economy. However, GNSS have weaknesses which can be reduced but will never be fully eliminated. Depending solely on a system that can be disrupted is not acceptable for safety of life applications, such as aviation. The implementation of GNSS also raises unique legal issues and ICAO has been working on the establishment of a legal framework for GNSS since 1992. Nevertheless, disagreement between states on the need for an international convention remains significant. Legal discussions should not slow down the implementation of GNSS which, when used in conjunction with terrestrial navigation aids, have the potential to revolutionize air navigation.</description><creator>Jaugey, Delphine.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Navigation (Aeronautics)</subject><subject>Artificial satellites in navigation -- Law and legislation.</subject><title>The use of Global Navigation Satellite Systems (GNSS) for air navigation purposes : benefits, vulnerabilities of the systems and legal issues</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Delphine Jaugey, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d006c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719m69c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h415p970k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>China now is one of the most attractive destinations for foreign direct investment (FDI) and mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;As) have become an increasingly important mode of FDI entry in China since its accession to the World Trade Organization. M&amp;As in China are expected to play a vital role in the restructuring of its inefficient State-owned enterprises. This thesis characterizes and analyzes the evolving Chinese legal regime governing M&amp;As in the context of the ongoing economic reform. In addition, it identifies the antitrust issues arising from foreign acquisitions of Chinese domestic enterprises, which can result in market dominance and restrictive practices in China. The thesis concludes that China's M&amp;A regime can be improved and aligned more closely with international practices as its economy becomes further integrated into the world economy.</description><creator>Ma, Hong, 1968-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Consolidation and merger of corporations -- China.</subject><subject>Antitrust law -- China.</subject><subject>Investments, Foreign -- China.</subject><title>Mergers and acquisitions of state-owned enterprises by foreign investors in China</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Hong Ma, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m6834.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415p970k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v692t656q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Very Large Optical Telescope (VLOT) is a concept, proposed by the National Research Council - Herzberg Institute of Astrophysics, to address future demands of the international astrophysics community. To develop and evaluate the VLOT designs, an Integrated Modeling approach is employed. The Integrated Model (IM) is a single simulation tool which accounts for the interactions between different telescope modules to produce the final image quality generated by the telescope. The work in this thesis relates directly to two of the modules of the IM: (1) the structural dynamics and (2) the primary mirror control module. In order to obtain accurate optical performance predictions from the IM, a high fidelity structural model of the telescope is required. However, the finite-element model of the telescope, which is its nascent structural model, is prohibitively large in size for practical simulation. This problem can be addressed by applying a suitable Model Order Reduction technique. In the first half of this thesis, we compare five Model Order Reduction techniques from the literature for the VLOT application. These methods are evaluated and compared in frequency and time domains. Based on these results, we conclude that the Singular Perturbation Approximation method is suitable for the VLOT application. The primary mirror, which is the main light-gathering surface of the telescope, must be maintained in a particular profile in order to provide the desired image quality. Currently, this control objective is achieved with an enhanced integral controller based on a SISO control approach. The primary mirror, however, is a MIMO system and hence the second objective of this thesis is to evaluate a MIMO control design approach, in particular, the Linear Quadratic Gaussian (LQG) controller. The LQG design is evaluated in two steps: initially with a single mirror segment model and then with the VLOT structural model. Based on our results, we conclude that even with currently available computational resources, it is not feasible to employ the LQG control approach in a centralized manner to a large scale system such as VLOT.</description><creator>Yu, Kintak Raymond.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Model order reduction and controller design for segmented primary mirror of a large optical telescope</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Kintak Raymond Yu, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732d9242.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t656q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b8515n655</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Organic light emitting devices (OLED) based on small molecule materials capable of white light emission have been fabricated and electrical and optical performance of devices was characterized. The fabricated OLEDs utilize one hole transport material, N, N'-diphenyl-N, N'-bis(3-methylphenyl)-1, 1'-biphenyl-4, 4'-diamine [TPD], and three light emitting materials including 4, 4'-bis(2, 2'-diphenylvinyl)-1, 1'-biphenyl [DPVBi], Tris-(1-phenylisoquinolinato-N) iridium (III) [Ir(piq)3], and tris-(8-hydroxyquinoline) aluminium [Alq3] to achieve the color blending close to the white light. The overall OLED configuration is in a multi-layer stacking structure. A total of 6 different OLED layer thickness configurations were implemented to investigate the effect of the layer thickness parameters. In one particular configuration, the CIE color coordinates range from (0.357,0.358) at 140.4 cd/m2 to (0.303,0.360) at 1321.7 cd/m2, which indicates adequate color stability in the medium to high luminance range. The luminance value of 1321.7 cd/m2 at the current density of 64.9 mA/cm2 and the operating voltage of 14 V indicates that the device is capable of producing a relatively high level of brightness while operating at relatively low operating voltage and low driving current density.</description><creator>Yang, Han-Jen, 1979-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Fabrication and characterization of white light emission organic light-emitting devices</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Han-Jen Yang, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988k09p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515n655</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mm53g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis describes a method to analyze proton magnetic resonance spectroscopy imaging (MRSI) of multiple sclerosis (MS) patients. Multiple sclerosis is a chronic disease of the central nervous system (CNS). MRSI can non-invasively measure the metabolites in the brains and is helpful in research of progression of MS. Conventional approaches to analyze MRSI data are either using region-of-interest (ROI) methods or averaging the resonance intensities over the whole study area. This thesis documents an approach to use all reliable resonance intensities in MRSI based on multivariate mixed effect statistical models for repeated measurement. We applied the method in a series of studies and demonstrated that the distribution of brain metabolites was different among MS patients in different disease phases. These studies also showed the correlations between the brain metabolites and clinical data such as disease duration and clinical disability.</description><creator>Xu, Li, 1971-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Improved methods for analyzing MR spectroscopic imaging in order to better understand neurological injury</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Li Xu, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096730t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mm53g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1c18dg042</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bisphosphonates, drugs typically used to prevent bone loss for patients with osteoporosis, could also be used to enhance bone growth into porous implants. Since systemic administration of bisphosphonates is not appropriate for all patients, there is a need to develop a localized drug delivery system and characterize the drug release. The chemical affinity of bisphosphonates for hydroxyapatite was used to temporarily bind them to hydroxyapatite coatings on porous implants. Implants were immersed in aqueous solution and the drug elution was measured using UV spectrophotometry. With hydroxyapatite coating there was an initial burst of elution followed by more gradual drug release over several weeks. Without hydroxyapatite coating, all of the drug eluted in a maximum of three hours. This study served to demonstrate the feasibility of binding bisphosphonate compounds to hydroxyapatite coatings and characterized the elution characteristics as a function of time.</description><creator>White, Courtney Ellen.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Characteristics of bisphosphonate elution from orthopaedic implants</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Courtney Ellen White, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j6731414f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dg042</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wh246s36v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Grinding in mineral processing is used to liberate valuable minerals from ore and prepare feed for mineral separation. It accounts for up to 50% of a concentrator's energy consumption. Ball mills are usually adopted in grinding processes; however their energy efficiency is low. Consequently, a small improvement can lead to important savings. Population balance models can be used for ball mill optimization, but their use is limited because they are black box models based on incomplete information about the breakage events inside ball mills. Charge motion simulators, based on the discrete element method (DEM), not only provide information about charge media motion, but also collision energy distributions inside ball mills. Ball mill optimization can be achieved using charge motion simulators if the product size distribution can be predicted by linking charge motion results with single particle breakage tests. Single particle drop tests were carried out to determine the effect of different levels of impact energy. Fundamental ore breakage model equations for an impact breakage event were established, and were applied for the drop weight tests based on a theoretical breakage mechanism. The energy consumptions are calculated with the given feed and product size distribution with the established equations. The comparison of two kinds of drop weight test devices were made and the effect of impact speeds of drop blocks on particle breakage at constant impact energy level was also discussed.</description><creator>Li, Wenwu, 1972-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Exploring the fundamentals of impact breakage events in grinding</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Wenwu Li, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059c769z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246s36v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mv444</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>With the increasing popularity of the Internet, computer networking courses are becoming important elements of undergraduate and graduate curricula. Unfortunately, due to the security and cost worries, it is impractical to establish a real network environment for teaching and learning purposes. The GINI toolkit developed by Advanced Networking Research Lab of Mcgill University provides the solution for it. It is an overlay experimentation platform that allows running a virtual micro network on a single host. However, wireless applications are not supported by GINI currently while the explosive growth of the wireless computing calls for a deep understanding of the wireless network. Therefore, in my thesis, an emulator for ad-hoc wireless local area network is implemented and plugged into the GINI toolkit. It is built on a virtual Linux kernel, called Usermode Linux, running on top of a central controlling instance. The central controlling instance, also known as wireless GINI center, provides efficient medium access control mechanisms, a set of complete propagation channel models, concrete frame corruption functions, and practical node mobility patterns. Generally, the wireless GINI can establish a software-based but realistic wireless environment, helping diverse experiments on new wireless network algorithms.</description><creator>Liao, Sheng, 1979-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Wireless GINI : an emulator for ad-hoc wireless local area networks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Sheng Liao, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mp94w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mv444</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21tf651</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Renal failure affects a wide global population; while acute renal failure may be reversed given prompt treatment, chronic renal failure often degenerates to end stage renal disease (ESRD). Dialysis is the main treatment modality for renal failure, but its long term use is associated with complications leading to morbidity and mortality events. In this thesis, a safe, economic and convenient adjunct consisting of microencapsulated active agents is formulated for oral administration. Probiotic bacteria Lactobacillus acidophilus and Bifidobacteria longum were metabolically induced for urea uptake, and the better adapted bacterium microencapsulated with activated charcoal in a calcium-alginate matrix with a chitosan membrane. The efficacy of the microcapsules was tested in-vitro in a simulated gastric media containing uremic analytes similar to pathological levels in ESRD patients. Results showed that the combination of probiotic bacteria and adsorbent not only trap uremic toxins such as creatinine and urea, but also, activated charcoal offer support in preserving the viability of the live bacterial cells in the gastric transit as well as in storage conditions for over a month.</description><creator>Lim, Trisna.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Microcapsules immobilizing activated charcoal and metabolically induced Lactobacillus acidophilus cells as potential oral renal failure therapy formulation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Trisna Lim, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s0413.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21tf651</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jk62b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Scalp electroencephalograms (EEGs) constitute a well-established modality in the diagnosis of epilepsy. EEGs are frequently contaminated by artifacts originating from various sources such as scalp muscles, ocular activity, or patient movement. Recently, independent component analysis (ICA) has been applied to separate and remove statistically independent artifactual sources from scalp EEG recorded during seizures. However, this method requires a trained electroencephalographer to visually identify the artifacts among the components extracted by ICA. Proposed is a system to automate this process, using a Bayesian framework to classify the components as either brain activity or artifact. The system identified EEG components with 87.6% sensitivity and 70.2% specificity. Most misclassified components were mixtures of EEG and artifactual activity. The classification error rate was comparable to the human intra-expert variability observed in EEG classification tasks. The value of system lies in its ability to remove simultaneously and automatically several types of artifacts from the EEG.</description><creator>Levan, Pierre.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>A system for automatic artifact removal in ictal scalp electroencephalograms /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Pierre Levan, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45q9195.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jk62b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3484zh159</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this work was to develop novel 3D coralline-chitosan macroporous composite scaffolds for in vitro bone tissue engineering and investigate cellular responses to these scaffolds. In these composites, coral skeletal material, which is made of calcium carbonate (CaCO3), was simultaneously used as particulate reinforcing phase and gas-forming agent to obtain a structure with large pores and improved mechanical and biological properties. The reaction between the coralline material and the acidic chitosan polymer solvent, which produces carbon dioxide (CO2), was rapidly stopped by the subsequent thermally induced phase separation step, leaving coral particulates in the polymeric structure. Scaffolds containing 5 different proportions of coralline material (0, 25, 50, 75, and 100 wt%) were developed and studied under two different aspects. In a first part, the coralline:chitosan weight ratio parameter was studied for its effects on the physical properties of the scaffolds with a combination of scanning electron microscope (SEM), micro-CT imaging, and compression testing. In a second part, the scaffolds were cultured with mice MSCs. Cellular morphology, DNA content, as well as expression of osteogenic markers alkaline phosphatase (ALP) activity and osteocalcin release were evaluated. The effect of cell culture medium supplementation with beta-glycerophosphate and dexamethasone was studied. The results showed that higher coralline concentration increased the pore wall thickness and favoured large pore formation. Varying the coralline powder to chitosan polymer ratio from 0 to 75 wt% increased the observed pore sizes from 80 microm to 400 microm in average and decreased the porosity from 91% to 78%. The equilibrium compressive modulus was improved proportionally with the coral content, and the 75 wt% composites had a significantly higher modulus than all the other chitosan-based scaffolds. The coralline scaffolds showed by far the highest evaluation of cell number and ALP activity over all the other chitosan-based scaffolds. They were the only materials on which the osteocalcin protein was release throughout the study and generally at a high level. Nevertheless, the coralline:chitosan composite scaffolds containing high coralline ratios generally showed higher results than the pure chitosan scaffolds. Of all the chitosan-based scaffolds, the cells cultured on the 75:25 coralline:chitosan scaffolds obtained the highest peak of ALP activity and generally obtained the highest cell number. While the presence of osteogenic supplements had no obvious effect on cell behaviour and osteogenic differentiation, distinct cell morphology and osteoblastic phenotype expression were observed depending on the coralline to chitosan ratios composing the scaffolds. The results strongly suggest that coralline:chitosan composites, especially those having a high coralline content, may enhance adhesion proliferation and osteogenic differentiation of MSCs in comparison with pure chitosan. In conclusion, composite scaffolds with improved mechanical and biological properties concomitant with large pores were achieved by increasing the coralline:chitosan weight ratio. These composites possess therefore many advantages over coralline and chitosan scaffolds, suggesting that they have an excellent potential as biomatrices for tissue engineering.</description><creator>Gravel, Mylène.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Novel chitosan-coralline composite biomatrices for bone tissue engineering applications : microarchitectural features and in vitro mesenchymal stem cell responses</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Mylène Gravel, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p0623.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zh159</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848q872</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The last decade has witnessed an explosive growth in internet protocol, packet based traffic. Although long-haul fiber backbone networks provide capacities on the order of Tb/s, a bottleneck at the access network has arisen due to electronic domain signal processing. Recent developments in optical multiprotocol label switching (MPLS) access networks promise to remove this bottleneck and allow Gb/s capacities per user and satisfy foreseeable future bandwidth requirements. This thesis introduces an optical MPLS network where packet payloads are wavelength multiplexed and labels correspond to spectral optical code division multiple access codes. Using this network, we examine payload and label processing issues in nodes as packets transit through the core network. We develop a software package to model data traffic flow in a node, where reduced sets of realistic wavelength converters are used to mitigate payload wavelength contentions. Furthermore, we successfully demonstrate an all-photonic label switching system to convert (7,4) spectral m-sequence labels using commercially available optical components.</description><creator>Gordon, Reuven Eli.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Contention resolution and label switching in optical multiprotocol label switching networks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Reuven Eli Gordon, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q1768.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848q872</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kb02w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Structural damage detection at the earliest possible stage is very important in the aerospace industry to prevent major failures. In this work, a potential cost-effective crack detection method using piezoelectric strips bonded on the structure was studied. A crack model was developed and validated. Static, modal and transient dynamic analysises are performed for the case of piezoelectric strips bonded to the structure by using a finite element method to explore the effectiveness of the crack detection method. Panel methods are used for steady flow problems of fixed wings in order to calculate the pressure distributions on the wing surface. A flat wing with a crack subjected to aerodynamic load was simulated to predict the presence of the crack. It is found that the voltage difference between the piezoelectric strips bonded at the same location (one on the upper side and the other on the lower side) can be used to predict the presence of the crack. For wing structure crack detection, the sensitivity is limited if the steady aerodynamic load is used as an excitation.</description><creator>Han, Yong, 1969-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Detection of cracks in aircraft structures using piezoelectric sensors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Yong Han, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zn68w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kb02w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62f847q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The degradation of C8-C16 alpha,beta-dichloroalkanes by Rhodococcus rhodochrous ATCC 13808 and Pseudomonas oleovorans ATCC 29347 was studied. The carbon chain length of the alpha,beta-dichloroalkane influenced the degradation rates of these compounds and the observed trends were species-dependent. R. rhodochrous exhibited faster rates towards the longer-chained compounds whereas P. oleovorans most rapidly degraded the shorter-chained compounds. This observation is consistent with the chain-length specificity of the hydroxylase enzymes responsible for initiating the degradation of alkanes by each organism. Studies conducted in a cyclone batch reactor indicated that alpha,beta-dichloroalkanes are modified to chlorinated metabolites prior to the dechlorination step. This indicates that the degradation of alpha,beta-dichloroalkanes is initiated by a hydroxylase acting on the non-chlorinated end of the molecule.</description><creator>Harris, Randall.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Degradation of dichloroalkanes by Rhodococcus rhodochrous and Pseudomonas oleovorans</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Randall Harris, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cd406.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62f847q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kb09t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>OBJECTIVE: Innovations in surgery are advocated on the basis of "enhanced recovery", currently measured using a mix of narrowly focused administrative indicators or patient-reported multiple-item questionnaires. Questionnaire length and the difficulty of integrating these different viewpoints limit accurate measurement. The objective of our study was to describe a method to develop a harmonized single linear measure that would be sensitive to expected differences in surgical recovery.  METHODS: The measure was developed and validated using data from 50 patients undergoing laparoscopic   cholecystectomy.  Patients were assessed preoperatively, 1week and 1month postoperatively by the following measures:health-related quality-of-life[generic(SF-36) and disease-specific(GIQLI)], symptoms (visual analog scales for pain and fatigue), physical activity (questionnaire) and function(6-minute-walk-test). Rasch analysis combined items across domains of the various instruments to develop the new measure on a logit scale which was transformed to a score from 0-100(SD). Reliability and validity were assessed.  *P&lt;0.05 RESULTS: A 34-item measure met all model requirements and included items from all domains. Reliability was excellent (0.96). Mean score decreased from 60(18) preoperatively to 55(15) at 1week* and increased above baseline to 68(18) at 1month*. Construct validity was assessed by comparing patients with or without complications. Groups were similar preoperatively (54vs62), but patients with complications had lower scores at 1 week (48vs58*) and 1month (57vs73*). The measure had moderate correlations with all instruments at all time points (r=0.33-0.87). CONCLUSIONS: A novel measure of surgical recovery was developed encompassing a broad range of domains. Results are compatible with clinically observed postoperative recovery trajectories.  This method illustrates that recovery can be quantified with mathematical units.</description><description>OBJECTIF: Innovations en chirurgie sont préconisées sur la base de «convalescence amélioré», actuellement mesuré en utilisant un mélange d'indicateurs administratifs étroitement ciblés ou des questionnaires à choix multiples rapportés par les patients. La longueur du questionnaire et la difficulté à intégrer ces différents points de vue limitent la précision de ces mesures. L'objectif de notre étude était de décrire une méthode pour déveloper une mesure harmonisée et quantitative qui serait sensible aux différences attendues en matière de rétablissement chirurgicale. MÉTHODES: La mesure a été développé et validé en utilisant des données de 50 patients devant subir une cholécystectomie laparoscopique. Les patients ont été évalués en préopératoire, 1 semaine et 1 mois après l'opération par les mesures suivantes: la santé liée à la qualité de vie [générique(SF-36) ou spécifique à la maladie (GIQLI)], les symptômes (échelles visuelle analogique de la douleur et la fatigue), l'activité physique (CHAMPS questionnaire) et la fonction (6MWT). L'analyse selon le modèle Rasch a combiné à travers les domaines des différents instruments pour développer la nouvelle mesure sur une échelle logit qui a été transformée à un score de 0 à 100 (SD). La fiabilité et la validité ont été évaluées.   * P = 0,05 RÉSULTATS: Une mesure de 34 items a satisfait toutes les exigences du modèle et a inclus des items de tous les domaines. La fiabilité a été excellente (0,96). Score moyen a diminué de 60 (18) en préopératoire à 55 (15) * à 1 semaine postop et a augmenté à 68 (18) à un mois *. La validité de construct a été évaluée en comparant des patients avec ou sans complications. Les groupes étaient similaires en préopératoire (54vs62), mais les patients présentant des complications avaient des scores inférieurs à 1 semaine (48vs58 *) et à un mois (57vs73 *). La mesure avait une corrélation modérée avec tous les instruments à tous les points dans le temps (r = de 0,33 à 0,87). CONCLUSIONS: Une nouvelle mesure de rétablissement chirurgicale a été élaboré englobant un large éventail de domaines. Les résultats sont compatibles avec les trajectoires de récupération postopératoire observées cliniquement. Cette méthode démontre que la récupération peut être quantifiée avec des unités mathématiques. </description><creator>Tran, Tung</creator><contributor>Liane S Feldman (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Nancy Mayo (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</subject><title>Development of a novel measure of surgical recovery using Rasch analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/44558d705.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kb09t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sj93z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study aims to expound the distinctive character of 16th-century Spanish Protestant theology, with special reference to the works of two exiled former monks from Seville, Casiodoro de Reina (c. 1520–1594) and Antonio del Corro (1527–1591), and thereby to shed light on a relatively neglected Reformation movement.  A particular aim is to trace the ecclesiological significance of the Spaniards' distinctive image of the church as a persecuted people who share in Christ's sufferings in a very public way, with particular reference to standards of authority, formal ordinances, and mission in the world.  In Chapter One we investigate the origins of Spanish Protestantism by considering the reforming impulse in the theology of the exiles' mentor, the Sevillian cathedral preacher Constantino Ponce de la Fuente (1502 – 1559).  In Chapter Two we outline the orthodox (or 'Chalcedonian') Christological assumptions which undergird the Spanish Protestant view of salvation as participation in Christ's work as Prophet, Priest and King.   In Chapter Three we examine the way in which Reina's and Corro's doctrine of the church's authority in relation to Scripture and their view of the church's whereabouts with reference to its marks of obedience, both illustrate and reinforce a nomadic theme in their theology.   In Chapter Four we relate their concerns for Christian unity and holiness to their mediating approaches to disputes about the Lord's Supper.  Here we give special attention to Reina's 'instrumental realism' in relation to religious signs, and to the centrality of the ministry of the Word in both reformers' sacramental theology.  Finally, in Chapter Five we study the missiological aspect of Spanish Protestant ecclesiology, highlighting the way in which questions about human agency, personal holiness and religious tolerance shape a robust understanding of the church's witness in the world in general and to Muslims in particular.  </description><description>La présente étude vise à exposer le caractère distinctif de la théologie protestante espagnole du XVIe siècle, notamment à travers des travaux de deux anciens moines exilés de Séville, Casiodoro de Reina (c. 1520 à 1594) et Antonio del Corro (1527-1591) et, partant, à faire la lumière sur un mouvement plutôt délaissé de la Réforme. Il s'agit en particulier de retracer l'importance ecclésiologique de l'image distinctive qu'entretiennent les Espagnols de l'Église en tant qu'un peuple persécuté qui partage les souffrances du Christ d'une façon très publique, avec l'accent sur les normes de l'autorité, les ordonnances officielles et leur mission dans le monde. Dans le premier chapitre, nous examinons les origines du protestantisme espagnol en tenant compte de l'élan réformateur retrouvé dans la théologie du conseiller des deux exilés, Constantino Ponce de la Fuente (1502-1559), prédicateur de la cathédrale de Séville. Au deuxième chapitre, nous traçons les grandes lignes des suppositions christologiques orthodoxes (ou « chalcédoniennes ») qui sous-tendent le point de vue protestant espagnol du salut comme étant la participation à l'œuvre du Christ Prêtre, Prophète, Roi. Au troisième chapitre, nous examinons la manière dont la doctrine de l'autorité de l'Église concernant l'Écriture Sainte, ainsi que l'opinion de la position de l'Église relative à ses marques d'obéissance, à la fois illustrent et renforcent un thème nomade dans leur théologie. Dans le quatrième chapitre, nous rattachons leurs préoccupations concernant l'unité et la sainteté chrétiennes à leurs approches médiatrices visant les querelles au sujet de la Cène du Seigneur. Nous portons une attention particulière au « réalisme instrumental » de Reina quant aux signes religieux et à la centralité du ministère de la Parole dans la théologie sacramentelle desdits deux réformateurs. Enfin, au chapitre cinq, nous étudions l'aspect missiologique de l'ecclésiologie protestante espagnole, soulignant la manière dont les questions concernant l'action humaine, la sainteté personnelle et la tolérance religieuse façonnent une compréhension solide du témoignage de l'Église dans le monde en général et aux musulmans en particulier.</description><creator>Griffin, Steven Richard</creator><contributor>W J Torrance Kirby (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Theology</subject><title>Participants in the sufferings of Christ (1 Pet 4:13): 16th-century Spanish protestant ecclesiology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n296wz480.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sj93z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rj430504t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:20:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette recherche analyse les revendications et les contre-revendications liées à la citoyenneté et à la foi faites par les acteurs politiques musulmans américains et canadiens durant la période 2001-2008. Elle met en évidence les processus interactifs par lesquels des discours en concurrence sur la citoyenneté et sur la foi sont négociés et aboutissent à des constructions divergentes de la citoyenneté musulmane, ces constructions étant de type dominant, libéral, laïque ou progressiste.  En utilisant des concepts des théories sur la citoyenneté, sur l'identité collective et sur les mouvements sociaux, la recherche explique comment des identités collectives divergentes sont produites au sein d'un même groupe à travers des interactions complexes entre : a) le bagage idéologique et les biographies des revendicateurs; b) les structures démographiques des communautés; c) les tensions historiques par rapport aux traditions et aux identités qui sont négociées; et d) les constellations politiques actuelles et préalables aux revendications et contre-revendications. De plus, ces contestations concernant l'identité collective, de la citoyenneté et de la foi ne sont pas seulement pertinentes pour le groupe étudié (les musulmans canadiens ou américains), mais elles contribuent aussi à mettre en relief les éléments qui sont inclus, exclus et omis dans les discours nationaux sur  l'appartenance des citoyens et sur les hiérarchies dans les obligations, ainsi que la façon dont ces discours sont remis en question.</description><description>This study analyzes the claims-making and counter-claims-making on citizenship and faith by American and Canadian Muslim political actors over the 2001-2008 period.  It highlights the interactive processes by which competing discourses on citizenship and faith are negotiated to produce divergent constructions of Muslim citizenship: mainstream, liberal, secular, and progressive.  Utilizing insights from theories of citizenship, collective identity and social movements, I show how divergent collective identities are produced within the same categorical group through complex interactions between: a) ideological baggage and biographies of claims-makers; b) demographic patterns of communities; c) historical tensions in the traditions and identities that are being negotiated; and d) the actual political constellations, both proximate and durable, in which such claims and counter-claims are being made.  Moreover, such contests about collective identity, citizenship and faith are not only relevant for the group (American Muslim or Canadian Muslim), but also help highlight the inclusions, exclusions and blindspots in national narratives about belonging and hierarchies of obligations and how these are challenged.</description><creator>Amin, Sara Nuzhat</creator><contributor>Kathleen Fallon (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Steven Rytina (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2011</date><subject>Sociology - Ethnic and Racial Studies </subject><title>Contesting citizenship and faith: Muslim claims-making in Canada and the United States, 2001-2008</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415p975z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rj430504t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):26200</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>