<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T00:51:08Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):12625" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hd07s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:20:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This doctoral dissertation addresses land art—ephemeral, site-specific works created from found materials, such as plants, stones, logs, earth, and water, in public and private outdoor  locales—by Canadian artists from 1969 to 1980. I examine lesser-known artworks and writings by, and archival materials pertaining to, the N.E. Thing Co. (Iain and Ingrid Baxter), Dean Ellis,   Robin Mackenzie, Reinhard Reitzenstein, and Bill Vazan. Despite the diversity of materials and   settings chosen by artists, the artworks of interest to this study are united by their operation as   viewing devices that transformatively mediate the beholder's view of the sites in which the   works are located. My central argument is that three viewing devices featured in Canadian land   art—frames, viewfinders, and apertures—deliberately destabilize the conception of site. These   devices undermine the commonly assumed stability, visual coherence, fixity, and boundaries of   sites by producing new, visually experienced sites displaying unstable, mutable, even contradictory appearances. I further underscore that these views respond critically to issues in Canadian culture, history, and regional politics in the post-Centenary era. To develop this argument, the Introduction situates Canadian land art in relation to existing scholarship on theories of visual perception and site specificity in 20th-century outdoor art (predominantly devoted to American and European art). The Introduction specifies this study's original contributions to previous scholarship before mapping the structure of the dissertation. Chapter One defines essential terms, concepts, and debates, and proposes a contextual definition of visually oriented land art in Canada. Each of the subsequent four chapters, chronologically and thematically ordered, analyzes a particular type of viewing device and model of site in an artwork by a Canadian artist discussed in connection with contemporaneous works by international artists. The Conclusion reprises the central argument, expands on the contextual definition, and extricates the principal characteristics defining land art's manipulation of site through sight. </description><description>Cette thèse analyse le « land art » canadien produit entre 1969 et 1980. Cet art comprend     des œuvres éphémères installées dans des lieux publiques et privés et fabriquées d'objets et de     matériaux trouvés, incluant des plantes, des pierres, des bûches, de la terre, et de l'eau.     J'examine des œuvres d'art moins connues, des textes, et des documents d'archives des artistes     N.E. Thing Co. (Iain et Ingrid Baxter), Dean Ellis, Robin Mackenzie, Reinhard Reitzenstein, et     Bill Vazan. Malgré la diversité des matériaux et des lieux sélectionnés par ces artistes, leurs     œuvres partagent la fonction d'agir comme « dispositifs visuels » qui médiatisent la perception     visuelle du sujet face aux sites où se trouvent les œuvres. Mon argument central propose que les     trois catégories de dispositifs visuels caractérisant le land art canadien—cadres, viseurs, et    ouvertures—déstabilisent le concept du site. Ces œuvres sapent la stabilité, la cohérence, la fixité, et les limites conventionnellement attribuées aux sites en produisant des nouvelles vues dotées d'apparences instables, changeantes, et parfois paradoxales. Je souligne aussi que les vues produites par ces œuvres répondent de façon critique à la culture et l'histoire canadiennes post-    centenaires ainsi qu'aux politiques régionales. Pour développer cet argument, l'introduction situe     le land art canadien par rapport aux publications scientifiques (dont la majorité traite de l'art     américain et européen) concernant les théories de la vision et du lieu dans l'art in situ     contemporain du vingtième siècle. L'introduction identifie les contributions originales de cette étude à la littérature scientifique et décrit la structure de la thèse. Le premier chapitre définit les termes, les concepts et les débats essentiels au développement du land art. Il propose également une définition contextuelle du land art canadien orienté visuellement. Chacun des quatre chapitres suivants, organisés chronologiquement et thématiquement, examine un dispositif visuel et un type de site dans une œuvre spécifique d'un artiste canadien en tissant des liens avec des œuvres d'artistes internationaux. La conclusion reprend l'argument, développe la définition contextuelle, et démontre les caractéristiques principales de la manipulation des sites à travers une diversité de stratégies visuelles.  </description><creator>Van Toorn, Tai Amida</creator><contributor>Christine Ross (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Art History</subject><title>On site, out of sight: viewing devices in Canadian land art, 1969-1980</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580q93c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hd07s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33s0802</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:20:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>De nombreux auteurs suggèrent que les changements environnementaux d'origine anthropique (c.-à-d., eutrophisation et réchauffement climatique) ont créé des conditions propices pour une dominance globale des cyanobactéries dans les communautés phytoplanctoniques. Cependant, à ce jour, il n'existe pas de synthèse quantitative pour appuyer cette présomption et nous avons très peu d'évidences empiriques des relations synergétiques entre les facteurs environnementaux qui peuvent être responsables d'une expansion des cyanobactéries à travers le temps. Un échantillonnage pluriannuel des lacs, couplé avec des reconstitutions paléolimnologiques s'est avéré une stratégie efficace pour répondre à ces questions. Dans ma thèse de doctorat, j'ai quantifié les tendances temporelles (bi-décennale; 1985-2011 CE à centenaire; 1800-2011 CE) de cyanobactéries, aussi bien au niveau régional (Alberta, Canada) qu'au niveau mondial. De plus, afin d'expliquer les tendances de cyanobactéries observées dans certains sites ou points temporels, j'ai également évalué les effets additifs et synergétiques entre les facteurs environnementaux. Par exemple, en utilisant des suivis de données de phytoplancton à long terme, provenant de cinq lacs albertains, j'ai démontré que l'augmentation de la biomasse des cyanobactéries est due à l'effet additif de la hausse des températures d'eau, de l'intensification de la stratification thermique, et des concentrations de nutriments élevés. En comparant des modèles empiriques basés sur des données spatiales à des données temporelles, j'ai démontré que l'utilisation de données spatiales est une méthode valide pour prédire la biomasse des cyanobactéries à l'échelle décennale. J'ai ensuite comparé des modèles basés sur différentes échelles temporelles (bi-décennale à centenaire) pour vérifier si la réponse des cyanobactéries face aux développements environnementaux a changée depuis le début de l'Anthropocène (ca. 1850 CE). En prolongeant l'échelle temporelle, j'ai noté une perte de variance expliquée de plus de 70% chez les modèles centenaires. Au niveau régional, les changements anthropiques qui sont survenus depuis les années ca. 1945 CE (eutrophisation et augmentation de la température de l'eau) ont facilité et expliquent l'expansion des cyanobactéries. Finalement, j'ai quantifié l'augmentation de l'abondance des cyanobactéries (accélération et ampleur) au cours des dernières ~200 ans en menant une synthèse de plus de 100 archives paléolimnologiques et ~20 suivis de phytoplancton à long terme. Avec ces données, j'ai démontré que dans l'hémisphère nord, l'augmentation des cyanobactéries est reliée à l'augmentation de l'apport en nutriments, l'élévation et la morphométrie des lacs. En termes généraux, ma thèse a amélioré nos connaissances de la dynamique spatio-temporelle des cyanobactéries dans les lacs tempérés et des facteurs expliquant cette dynamique. Ma thèse a également permis d'isoler certaines causes de l'expansion accélérée des cyanobactéries lorsque des seuils environnementaux sont franchis et lorsque des interactions entre ces facteurs se développent.</description><description>Numerous authors are reporting that anthropogenic changes to the environment (i.e., cultural eutrophication and climate warming) have provided opportune conditions for a global dominance of phytoplankton communities by cyanobacteria. Yet, to date there has been no quantitative synthesis to support this claim and we have very little empirical evidence of synergistic relationships among the environmental drivers that could be responsible for an expansion of cyanobacteria through time. Multi-year lake monitoring data coupled with paleolimnological reconstructions proved to be an effective strategy to address these questions. In my doctoral thesis, I quantified temporal (decadal; 1985-2011 CE to centennial; 1800-2011 CE) cyanobacterial trends, both at the regional (Alberta, Canada) and global scale. Furthermore, to explain cyanobacterial trends observed in certain sites or time points, I evaluated additive and synergistic effects among drivers. For example, using phytoplankton time series data from five Albertan lakes, I show that the increase in cyanobacterial biomass is greatest under a combination of warmer water temperatures, increased intensity of thermal stratification, and elevated nutrient concentrations. I further show that space for time substitutions are valid for predicting cyanobacterial biomass by comparing empirical models developed from lake surveys to decadal-scale time series. To test whether the response of cyanobacteria in the face of environmental development has changed since the start of Anthropocene (ca. 1850 CE), I then compared models based on different time scales (decadal to centennial scales). In extending the timeframe, I found as much as a 70% loss in variance explained with the centennial models. At this regional scale, I showed that the anthropogenic changes that have taken place since ca. 1945 CE (eutrophication and warming of surface waters) have facilitated and explained the expansion of cyanobacteria. Finally, I quantified the increases in cyanobacterial abundance (rate and magnitude) over the past ~200 years by conducting a synthesis of more than 100 paleolimnological records and ~20 long-term monitoring records. With this dataset, I have shown that in the Northern Hemisphere, the increase in cyanobacteria is related to nutrient concentrations, lake elevation and lake morphometry. In general, my thesis has advanced our knowledge of the spatio-temporal dynamics of cyanobacteria in temperate lakes and the factors that can explain these dynamics. My thesis also helped isolate some of the causes of the accelerated expansion of cyanobacteria when environmental thresholds are crossed and when interactions amongst these drivers develop.</description><creator>Taranu, Zofia Ecaterina</creator><contributor>Irene Gregory-Eaves (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Limnology</subject><title>Historical and contemporary drivers of cyanobacterial dynamics: regional and global perspectives</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sk594.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33s0802</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gr572</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:20:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les virus Coxsackie du groupe B3 (CVB3) sont retrouvés partout dans le monde et il y a une prévalence saisonnière. L'infection par CVB3 se manifeste de manière différente selon les personnes. Certains individus ne développent pas de maladies cliniquement apparentes et guérissent spontanément, tandis que d'autres risquent de développer des complications plus sévères comme des affections cardiaques, des hépatites où des atteintes du système nerveux central.  Les cas les plus graves peuvent entraîner la mort du sujet. La souris de laboratoire constitue un modèle idéal pour étudier les mécanismes inhérents à ces formes diverses des maladies induites par l'infection. En effet, des lignées des souris consanguines peuvent être infectées expérimentalement avec des souches humaines du virus CVB3. Les lignés des souris présentant un large spectre des signes cliniques indique que la constitution génétique des individus infectés est un facteur déterminant dans la gravité de l'infection. Nous avons donc formulé l'hypothèse que l'investigation des facteurs génétiques étant à l'origine de  la réponse de l'hôte à l'infection par CVB3 devrait nous conduire à identifier des gènes et des mécanismes moléculaires directement impliqués dans le contrôle de cette infection dont on n'aurait pas eu connaissance dans le passé.Dans le but de mieux cerner la contribution des facteurs génétiques de l'hôte dans l'évolution de l'infection par CVB3, nous avons utilisé une approche de cartographie génétique. En ce sens, nous avons examiné une collection des lignées de souris recombinantes consanguines (RCS) issues des lignées parentales A/J et C57BL/6.  Nous avons constaté que la plupart des lignées BcA (dont le fonds génétique est majoritairement issu de la  lignée C57BL/6) présentaient une susceptibilité accrue en comparaison à C57BL/6. Dû à son taux précoce de mortalité, la lignée BcA86 a été particulièrement visée. En ayant recours à un croisement (BcA86  x C57BL/10)F2 il nous a été possible de détecter un locus dans la région distale du chromosome 13 liée à la sévérité des lésions du foie pendant l'hépatite coxsackievirale. Une étude préalable de liaison génétique, nous avait permis de mettre en évidence le locus Vms1 (viral myocarditis susceptibility) dans la région distale du chromosome 3. Le locus Vms1 est responsable du niveau de la réplication virale, de la nécrose du myocarde et de l'infiltration cellulaire que l'on observe dans le cœur des souris infectées par CVB3. En étudiant des lignées de souris consomiques ainsi qu'en réalisant de nouveaux croisements entre souris sensibles et souris résistantes, nous avons élaboré une cartographie fine de l'intervalle critique contenant le locus Vms1. Aussi avons-nous pu constater que le contrôle de la multiplication virale par Vms1 précède l'infiltration des cellules inflammatoires dans les tissus cardiaques.Le gène Tnni3k code pour une kinase dont l'expression étant spécifique aux cellules cardiaques apparaît comme un gène candidat de choix pour le locus Vms1. En comparant avec les souris normales, nous avons trouvé que la surexpression du gène Tnni3k dans des souris transgéniques leur confère un phénotype de nécrose et d'inflammation extrêmes du tissu cardiaque suite à l'infection par CVB3. Nous avons également établi que l'infection des cardiomyocytes isolés à partir de ces mêmes souris provoque un accroissement de la réplication du virus CVB3 ainsi qu'un profil d'expression unique des gènes inflammatoires. Les  résultats ainsi obtenus ont mis en lumière que la kinase TNNI3K est impliquée dans un circuit de signalisation immunitaire propre au cœur. Ainsi, pris dans leur ensemble, nos travaux apportent des nouvelles voies pour la compréhension du déterminisme génétique de l'hôte dans la sensibilité aux infections par CVB3 ainsi qu'une meilleure connaissance de la pathogénèse de ce virus dévastateur. </description><description>Coxsackievirus B3 (CVB3) is a relatively common cause of infection. Infection by coxsackieviruses is typically mild and resolves quickly without lasting complications. In a subset of individuals, coxsackievirus infection can be severe, leading to permanent damage of vital organs or even death. The mouse presents an ideal model to study natural variation in response CVB3 infection as human isolates of CVB3 productively infect the mouse, and lead to similar pathologies as found in humans. Inbred strains of mice respond differently to CVB3 infection, therefore the genetic background of the host can determine susceptibility to CVB3 infection. We hypothesize that interrogation of genetically determined susceptibility to CVB3 infection will help to identify genes whose direct involvement in control of CVB3 was previously unsuspected. To characterize the contribution of host genetics to coxsackievirus, we screened a panel of recombinant congenic strains (RCS) generated from susceptible A/J and C57BL/6 progenitors. While most C57BL/6 background (BcA) strains were more susceptible than C57BL/6, BcA86 in particular was particularly susceptible to early lethality and hepatic necrosis. A segregating [BcA86xC57BL/10]F2 mapping cross led to the identification of a locus on distal chromosome 13 controlling liver damage during coxsackieviral hepatitis. Previously through the analysis of a segregating we detected the Vms1 (viral myocarditis susceptibility) locus on distal chromosome 3. Vms1 controls viral replication, inflammation and necrosis within the heart during CVB3 infection. We have further refined this locus in additional mapping crosses and congenic lines of mice. We have also determined that Vms1 controls viral replication before inflammation becomes evident within the heart. The cardiac specific kinase Tnni3k is a candidate gene for Vms1. We found that overexpression of TNNI3K greatly enhanced necrosis and inflammation in the heart following CVB3 infection. Furthermore, we found increased viral replication and gene expression and changes within isolated cardiomyocytes, indicating TNNI3K is implicated in a heart specific immune pathway. Altogether, our results provide new functional insight into the host determinants of pathogenesis following infection with coxsackievirus B3. </description><creator>Wiltshire, Sean Andrew</creator><contributor>Silvia Vidal (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>Mouse genetic models of cardiovirulent coxsackievirus B3 infection</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924f93k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gr572</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5h73q0395</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:20:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nétrine-1 est une molécule sécrétée de ~75kDa qui existe depuis le développement de la symétrie bilatérale chez les animaux, et dont l'existence a été postulé il'ya plus d'un siècle par Ramon y Cajal. Depuis la découverte initiale de la nétrine-1 comme un déterminant dans la guidance  des axones  commissure dans la moelle neurone, la nétrine-1 a été attribué à multiples rôles dans l'histogenèse des tissus embryonnaires, fonctionnant à la fois autonome cellulaire et non cellulaire, et à des distances courtes et longues de la source de sa sécrétion. Les neurones corticaux nées le long des ventricules latéraux mettent en place des processus polarisés qui relient des circuits synaptiques capables de codage, prévision, mémoire, et même la compréhensions des statistiques complexes de l'environnement. Des défauts de développement dans la formation de ces circuits sont associés à des troubles du développement cognitif et la désintégration des circuits corticaux conduisant à des pathologies cognitives dévastateurs de la démence. Dans cette thèse, je présente des preuves que la nétrine-1 dirige le développement du cortex à la fois au cours de la prolifération des neurones corticaux, et plus tard, lors de la mise en place des synapses corticales excitateurs. Ces résultats permettent d'identifier la nétrine-1 comme un nouveau régulateur dans le développement des circuits corticaux au cours de la génération de neurones corticaux et leur connexion à des circuits synaptiques.</description><description>Netrin-1 is a ~75kDa secreted molecule as old as bilateral symmetry in animals, whose existence was initially postulated more than a century ago by Ramon y Cajal. Since the initial discovery of netrin-1 as a determinant of spinal commissural neuron axon guidance, netrin-1 has been attributed manifold roles in the histogenesis of embryonic tissues, functioning both cell and non-cell autonomously, at short and long ranges from the source of its secretion. During mammalian embryonic development, a laminated pallium - the cerebral cortex - blooms out of the neural tube. Cortical neurons born along the lateral ventricles establish polarized processes which connect into synaptic circuits capable of encoding, predicting, remembering, and even comprehending the complex statistics of the environment.  Developmental defects in the formation of these circuits are associated with developmental cognitive disorders and the disintegration of cortical circuits leads to the devastating cognitive pathologies of dementia. In this thesis I present evidence that netrin-1 directs the development of cortex both during the proliferation of cortical neurons and later during the establishment of excitatory cortical synapses. These findings identify netrin-1 as a novel regulator of the development of excitatory circuits of the cerebral cortex during the generation of neurons and their connection into synaptic circuits.</description><creator>Goldman, Jennifer Sarah</creator><contributor>Timothy E Kennedy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Netrin-1 regulates early development of cerebral cortex</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c3894.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73q0395</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b922w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:20:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Traditionnellement, la chimiothérapie utilisée pour le traitement du cancer du sein comptait sur des combinaisons qui contiennent 5-Flurouracile (5-FU).  Récemment, pour améliorer l'index thérapeutique de 5-FU et sa disponibilité par voie orale, un nouveau promédicament nommé capécitabine (Xeloda ®) a été développé. Capécitabine nécessite l'activation enzymatique par l'enzyme hépatique carboxylestérase (CES), pour générer 5'-DFCR, puis 5'-DFUR, ce dernier à son tour est métabolisé par thymidine phosphorylase (TP) en 5-FU. La bonne tolérance de capécitabine a inspiré la recherche d'agents avec lesquels ce médicament peut avoir une synergie. De nombreuses combinaisons de deux médicaments à base de capecitabine ont été proposées avec différents agents, tels que les taxanes et les inhibiteurs de kinases, avec divers degrés de succès. Nous avons avancé l'hypothèse que exploiter des enzymes impliquées dans l'activation de capécitabine devraient conduire à des fortes modalités synergiques. Ici, nous avons exploité deux de ces enzymes impliquées dans le métabolisme de capécitabine, CES et TP, afin de concevoir des molécules uniques, appelés « combi-molécules » capables de mimer la combinaison de  capécitabine + un inhibiteur du récepteur EGFR. Notre logique de conception a été renforcée par l'observation initiale que l'inhibition de l'EGFR conduit à une augmentation des niveaux TP. Cette thèse définit d'abord le profil pharmacologique de la combinaison d'un inhibiteur de EGFR + 5'-DFUR, qui a démontré une corrélation linéaire entre l'inhibition de la tyrosine kinase de l'EGFR et l'augmentation dans l'expression de TP (y = 0,02922 * x + 0,4642, R2 = 0,88, P = 0,005). Ainsi, nous avons conçu et synthétisé deux classes de combi-molécules: l'une basée sur la fonction carbamate de capécitabine, nécessitant CES pour être activée (les combi-molécules à base de 5'-DFCR ) et une autre contenant une liaison au niveau du N1 du 5'- DFUR qui peut être hydrolysé spontanément. Notre premier prototype, ZRX1 (une combi-molécule à base de 5'-DFCR) était inefficace sous sa forme intégrale. Cependant, quand CES était présente, ZRX1 a induit une augmentation de l'inhibition d'EGFR, d'expression TP, des lésions à l'ADN et de l'apoptose. ZRX1 était, au moins 3 fois plus puissant que capécitabine et 5'-DFUR et a récapitulé les effets de la combinaison. Malheureusement, ZRX1 manquait de puissance inhibitrice  d'EGFR (IC50 = 4 µM) et ne pouvait être activé que dans présence de CES. Vu que ZRX1 n'exerce pas une forte inhibition d'EGFR, nous avons entrepris une étude d'optimisation de la structure de nos molécules, pour améliorer leur pouvoir inhibiteur d'EGFR. Les résultats ont montré que le remplacement de la fonction éthoxyéthyl de ZRX1 par des chaînes contenant des amines a conduis à  des combi-molécules avec des valeurs de IC50 d'inhibition de l'EGFR en nanomolaire, même sous leur forme intégrales. Ceci est valable pour les combi-molécules à base de 5'- DFCR qui avaient le bras inhibiteur d'EGFR greffé sur N3 du sucre comme  CT3-51, et CT3 – 138 et les combi-molécules à base de 5'- DFUR (CT3 -55 CT3 - 127, CT3-1343 et MAT54) substituées en N1. Ces combi-molécules optimisées ont généré des profils d'activité qui imitent la combinaison d'un inhibiteur d'EGFR + capécitabine ou son métabolite 5'- DFUR. Cependant, contrairement à la classe à base 5'-DFCR, la classe à base 5'-DFUR n'exige pas la présence de CES pour générer son double mécanisme d'action d'inhibiteur d'EGFR et d'anti-métabolite. Après avoir défini l'exigence structurelle pour obtenir une combi-molécule efficace, nous avons choisi une de ces molécules afin de se concentrer sur la dissection du mécanisme d'action de notre nouvelle approche.</description><description>Traditionally chemotherapy, used for the treatment of breast cancer, relied on combinations containing 5-Flurouracil (5-FU). Recently, to improve the therapeutic index of 5-FU and its oral availability, a new prodrug termed capecitabine (Xeloda ®) was developed. Capecitabine requires enzymatic activation by hepatic carboxylesterase (CES), to generate 5'-DFCR, then 5'-DFUR, the latter in turn is metabolized by thymidine phosphorylase (TP) into 5-FU. The good tolerance of capecitabine has inspired the search for agents with which it can synergize. Many capecitabine-based two-drug combinations have been proposed with different agents, such taxanes and kinase inhibitors with various degrees of success. We hypothesized that approaches that exploit enzymes involved in the activation of capecitabine should lead to strong synergistic modalities. Here, we exploited two such enzymes involved in the metabolism of capecitabine, TP and CES, to design single molecules, termed "combi-molecules" capable of mimicking the combination of capecitabine with an EGFR tyrosine inhibitor. Our rationale design was further strengthened by the initial observation that EGFR inhibition leads to an increase in TP levels. This thesis first defines the pharmacological profile of the EGFR inhibitor + 5'-DFUR combination, which showed a linear correlation between inhibition of the tyrosine kinase of EGFR and enhancement of TP expression (y = 0.02922*x + 0.4642, R2=0.88, P value=0.005). Thus, we designed and synthesized two classes of combi-molecules: one based on the carbamate function of capecitabine that requires CES for activation (5'-DFCR-based combi-molecules) and another containing a linker at the N1 of 5'-DFUR that can be spontaneously hydrolyzed. Our first prototype, ZRX1 (a 5'-DFCR-based combi-molecule) was ineffective when intact. However, when CES was present, ZRX1 induced an increase in EGFR phosphotyrosine inhibition, TP expression, DNA damage and apoptosis. ZRX1 was, at least, 3-fold more potent than capecitabine and 5'-DFUR and recapitulated the effects of the combination. Unfortunately, ZRX1 was deprived of EGFR inhibitory potency (IC50= 4 µM) on its own and required carboxylesterase (CES) activation to elicit optimal effects. Given the fact that intact ZRX1 would not exert strong EGFR inhibitor, we undertook a structure optimization study of our molecules to enhance their EGFR inhibitory potency. The results showed that replacing the ethoxyethyl linker of ZRX1 by amine-containing chains led to combi-molecules with nanomolar range EGFR inhibition IC50 values even when intact. Whether they had their EGFR inhibitory arm grafted on N3 of the sugar, resulting as in the 5'-DFCR-based combi-molecules (CT3-51, and CT3-138) or on the N1, as in the 5'-DFUR-based combi-molecules CT3-55, CT3-127, CT3-1343 and MAT54. These optimized combi-molecules generated activity profiles that mimicked the combination of EGFR inhibitor + capecitabine or metabolite 5'-DFUR. However, in contrast to the 5'-DFCR-based class, the 5'-DFUR-based class did not require the presence of CES to generate its dual EGFR inhibitory and anti-metabolite mechanism of action. Having defined the structural requirement to obtain a potent combi-molecule, we selected one of such molecule to focus on the dissection of the mechanism of action of our novel approach.</description><creator>Ait Tihyaty, Maria</creator><contributor>Bertrand Jean-Claude (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery </subject><title>Mechanism of action of novel combi-molecules engineered to mimic combinations of EGFR inhibitors with capecitabine- derived metabolites</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000330b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b922w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z9033191</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:20:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mosses play a key role in the carbon (C) budget of black spruce forests, which are widely distributed across Canada and throughout the circumboreal region. Mosses are currently not included in the forest C stock accounting of large-scale national models used by Canada to meet international greenhouse gas reporting requirements. It is therefore essential to increase our scientific understanding of the dynamics of moss-C accumulation in black spruce forest ecosystems in a national-scale context. This thesis was inspired by Canada's national-scale carbon accounting model, the Carbon Budget Model of the Canadian Forest Sector (CBM-CFS3). The model was designed to provide operational forest managers with a tool to make informed management decisions based on C balance simulation of future scenarios.  The model can also be scaled-up to provide regional- or national-C estimates. Previous research and inventory has shown that black spruce forests are widespread in many regions across the country, and that mosses have the potential to contribute significantly to the carbon budget of these systems.  Nevertheless, the CBM-CFS3 does not account for moss-derived carbon in these forests.  My overall objective is to improve scientific understanding of the C dynamics of mosses in black spruce-dominated forests from the perspective of including them in nationally-scaled models such as the CBM-CFS3. To accomplish this I: 1) investigate the potential of moss-derived C to improve the current inadequacy present in the simulation of black spruce soil carbon by CBM-CFS3, 2) collect ground plot data across several study regions in Canada to define moss-tree relationships that can be used as tools to model moss-C accumulation at the regional- or national-scale, and 3) build, test and examine a sub-model for moss-C accumulation that can be added to the CBM-CFS3 model framework to improve carbon budget accounting in black spruce forests across Canada. This research demonstrated that large differences between field-measured C stocks and CBM-CFS3 model predictions in poorly drained black spruce forests were of the same order of magnitude as would be expected if mosses could be included in the model. The field component of the research identified significant relationships between merchantable timber, canopy openness, and the relative abundance and productivity of feather moss and sphagnum moss. Together, these relationships allowed the input and loss of C via mosses to be modelled. The addition of the MOSS-C sub-model to CBM-CFS3 reduced the residual error by five fold; however, we found that the dynamics of the productivity-decomposition pathway included in the model were insufficient to account for all of variation in observed C stocks. The study suggests avenues for future research to better understand the complex interactions between decomposition, weather and fire regime on deep layer carbon storage. The key scientific merits of this thesis are: 1) the demonstration and quantification of the importance of mosses in the carbon budget of black spruce forests in national-scale models such as the CBM-CFS3, 2) the examination of the moss-tree relationships derived from field collected data that can be used to predict moss-C accumulation across several study regions in Canada, 3) the creation of a MOSS-C sub-model that can be directly applied into the current CBM-CFS3 model framework and strengthen the model's ability to predict organic soil C in black spruce forest systems nationally. Together these contributions act to provide an important first step at studying moss-C accumulation from the perspective of large-scale national or regional forest carbon budgets.  They also help to demonstrate that if natural resource scientists aim to improve our ability to predict moss-C in black spruce stands at a national-scale than future work is needed in black spruce-moss ecology from a multi-scaled perspective to complement the work presented in this thesis.</description><description>Les mousses représentent une partie importante du carbone (C) stocké dans les pessières noires qui dominent les régions boréales et circumpolaires canadiennes. Cependant, celles-ci ne sont pas prises en compte dans les modèles utilisés par le Canada pour rendre compte des stocks forestiers de C dans le cadre des exigences internationales en lien avec les gaz à effet de serre. Il est donc nécessaire d'améliorer les connaissances scientifiques sur la dynamique de stockage du C par les mousses dans les écosystèmes dominés par les épinettes noires à l'échelle nationale.  Le modèle CBM-CFS3 du bilan du carbone pour le secteur forestier canadien a servi d'inspiration pour cette thèse. Le CBM-CFS3 ne prend pas en compte le carbone entreposé dans la mousse des pessières noires, même si nous savons que ce stock important peut influencer de façon significative le bilan en C de ces écosystèmes et affecter les comptes rendus nationaux. Mon objectif principal est d'améliorer les connaissances scientifiques sur la dynamique du carbone dans les pessières noires à mousses et de contribuer à sa prise en compte dans les modèles nationaux comme le CBM-CFS3. Pour arriver à ces fins: 1) nous étudions la contribution potentielle du C stocké dans la mousse pour améliorer la simulation du C avec CBM-CFS3 dans les sols des pessières noires, 2) nous récoltons des données de terrain dans différentes régions du Canada que nous utilisons pour établir les relations mousses-arbres qui serviront à améliorer la modélisation du C stocké dans les mousses aux échelles régionales et nationale, et 3) nous construisons, testons et examinons un sous-modèle de stockage de C dans les mousses qui pourra être intégré dans le CBM-CFS3 pour améliorer les estimations du C dans les pessières noires canadiennes. Dans le cadre de ce projet de recherche, j'ai pu démontrer que les différences observées entre les stocks de C mesurés sur le terrain et les prédictions du CBM-CFS3 sont du même ordre de grandeur que les contributions anticipées des mousses. Les études que nous avons effectuées sur le terrain nous ont permis d'identifier des relations significatives entre le bois marchand, utilisé comme entrant principal dans le CBM-CFS3, l'ouverture de la canopée, et l'abondance relative et la productivité des mousses hypnacée et de sphaigne. La mise en commun de ces relations permettent de modéliser les ajouts et pertes de C attribuables aux mousses. L'intégration du sous-modèle MOSS-C au CBM-CFS3 reduit par un facteur de cinq son erreur résiduelle. Cependant, nous avons observé que la dynamique productivité-décomposition ajoutée au modèle était insuffisante pour expliquer complètement la variabilité observée des stocks de C.  Ces résultats suggèrent des pistes de recherches futures qui permettront de mieux comprendre les interactions complexes entre la décomposition, le climat et les feux sur le stockage du carbone. Les contributions scientifiques principales de cette thèse sont: 1) la démonstration de l'importance des mousses dans le bilan de carbone des pessières noires à l'échelle nationale, 2) une meilleure compréhension, grâce aux données de terrain collectées, des relations mousses-arbres qui pourra être utilisée pour prédire les stocks de C dans différentes régions du Canada, 3) la création d'un sous-modèle MOSS-C pouvant être incorporé dans le modèle CBM-CFS3 actuel et en améliorer les prédictions du C organique des sols des pessières noires. Mises ensembles, ces contributions représentent une importante première étape sur l'étude des stock de C dans les mousses dans le contexte des bilans régionaux et nationaux de C. Elles aident aussi à faire la démonstration qu'une amélioration des prédictions des stocks nationaux de C dans les pessières à mousses nécessitera davantage de recherche sur l'écologie de l'épinette noire et des mousses dans une perspective multi-échelle, en complément à la recherche présentée dans cette thèse. </description><creator>Bona, Kelly Ann</creator><contributor>James W Fyles (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Ecology</subject><title>Understanding and modelling moss carbon dynamics in black spruce forests</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fs10t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z9033191</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8049g8264</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:20:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>         Cette thèse analyse la relation entre constitution d'une classe, pratiques religieuses des femmes et espace privé, au sein de la communauté marchande Visnouiste Pustimarg du Gujarat. Il s'agit de montrer, d'une part, que, dans l'Inde moderne, les activités religieuses accomplies par les femmes Pustimarg participent à la formation de la caste baniya et à sa reconnaissance, et que, d'autre part, ces pratiques représentent un appui fondamental à la secte Pustimarg dans l'espace domestique. Les pratiques sociales et religieuses des femmes constituent ainsi un élément central pour comprendre ce que signifie être Visnouiste Pustimarg dans le monde actuel. À partir d'archives et de sources écrites, je commence par mettre à jour l'histoire sociale et économique des communautés baniya durant la période pré-coloniale et coloniale, de manière à montrer comment ces communautés sont devenues les mécènes les plus prestigieux du Pustimarg. Tout au long des XVIIe et XVIIIe siècles, imitant la noblesse du Rajasthan, les baniya manifestent publiquement leur prospérité et leur distinction en faisant des offrandes rituelles dans les temples Pustimarg  (seva, « service »), ou par le biais de dons remis aux maîtres brahamanes de la tradition, les Gosvamis. Alors que la « classe » s'impose comme marqueur d'appartenance sociale dans l'Inde coloniale, les femmes de la haute société Pustimarg tiennent une place essentielle dans l'élaboration du prestige et de la reconnaissance de la famille au sein de l'espace privé. Dans ce travail, je m'intéresse à la manière dont les baniya Pustimarg négocient leur passage dans la modernité. J'examine les questions que posent l'identité sectaire notamment aux hommes baniya dans le contexte des mouvements de réformes sociales pour les femmes qui ont lieu dans la Province de Bombay au XIXe et début XXe siècle (par exemple dans le très connu « Cas Maharaj Libel » en 1862).Pour comprendre les pratiques religieuses des femmes ainsi que leur rôle dans la reconnaissance de la communauté, je m'appuie également sur des sources traditionnelles, telle que la littérature hagiographique Pustimarg (vartas) et les chants de dévotion dhol ou garba composés par les femmes. L'analyse des vartas montre le rôle social de ces femmes et leur place dans l'imaginaire Pustimarg. Elle révèle également que les genres réservés aux femmes constituent un pendant important aux chants liturgiques officiels et plus célèbres des temples Pustimarg. Dans le dernier chapitre de cette thèse, une approche ethnographique permet de montrer comment, dans le contexte contemporain, le mélange de culture matériel et spirituel est perceptible dans des rituels privés de plus en plus tournés vers la consommation ainsi que l'acquisition et l'exposition d'objets religieux dans la maison. Récemment, des femmes de la haute société Pustimarg ont commencé à prendre des leçons sur ce qu'elles considèrent comme le style « classique » des temples, la musique haveli. L'ensemble de ces phénomènes confère aux femmes les rôles de productrice, actrice et témoin de l'identité Pustimarg chez les élites. Les formes matérielles de la dévotion dans l'espace domestique, de même que les pratiques religieuses des femmes (la pratique quotidienne du seva, l'organisation de réunion à la maison, les leçons de musique au temple) font aujourd'hui de la maison le lieu central du Pustimarg.  </description><description>        This dissertation explores the relationship between class formation, women's religious practices, and domesticity among the Pustimarg Vaisnav mercantile communities (baniyas) of Gujarat. It argues that in modern India, Pustimarg women's religious activities inform baniya class formation and respectability on the one hand, and constitute the domestic patronage of Pustimarg on the other.  Women's social and religious practices thus come to be centrally implicated in the question of what it means to be a Pustimarg Vaisnav in the modern world. Using archival and textual sources, I begin by unpacking the social and economic histories of baniya communities in both pre-colonial and colonial contexts, and trace their emergence as Pustimarg's most prestigious patrons. Throughout the seventeenth and eighteenth centuries, in emulation of Rajasthani nobility, baniyas publically displayed wealth and prestige through donative activities centered around both Pustimarg temple ritual (seva, "service"), and gifts offered to the Brahmin religious leaders of the tradition, the Gosvamis. As "class" begins to emerge as a discrete marker of status in colonial India, upper-caste Pustimarg women are positioned as vital actors in the production of family prestige and respectability within the domestic sphere. In this dissertation, I therefore focus on Pustimarg baniya negotiations with modernity and identify baniya men's concerns around sectarian identity as they come to be dramatized in nineteenth and early twentieth-century social reform movements centered upon women in the Bombay Presidency (including the well-known "Maharaj Libel Case" of 1862).   This study also turns to traditional sources, such as Pustimarg hagiographic literature (vartas) and devotional songs composed by women in the dhol and garba genres, in order to understand the religious practices of women in these communities and their relationship to the production of prestige. My analysis of the vartas provides a sense of women's social roles and positions in the Pustimarg imagination, while women's performance genres provide an important counterpoint to the much-celebrated "official" liturgical music of Pustimarg temples (havelis). In the final chapter of the dissertation I draw on my ethnographic work to demonstrate how, in the contemporary context, the imbrication of material and religious cultures is seen through the performance of increasingly commodified styles of domestic ritual and through the consumption and display of religious commodities in the home. Recently, women from upper-class Pustimarg families have also begun taking lessons in what they regard as the "classical" style of temple or haveli music. All these processes, I argue, cast women as the producers, performers, and pedagogues of elite Pustimarg sectarian identities. The material expressions of their devotion in domestic contexts as well as women's religious practices – which includes performing seva daily, organizing religious gatherings in the home, and participating in temple music lessons – have reconstituted the home as a modern site of Pustimarg patronage.</description><creator>Sharma, Shital</creator><contributor>Davesh Soneji (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Religion - Religion General</subject><title>A prestigious path to grace: class, modernity, and female religiosity in Pustimarg Vaisnavism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n178x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g8264</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bf976</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:20:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La première étude présentée met l'emphase sur la formation des bulles au bout d'un tube capillaire immergé dans l'eau en utilisant la photographie à haute vitesse afin de réexaminer les procédés à l'origine de la scission. Plusieurs auteurs ont noté la présence d'une distribution de la taille des bulles (DTB) qui est bimodale pour des systèmes de flottation ayant de faibles concentrations d'agent moussant ou de composé inorganique. Cette distribution semble être reliée à des interactions bulles-bulles. L'étude démontre visuellement des mécanismes reliés à la coalescence et à la trainée d'une bulle créant des bulles plus fines et ainsi une distribution bimodale. La comparaison des modes des petites et grosses bulles (d'un rapport 1/10) révèle les mécanismes potentiels. Sachant que les agents moussants produisent une DTB monomodal et que leurs rôles est de prévenir la coalescence, la création de la DTB bimodal semble être relié à la coalescence.La deuxième étude utilise une technique similaire pour quantifier l'effet des agents moussant et des composés inorganiques sur le type de bulles produites au bout d'un tube capillaire. La photographie à haute vitesse a été utilisée pour déterminer la transition entre la non-coalescence, la coalescence, et la coalescence avec scission. L'ajout d'un soluté inhibe la coalescence des bulles et retarde le début de la production des petites bulles. Les résultats permettent la caractérisation des agents moussants en termes de puissance.Le troisième groupe d'expériences utilise l'enregistrement des signaux sonores passifs pour étudier le rôle des particules (hydrophobes et hydrophiles) sur la coalescence des bulles. Plusieurs études utilisent des techniques optiques pour mesurer directement ou indirectement l'effet d'un soluté sur la coalescence des bulles. Les techniques optiques sont typiquement limitées à l'étude de systèmes biphasés (solution-air) puisque les systèmes triphasés (solution-air-particules) sont généralement opaques. L'enregistrement des signaux sonores passifs a été utilisé pour déterminer l'effet des particules (en concentration de 1 à 10 % m/m de talc ou de silice), sur la formation et la coalescence des bulles produites au bout d'un tube capillaire en présence de MIBC ou chlorure de sodium. Les deux types de particules ont inhibé la coalescence de bulles et la silice a crée la plus grande région de coalescence partielle en comparaison au talc. À 10 % m/m de silice, la coalescence est favorisée s'il y a haute concentration de MIBC.Non seulement les agents moussants et certains composés inorganiques inhibent la coalescence des bulles, mais ils réduisent aussi la vitesse d'ascension. La photographie des bulles ascendantes à montré que la présence de soluté affectait la forme et la vitesse des bulles de façon combinée. Une étude a donc été menée afin d'examiner la relation entre la forme et la vitesse des bulles. Des bulles individuelles d'environ 2.3 mm de diamètre ont été produites au bout d'un tube capillaire immergé dans de l'eau contenant un composé inorganique (NaClO4, KCl, NaCl, Na2SO4, or CaCl2). À l'aide de la photographie à haute vitesse et de techniques d'analyse d'image, le facteur de forme et la vitesse d'ascension de bulles ont été mesurés à un intervalle de 1 ms à une distance d'environ 1.15 à 1.20 m au-dessus du capillaire. Tous les mélanges ont montré des oscillations du facteur de forme et de la vitesse d'ascension reliées. Généralement en augmentant la concentration, on crée des bulles plus sphériques montant à une vitesse plus faible. Les mêmes observations ont été faites en présence de MIBC. Les résultats suggèrent une corrélation unique entre la forme et la vitesse d'ascension des bulles, indépendamment du type de soluté présent.</description><description>Bubble formation, coalescence and break-up processes coupled with bubble velocity determine gas dispersion properties in a flotation cell. Frothers are typically added to inhibit bubble coalescence (decrease bubble size) and reduce bubble rise velocity. If present at elevated concentration the presence of certain inorganic salts has been shown to have a similar capability to frother.Much of the literature focuses on the role of bubble coalescence on the production of fine bubbles. Researchers have hinted that the presence of frother may also affect bubble break-up. For the most part, little attention has been paid to the role of frother in bubble break-up. A few researchers have noted that bubble-bubble interactions may play a role in bubble break-up processes.The first study in the thesis examines bubble formation in water at a capillary using high-speed photography and reviews the processes which lead to bubble break-up. Several authors have noted bi-modal bubble size distributions (BSD) in flotation systems at low frother or inorganic salt concentrations. The origin appears to be related to bubble-bubble interactions. The study provides visual evidence of coalescence-related and wake-related mechanisms creating fine bubbles and bi-modal distributions. Four coalescence mechanisms are identified: coalescence-induced break-up, droplet formation and collision, liquid jet formation and collision, liquid jet disruption to droplets and collision; and two wake-related events: distortion and break-up of trailing bubble, and premature detachment. Comparing the fine/coarse mode ratio in water only systems (ca. 1/10) the possible relevant mechanisms are suggested. Knowing that frothers produce a mono-modal BSD and act to retard coalescence, the origin of the bi-modal BSD is argued to be coalescence-related.The second study uses a similar technique to quantify the effect of frothers and inorganic salts on bubble regimes at a capillary. High-speed photography was used to determine the transition air flow rate between non-coalescence, coalescence, and coalescence with fine bubble production (break-up). The addition of solute inhibited bubble coalescence and delayed the onset of fine bubble production. The tests allow for frother and salt strength characterization.The third set of experiments uses passive acoustic emission monitoring to study the role of solid particles on bubble coalescence. The systems being opaque argue against the use of optical techniques. The effect of 1 to 10% w/w talc (hydrophobic) or silica (hydrophilic) on air bubble formation and coalescence at a capillary in the presence of MIBC or sodium chloride was determined. Both solids slightly inhibited bubble coalescence while the silica created a larger region of partial coalescence compared to talc. At 10% w/w the silica appeared to promote coalescence at high MIBC concentration.Frothers and certain inorganic salts not only inhibit bubble coalescence but also reduce bubble rise velocity. Upon inspection of high-speed records of rising bubbles, it became clear that the presence of solute affected bubble shape and rise velocity in tandem. A study was undertaken to examine the relationship between bubble shape and rise velocity for a single rising bubble. Individual bubbles ca. 2.3 mm in diameter were produced at a capillary in water containing an inorganic salt (NaClO4, KCl, NaCl, Na2SO4, or CaCl2). Using high-speed photography and image analysis techniques, bubble aspect ratio and rise velocity were measured at 1 ms time intervals over a distance ca. 1.15 to 1.20 m above the capillary. All conditions showed oscillations in bubble aspect ratio and velocity that were related. Increasing concentration, on average, created more spherical bubbles that rose at lower velocities. The same observations were made in the presence of MIBC frother. Results suggest a unique relationship between bubble shape and rise velocity independent of solute type.</description><creator>Quinn, Jarrett</creator><contributor>James A Finch (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Metallurgy</subject><title>Bubble behaviour in frother and inorganic salt solutions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z1396.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bf976</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pr14s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:20:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The dissertation develops an interdisciplinary account of the psychological and affective state of shyness, and examines representations of the emotion, along with its variant states shame, bashfulness, and modesty, in Shakespeare and in other early English literature. It brings together work from various fields: literature, psychology, neuroscience, sociology, religious studies, classics, and ancient philosophy. It is a literary study, but also considers medical, political, theological, and social tracts. The dissertation begins with an exploration of the classical emotion concept the fear of shame, and finds the roots of shyness in the virtue ethics tradition of Aristotle. It then moves on to examine the influence Aristotle's moral philosophy had on early modern conceptions of shyness, especially as a religious passion associated with conscience. In view of the way new modes of courtesy, social humility, and courtly interaction infiltrated the predominantly male world of civil conversation, the dissertation outlines how the cultural status of shyness shifted throughout the period. As I demonstrate, shyness underwent a radical secularization and went from being widely understood as a religious emotion to a pathological condition linked to melancholy.Chapter one investigates Shakespeare's interest in the gendering of shyness, and argues that the rising prevalence of bashfulness amongst male courtiers contributed to the medicalization of the emotion in the period. The chapter develops an account of Shakespeare's King Henry the Sixth: a figure whose characterization exemplifies the rapid transformation of shyness as it devolved from a virtuous moral and religious passion into one associated with notions of male disease and political immorality. The following chapters, however, reveal a shift in perspective. In Coriolanus, The Merchant of Venice, and Measure for Measure, Shakespeare questions the early modern pathologization of bashfulness through his endorsement of an Aristotelian account of shyness as a social, ethical, and religious virtue. In these plays the experience of bashfulness operates as a governing emotional force over the advancement of sinful forms of pride and vengeance, and produces a spiritually reformative and transformative effect within the Christian subject. By calling attention to the moral and religious connotations associated with bashfulness throughout its history, the dissertation seeks to counter the medicalization and denigration of shyness currently taking place in the modern world.</description><description>La présente thèse s'inscrit dans le cadre interdisciplinaire d'une étude psychologique et affective de la timidité. Aussi rend-elle compte, chez Shakespeare et autres premiers littérateurs anglais, des représentations de l'émotion dans ses états de honte, d'embarras et de modestie. Elle fait également appel à plusieurs disciplines: littérature (y compris celle des Anciens), psychologie, neuroscience, sociologie, études religieuses. Elle est assurément une étude littéraire, encore qu'elle s'appuie également sur les apports de la médecine, de la politique, de la théologie et de la sociologie. La thèse débute par une étude sur la crainte de la honte sous l'angle classique et dans la tradition de l'éthique aristotélicienne. Elle enchaîne sur l'influence exercée par la philosophie morale d'Aristote sur les premières conceptions modernes de la timidité, vue essentiellement comme passion religieuse en étroit lien avec la conscience. Par ailleurs, à mesure que s'établissait un nouveau code de bienséances (courtoisie, humilité, courtisanerie), le monde largement masculin et le comportement qui s'ensuivit en furent affectés. D'où un changement de l'état culturel de la timidité au cours de l'époque. C'est dire que la timidité se vit entièrement sécularisée et devint, d'émotion religieuse qu'elle avait été, une condition pathologique causée par une humeur mélancolique.Le premier chapitre a, pour objet, l'intérêt porté par Shakespeare pour la différentiation sexuelle de la timidité. Son constat: la prévalence grandissante de la timidité chez les courtisans mâles eut pour effet, à l'époque, la médicalisation de l'émotion. Le chapitre renvoie au roi Henri VI, personnage qui illustre la transformation religieuse et morale de la timidité en une maladie d'homme immoral et politique. Les chapitres suivants, toutefois, font montre d'une perspective nouvelle. Dans Coriolanus, The Merchant of Venice et Measure for Measure, Shakespeare revient sur son idée initiale. Il met en doute la pathogenèse de la timidité pour reprendre le concept aristotélicien de vertu religieuse, éthique et sociale. Dans les pièces citées, un sentiment de timidité apparaît comme un état émotionnel en pleine force maîtresse plutôt que comme la manifestation d'un péché d'orgueil et de vengeance. Il appelle ainsi à une réformation du cœur et de la spiritualité dans une dogmatique chrétienne. Ainsi, par son retour historique aux diverses connotations morales et religieuses liées à l'embarras, la thèse s'emploie ici, dans un renversement du pour au contre, à démythifier l'actuelle et universelle conception de la timidité, tout ensemble gratuite et dénigrante, comme une source profane de stigmatisation médicale.</description><creator>Hoffman, Tiffany</creator><contributor>Paul Edward Yachnin (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Kenneth H Borris (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Literature - English</subject><title>Virtuous passions: Shakespeare and the culture of shyness in early modern England</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hs894.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pr14s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pg15bj196</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:20:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le glycosome est une structure subcellulaire unique qui se trouve dans le parasite Leishmania donovani. Cette organelle compartimente la machinerie enzymatique requise pour de multiples voies métaboliques, y compris la glycolyse. Le bon ciblage des enzymes du glycosome est essentiel pour la viabilité du parasite. Les protéines ciblées pour le glycosome ont une séquence signal topogénique, un PTS1 C-terminale ou un PTS2 N-terminale, qui est reconnue par les récepteurs cytosoliques, le LdPEX5 ou le LPEX7, respectivement. Ces complexes de récepteurs chargés s'interagissent avec la protéine LdPEX14, située du côté cytosolique de la membrane glycosomale, un événement requis pour le transport des protéines à travers la membrane du glycosome. Cependant, la voie complète d'importation de protéines glycosomales n'a pas été totalement élucidée. Ce travail a été entrepris pour mieux comprendre ces interactions protéine-protéine.La fraction cytosolique des parasites L.donovani a été utilisée pour déterminer les interactions protéine-protéine des récepteurs LdPEX5 et LPEX7. La chromatographie d'exclusion de taille, la focalisation isoélectrique, et les interactions d'affinité proteine-proteine ont montré que, dans les cytosols, ces récepteurs forment des grands complexes hétérologues. Les glycosomes purifiés ont été utilisés pour évaluer l'effet des complexes récepteur sur la conformation du LdPEX14. Une protéolyse limitée a montré que l'interaction du LdPEX14 chargé avec les complexes récepteur l'à protèger de la digestion à la surface de la membrane. L'électrophorèse sur gel natif a montré que le LdPEX14 forme des grands complexes de ~ 800 kDa et que lorsqu'il est associé à des complexes récepteur, le poids moléculaire des complexes LdPEX14 passe à ~ 1200 kDa. Les extractions avec le carbonate alcalin a déterminé que le LdPEX14 seul s'agit comme une protéine périphérique; mais son chargement avec des complexes récepteur l'entrainer à s'agir comme une protéine membranaire intégrale. L'insertion de LdPEX14 dans la membrane du glycosome conduit à l'insertion du LdPEX5 et LPEX7 dans la membrane aussi. L'association des complexes récepteur à causer LdPEX14 à subir un changement de conformation causant l'insertion profonde dans la membrane et l'augmentation de la taille des complexes.La purification du récepteur LPEX7 recombinante été entravée par son association avec la protéine chaperonne bactérienne GroEL. Une technique de repliement a été développé pour purifier LPEX7 en évitant l'association de protéines bactériennes. Les techniques de Far Western et d'affinité protéine-protéine ont montré que ce LPEX7 replier est spécifiquement associé à des protéines PTS2, le co-récepteur LdPEX5, et le LdPEX14. La cartographie des domaines d'interaction de LPEX7 a montré que  l'interaction LPEX7-PTS2 nécessit le LPEX7 entière, alors que les motifs d'interaction avec LdPEX5 et LdPEX14 étaient situés dans sa région N-terminale.Il y a des métabolites glycosomal qui ne sont pas importés par la voie de l'importation glycosomale, mais par des transporteurs membranaires du glycosome. L-arginine est un de ces métabolites, substrat de l'enzyme glycosomale PTS1 arginase. L-arginine est récupéré dans le milieu extracellulaire par son transporteur, LdAAP3. Un fractionnement subcellulaire a été utilisés pour séparer les membranes plasmiques des glycosomes, et LdAAP3 a été localisé sur les deux membranes. De plus, des promastigotes de L. donovani sont capable de detecter le niveau de L-arginine dans le millieu, ce qui provoque une régulation positive de l'expression de LdAAP3 à la fois dans la membrane plasmique et dans la membrane du glycosome. Ces études fournissent des preuves que des transporteurs de métabolites spécifique sont présent dans la membrane du glycosome.Ensemble, ces études contribuent à l'élucidation de la fonction glycosomale de Leishmania donovani, et une meilleure compréhension de certains mécanismes nécessaires pour l'importation glycosomale.</description><description>A unique subcellular structure found in Leishmania donovani is the glycosome. This organelle compartmentalizes the enzymatic machinery required for multiple metabolic pathways, including glycolysis. Correct targeting of glycosomal enzymes is essential for parasite viability. Proteins targeted to the glycosome have either a C-terminal PTS1 or N-terminal PTS2 topogenic signal sequence, which is recognized by cytosolic receptors LdPEX5 or LPEX7, respectively. These cargo-loaded receptors interact with the peroxin protein LdPEX14, located on the cytosolic face of the glycosomal membrane, an event required for import of the cargo proteins into the glycosomal lumen. However, the complete glycosomal protein import pathway has not been fully elucidated. This work has been undertaken to better understand the protein-protein interactions involved in the trafficking of cargo proteins across the glycosomal membrane.The cytosolic fraction from L. donovani parasites was used to determine protein-protein interactions of receptors LdPEX5 and LPEX7. Size exclusion chromatography, isoelectric focusing, and affinity pull-downs showed that in the cytosol these receptors form large heterologous PTS1-LdPEX5-LPEX7-PTS2 complexes. Purified glycosomes were used to evaluate the effects of receptor-cargo complexes on glycosomal LdPEX14 conformation. Limited trypsin proteolysis showed that interaction of receptor-cargo complexes with native LdPEX14 protected this protein from digestion, whereas native LdPEX14 alone was highly sensitive to proteolysis. Protection was not dependent on membrane integrity as disruption of the lipid bilayer did not alter the effect of trypsin on these proteins. Native gel electrophoresis showed that native LdPEX14 forms large ~800 kDa complexes; however, when associated with receptor-cargo complexes the molecular weight of LdPEX14 complexes increased to ~1200 kDa. Alkaline carbonate extractions showed that native LdPEX14 acts like a peripheral glycosomal membrane protein; however loading with receptor-cargo complexes caused LdPEX14 to behave like an integral membrane protein. Furthermore, membrane insertion of LdPEX14 drove insertion of LdPEX5 and LPEX7 into the glycosomal membrane. Receptor-cargo complex association causes LdPEX14 to undergo a conformational change resulting in deeper membrane insertion and increase in complex size.Purification of recombinant LPEX7 was hampered by its association with bacterial chaperone protein GroEL. A refolding technique was developed to purify LPEX7 from inclusion bodies free of bacterial proteins. Far Western and protein-protein affinity assays showed that refolded LPEX7 specifically bound PTS2 proteins as both a monomer and a dimer, the co-receptor LdPEX5, and LdPEX14. Mapping of the interaction domains on LPEX7 showed that LPEX7-PTS2 interaction required the entire receptor protein, while LdPEX5 and LdPEX14 interaction motifs were situated in the N-terminal region of LPEX7.There are metabolites in glycosomes that are not imported via the peroxin based glycosomal import pathway but by glycosomal membrane transporters. L-arginine is one such metabolite; it is the substrate for the PTS1 glycosomal enzyme arginase, which catalyses the first step in the polyamine biosynthetic pathway. L-arginine is scavenged from the extracellular milieu and by the L-arginine transporter, amino acid permease 3 (LdAAP3). Subcellular fractionation showed that LdAAP3 localized to both the plasma and glycosomal membranes. Furthermore, L. donovani promastigotes were capable of sensing the L-arginine levels in the media and upregulated LdAAP3 expression on the plasma and glycosome membrane in the absence of L-arginine. These studies provide evidence that metabolite specific transporters are present on the glycosomal membrane.Together these studies contribute to the elucidation of glycosomal function in Leishmania donovani, and a better understanding of some of the mechanisms required for glycosomal import.</description><creator>Strasser, Rona</creator><contributor>Armando Jardim (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Parasitology</subject><title>Protein-protein interactions of receptors LdPEX5 and LPEX7 with PTS1 and PTS2 cargo proteins, and with glycosomal docking protein LdPEX14 for protein import into «Leishmania donovani»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d3213.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bj196</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cf95jf434</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:20:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse met en évidence quatre modes de production distincts dans l'histoire économique des indiens Ahtna Athabaskans de la haute "vallée du cuivre" en Alaska pour la période allant environs de 1700 jusqu'en 1974: l'époque aborigènes de production de denrées d'usage, puis les époques dominées respectivement par le capitalisme des grandes compagnies de négoce, le capitalisme des monopoles et le capitalisme d'état. L’époque des grandes compagnies de négoce correspond à l'introduction  de la production de fourrures pour la vente et au début d’une dépendance aux marchandises utilisées comme moyens de production des denrées de subsistance. Celle du capitalisme des monopoles entraine l'apparition du travail salarie et le fait de dépendre d'une manière plus totale de l'achat d'ustensiles permettant de subvenir aux besoins. Enfin époque du capitalisme d’état correspond  [...]</description><description>This thesis isolates four distinct patterns of production in the economic history of the Ahtna Athabascan Indians of the Upper Copper Valley, Alaska in the period from the 1700's to 1974: the aboriginal period of production for use and the periods dominated by mercantile capitalism; monopoly capitalism; and state capitalism. The period of mercantile capitalism involved the introduction of commodity fur production and the beginnings of a dependence upon commodities used as the means of subsistence production. The period of monopoly capitalism involved the introduction of wage labour and a fuller dependence upon commodities as the means of subsistence production. The period of state capitalism involved a fuller dependence upon wage labour and a direct dependence upon commodities. The common thread through the diverse periods of Ahtna history is the progressive rise and elaboration of a Native class society. The nature of the national economies, the type of commodity production introduced, and the role of commodities introduced are shown to be crucial in this development. </description><creator>Strong, B. Stephen</creator><date>1976</date><subject>Athapascan Indians -- Economic conditions.</subject><subject>Athna Indians -- Economic conditions.</subject><subject>Alaska -- Economic conditions.</subject><title>Historical sequence of the patterns of production of the Athna Athabascan Indians of the Upper Copper Valley, Alaska : the development of capitalism in Alaska</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jv49w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jf434</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:js956k22b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Certain laboratory measurements require the use of a selective audio frequency amplifier. The limitations of physical size on conventional circuits become important in this frequency range. It is necessary to consider selectivity ease of tuning, economy of components, and stability, in the comparison of various types of amplifiers which operate in the range below 20,000 cycles per second. At radio frequencies, use of the parallel resonant circuit as a selective load impedance for a vacuum tube is highly satisfactory. (Figure 1) When the frequency of resonance is decreased, the product of the inductance and capacitance must be increased inversely as the square of the frequency. It becomes difficult to produce variable condensers with a large enough capacity to cover the range desired. In order to obtain the required value of inductance, iron cored inductors must be used. These have greater losses than air cored inductances, and require careful design to avoid change of inductance due to variable permeability. It becomes essential at low audio frequencies to employ other circuits. Inverse feedback or degenerative amplifiers, (Figure 2) using selective networks that reject one frequency fulfill the requirements. The gain of a feedback amplifier is (la, 2a): G = A / 1 - ßA. [...]</description><creator>Chapman, John Herbert, 1921-</creator><contributor>Watson, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>A critical investigation of tuned audio amplifiers.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kf017.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956k22b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290d83c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Knights of Labor had their beginning in the United States in 1869. KNown originally as the “Noble and Holy Order of the Knights of Labor”,they were at first a secret body. This secret nature was due in part at least, to the founder of the Order, Uriah Smith Stephens, who, being himself a Freemason, naturally tended towards secrecy. Mr. Stephens argued: “I don’t know of any great good that has been accomplished except through the agency of secret societies. I believe that all legitimate occupations have their secrets. Ministers and medical men have their associations, merchants their exchanges, lawyers their bar associations, and so on, and they all have their secrets, and I see no reason why those upon whom the commerce of the world rests should not have theirs.”1 Closely associated with this secrecy, was the ritual of the Order. When a candidate was invited to join the Order, he attended a secret meeting where he was first asked three questions: ‘Do you believe in God, the creator and Father of all? Do you obey the Universal Ordinance of God, in gaining your bread by the sweat of your brow? Are you willing to take a sollemn vow binding you to secrecy, obedience and mutual assistance?’ [...]</description><creator>Chan, Victor O. (Victor Oscar).</creator><contributor>Cooper, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Knights of Labor (Canada).</subject><subject>Labor movement -- Canada -- History.</subject><title>Canadian Knights of Labor with special reference to the 1880’s.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859j855.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290d83c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nm476</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The decomposition of dry bovine serum albumin by alpha-rays has been investigated using an ultracentrifuge with Svedberg optical system and spectrograph. Alpha-particle radiation of 8 x 10^7 to 5 x 10^9 roentgens was obtained from slow neutron capture in boron mixed with albumin samples. In a centrifugal field of 115,000 g buffered aequeous solutions formed from the irradiated samples were found to contain cleavage products ranging in size from effectively non-centrifugible material to apparently normal albumin and aggregation products. Marked increase in absorption, extending toward the visible, was apparently associated with cleavage products of all sizes, but mainly attributable to smaller fragments. Inappreciable effect in the heat-treated control sample supports the belief that dissociation of the albumin can be attributed to the direct action of the ionizing radiation. In the sample receiving least radiation rough agreement was obtained with predictions of the single-ionization target theory. A new method for obtaining the concentration scale has been used in the experiments.</description><creator>Carruthers, James Alexander.</creator><contributor>Foster, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>The ultracentrifuge study of alpha-irradiated albumin.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p359d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nm476</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f4535</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The grey-wooded soils of Western Canada are becoming increasingly important due to the fact that future settlement will be largely confined to such soils. In the Peace River region today sizeable tracts of wooded soils are being brushed and broken for crop production by modern power machinery. Over the three Prairie Provinces grey-wooded soils consist well in excess of 100,000,000 acres and of the four major soil zones (brown, dark brown, black, grey-wooded) they represent by far the largest area. About two-thirds of the entire province of Alberta is made up of the grey soil zone. Vyatt (39) points out that ultimately over 50 per cent of all cropped land of this province will belong to the grey soil group. Of the surveyed area of the Peace River region 78 per cent or approximately 13,000,000 acres is of the grey-wooded or grey-transitional type. The grey-wooded soils are generally rather poor in fertility as they represent a degraded phase, the result of prolonged leaching under a forest cover. Under cultivation their scant organic matter rapidly disappears and the limited amount of available nitrogen is quickly absorbed by crop growth. Moreover, their initial poor physical condition is enhanced with puddling, washing, and blowing as the inevitable result. [...]</description><creator>Carder, A. C., 1910-</creator><contributor>Cowan, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Agronomy.</subject><title>The use of sweet clover in a grain rotation as a means of increasing the fertility of grey-wooded soils.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn1072331.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f4535</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agronomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b6684</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Changes in memory and the nature of the mnemonic trace are a source of never-ending interest, as well as of physiological importance, to the investigator. To date, no satisfactory solution has been provided as to exactly what occurs within the trace itself when increasing errors of memory are manifested with the passage of time. Traditionally there have been two opposing theories - one, supported by G. E. Müller, which maintains that forgetting consists principally of an increasing indefiniteness of the trace, and the other, originated by Wulf, who concluded, from studies pursued under Koffka’s direction, that the trace tends, not towards vagueness, but towards “better figures”. That is, in certain instances, such as in the perception of an irregular figure, the unstable organization of forces within the trace itself will tend towards equilibrium overriding the influence of external events upon it. (Wulf himself distinguished three sources of error, “normalizing”, “emphasizing” and “autonomous changes”, but Koffka later reduced these to two, namely “external influence” and “spontaneous change”). Not only this, the tendency towards stability which is manifested in increased symmetry, tendency to close a gap, sharpening, etc., will be progressive in time. [...]</description><creator>Calvert, Margaret Nelson.</creator><contributor>Blackburn, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Reproduction (Psychology) -- Testing.</subject><subject>Visual perception -- Testing.</subject><subject>Recognition (Psychology) -- Testing.</subject><title>Errors of recognition and reproduction of a perceived object.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74ct93k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b6684</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cx47v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Changes in the physical properties of the atmosphere are caused by geographic influences and dynamic effects. The nature of the surface of the earth over which the air passes is usually the main factor in modifying the air in the lower levels of the troposphere. The ocean area of Hudson Bay in northeastern Canada presents an extensive surface for modification of air. Continental polar air crossing Hudson Bay and continuing into eastern Canada is modified not only by the underlying surface but also by the dynamic effects occurring in the atmosphere during its trajectory over these regions. The amount of modification is of major importance in the climate of the surrounding area, and in the meteorology of North American air masses. It was the purpose of this study: 1. To compute the changes in the physical properties that occur in continental polar air over Hudson Bay, Consequently, a project was undertaken to determine the amount of ice that forms on Hudson Bay in winter. The effect of the formation of ice in changing the modification of air was then studied. [...]</description><creator>Burbidge, Frederick Edward.</creator><contributor>Hare, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Air.</subject><subject>North America -- Climate.</subject><subject>Weather.</subject><subject>Canada -- Climate.</subject><title>The modification of continental polar air over Hudson Bay and eastern Canada.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj4307888.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cx47v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xj04p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Various methods have been employed in the evaluation of item selection methods. Typical among these studies are those made by Barthelmess, Lentz and Long and Sandiford. Barthelmess (l), has used an intercorrelational technique in evaluating various methods of item selection. Validity values were computed for each of the hundred elements of the McCall Multi-Mental Scale, Elementary Form 1, by each of the methods of item selection being studied, namely, Eta, Long, McCall, Vincent, Corrected Vincent and Bi-serial r. These methods were then evaluated on the basis of intercorrelation of each method with all the other methods. Results showed that the Eta (Correlation Ratio) and the Bi-serial r methods ranked first and second respectively. Using a criterion X, composed of a series of tests (Stanford Achievement Test, Stanford Revision of the Binet-Simon Intelligence Test A, Thorndike-McCall Reading Scale, Woody-McCall Mixed Fundamentals in Arithmetic, Morrison-McCall Spelling Scale), Barthelmess judged the validity methods under study according to their success in selecting the ten best, twenty best, thirty best, forty best, fifty best items. On the basis of correlations with criterion X of the ten best items, as chosen by each method, the Long, McCall, Eta, and Biserial r methods ranked first, second, third and fourth respectively. [...]</description><creator>Blascik, Frank.</creator><contributor>Ferguson, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>PSYCHOLOGY, EXPERIMENTAL.</subject><subject>PSYCHOLOGY, MENTAL TESTS.</subject><title>An evaluation of item selection methods by a criterion of internal consistency.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02871024p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xj04p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wg95p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since the disposal of by-product bark in logging operations is often a serious problem in the wood pulp industry, advantageous methods of bark utilization are of definite interest. A partial solution to this problem has been obtained in the production of marketable products by mechanical processing of bark but more recently the possibility of extracting economically valuable products with solvents has received some attention. In investigations along these lines interest has been centered in the ether and alcohol soluble fractions, perhaps because these solvents extract material of greater potential economic value such as fats, waxes, resins or sitosterols. Another reason for the slight amount of interest in the aqueous extract might possibly be that most of the substances extracted by water, such as tannins and polysaccharides, are amorphous mixtures, whereas ether and alcohol extract compounds whose lower molecular weight improves the chance of sharp separation and definite identification. Since the percentage amount of any chemical individual in extracts of bark is generally small, investigators in this field have had considerable difficulty in identifying the constituents. This disadvantage was overcome in the present investigation by using an unusually large amount of starting material. Aqueous extractions of white spruce bark have been made and the extracts fractionated, on an empirical basis, with inert solvents. [...]</description><creator>Bishop, Claude Titus.</creator><contributor>Purves, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The chemical investigation of the aqueous extract of white spruce bark.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801pk47m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wg95p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4x51hn61w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Variable frequency oscillators are an essential element of many radio communication systems. One of the problems in their design is the elimination of undesirable variations in the output frequency. Present day knowledge of the causes of frequency instability in oscillators used in radio communication equipment, and of the methods developed to achieve good stability, is thoroughly outlined. The functions required of a variable frequency oscillator, and means of achieving variable frequency output with crystal control are mentioned. The special conditions applicable to very high frequency oscillators are presented. The record is given of an experimental investigation of the frequency fluctuations existing in small, battery operated oscillators operating in the frequency range of 30 to 80 megacycles, and of a procedure suitable for reduction of these variations. The results should be useful in the design of miniature, man-portable transmitters and receivers for short distance communication.</description><creator>Bennett, John Robert Gordon.</creator><contributor>Howes, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Electrical engineering.</subject><title>Design of a variable frequency oscillator for good frequency stability.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322h93v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hn61w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sg91t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The governing feature in writing an acceptance code for any purpose is to specify conditions which will be easily duplicated in all details so that results obtained may be directly compared. These conditions, while being those most easily reproducible, are not always those with which it would be most economical to comply, especially in cases where a manufacturer is making a large number of tests during development of a process or material. In the development of arc-welding electrodes, the properties of the deposited weld metal must be controlled within the limits set out in the following specifications. [...] In view of the above, it can be understood why a company engaged in electrode development would be interested in developing a test which could be more economically carried out, while producing the same results as the standard test. The main object of this study therefore, is to attempt to develop an alternative test that will give results that are identical with, or could be correlated to, the results obtained by the Standard method. The problem may be divided into two parts. 1) To develop a sample which will be metallurgically identical with the standard sample. This specimen should be such that it is easier and more economical to produce. 2) To develop a method of testing the specimen that will yield data concerning the elongation of the sample at fracture. This method should, if possible, be more economical to produce than the standard method.</description><creator>Barrett, George Francis Williams.</creator><contributor>Stafford, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Mechanical Engineering.</subject><title>An alternate test for the physical properties of arc-weld metal.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jx76p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sg91t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b9235</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Acronecrosis, or top-necrosis, is a systemic virus disease which manifests itself in certain potato varieties following graft introduction of certain specific plant viruses. Acronecrosis is externally characterized by a necrotic spotting of the uppermost leaves followed by a dying of the plant from the top, downward, in the absence of any mottling. Necrotic areas are invariably found in the stem. These necroses, which are most severe in the distal portions of the plant, originate usually but not always, In the internal phloem and spread into the surrounding tissues. Necroses, similar in their origin and appearance to those in the stem, are found in the petioles, frequently being so severe as to lead to the death of the leaf blades. Axillary buds also become infected and are ultimately killed. In the tubers the necroses develop in the same manner as those in the stem, and spread rapidly to the storage parenchyma. Cork layers abstricting the necrotic areas are always found in affected tubers and are produced occasionally in stems grown at high temperatures. Usually the tuber necrosis spreads by way of the vascular tissues to one or more of the eyes and kills the buds, causing an irregular, sunken depression on the surface of the tuber. Often, buds of some eyes survive to produce secondary plants which soon develop necrotic spots similar to those in the parent plant. [...]</description><creator>Bagnall, Richard Herbert.</creator><contributor>Coulson, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Plant pathology.</subject><title>Varietal resistance and immunity of potatoes toward certain viruses.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hg395.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b9235</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x346d737j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ce travail s’efforce de déterminer dans quelle mesure une civilisation de langue française s’est maintenue au Nouveau Brunswick et si son domaine tend à s’étendre ou à se restreindre. Il comporte d’abord une partie historique rappelant les origines et les vicissitudes des établissements français dans la région considérée. La deuxième partie examine les facteurs qui ont favorisé le maintien du français et les secteurs de la vie publique ou privée où cette survivance se manifeste, sans négliger les revendications actuelles des francophones de la province. Pour la documentation on a naturellement utilisé un certain nombre d’études parues sur ce sujet sous forme de livres ou d’articles, mais on a fait également appel à des rapports officiels et à des renseignements fournis par des fonctionnaires du gouvernement provincial et des membres du clergé catholique romain. Des tables statistiques et des cartes démographiques et linguistiques complètent la thèse.</description><creator>Sloat, A. Prudence (Annie Prudence)</creator><contributor>Darbelnet, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1946</date><subject>History, Canadian.</subject><subject>Acadians -- New Brunswick.</subject><subject>New Brunswick -- History.</subject><subject>Acadians.</subject><title>La survivance française au Nouveau Brunswick</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55zc03s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d737j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50h046b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The primary purpose of this investigation is to produce a method whereby the cerebral cortex of man may be rendered temporarily nonfunctional in any focal area desired. It is felt that by such a method the effects of removal of an area may be determined in advance, and thus important areas such as hand and speech may be avoided, yet approached more closely with safety than is possible at present. It may also be possible to distinguish the true epileptic focus from a referred or transmitted epileptic pattern. Since such a method would cause temporary arrest of all activity and function in the given area, it would be useful in the prevention of full development to a generalized seizure when one has been initiated by cortical stimulation in man. Such initiated seizures almost invariably start as a localized involvement of one extremity, the face, or the like, and if this area of firing cortex could be rendered inactive, the activity could not spread to other areas and the subcortical areas. It may be useful in testing the effect of the temporary arrest of an area of cortex under different circumstances, such as mental arithmetic, writing, speaking, identifying objects, complex motor movements, etc., in other words, temporary ablation experiments in the human.[...]</description><creator>Ziegler, James E.</creator><contributor>Jasper, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Neurology &amp; Neurosurgery.</subject><title>Methods for temporary and reversible paralysis of local areas of the cerebral cortex.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nv18n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50h046b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j333569d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:21:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study is to show not only how export credit insurance schemes may offset the credit risks of the individual exporter and promote a revival of trade, but, also, in what manner such schemes under government sponsorship may become concealed political mechanisms that distort the pattern of trade to serve nationalistic ends. Various schemes of export credit insurance, both private and governmental, are examined and compared in order to establish some common identities of purpose, organization, and operation. Since the Export Credits Insurance Corporation in Canada has only been in operation three and a half years, it is difficult to make a good prediction of the future direction of its activities on the basis of past results as revealed in the Annual deports from 1946 on. Yet, an analysis of the available data may be attempted and the results compared with the data from the longer established organizations abroad. This much, I hope that I have done. I wish to acknowledge the assistance that I received from Mr. D. C. Taylor, Economist for the Export Credits Insurance Corporation, who was kind enough to furnish me with the basic material for this study. Needless to say, I am indebted to Dr. D. B. Marsh for reading the drafts and for his encouragement throughout the period of writing. However, I assume full responsibility for errors and omissions that may be found in this study. In apology, if this is necessary, I must point out that the work is an introductory study of export credit insurance and I do not pretend to have exhausted all that can be said on this subject.</description><creator>Wilson, James Dunlop.</creator><contributor>Marsh, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1949</date><subject>Credit insurance.</subject><title>A comparative study of export credits insurance and its operation in Canada.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79408135z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j333569d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):12650</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>