<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:52:38Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):25900" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225b31k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis attempts to chart the development of a Jamaican musical form known as dub. This development is considered primarily in terms of the island's encounter with a series of new playback, amplification, recording, and sound treatment technologies. Section I focuses on the formation of the Jamaican sound system (a network of powerful mobile discos) and its pivotal role in the birth of a fertile domestic record industry. Section II extends the investigation to the Jamaican recording studio and record industry. What distinguishes this work from others on Jamaican dub is its emphasis on technology, and theories of technology, within a geo-political framework. In Section I, this emphasis is most notably informed by the work of Harold Innis, Karl Marx and Lewis Mumford, with Marshall McLuhan and Walter Benjamin becoming more prominent in Section II. Key technologies in this analysis include mechanization (mechanical reproducibility), the Williamson amplification circuit, the House of Joy speaker, the dub plate (acetate phonograph) and vinyl record, twin-turntables and the microphone, the magnetic tape recorder, and perhaps most importantly, the multi-track recorder and interface (the multi-track mixing-board).</description><creator>Lapp-Szymanski, Jean-Paul.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Sound -- Recording and reproducing -- Jamaica.</subject><subject>Dub (Music) -- Jamaica -- History and criticism.</subject><title>Technology inna rub-a-dub style : technology and dub in the Jamaican sound system and recording studio</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Jean-Paul Lapp-Szymanski, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722h920q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225b31k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h2289</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores the role of popular music in articulating socio-cultural identities by examining the contribution of the Acadian group, 1755. As the rapid modernization of Acadians' way of life led to a sense of cultural alienation, cultural products played a prominent role in asserting their cultural specificity. Accordingly, the 1970s were not only rich in artistic production, but also saw the development of a distinctive Acadian popular music practice. Responding to fears of acculturation and folklorization, Acadian popular music embodied Acadians' desire to embrace a modern identity all the while maintaining ties with their traditional identity. 1755's music actively took part in reinventing Acadian identity by constructing a cultural narrative that reflected Acadians' contemporary reality and by renegotiating what was commonly held as "Acadian" music. As a result, it became invested with ideological significance by Acadian consumers, regarded not merely as commercial music but rather as a symbol of their cultural emancipation.</description><creator>LeBlanc, Sylvie.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Acadians -- Music.</subject><subject>Folk music -- Acadia.</subject><subject>1755 (Musical group)</subject><subject>Musical groups -- Canada.</subject><subject>Acadians -- History.</subject><title>&amp;quot;Le monde qu'on connaǐt&amp;quot; : the music of 1755 and the construction of Acadian identity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Sylvie LeBlanc, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544bp41f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h2289</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gn45n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study is to explore how the Arabic novel can and does challenge the conventional characterization of what constitutes constructive Middle East historiography. The thesis draws on a case study of undergraduate history course syllabi in order to highlight a number of crucial issues related to Arabic literature and the production of modern Middle East history. My analysis of the syllabi concludes that in general, Arabic novels in translation are part of a varied group of resources selected by a professor in order to complement the "official" histories provided by textbooks and government documents. The novel is deemed helpful because it often describes the "ordinary" or daily life of people. Also, the novel is presented as the contribution of an "indigenous voice" to the historical narrative.</description><creator>Leeke, Jane.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Middle East -- History -- Study and teaching -- United States.</subject><subject>Middle East -- History -- Study and teaching -- Canada.</subject><subject>Arabic fiction -- History and criticism.</subject><title>A novel reading : literature and pedagogy in modern Middle East history courses in Canada and the United States</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Jane Leeke, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w7573.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gn45n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m1960</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study concerns the concept of sacred architectural imitation, using the Platonic notion of mimesis which then later finds expression in the medieval idea of imitatio. In Religious as well as in artistic and architectural forms of expression, the notion of imitation is indeed a very central and complex issue. At the heart of this concept is the question of meaning, or, more precisely, the transference or translation of meaning; from original to copy, from prototype to reproduction. In order to better illustrate and understand the principles guiding the notion of medieval sacred architectural imitation I have chosen to focus on five specific instances surrounding the replication of the Holy Sepulcher in Jerusalem, arguably the most revered landmark in Christendom. A close examination of the relationships which exist between model and copy will bring to the fore the dynamics which govern the process of mimesis by which meaning is reproduced in the architectural replicas. From this comparative analysis will emerge a more universal picture of the medieval concept of religious imitation. Indeed, if anything, a preliminary survey of the great many imitations of the Holy Sepulcher spread throughout Europe reveals to the observer a surprising trend, namely a consistency of inconsistencies in their effort to "copy". The present study will demonstrate that these seeming inconsistencies within the application of the mimetic process nevertheless reveal a somewhat unexpected structure. From the pattern of these inconsistencies will emerge a clearer picture of the principles governing the transfer of sacred meaning via the method of imitatio during the Middle Ages.</description><creator>Angers, Philippe, 1968-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Architecture, Medieval -- Europe.</subject><subject>Christian art and symbolism -- Europe -- Medieval, 500-1500.</subject><subject>Holy Sepulcher.</subject><subject>Imitation in art.</subject><title>Principles of religious imitation in mediaeval architecture : an analysis of the Holy Sepulchre in Jerusalem and its European copies from the Carolingian period to the late Romanesque</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Philippe Angers, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fk81s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m1960</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c7710</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Salman Rushdie's Midnight's Children and Ahdaf Soueif s The Map of Love both construct cosmopolitan figures, who through their narratives, attempt to reformulate nationalist constructions of nation. This study compares Rushdie and Soueif's configuration of the cosmopolitan global consciousness and its rootedness in the postcolonial local centers of Bombay and Cairo respectively. The comparison shows that the multiply determined identity of cosmopolitans can both impede, as well as allow for, the active participation in the social and political life of the country in which they inhabit and aim to represent. This thesis considers Rushdie and Soueif's journey back into postcolonial centers where the contested threshold between homogenous constructions of national identity and the heterogeneity of cosmopolitans has to be negotiated before productive critique and reform can begin at home.</description><creator>Ayoub, Dima.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Cosmopolitanism.</subject><subject>Soueif, Ahdaf. Map of love.</subject><subject>Rushdie, Salman. Midnight's children.</subject><title>&amp;quot;The privilege and the curse&amp;quot; of the cosmopolitan consciousness : redefining Ūmmah-gined communities in Salman Rushdie's Midnight's children and Ahdaf Soueif's The map of love</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Dima Ayoub, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qj002.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c7710</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311p669</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The subject of this thesis is an American Zen monastery in New York, Zen Mountain Monastery (ZMM). The study is approached through a survey of methodologies: (1) through the scholarship on American culture and religion, (2) through the sociology of the study of religious institutions and communities and (3) through a comparison with East Asian Zen monasticism. The study reveals that ZMM's monasticism: (1) is part of a systematization of Zen in America that has made Zen into a mainstream option in American society, (2) has created group practices and commitment mechanisms that put ZMM in a better position than American lay Zen centers to challenge the individualist trends of American society and spirituality and (3) is based on a conception of the self more in line with the individualism of American society than the asceticism of East Asian Zen monasticism.</description><creator>Arslanian, Varant Nerces.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Zen Buddhism -- New York (State)</subject><subject>Zen monasticism and religious orders -- New York (State)</subject><title>Leaving home, staying home : a case study of an American Zen monastery</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Varant Nerces Arslanian, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr171x55p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311p669</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591885p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>I propose and test a new model determining the choice of the exchange rate regime in Latin America and the Caribbean. The key insight is that systemic level instability plays an important role in choosing the exchange rate regime. Using new data from Reinhart and Rogoff (2004), a second insight is that countries do not always follow the type of exchange rate regime they claim. Testing the determinants of regime choice against both the traditional, official de jure and new, market de facto data, I find that policymakers are strategically using the observed gap between the measures. The evidence reveals that systemic level variables, namely instability in the US interest rate and the bilateral USD:DEM/Euro exchange rate, significantly impact the choice of the exchange rate regime.</description><creator>Baerg, Nicole R.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Foreign exchange rates -- Latin America.</subject><subject>Foreign exchange rates -- Caribbean Area.</subject><title>Shocks from the system : remodelling exchange rate regime choice in Latin America and the Caribbean 1960-1995</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Nicole R. Baerg, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612n93k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591885p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mj255</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background. Clustering of observations occurs frequently in epidemiological and clinical studies of time-to-event outcomes. However, only a few papers addressed the challenge of accounting for clustering while analyzing right-censored survival data. I propose two bootstrap-based approaches to correct standard errors of Cox's proportional hazards (PH) model estimates for clustering, and validate the approaches in simulations. Methods. Both bootstrap-based approaches involve 2 stages of resampling the original data. The two methods share the same procedure at the first stage but employ different procedures at the second stage. At the first stage of both methods, the clusters (e.g. physicians) are resampled with replacement. At the second stage, one method resamples individual patients with replacement for each physician (i.e. units within-cluster) selected at the 1st stage, while another method picks up all the patients for each selected physician, without resampling. For both methods, each of the resulting bootstrap samples is then independently analyzed with standard Cox's PH model, and the standard errors (SE) of the regression parameters are estimated as the empirical standard deviation, of the corresponding estimates. Finally, 95% confidence intervals (CI) for the estimates are estimated using bootstrap-based SE and assuming normality. Simulations design. I have simulated a hypothetical study with N patients clustered within practices of M physicians. Individual patients' times-to-events were generated from the exponential distribution with hazard conditional on (i) several patient-level variables, (ii) several cluster-level (physician's) variables, and (iii) physician's "random effects". Random right censoring was applied. Simulated data were analyzed using 4 approaches: the proposed two bootstrap methods, standard Cox's PH model and "classic" one-step bootstrap with direct resampling of the patients. Results. Standard Cox's model and "Classic" 1-step bootstrap under-estimated variance of regression coefficients, leading to serious inflation of type I error rates and coverage rates of 95% CI as low as 60-70%. In contrast, the proposed approach that resamples both physicians and patients-within-physicians, with the 100 bootstrap resamples, resulted in slightly conservative estimates of standard errors, which yielded type I error rates between 2% and 6%, and coverage rates between 94% and 99%. Conclusions. The proposed bootstrap approach offers an easy-to-implement method to account for interdependence of times-to-events in the inference about Cox model regression parameters in the context of analyses of right-censored clustered data.</description><creator>Xiao, Yongling, 1972-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><title>Bootstrap-based inference for Cox's proportional hazards analyses of clustered censored survival data</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Yongling Xiao, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tc281.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mj255</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vk42v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The self-assembly behavior of poly(ethylene oxide)-b-polystyrene- b-poly(acrylic acid) (PEO-b-PS-b-PAA) triblock copolymers in solution is the focus of this thesis. The triblock copolymers were synthesized by atom transfer radical polymerization (ATRP). The compositions of the block copolymers were determined by 1H NMR. The synthesized block copolymers have relatively low polydispersity indexes (PDI &lt; 1.3) as proved by GPC. The influence of several factors on the ATRP of styrene or t-BA, such as temperature, catalyst and polymerization time, was also explored. The effects of several parameters on the self-assembly behavior of this triblock copolymer were investigated, including the nature and composition of the common solvent, PAA block length, pH, water content, and initial copolymer concentration. Multiple morphologies, such as spheres, vesicles, lamellae and rods have been prepared by varying the above parameters. In particular, vesicles with either PEO or PAA outside have been successfully prepared in dioxane/water. These vesicles may serve as carriers for potential encapsulation applications. The average size and corona chain composition of the triblock copolymer vesicles can be controlled by varying factors such as the PAA block length and pH. The polymer chains may have different arrangements in the vesicle wall, resulting in different corona chain compositions. The vesicles with PAA outside are stable in water, while the vesicles with PEO outside tend to flocculate. Nevertheless, the sediment can be redispersed under vigorous stirring.</description><creator>Wu, Qinghua, 1977-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>Self-assembly of poly(ethylene oxide)-b-polystyrene-b-poly(acrylic acid) triblock copolymers in solution</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Qinghua Wu, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qv33rw97f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vk42v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b8515n67q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The phosphoenolpyruvate-dependant carbohydrate transport system (PTS) couples uptake of a variety of carbohydrates with phosphorylation in prokaryotes. In this system, a phosphoryl group is sequentially transferred through two general phosphoryl carrier proteins, enzyme I (EI) and HPr, and a carbohydrate-specific permease enzyme II (EII). EII is constituted of two cytoplasmic domains IIA and IIB, and a transmembrane channel IIC domain. The galactitol-specific transporter (IIgat) belongs to the glucitol family and is structurally the least well-known. Nuclear Magnetic Resonance (NMR) spectroscopy was used to solve the three-dimensional structure of IIBGat. IIB Gat is composed of a central four-stranded parallel beta sheet flanked by alpha helices on both sides. NMR titrations and isothermal titration calorimetry (ITC) with IIAGat allowed the identification of the binding interface and preliminary modeling of the structure of the IIB Gat - IIAGat heterodimer. IIAGat was also phosphorylated in-vitro, producing several large chemical shift changes, but no changes to the overall structure.</description><creator>Young, Chris, 1981-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biophysics, General.</subject><title>NMR studies if the Galactitol-specific PTS proteins IIA and IIB</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Chris Young, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0z708w79k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515n67q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gf06g304b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Botulinum A toxin (BTX) has become increasingly recognized as a treatment option in the management of spasticity in children with cerebral palsy (CP). Preliminary evidence suggests that certain baseline characteristics of the child may affect responsiveness to BTX. However, the contribution of these factors has not been fully elucidated. The primary objective of the study was to examine whether specific intrinsic and extrinsic characteristics of the child were associated with responsiveness to BTX. The results indicate that age, number of treatments, parenting stress and child's motivation were associated with the degree of change in gait pattern, level of ambulation, gross motor function and functional independence. The findings suggest that the contribution of contextual factors (personal and environmental) on responsiveness to BTX is underappreciated in children with mild CP. Identification of potential factors contributing to responsiveness to BTX will assist clinicians in identifying children who would benefit most from this procedure.</description><creator>Yap, Rita.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><title>Determinants of responsiveness to botulinum A toxin in children with cerebral palsy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Rita Yap, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73pw36j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g304b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m039k521w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this paper was to characterize and compare pressure patterns in the skate boot of elite and recreational players during the forward crossover turn. In-skate pressure patterns of eight elite varsity level hockey players (mean +/- SD: height (m) = 1.80 +/- 0.07, weight (kg) = 87 +/- 0.06) and eight recreational hockey players (mean +/- SD: height = 1.76 (m) +/- 0.06, weight (kg) = 82 +/- 0.07) were measured using fifteen piezo-resistive sensors per foot during the forward crossover skating stride. Each participant performed three trials in both the clock-wise (CW) and counter clock-wise (CCW) directions. For each trial the pressure profiles of three strides were cut and averaged according to ability groups and turn directions. The results showed that the elite skaters performed the skill quicker than the recreational skaters (6.85 (sec) +/- 0.114 vs 7.62 (sec) +/- 0.125), respectively (p &lt; 0.01). Other significant differences (p &lt; 0.05) were found in peak pressures on the plantar, medial and lateral surfaces between groups. No significant differences were found when turn directions were compared. These results show that recreational skaters differ from elite skaters by displaying higher peak pressures on the plantar surface and lower peak pressures on the lateral and medial surfaces. Also, pressures on the plantar, medial and lateral surfaces appeared to be higher on the inside foot when compared to pressures on the outside foot for both groups.</description><creator>Trumper, Alex.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Skating -- Physiological aspects.</subject><subject>Hockey players.</subject><title>Comparison of skate boot pressure of elite and recreational hockey players during the performance of forward crossovers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Alex Trumper, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cg876.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k521w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602095p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Ras proteins (H-Ras, N-Ras and K-Ras4B) are monomeric GTP-binding proteins that play key roles in cell regulation. It has been proposed that correct plasma membrane localization of the Ras proteins requires 'two signals', the processed farnesylation sequence and an adjacent palmitoylation site(s) or polybasic sequence. First, to investigate potential proteinaceous binding partners for the K-Ras4B targeting sequence at the plasma membrane, an in vivo crosslinking analysis was carried out. Consistent with current suggestions that K-Ras4B interacts via electrostatic interactions with plasma membrane lipids, no indication of a K-Ras4B plasma membrane binding partner was found. In the second portion of this thesis, I describe the development of a new approach, using fluorescence microscopy and the technique of rapamycin-induced protein heterodimerization, to demonstrate that prenylated proteins lacking a 'second signal' are not specifically sequestered in the endoplasmic reticulum and Golgi compartments as suggested previously but can distribute freely and rapidly between different cellular membranes.</description><creator>Terrone, Donato Gerardo.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Ras protein targeting in mammalian cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Donato Gerardo Terrone, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kj916.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602095p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75r822v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In designing compiler analyses and optimisations, the choice of intermediate representation (IR) is a crucial one. Static Single Assignment (SSA) form in particular is an IR with interesting properties, enabling certain analyses and optimisations to be more easily implemented while also being more powerful. Our goal has been to research and implement, various SSA-based IRs for the Soot compiler framework for Java. We present three new IRs based on our Shimple framework for Soot. Simple Shimple is an implementation of the basic SSA form. We explore extensions of SSA form (Extended SSA form and Static Single Information form) and unify them in our implementation of Extended Shimple. Thirdly, we explore the possibility of applying the concepts of SSA form to array element analysis in the context of Java and present Array Shimple. We have designed Shimple to be extensible and reusable, facilitating further research into variants and improvements of SSA form. We have also implemented several analyses and optimisations to demonstrate the utility of Shimple.</description><creator>Umanee, Navindra.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Shimple : and investigation of static single assignment form</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Navindra Umanee, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wc94s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75r822v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rb68xc15q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, we present numerical examples of class invariants constructed by DeShalit-Goren in [14]. These class invariants are an attempt to generalize the classical theory of elliptic units. The hope is that a better understanding of these class invariants would lead to other cases of Stark's conjectures expressing the value of derivatives of Artin L-functions at s = 0 in term of a regulator of linear forms in logarithms of S-units.</description><creator>Vallières, Daniel.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Class invariants</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Daniel Vallières, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784m14f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xc15q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77fr67f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In many countries around the world, municipal sewage and industrial wastewaters are typically treated, or sometimes only partially treated, prior to their discharge into surface waters. A major anionic surfactant, Linear Alkyl benzene Sulfonate (LAS), and a degraded product of a non-ionic surfactant, Nonylphenol (NP), are frequently found in municipal wastewaters. When wastewater containing such surfactants and their degraded products is used for irrigation, it can have an effect on the sorption/desorption and movement of pesticides in soils. Therefore, a lysimeter study was conducted, in summer 2004, to assess the effect of LAS and NP on the movement of agricultural herbicides through a sandy loam soil. The degradation of the herbicides was studied in lysimeters over a ninety-day period. Irrigation water with a concentration of 12 mg L -1 of LAS and NP was used to assess their effect on the leaching of atrazine, metolachlor, and metribuzin. Moreover, a laboratory sorption experiment was undertaken to estimate the partition coefficients (kd) of the three herbicides with water containing the same concentrations of LAS and NP. Irrigation water containing low concentrations of surfactants (LAS and NP) did not increase leaching of the three herbicides. Therefore, these results would reduce the concerns regarding pesticide leaching through sandy soil brought on by LAS and NP in wastewaters for irrigation, which is becoming more important due to increasing water scarcity in the dry climate regions of the world. Beside the lysimeter study, mathematical models can be used effectively and economically in a very short period of time for simulating herbicide concentrations into soil. PESTFADE, a one dimensional transient flow model, was used, in this study, to simulate the fate of the three herbicides in sandy soils. Another model, Artificial Neural Network (ANN), was also used over mathematical modeling due to its faster execution period and less input parameter requirements, for predicting the concentrations of the three herbicides in a sandy loam soil. The predicted concentrations, from both models were compared with the experimental results from the lysimeter study. Although slight overestimations and underestimations were observed, both models simulated herbicide concentrations in the soil profile satisfactorily.</description><creator>Nilufar, Fahmida.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Soils -- Herbicide movement.</subject><subject>Nonylphenol -- Environmental aspects.</subject><subject>Soils -- Herbicide movement -- Computer simulation.</subject><subject>Irrigation water.</subject><subject>Surface active agents -- Environmental aspects.</subject><subject>Alkylbenzene sulfonates -- Environmental aspects.</subject><title>Fate and transport of herbicides in soil in the presence of surfactants in irrigation water</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Fahmida Nilufar, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r1217.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77fr67f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c534fp28n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Schizophrenia research over the years has documented evidence of structural neurodevelopmental abnormalities in the hippocampus and functional aberrations at the level of the prefrontal cortex. Rats with neonatal ibotenic acid lesions in the ventral hippocampus (nVH) mirror some of these disruptions and it is believed that these lesions may lead to structural and/or functional reorganization within cortical circuits (Lipska et al., 1993; Flores et al., 1996). Our laboratory has provided evidence of increased cortical alpha-1 adrenergic receptors in nVH lesioned animals. To further assess the possible role of these receptors in amphetamine-induced hyperlocomotion exhibited by nVH lesioned animals, the effect of a local mPFC injection of an alpha-1 antagonist benoxathian on amphetamine-induced locomotor activity was evaluated on postnatal day 56 in sham and nVH lesioned rats. A large decrease in locomotion in sham animals treated with benoxathian was observed, whereas locomotion was not attenuated in the lesioned rats. As amphetamine-induced locomotion is dependent on the functional activity of nucleus accumbens neurons, whether the differential effects of benoxathian was related to alterations in glutamatergic mechanisms within the nucleus accumbens was assessed. In vivo microdialysis was employed to measure glutamate levels in the nucleus accumbens under basal condition and after administration of amphetamine. There was no apparent difference in sham animals treated with saline or amphetamine. However, nVH lesioned animals showed a trend for increased glutamate release following amphetamine administration as compared with all other groups. Taken together, the increased amphetamine-induced locomotor activity in the nVH lesioned animals may be driven by enhanced glutamate release within the nucleus accumbens, which in turn may be derived from alpha-1 receptor-induced increased activity of cortical glutamatergic neurons projecting to the nucleus accumbens.</description><creator>Palardy, Melissa K.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Role of adrenergic and glutamatergic transmission in neonatal ventral hippocampal lesioned rats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Melissa K. Palardy, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43nx21j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c534fp28n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vb62r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Prolactin is a key mammary gland differentiation factor. However, the contribution of prolactin (PRL) to breast carcinogenesis is less clear. Accumulating evidences indicate that in established breast carcinomas autocrine/paracrine PRL can enhance growth/viability of breast cancer cells. Still, it is not known whether the ascribed pro-oncogenic activity of PRL describes fully the role of PRL in regulating breast carcinogenesis. On the other hand a critical role for Ras-Erk1/2 and TGF-beta (Transforming Growth Factor beta) pathway in breast cancer progression has already been established. Our results indicate that blocking PRL signal leads to activation of Ras-Erk1/2 pathway and TGF-beta pathway, two key pathways contributing to breast cancer metastasis. I showed that modulation of PRL signaling in breast cancer cells alters their morphogenic program. My results highlight a critical role for PRL in regulating epithelial plasticity and implicate PRL as invasive suppressor hormone in breast cancer cells.</description><creator>Nouhi, Zaynab.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Prolactin plays a dual role in breast cancer : promoting formation of breast tumour while inhibiting its metastasis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Zaynab Nouhi, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dq00k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vb62r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53jx329</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Free braided pivotal categories are equivalent to free strict monoidal categories on a graph with relations. This is important in the study of knot invariants in that new invariants can be constructed simply by finding suitable strict monoidal categories. This is demonstrated by developing the formal language of strict monoidal categories on a graph with relations, creating categories with relations corresponding to the Reidemeister moves of knot theory and finally showing that these categories are in fact free braided pivotal categories and further equivalent to the categories of link diagrams from knot theory.</description><creator>Oury, David.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Free braided pivotal categories</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© David Oury, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj1392282.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53jx329</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f1881m24x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores the phenomenon of mind-brain dualism in contemporary Western psychiatry from an anthropological and social psychological perspective. In a first chapter, it reports on an empirical study involving 127 staff psychiatrists and psychologists at McGill University who responded to a questionnaire based on clinical vignettes. Results revealed a latent process of judging patients' responsibility for illness, where the more a behavioural problem was seen as 'psychological,' the more the patients tended to be viewed as responsible and blameworthy for their symptoms, while behaviours with 'neurobiological' causes showed the opposite tendency. A second chapter reviews the history of psychosomatic medicine and argues that specific biomedical and psychological sick roles exist for patients that determine the ways in which their actions are judged, as well as how the functions of the rational mind are commonly understood. Insights from evolutionary psychology are used in a third chapter to speculate on new models of mental illness that may provide new contexts for negotiating mind-brain dualism and judgements of responsibility.</description><creator>Miresco, Marc J.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Psychology, Clinical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health.</subject><title>Judgements of responsibility and mind brain dualism in clinical psychiatry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Marc J. Miresco, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kn43v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f1881m24x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v8380833</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Volatile metabolites from headspace gas of mango cultivars Tommy Atkins and Keitt, wounded and inoculated with two pathogens, Colletotrichum gloeosporioides and Lasiodiplodia theobromae or non-inoculated controls were profiled using a GC/MS to develop a technology to discriminate diseases. Several disease discriminatory compounds were identified and classified into three groups: (i) compounds unique to only one treatment; (ii) compounds common to two or more treatments but not to all; and (iii) compounds common to all treatments but with varying in their abundance. 1-pentanol and boronic acid ethyl were detected in only Lasiodiplodia-inoculated mangoes while thujol was observed only in Colletotrichum-inoculated mangoes. Models based on significant mass ions classified up to 100% of the diseases/inoculations. The disease discriminatory compounds and discriminant analysis models developed here could be used in the early detection of postharvest diseases of mango fruit, after validation under commercial conditions.</description><creator>Moalemiyan, Mitra.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Mango -- Postharvest diseases and injuries.</subject><subject>Colletotrichum gloeosporioides.</subject><title>Volatile metabolic profiling to detect and discriminate diseases of mango fruit</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Mitra Moalemiyan, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278t35p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v8380833</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085k29f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Vitamin B12 (cobalamin, Cbl) is required as a cofactor for two human enzymes: methylmalonyl-CoA mutase (MCM) and methionine synthase (MS). Fibroblasts from patients with inborn errors of cobalamin metabolism have been classified into nine distinct complementation classes ( cblA-cblH and mut). Previous studies have shown that cobalamin binds MCM in mitochondria and MS in the cytosol. Cobalamin binding patterns were analyzed in crude mitochondrial fractions obtained from normal and mutant fibroblasts. Crude mitochondrial fractions from wildtype fibroblasts confirmed that the majority of [57Co]Cbl eluted with MCM. However, in six of the nine disorders, at least one previously unidentified mitochondrial cobalamin binding protein was observed to bind [57Co]Cbl. The proportion of [57Co]Cbl that binds, is increased when a deficiency in either adenosylcobalamin synthesis or utilization prevents binding to MCM. Furthermore, unique cobalamin binding profiles emerged, demonstrating how known mutations in these patients affect cobalamin binding to accessory proteins.</description><creator>Moras, Emily.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>Mitochondrial cobalamin binding proteins in patients with inborn errors of cobalamin metabolism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Emily Moras, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935324s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085k29f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j67314178</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main objective of this observational, cross sectional study is to estimate the extent to which muscle strength is independently associated with functional walking capacity among stroke patients. Sixty three stroke patients, from 3 to 12 months post onset, were evaluated on functional walking capacity (6 Minute Walk Test), muscle strength (hand held dynamometry), balance (Berg Balance Scale), and tone (Modified Ashworth Scale and Composite Spasticity Index). The results showed that a global index of muscle strength, balance, tone and comorbids explain 70% of the variability of the 6MWT. Moreover, the muscle strength of the affected side in gravity related positions, as an index, explain most of the variability (37%), in comparison to the other positions. In addition, the hip flexor in an alternate against gravity position, as an individual muscle, explains the most variability of walking capacity.</description><creator>Moriello, Carolina.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><subject>Biology, Physiology.</subject><title>Relation of muscle strength to functional walking capacity post stroke</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Carolina Moriello, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021f481.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j67314178</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd375w49p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Regulators of G-protein Signaling (RGSs) are proteins which attenuate G-Protein coupled receptor (GPCR) signaling by acting as GAPs (GTPase activating proteins) for the Galpha subunit of the heterotrimeric G protein. Although RGSs have been clearly shown to bind the Galpha subunit of heterotrimeric G-proteins, recent studies have shown that RGS specificity occurs via receptor association. To examine possible RGS/GPCR interactions, we constructed a somatostatin 5 (SST5) receptor deletion mutant lacking most of its intracellular C-tail. Here we show that the activation of a GPCR-responsive FUS1 -LacZ reporter gene in yeast strains expressing full length WT SST5 receptor as well as the C-terminally truncated mutant were both inhibited by RGSs 1, 2, 5 and 16, suggesting that the C-tail does not play an integral role in RGS function. As an alternative approach to examine possible RGS/GPCR interactions, RGS function was analyzed via halo assay in yeast cells expressing different RGSs as well the C-tail of different GPCRs including mouse LPA 1, LPA4, Cbeta1, 5HT2A, beta 2AR and human SST5 receptors as well as the third intracellular loop of human SST5. The C-tails and the i3-loop were constructed as GFP fusions. Western blot analysis confirmed that the fusions were expressed in yeast. Of all the combinations of GPCR-C-tail-GFP fusions and RGSs expressed in yeast, only LPA4-GFP was able to interfere with RGS2 function. RGS function was also not inhibited by the expression of SST5-i3-GFP. This suggests that there is a high degree of specificity involved in dictating the interaction between RGSs and GPCRs. In a second study, we wanted to further characterize an immunoreactive RGS5 protein band which was detected from western blot analysis of extract from a yeast strain expressing RGS5 and that was double the size of RGS5. To examine the possibility that this band represents an RGS5 dimer, we examined the molecular weight of RGS5 protein in yeast cells expressing an RGS5-GFP fusion. Western blot analysis of yeast extract expressing GFP-tagged RGS5 detected a band at approximately 50 kDa (representing RGS5-GFP) and a second band at 100 kDa. This suggests that RGS5, like GPCRs, are capable of forming dimers.</description><creator>Gaudio, Sabrina.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Functional characterization of the interaction between G protein coupled receptors (GPCR) and regulators of G protein signaling (RGS) in yeast</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Sabrina Gaudio, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c3110.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375w49p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wc96b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:18:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Type I IFNs modulate the onset of immune responses against viruses through the activation of numerous rapid signaling pathways. Although beneficial on specific infected cells, administered IFNs were shown to decrease thymic cellularity. Herein, we developed a murine model treated with polyinosinic:polycytidylic acid (Poly IC) to dissect the mechanisms and the role of in vivo produced IFNs on the thymus. Treatment induced thymic atrophy, while having no effect on the lymph nodes. However, under chronic conditions, we observed a complete thymic replenishment. These findings should be the result of a LPS contamination, since the use of a new certified LPS-free Poly IC induced a maintained thymic atrophy in time. DP (CD4+CD8+) cells were mostly affected, where part of this decrease was contributed by apoptosis. T cell receptor excision circle (TREC) levels, produced during T cell receptor (TCR) rearrangements, were unaffected, suggesting no alteration of this diversity factor. Additionally, measured up-regulation of MHC class I expression could result in aberrant thymic selections with a modification of selection ranges. Finally, using Caspase 3 KO mice, we showed that DP apoptosis was Caspase-3 independent.</description><creator>Gerarduzzi, Casimiro.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Poly IC induced antiviral responses of type I IFNs alter thymopoietic processes in mice : an apoptotic liaison</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Casimiro Gerarduzzi, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jk64w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wc96b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):25925</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>