<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:00:54Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):27900" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w37638519</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A boundary element model was developed for stress/stability analysis of underground excavations in the vicinity of faults. The boundary element formulation adopts the Fictitious Stress Method for the simulation of excavation boundaries and the Displacement Discontinuity Method for the representation of faults. With the assumption that deformations and stress changes can generally be attributed to the presence of faults rather than to elastoplasticity of the rock mass, the numerical model employed a linear elastic constitutive relation for the rock, and nonlinear behaviour for the fault. This assumption is particularly justified in hard rock environment. Following a comprehensive review of constitutive models for rock joints, both deformation and peak strength models were incorporated for modelling the mechanical behaviour of the fault. Deformation or stiffness models include Goodman's constant stiffness model and Barton-Bandis' nonlinear model. The latter, considers the effect of a wide range of parameters such as coupling between shear and normal stresses and displacement, joint closure, joint separation, hardening followed by postpeak or residual behaviour. Peak strength models include Mohr-Coulomb and Barton-Bandis which employs a mobilized nonlinear shear strength envelope. An incremental, in situ stress relaxation algorithm is developed and implemented for the nonlinear analysis of the faults. Model verification was done by a comparison of its predictions with previously published results found in the literature. The comparison showed excellent agreement. A model sensitivity analysis was then carried out to compare the response of different discontinuity models. A case study of an underground hard rock mine was conducted to examine the stability of a mining ore zone intersected by faults. A user friendly graphical interface was developed to help generate the data and interpret the output results more efficiently.</description><creator>Fotoohi, Keyvan</creator><contributor>Mitri, H. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Nonlinear boundary element analysis of a rock mass with discontinuities</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s633t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w37638519</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nj724</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The intensity returns obtained by a radar from precipitation are well known to fluctuate violently in space and time. We present a systematic study of the resolution dependence time series with overlapping time resolutions spanning 10 orders of magnitude (0.77 ms to 4 months), of the fluctuating radar echo from precipitation. The results undermine the current assumptions of homogeneity of rainfield at scales smaller than the radar resolution, due to Marshall and Hitschfeld (1953), by showing that the only length scales identifiable in the time series are those of the radar pulse volume, the wavelength, and a very small inner scale of the order of millimeters. An analysis of the multiscaling nature of the time series of echo fluctuations reveals multiscaling behaviour at scales down to the resolution or pulse volume scale. Since there are no a priori scales in the rainfield we proceed to model the fluctuating radar echo by assuming a multiscaling model of rainfield variability which extends to sub-resolution scales. A systematic analysis of the statistical behaviour of computed reflectivities from this variability gives a full statistical description of reflectivity originating from multiscaling variability, and solves the scalar multifractal radar observer's problem. Computation of time series of reflectivities from a time-space representation of this variability reveals quantitative and qualitative behaviours consistent with those of observed echo fluctuation time series. We conclude that a multiscaling model of the rainfield which extends to the smallest scales of the rainfield is consistent with observation.</description><creator>Duncan, Mike R. (Mike Ross)</creator><contributor>Lovejoy, Shaun (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Radar meteorology.</subject><subject>Precipitation (Meteorology)</subject><title>The universal multifractal nature of radar echo fluctuations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s6343.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nj724</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62f991g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The overall aim of this thesis was to determine the relative importance of heterotrophy and autotrophy in lake plankton. Empirical analyses using extensive surveys of literature data revealed three specific patterns in metabolism and biomass structure in freshwater plankton. First, the ratio of phytoplankton production to plankton respiration (P/R ratio) tends to be low in unproductive lakes ($&lt;$1), and increases along gradients of enrichment. Second, the contribution of planktonic heterotrophs (bacteria and zooplankton) to community respiration is highest in oligotrophic lakes. Third, planktonic heterotrophs dominate community biomass in oligotrophic lakes, whereas phytoplankton increasingly dominate plankton biomass along gradients of enrichment. These three distinct patterns were then tested simultaneously in a set of lakes that span a wide trophic gradient. Results indicated that the plankton of oligotrophic and mesotrophic lakes were characterized by P/R ratios well below unity, and a high contribution of heterotrophs to both community respiration and biomass. These trends are completely the opposite in the most productive lakes. The plankton communities of oligotrophic temperate lakes are predominantly heterotrophic and extensively utilize external inputs of carbon, and therefore only the plankton of eutrophic lakes conformed to the classical phytoplankton-based food web. In most lakes, excess heterotrophic activity could be supported by inputs of organic matter from the drainage basin. Excess plankton respiration, fueled by allochthonous organic carbon, could represent an important source of CO$ sb2$ to lakes.</description><creator>Del Giorgio, Paul A.</creator><contributor>Peters, R. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Bacteria, Heterotrophic</subject><subject>Freshwater plankton</subject><subject>Freshwater productivity</subject><title>Heterotrophy in lake plankton</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h612x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62f991g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns064739d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis undertakes to refine our understanding of the syntactic properties of sentential negation. The proposed analyses operate at the juncture of recent innovations to Case, Agreement, and X-bar theories, within a Government and Binding framework. Case is checked in a Specifier/Head configuration whenever possible, and agreement is analyzed as the reflex of a Case-checking operation at S-structure. The proposal that the inventory of functional categories available in Universal Grammar includes a Negation Phrase (NegP) is adopted as a point of departure. In the context of this investigation, certain syntactic properties are attributed to the head and specifier of NegP. It is proposed that the specifier of NegP provides an A-position in which NPs may be Case-checked. S-structure Case-checking is reflected in agreement marking on the negative head. Evidence for LF Case-checking in this position is derived from the Case-licensing of direct objects in negated clauses in Colloquial Welsh and Russian. Definiteness effects are analyzed as due to constraints on an additional Case-licensing option required if negation blocks Case assignment under government. Variations in agreement patterns in affirmative and negative relative clauses in Literary and Colloquial Welsh are attributed to the barrier status of the head of NegP.</description><creator>De Freitas, Leslie J. (Leslie Jill)</creator><contributor>Baker, Mark (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Grammar, Comparative and general -- Negatives.</subject><subject>Welsh language -- Negatives.</subject><subject>Russian language -- Negatives.</subject><title>The syntax of sentential negation : interactions with case, agreement, and (in)definiteness</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zg06d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064739d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945s40t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Atrial natriuretic factor (ANF) and angiotensin II (ANG-II) have multiple biological actions, most of them related, directly or indirectly, to blood pressure regulation and fluid homeostasis. The present work was undertaken to study the regulation of renal glomerular ANF receptors by renal sympathetic nerves and ANG-II, to characterize ANF and ANG-II receptor subtypes in rat renal preglomerular vessels, and to define the precise localization of these receptors in the rat mesentery. Using radioligand binding techniques, we demonstrated that renal denervation up-regulated glomerular ANF receptors, and ANG-II blunted this effect, independently of modifications in plasma ANF levels. Receptor characterization studies showed that rat renal preglomerular vessels and glomeruli do not express detectable amounts of ANP-B receptors, and that they have a different proportion of ANP-A and ANP-C receptors. In glomeruli, 85% of receptors are ANP-C and 15% are ANP-A. In preglomerular vessels, ANP-A receptors represented 60% whereas ANP-C accounted for 40%. The large majority of ANG-II receptors in rat renal preglomerular vessels corresponds to the AT$ sb1$ subtype. In the rat mesentery, saturation binding experiments demonstrated that all ANF and most ANG-II receptors (90%) were localized not in the arteries, but in the surrounding perivascular adipose tissue. Most ANF receptors were ANP-C, and a minor fraction were ANP-A and ANP-B. Competition studies with selective ANG-II antagonists revealed that only the AT$ sb1$ receptor subtype is expressed in mesenteric adipose tissue. We expect our studies may contribute to the understanding of the physiological significance of tissue-specific distribution of receptors for ANF and ANG-II in intrarenal structures and within the entire vascular tree. Further studies are required to comprehend the challenging role of ANF and ANG-II in adipose tissue.</description><creator>De León, Héctor</creator><contributor>Garcia, Raul (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Characterization of atrial natriuretic factor and angiotensin II receptors in rat renal glomeruli, preglomerular vessels and mesentery</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128c43b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945s40t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b4797</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The response of target cells to the polypeptide hormone, prolactin, is initiated by the inaction of the hormone with a cell surface receptor that belongs to the class of receptors with a single membrane-spanning domain, designated as the cytokine/GH/PRL receptor family. The mechanism of signal transduction for this family of receptors is not yet determined. Cloning and functional analysis of different forms of the prolactin receptor (PRL-R) were carried out to elucidate the mechanism of signal transduction. The protein sequence deduced from cDNAs isolated from a rat ovarian cDNA library revealed the existence of a long form of the PRL-R in the rat. The mature form has a predicted size of 591 amino acids and shows strong overall sequence similarity with previously cloned long forms of the PRL-R from other species. Another form of the PRL-R was characterized in Nb$ sb2$ cells, a rat lymphoma cell line, dependent on PRL for mitogenesis. This receptor is a deleted form of the long form of the PRL-R missing 198 amino acids in the cytoplasmic domain. The ability of the different forms of the PRL-R to transmit a lactogenic signal was tested in functional systems. The systems consisted of the transient co-transfection of chinese hamster ovary (CHO) cells with a fusion gene containing a milk protein gene promoter linked to the chloramphenicol acetyl transferase (CAT) gene coding region and an expression vector containing various forms of PRL-R cDNAs under the control of the SV-40 early promoter. CAT activity was measured three days after transfection. Results indicate that the long form of the PRL-R is capable of transmitting PRL's signal and activating the milk protein gene promoter. However, when the short form of the receptor was transfected, there was no induction of CAT activity. Interestingly, the Nb$ sb2$ form of the PRL-R was fully capable of transmitting PRL's signal, when examined in the above functional system. This implies that the 198 amino acids segment of t</description><creator>Ali, Suhad Kamil M.</creator><contributor>Kelly, Paul A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Molecular cloning and functional analysis of different forms of the prolactin receptor</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913r44t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b4797</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rj57s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Hox-4.2 is a member of the vertebrate Hox genes. These homeobox genes encode sequence-specific DNA-binding proteins that play a role in vertebrate pattern formation. Their complex spatiotemporal expression patterns during embryogenesis are established in response to positional cues. To characterize regulatory regions involved in Hox-4.2 expression, transient expression assays in P19 murine embryonal carcinoma cells with luciferase reporter gene constructs, under the control of 5$ sp prime$ flanking sequences of Hox-4.2, were performed. Cotransfections of such luciferase reporter constructs with an expression vector for the Hox-4.2 product, resulted in the identification of a 217 bp fragment that functioned as an autoregulatory enhancer. Two binding sites for the Hox-4.2 product within this fragment were characterized by electrophoretic mobility shift assays and their role for autoregulation was demonstrated by site-directed mutagenesis. These findings suggest an autoregulatory mechanism in the control of Hox-4.2 expression and established the Hox-4.2 product as a transcriptional activator in a mammalian system. The use of luciferase reporter gene constructs in P19 embryonal carcinoma cells also led to the identification of a retinoic acid response element (RARE) in Hox-4.2 5$ sp prime$ flanking sequences which was critical for retinoic acid-mediated activation of reporter gene expression in cultured cells. The involvement of retinoic acid receptors in this response was demonstrated by mutation of the Hox-4.2 RARE and cotransfection of an expression vector for a dominant negative form of retinoic acid receptor $ alpha$, both of which inhibited the response to retinoic acid. Furthermore, retinoic acid receptors bound to the RARE as demonstrated in electrophoretic mobility shift assays. The characterization of the Hox-4.2 RARE represented one of the first direct indications for a retinoic acid receptor-mediated regulation of Hox genes. In addition, lacZ reporter gen</description><creator>Pöpperl, Heike</creator><contributor>Featherstone, Mark S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Characterization of regulatory regions for the murine Hox-4.2 gene</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977w55z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rj57s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4f16c4273</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two rabbit and three guinea pig corticostatic (anti-adrenocorticotrophic) peptides were isolated from bone marrow cells and identified. The third guinea pig peptide proved to be a novel 13-member anti-parallel dimer. Removal of the two C-terminal arginines from rabbit corticostatin 1 lowered the biologic activity but removal of the two N-terminal arginines from the guinea pig peptides was without effect. Immunocytochemical localization of rabbit corticostatin 1 in the rabbit indicated that it was localized in immune tissues such as spleen and bone marrow but also in non-immune tissues such as lung, placenta, adrenal, anterior pituitary and various parts of the brain, Rabbit corticostatin 1 was measured in maternal and fetal tissues and in blood at 24, 27 and 30 days of pregnancy in the rabbit and marked changes were noted with increasing gestation, Rabbit corticostatin 1 did not inhibit the action of angiotensin II or Atrial Natriuretic Peptide but it did inhibit $ alpha$-Melanotrophic Stimulating Hormone binding to specific zona glomerulosa receptors.</description><creator>Hu, Jing</creator><contributor>Solomonl, Samuel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Health Sciences, General.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Isolation, tissue localization and physiological action of corticostatic peptides</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752j322.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c4273</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p185m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The object of software frameworks is to mechanize human processes in order to accomplish high-level tasks that call upon diverse software tools. This thesis describes the ELISA framework prototype which performs power-system dynamic security analysis in the operations planning environment. ELISA mechanizes routines traditionally carried out by experts that are essential to power-system dynamic security analysis, greatly accelerating the realization of complex processes. Typically, ELISA executes appropriate load-flow and transient-stability simulations (i.e. using commercially available simulation software), performs result analysis, identifies and executes changes to the input and repeats this process until a user-defined goal, such as finding transient stability transfer limits, has been achieved. A taxonomy of dynamic security analysis in operations planning is proposed employing the semantic net, class-object-property and rule paradigms. All of these are required to cover the full spectrum of knowledge found in the high-level goals, the process details, the complex conditional structures and the acceptance criteria which characterize dynamic security analysis. This taxonomy also describes the language of operations planners, defining not only the features presently supported by ELISA, but also providing a roadmap to future enhancements. Typical sensitivity studies are presented using a 700-bus production model of the Hydro-Quebec network to illustrate the considerable leverage afforded from using ELISA-like software. In addition, the thesis addresses the issue of how such tools can assist in performing research to improve our understanding of fundamental power systems behaviour. Using the ELISA prototype as a laboratory test bed, it is shown that the signal energy E of a network's transient response acts as a barometer to define the relative severity of any normal contingency with respect to power generation or transfer P. For a given contingency, as P is varied and the network approaches instability, signal energy increases smoothly and predictably towards an asymptote which defines the network's stability limit: This limit, in turn, permits us to compare the severity of different contingencies. This behaviour can be explained in terms of the effect of increasing power on the damping component of dominant poles, and a simple function is derived which estimates network stability limits with surprising accuracy from two or three stable simulations. As a corollary to this, it is also shown that a network's transient response can be screened for instability using a simple frequency-domain criterion. Essentially, this criterion requires performing the Fourier transform of a network's transient voltage response at various monitoring locations: When P is varied and the network goes beyond its stability limit, the angle of the Fourier transform's polar plot fundamentally changes its behaviour, passing from a clockwise to a counterclockwise rotational behaviour about the origin. This is confirmed by results obtained from performing stability-limit searches on the Hydro-Quebec system. Used in conjunction with signal energy analysis for determining stability limit proximity, this criterion can be quite useful for mechanized security-limit-determination tools such as ELISA. Signal energy limit estimation and the proposed stability criterion are shown to be applicable to all normal contingencies and these results hold not-withstanding the presence of many active, nonlinear elements in the network.</description><creator>Marceau, Richard J.</creator><contributor>Galiana, F. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, System Science.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Mechanizing dynamic security analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bc386k92s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p185m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x920fz28g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Radiosurgery is characterized by high radiation doses, delivered via small diameter radiation beams in a single session, placing stringent requirements on the numerical and spatial accuracy of dose delivery to the target volume within the brain. In this thesis, physical and clinical aspects of radiosurgery are discussed, including a method for the production of cylindrical dose distributions with rectangular beams using cylindrical dynamic rotation. The measurements of radiosurgical x-ray beam parameters are presented. Monte Carlo simulations determine that a measured increase depth of dose maximum with increasing field size is a result of primary dose deposition in phantom for small diameter beams. An analytical representation based on a curve-fitting process is developed to parametrize radiosurgical x-ray beam percentage depth doses as a function of depth in phantom, field diameter and beam energy using bi-exponential and polynomial functions. Measurements of dose in the build-up region of x-ray beams ranging from 1 x 1 cm$ sp2$ to 30 x 30 cm$ sp2$ show that the depth of dose maximum increases rapidly with increasing field size at small fields, reaches a maximum around 5 x 5 cm$ sp2$ and then gradually decreases with increasing field size for large fields. Monte Carlo simulations attribute effect observed at large fields to the scatter contamination of the primary beam from the linac head. This scatter contamination is measured by a half-block technique and further experiments show that it consists of electrons originating in the flattening filter of the linac.</description><creator>Sixel, Katharina E. (Katharina Elisabeth)</creator><contributor>Podgorsak, E. B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><subject>Physics, Radiation.</subject><title>Measurements and Monte Carlo simulations of X-ray beams in radiosurgery</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977w567.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fz28g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354g80g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigates the foreign market entry decision of multinational firms from three theoretical perspectives--namely transaction cost/internalization, competitive strategy and organizational capability. It is argued that each perspective primarily focuses on a different level of analysis--the firm or division, the transaction and the organizational unit respectively. The final decision regarding the means of foreign market entry is a choice made after considering these three forces simultaneously. The study contributes by developing an understanding of the role of organizational capability in the mode of entry decision. It further enriches theory through developing some of the interrelationships between the three perspectives. The empirical research was conducted through a field study and a cross-sectional questionnaire survey sent to multinational firms with headquarters in Europe and North America. The results suggest that competitive strategy and organizational capability perspectives are most significant in determining the choice of entry mode. The transaction cost perspective does not appear to be significant. One broad implication for managers is the importance of both analyzing the characteristics of the chosen product-market and critically examining the firm's capabilities in order to focus on what it does best, build upon it and, where necessary, complement this through collaboration with others.</description><creator>Madhok, Anoop</creator><contributor>Jorgensen, Jan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Export marketing.</subject><title>Mode of foreign market entry : an integrative study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257g63k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354g80g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451k169</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the central Canadian Rocky Mountain thrust-fold belt, three types of first order decollements are outlined within or along the border of the present orogenic wedge: one basal decollement, three intermediate or internal decollements and one upper decollement. Structural relationships suggest that each internal decollement is the result of one of the successive forward shifts of early basal decollements to new positions within the stratigraphic pile. Two computer programs have been developed to analyze the propagation of multiple thrust faults and their influence on the geometry of a thrust belt. The computer programs generate graphical simulations used to demonstrate a model of thrust propagation and thrust belt development that fits current knowledge about fault propagation and can replace the thrust transfer zone concept. A structural analysis of mesoscale structures in two thrust sheets indicates that a thrust sheet consist of a series of elongated blocks separated by subtle brittle-ductile shear zones along which differential motion occurred. These shear zones are oriented perpendicular to the mean strike of the thrust faults.</description><creator>Lebel, Daniel</creator><contributor>Mountjoy, Eric W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>Geometry, kinematics, and computer simulations of thrust faulting, central Canadian Rocky Mountains, Alberta</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qd70g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451k169</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p1875</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The first part of my work evaluates bilateral supramaximal transcutaneous phrenic nerve stimulation as a diagnostic test for respiratory muscle fatigue. I found that twitch transdiaphragmatic pressure (Pdi,T) was inversely and linearly related to lung volume (V$ sb{ rm L}$) both before and after fatigue. Although fatigue caused significant decrease in Pdi,T amplitude at all V$ sb{ rm L}$, the fractional decrease in Pdi,T was greater at high V$ sb{ rm L}$, indicating the importance of V$ sb{ rm L}$ as an independent variable that needs to be controlled whenever Pdi,T is determined. Twitch mouth pressure (Pm,T) was found to be linearly related to twitch esophageal pressure (Pes,T), to Pdi,T, and to V$ sb{ rm L}$. All these relationships were reproducible. Diaphragmatic fatigue resulted in significant decrease in Pm,T proportional to the decrease in Pdi,T for a given V$ sb{ rm L}$ so that Pm,T-Pes,T and Pm,T-Pdi,T relationships were unchanged. Thus the Pm,T-V$ sb{ rm L}$ relationship can be used to assess diaphragmatic fatigue non-invasively. Paired phrenic nerve shocks which were well tolerated by normal subjects can be used to obtain a measure of the pressure-frequency curves of the diaphragm, which were reproducible. In particular, I showed that the pressure ratio of diaphragmatic twitch elicited by the second shock at 10Hz over that at 100Hz (T2$ sb{10/100}$) is a valuable index of low frequency fatigue. In the second part of my work I studied the effect of respiratory muscle fatigue on ventilatory response to CO$ sb2$ and respiratory muscle recruitment. The data showed that ventilatory response and respiratory muscle recruitment patterns were different in a number of aspects between diaphragmatic fatigue and global inspiratory muscle fatigue. After diaphragmatic fatigue, the only change was an increase in the recruitment of rib cage muscles, which fully compensated for decreased diaphragmatic contractility because all the ventilatory parameters were constant. After global fatigue, both the diaphragm and rib cage muscles contributed less to breathing but expiratory muscles were recruited resulting in a decrease in end-expiratory P$ sb{ rm L}$ and an increased contribution of elastic energy stored within the respiratory system to inspiratory tidal volume generation. In spite of this, rapid shallow breathing developed while minute ventilation remained constant. These data suggest that the ventilatory control system can detect fatigue and has sufficient plasticity to alter inspiratory drive appropriately. The overall ventilation level can thus be maintained.</description><creator>Yan, Sheng</creator><contributor>Macklem, Peter T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Anatomy.</subject><title>Evaluation of human respiratory muscle fatigue</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999820h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p1875</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bd261</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ribosome binding to cellular eukaryotic mRNAs is proposed to occur by initial attachment at or near to the mRNA 5$ sp prime$ cap structure (m$ sp7$ GpppN, where N is any nucleotide) followed by scanning until the appropriate initiator AUG is encountered. A pivotal aspect of this model is the obligatory entry of ribosomes at the 5$ sp prime$ end of the mRNA regardless if it contains a cap structure. Recent experiments demonstrated that ribosomes access certain mRNAs by internal binding to the 5$ sp prime$ untranslated region (UTR). This was most clearly demonstrated for members of the picornavirus family such as poliovirus and encephalomyocarditis virus. Further experiments suggest that other viral mRNAs and even cellular mRNAs may use similar mechanisms of ribosome binding. Some features of the poliovirus 5$ sp prime$ untranslated region and possible trans-acting factors that are involved in this mechanism were studied. A cis-acting element comprising a conserved polypyrimidine tract was critical for poliovirus RNA translation in vitro. Using a mobility shift electrophoresis assay, a fragment of the poliovirus 5$ sp prime$ UTR was found to interact with a component in a HeLa cellular extract. A 52 kDa polypeptide (p52) has been identified as part of the protein-RNA complex using an ultraviolet-light cross-linking assay. p52 is not a known initiation factor and is limiting in a reticulocyte lysate. Purification of p52 and peptide microsequencing showed that p52 is identical to the human La autoantigen (that has previously been implicated in transcription termination) and stimulates the translation of poliovirus RNA in a reticulocyte lysate. This finding will undoubtedly shed light on the mechanism of poliovirus translation, its regulation and neurovirulence.</description><creator>Meerovitch, Karen</creator><contributor>Sonenberg, Nahum (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Studies on the mechanism of internal initiation of translation of poliovirus mRNA</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741t37d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bd261</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c907c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this project was to develop a reliable and valid battery for the assessment of spatial orientation skills (SOS) in persons with Alzheimer's disease (AD). The battery, comprised of 13 subtests, was administered to 97 normal control subjects, 25 subjects with early AD and 10 with late AD. The test-retest reliability of the battery was based on the test results of 33 normal control subjects and 25 early AD subjects. Inter-rater reliability was determined using four trained raters who evaluated 27 normal control subjects and the same 25 early AD subjects. Content validity was established using a panel of six experts and construct validity was determined by comparing the performance of the normal control and early AD groups. To establish criterion validity, the Global Deterioration Scale (GDS) was used as the criterion. For the AD group, eight subtests demonstrated acceptable test-retest and inter-rater reliability coefficients (ICC $ ge$.70). For the control group, three subtests had acceptable test-retest coefficients and four had acceptable inter-rater coefficients. The internal consistency of the battery was acceptable as shown by overall Cronbach's alpha of.86 for AD subjects and.72 for control subjects, and was further analyzed using factor analysis which yielded five factors. Logistic regression provided evidence for good construct validity. Scores on the SOS subtests were able to differentiate the three groups of subjects established on the basis of the GDS scores (GDS 1 and 2, GDS 3 and 4, and GDS 5). A preliminary shortened version of the battery was developed using six subtests which demonstrated high test-retest and inter-rater reliability. The performance of subjects with AD on the battery is discussed with respect to its implications for the theoretical basis and clinical assessment of spatial orientation in AD.</description><creator>Liu, Lili, 1962-</creator><contributor>Gauthier, Louise (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Jones, Lynette (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><subject>Psychology, Psychometrics.</subject><title>Assessment of spatial orientation in Alzheimer's disease : theoretical and clinical implications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mh17t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c907c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vq27zq069</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this inquiry was to conduct a comparative analysis of the legislative action taken by the government of each Canadian province and territory, as of December 31, 1992, with respect to the provision of equal educational opportunity for students with disabilities. The methodology consisted of a form of qualitative content analysis of the relevant legislative action, validated by provincial representatives, complemented by a study of relevant case-law. The analytical framework comprised 60 items grouped around five types of rights: non-discrimination, access, identification/placement, service delivery and parental participation. Overall, four jurisdictions, the Yukon, followed by Ontario, Quebec and Saskatchewan, were found to provide for a significant level of rights. Newfoundland, Prince Edward Island, Nova Scotia and the Northwest Territories were found to provide for the lowest level of overall rights. Equality rights and access received the highest ratings across all jurisdictions, while parental participation, service delivery and identification/placement were rated lowest. Extensive references and key extracts from all legislation analyzed are included.</description><creator>Smith, William J., 1947-</creator><contributor>Lusthaus, Charles (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Foster, William F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Students with disabilities -- Canada.</subject><subject>Educational equalization -- Canada</subject><subject>Educational equalization -- Law and legislation -- Canada</subject><title>Equal educational opportunity for students with disabilities in Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r9354.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zq069</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Administration and Policy Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591990r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Spring barley (Hordeum vulgare L.) is an important cereal crop in Quebec, where it is used as a crop for swine and poultry. Since barley is a better source of energy than protein, a protein supplement must be added to the feed. Consequently, the production of barley with high protein concentration in the grain (GPC) is desirable. Studies on intensive cereal management (ICM) practices in other countries have shown that high yields can be combined with a high GPC. From 1987 to 1990 three field experiments were conducted to evaluate the effects of ICM on the yields and GPC of six-rowed spring barley in Quebec. Our results describe the effects of individual ICM components (N fertilizer application, fungicide, and plant growth regulator) on the development of yield components and on GPC. In general, N had little effect on main stem yield spike$ sp{-1}$ and on tiller spikes m$ sp{-2}$. Possibly, plant density or environmental conditions may have imposed greater limitations on yield rather than N. Nitrogen treatments increased GPC generally by increasing the amount of protein grain$ sp{-1}$. Nitrogen treatments which increased the amount of protein grain$ sp{-1}$ increased the lysine and cyst(e)ine concentrations of the grain but decreased their concentration in the grain protein. The plant growth regulator ethephon increased GPC by increasing the amount of protein grain$ sp{-1}$, by decreasing the nonprotein content grain$ sp{-1}$, or by altering final grain size distribution. Ethephon often had damaging effects on yield. Large genotypic variation was observed for GPC, but could not be related to genotypic differences in N harvest index, total N accumulation, protein yield or post-anthesis N uptake and assimilation. Grain yield was weakly correlated with GPC. Examination of the cultivars grown from 1910 to 1988 showed that increases in grain yield were accompanied by increases in harvest index, total dry matter, and lodging resistance. Plant height was reduced over tim</description><creator>Bulman, Patrick G. M.</creator><contributor>Smith, D. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1991</date><subject>Barley -- Yields.</subject><subject>Proteins.</subject><title>Management and cultivar effects on the yield and grain protein of spring barley (Hordeum vulgare L.)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182m814.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591990r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r262p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Biomass production of chlorophyllase of the marine alga (Phaeodactylum tricornutum) at the exponential and stationary stages was performed. The results demonstrated that the biomass yield at the stationary stage was three times that of the exponential stage. A procedure for the extraction and purification of chlorophylls from fresh spinach leaves, used as substrate, was also developed. Chlorophyllase was extracted from photosynthetic membranes of the disrupted cells and partially purified. The purification procedure resulted into 70-fold increase in enzyme activity. Further purification of the partially purified enzyme was performed, using preparative isoelectric focusing on Rotofor-Cell System. Three enzyme fractions, FI$ sp prime$, FII$ sp prime$, and FIII$ sp prime$ were separated, however, most of enzyme activity (84%) was located in fraction FII$ sp prime$. The partially purified chlorophyllase was further purified by native preparative gel electrophoresis on Prep-Cell System, which resulted into a single active fraction. The purified enzyme fraction was then subjected to further purification, using automated Fast Protein Liquid Chromatography (FPLC) System, on ion-exchange Mono Q HR 5/5 column. The purification procedure resulted into two well separated isozymes, FI$ sp prime$ and FII$ sp prime$. Enzyme fraction (FI$ sp prime$) showed the highest enzymatic activity compared to FII$ sp prime$. The homogeneity of each fraction was demonstrated by a single protein band on SDS-PAGE. The molecular weights of these fractions FI$ sp prime$ and FII$ sp prime$ were 67 kD and 66kD, respectively. The optimum pH for chlorophyllase activity fractions FI$ sp prime$, and FII$ sp prime$ were 8.0 and 8.3, respectively. The enzymatic fraction FI$ sp prime$ showed higher activity towards commercial purified chlorophyll b when it was compared to that with the crude chlorophyll, partially purified chlorophyll and commercial purified chlorophyll a. However, enzymatic fraction FI</description><creator>Khalyfa, Abdelnaby</creator><contributor>Kermasha, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Plant enzymes.</subject><subject>Chlorophyll.</subject><subject>Diatoms.</subject><title>Extraction, purification and characterization of chlorophyllase from alga Phaeodactylum tricornutum</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f462705d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r262p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qr15d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The soil thermal regime is important to the soil and plant environment, being an influential factor in determining many processes in soil. Changes in soil bulk density, soil surface reflectance and soil temperature changes with depth and time were studied theoretically and experimental as a function of variable soil properties, soil surface state, crop cover and atmospheric conditions. A field experiment was carried out on sandy and clayey soils with each plot being subjected to a consistent tillage and fertilizer history of either conventional ploughing, reduced energy disking or zero tillage, and fresh dairy manure or manufactured inorganic fertilizer. The measured results and the quantitative models assist hopefully in identifying how soil management affects the soil thermal regime and in making cultivation management decisions. Soil bulk density for each fertilizer type can be predicted quantitatively from input tillage energy in a linear fashion. The reflectance of the soil surface was estimated as an integrated form of the individual reflectance and the area fractions of the soil surface components, with a soil roughness correction term. This model can cover various surface situations under different schemes of soil management. A simulation model for soil temperature was developed, which can be applied to bare soil, partially crop-covered soil and completely crop-covered soil. The models can also be used as submodels or be linked to other existing models.</description><creator>Chen, Ying, 1957-</creator><contributor>McKyes, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Soil temperature -- Computer simulation.</subject><subject>Tillage.</subject><subject>Soil temperature.</subject><title>Soil thermal regime resulting from reduced tillage systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430630n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qr15d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62f992r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effects of exogenous estrogen administration on aspects of memory and cognition in women were examined in two studies. In Study 1, women receiving estrogen replacement therapy were compared to untreated women on four measures of verbal memory. Those receiving estrogen had significantly better scores on a measure of delayed memory for propositional material. In Study 2, women in the early stages of Alzheimer's Disease (AD) were administered either estrogen or placebo on a double-blind basis for six months. Women given estrogen showed improvement on a measure of verbal memory and spatial attention compared to the placebo controls. The combined results of these studies provide evidence that estrogen enhances aspects of verbal memory in both healthy postmenopausal women and in postmenopausal women in the early stages of AD as measured by neuropsychological tests. These effects might be mediated by actions of estrogen on neuronal morphology and physiology in brain areas important for memory and cognition.</description><creator>Kampen, Diane L.</creator><contributor>Sherwin, Barbara B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Menopause -- Hormone therapy.</subject><subject>Memory -- Effect of drugs on.</subject><subject>Alzheimer's disease -- Patients.</subject><subject>Memory -- Age factors.</subject><subject>Estrogen -- Therapeutic use.</subject><title>The relationship between estrogen and memory in healthy postmenopausal women and women in the early stages of Alzheimer's disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fd283.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62f992r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085m84q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The intrahypothalamic distribution of mu, delta and kappa opioid receptor types was examined by in vitro radioautography using the opioid ligands $ sp{125}$I-FK-33 824, $ sp{125}$I-DTLET and $ sp{125}$I-DPDYN, respectively as selective markers. The density and distribution of these receptors in the hypothalamus of normal rats was then compared to that of rats injected with estradiol valerate in order to verify the location of the described increase in $ sp3$H-naloxone binding and to identify the specific opioid receptor type involved. Analysis of opioid receptor changes following long-term exposure to estradiol revealed that mu opioid binding densities were significantly increased in the medial preoptic area of EV-treated animals. Delta and kappa opioid binding densities were unchanged in the medial preoptic area although a slight decrease in delta sites was observed in the suprachiasmatic nucleus. Hypothalamic $ beta$-endorphin concentrations were concomitantly decreased in EV-treated animals, suggesting that observed increases in mu opioid binding were due to a compensatory up-regulation of receptors secondary to loss of $ beta$-endorphin input from the arcuate nucleus. To confirm this interpretation, mu opioid receptor binding was measured in the MPOA of animals treated with monosodium glutamate, which destroys the arcuate nucleus. Results indicated that mu opioid receptor binding densities were inversely proportional to hypothalamic $ beta$-endorphin concentrations in the same animals supporting the existence of a causal relationship between chronic reductions in hypothalamic $ beta$-endorphin concentrations and mu opioid receptor upregulation in the medial preoptic area. To further document the decreased concentrations of $ beta$-endorphin in the hypothalamus of EV-treated animals, light microscopic immunocytochemistry for $ beta$-endorphin was performed in colchicine treated control and EV-injected rats. Eight weeks following EV treatment, a 60% decrease in the total number of $ beta$-endorphin-immunoreactive neurons was detected in the arcuate nucleus, while neuron numbers for nearby neuronal populations were unchanged. These results were confirmed in biochemical experiments demonstrating reduced hypothalamic $ beta$-endorphin concentrations in the absence of changes in neuropeptide-Y and met-enkephalin in EV-treated rats as compared to controls. Cell counts performed in Nissl-stained material using unbiased stereological methods revealed a reduction in the total number of neurons in the EV-treated group as compared to controls. Furthermore, the estimated number of neurons lost ($ sim$3500) corresponded precisely with the total number of $ beta$-endorphin neurons lost ($ sim$3600) as estimated using quantitative immunocytochemistry. Together, these findings strongly suggest that $ beta$-endorphin neurons are selectively destroyed following long-term exposure to estradiol. Results demonstrated that EV-treated animals co-treated with vitamin E displayed hypothalamic $ beta$-endorphin concentrations similar to controls. In addition, these animals maintained regular estrous cycles and displayed normal ovarian morphology. These findings suggest that estradiol-induced neurotoxicity of $ beta$-endorphin neurons involves the production of free radicals and further supports the notion that the loss of these neurons is important to the induction of chronic anovulation and polycystic ovaries resulting after EV treatment. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Desjardins, G. Clarissa (Gina Clarissa)</creator><contributor>Beaudet, Alain (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Role of the hypothalamic opioid system in estradiol-induced polycystic ovarian syndrome</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977w592.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085m84q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30pv164</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effects of intraspecific and interspecific competition, host plant, and prior host plant experience on fecundity, rate of oviposition and mortality of adults and larval survival of Delia radicum Bouche (Cabbage Maggot (CM)), D. antiqua Meigen (Onion Maggot (OM)), and D. platura Meigen (Seed Corn Maggot (SCM)), were studied on cabbage, onion and bean plants. An optimum density for maximum fecundity per female was observed when the four experimental densities were compared. This optimum density was higher on host than on non-host plants. CM females were host specific and did not oviposit on non-host plants. Rates of oviposition and mortality over a 30-day period were calculated for each density. The rate of oviposition was slower at higher densities on host plants for CM, OM and SCM. The rate of mortality increased at the highest density for CM (cabbage), OM (bean) and SCM (cabbage), but remained unaffected for OM on onion and cabbage and for SCM on onion and bean, when densities were compared. For OM, a delay in the rate of oviposition and mortality on cabbage (non-host plant) when compared with onion (host plant), suggests that cabbage was not as readily accepted as an oviposition site. Interspecific competition experiments at six density ratio's of SCM:OM indicated increased fecundity, or an increase in the rate of oviposition for OM, at the lower densities when single and mixed species were compared. For SCM no effects on fecundity were recorded, but the rate of oviposition was slower and rate of mortality faster at the lowest density in the presence of OM. Similar studies with SCM and CM showed no such effects of competition. Host plant exposure of SCM females during the pre-oviposition period resulted in a delay in initial acceptance of subsequent host plants as oviposition sites. This happened only when females were exposed to a secondary host during the pre-oviposition period. Once oviposition began, host discrimination ceased and a switch in oviposition sites to the preferred host did not alter the rate of oviposition. In CM, the rate of larval development increased at density 6 (optimum density). Above this density a decrease in the rate of development and a significant reduction in pupal weight was observed. Time required for fly emergence was not affected by increasing larval densities.</description><creator>Noronha, Christine M. (Christine Mary)</creator><contributor>Hill, S. B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Onions -- Diseases and pests.</subject><subject>Cabbage maggot.</subject><subject>Cabbage -- Diseases and pests.</subject><subject>Beans -- Diseases and pests.</subject><subject>Hylemya.</subject><title>Effects of density and host plant type on fecundity and survival of Delia radicum (Bouché), D. Antiqua (Meigen) and D. Platura (Meigen) (Diptera: Anthomyiidae)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f5108.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pv164</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074w79t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Modified biphenols which contain 2,2$ sp prime$-disubstituents on the biphenyl groups and also hydroquinones containing multiple substituents were synthesized in order to prepare novel thermally stable polymers. The structure/properties relationship which were investigated using viscometry, DSC, TG/DTA, TMA, and GPC are discussed. The prepared polymers (polysulfones and poly(ether ketone)s) exhibit considerably enhanced glass transition temperatures and are soluble in common organic solvents due to the noncoplanar biphenyl rings which increase the disorder along the polymer backbone thereby reducing interchain interactions. The polyesters prepared show poor solubility and their Tg's and Tm's increase considerably over the unhindered polyester analogs due to the chain stiffness. Polyimides were prepared from the reaction of novel dianhydrides and m- and p-phenylene diamines. A series of bisanhydrides were prepared via the nitro-displacement reaction of hindered biphenols and N-methyl-4-nitrophthalimide. The polymers exhibit good solubility in common organic solvents and show high Tg's. Blends of polycarbonate and polyimides, prepared from m-phenylene diamine, show better miscibility compared to those of polyimides from p-phenylene diamine. The 2,2$ sp prime$-substituted biphenols which can be oxidized to bisphenoxydiradicals are applicable as oxidizing agents for diphenylmethanes and primary alcohols, and also undergo C-O coupling reactions with activated methylene groups. An additional modified biphenol was synthesized for REDOX polymers applications and the properties of these polymers are discussed.</description><creator>Kim, Whan-Gi</creator><contributor>Hay, A. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>Synthesis and properties of novel thermally stable polymers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920fz29r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074w79t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ms35t998k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Granular-fluid mixtures flowing down an incline in the grain-inertia regime were studied experimentally and analytically. The equations of motion are based on the kinetic theory for granular flow. The boundary conditions are formulated following two methods. The first is a simple mechanical approach based on the energy exchange at the wall. The other is based on the kinetic theory for granular flow. Solutions for dry granular flow down a chute are studied in order to compare both methods. The extension of the kinetic theory presented here, includes drag forces resulting from the interstitial fluid that cushions interparticle collisions and particle-wall collisions. Frictional stresses, produced when long term contacts are present, and fluid turbulent fluctuations are introduced in the model. The results are compared with measurements from an experimental chute in which the inclination, the solids flow rate and fluid flow rate are all varied. The theory is found to give a good qualitative account of the observed behaviour. Finally an application of the model to the description of the mechanical behaviour of the Nevado del Ruiz 1985 debris flow is attempted.</description><creator>García Aragón, Juan Antonio</creator><contributor>Savage, Stuart B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Applied Mechanics.</subject><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Experimental and analytical investigations of granular-fluid mixtures down inclines</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/12579t81c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35t998k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290c09w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:01:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>ABRÉGÉDélivrer un traitement conforme à la planification est une des responsabilités duphysicien médical; ceci est relativement simple à vérifier en RadiothérapieConformationnelle. Cependant, la complexité des calculs en Radiothérapie avecModulation d’Intensité (RTMI) rend cette vérification moins évidente puisque larelation entre la dose et les unités moniteures est plus difficile à établir. Enconséquence, irradier un fantôme conformément au plan établi pour le patient estune étape effectuée avant chaque traitement. Cette irradiation s’accompagned’une mesure à l’aide d’une chambre d’ionisation et d’une mesure desdistributions de doses à 2D. Dans cette thèse trois points sont soulevés. Lepremier consiste à évaluer le Computed Radiography (CR) en dosimétrie; leprotocole proposé a mené à une réponse linéaire mais dépendante en énergie et enlargeur de champ. En second lieu, une comparaison de deux films (EDR2 et EBT)largement utilisés pour l’assurance qualité en RTMI a été effectuée. L’étude amontré qu’en dose relative, EDR2 donnent de meilleurs résultats que EBT. Ceciest attribuable au fait que le contraste enregistré avec EDR2 rend les artefacts descanners moins importants sur le calcul de dose comparativement à EBT. Latroisième partie de ce travail traite de l’importance des artefacts introduits lors dela lecture des EBT sur le scanner EPSON1680. Une correction de ces artefacts,effectuée sur MATLAB, a prouvé leur importance. Le logiciel FILMQA utilisé enclinique pour le traitement des films a montré une grande erreur sur la mesure desprofils, mais sur 15 plans d’RTMI étudiés, un seul cas a véritablement étéamélioré par la correction effectuée sur MATLAB.</description><description>ABSTRACT  Intensity modulated beams use complicated computerized treatment planning systems; this makes a manual verification of the number of monitor units difficult to perform. Consequently, before treatment, patient-specific quality assurance must be done in order to ensure that the delivery agrees with the plan; this process involves a measurement of 2D dose distribution in a phantom. In this thesis, first, a photostimulable phosphor luminescence device (also referred to as computed radiography or CR) was evaluated for dosimetric purposes. The proposed protocol showed linearity response of the CR, but energy and field size dependence were discovered. Second, two widely used films for IMRT QA were compared: the radiological film, EDR2, and the radiochromic film, EBT, with the use of the scanner EPSON1680 and the software FILMQA. Results showed that in the relative dose mode, EDR2 gives higher number of pixels passing a chosen criterion compared to EBT. This fact is attributed to the highest contrast observed with EDR2; therefore, any change on pixel value due to scanner artifacts will have less impact on dose calculations with EDR2. Finally, the impact of scanner artifacts on dose assessment with EBT films, processed with FILMQA and a program written on MATLAB, was studied. A correction was introduced on MATLAB that proves the importance of taking scanner artifacts into account for the measurements with the scanner EPSON1680 and EBT films digitized in the portrait orientation. Comparison between FILMQA and MATLAB was performed on profile’s measurements and on fifteen head and neck IMRT QA cases. This comparison showed that one case out of fifteen was drastically improved with MATLAB, yet FILMQA gave inaccurate results of profiles compared with the correction applied on MATLAB.</description><creator>Chaal, Kahena</creator><contributor>Russell Ruo (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>William A Parker (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Physics - Radiation</subject><title>Film dosimetry of intensity modulated beams</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/70795931x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290c09w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Medical Physics Unit</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):27925</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>