<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:36:48Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):38500" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v838243j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:50:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The principles governing isothermal creeping shear flow and orientation behavior of low and high molecular weight nematic liquid crystalline materials are established. New adaptive numerical methods are developed and successfully implemented in conjunction with computational bifurcation methods to simulate the steady and transient flow, morphological, rheological and optical characteristics of nematic liquid crystalline materials. The simulation results are in remarkable agreements with a large number of widely reported experimental measurements and observations of morphological, rheological, and optical phenomena. Furthermore, they establish for the first time the origin of these responses, and provide guidelines to experimental studies on these phenomena. The present thesis resolves a twenty-year old controversy on the flow characteristics of low molecular weight nematics. Experimentally measured highly complex rheological responses have been accurately reproduced by the simulations, and explained by the underlying three-dimensional orientation structure. Finally, the origin of the ubiquitous pattern formation of sheared nematic polymers is explained.</description><creator>Han, Won Hee</creator><contributor>Rey, Alejandro D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Computational modelling of orientation and flow instabilities, textures, rheology, and optics of shearing nematic liquid crystalline materials</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1831cm85z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838243j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nk06r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:50:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The migration phenomenon of a neutrally buoyant solid particle suspended in an arbitrary flowing fluid of zero Reynolds number bounded by a plane solid wall has been analytically studied for the situation where the influence of boundary conditions is important. In particular, it is shown that for flows near a solid wall, particles can move in such a manner so as to cause large spatial variations of particle concentration in the suspension. Similar techniques are used to obtain a theoretical formulation for the non-deformable spherical droplet suspended in the prescribed flowing fluid bounded by the solid plane boundary. Special cases such as flows containing a vortex near the solid boundary or flows which are periodic along the wall are particularly examined. Experiments have been performed to verify the validity of the theory for the solid particles and non-deformable fluid drops. Experimental results are also compared to theoretical conclusions.</description><creator>Gu, Lian Sheng</creator><contributor>Cox, R. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Migration of a neutrally buoyant particle suspended in a general bounded creeping flow</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pv54j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nk06r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c247d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:50:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study was designed in an effort to address two general questions: (1) the primacy of social dysfunction in bulimia nervosa, and its potential as a risk factor in disease onset; and (2) the proximal antecedents of the binge eating episode in bulimic patients. Given the substantial clinical and empirical evidence of social impairment in this psychiatric group, as well as findings documenting the treatment effectiveness of Interpersonal Psychotherapy (a therapeutic program designed to exclusively address social disturbances) with bulimic patients, it has been speculated that difficulty with interpersonal relationships may be a predisposing factor in the development of bulimia. The present study sought to determine whether social problems could present as potential markers for later disturbances of eating in weight-preoccupied women. A comparison of bulimic patients with a group of restrained eaters and a group of unrestrained eaters on such features as social adjustment across domains of functioning, specific deficits in interpersonal transactions, and qualitative aspects of everyday social experiences was undertaken to determine whether deficits in the social sphere parallel the continuum of eating pathology. In support of previous research and consistent with predictions, bulimic subjects were found to display greater social maladjustment and interpersonal deficits, and to report more negative social interaction experiences than control subjects. Few dimensions of social dysfunction were found to differentiate restrained eaters from unrestrained eaters, thereby suggesting that bulimia nervosa and restrained eating are not continuous with regard to social problems. Studies examining the proximal antecedents of binge eating episodes have suggested that negative affect reliably precedes binge eating, and as such, has been considered a precipitant to bulimic episodes. However, no previous empirical work has addressed the precursors of this negative mood state. The present study postulated an "interpersonal stress" model of the binge/purge episode which incorporates disturbances in social relatedness and negative interpersonal interaction as precipitants of the negative affect that characterizes the pre-binge state. The model was evaluated in a naturalistic investigation of social interaction experiences and eating behavior in a sample of clinical eating disorder patients. The interpersonal distress/negative affect/binging linkages postulated in the present study were supported, thus highlighting the significance of negative social interaction experiences in the elicitation of binge eating. The clinical implications of the present findings are substantial as they underscore the effectiveness of eating disorder treatment programs which consider interpersonal disturbances in their therapeutic interventions.</description><creator>Chinoy, Tinaz</creator><contributor>Koestner, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Bulimia -- Psychological aspects.</subject><subject>Social interaction.</subject><title>Evaluation of the social dysfunction in bulimia nervosa and interpersonal distress in the elicitation of binge eating episodes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526f22t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c247d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hb72p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The gelling characteristics of whey proteins is governed by factors which affect the structural properties of the protein. To understand this structure gelling relationship, the following factors were investigated; protein concentration, heating temperature and time, pH, NaCl and sugars. The effect of these factors on the molecular structure and gelatin properties of whey protein concentrate (WPC), $ beta$-lactoglobulin ($ beta$-lg), $ alpha$-lactalbumin ($ alpha$-lac) and bovine serum albumin (BSA) were studied using polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis, HPLC, mass spectrometry, differential scanning calorimetry and Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy. The results showed that protein concentration affected textural properties without affecting the molecular structure of the whey proteins while heating temperature, pH and NaCl affected both molecular structure and the textural characteristics. NaCl and sugars increased the stability of whey proteins to thermal denaturation but decreased gel formation. $ beta$-lg formed an opaque gel at pH 3 and a translucent gel at pH 9; the peak temperature of denaturation was 84$ sp circ$C at pH 3 and 70$ sp circ$C at pH 9. At both acid and alkaline pH, denaturation of $ beta$-lg resulted in the formation of intermolecular $ beta$-sheet structures associated with aggregation. These $ beta$-sheet aggregate structures were also observed when $ alpha$-lac was heated at pH 3 and 5 but not at pH 7 and 9. At pH 7, heating $ alpha$-lac resulted in a loss of $ alpha$-helix, $3 sb{10}$-helix and $ beta$-sheet and an increase in turns. DSC showed two reversible transitions at 39.6$ sp circ$C (A) and 64.8$ sp circ$C (B). At pH 3, transition A was partially reversible (14%) while transition B was completely reversible. At pH 9, transitions A and B were completely irreversible and a translucent gel was formed. Bovine serum albumin (BSA) showed maximum stability to thermal denaturation at pH 5. Denaturation of BSA resulted in the loss of $</description><creator>Boye, Joyce Irene Ashami</creator><contributor>Alli, Inteaz (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Globular proteins.</subject><subject>Whey products.</subject><subject>Gelation.</subject><title>Thermodynamic and structural properties related to the gelation of whey proteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qk72h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hb72p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s4330</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis deals with the flow mechanics of hydraulic and high density mine backfill slurries in pipelines. Various empirical, rheological and mechanistic approaches are presented and analysed along with some aspects pertinent to experimental testing of backfill slurries. The main contribution of this work is, particularly, in the development of an analytical model to describe the flow and predict the pressure gradient of a class of high density backfill whose motion in pipelines follows the Plug Flow Model (PFM). The development of the model called for investigating the conditions required for establishing Plug Flow. It was found that mix proportioning procedures, similar to those found in the concrete industry, are key factors in obtaining Plug Flow. Pressure drop was found to be a function of the thickness of the Bingham plastic annular layer surrounding the cylindrical core of aggregates. Analytical equations were proposed to solve for the thickness of this layer by considering the rheology of the mixture. Alternatively, the thickness of the annular layer may be estimated by considering the relative proportions of the mixture with respect to aggregates void content. The model offered pressure drop predictions in good agreement with published data. The proposed model may also serve as an alternative to Mooney's method, when dealing with the annular lubricating layer effect characterising mixtures in Plug Flow.</description><creator>Bouzaiene, Riadh</creator><contributor>Scoble, Malcolm (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Hassani, Ferri (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>On the flow mechanics of mine backfill slurries in pipelines</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p226n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s4330</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p2676x61r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis represents an effort to examine certain aspects of the differentiation potential of normal and neoplastic (spontaneously- and chemically-transformed) cultured rat pancreatic ductal cells under the influence of two microenvironments. The technique of in vivo implantation of cells to subcutaneous and intraperitoneal sites is used as it not only reveals the intrinsic potential of the implanted cells but also reflects the effects of the microenvironment on phenotypic expression. The results of these studies indicate that when implanted in vivo normal propagable cultured cells derived from the duct epithelium of adult rat pancreas develop phenotypic features of a hepatocyte, and that the extent of this phenotypic expression is influenced by the microenvironment in which these cells are implanted. When localized subcutaneously, the cells displayed partial differentiation toward hepatocytes but retained some of their ductal phenotype. In contrast, when the same cells were implanted intraperitoneally, they expressed the full phenotypic properties of mature hepatocytes. Both spontaneously- and chemically-transformed pancreatic ductal cell lines did not display phenotypic differentiation along the hepatocytic lineage after in vivo implantation. It is concluded that (1) pancreatic ductal cells can be the progenitor cell for pancreatic hepatocytes; (2) Neoplastic transformation of these cell lines results in partial or total loss of hepatoctyic differentiation.</description><creator>Chen, Jim-Ray</creator><contributor>Duguid, W. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Tsao, M.-S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Hepatocytic differentiation of normal but not neoplastic cultured rat pancreatic duct cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wp66c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676x61r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w3763892j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Reverse micelles have been formed for the first time with a two tailed cationic surfactant, dioctyldimethyl ammonium chloride (DODMAC), in alcohol/isooctane mixtures. The effect of different alcohols and salts on water uptake of the DODMAC reverse micelles has been studied. The effects of pH and of the concentrations of amino acid, NaCl, DODMAC and l-decanol on the reverse micellar extraction of aspartic acid, glutamic acid and threonine from aqueous salt solutions were determined by phase contact experiments. The concentrations of all ionic species in the aqueous phase were measured and the corresponding concentrations inside the reverse micelles were obtained by material balances and the condition of electrical neutrality. The results show that the amino acids were mainly extracted through an ion exchange mechanism. Important factors which dominate the amino acid extraction are the net charge of amino acid, the competition among anions, the dissociation equilibrium of DODMAC and the water uptake in the reverse micelles. The ionic species in the reverse micelles tend toward their undissociated states as the water uptake by the reverse micelles decreases. The renormalization of Guggenheim's canonical partition function to satisfy the limits of order and disorder has been used to generate excess Gibbs energy models for liquid mixtures. Under well defined assumptions, the contributions to the activity coefficients arising from the new partition function correspond exactly with those given by existing semi-empirical models. A thermodynamic model has been developed to calculate the concentrations of all ionic species in both the aqueous and the reverse micellar phases. With this model it is possible to study the effect of changes of extraction variables, such as the concentrations of salt, surfactant and cosurfactant, in the extraction of amino acids by reverse micelles. The model has been tested by performing flash calculations for the system DODMAC, l-decanol isooctane, NaCl an amino acid and water. Three different amino acids were considered. The calculated results are in good agreement with the experimental data.</description><creator>Wang, Wenhua, 1960-</creator><contributor>Vera, Juan H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Reverse micellar extraction of amino acids using the two-tailed cationic surfactant DODMAC</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g696d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763892j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pq007</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Transverse energy and charged particle multiplicity produced in 14.6 GeV/c p + Al and p + Pb collisions have been studied using the E814 set-up at the BNL-AGS. Measurements of d$ sigma$/d$E sb{T}$, d$E sb{T}$/d$ eta$,d$ sigma$/d$N sb{c}$, and d$N sb{c}$/d$ eta$ are presented. From the present data the mean transverse energy per particle is obtained and it is compared to values observed in Si induced collisions at the same energy. In contrast to what is observed in nucleus-nucleus collisions, a very weak correlation is found between the transverse energy and the charged particle multiplicity. These results are compared to the predictions of various theoretical models used to describe heavy-ion collisions. The event generators RQMD and HIJET reproduce well the pseudorapidity distribution of both the transverse energy and charged particle multiplicity, whereas FRITIOF fails to reproduce the measured distributions. Contrary to what had been suggested previously in a Si + A study, the present study shows that the pseudorapidity dependence of charged particle multiplicity distributions do not follow KNO scaling.</description><creator>Wang, Gang, 1958 Nov. 28-</creator><contributor>Barrette, Jean (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><subject>Physics, Nuclear.</subject><title>Transverse energy and charged particle multiplicity in 14.6 GeVc proton-nucleus collisions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p908b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pq007</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tx08x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis theoretical investigations of quantum ballistic transport in semiconductor nanostructures is presented. Particular systems under consideration include quantum wire, quantum dot, and combinations of them. Effects of quantum interference, chaotic scattering, inelastic scattering, many-electron interaction, and junction resonance are examined. Conductance of the system is computed as a quantum scattering process, and fluctuations in conductance and magnetoconductance in ballistic structures are investigated in detail under the influence of the above mentioned physical effects. For the resonant transmission process, evidence is presented of the universal statistics satisfied by the quasi-bound states of the system which mediate the scattering. Computational framework is developed to solve the quantum scattering problem in multi-probe structures, and to include Coulomb interactions and other scattering potentials.</description><creator>Wang, Yongjiang.</creator><contributor>Guo, Hong (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Ballistic transport in semiconductor nanostructures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806181v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tx08x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290c45r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The determinants of repolarization in human atrium are poorly understood, and many discrepancies between basic research and clinical observations remain unexplained. This thesis presents a series of studies aimed: (1) to understand factors determining the occurrence of atrial arrhythmias; (2) to evaluate cellular mechanisms of drug actions on arrhythmias; (3) to determine ionic mechanisms controlling atrial repolarization. To achieve these goals we used approaches at three different levels: the whole animal level (with a mapping system), the cellular level (with microelectrode techniques), and the ionic level (with whole-cell patch-clamp techniques). Several antiarrhythmic agents have been used as pharmacological probes to study the mechanisms of drug action in arrhythmias, to assess the properties of desirable drug actions, and to explore the characteristics of drug-channel interactions. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Wang, Zhiguo, 1959-</creator><date>1994</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Determinants of atrial repolarization and arrhythmias</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fd71c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290c45r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20sv727</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Enantiomerically-pure compounds are becoming increasingly important particularly to the pharmaceutical industry. Enzymes are useful tools in the synthesis of such compounds. To better understand how lipases discriminate between enantiomers of chiral secondary alcohols we obtained x-ray crystal structures of covalent complexes of Candida rugosa lipase with the transition-state analogs (1R)-menthyl hexylphosphonate and (1S)-menthyl hexylphosphonate. These compounds are transition-state analogs for the hydrolysis of menthyl esters. We observed that the transition-state analog of the unfavored (1S)-enantiomer of menthol disrupted the hydrogen bond between N$ varepsilon$2 of histidine 449 and the menthol oxygen. His 449 is part of the catalytic triad in CRL. This may account for the slower reaction of the (1S)-enantiomer of menthol. The crystal structures also identified binding site regions for secondary alcohols in CRL. These regions are common among many lipases and esterases and account for their common enantiopreference toward secondary alcohols. Lipases and esterases can resolve compounds with phosphorus and sulfur stereocenters by hydrolysis of a pendant acetoxy group. Both CRL and cholesterol esterase have high selectivity for (2-acetoxy-1-naphthyl)methylphenylphosphine oxide. They resolved this substrate with and E of 81 and 32 respectively. A synthetic scale resolution of this substrate with subsequent recrystallization and chemical transformation followed by stereospecific reduction gave both enantiomers of (2-methoxy-1-naphthyl)methylphenyl-phosphine with 96-97% ee. This chiral phosphine is potentially useful in asymmetric syntheses. CE is the most selective enzyme for the sulfur substrates tested but these enantioselectivities were moderate, E's ranged from 5 to 25. From the CE resolution of the phosphorus and sulfur compounds and others we propose an empirical model that predicts which enatiomer reacts faster. The model is based on the size of the substituents and their conformational preferences. Crude Aspergillus niger resolves esters of pipecolic acid with an E of 20 $ pm$ 4. A simple partial purification of ANL by fractional precipitation with ammonium sulfate increased the enantioselectivity to $&gt;$100. The partially purified ANL can be used in a synthetic scale resolution of ($ pm$)-n-octyl pipecolate to give (S)-($-$)-pipecolic acid (93% ee) and (R)-(+)-pipecolic acid (97% ee).</description><creator>Serreqi, Alessio N.</creator><date>1994</date><subject>Chemistry, Pharmaceutical.</subject><title>Hydrolase catalyzed resolutions of enantiomers : a structural basis for the chiral preference of lipases : preparation of enantiomerically-pure phosphines, phospine oxides, sulfoxides and pipecolic acid</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773x63j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20sv727</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zg46c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation examines the possible impact of direct political participation by urban popular movements at the level of local government. It is argued that these movements harbour a democratic potential, which is contained in their social, cultural, and political practices, as well as in the collective identities of their participants. The relevance of this democratic potential derives from the fact that it could serve to democratize other political actors, particularly political parties, and to render local political institutions more democratic and efficient, depending on three conditions. First, effective political decentralization has to result in the creation of institutional openings for popular participation at the local level. Second, in order to overcome their various limitations and to project their potential for change into the political arena, urban popular movements have to form alliances with other actors, particularly political parties. Third, since such alliances often result in cooptive pressures, urban popular movements should strive to form multiple alliances with more than one actor in order to better preserve their autonomy. In the second part of the dissertation, this theoretical framework is applied to a study of popular participation at different levels of local government in Lima, Peru. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Schönwälder, Gerd</creator><contributor>Oxhorn, Philip (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Local government -- Peru</subject><subject>Peru -- Politics and government</subject><title>Urban popular movements, political parties, and the state in post-authoritarian Peru : the local government nexus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r9675642.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zg46c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mk84j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study quantifies electromyographic variables in one and two degree of freedom elbow movements involving flexion/extension and pronation/supination, in order to understand the associated central commands. Agonist burst magnitude varied with motion in a second degree of freedom for some muscles but not for others. In movements for which a biarticular muscle acted as agonist in two degrees of freedom, agonist burst magnitudes were approximately the sum of the magnitudes in the component movements. Agonist burst magnitude varied with motion in a second degree of freedom for some, but not all, monoarticular muscles. When biarticular muscles acted as agonist in one degree of freedom and antagonist in the other, the muscle often displayed both components simultaneously. The additivity of EMG burst magnitudes in two degree of freedom movements and the presence of both agonist and antagonist bursts in a muscle suggest that central commands associated with motion in individual degrees of freedom are superimposed in producing two degree of freedom movements.</description><creator>Sergio, Lauren E. (Lauren Elisabeth)</creator><contributor>Ostry, David J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Human mechanics.</subject><subject>Electromyography.</subject><subject>Elbow -- Muscles.</subject><subject>Joints -- Range of motion.</subject><title>Coordination of multiple muscles in two degree of freedom elbow movements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35tb39m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mk84j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v490r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The satisfactory measurement of banking output has eluded statistical agencies since the inception of national income accounting. At the heart of the problem is the treatment of interest. Net interest payments are considered part of the output originating in the paying industries. When applied to the banking sector this practice results in unrealistically low or even negative output and an imputation is carried out to rectify the problem. This thesis identifies the problems surrounding the existing concepts and practices, discusses alternatives that have been proposed and develops a new approach to measuring banking output. The rate of interest is decomposed into a transfer and a service part and economic prices for banking services are constructed. Thus, nominal and real banking output are obtained in a straightforward manner. Empirical work points to the viability of the new approach.</description><creator>Sciadas, George</creator><contributor>Handa, Jagdish (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Interest</subject><subject>Banks and banking</subject><title>The measurement of banking output and the treatment of interest in the system of national accounts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rn222.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v490r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:08612q60f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Masai Mara, a large nature reserve in south-western Kenya, was created in the midst of semi-arid agropastoralist rangelands to protect wildlife. Wildlife and indigenous people co-existed for many years, usually with limited conflict; but in recent years, the conflict has intensified, mainly due to increasing human population, changing land use patterns, and altered perceptions of wildlife. This study examines the causes and nature of wildlife-human conflict in the Masai rangelands of Kenya, and considers how wildlife conservation and human development needs can best be integrated. Findings indicate that common conflicts are livestock depredation and crop damage, human deaths or injuries, transmission of diseases, and competition for resources. Land surrounding the reserve can be divided into two distinct topographic and agroclimatic regions. The degree of conflict is spatially varied within the region. Upland ranches have high land use potential, high human and livestock population densities, and more development of agriculture. They experience limited conflict with wildlife. Lowland ranches are more arid, have lower human population density and little agriculture, but have high wildlife and livestock population densities and experience a high degree of conflict. These conflicts vary seasonally, and with distance from the protected area. Perceptions of wildlife and attitudes towards conservation are related to past experience with wildlife. The degree of loss, effectiveness of damage control, fairness of government compensation, and involvement in wildlife tourism affect the degree of tolerance for wildlife conflict. Various socio-economic factors including level of education, knowledge of conservation priorities, and system of land ownership are related to attitudes towards wildlife. As human activity increases in the region, wildlife is more likely to be displaced. Because most animals are migratory, conflict in the land surrounding the reserve puts the viability of animal population in the protected area in question. A two-phase program for integrating wildlife conservation with human needs is proposed. The first phase involves designation of the region into four zones: Zone A--the protected area, Zone B--the peripheral area, Zone C--multiple use, and Zone D--agriculture. The second phase of the program is the integration of the wildlife conservation with human interests through: community wildlife-damage-control, compensation for loss, sharing of tourism benefits with local people, conservation education, and local participation in wildlife conservation policy. The program provides a framework within which operational decisions can be made, and serves broader natural resource management and community development objectives in the rangelands.</description><creator>Omondi, Paul</creator><contributor>Meredith, T. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Masai (African people) -- Social conditions</subject><subject>Human-animal relationships -- Kenya -- Masai Mara National Reserve</subject><subject>Wildlife conservation -- Kenya -- Masai Mara National Reserve</subject><subject>Masai (African people) -- Economic conditions</subject><subject>Human ecology -- Kenya -- Masai Mara National Reserve</subject><title>Wildlife-human conflict in Kenya : integrating wildlife conservation with human needs in the Masai Mara Region</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j740x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612q60f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s204c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis pieces together the years of Jacques Ferron's intellectual development, from 1921 to 1949, through both biographical (contextualisation of the author's life) and institutional (emergence strategies and literary creations) approaches, and through an analysis of the autobiographical and of descriptions of childhood memories in his works. The first section focuses on the writer's childhood. Product of both the liberal bourgeoisie and of a rural society, Jacques Ferron inherits a certain mistrust regarding nationalism; however, born in an era where the elite had a great deal of influence over local culture, he is influenced by this trend. In the second section, the author's adolescence is examined, along with his years of study at College Jean-de-Brebeuf. This period of his life briefly emphasizes his "aristocratic" leanings and accentuates, against the attitude of the time, his predispositions towards individualism. His appreciation of beauty leads to a loss of interest in politics, and his early literary essays take no political stand whatsoever. The third part concerns the tumultuous years which precede the settling down of Dr. Ferron in Longueuil. In 1941, the young man enrolls in medical school at Laval University, and then spends a year in the Canadian army; discharged in 1946, he moves to Gaspesie. His first stories, born of a tension between the two cultural universes that influenced his sensibility, are from this period. Faced with poverty, all around him, he declares himself a Communist and from this moment on, considers it essential that the elite give up their privileges and stand up for the most destitute around them. The autobiographical, in Ferron's works, will be coloured by these choices made in his youth. The author often evokes his childhood through self-analysis; he does not speak willingly of his years of study, nor of his stay in the army, but deals abundantly with his years in Gaspesie. It turns out, all things considered, that this literary "revisionism" is the very form of literary creation found in this author's works. The journey of young Ferron illustrate the paradox of a man born in a well-to-do family, taught to appreciate fine art, predestined to an uneventful career, and who one day turns away from this destiny owing to his social convictions.</description><creator>Olscamp, Marcel</creator><contributor>Lamonde, Yvan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Ferron, Jacques -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>Ferron, Jacques</subject><title>Le jeune Ferron : genèse d'un écrivain québécois, (1921-1949)</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193b883.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s204c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860883t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study has two major goals: first it reconstructs the history of travel-literature from the Middle Ages to the 19th century with a special focus on the role of women, second it attempts to analyse and evaluate travel-accounts by women who travelled to the Orient in the 19th century (Engel-Egli, Forneris, Pfeiffer, Hahn-Hahn and Muhlbach). The reconstruction of the history of travel and travel-literature up to the 18th century shows that it was possible for women to travel with relative freedom. With the polarization of gender-roles in the last third of the 18th century, however, women were declared 'unfit for travel' and confined to their homes. Due to this development, travel-accounts by women travelling to the Orient, that were written in the middle of the 19th century, have to fulfil a special function. Besides representing an attempt to reestablish the tradition of female travellers that had been suppressed from the middle of the 18th century on, travelling to the Orient meant that the female authors in question had access to areas and spaces that were both off limits to their male counterparts (i.e. the harem) and charged with sexually connoted images. Forneris,' Pfeiffer's and Hahn-Hahn's statements can be interpreted as a conscious attempt to criticize European man through the deconstruction of the images of the Oriental femme fatale in two ways: the first criticism is that they present themselves as authorities with regard to the domain of the Oriental woman. The second occurs through consciously creating grotesque anti-images, whereby women turn the "oriental dream" of their male contemporaries into a nightmare. This act of turning the images into their opposite happens without taking into account the culturally different woman. She has been reduced to the status of an object by women travelling to the Orient exactly in the same manner as male colleagues reduced them. In addition, this analysis gives special consideration to much discussed 19th century elements of racial theories which found their way into the travel accounts.</description><creator>Ohnesorg, Stefanie</creator><contributor>Goldsmith-Reber, Trudis E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Orient -- In literature</subject><subject>Travel in literature</subject><subject>Women travelers</subject><title>Sie zogen in die Fremde und fanden sich selbst : Neubewertung der Orient-Reiseberichte von Frauen aus dem 19. Jahrhundert vor dem Hintergrund der Geschichte des Reisens und der Reiseliteratur</title><language>ger</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sr91c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860883t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of German Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:05741t69p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The osmotic control of neurohypophysial hormone release is mediated by central and peripheral osmoreceptors which perceive changes in fluid osmolality. The mechanism underlying signal transduction in these structures, however, has remained obscure. Supraoptic neurons, which synthesize and secrete the neurohypophysial hormones, are themselves recognized to be osmoreceptors. Combined electrophysiological and micromorphometric measurements were therefore obtained in acutely isolated rat supraoptic neurons to determine the cellular basis for signal transduction in osmoreception. Osmotically-evoked changes in cell volume and a gadolinium-sensitive cationic conductance were found to be temporally and proportionally related. In agreement, cell-attached patch-clamp recordings revealed the presence of gadolinium-sensitive cationic channels modulated in response to osmotic stimuli. The mean closed time of these channels was found to increase as a function of changes in membrane tension mediated either by external osmotic perturbation, or by application of pressure inside the patch pipette. The ionic selectivity, density, mechanosensitivity, and pharmacological properties of these channels are consistent with an involvement in the mechanism underlying osmosreception in supraoptic neurons.</description><creator>Oliet, Stéphane H. R.</creator><contributor>Bourque, C. W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Osmoreception in rat supraoptic neurons</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sr903.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741t69p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tn90b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In Radio Detection and Ranging, the inverse problem is that of acquiring knowledge of the physical features of a body by making observations of the reflected energy and synthesising the model from the measured data. This procedure is in contrast to the forward problem, which consists of calculating the observable effects from a given model. The forward problem has unique solution whereas the inverse process, being carried out on the basis of hypotheses, is always characterized by a lack of uniqueness. The approach taken towards developing the synthesis framework is to consider a logic argumentation of belief functions which is used to represent the various symbolic aspects of belief and uncertainty. The logic extends so that not just one argument, but all arguments, supporting or opposing a hypothesis are considered. That is the logic used to solve the inverse problem. As arguments are identified among measurements, the support they confer on a hypothesis or its negation is aggregated to provide a measure of the degree of belief in the hypotheses of interest. The aggregation operation, or the synthesis regularization, will depend on an entropy calculation to represent the uncertainty associated with the arguments. Based on the theory of Kalman filters, sensor fusion is used to finally establish probabilistic models of the hypotheses. In conjunction with the synthesis regularization, consistent estimates will converge to a qualitative image reconstruction. The synthesis framework is compared to current solutions to the inverse problem in radio detection and ranging and applied to Ground Penetrating Radar image reconstruction.</description><creator>Maluf, David Ameen</creator><contributor>Daneshmend, L. K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>World modeling in radar : a regularization by synthesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj1393954.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tn90b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn107096w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, a new approach to the design of digital control systems is introduced. In particular, three new methods are presented, two for the digital redesign of a pre-designed analog control system, and one for the digital implementation of a pre-specified continuous-time reference model. The proposed approach is based on the novel idea of relating digital and analog control systems through their plant-input transfer functions, i.e., the transfer function from the command input to the plant input. The main advantages of the new approach are the guaranteed closed-loop stability for almost all sampling periods, and the recovery of the continuous-time performance when the sampling period approaches zero. The effectiveness of the proposed approach is illustrated by applying it to some famous example, borrowed form other references for the purpose of comparison. The proposed approach is applicable to multi-input multi-output, unstable and non-minimum-phase plants, as long as a suitable analog controller exists. As far as the author of this thesis is aware, such generality is not available with other existing methods. Since discrete-time models of continuous-time transfer functions play an important role in the proposed approach, a new characterization of these models is also present in this thesis.</description><creator>Markazi, Amir H. D. (Amir Hossein Davaie)</creator><contributor>Hori, Noriyuki (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>A new approach to the digital implementation of analog controllers and continuous-time reference models</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cz491.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn107096w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vx021h14m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Vesicle (exosome) externalization is a mechanism for removal of obsolescent membrane proteins, such as the transferrin receptor (TFR), during reticulocyte maturation. This thesis involves further characterization of the exosomal phenomenon using avian (nucleated) and mammalian erythroid systems. Chicken reticulocytes release exosomes, indicating independence of this process from enucleation. Exosome release during chicken erythroleukemic cell (HD3) differentiation (representing pre-reticulocyte development) demonstrates that this process commences prior to the reticulocyte stage. The heat shock protein, hsp70, has been found in exosomes from every species examined (four species, including the chicken). It is shown that hsp70 is physically, but non-covalently, associated with exosomal TFR, suggesting its possible involvement in targeting proteins into exosomes during their formation. Exosome formation is an energy-dependent process. Our observations indicate that the primary energy substrate for avian red cells is not glucose, but glutamine, inosine and guanosine. Work with the HD3 cells (capable of glucose transport), suggests there is an early differentiation-associated switch in the chicken red cell's ability to use glucose as a major energy substrate.</description><creator>Mathew, Anu</creator><contributor>Johnstone, R. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Selective loss of protein and exosome formation during erythroid maturation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r0377.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021h14m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50gz02w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis stresses the existence of a fundamental link between potential competition and multi-product activity. Potential competitors are identified as already-existing firms that possess "latent capacity", a principal source of scope economies, which enable firms to expand or alter their product portfolio in the short period. When latent capacity is accompanied by certain sunk costs, hit-and-run entry becomes profitable as the "latent competitor" is able to easily surmount the major barriers to entry, avoid the disadvantages in cost associated with small batch production, and exit cheaply from the various markets. This new theory of potential competition further demonstrates that when framed within a multi-product environment, the major criticisms that are levelled against the theory of contestability can be addressed. Additionally, it shows how the age-old conundrum of increasing returns and competitive behaviour may be reconciled. Empirical evidence confirms the existence of latent capacity. Such capacity is embodied in the Flexible Manufacturing Systems (FMS) and flexible manpower resources that are increasingly being employed by firms.</description><creator>Mahabir, Dhanayshar</creator><contributor>Rowley, J. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Competition</subject><subject>Commercial products</subject><title>Potential competition and multi-product activity</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m129c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gz02w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn301330w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, dynamics and control of multi-body tethered satellite systems are investigated. First a dynamical model is developed that takes into account the three dimensional librational motion of the system as well as the nonlinear vibrations of the tethers, both in longitudinal and transverse directions. The assumed modes method is used to discretize the continuous tethers. Using Lagrange's equations, splitting the vector of generalized coordinates to a set of subvectors, where each subvector corresponds to a specific tether, a set of nonlinear ordinary differential equations governing the motion of the system is obtained in the explicit analytical form. A fourth order strain energy expression is used in the formulation to allow the possibility of moderately large deformation of the tethers. The equations are applicable whether the length of the tethers are constant (station-keeping phase) or changing with time (deployment and retrieval phases). They are transformed into vector form for simulation purposes. Among the external forces, the aerodynamic forces and their effects on the dynamics and stability of the system are given more attention. The free molecular flow model is used to calculate the aerodynamic forces resulting from the material damping of the tethers are considered in this investigation. These forces, which are very difficult to model accurately, are modelled using a viscous damping model. Equilibrium configurations of the system, as special solutions of the equations of motion, in the absence or presence of the aerodynamic forces, are studied in more detail. A closed form solution to the static equilibrium equations is obtained when there is no external force acting on the system other than the gravitational force. The set of nonlinear equations of motion is then linearized analytically about a particular equilibrium configuration for stability and eigenvalue analysis. The natural frequencies of some single-tether as well as multi-tether systems are calculated using these linearized equations. Stability of a single-tether system in low orbit missions is investigated, ignoring the aerodynamic forces on the main-satellite as well as on the tether. Assuming a particular geometrical configuration for the subsatellite and using the linearized equations, the effect of the aerodynamic forces, particularly aerodynamic lift, on the stability of the system as well as the equilibrium configuration of the system is examined through the eigenvalue analysis. This analysis is then extended to multi-body systems. Finally the problem of controlling the nonlinear system through the application of Lyapunov's stability theory is examined for multi-body tethered systems, ignoring the transverse oscillations of the tethers. Initially, based on the Hamiltonian of the system, a Lyapunov function is introduced for a system with massless and rigid tethers. It leads to a linear tension control law. When the mass of the tethers is taken into account the Lyapunov function is modified and a new tension control law is developed which is no longer linear. With the assumption that the longitudinal oscillations of the tethers are small compared to the length of the tethers, a Lyapunov functions is constructed for systems with elastic tethers. At the end, a hybrid control law is examined to improve the performance of the controlled system.</description><creator>Keshmiri, Mehdi</creator><contributor>Misra, Arun K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><title>Dynamics and control of multi-body tethered satellite systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m1304.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301330w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j6731588f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>HVDC wall bushings constitute a basic component of converter stations and their adequate performance is vital to insure a highly reliable level of operation. Service records show that the number of flashovers in converter stations has increased substantially during recent years and that the majority of flashovers occurred on HVDC wall bushings. This work presents the first mathematical model to provide the necessary and sufficient conditions for flashover of HVDC wall bushings under nonuniform wetting. The model suggests that the onset of streamers bridging the dry zone and initiated by the nonuniform voltage distribution along the bushing triggers the process of flashover. Fast voltage collapse across the dry zone due to the energy stored in the bushing internal and external leakage and stray capacitance leads to impulsive stressing of the wet part of the bushing. The nonuniform distribution of that impulse and the process of streamer bridging, fast voltage collapse as well as subsequent recharging of the bushing capacitance may lead to consequent discharges and arc propagation along the bushing and eventually to a complete flashover. The random processes associated with the wetting dynamics and pattern as well as the air gaps breakdowns are accounted for in a novel statistical approach to model the flashover process of the HVDC wall bushings under the proposed mechanism. The work is supported by an experimental investigation into surface resistance and minimum flashover stress of full scale HVDC wall bushings under nonuniform rain. The findings of the model have been satisfactorily compared with experiments and field observations and can for the first time account for the following aspects of flashover mechanism: critical dry zone length, polarity effect, specific leakage length, wet layer conductance, dry zone position as well as DC system voltage. The model was also used to assess the performance of RTV coated bushings and to compare the strength or an SF$ sb6$ bushing to that of a conventional oil-paper design under nonuniform rain.</description><creator>Kamel, Sherif I. (Sherif Ibrahim)</creator><contributor>Rizk, F. A. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Mathematical modeling of wet flashover mechanism of HVDC wall bushings</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580p472.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j6731588f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558g172</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:51:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette recherche comprend l'etude de la bioacatalyse de la chlorophyllase partiellement purifiee a partir d'algue (Phaeodactylum tricornutum) dans differents milieux organiques incluant les solvants miscibles et non miscibles a l'eau et les systemes micellaires tertiaires. Les quantites optimales d'eau et de solvant, choisi en fonction de son degre d'hydrophobicite et incluant l'acetone, l'ethanol, le propanol, le butanol, le pentanol, l'hexanol, le toluene, le pentane, l'hexane, l'heptane et l'octane, necessaire a la catalyse de l'effet hydrolytique de la chlorophyllase, ont ete mesurees. Les valeurs d $V sb{ rm max}$ obtenues mesurant l'activite hydrolytique de la chlorophyllase sont plus elevees chez les solvants miscibles a l'eau (log P  0.8). L'activite hydrolytique de la chlorophyllase decroit d'approximativement 12 fois lorsque le nombre de carbone pour les alcools, passent de 2 a 5. Certains resultats a partir du FTIR ("Fourier transform infrared spectroscopy") tendent a montrer que le phytol pourrait agir comme un donneur d'electron, ainsi, si un compose nucleophilique approprie est ajoute a un syteme biphasique, la solubilite de la chlorophylle dans l'hexane augmentera et l'activite hydrolytique de la chlorophyllase augmentera. En milieu biphasique (hexane/eau), l'addition de solvants polaires tels que l'acetone, l'ethanol, et le propanol augmente l'activite de la chlorophyllase et ce seulement a certaines concentrations. La mesure optimale de l'activite hydrolytique de la chlorophyllase en milieu micellaire tertiaire (tampon/hexane/surfactant) utilisant les polysorbates et les Spans ainsi que differentes chai nes hydrophobiques comme surfactant indique que les concentrations necessaires de surfactants sont dependantes a la fois de la chai ne hydrophobique et du groupement polaire. Toutefois, l'utilisation du Span 85 s'est avere plus approprie et les valeurs de $V sb{ rm max}$ obtenues mesurant l'activite enzymatique de la chlorophyllase sont 288 fois</description><creator>Khamessan, Ali</creator><contributor>Kermasha, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Chlorophyll.</subject><subject>Plant enzymes.</subject><title>Chlorophyllase biocatalysis of chlorophyll in organic solvent media</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jq69v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558g172</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):38525</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>