<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:41:22Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):39600" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j6731573t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background. Otitis media with effusion (OME) is more common in atopic children. Few studies have looked for the presence of inflammatory mediators in the middle ear effusions of this population. Objectives. We hypothesize that atopic children with OME have a different inflammatory cell and cytokine profile than non-atopic children with the disease. Methods. The atopic status of 26 children with OME was determined. Using immunocytochemistry, fluid specimens were assessed for T lymphocytes, eosinophils, neutrophils, mast cells, and basophils. The expression of IL-4, II.-5, and IFN-gamma mRNA was assessed using in-situ hybridization. Results. There is a higher percentage of eosinophils, T lymphocytes and cells expressing IL-4 and IL-5 mRNA in atopic children (n = 8) compared to non-atopic controls (n = 18) (p &lt; 0.01). Conclusion. The predominance of eosinophils, T lymphocytes and Th2 mediators in the middle ear effusions of atopic children provides strong evidence that atopy plays a role in the pathogenesis of this condition.</description><creator>Sobol, Steven E.</creator><contributor>Hamid, Qutayba (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Audiology.</subject><title>Th2 cytokine expression in atopic children with otitis media with effusion</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s194b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j6731573t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Otolaryngology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tx31qk628</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objectives of the present study were to examine the effects of dietary fat type and level of energy intake on hypothalamic leptin binding affinity and membrane fatty acid composition, circulating leptin levels, and body weight homeostasis in rats. Animals were fed diets containing tallow, safflower oil, or menhaden oil (20% wt/wt) for 10 wks, ad libitum or at 60% of ad libitum intakes. Specific leptin binding could not be detected in hypothalamic membrane homogenates; hypothalamic leptin levels were unaffected by diet or energy intake. Levels of tracer exceeding assay reference values were found in homogenates, suggesting intra-membrane binding. Excess tracer levels were weakly associated (p &lt; 0.07) with the sum of hypothalamic phospholipid monounsaturates. Restriction lowered weight gain and food intakes (p &lt; 0.0001 for both). In hypothalamic phospholipids, energy restriction lowered levels of 18:3(n-3) and increased levels of 20:1(n-9), 20:4(n-6), and 22:4(n-6) (p &lt; 0.05, p &lt; 0.02, p &lt; 0.05, and p &lt; 0.04, respectively). Fat type and energy level interactively affected hypothalamic levels of 20:4(n-6), 22:5(n-3) and 22:6(n-3) (p &lt; 0.05, p &lt; 0.006, and p &lt; 0.05, respectively). Restriction lowered circulating leptin levels (p &lt; 0.0001); overall plasma leptin levels were marginally associated (p &lt; 0.07) with hypothalamic 16:0 concentrations. The results of the study support previous findings suggesting that leptin binding at the level of the hypothalamic membrane may not be detectable. The results also support the lack of a dietary fat effect on plasma leptin levels and levels of certain hypothalamic fatty acids, such as 20:4(n-6), 22:4(n-6), and 22:5(n-3), with energy restriction. The findings of the study suggest a link between increased membrane fluidity, increased binding affinity, and lower circulating leptin levels, promoting the possibility that the biological actions of leptin can be controlled through dietary effects on</description><creator>Heshka, Jodi T.</creator><contributor>Jones, Peter J. H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Hypothalamus.</subject><subject>Leptin.</subject><subject>Lipids in human nutrition.</subject><title>Effects of dietary fat type and energy restriction on hypothalamic membrane structure and leptin receptor function</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059c9348.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qk628</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4f16c447k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>To evaluate why discordance may occur between regression coefficients from cross sectional and longitudinal analyses when ventilatory function is related to ageing, a population was created by computer, and modelled to simulate functional change during life. The program incorporated the effects of many factors known to influence lung function measurements, which were adjusted experimentally so that their contributions to any discordance could be assessed. Regression analyses showed that significant discordance could be induced if the oldest birth cohort failed to reach the same maximal level of function as the youngest; if a quadratic ageing term was excluded from the independent regression variables; or if the effects of certain confounders were present. Discordance occurred additionally if cross sectional estimates became imprecise, but then the differences (often marked) from longitudinal estimates were not significant. It is concluded that discordance may be fundamental and unavoidable (though explicable), or merely a consequence of imprecision.</description><creator>Hendrick, David J.</creator><contributor>Becklake, M. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Hanley, J. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Human Development.</subject><title>Discordance between cross sectional and longitudinal estimates for the effect of ageing on lung function</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f5329.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c447k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Occupational Health</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn301314h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>White blood cell phagocytosis was investigated and used with avian blood, and assessed as a potential biomarker for mercury immunotoxicity in free ranging birds (common loons). Phagocytosis is an essential immunological function and can be measured using flow cytometry. The assay was assessed with in vitro exposure using whole blood and isolated white blood cells (WBC) from domestic chickens, and with in vivo exposure using whole blood from captive doves and wild loons. McHg at 0.1ppm significantly depressed phagocytic capacity of isolated WBCs without affecting their viability, but did not affect phagocytic activity when added to whole blood up to 50ppm. Also, no significant relationship between blood-Hg level and phagocytic capacity of WBCs was observed in ringed turtle doves fed McHg in their diets, nor in wild common loons having a range of blood-Hg concentrations. The phagocytosis assay is a convenient assay for use in field studies of free-living birds, but is not responsive to McHg exposure in birds, and so is not recommended as a biomarker of immunotoxicity in Hg-exposed loons.</description><creator>Holloway, Jennifer C.</creator><contributor>Chan, Laurie (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Common loon -- Effect of water pollution on.</subject><subject>Phagocytosis.</subject><subject>Immunotoxicology.</subject><subject>Biochemical markers.</subject><subject>Methylmercury -- Toxicology.</subject><title>Investigation of white blood cell phagocytosis as a potential bio-marker of mercury immunotoxicity in birds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623f400.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301314h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:00000195r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Objective measurement of the subglottic lumen is still lacking in clinical practice. The objective of this study is to evaluate the accuracy of ultrasound and video-bronchoscopy in measuring the subglottic diameter in the pediatric population. This was a blind, prospective clinical study. Ten children undergoing non-life threatening bronchoscopy had their subglottic diameters measured with ultrasound, video-bronchoscopy and endotracheal tube sizing. Ultrasound and video-bronchoscopy strongly correlated with endotracheal tube sizing in measuring the subglottic diameter. Ultrasound had measurements that were always smaller while video-bronchoscopy had measurements that were slightly larger than endotracheal tube sizing. Video-bronchoscopy may be more accurate than endotracheal tube sizing as the latter method will often underestimate the size of the lumen due to its own limitations. The smaller values obtained by ultrasound suggest it is not ideal to give absolute measurements in this area, but rather a potential tool to detect change of lumen size on follow-up.</description><creator>Husein, Murad.</creator><contributor>Platt, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Manoukian, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Ultrasound and video-bronchoscopy to assess the subglottic diameter in the pediatric population Dr. Murad Husein.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q594q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000195r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Otolaryngology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311r17s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation describes the characterization of polystyrene- b-poly(acrylic acid) (PS-b-PAA) copolymer micelles by nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy (NMR). The segmental chain dynamics of the polystyrene-b-poly(acrylic acid) copolymer during the micellization process was investigated by solution-state proton NMR measurements. The spin-lattice and spin-spin relaxation parameters revealed the increased motional restriction of the PS blocks of the PS-b-PAA copolymer as aggregation was induced. The mobility of the PAA segments also decreased during the micellization process. However, the PAA blocks experienced greater motional freedom than the PS component forming the aggregate core. 129Xenon NMR spectroscopy was used to determine the glass transition temperature of the PS core of the polystyrene-b-poly(acrylic acid) copolymer aggregates in dioxane/water mixtures. The temperature dependence of the NMR line shapes and resonance shifts of xenon in the PS and solvent phases of the PS-b-PAA copolymer micelles was analyzed. Discontinuities in the slope of the chemical shift-temperature curves for xenon sorbed in the PS component revealed phase transitions in the copolymer micelles. The PS core of the phase separated PS100-b-PAA 25 copolymer aggregates underwent the glass transition in the temperature region of 40°C to 45°C. The glass transition temperature of the PS core of PS218-b-PAA20 copolymer aggregates suspended in solution was in the 33°C to 35°C temperature region.</description><creator>Chijiwa, Sachiko.</creator><contributor>Eisenberg, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Reven, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>Characterization of polystyrene-b-poly(acrylic acid) copolymer micelles by nuclear magnetic resonance spectroscopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b2904.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311r17s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62fb11r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Laboratory studies on speciation have revealed that selection must be disruptively applied on traits related to the mating system in order to produce deviations from random mating in experimental populations. One problem with these experiments, however, has been the complexity of the model organism used, most frequently Drosophila species. Due to the multi genic nature of the mating systems of such organisms, it has been difficult to obtain the necessary gene combinations that result in complete sexual isolation. In the present study, I have used a simple sexual organism, the unicellular green algae Chlamydomonas reinhardtii, as a model for ecological and sexual differentiation. Disruptive selection was applied on the flagella, by selecting simultaneously for photo taxis and mating, behaviours for which these organelles are of fundamental importance. An asymmetric response to selection for photo taxis and zygote production was obtained in populations selected for conditions at opposite ends of the environmental spectrum used, differentiating these two populations in both movement capacity and mating efficiency. These results are discussed in relation to previous experiments on speciation and to the implications of future experimental studies on the same subject.</description><creator>Chao, Vincent, 1973-</creator><contributor>Bell, Graham (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Chlamydomonas reinhardtii -- Reproduction.</subject><subject>Chlamydomonas reinhardtii -- Genetics.</subject><title>Ecological and sexual divergence in experimental populations of Chlamydomonas</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w4163.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fb11r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8k71nj945</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Distraction osteogenesis is a form of in vivo tissue engineering used to lengthen bone. Bone morphogenetic proteins (BMPs) are known mediators of bone formation during the distraction of enchondral bones. Their role in the distraction of membranous bones remains unknown. A rabbit model was used to characterize the expression of BMP-2, 4 and 7 during mandibular distraction osteogenesis. Fourteen animals were subjected to a defined distraction protocol. At weekly intervals, two rabbits were sacrificed and the generate bone harvested for radiographic, bone densitometric, histologic and immunohistochemical analyses. The results demonstrate that during distraction, bane forms primarily by intramembranous ossification. BMP-2 and 4 were maximally expressed in osteoblastic cells during the distraction period and in chondrocytes during the consolidation period. The pattern of mandibular BMP expression was different than previously described for long bones. Understanding the pattern of BMP expression may guide the strategic administration of recombinant BMPs to enhance the rate and quality of bone formation during distraction osteogenesis thereby shortening the time required for consolidation of the generate bone.</description><creator>Campisi, Paolo.</creator><contributor>Lessard, M. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Characterization of the expression of bone morphogenetic proteins during distraction osteogenesis of the mandible</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh40w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8k71nj945</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Otolaryngology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9c67wp59z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background. beta-blockers have been the cornerstone of therapy for hypertension for at least 20 years. The use of newer agents including calcium antagonists and ACE inhibitors is increasing. Objective. To examine whether calcium antagonists and ACE inhibitors independently are associated with increased all-cause and cause-specific mortality relative to beta-blockers. Methods. This was a population-based cohort study. Within the cohort, a nested case-control approach was used for analysis. We used Saskatchewan Health databases. A cohort of 19,501 subjects initiating therapy for uncomplicated hypertension between January 1st, 1990 and December 31st, 1993 was identified. Cases were all deaths between January 1st, 1990 and April 1st, 1997. Cause of death was determined and coded according to ICD-9 as abstracted from the death certificate, specifically identifying cardiovascular disease, coronary heart disease and stroke. Five controls were matched to each case on entry date and time at risk of an event. Current use of antihypertensive drugs was defined as drugs dispensed within 90 days prior to the event date. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Cao, Zhenyuan, 1967-</creator><contributor>Ernst, Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Mortality with different antihypertensive agents</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644t332.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9c67wp59z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3j333418q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A field trial was conducted to demonstrate the applicability of a self-boring pressuremeter probe for in situ testing of cemented paste backfill. This technology proved to be efficient in evaluating behaviour of in situ conditions of mine backfill underground. Effectively, laboratory experience shows that it is not possible to insure that all physical and mechanical conditions prevailing underground are respected when samples are prepared and tested in the lab. Moreover, sampling by coring backfill underground proved to be sometimes not very efficient and the question of sample disturbance is a major concern. This thesis aims at presenting the considerations leading to the probe selection and the technical aspects related to conducting pressuremeter tests in an underground mine. A preliminary analysis of the experimental pressuremeter curves is presented with the derived in situ properties obtained from a paste backfill in a Canadian mine. It is shown that the selected instrument fulfilled the main objective of the project, which was the in situ characterization of a paste backfill. Recommendations are given for future applications of this testing technique for mine backfill and improve the efficiency of the work underground. Also, recommendations are given to improve test analysis and consequently the quality of the results obtained with the self-boring pressuremeter technique.</description><creator>Servant, Stéphane.</creator><contributor>Ouellet, Jacques (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Determination des parametres mecaniques des remblais miniers faits de residus cimentes</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rw289.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3j333418q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v730c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>All solid-state switches and attenuators are becoming increasingly popular over their mechanical counterparts. Their advantages include smaller size, no moving parts, and faster response times. The device presented here is a silicon on insulator waveguide attenuator, its operation is based on free-carrier absorption of photons. Free-carriers are provided by forward biasing a PIN diode structure integrated in a single mode rib waveguide where the guided mode propagates in the intrinsic region. The device was optimized optically using CAD tools to provide off-state losses of less than 1dB. The PIN diode electrical structure was also optimized to for a maximum power consumption of 1W at maximum attenuation. Good agreement of the theory developed was found when compared to experimental measurements of fabricated prototypes of similar structure. Fabrication and testing of devices according to the specifications arrived at in this thesis is suggested for future work.</description><creator>Wilson, Cynthia, 1974-</creator><contributor>Keyworth, Barrie (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Plant, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>A free-carrier based silicon on insulator waveguide attenuator /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h138k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v730c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053h889</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>I present a distributed vision system for testing and development of computer vision algorithms. The system's form follows a new approach to the construction of vision systems. Utilizing streaming video interconnects and distributed computer resources, the system provides researchers with sufficient processing power to run complex algorithms under real-time constraints. The system runs algorithms in a pipelined mariner, with data passed between functional units using streaming video protocols. DirectShow forms the basis for the system's processing block objects. Researchers can configure the system using functional units from a library of source, rendering, and transform processing blocks available on the system. To aid in configuring the system to the specifications of a given task, I have developed a system management tool that allows the user to configure the system via interaction with a web-based Java applet. This presents the user with a simple, object-oriented framework that is robust and easy to manage.</description><creator>Sidloi, Mark.</creator><contributor>Clark, James J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>A distributed vision system using streaming video interconnects /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kc47f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053h889</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sj10g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis deals with market rules that define the price and the generation schedule in electricity markets. The research has focused on three approaches: Pool Cost Minimization (PCM) with marginal pricing, Consumer Payment Minimization (CPM), and mixed Pool Cost/Consumer Payment Minimization (PCM/CPM). Each method is examined from the perspective of the solution characteristics and the relevant economic principle, together with numerical examples. Especially in the CPM method, several fundamental theoretical results are obtained regarding the nature of the minimum consumer payment and the corresponding generation schedule. In addition, some generator bidding strategies are studied with respect to PCM and CPM so as to identify how Gencos can obtain a competitive advantage.</description><creator>Ren, Yongjun, 1970-</creator><contributor>Galiana, F. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><subject>Economics, Commerce-Business.</subject><subject>Energy.</subject><title>A comparison of pool cost and consumer payment minimization in electricity markets /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh415.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sj10g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bd503</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study is an attempt to present the thought of Yusuf `Abd Allah al-Qarad&amp;dotbelow;awi and his views on the Islamic awakening of the last two decades. Considered one of the contemporary world's leading moderate Islamic thinkers and activists, he has undertaken the mission to promote the idea of what he sees as a "true Islam," which he envisions as a moderate force that is all-encompassing in human life. An Egyptian, now living in Qatar, he leads a major stream within the Islamic movement today, the tayyar al-wasa&amp;dotbelow;tiyah al-Islamiyah , which believes in the "inevitability of the Islamic solution." Al-Qarad&amp;dotbelow;awi recommends a "long-term plan," seeking in the first place to transform individuals as a prelude towards changing society. The chief step toward accomplishing this mission involves renewing the religion by rediscovering Islam's soundest foundation and going back to its purest sources, i.e., the Qur'an and Sunnah, in addition to applying the "moderate" methodology of the salaf (early Muslim generation). Al-Qarad&amp;dotbelow;awi employs this traditionalist methodology and the wasa&amp;dotbelow;tiyah's ideology in his approach to guiding the Islamic awakening and to directing the Islamic movement in its particular fields of work (which include education, politics, social work, economics, jihad, the media and propaganda, and finally, thought and learning) out of a conviction that these domains represent the crucial issues facing the Muslim world today. Yet despite al-Qarad&amp;dotbelow;awi's fondness for logical discourse, he is a victim of the tendency to make axiomatic statements, which in turn endangers the entire structure of his arguments and leads him into inconsistencies. Despite these problems, his moderate voice is a welcome corrective to some of the more extremist discourse of today.</description><creator>Wardeh, Nadia.</creator><contributor>Boullata, Issa J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Qaraḍāwī, Yūsuf.</subject><subject>Islam -- History -- 20th century.</subject><title>Yusuf al-Qaradawi and the "Islamic awakening" of the late 20th century</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zz353.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bd503</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cv775</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Manaqib al-`Arifin is a series of hagiographic biographies of the first Mevlevi masters. It was written in Persian by the dervish Eflaki in the first half of the fourteenth century in Konya. Because of the limited number of narrative sources from that period, Eflaki appears as an outstanding witness of the late Seldjuk, Ilkhanid, and early Beylik period in Anatolia. This thesis intends to evaluate the Manaqib al-`Arifin as a source for political history. While previous historical scholarship has made frequent use of this source for isolated episodes, barely any systematic study of the Manaqib has been published yet. The evaluation presented in this thesis results from a comparison between every element of information that can be considered "political" in the Manaqib al-`Arifin and current scholarship on the respective topic. These elements of information fall into four broad categories: The Seldjuk of Anatolia, the akhi organization, the Ilkhan state, and the beylik states. The most part of this thesis consists in an exhaustive enumeration of the elements of political history that could be found in the Manaqib. In turn, these elements set the tone of the global conclusion of the inquiry, that is to say that the Manaqib al-`Arifin, without being a revolutionary source, offers information which is often original and which, under certain conditions, can prove highly reliable.</description><creator>Trepanier, Nicolas.</creator><contributor>Turgay, A. Uner (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Turkey -- History -- To 1453.</subject><subject>Aflaki, Shams al-Din Ahmad, d. 1360. Manaqib al-`arifin.</subject><title>The Manaqib al-Arifin as a source for political history /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k904g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cv775</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v731n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A thematic and formal analysis of Jean-Aubert Loranger's poetic tale "Le Passeur" [1920], and of Gabrielle Roy's novel La Montagne secrete [1962], shows that the construction of the two heroes' respective identity is directly related to the representation of small and large rivers in the two stories. Considering the generic difference between the two texts, these similarities---which are shaped up in a four steps "organizing scheme"---suggest the existence of a real structure in the construction of the modern identity (quebecoise). La Grande traversee, an historical novel about the massive Irish emigration of 1847, narrates the quest of identity of Seamus Doyle, while following the same four steps of this particular movement.</description><creator>Vachon, Jean-Olivier.</creator><contributor>Ricard, Francois (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Boatmen.</subject><subject>Loranger, Jean-Aubert, 1896-1942 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Roy, Gabrielle, 1909- -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>L'artiste-passeur chez J. A. Loranger et G. Roy, et, La grange traversee</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zq35r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v731n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795952p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The online newsmagazine, by incorporating and extending the capabilities of traditional media, poses a challenge to the conventional notion of both the newsmagazine and the time-based nature of news. In examining the online newsmagazine as an abstract construct as well as a physical form of media, issues of time, space and interactivity can be redefined in terms of the online environment. Using samples culled from the web and the print versions of Maclean's, Newsweek and Time, this thesis considers issues such as layout and tactility, temporality and its effect on the concept of the newsmagazine, and the changing role of the editorial staff. These factors are especially relevant to not only the online newsmagazine's current struggle to establish itself as a credible form of news dissemination within the online environment, but also the future evolution that may be involved in order to ensure the survival of the online newsmagazine.</description><creator>Wu, Leslie, 1976-</creator><contributor>Hamilton, Sheryl (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Electronic journals</subject><subject>Press</subject><title>Netting the news : redefining space, time and interactivity for the online newsmagazine</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hx25k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795952p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c936t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>British government introduced a new General National Vocational Qualification (GNVQ) as an alternative to the A-level qualification in response to a low skilled workforce. Although these qualifications are promoted as equivalent to the A-levels, vocational qualifications are considered second best, causing an academic/vocational divide. Some researchers have analyzed the internal and external nature of the qualifications. However, little empirical evidence directly compares the two. This study focused on analyzing the two equivalent qualifications represented in the national framework. The study used common areas of the A-level Physical Education and the GNVQ Leisure and Tourism curriculum to construct an examination paper consisting of an equal number of A-level and GNVQ-style questions. Two groups of A-level and GNVQ students were randomly selected from Godalming Sixth Form College to take part in the examination, and the performance scores were analyzed. Findings suggest no significant difference in performance scores, t(28) = 0.08, p = 0.94, supporting the need for further research. These results may assist in closing the academic/vocational divide. In turn, this may lead to more opportunities in industry and in universities for those achieving the GNVQ. In order to achieve true parity of esteem between the qualifications, reform needs to focus on the internal structure of the qualifications by combining the two curricular into one course represented as one qualification rather than organising the separate qualifications in a hierarchical external framework that still promotes the academic/vocational divide within the framework.</description><creator>Keen, Susan.</creator><contributor>Downey, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>General National Vocational Qualifications (Great Britain)</subject><subject>Physical education and training -- Great Britain.</subject><title>Analyses of the English academicvocational divide in physical education an investigation into the claimed parity of esteem between the A-level physical education qualification and the advanced General National Vocational Qualification leisure and tourism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xb36j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c936t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977w834</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>English as a foreign language (EFL) is quite different from English as a second language (ESL) in many respects. Few EFL studies, however, have been conducted with consideration given to the unique EFL environment. This case study of South Korean elementary EFL was designed to evaluate the previous (1997--2000) and new (2001-- ) curricula and materials based on the researcher's experience and a review of the literature. This study first suggests communicative language teaching (CLT) criteria appropriate for elementary school pupils who are beginning to learn EFL in Korea, and then evaluates the two CLT-based curricula for the 4th grade based on the suggested criteria. Second, this study aims to examine the two different material sets for the two curricula focusing on spoken language communicative activities. For the material comparison, the Sisayoungasa Co. material set, one of 16 sets based on the previous curriculum, is compared to the new material set based on the 7th curriculum. Perceptions of the curriculum and material change were considered from three perspectives: three teachers, a policy maker and a researcher. It was revealed that opinions from the three perspectives vary considerably. The study also found that despite the recent attempt to implement CLT-based elementary EFL, there are still deficiencies in the Korean elementary EFL curriculum and materials.</description><creator>Kim, Hyun Jung, 1976-</creator><contributor>Turner, Carolyn E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>English language -- Study and teaching (Elementary) -- Korean speakers.</subject><title>A case study of curriculum and material evaluation : elementary English as a foreign language in South Korea</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hm00z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977w834</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Second Language Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z708z62t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The developmental trajectories of selective and divided attention were examined in relation to the processing of hierarchically integrated stimuli. Items consisted of square, diamond, and circle forms made up of smaller squares, diamonds, and circles. Participants included 20 observers in 5 age groups (6, 8, 10, 12, and 24) who decided whether a square or diamond was presented on any given trial. In one set of trials, they were told to selectively attend (and respond) at only one level of analysis (global or local) whereas in the divided attention task, the target could appear at either level. This procedure allowed a unique comparison between selective and divided attention tasks using the same stimuli, task requirements, and instructions. Thus only the mental and attentional state of the observer was manipulated across tasks. In addition, for the divided attention task, observers were biased to one level of analysis. For both tasks and for the cross-task comparison, a clear and qualitative developmental shift was evident from six years of age to eight and ten years of age. The shift occurred in terms of selective attention, sensitivity to the probability of bias, and relative efficiency in processing global and local targets.</description><creator>Kovshoff, Hanna.</creator><contributor>Shore, D I. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Burack, Jacob B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Attention.</subject><subject>Perception in children.</subject><title>Developmental differences in global and local perception : evidence from divided and selective attention tasks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wm08b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708z62t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cf95jd08b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>On April 26, 2000, Governor Howard Dean of the State of Vermont signed into law the Civil Union bill. The first of its kind in the United States, it extended the rights of marriage to same-sex couples. Holding that the rights of homosexual couples flowed from the Common Benefits clause of the State Constitution, this bill was the result of a contentious judicial and legislative process. Preceding as it did the state and national election contests later in the year, the Civil Union law generated anger, discord, elation and fear. In the year following its passage, Vermonters came to terms with this bill in many ways. This study considers the antecedents and the consequences of this bill.</description><creator>Houston, David.</creator><contributor>Rousseau, Jerome (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Gay rights -- Vermont.</subject><subject>Marriage law -- Vermont.</subject><title>Rethinking marriage : Vermont's Civil Union Bill</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jq547.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jd08b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dz010r99p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The most outstanding features of Gesualdo Bufalino's literary works are outlined in this dissertation. Bufalino, a Sicilian writer, made a name for himself in Italian literature in the early Eighties. The first part of this thesis deals with the author's biographic background and existential experiences which ostensibly contributed the most to his shifting life onto the literary page. It ends with an analysis of Diceria dell'untore , the novel which made him famous. The dissertation provides then an in-depth analysis of the various themes connected with memory, the centrepiece of this author's artistic universe, from which he ceaselessly carves out the contents of his writings. Memory makes up his prevailing narrative structure. This feature draws him close to French writer Marcel Proust, whom Bufalino makes frequent reference to, but from whom he succeeded in taking an arm-length stand, since Bufalino elaborates and interprets reminiscing his own way. Carrying memory's materials over into fiction, a typical procedure of European literature from the previous century, is dealt with by Bufalino in a manner all of his own. Components from the author's regional culture, interspersed in his literary works, have been singled out, making thus possible a comparison with other Sicilian authors. Bufalino's literary experience may thus be seen as deeply rooted in Sicily, but at one and the same time it may also be seen as an interpretation of European literary trends in the twentieth century.</description><creator>Balboni, Lara.</creator><contributor>Predelli, Maria (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Bufalino, Gesualdo -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Memory in literature.</subject><title>Cultura Europea e identita siciliana nella scrittura di Gesualdo Bufalino</title><language>ita</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jw42n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010r99p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Italian</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cj37d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study focuses on understanding the photochemical reactions that occur between ultraviolet stabilizers and lignin during irradiation in order to further comprehend the photo-protection mechanisms of these stabilizers during brightness reversion. The stabilizers chosen for study included a variety of ultraviolet absorbers (UVAs), in addition to a hindered nitroxide free radical (4-hydroxy-TEMPO). Irradiated samples were analyzed using quantitative 31P NMR, in addition to a technique known as 'Derivatization Followed by Reductive Cleavage'. Benzophenone-based UVAs have been shown to be actively involved in photochemical reactions with lignin during irradiation, while benzotriazole-based UVAs are comparatively photostable under identical irradiation techniques. All additive combinations were found to inhibit the formation of carboxylic acids and photochemical condensation reactions in lignin; however, the joint application of 2,4-DHB and 4-hydroxy-TEMPO demonstrated synergistic inhibition of these reactions. All additive combinations were shown to impede the formation of catechol structures and to retard the cleavage of lignin beta-arylether groups during irradiation. The combined use of Tinuvin 1130 and 4-hydroxy-TEMPO provided the most efficient inhibition of these reactions. These results provide insight into the excellent photoyellowing inhibition provided by this additive combination when applied onto mechanical pulps.</description><creator>Beaton, Christa.</creator><contributor>Argyropoulos, Dimitris S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><subject>Agriculture, Wood Technology.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Radiation.</subject><title>Photo-protection mechanisms of UV stabilizers on milled wood lignin</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t814m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cj37d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42n971h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The critique entitled "L'ecriture du deuil" studies ten contemporary works of literature in light of psychoanalytical theories on mourning. The authors of the chosen pieces are always a grieving narrator going through the long process of mourning and relating the past with the lost loved one. The objective of this memoire is to verify whether or not writing permits the narrators to come to terms with the death, in other words, if it helps them to detach themselves definitively from the lost or inversely, leads them to pathological grievance aimed at reviving the deceased. The work of fiction entitled "Un petit bruit sec dans la chambre et puis rien" describes the degeneration, the suffering and the death of a father along with the upheaval of the narrator's family unit, herself struck by the news.</description><creator>Beaudoin, Myriam, 1976-</creator><contributor>Rivard, Yvon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Grief in literature.</subject><title>L'ecriture du deuil, suivi de, Un petit bruit sec dans la chambre et puis rien</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128c69g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42n971h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8623j0690</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:58:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The focal point of the work is the turntable and DJ (or Disk Jockey; one who controls the turntables). This concept not only manifests itself through the utilization of actual turntables, but also much of the acoustic material performed by the ensemble consists of "metaphoric turntables". These are contrasting layers of sound superposed over one another that are played by small groups of specific instruments within the larger ensemble. These instrumental groups simulate the sonorities generated through turntable manipulation such as warping, oscillations, crossfading, transforming, and numerous scratching techniques. The DJ (sometimes referred to as a turntablist) employs many techniques, articulations, and effects that are notated and explained in the accompanying analysis.</description><creator>Lizée, Nicole.</creator><contributor>Bouliane, Denys (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Instrumental ensembles -- Scores.</subject><subject>Electronic music.</subject><title>RPM : for large ensemble and solo turntablist</title><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xw806.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623j0690</identifier><degree><name>Master of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):39625</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>