<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:26:21Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):22000" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d56zx47p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le phosphore (P) est un élément essential pour la croissance des    plantes. En excès il est cependant une menace pour la qualité des eaux, particulièrement dans le    cas des écosystèmes d'eaux douces. Alors que les recherches se concentrent sur la compréhension    des facteurs qui influencent la dynamique fluviale du P dans des zones non-urbaines, cette    dynamique en zone urbaine demeure méconnue. Or, le développement urbain est une des principales    causes de la détérioration des eaux fluviales en Amérique du Nord, en partie à cause des impacts    de la pollution par les nutriments. Pour cette raison, il est important d'identifier quels    prédicteurs du P communément étudiés dans les rivières et ruisseaux non-urbains restent d'utiles    prédicteurs dans un cadre urbain. Il convient également de déterminer si les caractéristiques    uniques aux zones urbaines (i.e., des facteurs socio-économiques) peuvent être utilisées pour    prédire le P du réseau fluvial urbain. Sept ruisseaux sur l'île de Montréal ont été    échantillonnés à chaque jour pour déterminer leur concentration en P. Le courant a aussi été    mesuré afin de calculer le flux de P. La concentration et le flux de P ont été comparés à    plusieurs caractéristiques physiques et biologiques de leur bassin versant qui sont des facteurs    connues qui gouvernent la pollution par les nutriments (pourcentage de surface imperméable,    occupation du territoire et surface de zone riveraine tampon). La concentration fluviale de P a    aussi été comparée à plusieurs caractéristiques socio-économiques des bassins versants que j'ai    supposée être de bons prédicteurs du P dans les ruisseaux urbains, incluant la valeur moyenne de    l'habitation, le revenu moyen et les dépenses en fertilisant. Deux caractéristiques des bassins    versants (le pourcentage de surface imperméable et l'occupation du territoire) ont été plus    efficaces pour expliquer la</description><description>Phosphorus (P) is an essential nutrient for plant growth, however, in excess, it    can pose a threat to water quality, most notably in freshwater systems. While researchers have    focused on understanding the factors that influence stream P in non-urban areas, research on P    dynamics in urban streams is lacking. Currently, urban development is the second-largest cause of    stream impairment in the North America due, in part, to the impacts of nutrient pollution. For    this reason, it is important to identify which commonly studied predictors of P in non-urban    streams remain useful predictors in an urban setting and to determine whether characteristics    unique to urban areas (i.e., socio-economic factors) can be used to predict P in urban streams.    Seven streams on the island of Montreal were sampled daily to determine the P concentration in    each. Stream flow was also measured in order to calculate the P flux in each stream. Stream P    concentration and flux were compared to several physical and biological watershed characteristics    that are commonly understood to be drivers of nutrient pollution, including percent impervious    cover, land use, and amount of riparian buffer. Stream P concentration was also compared to    several socio-economic watershed characteristics that I hypothesized would be good predictors in    urban systems, including (average home value, median household income, fertilizer expenditures).    Overall, two physical watershed characteristics (impervious surface cover and measures of land    use) were most effective at explaining the variation in P concentration and P flux in the    streams, while the biological and socio-economic variables were less effective. There is some    evidence, however, to suggest that socio-economic variables (e.g. dollars spent on fertilizer per    hectare of residential land) should continue to be examined with respect to urban stream P. After    removing impervious surface cover as a predicto</description><creator>Pfeifer, Laura</creator><contributor>Elena Bennett (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</subject><title>Environmental and social predictors of phosphorus in streams on the island of Montreal, Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000092q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zx47p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4f16c367v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La malaria est l'une des maladies infectieuses les plus fréquentes    dans le monde et demeure un problème de santé publique majeur dans plusieurs régions avec plus de    250 millions de cas et plus de 1 million de décès chaque année. Le parasite de la malaria, le    Plasmodium, infecte les globules rouges et catabolyse l'hémoglobine ce qui résulte en la    formation d'un pigment appelé hémozoïne. Utilisant une approche protéomique, nous avons comparé    le profil protéique de sérums de patients atteints de la malaria avec ceux provenant d'individus    sains afin d'identifier des biomarqueurs associés à la malaria. De plus, nous avons utilisé    l'hémozoïne de la malaria afin d'identifier des protéines de sérums s'y liant, ces dernières    pouvant également servir de biomarqueurs dans un contexte de malaria. La comparaison entre les    profils protéiques de sérum a été effectuée par l'utilisation du SELDI-TOF MS (Surface enhanced    laser desorption/ionization time-of-flight mass spectrometry). Au moyen de cette technique, nous    avons identifié 173 pics significatifs et potentiels biomarqueurs en utilisant des surface    chromatographiques (proteinChips) possédant différentes affinités (CM10 étant échangeuse de    cations et IMAC fixant des protéines via un métal) présents dans deux différentes fractions    (fraction 1 et 6). Également, nous avons utilisé l'hémozoïne de la malaria afin de capturer des    protéines sériques et nous avons étudié leur potentielle utilisation comme biomarqueurs    spécifiques. Les protéines sériques provenant de patients atteints de la malaria ou d'individus    sains liant des cristaux d'hémozoïne in vitro ont été analysées par chromatographie liquide    couplée à la spectrométrie de masse (LC-MS/MS) menant à l'identification de 41 protéines liant    l'hémozoïne. Notre étude quantitative et fonctionnelle utilisant les programmes Scaffold et    Blast2GO sur les protéin</description><description>Malaria is one of the most prevalent infectious diseases worldwide and remains    to be a major public health problem in most parts of the world with more than 250 million cases    and over one million deaths each year. The malaria parasite, Plasmodium, infects red blood cells    (RBCs) and catabolizes hemoglobin which results in the formation of hemozoin. Using proteomic    approaches, we compared the serum protein profiles of malaria patients and healthy individuals in    order to identify malaria biomarkers. Furthermore, we used the malarial hemozoin to identify    hemozoin-binding serum proteins, which can also serve as biomarkers in the malaria context. The    comparison of serum protein profiles was achieved using the surface enhanced laser    desorption/ionization time-of-flight mass spectrometry (SELDI-TOF MS). Using this approach, we    have identified 173 significant peaks (potential biomarkers) from two fractions (fraction 1 and    6) of CM10 and IMAC30 ProteinChips. Additionally, we used the malarial hemozoin to trap serum    proteins and analyzed their potential as specific biomarkers. By coating hemozoin with serum    proteins from malaria patients and healthy individuals in vitro, followed by a liquid    chromatography tandem mass spectrometry (LC-MS/MS) analysis, we have identified 41    hemozoin-binding proteins. Our quantitative and functional analysis on the identified    hemozoin-binding proteins using Scaffold and Blast2GO proteomic platforms revealed several    malaria biomarkers such as gelsolin, apolipoprotein E, and serum amyloid A. The major function of    the identified proteins was binding, which includes protein and lipid binding/transporter    activities. The detection of biomarkers and the identification of hemozoin-binding proteins aid    in the early detection of malaria and as diagnostic and therapeutic targets.</description><creator>Kassa, Fikregabrail</creator><contributor>Momar Ndao (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Martin Olivier (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health Sciences - Immunology</subject><title>Proteomic analysis of serum proteins from malaria patients and identification of hemozoin-binding proteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k06988420.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c367v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fx719n247</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pendant le dévelopment du squelette des mammifères, l'ossification    endochondrale est précédée par l'établissement d'une matrice cartilagineuse par un processus    appelé chondrogenesis. Toute altération dans la chondrogenèse produisant une telle matrice    résulte en une chondrodysplasie, maladie affectant le squelette appendiculaire et caractérisée    par un raccourcissement disproportionnel des membres. Chez le poisson zèbre et la souris,    l'ablation du gène encodant S1P (site-1-protease) engendre une chondrodysplasie sévère,    démontrant ainsi que S1P est une protéine essentielle au développement normal du squelette.    Ainsi, afin d'étudier le rôle de S1P dans l'ossification endochondrale, les    cellules ATDC5 on été utilisées comme modèle in vitro de chondrogenèse. L'inhibition de    l'activité de S1P dans ces cellules a eu pour effet de diminuer l'expression    des collagènes de type II et X, alors que l'expression du collagène de type I et de    l'aggrecane est restée inchangée. Les substrats de S1P sont des protéines membranaires    qui, une fois clivées, libèrent des facteurs de transcription actifs lesquels, après    translocation nucléaire, vont promouvoir la synthèse du cholestérol, ainsi que la voie UPR    (unfolded protein response). L'analyse par PCR en temps réel a permis de démontrer que    l'expression génique de deux substrats de S1P, ATF6 et CREB3/Luman, est augmentée de    façon significative lors de la chondrogenèse. Cependant, les expériences de suppression génique    de CREB3/Luman n'ont pas permis de révéler de phénotype spécifique du    cartilage.</description><description>During mammalian skeletal development, endochondral ossification is preceded by    the establishment of a cartilage template through a process termed chondrogenesis. Disruptions in    chondrogenesis result in chondrodysplasia, a disorder of the appendicular skeleton which is    characterized by disproportionately shortened limbs. A severe chondrodysplasia phenotype is    observed when site-1 protease (S1P) is disrupted in both the zebrafish and the mouse, indicating    that S1P is essential for normal skeletal development. To investigate the role of S1P during    chondrogenesis, ATDC5 cells were used as an in vitro model. Inhibition of S1P activity in these    cells decreases the expression of collagens type II and X, while type I collagen and aggrecan    remain unaffected. The substrates of S1P are membrane-bound proteins which, when cleaved, release    transcription factors promoting cholesterol biosynthesis and the unfolded protein response. Real    time-PCR analysis determined that the expression of two substrates, ATF6 and CREB3/Luman, were    significantly up-regulated during chondrogenesis. However, silencing of CREB3/Luman expression    revealed no cartilage-related phenotype.</description><creator>Allendorf, Sarah</creator><contributor>John S Mort (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Cell</subject><title>Site-1 protease in chrondrogenesis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62f923b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fx719n247</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54kp09r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'expression des protéines recombinantes de valeur pharmaceutique    dans la glande mammaire des animaux transgéniques est une solution émergeante pour les molécules    qui ne peuvent pas être produites efficacement par les bioréacteurs standards. Toutefois,    l'expression de grandes quantités de protéines recombinantes dans la glande mammaire    peut entraîner des phénotypes avec une physiologie de la lactation compromise. Ces conséquences    négatives ont été vaguement décrites dans la littérature et, dans la plupart des cas ; elles    n'ont pas été étudiées en profondeur pour comprendre les mécanismes qui perturbent la    glande mammaire suite à l'expression des transgènes. Par conséquent, en utilisant un    troupeau de chèvres transgéniques qui expriment la forme recombinée de la butyrylcholinesterase    humaine, les principaux objectifs de cette recherche étaient: a) d'étudier la performance de la    production laitière et les paramètres de base du lait; b) d'évaluer la composition du lait; c)    d'explorer l'intégrité des jonctions serrés épithéliales, le stress du réticulum    endoplasmique (RE) et la mort cellulaire accélérée; d) d'enquêter sur la lactogénèse retardée; et    e) d'évaluer les effets des "traitements compensatoires" sur la performance de la production    laitière des chèvres transgéniques. Nos résultats ont démontré que les lactations transgéniques    étaient caractérisées par un départ lent/retardé de la production laitière, un volume de lait    relativement normal au pic de la production et un arrêt prématuré de la production laitière par    rapport aux contrôles. Ces productivités compromises étaient associées à une perturbation de la    sécrétion des lipides au niveau de l'épithélium sécrétoire et une augmentation    dramatique des phagocytes dans le lait qui n'était pas associée à une infection mammaire. Les    études sur la composition du lait ont indiqués</description><description>Milk expression of recombinant proteins of pharmaceutical value in transgenic    dairy animals is an emerging solution for molecules that cannot be made efficiently using the    standard bioreactor platform. However, the expression of large quantities of recombinant proteins    in the mammary gland can result in phenotypes with compromised lactation physiology. These    negative consequences have been vaguely described in the literature and, in most cases; they have    not been studied in depth with view to understanding the mechanisms of mammary disruption by    transgene expression. Therefore, using a transgenic herd of goats expressing recombinant human    butyrylcholinesterase, the main goals of this research were to: a) study the lactation    performance and basic milk parameters; b) assess milk composition; c) explore the integrity of    epithelial tight junctions, endoplasmic reticulum stress and accelerated cell death; d)    investigate delayed lactogenesis; and e) assess the effects of "compensatory treatments" on    transgenic lactation performance. Our findings showed that transgenic lactations were    characterized by a slow/delayed start of milk production, a relatively normal milk volume at peak    and a premature shutdown of milk production compared to controls. These compromised    productivities were associated with a disrupted lipid secretion at the level of the secretory    epithelium, and a dramatic raise in the presence of phagocytes in milk that was not associated    with mammary infection. Milk composition studies indicated that transgenic goats produce lower    quantities of caseins and short chain fatty acids. Through determination of serum album presence    and Na:K ratio in milk we established the development of permeable tight junctions as an apparent    mechanism of lactation disruption in the transgenic animals. Delayed expression of α-lactalbumin    was proposed as a major determinant of the delayed lactogenesis observed in the tra</description><creator>Baldassarre, Hernán</creator><contributor>Vilceu Bordignon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Physiology</subject><title>Lactation performance and milk composition studies in transgenic goats expressing recombinant proteins in the milk</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623hz71n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kp09r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97kr40c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Decision making formulated as finding a strategy that maximizes a utility    function depends critically on knowing the problem parameters precisely. The obtained strategy    can be highly sub-optimal and/or infeasible when parameters are subject to uncertainty, a typical    situation in practice. Robust optimization, and more generally robust decision making, addresses    this issue by treating uncertain parameters as an arbitrary element of a pre-defined set and    solving solutions based on a worst-case analysis. In this thesis we contribute to two closely    related fields of robust decision making. First, we address two limitations of robust decision    making. Namely, a lack of theoretical justification and conservatism in sequential decision    making. Specifically, we provide an axiomatic justification of robust optimization based on the    MaxMin Expected Utility framework from decision theory. Furthermore, we propose three less    conservative decision criteria for sequential decision making tasks, which include: (1) In    uncertain Markov decision processes we propose an alternative formulation of the parameter    uncertainty -- the nested-set structured parameter uncertainty -- and find the strategy that    achieves maxmin expected utility to mitigate the conservatism of the standard robust Markov    decision processes. (2) We investigate uncertain Markov decision processes where each strategy is    evaluated comparatively by its gap to the optimum value. Two formulations, namely minimax regret    and mean-variance tradeoff of the regret, were proposed and their computational cost studied. (3)    We propose a novel Kalman filter design based on trading-off the likely performance and the    robustness under parameter uncertainty. Second, we apply robust decision making into machine    learning both theoretically and algorithmically. Specifically, on the theoretical front, we show    that the concept of robustness is essential to ''successful'' learning</description><description>La prise de décision, formulée comme trouver une stratégie qui    maximise une fonction de l'utilité, dépend de manière critique sur la connaissance précise des    paramètres du problem. La stratégie obtenue peut être très sous-optimale et/ou infeasible    quand les paramètres sont subjets à l'incertitude – une situation typique en pratique.    L'optimisation robuste, et plus genéralement, la prise de décision robuste, vise cette question    en traitant le paramètre incertain comme un élement arbitraire d'un ensemble prédéfini et en    trouvant une solution en suivant l'analyse du pire scénario. Dans cette thèse, nous contribuons    envers deux champs intimement reliés et appartenant à la prise de décision robuste. En premier    lieu, nous considérons deux limites de la prise de décision robuste: le manque de justification    théorique et le conservatism dans la prise de décision séquentielle. Pour être plus    spécifique, nous donnons une justifiquation axiomatique de l'optimisation robuste basée sur le    cadre de l'utilité espérée MaxMin de la théorie de la prise de décision. De plus, nous    proposons trois critères moins conservateurs pour la prise de décision séquentielle, incluant:    (1) dans les processus incertains de décisionde Markov, nous proposons un modèle alternative de    l'incertitude de paramètres –l'incertitude structurée comme des ensembles emboîtées – et    trouvons une stratégie qui obtient une utilité espérée maxmin pour mitiguer le conservatisme    des processus incertains de décision de Markov qui sont de norme. (2) Nous considérons les    processus incertains de décision de Markov où chaque stratégie est évaluée par comparaison de    l'écart avec l'optimum. Deux modèles – le regret minimax et le compromis entre l'espérance et    la variance du regret – sont présentés et leurs complexités étudiées. (3)Nous proposons une    nouvelle conception de filtre de Kalman b</description><creator>Xu, Huan</creator><contributor>Shie Mannor (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Artificial Intelligence</subject><title>Robust decision making and its applications in machine learning</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5m60qs93d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kr40c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999761j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis addresses a chapter titled Lienü zhuan, or Arrayed Traditions of    Women from Fan Ye's (398-446) Hou Han shu, or Book of Later Han as starting point to    challenge the prevailing image of early Chinese women as helpless victims of an oppressive    Confucian society. The women represented therein behave as purposeful, active participants in the    creation of Eastern Han social mores. Most remarkably, they can be interpreted as agents defining    their social roles as wives and daughters. Chapter One focuses on the historiography of the Hou    Han shu, generally, and the Lienü zhuan, in particular, and formulates some hypotheses about the    extent of Fan Ye's own creative input in the process of compiling his Lienü zhuan. Chapter Two    investigates previous scholarship on the genre of biographies of women and proposes a theoretical    model for reading the biographies of women found in Hou Han shu based on notions of ritual    discussed by Catherine Bell and by the collaboration between Seligman, Weller, Puett, and Simon.    In order to gain further insight into the women represented in the text, Chapter Three analyzes    the social, economic, and literary background of the seventeen women included in the text. These    findings on the commonalities and differences in marital status, economic situation, political    influence, literacy, and education are put to use in Chapter Four, which applies the ideas on    ritualization to the social roles the women in Fan Ye's text perform as wives and    daughters. The thesis ends with a partial translation of the Hou Han shu lienü zhuan chapter into    English.</description><description>Cette thèse traite d'un chapitre intitulé Lienü zhuan, ou    Traditions arranges des femmes, du livre de Fan Ye (398-446) Hou Han shu, ou le Livre de Han    postérieur, comme point de départ utile pour défier l'image dominante des femmes de la Chine    antique où elles sont perçues comme des victimes impuissantes d'une société confucéenne    oppressive. Les femmes dépeintes dans ce texte adoptent une attitude déterminée, participant    pleinement à la création des codes sociaux de la dynastie Han orientale. Fait remarquable, ces    femmes définissent elles-mêmes leur rôle social en tant qu'épouses et filles. Le premier chapitre    met l'emphase sur l'historiographie des Hou Han shu, en général, et le Lienü zhuan, en    particulier. Il s'agit aussi d'émettre des hypothèses sur la démarche créative de Fan Ye dans sa    compilation de biographies des femmes. Le deuxième chapitre s'attarde sur les études existantes    concernant les biographies de femmes et suggère une approche théorique dans la lecture de ce    genre littéraire dans Hou Han shu basée sur les notions de la ritualisation tel que discutées par    Catherine Bell et par la collaboration de Seligman, Weller, Puett, et Simon. Le troisième    chapitre analyse en profondeur le fond social, économique et littéraire des 17 femmes décrites    dans le texte. Le quatrième chapitre met en évidence les différences et les similitudes entre le    statut marital, la situation économique, l'influence politique, l'instruction aussi bien    que l'éducation. Dans ce chapitre, on retrouve aussi les notions de rituel du rôle social des    femmes en tant qu'épouses et filles. La thèse se termine par une traduction partielle en anglais    du chapitre Hou Han shu lienü zhuan.</description><creator>Selles Gonzalez, Ana</creator><contributor>Griet Vankeerberghen (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Literature - Asian</subject><title>Strong minds, creative lives: a study of the biographies of Eastern Han women as found in «Hou Han shu lienü zhuan»</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214q048.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999761j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of East Asian Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g732d9926</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse étudie la réponse sismique de réservoirs potentiels    chargés d'hydrocarbure, formés de grès appartenant à la formation Torok et situés dans la partie    nord de la réserve nationale d'hydrocarbure de l'Alaska (NPRA). En intégrant les diagraphies, les    données sismiques 3D, les attributs sismiques et la modélisation, je démontrons que les grès les    plus prospectifs sont caractérisés par une diminution de leur amplitude d'onde de compression,    une augmentation de leur amplitude d'onde transversale, une augmentation suggérée de la porosité    (diagraphie de densité) et une diminution du coefficient de Poisson qui cause des anomalies AVO    (variation de l'amplitude avec le déport) de classe II et III.Comme pour d'autres grès déposés    dans des chenaux de turbidite dans la région du NPRA, certains de ces grès potentiellement poreux    de la formation Lower Torok démontrent une augmentation de leur valeur absolue d'amplitude avec    un déport augmentant (gradient négatif) et une valeur positive ou négative pour un déport de    zéro. Ce travail suggère que ces réponses d'amplitudes anormales pourraient être causées par la    présence de grès saturés en fluide, ce qui cause une diminution de l'amplitude des ondes de    compression et une augmentation correspondante de l'amplitude des ondes transversales, ce qui    résulte en un coefficient de Poisson moins élevé et en une définition des anomalies AVO de classe    II et III.</description><description>This thesis examines the seismic responses of potential hydrocarbon charged    sandstone reservoirs within the Torok xxxFormation in a northern portion of the National    Petroleum Reserve – Alaska (NPRA). By integrating wireline logs, 3D seismic data, seismic    attributes and modeling, I show that the most prospective sandstones are those characterized by a    decrease in their p-wave, an increase in their s-wave, a suggested increase in porosity (by the    density wireline log), and a decrease in Poisson's ratio which causes AVO anomalies Class II and    III. Similar to other sandstones deposited in turbidite channels in the NPRA, some of these    potentially porous Lower Torok sandstones show an increase in their absolute amplitude values    with an increasing offset (negative gradient) and a negative or positive intercept. This work    suggests that those amplitude anomalous responses could be due to the presence of fluid saturated    sandstones, which cause the decrease and corresponding increase in p and s-waves that result in a    low Poisson's ratio and in the definition of the Class II and III AVO    anomalies.</description><creator>Herbas, Javier</creator><contributor>Bruce Samuel Hart (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Geophysics</subject><title>Identification of potential reservoir sands within the Torok formation in a northern portion of the National Petroleum Reserve - Alaska</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m7512.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732d9926</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53jz04b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Single-channel speech enhancement algorithms are used to remove background noise    in speech. They are present in many common devices such as cell phones and hearing aids. In the    Bayesian short-time spectral amplitude (STSA) approach for speech enhancement, an estimate of the    clean speech STSA is derived by minimizing the statistical expectation of a chosen cost function.    Examples of such estimators are the minimum mean square error (MMSE) STSA, the β-order MMSE STSA    (β-SA), which includes a power law parameter, and the weighted Euclidian (WE), which includes a    weighting parameter. This thesis analyzes single-channel Bayesian STSA estimators for speech    enhancement with the aim of, firstly, gaining a better understanding of their properties and,    secondly, proposing new cost functions and statistical models to improve their performance. In    addition to a novel analysis of the β-SA estimator for parameter β ≤ 0, three new families of    estimators are developed in this thesis: the Weighted β-SA (Wβ-SA), the Generalized Weighted    family of STSA estimators (GWSA) and a family of multi-dimensional Bayesian STSA estimators. The    Wβ-SA combines the power law of the β-SA and the weighting factor of the WE. Its parameters are    chosen based on the characteristics of the human auditory system which is found to have the    advantage of improving the noise reduction at high frequencies while limiting the speech    distortions at low frequencies. An analytical generalization of a cost function structure found    in many existing Bayesian STSA estimators is proposed through the GWSA family of estimators. This    allows a unification of Bayesian STSA estimators and, moreover, provides a better understanding    of this general class of estimators. Finally, we propose a multi-dimensional family of estimators    that accounts for the correlated frequency components in a digitized speech signal. In fact, the    spectral components of the clean</description><description>Les algorithmes de rehaussement de la parole à voie unique sont    utilisés afin de réduire le bruit de fond d'un signal de parole bruité. Ils sont présents dans    plusieurs appareils tels que les téléphones sans fil et les prothèses auditives. Dans l'approche    bayésienne d'estimation de l'amplitude spectrale locale (Short-Time Spectral Amplitude - STSA)    pour le rehaussement de la parole, un estimé de la STSA non bruitée est déterminé en minimisant    l'espérance statistique d'une fonction de coût. Ce type d'estimateurs incluent le MMSE STSA, le    β-SA, qui intègre un exposant comme paramètre de la fonction de coût, et le WE, qui possède un    paramètre de pondération.Cette thèse étudie les estimateurs bayésiens du STSA avec pour objectifs    d'approfondir la compréhension de leurs propriétés et de proposer de nouvelles fonctions de coût    ainsi que de nouveaux modèles statistiques afin d'améliorer leurs performances. En plus d'une    étude approfondie de l'estimateur β-SA pour les valeurs de β ≤ 0, trois nouvelles familles    d'estimateur sont dévelopées dans cette thèse: le β-SA pondéré (Weighted β-SA - Wβ-SA), une    famille d'estimateur du STSA généralisé et pondéré (Generalized Weighted STSA - GWSA) ainsi    qu'une famille d'estimateur du STSA multi-dimensionnel.Le Wβ-SA combine l'exposant présent dans    le β-SA et le paramètre de pondération du WE. Ses paramètres sont choisis en considérant    certaines caractéristiques du système auditif humain ce qui a pour avantage d'améliorer la    réduction du bruit de fond à hautes fréquences tout en limitant les distorsions de la parole à    basses fréquences. Une généralisation de la structure commune des fonctions de coût de plusieurs    estimateurs bayésiens du STSA est proposée à l'aide de la famille d'estimateur GWSA. Cette    dernière permet une unification des estimateurs bayésiens du STSA et apporte une meilleure    compréhensio</description><creator>Plourde, Eric</creator><contributor>Benoit Champagne (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Bayesian short-time spectral amplitude estimators for single-channel speech enhancement</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/76537209p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53jz04b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445cf216</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis concerns the relationship between four graph invariants: omega,    chi_f, chi, and Delta. These are the clique number, the fractional chromatic number, the    chromatic number, and the maximum degree, respectively. Trivially omega &lt;= chi_f &lt;=    chi &lt;= Delta + 1. We seek to improve the upper bound on chi. We are motivated by a    conjecture of Reed, which essentially states that chi is at most the average of its trivial upper    and lower bounds: Conjecture. For any graph, chi &lt;= (Delta + 2 + omega)/2. We call this    the Main Conjecture, and propose a Local Strengthening based on the closed neighbourhood of a    single vertex: Conjecture. For any graph G, chi &lt;= max{v in V(G)} (d(v) + 2 +    omega(G[N(v)]) + 1) / 2. We begin by showing that much of the early evidence supporting the Main    Conjecture also supports the Local Strengthening. In particular, the variant of the Local    Strengthening obtained by replacing chi by chi_f holds, as does the Local Strengthening when the    stability number is two. Guided by the first of these results we look towards line graphs, for    which chi_f and chi agree asymptotically. We prove the Main Conjecture for line graphs, then we    seek to generalize this result. To do this we use recent results of Chudnovsky and Seymour, who    characterized the structure of all claw-free graphs. We refine their results by introducing a    graph reduction on certain types of homogeneous pairs of cliques that preserves the chromatic    number. Thus we need only consider the problem of colouring _skeletal_ claw-free graphs, which    cannot be reduced. The structure of skeletal claw-free graphs is simpler than that of general    claw-free graphs. We generalize two results from line graphs to the class of quasi-line graphs.    Namely, that the Main Conjecture holds, and that chi_f and chi agree asymptotically. We then    consider all claw-free graphs. We prove the Main Conjecture for all claw-free graphs and we prove    the Local</description><description>Cette thèse a pour sujet la relation entre quatre invariants de    graphes : omega, chi_f, chi, et Delta.Il s'agit respectivement du nombre de clique, du    nombre chromatique fractionnaire,du nombre chromatique, et du degré maximum. Ces paramètres    vérifient trivialementl'encadrement suivant : omega &lt;= chi_f &lt;= chi    &lt;= Delta+1, dans lequel on cherche ça améliorerla borne supérieure sur chi. Une des    principales motivations pour ce travail est uneconjecture de Reed, qui dit essentiellement que    chi est au plus la moyenne de ses bornesinférieures et supérieures triviales.Conjecture. Pour    tout graph, chi &lt;= (Delta + 2 + omega)/2.On appelle cet énoncé la Conjecture Principale,    et on propose un RenforcementLocal basé sur le voisinage de chaque sommet.Conjecture. Pour tout    graphe G, chi &lt;= max{v dans V(G)} (d(v) + 2 + omega(G[N(v)]) + 1) / 2.On commence par    montrer que la plupart des arguments en faveur de la ConjecturePrincipale incitent également à    croire que le Renforcement Local est vrai. Enparticulier, la borne donnée par le Renforcement    Local vaut pour chi_f et le RenforcementLocal peut être montré lorsque le nombre de stabilité    vaut deux.Guidé par ces premiers pas, on s'intéresse aux graphes adjoints, pour lesquels    chi_fet chi sont asymptotiquement équivalents. On montre la Conjecture Principale dansle cas des    graphes adjoints et on cherche ensuite à généraliser ce résultat.Pour cela on utilise des    résultats récents de Chudnovsky et Seymour, qui ontcaractérisé la structure les graphes sans    griffes. On affine ces résultats en introduisantla notion de graphes squelettes. Dans les    problèmes auxquels on s'intéresse,on peut facilement se ramener au cas des graphes    squelettes, et la structure desgraphes squelettes sans griffes est plus simple que celle des    graphes sans griffes engénéral.On étend deux résultats des graphes adjoints aux graphes    quasi-adjoints : onmontre que la Conj</description><creator>King, Andrew</creator><contributor>Bruce Alan Reed (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>Claw-free graphs and two conjectures on omega, Delta, and chi</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17ct90h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cf216</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3n204008h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Lors d'études statistiques dans le domaine médical où    l'on mesure les variables au fil du temps, il arrive souvent que certains participants    abandonnent l'étude. En général, on néglige l'importance de traiter ces manques    de données avec des méthodes statistiques valides. Néanmoins, plusieurs méthodes existent pour    traiter ces lacunes, sous différentes hypothèses de manque de données. Une étude de simulation a    été effectuée afin de comparer différents modèles : mixte linéaire, mélange de configurations à    redressements répétés, PAN à redressements répétés (introduit par Schafer), et deux modèles de    sélection de Bayes. Les modèles ont été comparés en fonction de leur capacité à estimer la pente    de la réaction au fil du temps, ainsi que la variabilité de l'approximation de la pente    et des intervalles de confiance. En fait, la performance des modèles diffère en fonction de la    façon dont les données manquantes ont été produites : MCAR, MAR, et NMAR. Le modèle mixte et un    des modèles de sélection (celui avec le moins de dépendance entre la probabilité    d'obtenir une donné manquante et la valeur de la réaction) ont bien performé dans les    cas MCAR et MAR, tandis que le second modèle de sélection a mieux performé dans le cas NMAR. De    plus, le modèle à mélange de configurations a produit des intervalles de confiance qui ont bien    couvert la véritable pente, tandis que le modèle PAN, dans tous les cas, n'a pas produit    de bons résultats. Ces méthodes ont ensuite été appliquées aux données longitudinales    d'handicap physique du Groupe de recherche canadien sur la sclérodermie. Les modèles ont    presque tous été capables d'identifier une augmentation de l'handicap au fil du    temps. D'ailleurs, l'exemple sur la sclérodermie nous a permis    d'identifier les avantages des modèles plus faciles à utiliser, ainsi que les    désavantages du modèle à mélang</description><description>Longitudinal studies in the medical field often experience data loss resulting    from subject dropout. The general practice is still dominated by the use of unproven ad-hoc    techniques. Modeling methods for longitudinal data with absent values exist and are valid under    different missingness assumptions. A simulation study was performed that compared the linear    mixed model, a pattern-mixture model using multiple imputations, Schafer's multiple    imputation PAN model, and two fully Bayesian selection models. The models were contrasted in    terms of their ability to estimate the slope of the response over time, and variability of the    slope estimates and confidence bounds they produced. The success of each of these models varied    under different missing data mechanisms, with the mixed model and the selection model (with a low    amount of dependence between the probability of missingness and response values) outstanding in    the MCAR and MAR cases, and the selection model (with a higher amount of probability of    missingness/response dependence) alone doing very well for NMAR data. The pattern-mixture model    also had good coverage for MCAR and MAR cases, but the PAN model did the poorest under all three    missing data conditions. The modeling methods were then applied to longitudinal disability scores    from the Canadian Scleroderma Research Group registry. Almost all were able to identify an    increase in disability over time for patients, but with varying magnitudes. This example allowed    for insight into the benefits of the models that were simpler to implement (the mixed model and    PAN) and the pitfalls of using the pattern-mixture model in certain irregular    settings.</description><creator>Schnitzer, Mireille</creator><contributor>Russell Steele (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Pure Sciences - Statistics</subject><title>A comparison of methods for longitudinal data with nonignorable dropout with an application in systemic sclerosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h538v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n204008h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zf422</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les étudiants internationaux d'Asie de l'Est se retrouvent souvent    confrontés à de nombreux challenges quant il s'agit de s'identifier et de participer de manière    active et égale aux autres étudiants au sein des communautés universitaires occidentals (Morita,    2004). Même si l'on sait que les étudiants internationaux dépendent souvent d'internet durant    cette période cruciale (Yang, et al., 2004), la façon dont ils l'utilisent et    l'influence que cela peut avoir sur leur identité reste un domaine largement peu connu. En    utilisant des interviews semi structurés, cette étude phénoménologique explore les expériences de    sept étudiants universitaires au Canada, leur utilisation d'internet et comment cette    utilisation peut avoir une influence sur la construction de leur identité. Les résultats nous    révèlent que ces étudiants se retrouvent fréquemment confrontés à des challenges identitaires et    que l'utilisation d'internet à des fins de socialisation, d'amusement et d'information    les aident dans les difficultés qu'ils rencontrent. L'utilisation d'internet peut à la fois    affirmer leur identité ou alors être une source de contrainte suivant le degré de conscience et    les raisons pour lesquelles ils se servent d'internet. La compréhension de ces processus décrits    précédemment est non seulement utile pour les services aux étudiants au sein des Universités,    mais également pour les étudiants eux-mêmes, puisqu'elle met en lumière différentes manières dont    internet peut être utilisé afin de dépasser les difficultés que peuvent rencontrer les étudiants    internationaux durant leur parcours universitaire.</description><description>East Asian international students often face challenges identifying and    participating as active and equal members in western academic communities (Morita, 2004). Even    though international students often depend on the internet during this critical time (Yang, et    al., 2004), how their internet uses impact their identity is largely unknown. Using    semi-structured interviews, this phenomenological study explores the experiences of seven South    Korean graduate students in Canada, their internet uses, and how these uses influence their    identity construction. Findings reveal that these students often experience identity challenges    and report that using the internet for socializing, entertainment and information alleviates    these issues. Depending on the degree of awareness and purposes of their online practices, these    students' internet uses both enable and constrain their identities. Understanding these processes    is useful for university student services and students themselves in considering ways the    internet can be used to facilitate overcoming challenges international students face during    educational sojourn.</description><creator>Carpenter, Pauline</creator><contributor>Doreen Starke-Meyerring (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Ratna Ghosh (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Education - Technology</subject><title>Korean international graduate students in Canada: identity and internet use</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rm277.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zf422</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Integrated Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n009w3264</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Multiple Sclerosis (MS) is a chronic disease with an unpredictable course that    impacts significantly on physical performance. Exercise or fitness has become an essential part    of management and health promotion for persons with MS. The gold standard measure of exercise    capacity (VO2peak) is the maximal exercise test, a graded test that involves an increase in    workload until exhaustion is reached. Although this test is the most accurate measure of exercise    capacity, it is not clinically useful. Therefore, the main objective of this cross-sectional    study is to estimate the extent to which exercise capacity can be predicted by sub-maximal tests    in persons with MS. By using data from several functional sub-maximal tests, a regression    equation was formulated to estimate the exercise capacity of persons with MS. The results    indicated that the modified Canadian Aerobic Fitness Test (mCAFT), grip strength and body weight    explained 74% of the variability in VO2peak. Furthermore, MS literature has shown that    health-related quality of life (HRQL) is greatly reduced in MS, as it impacts health perception    and capacity to perform daily activities. Therefore, improving HRQL has become an important goal    of all health care interventions. It is essential to evaluate and understand patients' own    perceptions of the impact of symptoms on their overall health status and their well-being. Thus,    the objective of the second manuscript was to estimate the extent to which physical capacity    predicts perceived health status in persons with MS. Using multiple linear regression the    following variables: sex, vitality, pain, smoking status, walking capacity, social functioning    and cognition emerged as significant predictors of the outcome explaining approximately 50% of    perceived health status. Significant interaction terms between sex and pain, as well as between    sex and vitality were found, indicating that the contributions to perceive</description><description>La sclérose en plaques (SP) est une maladie chronique avec un    parcours imprévisible ayant un impact significatif sur la performance physique. L'exercice    physique est à présent une partie essentielle de la prise en charge et la promotion de la santé    pour les personnes atteintes de SP. La mesure la plus élévée de capacité d'exercice est le test    d'exercice maximal, étant un test à échelle qui implique une évolution des charges de travail    jusqu'à ce que l'exténuation soit atteinte. Malgré que ce test demeure la mesure la plus precise    d'évaluation de capacité d'exercice, il n'est cependant pas cliniquement utile. Par consequent,    l'objectif principal de cette étude est d'estimer l'étendue à laquelle la capacité d'exercice    peut être predite et ce avec un test sub-maximal sur une personne atteinte de SP. En utililsant    l'information puisée de multiple test sub-maximal fonctionnel, une équation régressive peut être    formulée pour estimer la capacité d'exercice du patient atteint de SP. Les résultats indiquent    que les tests d'aptitude aérobique canadien modifié et de force de préhension ainsi que la masse    corporelle explique 74% de la variation du VO2 peak. D'autant plus, le littérature sur la SP a    démontrée que la qualité de vie relative à la santé (QVRS) est immensement réduite dû à la SP car    cela a un impact direct sur la perception de la santé et la capacité de performer des activités    quotidiennes. Donc, l'amelioration de la QVRS est devenue un but primordial dans toutes les    interventions relatives aux soins de santé. Il est essentiel d'evaluer et comprendre comment le    patient perçoit l'impact des symptomes sur son statut de santé général et son bien-être. Ainsi,    l'objectif du second manuscrit est d'estimer l'étendue à laquelle la capacité d'exercice prédit    la perception du statut de santé chez une personne atteinte de SP. L'utilisation de multiples    variabl</description><creator>Kuspinar, Ayse</creator><contributor>Nancy Mayo (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health Sciences - Physical Therapy</subject><title>Predictors and health impact of exercise capacity in multiple sclerosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603qz384.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w3264</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827c65r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Multiple memory systems are involved in processing information during    navigation. A hippocampus-dependent "spatial" navigation system requires learning the    relationships between environmental landmarks to build a cognitive map, while habit-based    "response" learning involves the automatization of patterns of behavioral responses and is    mediated by the caudate nucleus. Studies have demonstrated that people will spontaneously use one    or the other of these two alternative strategies with almost equal frequency to solve a given    navigation task (Iaria et al., 2003) and that strategy selection correlates with grey matter    density (Bohbot et al., 2007). While there is evidence for experience modulating grey matter in    the hippocampus (Maguire et al., 2000), genetic contributions may also play an important role in    the hippocampus and caudate nucleus. Recently, the Brain-derived neurotrophic factor (BDNF)    val66met polymorphism has emerged as a possible inhibitor of hippocampal function. Here we    investigate a role for this polymorphism in strategy selection and functional magnetic resonance    imaging (fMRI) activity during human virtual navigation tasks as well as an effect of this    genotype on human brain morphology.</description><description>Plusieurs systèmes de mémoire sont impliqués dans le traitement    des informations durant la navigation. Un système de navigation « spatiale », qui dépend de    l'hippocampe, exploite les liens entre les points de repère pour construire une carte cognitive,    tandis que l'apprentissage par réponse, basé sur la répétition et le renforcement est dirigé par    le noyau caudé. Des études ont démontré qu'une proportion quasi égale de gens utilisent    spontanément l'une ou l'autre de ces stratégies pour résoudre une tâche de navigation donnée    (Iaria et al., 2003), et que la sélection d'une stratégie est corrélée avec la densité de la    matière grise l'hippocampe et aux noyaux caudés (Bohbot et al., 2007). Bien qu'il ait été    démontré que l'expérience en navigation module la matière grise a l'hippocampe (Maguire et al.,    2000), des contribution génétiques peuvent aussi y jouer un rôle. Plus récemment, le    polymorphisme val66met du FNDC se fait candidat comme inhibiteur potentiel de la fonction    hippocampique. Nous avons examiné le rôle de ce polymorphisme dans la sélection d'une stratégie    et dans l'activité neuronale par IRMf pendant des tâches de navigation virtuelle, ainsi que    l'effet du génotype sur la morphologie du cerveau humain.</description><creator>Banner, Harrison</creator><contributor>Veronique Bohbot (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience</subject><title>The BDNF val66met polymorphism predicts human spatial memory behaviour, fMRI activity and brain morphology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w6634471t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827c65r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cb801</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This MA Thesis is a study of the relationship between Jane Austen's critical    views on the novel and her own creative practice as a novelist. The first chapter delineates    Austen's novelistic theory using the five letters on fiction that Austen wrote to Anna Lefroy.    The second chapter focuses on "Opinions of Mansfield Park" and "Opinions of Emma," examining how    Austen's editorial ventriloquism of the opinions reflects her own critical voice. The third    chapter shows how Austen modified her reviewers' hints from "Plan of a Novel" to fit within her    own novelistic standards in Persuasion. The fourth chapter comprises a comparative reading of the    cancelled and published versions of the final chapters of Persuasion, observing the effects of    Austen's literary standards on her writing practice. Collectively, these chapters explore the    degree to which Austen's theoretical literary standards, and her reflections on the criticisms    that her readership made of her own works, inflect her own novelistic technique.</description><description>La présente thèse de maîtrise étudie le rapport entre les idées    théoriques de Jane Austen sur le genre du roman, et sa propre pratique créative comme romancière.    Le premier chapitre extrait sa théorie du roman des cinq lettres qu'elle a écrites à propos du    roman de sa nièce, Anna Lefroy. Le deuxième chapitre porte sur les « Opinions of Mansfield Park »    et « Opinions of Emma » rassemblées par Austen. Ce chapitre examine la manière dont sa    ventriloquie et sa mise au point des opinions reflètent sa voix de critique. Le troisième    chapitre montre comment Austen a modifié les suggestions des critiques dans « Plan of a Novel »    pour les rendre compatibles avec ses principes littéraires dans Persuasion. Le quatrième chapitre    compare les deux versions, publiée et non publiée, des derniers chapitres de Persuasion. Ce    chapitre examine les effets des normes littéraires d'Austen sur sa pratique comme ro mancière.    Collectivement, ces chapitres évaluent dans quelle mesure ses principes littéraires, et ses    réflexions sur les critiques que ses lecteurs ont faites de ses œuvres, guident sa propre    technique comme romancière.</description><creator>Gemmill, Kathleen</creator><contributor>Peter Sabor (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Literature - English</subject><title>Jane Austen as critic: a study of her novelistic theory and practice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn1070002.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cb801</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sh23b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In general, translation Initiation is considered the rate-limiting step of    protein synthesis for most mRNAs. Therefore, great interest and effort has been directed at    defining protein factors involved in the regulation of initiation. The role of one particular    initiation factor, eIF4H, has yet to be conclusively defined. Therefore, we utilized a protein    fragment complementation assay (PCA) method to detect possible interacting partners of eIF4H. We    identified a novel interaction between eIF4H and 4E-BP1. In vitro we were able to confirm their    interaction. However, we failed to detect the interaction of endogenous proteins in vivo. Further    evaluation of this interaction is required to confirm its validity.</description><description>Afin de détecter de nouvelles interactions impliquées dans    l'initiation de la traduction, un criblage de certains facteurs d'initiation de la traduction a    été effectué par test de complémentation de fragments de protéines. Parmi les résultats obtenus,    une interaction entre eIF4H et 4E-BP1 a été détectée. Cette interaction a été confirmée par    co-immunoprécipitation en utilisant His6-eIF4H et 4E-BP-GST recombinants. Afin de vérifier    l'importance physiologique de cette interaction, une immunoprécipitation de 4E-BP1 a été    effectuée sur des fibroblastes embryonnaires de souris, mais eIF4H n'a pas été détecté. Par    conséquent, bien qu'une interaction entre eIF4H et 4E-BP1 a été détectée in vitro et sous des    conditions de surexpression in vivo par complémentation de protéines, plus de recherche est    nécessaire afin d'évaluer l'importance physiologique de cette interaction puisqu'elle n'a pas été    détectée par immunoprécipitation de protéines endogènes.</description><creator>Chen, Jun-Duo</creator><contributor>Gerard Pelletier (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Chemistry - Biochemistry</subject><title>Identification of a novel putative interaction between elF4H and 4EBP1</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mq78q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sh23b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62f924m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The design, fabrication, and characterization of a GaAs/AlGaAs double quantum    well long-infrared photoconductor are reported. The double quantum well structure was designed    using a 1-D Schrodinger-Poisson solver to fine-tune the material composition, thickness, and    doping to control the 2-D electron gas (2DEG) subband energies, positions, carrier densities, and    lifetimes of transitions. The wafer was grown commercially and devices were fabricated using    cleanroom facilities at McGill and the Universite de Montreal. The device has a floating gate    architecture with perpendicular carrier transport, in contrast with the parallel transport scheme    employed by almost all commercial detectors, where the photocurrent is measured directly.    Perpendicular transport provides greater photoconductive gain than parallel transport, as seen in    the high responsivities achieved by competing groups. The device reported herein was engineered    to increase the coupling, and thus the responsivity, between the two wells by 40 % over the best    previously reported results. The fabricated devices were tested under various temperature,    biasing, and illumination conditions and fundamental properties of the device such as    responsivity, sensitivity, and stability were characterized. The peak photoresponse has been    observed for modulation frequencies from 20 Hz to 1 kHz, and is clearly discernible up to 30 K.    The device exhibits a responsivity of 80-160 A/W. This result is in fair competition with QWIPs    demonstrating responsivities of mA/W -10 A/W. The device shows a NEP = 4.7e-11 W/sqrt(Hz), and D*    = 1.7e8 cm sqrt(Hz)/W.</description><description>La planifcation, fabrication et characterization d'un    double puit quantique photoconducteuren longue-infrarouge de GaAs/AlGaAs sont presentes. La    structure dudouble puit quantique a ete creee avec le programme 1-D Schrodinger-Poisson    solverafin de bien ajuster la composition des materiaux, les epaisseurs et le dopage afin    decontroler les energies des sous-bandes, les positions, les densites de transporteurs descharge    et les dures de vies de transitions du gaz d'electrons bi-dimensionel (2DEG).La    plaquette a ete fabriquee commercialement et les dispositifs ont ete fabriques dansles salles    blanches de l'Universite McGill et l'Universite de Montreal. Le dispositifa une    architecture a la grille flottante avec transport de charge perpendiculaire contrairementau    concept de transport parallele utilise par presque tous les detecteurscommerciaux ou le    photocourant est mesure directement. Le transport perpendiculairedonne un gain photoconductif    plus grand que dans la geometrie parallele commedemontre par les plus grandes responsivites    produites par les competiteurs. Le dispositifa ete cree afin d'augmenter le couplage et    ameliore donc la responsivite entreles deux puits de 40 % de plus que les meilleurs resultats    publies. Les dispositifsfabriques ont ete testes a differentes temperatures, differents voltages    et differentesilluminations. Les proprietees fondametales du dispositif comme la responsivite,    lasensibilite et la stabilite ont ete mesurees. La photoreponse maximale a ete observeesous des    frequences modulatrices entre 20 Hz et 1 kHz et est clairement visible jusqu'a30 K. Le    dispositif demontre une responsivite de 80-160 A/W. Ce resultat est a lahauteur avec QWIPs qui    demontre des responsivite allant de mA/W-10 A/W. Cedispositif demontre NEP = 4.7e11 W/sqrt(Hz) et    D* = 1.7e8 cm sqrt(Hz)/W.</description><creator>Ledwosinska, Elzbieta</creator><contributor>Thomas Szkopek (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Design, fabrication, and characterization of a floating-gate double quantum well far-infrared photoconductor</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vc352.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62f924m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pn89d745x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Plasticizers aid in processing, and impart flexibility to plastics. Their broad    use and tendency to leach out of polymers have rendered them ubiquitous in the environment.    Phthalate plasticizers, in particular di-(2-ethylhexyl) phthalate (DEHP), are known to cause male    reproductive tract defects in animal models. It has been assumed that DEHP metabolite,    mono-(2-ethylhexyl) phthalate (MEHP), is the active compound, however the bioactivity of    metabolites such as 2-ethylhexanol, 2-ethylhexanal and 2-ethylhexanoic acid, has not been    thoroughly investigated. The aim of this study was to test the effects of these compounds in a    mouse Leydig tumour cell line, MA-10 cells. DEHP, MEHP and 2-ethylhexanal decreased cell    viability, as well as steroidogenic potential as quantified by an enzyme-linked immunosorbent    assay and gene expression analysis. Interestingly, 2-ethylhexanal was the most potent    steroidogenic disruptor, which offered an intriguing contribution to the search for the    mechanism(s) of phthalate toxicity and raised doubts that MEHP is the single active metabolite.</description><description>Il est connu que les phtalates utilisés comme plastifiants et plus    particulièrement les phtalates di-(2-éthylhexyle) (DEHP) sont à l'origine des malformations de    l'appareil reproducteur masculin dans les modèles d'animaux. Ces plastifiants sont essentiels    lors de la fabrication des plastiques pour leur donner de la flexibilité. Dus à une utilisation    excessive de ces plastifiants et à leur capacité à s'échapper des plastiques existant, ces    plastifiants sont maintenant omniprésents dans l'environnement. Dans cette étude, on fait    l'hypothèse que le métabolite de DEHP, le phtalate mono-(2-éthylhexyle) (MEHP), est la molécule    active, bien qu'il n'existe aucune autre étude concernant les métabolites comme 2-éthylhexanol,    2-éthylhexanal et l'acide 2-éthylhexanoïque. Le but de cette étude est d'évaluer les    effets de ces produits chimiques sur une lignée cellulaire tumorale interstitielle du testicule    de souris, les cellules MA-10. On a montré que le DEHP, le MEHP et le 2-éthylhexanal ont diminué    la viabilité des cellules, aussi bien que la stéroïdogénèse qui a été quantifiée par la méthode    ELISA et par l'analyse de l'expression génétique. Contre toute attente, le    2-éthylhexanal s'est avéré le plus puissant acteur dans la dégradation de la stéroïdogénèse, ce    qui a ouvert une nouvelle avenue de recherche concernant le ou les mécanisme(s) impliqués dans la    toxicité des plastifiants phtalates et a mis en doute le fait que le MEHP est le seul métabolite    actif.</description><creator>Piché, Carlie</creator><contributor>Bernard Robaire (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Richard L Leask (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Chemical</subject><title>Effects of di-(2-ethylhexyl) phthalate and four of its metabolites on steroidogenesis in MA-10 cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r494vk94m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89d745x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r197k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents a novel idea for object allocation, cache line reservation    (CLR), whose goal is to reduce data cache misses. Certain objects are allocated from    "reserved" cache lines, so that they do not evict other objects that will be    needed later. We discuss what kinds of allocations can benefit from CLR, as well as sources of    overhead. Prototypes using CLR were implemented in the IBM® J9 Java™ virtual machine (JVM) and    its Testarossa just-in-time (JIT) compiler. A performance study of our prototypes was conducted    using various benchmarks. CLR can offer a benefit in specialized microbenchmarks when allocating    long-lived objects that are accessed in infrequent bursts. In other benchmarks such as    SPECjbb2005 and SPECjvm2008, we show that CLR can reduce cache misses when allocating a large    number of short-lived objects, but not provide a performance improvement due to the introduced    overhead. We measure and quantify this overhead in the current implementation and suggest areas    for future development. CLR is not limited to Java applications, so other static and dynamic    compilers could benefit from it in the future.</description><description>Cette thèse présente une nouvelle idée pour l'attribution    d'objet, réservation de ligne d'antémémoire (RLA), dont le but est de réduire    les échecs d'accès à l'antémémoire. Certains objets sont alloués à partir    d'une antémémoire de réserve, de manière à éviter l'éviction d'autres    objets ultérieurement requis. Nous discutons les types d'allocation qui peuvent    bénéficier de RLA, ainsi que les sources de coûts indirects. Les prototypes que nous avons    développé qui font usage de RLA furent créés utilisant la machine virtuelle IBM® J9 Java™ et son    compilateur juste-a-temps Testarossa. Une étude de performance de nos prototypes fut conduite    avec plusieurs tests de performance. RLA peut offrir un bénéfice pour des microtests de    performance spécialisés dans les cas où des objets de longue vie sont lus en rafales    infréquentes. Dans d'autres tests que SPECjbb2005 et SPECjvm2008, nous démontrons que    RLA peut réduire les échecs d'accès a l'antémémoire dans les cas    d'allocation d'un grand nombre d'objets de court temps de vie, mais    n'offre pas d'amélioration de la performance vue l'introduction de    coûts indirects. Nous mesurons et quantifions ces coûts dans notre implémentation courante et    suggérons des domaines de développement futurs. RLA n'est pas limité aux applications    Java, ce qui permet à d'autres compilateurs statiques comme dynamiques d'en    tirer profit dans l'avenir.</description><creator>Bilicki, Ivan</creator><contributor>Zeljko Zilic (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>Cache line reservation: exploring a scheme for cache-friendly object allocation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6t053g972.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r197k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440t33q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of this thesis is to develop tools that will enable the design of the    components of the Rankine micro-engine in order to satisfy performance and reliability    requirements for high temperature operation. The Ashby approach was used to identify a set of    candidate materials – zirconia, silica, titanium alloy, nickel-cobalt alloy, silicon carbide and    silicon – for the insulating static structure and rotor. Subsequently, the stresses in, and    deformations of, the insulating static structure were analyzed using analytical models and the    method of finite elements. Subsequently, an idealized impact experiment was designed and    performed to assess reliability of the rotor in the event of an accidental high-speed impact with    the static sidewalls. The threshold velocity for initiating damage in alumina projectiles (balls)    impacting on alumina targets (discs) was found to be 30 m/s, while the corresponding value for    zirconia projectiles on alumina target was found to be around 65–70 m/s. These findings pave the    way for developing detailed designs for the rotor and static sidewall of the Rankine    micro-engine.</description><description>L'objectif de cette thèse est de développer des outils    qui permettront la conception de composants de moteur, afin de satisfaire les exigences de    performance et de fiabilité de l'appareil dans des conditions extrêmes. Le méthode Ashby    a été utilisée pour identifier un ensemble de matériaux - la zircone, la silice, de    l'alliage de titane, de l'alliage nickel-cobalt, de silicium et de carbure de    silicium – pour la structure statique isolante du rotor, ce qui révèle un compromis entre la    performance, la fiabilité et la fabricabilité . Ultérieurement, les contraintes, et les    déformations de la structure statique d'isolation ont été analysées par la méthode des    éléments finis.Par la suite, une expérience idéalisée d'impact a été conçue et réalisée    pour évaluer la fiabilité du rotor dans le cas d'un accident d'impact à grande    vitesse avec la paroi latérale de la structure statique. La vitesse seuil d'ouverture    des dommages dans des projectiles d'alumine (balles) un impact sur les objectifs de    l'alumine (disques) a été retrouvé à 30 m/s, alors que le projectile en zircone sur la    cible d'alumine a été jugé dans la région de 65 - 70 m/s. Ces résultats ouvrent la voie à la    formulation de matériaux de conception pour le rotor et la paroi latérale statique du    micro-moteur Rankine.</description><creator>Shahriar, Hassan</creator><contributor>Srikar Vengallatore (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical</subject><title>Structural design of the rotor and static structure of a microscale Rankine engine</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26xz20w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440t33q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q495s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Measles-associated morbidity and mortality can be decreased in response to    treatment with vitamin A. However, the mechanism underlying this beneficial effect is unknown. In    this work, we investigate the molecular interaction between measles virus (MeV) and retinoids in    vitro. Our first goal was to assess whether retinoids influence the in vitro replication of MeV.    We found all-trans retinoic acid (ATRA), as well as other natural and synthetic retinoids,    inhibited MeV replication in primary cells and a range of cell lines. This inhibitory effect was    mediated through retinoid nuclear receptor signaling, and retinoic acid receptor alpha (RARalpha)    in particular. Next, we sought to determine the role of type I interferon (IFN), since both MeV    and retinoids can modulate IFN signaling. Type I IFN blocking antibodies abrogated the inhibitory    effects of ATRA on MeV replication. IFN-stimulated genes (ISG) were upregulated by ATRA in    MeV-infected cell cultures when compared to either treatment or infection alone. Using a    transwell system, we determined that this increased gene expression occurred in initially    uninfected bystander cells. The ATRA-treated bystander cells did not support substantial viral    replication when subsequently challenged with MeV. Finally, we identified retinoid-induced gene I    (RIG-I) as a link between the RARalpha - and IFN-dependent mechanism of MeV inhibition by    retinoids. We found that RIG-I can be transcriptionally regulated by ATRA. Furthermore, RARalpha    function was necessary for the induction of RIG-I by MeV and ATRA, and could bind to the RIG-I    promoter. A retinoic acid response element (RARE) in the RIG-I promoter region was identified,    and RIG-I promoter constructs were shown to produce luciferase in response to ATRA. Finally, we    showed that functional RIG-I was necessary for ATRA to inhibit MeV replication. In summary, we    have demonstrated that transcriptional regulation of RIG-I</description><description>Les taux de morbidité et de mortalité associés à la rougeole    peuvent diminuer à la suite d'un traitement à la vitamine A ; or, le mécanisme à l'origine de cet    effet bénéfique est encore inconnu. Par ce travail, nous avons voulu étudier les mécanismes    résultant de l'interaction du virus de la rougeole (MeV) et des rétinoïdes in vitro. Nous avions    d'abord comme objectif de déterminer si les rétinoïdes avaient un impact sur la réplication du    MeV in vitro . Nous avons démontré que le ligand spécifique, l'acide tout-trans rétinoïque    (ATRA), ainsi que d'autres rétinoïdes naturels et synthétiques inhibent la réplication du MeV    chez des cellules primaires de même que chez un grand nombre de lignées cellulaires. Nous avons    aussi démontré que la signalisation par les récepteurs nucléaires des rétinoïdes, en particulier    le récepteur alpha de l'acide rétinoïque (RARalpha), était responsable de l'effet inhibiteur    observé. Nous avons ensuite voulu déterminer le rôle de l'interféron de type I (IFN) puisqu'il    est connu que MeV et les rétinoïdes peuvent moduler la signalisation de cet IFN de différentes    façons. Nos recherches ont permis de démontrer que des anticorps bloquant la signalisation par    l'IFN de type I renversent les effets inhibiteurs de l'ATRA sur la réplication du MeV, démontrant    ainsi l'importance de la signalisation par cet IFN. En outre, l'ATRA augmente l'expression des    gènes stimulés par l'IFN de type I (ISG) chez des cellules en culture infectées par le MeV    comparativement aux cellules uniquement traitées à l'ATRA ou uniquement infectées par le MeV.    L'utilisation d'un système Transwell a aussi permis de déterminer que l'augmentation de    l'expression de ces gènes survient chez des cellules de voisinage non-infectées initialement par    le MeV. Lorsque ces cellules, traitées à l'ATRA, étaient par la suite infectées au MeV, on n'y    observait pas d</description><creator>Trottier, Claire</creator><contributor>Wilson H Miller (Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Brian Ward (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health Sciences - Immunology</subject><title>Mechanism of measles virus by retinoids: the role of signaling by retinoid nuclear receptors and type I interferon</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xs60c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q495s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mj939</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La modulation du gain est consideree comme un mecanisme general    d'integration dans le cerveau, employee par les neurones pour combiner des informations    provenant de diverses sources et modalites. Ces characteristiques de champs de gain se sont    montrees souvent, repandues dans le cortex et sous-regions du cerveau. Elles sont soupconnees    detre a la base de fonctions fondamentales comme la transformation de coordonnees spatiales.    Neanmoins, l'existence de champs de gain n'a pas ete exploree dans les regions    inferieures du cerveau, comme le tronc cerebral.Dans cette these, un modele du systeme de    controle des yeux est developpe a la fois pour les phases lentes et rapides du reflexe    vestibulo-oculaire (VOR) angulaire, tout en soutenant la compatibilite avec les donnees    physiologiques pertinentes. Ce modele est ensuite utilise pour demontrer que si de tels champs de    gain nonlineaires sont ancres dans le circuit du VOR sur les neurones premoteures (contrairement    aux presumes neurones lineaires), le comportement et les aspects dynamiques du VOR dependraientt    automatiquement du contexte binoculaire sans recours a d'autres calculs exterieurs. Ceci    demontre que, en principe, les modulations du VOR et de plusieurs autres reflexes avec le    contexte sensori-moteur pourrait etre le resultat de nonlinearites locales. Notons que des    nonlinearites semblables ont deja ete decouvertes dans les circuits de la moelle epiniere. Des    simulations de ce modele hybride non-lineaire predisent que les mouvements oculaires seraient    disjoints pendant le VOR, en consequence inevitable de l'existence de tels champs de    gain dans les centres premoteurs bilateraux. Les donnees experimentales recueillies ici chez    l'homme et le singe soutiennent ces predictions: pendant le VOR angulaire dans    l'obscurite, nous avons observe une importante reponse en vergence dans les movements    binoculaires que ce soit en phase lentes ou rapides. Les resultat</description><description>Gain modulation is believed to be a common integration mechanism employed by    neurons to combine information from various sources and modalities. Gain fields have been shown    to widely exist in cortical and subcortical areas of the brain and are believed to be the basis    for fundamental brain functions such as coordinate transformation. Nevertheless the existence of    gain fields has not been explored in lower brain areas like the brainstem. In this thesis, a    physiologically relevant control system model is developed for both the slow and quick phases of    the angular horizontal vestibulo-ocular reflex (VOR). This model is then used as a framework to    show that if nonlinear gain fields are embedded in the response of VOR premotor neurons (in    contrast to generally assumed linear neurons) viewing-context-dependent behavior of the VOR    results automatically. This shows that, in principle, reflex modulations with sensori-motor    context could be the outcome of local premotor nonlinearities, and not complex cortical    computations. Interestingly, similar nonlinearities have been previously discovered in the spinal    circuits. Simulations of this hybrid nonlinear model predicts that disconjugate eye movements    during the VOR would be an inevitable consequence of the existence of such gain fields in the    central bilateral VOR pathway. Behavioral data collected from normal human subjects during the    angular VOR in darkness confirm the presence of large disconjugate components which are fully    compatible with the model predictions. These theoretical and experimental results have    implications for the design of clinical protocols to test reflexes.</description><creator>Khojasteh-Lakelayeh, Elham</creator><contributor>Henrietta L Galiana (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health Sciences - Human Development</subject><title>Reflex modulations with sensori-motor context could rely on premotor gain modulation: Implications for the VOR system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322f195.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mj939</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87pr269</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis comprises of three essays that explore the theoretical development   as well as the empirical applications of asset pricing models with Lévy jump processes. The first   essay presents a new discrete-time framework that combines heteroskedastic processes with rich   specifications of jumps in returns and volatility. Our models can be estimated with ease using   standard maximum likelihood techniques. We evaluate the models by fitting a long sample of   S&amp;P500 index returns, and by valuing a large sample of options. We find strong empirical   support for time-varying jump intensities. A model with jump intensity that is affine in the   conditional variance performs particularly well both in return fitting and option valuation. In   the second essay, we develop a new class of asset pricing model that combines the flexibility of   Lévy processes with the ease of implementation of affine GARCH dynamics. This framework produces   a large class of asset return processes that have analytical solutions for their pricing   transform, and lead to a simple valuation of derivatives. We apply this newly proposed framework   to various two-factor models consisting of a normal and a pure jump Lévy component. The results   from joint estimation of options and returns on the market index reveal the important economic   role of jumps. We find that models without jumps cannot reconcile the difference between   market-realized returns and investors' ex-ante expectations of returns with an   economically justifiable equity premium level. In the third essay, we provide evidence that the   market crash risk is priced in individual equity options. We proceed by developing a factor model   for equity returns and option pricing that takes into account the market's systematic   risk factors, namely the market volatility and jump risks. The probability of large negative   jumps in the market return produces the "crash fear" effect. In addition to the   market risk factors, we</description><description>Cette thèse comporte trois essais qui explorent le développement   théorique ainsi que les applications empiriques des modèles d'évaluation   d'actifs avec des processus de saut de Lévy. Le premier essai présente un nouveau cadre   d'évaluation en temps discret qui combine à la fois des processus heteroskedastic ainsi   qu'une large famille de spécifications à base des sauts dans les processus de rendement   et de la volatilité. Nos modèles peuvent être facilement estimés en utilisant des techniques   standard de maximum de vraisemblance. Nous évaluons les modèles proposés en les adaptant à un   long échantillon de rendement sur l'indice S&amp;P500, et en évaluant un grand échantillon   d'options. Nous trouvons un fort soutien empirique pour l'existence des sauts   avec intensités à temps-variables. Un modèle à saut dont l'intensité est affine avec la   variance conditionnelle performe particulièrement bien a la fois pour les rendements ainsi que   pour l'évaluation des options. Dans le deuxième essai, nous développons une nouvelle   famille de modèles d'évaluations d'actif qui combine la flexibilité des   processus de Lévy avec la facilité d'implémentations des modèles affines GARCH. Ce cadre   résulte à une grande classe des processus de rendement des actifs qui ont des solutions   analytiques pour leur «transforme», et mène à une évaluation simple des produits dérivés. Nous   appliquons ce cadre nouvellement proposé à de divers modèles à deux-facteurs-une composante   normale et une autre a base du processus à saut de Lévy. Les résultats de l'évaluation   commune des options et des rendements sur l'indice du marché indiquent le rôle   économique important des sauts. Nous constatons que les modèles sans sauts ne peuvent pas   réconcilier la différence entre les rendements réalisés du marché et les espérances des   investisseurs concernant les rendements avec un niveau de prime de risque économiquemen</description><creator>Ornthanalai, Chayawat</creator><contributor>Kris J J Jacobs (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Peter Frederik Christoffersen (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Economics - Finance</subject><title>Asset pricing with Lévy jump processes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xv98f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pr269</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Desautels Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j38607901</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chez les jeunes athlètes sportifs, le climat motivationnel de   l'équipe a été identifié comme un des facteurs qui influencent leur croissance et développement.   Les actions des entraîneurs telle l'identification de la présence des comparaisons sociales et le   degré auquel elles existent, les récompenses et punitions données aux joueurs, ainsi que le degré   d'encouragement à former des liens interpersonnels de qualité au sein d'une équipe peuvent créer   un climat qui tende soit vers la valorisation de l'accomplissement des tâches, soit à celle de   l'égo des joueurs. Les résultats des récentes recherches sur la motivation indiquent clairement   les aspects positifs qui découlent de la perception des joueurs appartenant à une équipe où règne   un climat motivationnel axé sur l'accomplissement des tâches. Traditionnellement l'on a supposé   que puisque le climat motivationnel dépend du comportement de l'entraîneur lors des matchs et   pratiques, que tous les joueurs devaient donc percevoir un même climat motivationnel. Cependant,   de récentes recherches dans ce domaine ont révélé que tous les membres d'une équipe n'ont pas   forcément la même perception du climat motivationnel de leur équipe, car cette perception est   fondée tout au moins en partie sur les liens qui unissent ces joueurs à leur entraîneur.   Utilisant ces données comme point de départ, le but de cette étude est d'analyser l'influence   qu'opère la perception d'un athlète selon les commentaires et critiques de son entraîneur en chef   sur le type de climat motivationnel de leur équipe. De plus, la présente étude a analysé   l'influence de la différence entre les commentaires et critiques préférés des joueurs et ceux   reçus par les joueurs sur les perceptions des athlètes du climat motivationnel de l'équipe. Les   participants de l'étude (n=70) étaient des joueurs de hockey masculins de calibre élite de 13 et   14 ans, qui avaient t</description><description>Team motivational climate has been identified as an important variable in the   growth and development of youth sport athletes. Coaching behaviors such as determining the   presence and extent of social comparison, rewarding and punishing players, and the quality of   interpersonal relationships fostered within the team can create a predominantly task- or   ego-oriented team climate. Research on motivation has clearly identified many of the positive   outcomes associated with athletes' perceptions of a task-oriented team climate. Since the   motivational climate refers to the coach's general behaviors in games and practices, it is   traditionally assumed that players within a team perceive the same type of team climate. However,   research has recently reported that athletes within the same team do not always share the same   perceptions of the motivational climate. This has partly been attributed to players' personal   interactions with the coach. Therefore, the purpose of this study was to examine the influence of   athletes' perceptions of the individual feedback they received from their head coach during   practices on their perceptions of the team's motivational climate. In addition, the present study   examined the influence of the discrepancy between athletes' preferred and perceived coach   feedback patterns on athletes' perceptions of the motivational climate. Participants (n = 70)   were 13-14 year old elite male hockey players , who each completed the Perceived Motivational   Climate for Sport Questionnaire-2 (PMCSQ-2; Newton, Duda, &amp; Yin, 2000) and the Coaching   Feedback Questionnaire (CFQ; Amorose &amp; Horn, 2000). Hierarchical regression analysis   revealed that perceptions of positive individual feedback from the coach (B=.44) led to   perceptions of a task-oriented climate, whereas perceptions of negative individual feedback from   the coach (B=.51) led to perceptions of an ego-oriented climate. Moreover, the discrepancy   between athletes' perceive</description><creator>Stein, Jonathan</creator><contributor>Gordon Bloom (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Education - Psychology</subject><title>Influence of perceived coach feedback on athletes' perceptions of the team's motivational climate</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343t09d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j38607901</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m039k5977</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les don nées sur les émissions des gaz à effet de serre (GES)    obtenues au niveau des fermes entières agricoles sont pertinentes au secteur agricole et ont le    potentiel d'éliminer une partie de l'incertitude qui se produit quant à l'extrapolation du niveau    de la parcelle jusqu'au niveau du champ. La couche limite nocturne (CLN) agit comme une    chambre virtuelle dans laquelle on fait plusieurs ascensions pour déterminer les fluxes de GES.    Dans le but géneral de raffiner la méthode du budget de la CLN afin d'obtenir de plus fiables    estimées au niveau de la ferme typique (environ 1 kilomètre carré), les fluxes de CO2, N2O, et    CH4 ont été mesurés sur deux fermes agricoles dans l'est du Canada. En 1998 et 2002, les sites    d'étude se trouvaient sur une ferme près d'une banlieue au sud-ouest    d'Ottawa (Ontario), où le terrain est relativement plat et les principales cultures sont    le maïs, le foin et le soya. En 2003, le site d'étude se situait dans la communauté rurale de    Coteau-du-Lac (Québec), environ 20 km au sud-ouest de Montréal. Bordé par le fleuve St-Laurent au    sud, ce terrain est plat et on y cultive surtout le maïs, le foin et un mélange de soya et de    légumes. Le flux moyen de CO2 mesuré aux deux sites par la méthode du budget de la CLN    correspondait bien avec celui mesuré par la technique de la covariance des fluctuations et aussi    avec ce qui est rapporté dans la littérature. Considérant toutes les directions de vent et toutes    les pratiques agricoles, la moyenne des flux de N2O mesurés par la technique de NBL était du même    ordre de grandeur, quoiqu'un peu plus élevée, que ce qui est rapporté dans la littérature pour    les émissions de base de N2O des écosystèmes agricoles. Les résultats pour le CH4 ont été jugés    non-valides car l'échantillonage concurrente des trois gaz aux alentours des deux sites a    confirmé que le CH4 était particulièrement sensible à la</description><description>Measuring greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions directly at the farm scale is most    relevant to the agricultural sector and has the potential to eliminate some of the uncertainty    arising from scaling up from plot or field studies or down from regional or national levels. The    stable nighttime atmosphere acts as a chamber within which sequentially-measured GHG    concentration profiles determine the flux of GHGs. With the overall goal of refining the    nocturnal boundary layer (NBL) budget method to obtain reliable flux estimates at a scale    representative of the typical eastern Canadian farm (approximately 1 km2), fluxes of CO2, N2O,    and CH4 were measured at two agricultural farms in Eastern Canada. Field sites in 1998 and 2002    were located on an experimental farm adjacent to a suburb southwest of the city of Ottawa, ON, a    relatively flat area with corn, hay, and soy as the dominant crops. The field site in 2003 was    located in the rural community of Coteau-du-Lac, QC, about 20 km southwest of the island of    Montreal, a fairly flat area bordered by the St. Lawrence River to the south, consisting mainly    of corn and hay with a mixture of soy and vegetable crops. A good agreement was obtained between    the overall mean NBL budget-measured CO2 flux at both sites, near-in-time windy night eddy    covariance data and previously published results. The mean NBL-measured N2O flux from all wind    directions and farming management was of the same order of magnitude as, but slightly higher    than, previously published baseline N2O emissions from agroecosystems. Methane fluxes results    were judged to be invalid as they were extremely sensitive to wind direction change. Spatial    sampling of CO2, N2O, and CH4 around the two sites confirmed that [CH4] distribution was    particularly sensitive to the nature of the emission source, field conditions, and wind    direction. Optimal NBL conditions for measuring GHG fluxes, present approximately 60% of the t</description><creator>Wittebol, Laura A., 1973-</creator><contributor>Ian Brett Strachan (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Elizabeth Pattey (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Atmospheric Sciences</subject><title>Refinement of the nocturnal boundary layer budget method for quantifying agricultural greenhouse gas emissions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xv99q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k5977</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kk91fm586</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:53:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background: The evidence to date in support of system related factors to account    for medication administration errors (MAE) remains scant and inconclusive. Objective: To examine    the predictive power of medication administration complexity (component and coordinative), work    interruptions and nurses' workload as potential contributing factors to MAE. Design: A    prospective correlational design. Setting: A medical patient care unit in a university teaching    hospital Sample: A convenience sample of medication administration rounds performed by registered    nurses with at least six months of professional experience. Method: Data were collected using    direct observation (MAE and work interruptions), self-report measures (subjective workload,    nurses' characteristics) and the Medication Administration Complexity (MAC) coding scale    (component and coordinative medication complexity). Results: One hundred and two rounds were    observed, during which 965 doses were administered and performed by 18 nurses. When wrong    administration time errors were included, MAE rate was 28.4% whereas it decreased to 11.1% when    wrong time errors were excluded. An interruption during the medication preparation phase (OR    1.596; 1.044 - 2.441) significantly increased the odds of MAE. Two significant interaction    effects were found (patient demand for nursing care X overtime and patient demand for nursing    care X professional experience). These interactions pointed to more negative effects of overtime    and professional experience among nurses who rated the demand for nursing care as above average.    Contrary to expectations, coordinative medication administration complexity significantly    decreased the odds of MAE (OR 0.558; .322-.967). Including wrong administration time errors    changed the cluster of predictors with component medication administration complexity (1.039;    1.016 - 1.062), and nurses' workload (1.221; 1.061 - 1.405) were significant pre</description><description>Introduction: Les résultats probants relatifs aux facteurs    prédictifs des erreurs d'administration des médicaments (EAM) sont peu nombreux et    non-concluants.Objectif: Examiner la complexité de l'administration (composante et coordination),    les interruptions dans le processus d'administration des médicaments et la charge de travail    infirmière subjective comme facteurs prédictifs des EAM.Devis: Un devis corrélationnel    prospectif. Milieu: Une unité de médecine dans un centre hospitalier universitaire.Échantillon:    Un échantillon de convenance formé de 102 cycles d'administration des médicaments effectués par    18 infirmières avec un minimum de six mois d'expérience professionnelle.Méthode: Les données ont    été colligées par observation directe (EAM et interruptions), mesures auto-rapportées (charge de    travail subjective, caractéristiques sociodémographiques) ainsi qu'avec l'échelle de la    complexité de l'administration médicamenteuse (MAC coding scale).Résultats: 102 observations ont    été effectuées au cours desquelles 965 doses ont été administrées par 18 infirmières. En incluant    les erreurs de temps d'administration, le taux d'EAM était de 28.4% et diminua à 11.1% lorsque    les erreurs de temps d'administration étaient exclues. Une interruption lors de la préparation    des médicaments (OR 1.596; 1.044 - 2.441) augmente significativement le risque d'EAM. Deux    interactions significatives ont été trouvées (charge de travail X temps supplémentaire et charge    de travail X expérience professionnelle). Ces interactions indiquent un effet plus négatif du    temps supplémentaire et de l'expérience professionnelle parmi les infirmières ayant une charge de    travail supérieure à la moyenne. La complexité de coordination de l'administration de médicament,    contrairement aux attentes, diminue significativement les risques d'EAM (OR 0.558; .322-.967).    L'inclusion des erreurs de temp</description><creator>Biron, Alain</creator><contributor>Melanie Lavoie-Tremblay (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Carmen Gisele Loiselle (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health Sciences - Nursing</subject><title>Medication administration complexity, work interruptions, and nurses' workload as predictors of medication administration errors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d7466.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kk91fm586</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Nursing</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):22025</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>