<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:27:57Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):22450" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:765372341</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examined the responses of algae and invertebrates to a single application of nutrients in a series of experimental wetland enclosures in the Interlake Region of Manitoba during 1989 and 1990. Water, sediment and vegetation chemistry were also monitored. The 3 fertilization treatments were: dissolved inorganic high (6200 $ mu$g/l N, 420 $ mu$g/l P), dissolved inorganic low (3200 $ mu$g/l N, 210 $ mu$g/l P) and organic high (alfalfa: 6200 $ mu$g/l N, 420 $ mu$g/l P). Dissolved nutrients in the high and low treatments were quickly depleted from the system but dissolved N increased in the alfalfa treatment as decomposition progressed. No changes in sediment or vegetation chemistry were detected. Phytoplankton biomass increased in all the fertilized enclosures while epiphytic periphyton exhibited only minor responses. Epipelon biomass increased in the alfalfa treatment and metaphyton standing crops were extensive in the high treatment enclosures. In the alfalfa treatment, high microbial respiration rapidly decreased dissolved oxygen concentrations which negatively affected invertebrates. This trend reversed as oxygen levels increased. Dominant nektonic and benthic herbivores-detritivores increased in the high and alfalfa treatment enclosures. Orthocladiinae emergence increased in the high and alfalfa treatments while Chironominae and Tanypodinae increased in the alfalfa treatment. Responses by algae and invertebrate communities to the fertilization treatments were minimal during 1990. Annual single pulse fertilization has the potential to increase the productivity of Interlake wetlands.</description><creator>Gabor, T. Shane (Thomas Shane)</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Wetlands -- Manitoba -- Interlake Region.</subject><subject>Wetland ecology -- Manitoba -- Interlake Region.</subject><subject>Wetlands -- Fertilizers.</subject><title>Nutrient addition experiments in the interlake region of Manitoba : effect of single pulse addition in spring</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j3860811k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/765372341</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Renewable Resources</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v692t7533</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We developed a methodology to measure plasma hepatic glutathione (GSH) turnover and we tested it in rats treated with an inhibitor of GSH synthesis. Our goal was to determine whether protein intakes above NRC recommendations maximize hepatic GSH stores and turnover in vivo. We also wished to learn if plasma GSH, cysteine, or methionine concentrations or plasma GSH turnover could be used as noninvasive predictors of liver GSH status. Rats were fed purified diets containing 0, 5, 10, 20 or 40% casein for one week. The 0 and 5% casein diets were considered inadequate in protein, 10% marginal, 20% adequate and 40% excessive. Liver GSH content (mmol/liver) of rats fed 0 and 5% casein diets was 12.29 $ pm$ 1.11 and 16.43 $ pm$ 0.95, respectively, and increased to 23.62 $ pm$ 1.82 in the 10% group. Liver GSH content did not differ between the 20 and 40% groups. As dietary casein increased from 0-20%, free plasma GSH and cysteine concentrations and plasma GSH turnover increased, but did not increase further with the 40% diet. A sigmoidal relationship between plasma GSH turnover and hepatic GSH content was demonstrated. The best predictor of liver GSH content was not free plasma GSH concentration nor plasma GSH turnover, but the free plasma cysteine concentration.</description><creator>Hum, Susan</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Rats -- Nutrition.</subject><subject>Liver -- Diseases -- Nutritional aspects.</subject><subject>Glutathione -- Metabolism.</subject><title>Glutathione metabolism in the rat under varied nutritional conditions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/765372359.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t7533</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ht24wk394</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Indices of nutritional condition and diet were evaluated in harp seals Phoca groenlandica obtained from hunters in Hudson Strait and the Gulf of St. Lawrence, December 1988 to October 1990. In winter seals, blubber and the lean, eviscerated carcass contributed 90% and 9% of total body lipids, respectively. Lipid was distributed homogeneously throughout the blubber. Blubber thickness and girth at 50% of length showed the strongest correlation to fat stores. Sculp and core mass in females increased from autumn to winter. Mature males were observed to significantly increase their blubber mass from early to late winter. Muscle and liver lipid content varied seasonally in both sexes, and were highest in a sample of females one month post-partum which were feeding very intensively. These females had reduced blubber mass and blubber lipid content, but the highest observed core mass, the later being significantly heavier than in autumn. Changes in nutritional condition reflect seasonal variation in feeding intensity.</description><creator>Beck, Gregor Gilpin</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Harp seal -- Nutrition.</subject><title>Evaluation of condition indices relating to seasonal changes and diet of harp seals, Phoca groenlandica Erxleben 1777</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w66344880.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wk394</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Renewable Resources</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9880vs08z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Taxonomic descriptions in English and Spanish, and keys to 16 closely related species of the Muhlenbergia montana (Nutt.) Hitchc. complex were generated by means of DELTA programs, using morphological character data from an automated taxonomic data bank. A chromatographic survey of the flavonoid content of 14 species produced 24 different flavonoids, of which 22 were chemically identified. The flavonoid profiles supported the morphological delimitation of the species and provided a basis for clearly separating the annual species (M. crispiseta and M. peruviana) from the perennial species in this complex. Two new perennial species (M. cualensis and M. michisensis) were described from populations which are morphologically and chemically distinct.</description><creator>Herrera Arrieta, Yolanda</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Mountain muhly -- Classification.</subject><title>A biosystematic study of Muhlenbergia montana complex (Poaceae, Eragrostideae) /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b7373.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vs08z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913r04v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examined the intergenerational conflict between Greek immigrant parents and their Greek-Canadian children caused by differences in beliefs and practises concerning core cultural values (Greek language, Greek Orthodox religion, and Family ties). Data collected consisted of responses to open-ended, semi-structured interview questions. Interpretation of the data revealed that parents and children held congruent beliefs concerning the Greek language, yet differed in their practises of language usage. Their differing practises led to a breakdown in parent-child communication. With regard to the Greek Orthodox religion, parents and children held parallel beliefs and practises, and no apparent conflict on this issue existed. Parents' and children's opinions and actions on family solidarity were in harmony. Divergent opinions and practises emerged on issues of intermarriage and family hierarchy. Conflict manifested itself when issues of family hierarchy arose, while intermarriage was considered a potential source of conflict. The nature and amount of conflict expressed was found to be influenced by (1) parents' educational levels, and (2) gender roles of family members.</description><creator>Vlahou, Anastasia</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Intergenerational relations -- Canada</subject><subject>Greek Canadians</subject><title>Intergenerational conflict in Greek immigrant families</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jv946.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913r04v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311q436</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An experimental set-up consisting of an electron-impact induced ionization chamber, a quadrupole mass filter and an ion detector has been constructed. The operating characteristics of the quadrupole mass filter system have been examined and compared to the theoretical predictions. With a moderate mass resolution of 30, an absolute ion transmission efficiency of about 10% has been obtained. This system has been used to investigate the ionization efficiency of noble gases. Charged species up to He$ sp{2+}$, Ne$ sp{4+}$, Ar$ sp{6+}$, Kr$ sp{5+}$ and Xe$ sp{7+}$ have been studied. The behavior of the ionization efficiency curve near threshold is analyzed using a power law fitting approach. For the first and second degree ionization processes, the fitting power law coefficients k are found to be close to the charge number of the ions produced, in agreement with the theoretical predictions. The extracted ionization potentials also agree with the accepted values. For the third and higher degree of ionization, the k-values are generally much lower than the theoretical predictions. However, the extracted ionization potentials are still consistent with the accepted values.</description><creator>Wang, Gang, 1958 Nov. 28-</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Physics, Atomic.</subject><title>Performance of a quadrupole mass filter and its application for ionization potential measurements</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42n917q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311q436</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ff365622m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Odour recognition memory was studied in 49 patients with unilateral temporal lobe excision, and 20 control subjects. Odours were presented monorhinally to explore any asymmetry in performance between nostrils, and to test for hemispheric differences between patients with excision from the right versus the left temporal lobe. Testing was by a 2-alternative, forced-choice procedure, immediately after presentation and 24 hours later. A discrimination test was carried out at the conclusion of the memory test, and nondiscriminated odours were excluded from the final memory scores. The contribution of the hippocampus to odour memory was investigated by dividing patient groups according to the size of hippocampal excision. The memory test showed that only patients with excision from the left temporal lobe that included a large hippocampal removal were impaired after 24 hours. The discrimination test revealed deficits only for patients with right temporal lobectomy, and only in the right nostril.</description><creator>Williams, Jacqueline C. (Jacqueline Clare)</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Smell.</subject><subject>Olfactometry.</subject><subject>Memory.</subject><title>Human olfactory memory : effect of temporal-lobe lesions on immediate and delayed recognition of odours</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z8990.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff365622m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x513g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present work represents a study of the mixing and slag entrainment behaviour of metallurgical processes. Two immiscible fluids were mixed in a model reactor, equipped with a single centrally located tuyere, through which air was blown. For low energy input systems, it was found that the thickness of the second liquid phase can significantly affect the mixing time of the bulk phase by altering the fluid flow pattern of the liquid. The entrainment of the upper phase into the lower phase was also affected by the thickness of the upper phase, as well as by the intensity of bath agitation. At low flowrates, the number density of entrained droplets was constant with time, increasing with increasing agitation and thickness of the layer. The air flow required for the transition in the entrainment behaviour increased with an increase in the thickness of the upper phase.</description><creator>Verhelst, Dominic</creator><date>1991</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Physical modelling of gas stirred metallurgical reactors containing two liquids</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613mz72p.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x513g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87pr472</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis addresses those mine design considerations applied to mining with backfill at Denison Mines Ltd., Elliot Lake, Ontario, and reviews the specific circumstances of pillar recovery during 1985 to 1988. The rock mechanics elements of the project are presented with a case history of pillar recovery in a specific stopping district (cost center). The use of hydraulically placed cemented tailings to recover additional ore reserves from rib pillars in a room and pillar mine required a design rationale beyond the traditional empirical approach. The work undertaken to achieve this improved design includes both the study of the physical properties of the backfill, and its overall support characteristics. Design techniques involving analytical and numerical methods were coupled with ground behaviour data from daily monitoring and rock instrumentation. The backfill cost center used as a case study is back analyzed with reference to a new proposed pillar strength classification system. Improvements in ground stability are assessed and comparisons with rock burst alleviation studies are made. The geomechanical parameters involving pillar design are discussed at length in the context of rock mechanics theory. This thesis attempts to demonstrate the manner in which an integrated design rationale may be employed in a room and pillar mining environment.</description><creator>Hunt, W. G. (Wm. Gregory)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>The use of consolidated backfill for pillar recovery in room and pillar mining : an integrated design rationale</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fs539.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pr472</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p580t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A simple linear reduced-gravity ocean model is developed to simulate the North Water polynya located in northern Baffin Bay. The model is an extension of Pease (1987) latent-heat model for a coastal polynya. Both northerly surface wind forcing and coastal upwelling processes are taken into account in modelling the steady state and time-dependent water velocities, upper layer depth, and polynya width measured southward from its northern boundary. Also, both uniform and variable wind forcing are considered. In most of this thesis a semi-infinite domain model is used in which upwelling occurs along the eastern boundary (the Greenland coast). It is found that the steady state polynya width is a strong function of the air temperature, but a weak function of the wind speed. The model results show that in the upwelling region near the Greenland coast, the polynya width is larger than further offshore (distance $&gt;$ 2 Rossby radii), where it is a constant (the limiting Pease width). For a variable wind forcing, the southern ice edge of the North Water has a form that is similar to that of the wind forcing. In a channel, upwelling occurs in the eastern part and downwelling in the western part. Thus the polynya is much wider near Greenland and narrower near the Canadian Islands.</description><creator>Huang, Fengting</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Polynyas -- Baffin Bay (North Atlantic Ocean)</subject><subject>Polynyas -- Mathematical models</subject><title>A simple polynya model for the north water, northern Baffin Bay /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676w80r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p580t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Meteorology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5h73px22d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>"Ititu" is a concentrated fermented milk utilized by Borana pastoralists in Southern Ethiopia. The effect of types of container used (glass, fibrous), smoking (smoked, non-smoked) and whey withdrawal (whey, non-whey withdrawn) treatments on the microbiological and chemical compositions of the fermented milks were investigated over a storage period of 28 days. Microbiological results indicated that the type of container used had significant effect (p $&gt;$ 0.05) on total bacterial count (TBC) and lactic acid bacterial counts (LAB) for Weeks 1, 2, 3 and 4 and on coliform count (COLI) for Weeks 3 and 4. These counts determined for the fermented milks in the glass containers were found to be significantly lower compared to those in the fibrous vessels. There was significant difference (p $&gt;$ 0.05) in the overall proximate composition for container and whey withdrawal treatments compared to smoking treatment. An increased breakdown of the major caseins ($ alpha sb{ rm s1}$ and $ beta$) over the storage period was indicated. A significant increase was noted on the content of the free amino acids compared to the total amino acids over the storage period.</description><creator>Kassaye, Tarik</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Fermented milk -- Ethiopia -- Storage.</subject><subject>Milk -- Microbiology.</subject><subject>Fermented milk -- Composition.</subject><title>The microbiological and chemical composition of "Ititu" and factors affecting its production /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vs118.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73px22d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fb494964w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this thesis is to identify the implications of Paulo Freire's philosophy for education in North America. To appreciate fully the value of Freire's philosophy, this study will review six themes which are commonly found throughout his work and are significant for education. The implications of his ideas will be identified by reviewing specific case-studies conducted in the United States and Canada. Freire's ideas are developed within the context of Latin American societies. Elements of oppression and injustice in his homeland differ from the dehumanizing elements in North America. Yet, his insistence upon reflection and action as a means to emancipate people from social and political oppression has direct implications for education in the United States and Canada. North American educators have adopted, modified, and applied Freire's methodology with remarkable results.</description><creator>Hill, Philip G.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Education -- United States.</subject><subject>Freire, Paulo, 1921-1997.</subject><subject>Education -- Philosophy.</subject><subject>Education -- Canada</subject><title>Implications of Paulo Freire's thought for North American education</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78td31j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494964w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Religion and Philosophy in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sh418</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis provides an overview of the complex problems related to the extraterritoriality of export controls. In the last decades when trade became increasingly international, the tendency of governments to use trade embargoes as a political tool grew considerably. Since the effect of trade controls largely depends on the importance of the affected trade, the regulating State commonly interprets its jurisdiction in broad terms. Thus, the number of conflicts between countries concerning the extent of their jurisdiction increased. This thesis focuses on some pivotal cases and analyzes the different principles suggested to solve the problems. Based on a territorial concept of sovereignty, it finally suggests a doctrine of evasion. The fundamental idea of the doctrine has already been applied in the tax laws of several countries. It is designed to close legislative loopholes. It is believed that this doctrine, if applied, would strike an acceptable compromise between the interests of the parties concerned: the regulating State could evaluate the risks and costs involved in sanctioning other countries; the business community would be granted a higher degree of certainty in assessing the political risks involved in a commercial engagement with foreign partners and, finally, the sovereignty of foreign States would remain unimpeded.</description><creator>Rizor, Stefan</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>Extraterritoriality of export controls</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859g85r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sh418</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6395w8536</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The prevalence of abnormal pregnancy outcomes in the offspring of 103 epileptic women followed prospectively during pregnancy between 1982 and 1989 was compared with that in the previous study of 119 pregnancies by Dansky et al. from the same institution. Our results have shown a significant decrease in the prevalence of major malformations, as compared with the previous study: 8.8% vs. 24.1% (P $&lt;$ 0.01). Monotherapy was more frequent and the mean number of drugs used during pregnancy was significantly smaller in the present study. Phenytoin, phenobarbital and primidone were prescribed less frequently in the present study, whereas carbamazepine and valproic acid were used more frequently. Plasma levels of valproic acid during pregnancy were higher in mothers of malformed babies. In the present study, plasma folate levels were significantly higher, and more patients were taking folate supplements during pregnancy. In conclusion, the type and number of drugs used during pregnancy, as well as the plasma concentrations and serum folate levels, may determine the frequency of abnormal outcomes.</description><creator>Oguni, Miyako</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Health Sciences, Human Development.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Obstetrics and Gynecology.</subject><title>Trends in pregnancy outcome in epileptic women over two decades : relationship to maternal anticonvulsant therapy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20st87n.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w8536</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6q182m369</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recent years have seen major developments in the way commercial civil aviation is dealt with worldwide. As 1992, the target date for the completion of the internal market rapidly approaches, a common air transport policy is slowly taking shape in the European Economic Community. In order to allow the EEC air transport industry to adapt progressively to the new competitive environment, a two-tier liberalization process is being pursued. The second phase of the process has already commenced. Difficulties are being faced: on the one hand, the EC Commission is firmly determined to push for further liberalization; on the other hand, however, Member States are still reluctant to give up control over the airline industry. Whether a common Community air transport system will be attained by the end of 1992 necessarily depends upon each EEC Member State's political will to contribute effectively to the process of European integration.</description><creator>Pizzino, Alessandro</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Transportation.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>EEC air transportation law and its implications for the member states : focus on Italy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/70795890w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182m369</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gp53j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The impact of different methods of analysis of longitudinal pulmonary data was assessed using computer simulation and a real data set. Thirty data sets were generated: ten without random error, ten with a 10% random error and the other ten with a 20% random error. In each data set, three methods of analysis of longitudinal pulmonary data, i.e., piecewise-linear regression, linear regression and the proportional change model, were employed. In the generated data sets the piecewise-linear regression showed a 26% and 20% increase in precision of estimation of effect of exposure over the linear regression and the proportional change approaches, respectively. But such a gain in precision could not be demonstrated when the models were applied to a real data set. The effect of random measurement error in measured FEV$ sb1$ was to increase the standard error of estimation of effect of exposure, hence reduced power.</description><creator>Negassa, Abdissa</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><title>A comparative study of methods of analysis of longitudinal data with application to lung function tests /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924c935.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gp53j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54kp343</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study reports on the design, development and evaluation of a dynamic simulator for the human knee joint. The simulator was designed to facilitate the study of knee mechanics corresponding to dynamic functional activities (e.g., walking, stair ascent and descent). The simulator can be programmed to apply specified load histories to a knee specimen, in an unconstrained manner, such that the normal physiological response of the joint is reproduced. The simulator comprises of four actuators. Two stepping motors, acting as the main muscle groups, control the flexion angle histories of the joint through steel cables. Two electrohydraulic actuator systems apply the two main components of the foot-to-floor reaction; the flexing/extending moment and the tibial axial force. Actuation control and data acquisition are performed separately through two micro-computer/interface systems. Satisfactory function reproduction, corresponding to walking gait, was obtained within the following ranges and error margins for a gait cycle time of 1.25 sec: Flexion Angle: 70 $ pm$ 5$ sp circ$; Flexing Moment: 55 $ pm$ 5 Nm; Tibial Axial Force: 670 $ pm$ 67 N.</description><creator>McLean, C. A. (Christopher A.)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Design, development and performance evaluation of a dynamic knee simulator</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35t9669.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kp343</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999788z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effect of low dietary zinc on the survival and reproduction of an intestinal nematode (Heligmosomoides polygyrus) during both primary (Experiment 1) and challenge (Experiment 2) infections was investigated. Plasma zinc concentrations were significantly lower in mice fed a 5 ppm zinc diet (ZR), compared with control mice fed a 60 ppm zinc diet (C) in both experiments. There were no significant differences between ZR and C mice in any other zinc parameter or on worm burdens or worm fecundity in either experiment. Comparisons between the primary infection and the challenge infection did suggest a possible effect of calorie restriction on worm burdens. Parasitic infection did, however, affect the host nutritional status. Spleen weight was significantly higher in infected mice in both experiments. In the challenge infection, both liver and spleen copper concentrations were significantly higher, and spleen iron concentration significantly lower in the infected mice. That these significant results were seen only in the challenge infection may suggest the role of the host immune response.</description><creator>Minkus, Tracy M.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Heligmosomatidae.</subject><subject>Zinc deficiency diseases.</subject><subject>Mice -- Parasites.</subject><subject>Helminthiasis -- Nutritional aspects.</subject><title>The effect of low dietary zinc on outcome of primary and challenge nematode infections in mice /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qb115.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999788z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j675t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The works of Ernesto Sabato resemble an extensive allegory related to various aspects of humanity. Sabato is considered one of the most outstanding writers of Argentina, who has dedicated himself to commentary on contemporary issues, not only of his homeland but also of the world in general. He also invites us to share in the turmoil of his own inner self. His essays are a reflection and analysis of the sorrows and sufferings of mankind which characterize the universal catastrophe of our time. In this thesis we study the ideas contained in several of Sabato's essays, reinforced by the personal preoccupations that characterize the author's perspective. In the various stages of our pilgrimage through the universe of his essays, we observe his quest as witness to artistic Argentinian creativity, as well as spokesman of human reactions in the midst of the present-day cataclysm. We not only emphasize Sabato's trajectory throughout perversity and corruption, but also the solidarity and hope, as total expression of the human being that lives and struggles in a chaotic universe.</description><creator>Contente, Maria G.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Sábato, Ernesto R. -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>Temas ensayísticos de Ernesto Sábato</title><language>spa</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5x21tg54q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j675t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Hispanic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445cf44h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A survey of the minimal realization theory of Arbib and Manes for "state-behavior" machines in a category is given, and how the closed category machines of Goguen are included in the above machines is discussed in detail. A survey of the non-deterministic treatment due to Arbib and Manes is given. A study of C-machines in a closed category for a monoid C is given in both the deterministic and the non-deterministic cases. A notion of u-machine in a topos for a morphism of monoids u is introduced and studied. A discussion of the category of H-valued sets as a topos is given and finally some of the concepts of automata theory for the deterministic case are investigated in this context, regarding the category of H-valued sets as a closed category and especially when H is a finite chain.</description><creator>Monserrat Antich, Miquel</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Machines in closed categories in general and in categories of heyting Algebra valued sets in particular</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924c94f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cf44h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806058v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Leigh-Browne, Giles.</creator><date>1973</date><subject>Ascariasis</subject><subject>Ascaris</subject><subject>Intestine, Small</subject><title>An in vivo study of the effects of controlled Ascaris infections on the small intestine of the miniature pig.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741s54v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806058v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nv34h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Langford, John W.</creator><date>1973</date><subject>Canada. Dept. of Transport</subject><title>The reorganization of the federal transport portfolio; the application of a ministry system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cr20n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nv34h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149q61j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Kwan, Wan Hing.</creator><date>1972</date><subject>Diptera -- Québec (Province)</subject><title>Culicoides spp. (Diptera: Ceratopogonidae) at Lac Serpent, Quebec, with emphasis on the larval habitats and numbers of C. sanguisuga (Coquillett) and C. obsoletus (Meigen).</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rn301207w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149q61j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn9997455</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Lavoie, Clermont</creator><date>1972</date><subject>Prospecting -- Geophysical methods</subject><subject>Electromagnetic measurements</subject><title>Une combinaison des methodes electromagnetiques a cadres horizontaux "Slingram" et Turam.</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311q10n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn9997455</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining Engineering and Applied Geophysics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k0698827w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:56:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Kubina, Stanley James</creator><date>1972</date><subject>Airplanes -- Radio antennas.</subject><subject>Mobile communication systems</subject><title>Radiation characteristics of vehicle-mounted antennas and their application to comprehensive system design.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z864w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698827w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):22475</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>