<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:40:48Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):39450" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf268705x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis investigates the implementation of lazy functional programming languages on parallel machines using a novel approach to strictness analysis called "abstract demand propagation" and examines the impact of laziness on parallelism. Although some work on strictness analysis using demand propagation has been done before, the present work is original in that it gives a precise interpretation of the notions of demands and demand propagation using non-standard denotational semantics. The intuition behind the notion of (abstract) demand propagation is that it can be seen as a form of (abstract) inverse computation. This form of strictness analysis has been incorporated into a prototype compiler for a lazy variant of (a subset of) the Id functional programming language targeted for the TTDA dataflow machine, which makes it the first implementation of a lazy language on a dataflow architecture. The overall structure of that compiler is described together with some novel features incorporated in the compiler. The last part of the thesis examines the question of whether sufficient parallelism can be obtained from programs written in a lazy functional language, which is done by comparing various implementation strategies: purely lazy, optimized lazy and lenient. As little parallelism can effectively be obtained using lazy strategies, the notion of "bounded speculative laziness" is introduced in order to tentatively improve the parallelism of the programs while preserving the key characteristic of laziness, i.e., the ability to manipulate potentially infinite data objects.</description><creator>Tremblay, Guy</creator><contributor>Gao, G. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Parallel implementation of lazy functional languages using abstract demand propagation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451k57j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268705x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dj52w670q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A three-year (1991-1993) investigation was done in the field and laboratory to study the bionomics of Smicronyx guineanus Voss and Sm. umbrinus Hustache and the spatial distribution of Striga hermonthica (Del.) Benth. Studies on the life history of the weevils were undertaken. Seasonal activity and habits were established by monitoring life stages in the field. A behavioral Time Budget of Smicronyx adults was established in semi-field conditions. Dispersion patterns and the optimum sample size for Smicronyx and Striga were determined. Smicronyx adults as well as Striga plants were aggregated in the field. Smicronyx larvae were located in the upper stratum of the witchweed (93.2%) where they make galls and destroy large number of seeds. The effect of precipitation on emergence of Smicronyx adults was investigated in the insectary. The optimum rainfall required for Smicronyx adult emergence ranged from 30 to 40 mm. Good synchrony and positive association of Sm. guineanus and Sm. umbrinus with S. hermonthica were observed. There are good prospects for augmentation and/or conservation of Smicronyx populations as part of an integrated control strategy of S. hermonthica.</description><creator>Traoré, Doulaye</creator><contributor>Stewart, R. K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Purple witchweed -- Biological control -- Burkina Faso.</subject><subject>Smicronyx -- Burkina Faso.</subject><title>Bionomics of Smicronyx guineanus Voss and Sm. umbrinus Hustache (Coleoptera:Curculionidae) : potential biocontrol agents of Striga hermonthica (Del.) Benth. (Scrophulariaceae) in Burkina Faso (West Africa)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cv90q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w670q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290c461</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The potential of dielectric heating with microwaves at 2450 MHz for drying grapes into raisins was studied. Feasibility studies in a conventional microwave oven were successful. A new microwave drying system equipped with specialized instrumentation and data acquisition components and permitting full control of microwave power levels and duration of application was then developed and used for detailed experimental work. It was found that when the grapes were dipped in surfactants, as is common practice in the raisin industry, microwave drying was not only faster than convective drying but also had a much lower specific energy requirement. However, it was also possible to obtain raisins of adequate quality without dippings. Good quality light coloured raisins were obtained without sulphur dioxide fumigation. Thus, microwave drying has potential in reducing both the quantity of chemicals entering at this point in the food chain and the energy consumed for food preservation. The shrinkage and density of grapes were found to be linearly related to moisture content; initial size and method of drying had no influence. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Tulasidas, Tarikere N.</creator><contributor>Raghavan, G. S. V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Microwave drying.</subject><subject>Grapes -- Drying.</subject><subject>Raisins.</subject><title>Combined convective and microwave drying of grapes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544br378.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290c461</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x3287</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Saccharomyces cerevisiae genes KRE6 and SKN1 encode a novel pair of highly homologous proteins involved in cell wall (1$ rightarrow$6)-$ beta$-glucan assembly. Disruption of KRE6 results in a slow growing, killer-toxin resistant mutant possessing reduced levels of structurally wild type (1$ rightarrow$6)-$ beta$-glucan. Although deletion of SKN1 has no effect on killer sensitivity, growth, or (1$ rightarrow$6)-$ beta$-glucan levels, SKN1 appears to overlap in function with KRE6, suppressing kre6 null alleles in a dosage-dependent manner. Strains deleted of both KRE6 and SKN1 possess an exaggerated growth phenotype, enhanced cell wall ultrastructure defects, and more severe (1$ rightarrow$6)-$ beta$-glucan reductions compared with either single disruptant. Moreover, the residual (1$ rightarrow$6)-$ beta$-glucan polymer in kre6 skn1 double mutants is smaller in size and altered in structure. Since single disruptions of either gene lead to structurally wild type (1$ rightarrow$6)-$ beta$-glucan, KRE6 and SKN1 appear to function independently and to act early in the assembly of the polymer, possibly as glucan synthases. Consistent with their direct role in the assembly of this polymer, both Kre6p and Skn1p possess C-terminal domains with significant sequence similarity to two recently identified glucan-binding proteins. An initial characterization of Kre6p and Skn1p reveal both to be phosphorylated integral-membrane glycoproteins, with Kre6p likely localized to the Golgi apparatus. The topology implied by the post-translational modifications of Kre6p and Skn1p, offers the potential for both proteins to link cytoplasmic regulation with a secretory pathway-based assembly of the (1$ rightarrow$6)-$ beta$-glucan polymer. The observed phosphorylation of both Kre6p and Skn1p prompted an examination for genetic interactions with suspected cell wall regulating kinases. KRE6-dependent suppression of the pkc1 lysis defect, as well as synthetic lethal interactions between several KRE genes and members of the PKC1-mediated MAP kinase pathway, supports a role for the PKC1 pathway in regulating synthesis of cell wall components, including (1$ rightarrow$6)-$ beta$-glucan.</description><creator>Roemer, Terry</creator><contributor>Bussey, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Glucans</subject><subject>Saccharomyces cerevisiae -- Genetics</subject><title>Characterization of the Saccharomyces cerevisiae KRE6 and SKN1 genes and their role in (1-6)-B-D glucan production</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g934f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x3287</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gf90c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The formulation and implementation of a far field boundary condition (FFBC) model for compressible flows is reported in this thesis. This FFBC model, developed for quasi-one-dimensional and two-dimensional flows, aims to permit a substantial reduction of the computational domain, leading to a considerable improvement in the computational efficiency. The present FFBC approach uses asymptotic expansions of the Riemann variables, which are truncated up to the required degree of accuracy. Then, the far field perturbation equations are integrated in time and applied in conjunction with the solution calculated within the computational domain. The propagating information from the computational domain is determined along the outgoing characteristic fronts, based on the estimation of the wave front orientation. The proposed FFBC model is implemented in conjunction with an implicit finite-difference flow field solver using an alternating direction implicit (ADI) scheme for solving the Euler equations. The discretized form of the governing equations are solved using a time-marching technique until the steady-state solution is reached. An accurate procedure for the solid boundary treatment was also used. The proposed FFBC model was used for solving typical problems of confined and external compressible flows in subsonic and transonic regimes. For the transonic regime, the proposed FFBC model has been extended for the case of non-isentrophic outgoing flows, which appear behind the shock waves. The solutions obtained are compared with previous theoretical and numerical results. This comparison shows that the proposed FFBC model can generate accurate solutions using a substantially reduced computational domain, which reduces by an order of magnitude the size of the block tridiagonal matrices to be inverted. This leads to a corresponding improvement in the overall computational efficiency.</description><creator>Razavi, Seyed Esmail</creator><contributor>Mateescu, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><title>Far field boundary conditions for computation of compressible aerodynamic flows</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612q59p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gf90c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rg40s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Myeloid cells are important reservoirs of HIV-1 infection. In response to pathogenic agents, macrophages secrete inflammatory cytokines which can stimulate viral replication and contribute to AIDS pathogenesis. Two promonocytic cell models were used to investigate the relationship between NF-$ kappa$B dependent cytokine gene expression, differentiation, and HIV infection: the U937 and PLB-985 cell lines and their chronically infected counterparts U9-IIIB and PLB-IIIB. Chronic HIV-1 infection of U9-IIIB cells did not generally lead to constitutive transcription of cytokine genes. However, when co-infected with Sendai virus or stimulated with lipopolysaccharide, the induction of IFN$ beta$, IL-1$ beta$, IL-6 and TNF$ alpha$ mRNA occurred more rapidly and was increased to levels 10 to 20-fold higher in U9-IIIB cells compared to similarly induced U937 cells. Chronic infection of PLB-985 cells led to irreversible differentiation along the monocytic pathway. In PLB-985 cells, TNF$ alpha$ or PMA treatment led to induction of NF-$ kappa$B p50 subunit binding, whereas chronic HIV or acute Sendai virus infection led to a distinct NF-$ kappa$B-like binding activity composed of 70, 90 and 100 kDa proteins with high specificity for binding the PRDII domain of IFN$ beta$. UV cross-linking, shifted-shift and immunoprecipitation analyses indicated that p50 and the strong transcriptional activator p65 represented the major constituents of this NF-$ kappa$B DNA-binding activity. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Roulston, Anne</creator><contributor>Hiscott, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>Regulation of NF-kB dependent cytokine gene expression in chronically HIV-1 infected myeloid cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096914v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rg40s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gj38f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis uses a theoretical model to consider whether plaintiffs paying lawyers on a contingent fee basis receive smaller payoffs than those retaining lawyers on an hourly basis. This is the view in England, where contingent fees are illegal. It is also a view recognised in America, where contingent fees are legal and commonly used in some areas of law. The issue revolves around whether contingent fee lawyers will settle cases too soon for their clients to receive a substantial settlement offer. In an incomplete information, multiperiod bargaining model of personal injury litigation, we show that this need not be true: even if lawyers are self-interested, plaintiffs can receive higher payoffs under contingent fees than under hourly ones. Considerable ambiguity surrounds plaintiffs' preferred fee arrangement and the speed at which any settlement occurs under the different fee contracts. The most crucial role in this comparison is played by the distribution of legal expenses between plaintiffs and their lawyers. Our model therefore confirms the payoff ambiguity found in previous literature while being the first to address the settlement timing issue. It also suggests that the issue of how different fee arrangements affect the plaintiff in litigation is somewhat more complicated than policy debates on both sides of the Atlantic have implied.</description><creator>Rickman, Neil</creator><contributor>Long, N. V. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Hogan, S. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Lawyers -- Fees -- Mathematical models</subject><title>The effects of contingent and hourly fees on litigation outcomes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nd015.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gj38f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xt72c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Study of the Entomophthorales infection in selected black fly populations from two outlets of a lake was conducted at the Reserve Faunique du Saint-Maurice (Quebec). Entomophaga near limoniae infected Simulium verecundum/rostratum, whereas Erynia curvispora predominantly parasitized Simulium decorum, and Erynia conica infected Simulium venustum and the Simulium verecundum/rostratum and Simulium vittatum complexes. This is the first report of the presence of Erynia conica and Entomophaga near limoniae in North America and Erynia curvispora in Canada. Entomophaga near limoniae in black flies represents a new association. A successful method for rearing Simulium rostratum, and the in vitro production of fungal conidiospores, produced a sufficient supply of material to study the cuticular invasion process of Erynia conica in the laboratory. Both Erynia species exhibited a diurnal periodicity in the formation of secondary conidiospores in darkness in vitro. This mode of development was influenced by the pH of the medium. The cyclic pattern in secondary conidia formation by Erynia conica disappeared with exposure to light, which suggests that photoperiod may be a factor contributing to host infection. Only secondary type 2 conidia of Erynia conica produced germ tubes that invaded the cuticle of the proper host, Simulium rostratum as opposed to the primary conidia. The infective unit exhibited delayed germination and formed neither appressoria nor invaded the cuticle of the non-host, Simulium decorum, which may explain the host specificity observed in the field study. Cuticular lipids triggered appressoria formation and penetration pegs on the host black fly and did not seem to inhibit fungal invasion on the non-host. The effects of selected physical factors on the development of the infective unit of Erynia conica were determined. Germination and sporulation in vitro were influenced by medium pH, environmental temperature and charge of the substrate, but both processes were independent of substrate hydrophobicity. Germination and sporulation occurred throughout the pH and temperature ranges tested, with both achieving maximum at pH 7.5-8.0 and 10-20$ sp circ$C. Temperature range of the germination of the conidiospores in situ was similar that in vitro, which corresponded to the temperature variation in the field. Production of invasive structures was noted for in situ experiments only and was more temperature sensitive than was germination.</description><creator>Nadeau, Martin P. (Martin Pierre)</creator><contributor>Dunphy, Gary (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Entomophthorales.</subject><subject>Simuliidae -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Simuliidae -- Biological control.</subject><title>Physiological ecology of Erynia conica and Erynia curvispora (Zygomycetes: Entomophthorales) attacking black flies (Diptera: Simuliidae) in Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591b26x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xt72c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q610w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since the formulation of the monoaminergic hypotheses of depression, several investigations have established that the serotonin (5-HT) as well as the noradrenaline (NA) systems are altered by antidepressant treatments. In the last few years, several studies have indicated that interactions between these two systems might also be important in the mechanism of action of antidepressant drugs. We have thus undertaken: (1) to elucidate the nature of some interactions between the 5-HT and NA systems in the rat hippocampus using in vivo electrophysiology and in vitro superfusion techniques; and (2) to determine whether antidepressant treatments alter these interactions. It was found that NA tonically inhibits 5-HT neurotransmission via $ alpha sb2$-adrenergic heteroreceptors. In addition, the presence of 5-HT$ sb3$ receptors facilitating the release of NA was also documented in this brain region. These receptors were shown to be activated by elevated levels of endogenous 5-HT, but did not appear to be activated by basal levels of this neurotransmitter. Long-term administrations of antidepressant drugs commonly known to increase the synaptic concentration of NA, i.e. monoamine oxidase and NA reuptake inhibitors, were found to desensitize the $ alpha sb2$-adrenoceptors that inhibit the release of 5-HT. This effect was also produced by atypical antidepressant drugs that have $ alpha sb2$-adrenergic antagonist properties (e.g. mianserin and idazoxan), but not by other antidepressant treatments, (e.g. selective 5-HT reuptake inhibitors or electroconvulsive shocks). In contrast to $ alpha sb2$-adrenergic heteroreceptors, 5-HT$ sb3$ receptors that enhance the release of NA did not become desensitized following long-term treatments with drugs that elevate the synaptic concentration of their endogenous neurotransmitter. Rather, the responsiveness of these 5-HT$ sb3$ receptors became blunted following an antidepressant treatment (desipramine) that caused a large increase in the r</description><creator>Mongeau, Raymond</creator><contributor>Blier, Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>de Montigny, Claude (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>The serotonergic and noradrenergic systems of the hippocampus : their interactions and the effects of antidepressant treatments</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xg79b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q610w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qr53t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The catalytic $ alpha$ subunit of the heterodimeric Na,K-ATPase comprises three distinct isoforms which are expressed in a tissue-specific manner. For example, the $ alpha sb1$ isoform can be detected in virtually all mammalian tissues, whereas the appearance of the $ alpha sb2$ and $ alpha sb3$ isoforms is more restricted to particular tissues such as muscle and nervous tissue. Previous comparative functional studies of Na,K-ATPases isolated from various tissues indicated that there are differences, including apparent cation affinities, among these enzymes. While these differences often appear to correlate with the presence of distinct isozymes, their precise molecular bases remain to be determined. Moreover, certain studies suggest that the behavior of the same isoform can vary from tissue to tissue (e.g., the erythrocyte versus the kidney, both of which contain only the $ alpha sb1$ isoform). An hypothesis that may explain these observations is that the cell-specific membrane environment influences Na,K-ATPase activity. To investigate this possibility, polyethylene glycol-mediated membrane fusion was used to deliver pumps from high-specific-activity microsomes derived from various tissues into mammalian erythrocyte membranes. The success of this methodology was verified using two distinct experimental systems. In the first system, rabbit sarcoplasmic reticulum Ca-ATPase was delivered into human erythrocyte membranes. Cellular Ca$ sp{2+}$ uptake fueled by extracellular ATP was used as a measure of the functional delivery of the Ca-ATPase into these membranes. In the second system, ATP- and cardiac glycoside-dependent rubidium fluxes verified the functional delivery of axolemma or kidney Na,K-ATPases into mammalian erythrocytes. Among these studies was a series of experiments demonstrating that the L$ rm sb{p}$-antigen of sheep erythrocyte membranes is a distinct membrane component that interacts with and alters the behavior of rat kidney pumps fused into LK she</description><creator>Munzer, Jon Scott</creator><contributor>Blostein, Rhoda (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Comparative kinetic properties of tissue-specific Na,K-pumps</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f545c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qr53t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ht24wm21w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation analyzes the nature and degree of attitudinal change that has taken place within a key sector of the Catholic Church, i.e, lay leaders, in the period between 1966 and 1987 in two different national contexts, Chile and the United States. It builds on an unfinished study by Ivan Vallier, who attempted to clarify the ambiguous position of the laity in the Church and in society, in implementing the reforms of Vatican II. The author interviewed 96 middle-class lay leaders, plus dozens of informants. The analysis examines continuity and change on three issues. Some key findings include: a significant change in concepts of Church and God, toward more intimate/maternal images that encompass an active social dimension; much greater salience and complexity of the 'democratization' issue, particularly concerning the role of women, in the American Church; and the continuing imperative of the socio-political issue for the Chileans and their demands for more, not less, political involvement by the hierarchy. The results reflect the persistent tensions between 'progressive' and 'conservative' models of change, and help to explain the continuing importance of religion in modern society.</description><creator>Mooney, Mary</creator><contributor>Oxhorn, Phil (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Catholic Church -- Chile -- Public opinion</subject><subject>Catholic Church -- Chile -- Political activity</subject><subject>Laity -- United States -- Catholic Church -- Attitudes</subject><subject>Laity -- Chile -- Catholic Church -- Attitudes</subject><subject>Chile -- Church history -- 20th century</subject><subject>Catholic Church -- United States -- History -- 1965-</subject><subject>Catholic Church -- United States -- Public opinion</subject><subject>United States -- Church history -- 20th century</subject><subject>Catholic Church -- Chile -- History -- 1965-</subject><title>Challenge to authority : Catholic laity in Chile and the United States, 1966-1987</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87ps40b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wm21w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kv78c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The concentration of hydrogen is one of the most important parameters in liquid aluminum processing because it is responsible for gas porosity which affects casing quality, ie. pressure tightness, mechanical properties etc. In order to gain optimum quality, the amount of hydrogen dissolved in liquid aluminum must be known prior to casting. This has led to the development of several techniques to quantify hydrogen in liquid aluminum. Among these is the Reduced Pressure Test (RPT). The RPT is simple, very inexpensive and commonly used in aluminum foundries to obtain a qualitative evaluation of the melt hydrogen level. In this thesis the development of the RPT to a truly quantitative level is discussed. This includes redesigning of the steel mold and the application of a riser. The mold was redesigned to improve the test sensitivity while a CO$ sb2$-bonded sand riser was applied in order to eliminate volumetric shrinkage and ensure a constant volume sample. As the sample has a constant volume, either the sample weight or density can be used to quantify the hydrogen content. The simplest technique is to use the sample weight. Several parameters that affect the test sensitivity and reproducibility were studied, such as chamber pressure, amount of inclusions, pouring temperature, and mold temperature. It was found that there are two important parameters that strongly affect the test; chamber pressure and amount of inclusions. The lower the chamber pressure the better the test sensitivity but the poorer the test reproducibility. Increasing the amount of inclusions improves the test sensitivity. The constant volume sample can be used to predict the amount of hydrogen in the melt for various types of alloys including 319, 356, 357 and 413 within a reasonable margin of error. The error as measured by this technique was found to be in the range of $ pm$0.025-0.049 ml./100 g.Al. if the sample weight is used, and in the range of $ pm$0.025-0.047 ml./100 g,Al. if the sample density is used. A simple mathematical model based on a mass balance approach was developed to calculate pore size and sample density. The model predicts the density accurately for various types of alloys and different melt treatments.</description><creator>La-Orchan, Wittaya</creator><contributor>Gruzleski, J. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Quantification of the reduced pressure test</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n309m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kv78c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354h21h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In order to identify organizational differences between sterile Polima (pol) and fertile Campestris (cam) mitochondrial genomes that could be linked to cytoplasmic male sterility (CMS), the physical map of the pol mitochondrial genome was constructed and compared to the physical map of the cam mitochondrial genome. The only structural differences between the two genomes are confined to a region encompassed by a 4.5 kb segment, present in pol mtDNA but absent in cam mtDNA. This 4.5 kb CMS-associated pol segment contains a chimeric gene called orf224 that is cotranscribed with atpG and comprises the single mtDNA region expressed differently in fertile, sterile and fertility restored plants which makes it a good candidate for specifying the sterility trait. Sequence analysis of the pol 4.5 kb segment has shown that orf224 was the only significant open reading frame (ORF) within the segment that gives rise to abundant transcripts, strengthening the view that the orf224/atp6 gene region is conferring pol male sterility. The pol 4.5 kb segment is also present and similarly organized in the common Brassica napus nap mtDNA but the sequences flanking the two segments are unrelated. Thus, the 4.5 kb segment appears to have transposed during the evolution of the pol and nap mitochondrial genomes and appears to have been lost in the cam mitochondrial genome. Sequence analysis of the nap segment revealed the presence of an ORF related to but divergent from orf224. This open reading frame (orf222) potentially encodes a protein of 222 amino-acids with 79% homology to the predicted product of orf224. orf222 is co-transcribed with the third exon of the trans-spliced gene, nad5, and another ORF of unknown function. Expression of the orf222 gene region is tightly associated with nap CMS since the levels of orf222 transcripts are significantly reduced upon restoration while the expression of 22 other mitochondrial genes do not consistently correlate with nap CMS. Antibodies were rai</description><creator>L'Homme, Yvan</creator><contributor>Brown, G. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Cytoplasmic male sterility</subject><subject>Plant mitochondria</subject><subject>Mitochondrial DNA</subject><subject>Rape (Plant) -- Cytogenetics.</subject><title>Molecular characterization of cytoplasmic male sterility in Brassica napus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117q793.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354h21h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nc580p46s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Monte Carlo simulations used for representing dynamical physical phenomena are studied in terms of a Markov chain operator acting on the probability distrubution of the states of a given system. The most general transition rule satisfying detailed balance and leading to a canonical ensemble probability distribution is derived using this formalism. The explicit Markov chain representing the two most commonly used canonical algorithms, the Metropolis and the Glauber transition rules, is then constructed and numerically applied to the states of an Ising model. The dynamical properties of the system are studied for each algorithm. Various measures, such as time-time correlation functions, are estimated for different system sizes and finite-size sealing is applied. In particular, the effects of the transition rule on the dynamic critical exponent is investigated. We at first examine one- and two-dimensional systems using periodic boundary conditions. Systems with free boundary conditions were also studied, and their results were equivalent with respect to the dynamical critical properties of the system. The effects of conservation laws were also investigated and both conserved and non-conserved systems were studied. Both local and non-local spin-exchange dynamics were investigated for conserved systems. Finally, our approach was used to simulate quenches on small systems. This method is them used to analyze phenomenological transformations done by dynamical renormalization-group (RG) methods. It is found that, when the RG transformation is linear in probability space, there exists a corresponding Markov chain generating the time sequence of the renormalized systems. An example is given for the one-dimensional Ising model.</description><creator>Lacasse, Martin Daniel</creator><contributor>Grant, Martin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Exact dynamics of small Ising systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t1116.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580p46s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tx096</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Urea, N-methylurea and carbamate linked thymidine dimers, 38, 37 and 39 respectively, were synthesized efficiently and incorporated into 12- and 19-mer DNA oligonucleotide strands, via solid-phase synthesis. Thermal denaturation studies utilizing complementary single stranded DNA, RNA and duplex DNA, indicated selectivity of binding of all three backbone modified oligomers to single stranded DNA. The oligomer containing dimer 37 exhibited the strongest binding to single stranded DNA. Carbamate and 5$ sp prime$-N-methylurea modified dimers suitable for the preparation of longer nucleoside homopolymers were efficiently prepared from either thymidine or 3$ sp prime$-azido-3$ sp prime$-deoxythymidine. Three efficient syntheses of precursors (7, 33, 36) of carbamoylpolyoxamic acid starting from L-arabinose were developed. Utilizing uridine as the starting material, an expedient synthesis of a precursor (44) to the nucleoside moiety of polyoxin L was also achieved. The conversion of cyanides to carboxylic acids was extensively investigated. Protected polyoxamic acid 17 was synthesized in 11 steps from L-arabinose.* ftn*Please refer to the dissertation for diagrams.</description><creator>Kutterer, Kristina M. K.</creator><contributor>Just, George (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Urea and carbamate backbone modified DNA &amp; work towards a synthesis of polyoxin L and analogues</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278w18f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tx096</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591b276</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A comprehensive characterization of silver and bismuth refining crusts produced during the pyrometallurgical refining of lead was undertaken. Parameters such as intermetallic crystal size and composition, and degree of metal entrainment were determined. Silver crust was found to be composed mostly of the $ epsilon$-phase (AgZn$ sb3$) with an average particle size of 50 $ mu$m. Liquid lead entrainment of 80 volume percent was measured. The intermetallic phase in bismuth crust was composed entirely of CaMg$ rm sb2Bi sb2$ crystals with an average diameter of 50 $ mu$m. Lead entrainment in bismuth crust was approximately 90 volume percent. The high degree of metal entrainment observed in both silver and bismuth crusts was not adequately explained through a capillary model of liquid metal entrainment in a static bed of solid particles. The models used to predict swelling in colloidal particle systems (such as clay soils) were found to better approximate the high degree of liquid entrainment. Experiments were performed in which particle beds of $ gamma$-phase ($ rm Ag sb5Zn sb8$) intermetallic compound were infiltrated with liquid lead under controlled conditions and examined under the optical microscope. Image analysis revealed pronounced swelling of fine particle beds relative to coarse. The effect was most noticeable for average particle diameters less than 100 $ mu$m where the solids volume fraction decreased from 50 to 30 vol.%. Data showed samples LO exhibit a constant increase in inter-particle spacing of approximately 50 $ mu$m. The increase in spacing explained the degree of swelling at low particle diameters and was also used to develop an expression to predict height of capillary rise. Based on an osmotic pressure analogy in colloidal particle systems, a swelling pressure term was defined to explain the increase in inter-particle spacing. The swelling pressure was defined as equal and opposite to the capillary pressure tending to force particles to random packing. It was concluded that swelling was related to mass transfer at the solid-liquid interface of the intermetallic crystals giving a reduced static pressure due to a localized minimization of Gibbs energy. The static pressure change (swelling pressure) was attributed to overlap of mass transfer boundary layers where mid-point static liquid metal pressure is less than the pressure in the bulk liquid. For the system studied, the mass transfer boundary layer was estimated to be approximately 100 $ mu$m in thickness. Further experiments, using the sessile drop technique, were used to support the study findings by showing rapid spreading of liquid lead on Ag-Zn intermetallic substrates. The rapid spreading was attributed to mass transfer at the solid-liquid interface giving a reduced interfacial energy, $ gamma sb{ rm s1}$ due to a localized reduction in Gibbs energy. The analysis of experimental results led to the development of two new industrial processes in the lead industry aimed at reducing lead loss to silver and bismuth crusts. Tests employing continuous agitation during bismuth removal from lead promoted the growth of large $ rm CaMg sb2Bi sb2$ crystals. The larger crystals minimized the effect of mass transfer boundary layer overlap and reduced lead entrainment from 90 to 80 volume percent. The addition of a low melting point KCl-ZnCl$ sb2$ salt during silver crust formation was found to remove up to 90% of entrained lead by the salt preferentially wetting Ag-Zn intermetallic particles. This was found to eliminate surface forces which retained liquid in the system of solid particles.</description><creator>Hancock, Peter</creator><contributor>Harris, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Metal entrainment in continuous liquid phase drosses</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666649m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591b276</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591b28g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Five experiments were undertaken to identify metabolites and hormones that could mediate the effect of dietary energy status on reproduction, particularly pulsatile secretion of luteinizing hormone (LH) postpartum dairy cows. In the first two experiments, the concentration of progesterone (P4) in tailhead adipose tissue and plasma in 12 cows at different stages of pregnancy and lactation was determined as was P4 produced in vitro by explants of tailhead adipose tissue. Concentration of P4 in adipose tissue was correlated with that of plasma P4 near estrus and during the luteal phase of the estrous cycle, and P4 was released in vitro by fat mobilization. In the third and fourth experiments, blood was collected continuously for 16 h from four ovariectomized cows offered maintenance or restricted energy diets after priming with P4 or estradiol (E2) using a crossover experimental design. The results indicated that P4 released during body fat mobilization is minor and is not related to LH secretion. Dietary energy restriction influenced plasma LH concentration and pulse amplitude but the effect was modulated by P4 and E2 priming. Dietary energy restriction decreased glucose concentration but did not influence plasma non-esterified fatty acids (NEFA), cortisol, P4 and insulin levels. Cortisol was negatively related to LH pulse frequency. Glucose and insulin were positively and negatively correlated with LH pulse amplitude, respectively. Cortisol, NEFA and glucose jointly had a negative correlation with LH concentration. In the fifth experiment, blood samples were collected daily for 60 d and every 10 min for 8 h on 18, 36 and 54 d postpartum from 24 cows (12 ovariectomized) fed low (1.4 Mcal/kg DM) (L) or high (1.7 Mcal/kg DM) (H) energy in a 2 x 2 factorial treatment design. LH pulse frequency was reduced at 18 d postpartum in ovariectomized cows, but not in intact cows, fed L. First postpartum ovulation occurred later in intact cows fed L compared to those fed H. Energy balance and plasma glucose concentration were lower, but plasma NEFA, $ beta$-hydroxybutyrate (BHB) and E2 concentrations higher, in cows fed L compared to those fed H. E2 concentration in intact cows fed L was elevated for a prolonged period prior to first ovulation. Diet had no influence on plasma P4 and insulin concentrations. Plasma E2 and BHB concentrations were positively correlated with LH pulse frequency in intact cows across diets and ovariectomized cows fed L, respectively. NEFA were negatively correlated with LH pulse amplitude in ovariectomized cows fed L. Glucose, NEFA and P4 were negatively, but BHB, E2 and insulin positively correlated, individually or in association, with LH concentration. Overall, the results suggest that the effect of dietary energy status on LH patterns and timing of onset of postpartum ovulation is modulated by priming with or presence of ovarian steroids. The relationships of metabolites and hormones with LH patterns appear to change with dietary energy level, ovarian status and mutual associations among the metabolites and hormones. These parameters, especially glucose and BHB, may be potential mediators of the effect of dietary energy status on LH patterns. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Hamudikuwanda, Humphrey</creator><contributor>Downey, B. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Dairy cattle -- Reproduction.</subject><subject>Dairy cattle -- Metabolism.</subject><subject>Reproduction -- Endocrine aspects</subject><title>Endocrine and metabolic mediators of dietary energy status and reproduction in dairy cows</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d192n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591b28g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k643b311p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A Cooperative Distributed Problem Solving system (CDPS) is composed of a set of agents designed to solve a single problem by working together in a cooperative fashion. In this thesis, we present models and tools which aid the CDPS designer in determining how data items are to be shared between the agents (data distribution) in a CDPS, when the agents are implemented as rule-based systems. Our models consider CDPS from two different perspectives: the inter-agent perspective, and the intra-agent perspective. The inter-agent perspective is concerned with issues relating to the manner in which the agents in a CDPS achieve cooperation. The intra-agent perspective is concerned with the internal structure of an agent, and how an agent is affected when it cooperates with other agents. The inter-agent perspective is modeled using a notion of an "organization" that is imposed on a set of agents sharing data items via a "blackboard"; this model permits the CDPS designer to indicate the mechanism used to achieve both forms of cooperation between the rule-based systems in a CDPS: cooperation by sharing data, and cooperation for control. The intra-agent perspective is modeled using a notion of a "path", which captures the sequence of rules fired by a rule-based system. Based upon the path model, we have developed two tools: Path Hunter and Path Tracer. The models and tools described in this thesis permit the CDPS designer to study the impact of the data distribution chosen for a CDPS on the performance of a rule-based system that will be a member of that CDPS; this helps the CDPS designer in setting the data distribution within a CDPS.</description><creator>Grossner, Clifford</creator><contributor>Radhakrishnan, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Newborn, Monty (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Models and tools for cooperating rule-based systems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w168g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b311p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h643x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Germaine Tailleferre (1892-1983) is best known as the only woman in the "Groupe des Six". This thesis purports to shed greater light on her work, hitherto largely unknown, as well as to present biographical information and a catalogue of compositions. The analytical study intends to demonstrate expertise, which lay in the use of the "motive" as a generative component of form. In order to demonstrate the latter concept, an analytical model has been developed comprising three methods of analysis: motivic, reductive and formal. Three pieces of different genres and styles representative of Tailleferre's work have been analyzed using this analytical model: (1) Quatuor a cordes (1917-1919); (2) it Image (1918); (3) Cantate du Narcisse (1938). Musical analysis of these pieces reveals the "organic cohesion" in Tailleferre's work, which consists of an intrinsic relation between motive and form.</description><creator>Harbec, Jacinthe, 1955-</creator><contributor>Alphonce, Bo (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Tailleferre, Germaine, 1892-1983 -- Bibliography -- Catalogs</subject><subject>Tailleferre, Germaine, 1892-1983 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>Oeuvres de Germaine Tailleferre : du motif à la forme</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jd24q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h643x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r781wh96m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>DiGeorge syndrome (DGS) is a developmental defect associated with deletions in chromosomal region 22q11.2. Recently, other syndromes (Velo-Cardio-Facial syndrome, Conotruncal Anomaly Face syndrome, isolated conotruncal cardiopathy) with overlapping phenotypes have been found to be associated with deletions of a similar extent in this chromosomal region. All these syndromes have been grouped under the acronym CATCH 22 (Cardiac defect, Abnormal facies, Thymic hypoplasia, Cleft palate, Hypocalcemia, chromosome 22q11.2 deletions). In order to characterize genetically this group of syndromes, we have searched for deletions in the 22q11.2 chromosomal region by fluorescence in situ hybridization (FISH). A set of 6 cosmid probes dispersed within the whole length of the DGS deleted region was used to screen 23 patients. A 22q11.2 deletion was observed in 96% of the patients studied. Furthermore, there does not seem to exist any correlation between the size of the deletion and the phenotype observed, since the majority of patients studied, although widely divergent in their clinical manifestation of DGS, appeared to present the same extent of deletion in this genomic region. There appears to be a predominance of deletion-bearing mothers in familial CATCH 22 when published pedigrees are examined. Furthermore, our own familial cases and the sporadic cases where the parental origin of the deletion could be deduced using a chromosome 22 short arm heteromorphisms seem to confirm this tendency. Because we had isolated a CA-repeat locus mapping within the DGS deleted region, the parental origin of the deletion in sporadic DGS/VCFS cases was studied by assessing the inheritance pattern of this microsatellite marker. The deleted portion of chromosome 22 was of maternal origin in 16 out of 22 cases (72%). When cases of sporadic, familial and unbalanced translocation inheritance reported in the literature were pooled with these results, there appears to be a net tendency for the deletions to be of maternal origin in CATCH 22 (70 deletions of maternal origin, 21 of paternal origin, X$ sp2$ = 26.4, p $&lt;$ 0.0001). In order to identify the molecular defect underlying DGS, we embarked on a positional cloning approach. A detailed physical map of the 22q11.2 region was made using one- and two-color FISH on metaphases and G$ sb0$ interphase nuclei, and by hybridization to a chromosome 22 hybrid panel. This permitted delineation of a critical region, within which the breakpoint of a balanced translocation carrier affected with DGS was mapping. This breakpoint was cloned by the construction of cosmid contigs, and a novel gene mapped to this region was isolated. The gene potentially encodes an adhesion receptor, and is not interrupted by the balanced translocation breakpoint. Possible mechanisms through which this gene can be involved in the pathogenesis of DGS are presented. This research project has contributed toward the understanding of the genetics of DGS and related syndromes. Furthermore, a candidate gene for the CATCH 22 syndromes has been isolated and further work will confirm whether it plays a major role in the pathogenesis of these syndromes.</description><creator>Demczuk, Suzanne</creator><contributor>Rosenblatt, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Rouleau, G. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Human chromosome abnormalities</subject><subject>Human cytogenetics</subject><title>Genetic characterization of DiGeorge and related syndromes associated with 22q11.2 deletions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278w19q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r781wh96m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80hx37c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Four strains of the swine pathogen Actinobacillus pleuropneumoniae, namely, the type strain (ATCC 27088), the "reference" strain of biotype 2 (Bertschinger 2008/76) and two additional biotype 1 strains, strain BC181, which is less virulent than the type strain, and strain K17 (reference strain of serotype 5A), which was isolated from a lamb, were investigated with respect to iron acquisition. All four strains produced iron-repressible outer membrane proteins. However, only strains ATCC 27088 and Bertschinger 2008/76 could acquire iron from porcine transferrin. No organism could utilize human, bovine or ovine transferrin, or ovine or porcine lactoferrin. Haemoglobin supported good growth of all strains except K17 (which also failed to acquire iron from haemin). In all cases, iron acquisition from transferrin or haemoglobin required direct contact between the organisms and the proteins. Total membranes derived from iron-restricted organisms were subjected to an affinity isolation technique based on biotinylated porcine transferrin and streptavidin-agarose, and the following polypeptides were isolated: 99 kDa and 64 kDa from strain ATCC 27088; 93 kDa from strain Bertschinger 2008/76; 95 kDa (trace amounts) and 60 kDa from strain BC181; none from strain K17. These polypeptides appear to be transferrin receptor components. The 99 kDa polypeptide (TBPl) from the type strain was purified by SDS-PAGE and transferred electrophoretically onto polyvinylidene difluoride membrane. The N-terminal amino acid sequence of the polypeptide was determined commercially. A commercially-synthesized oligonucleotide probe was used to clone the gene encoding the TBPl of the type strain in competent Escherichia coli DH5$ alpha$ cells.</description><creator>D'Silva, Colin Gerard</creator><contributor>Niven, Donald F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Pneumonia in swine.</subject><subject>Swine -- Infections.</subject><subject>Iron -- Metabolism.</subject><subject>Pleuropneumonia.</subject><title>Iron acquisition by Actinobacillus pleuropneumoniae</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wp67n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hx37c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8910jw52w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation looks at old age homes in British Columbia between 1920 and 1960. It describes and explains how changes in institutional care for aging men and women intersected with professional ideals, welfare state economics and political imperatives. It also considers how broader developments altered the physical and cultural world of the institution and the strategies employed by the elderly. Facilities for the elderly changed significantly during the period. In 1920 provision of residential care for older British Columbians was extremely limited, and existing institutions operated under a poorhouse model, providing only custodial care. By 1960 a sizeable network of provincially regulated facilities had developed. Medical professionals urged that these establishments be medical facilities and that the elderly receive compassionate, therapeutic care. However, circumstances inside these facilities limited change. While some institutions were run along medical lines, new policy initiatives were modified by strong historical links with older systems of custodial care and punitive poorhouse ethics.</description><creator>Davies, Megan Jean</creator><contributor>Levesque, Andree (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Old age homes -- British Columbia -- History</subject><subject>Older people -- Institutional care -- British Columbia -- History.</subject><title>Institutionalizing old age : residential accommodation for the elderly in British Columbia, 1920-1960</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hx363.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jw52w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bd59k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Previous studies of the life and thought of Edmund Bishop (1846-1917), an English liturgiologist and convert to Catholicism, have underplayed the change in his attitude from positive to negative with respect to the institutional Catholic Church. This crucial shift in thinking occurred during 1899-1901, and is clearly reflected in his own writings. From then on, he differentiated between the institution that was the Catholic Church and Catholicism as a religion. Although he remained faithful to the latter, his diaries and letters preserve an intentional record of his severe criticism of the Catholic hierarchy. Bishop's views represent those of a layman and of an informed observer at a time when the Catholic Church was confronting the Modernist challenge.</description><creator>Dalgaard, Anne Elisabeth</creator><contributor>Furcha, E. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Bishop, Edmund, 1846-1917</subject><subject>Catholic Church -- England -- History -- 19th century</subject><title>For and against "Rome" : the case of Edmund Bishop, 1846-1917</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cv94t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bd59k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f791n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study of catenated polysulfur oxide ligands as homogeneous models of possible species involved in the Claus reaction has led to the investigation of SO$ sb2$ complexes as precursors to the MSO$ sb2$SR moiety. In the first part of this study, cationic Cp-ruthenium complexes having a planar SO$ sb2$ ligand were treated with thiolate anions and thiols. When (CpRu(PPh$ rm sb3) sb2SO sb2 rbrack PF sb6$ was treated with LiSCHMe$ sb2$, no reaction occurred and the starting complex was recovered. Treatment with a weaker nucleophile $ rm LiSC sb6F sb5$ gave CpRu(PPh$ rm sb3) sb2SC sb6F sb5.$ Replacing LiSR with NaSR.HOEt gave CpRu(PPh$ rm sb3) sb2SO sb2OEt$ as the major product. When an excess of RSH (R = CHMe$ sb2$, and 4-$ rm C sb6H sb4$Me) was used in the presence of $ rm Na sb2CO sb3$, loss of SO$ sb2$ occurred to give ($ rm CpRu(PPh sb3) sb2HSCHMe sb2 rbrack PF sb6$ and CpRu(PPh$ sb3) sb2$S-4-$ rm C sb6H sb4Me$, respectively. Treatment of (CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)(CO)SO$ sb2$) SbF$ sb6$ with LiSR or NaSR resulted in a mixture of products. Treatment with excess RSH (R = $ rm CHMe sb2, C sb3H sb7$ and 4-$ rm C sb6H sb4Me)$ in the presence $ rm Na sb2CO sb3$ gave CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)(CO)SO$ sb2$SR, which are unstable and readily hydrolysed in trace amounts of H$ sb2$O to give CpRu(PPh$ sb3$)(CO)SO$ sb2$OH. The X-ray structures of ($ rm CpRu(PPh sb3) sb2SO sb2 rbrack PF sb6,$ ($ rm CpRu(PPh sb3(CO)SO sb2 rbrack Sbf sb6$, $ rm CpRu(PPh sb3) sb2SO sb2OEt,$ ($ rm CpRu(PPh sb3) sb2HSCHMe sb2 rbrack PF sb6$ and $ rm CpRu(PPh sb3)(CO)SO sb2OH$ were determined. In the second part of the study, nucleophilic complexes having a pyramidal SO$ sb2$ ligand were reacted with sources of "RS$ sp+$". Treatment of Ir(Cl)(CO)(PPh$ rm sb3) sb2SO sb2$ with sulfur transfer reagents resulted in the loss of SO$ sb2$. Treatment of $ rm Pt(PPh sb3) sb3SO sb2 cdot C sb6H sb6$ with RSphth (phth = phthalimido and R = Me, Et, $ rm C sb3H sb7$, CHMe$ sb2$, 4-$ rm C sb6H sb4Me$ and CH$ sb2$Ph) gave stable complexes of the type trans-Pt(PPh$ sb3) sb2$(phth)SO$ sb2$SR. The mechanism of this oxidative addition is discussed. Trans-$ rm Pt(PPh sb3) sb2(phth)SO sb2SCH sb2Ph$ readily reacted with ROH (R = H, Et and CHMe$ sb2$) to give trans-Pt(PPh$ sb3) sb2$(phth)SO$ sb2$OR and it thermally extruded SO$ sb2$ irreversibly to give the thiolate complex. Treatment of $ rm Pt(PPh sb3) sb3SO sb2 cdot C sb6H sb6$ with RSSphth and RS(O)phth also gave trans-$ rm Pt(PPh sb3) sb2(phth)SO sb2SR$ as the major products. The probable cause of this is discussed. Treatment of $ rm Pt(PPh sb3) sb3SO sb2 cdot C sb6H sb6$ with H$ sb2$S resulted in SO$ sb2$ loss. The X-ray structure of trans-$ rm Pt(PPh sb3) sb2(phth)SO sb2SCH sb2$Ph is reported.</description><creator>Boily, Hélène Louise</creator><contributor>Shaver, Alan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Inorganic.</subject><title>The chemistry of platinum and ruthenium complexes containing a thiosulfonate ester ligans (-SO2SR)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cc82s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f791n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj139397p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:57:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Soft magnetic $ rm Ni sb{ it x}Co sb{ it 100-x}$/Cu multilayers in the range x = 20 to 80 have been prepared by DC-magnetron sputtering. NiCo alloys were chosen because of their small magnetoelastic parameters around the range x = 70-80 and very small lattice mismatch between NiCo and Cu. This combination of parameters should lead to good giant magnetoresistance (GMR) with a small saturation field. Structural characterization reveals that high quality layered structures were obtained. Quantitative interpretation of the superlattice structure parameters, such as interface roughness, interfacial mixing profiles and layer-thickness disorders, have been carried out by modelling the X-ray diffraction data. GMR was found to be largest at x = 80 with well-defined oscillations as a function of the thickness of the Cu layer, mirroring the interlayer magnetic coupling. In particular, GMR with small saturation fields around Cu thickness near the second MR maximum (t$ sb{Cu}$ = 20A) will be technologically important because of the very high magnetic field sensitivity. Correlating the multilayer structure to the GMR allow us to optimize the structural parameters by enhancing the spin-dependent interfacial scattering in a high quality layered structure. Direct observation of the simple antiferromagnetic order has been achieved by the presence of the (0,0,${1 over2})$ wavevector in small angle neutron scattering experiments. A near-perfect antiferromagnetic spin arrangement is found for a Cu thickness t$ sb{Cu}$ = 20 A, that can be readily aligned ferromagnetically in a small external field of less than 200 Oe. A complementary system, FM/Ag (FM = $ rm Ni sb{81}Fe sb{19}, Ni sb{80}Co sb{20}$ and $ rm Ni sb{66}Co sb{18}Fe sb{16})$ granular multilayer prepared by annealing multilayers, has also been studied. Enhanced magnetoresistance observed in these systems is shown to be controlled by the size, concentration and thermal stability of the magnetic precipitates in a nonmagnetic matrix. For a particular multilayer structure with a magnetic layer of 20 A, annealed at around 325$ sp circ$C, a GMR of $ sim$4% with a characteristic saturation field of 10 Oe was found, leading to a high magnetoresistive sensitivity of $ sim$0.4%/Oe at room temperature.</description><creator>Bian, Xiaoping</creator><contributor>Strom-Olsen, John O. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Altounian, Zaven (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Giant magnetoresistance in soft magnetic multilayers and granular films</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cj57w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139397p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):39475</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>