<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:38:19Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):38850" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311r246</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the last decade, the European air transport industry has undergone a process in several stages of transition towards a single market. Liberalization has been closely linked to the effective application of the state aid rules of the EC Treaty. In principle, direct aid to undertakings within the common market is not prohibited by the state aid rules in the Treaty. However, aid granted by Member States that distorts or threatens to distort competition by giving one airline an unfair advantage over its competitors, and in so far as it affects trade between Member States, is incompatible with the Treaty. Certain mandatory or discretionary exemptions may apply to aid to airlines providing that the measure fulfills the conditions and requirements as stated by the Treaty. The European Commission and the EFTA Surveillance Authority have a wide discretion in deciding whether or not certain aid measures fall within the stated exemptions. Where the market forces alone are not able to achieve the desired results or if they are only able to do so in a limited capacity, such exemptions may be warranted to the extent not contrary to the common interest. A special mechanism is in place to ensure that state aid is properly scrutinized in the light of the demands of the Treaty and the EEA Agreement. The EC Commission or the EFTA Surveillance Authority must be notified of all aid measures in order to assess their compatibility with state aid rules.</description><creator>Scheving Thorsteinsson, Astridur.</creator><contributor>Weber, Ludwig (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Law and legislation.</subject><subject>Federal aid to transportation.</subject><subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Finance.</subject><title>State aid to airlines</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440v54p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311r246</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb397b08h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The air cargo industry is evolving rapidly, as is its international law regime. The recent entry into force of the Montreal Protocol No. 4 and adoption of the Convention for the Unification of Certain Rules for International Carriage by Air signed at Montreal on 28 May 1999 constitutes a new legal framework for air cargo claims. Rather than offering definite answers, this thesis identifies some current and emerging issues in the law of air cargo claims, particularly those aspects that the claimant must prove. The work traces the development of the Warsaw System by writers and courts, and attempts to identify trends in the application and interpretation of the new legal framework. The evolution towards independence of the law of carriage of goods by air from other similar regimes, and the existing connections among them, are examined. When appropriate, common law and civil law solutions to some legal issues will be introduced. Finally, the thesis concludes that conflicting decisions in this field could be avoided by adopting uniform rules to solve conflicts of laws and to interpret international carriage conventions.</description><creator>Salazar, Juan Carlos.</creator><contributor>Tetley, William (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Law and legislation.</subject><subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Freight.</subject><subject>Liability (Law)</subject><title>The burden of proof of the air cargo claimant under international law /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149r54b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397b08h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qn90k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>International air transport has grown at a staggering rate over the last 50 years and the industry which supports it, now bears little resemblance to that which existed even twenty-five years ago. As the number of operators and the size of their respective fleets have increased, so too have the pressures on the infrastructure which support them. Particularly affected are the major airports where runway, apron and terminal capacity are limited. Unlike other elements of the aviation infrastructure, airport capacity is physically constrained and therefore capacity increases can only be obtained through further development or through more efficient uses of existing resources. As the first option is politically controversial and the latter only provides for incremental increases, the air transport industry, through IATA, has developed an allocation mechanism to distribute available capacity based on historic precedence. This thesis reviews the main issues surrounding the current regime. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Schmid, Thomas, 1969-</creator><contributor>Haanappel, P. P. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Aeronautics -- Safety measures.</subject><subject>Airports -- Europe -- Traffic control.</subject><subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Europe.</subject><title>Slot allocation at European airports</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q524jq62x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qn90k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qr48z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Securities on movables are one of the major feature of credit mechanisms. Under domestic law, this type of guarantee is widely used, specifically in France, Great-Britain and Canada, under different forms. On the other hand, due to legal uncertainties surrounding operations bearing an international character, securities on movables are rarely used in international transactions. Regrettably, this established fact, particularly illustrated by French law, appears to go against modern tendencies to favour the internationalisation of commercial activities. The analysis of the rules of French private international law in the light of the corresponding rules of English and Canadian law allows us to identify the main obstacles in the international traffic of securities on movables and to propose reforms initiatives. Consequently, the analysis of several ratified or drafted international conventions which are related to some aspects of securities on movables in an international context can bring suitable solutions to problems raised by the internationalisation of securities. This thesis proposes that these international agreements carrying conflict of law rules or uniform substantive law constitute the most promising means of regulating these mechanisms which are directly connected to modern international financing.</description><creator>Henry, Elisa.</creator><contributor>Saumier, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Securities -- France.</subject><subject>Conflict of laws -- Securities.</subject><title>Les sûretes mobilières en droit international privé : étude critique du droit francais à la lumière du droit comparé et du droit uniforme</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085n22x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qr48z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848s40k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In 1989, Jordan chose to follow the track of democracy and open economy. From that time on, Jordan has embarked upon plans to reform its legal as well as economic and social structures. Continuous and serious efforts have been underway to enable Jordan to join the WTO (World Trade Organization) and become part of the new "economic global village". Many observers see this as a step to help Jordan materialize these plans and to help put it on a road that will inevitably lead to more freedom of choice and more competitiveness. Opening the national markets means exposing the domestic industry and market to foreign competitors. In order to preserve the domestic economic and social fabrics, local industries have to gain the maximum efficiency and market width possible or they will go under. Such efficiency and investors' inducement can and should be encouraged through providing a "liberal" legal framework. Such a framework, applied to the field of corporate law, can impose market control over management's inefficiency, and give businesses the diversity they need to attract investors.</description><creator>Haddadin, Fadi.</creator><contributor>Stevens, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Stockholders -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- Jordan.</subject><subject>Corporation law.</subject><subject>Corporation law -- Jordan.</subject><subject>Consolidation and merger of corporations.</subject><title>Critique of shareholder status in Jordanian corporate law : a comparative approach</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sm346.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848s40k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65v9675</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis deals with the plan of the Dutch government to build an offshore airport outside its territorial waters. Because the airport will be outside territorial waters several problems may arise. Under the Law of the Sea the question is whether such an airport can lawfully be built and what the different conditions are under which it is possible. The Convention on International Civil Aviation is older then the new Law of the Sea Convention and therefore not up to date with the new zones in the sea that have emerged. Air law therefore needs to be interpreted in the light of those new developments. The first chapter deals with the reasons behind the plan to build such an airport. Thereafter, subsequent chapters discuss the law of the sea, air law, European law and the law of other organizations, which will have an influence on an offshore airport outside the territorial sea. The final chapter deals with plans and examples of other uses of artificial islands, including offshore airports.</description><creator>Hulsewé, D. (Daphne)</creator><contributor>Haanappel, P. P. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Law and legislation.</subject><subject>Offshore structures -- Law and legislation.</subject><subject>Law of the sea.</subject><subject>Airports -- Economic aspects -- Netherlands.</subject><subject>Jurisdiction (International law)</subject><title>Moving out to sea : international legal implications of building an offshore airport outside territorial waters</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128c76w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65v9675</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354h15c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Arbitrating of competition law claims has generated a substantial tension between the policies served by promoting international arbitration and those protected by the national competition law. Despite the legal tension and unpredictability associated with arbitrating competition law issues, the arbitrator should, in principle, resolve such issues. This study analyses the main concerns when arbitrating competition law issues, such as jurisdiction, choice of law and, in particular, the position of national jurisdiction regarding the enforcement of the award conflicting national competition law. This study proposes the functional approach to choice of law problems according to which the arbitrator will decide on the applicable competition law bearing in mind the content of mandatory norm, its connection with a dispute and the consequences of its application and non-application. In that regard, this thesis will examine how an arbitrator should address the extraterritorial effect of the competition law. The study will suggest that if the competition law policies of states connected with a dispute serve opposing and conflicting goals, the arbitrator should, in order to preserve his/her neutral function refuse to decide whose competition policy is "better" and should consequently decline jurisdiction.</description><creator>Hrle, Jelena.</creator><contributor>Toope, Stephen (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Competition -- Government policy.</subject><subject>Arbitration, International.</subject><title>International arbitration and competition law</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418q04m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354h15c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77ft306</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is concerned with the role of fairness in international environmental law and, by way of example, focuses specifically on the perspective of developing countries in the context of the climate change regime. A brief analysis of underlying conceptions of fairness in general international law serves as the backdrop for an evaluation of both procedural and substantive aspects of fairness within the climate change regime. This evaluation includes a detailed consideration of the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change and the Kyoto Protocol to that Convention. The thesis concludes that the role of fairness in the climate change regime, and in international environmental law more generally, has become significant in recent years. It is likely that this trend will continue through further articulation of claims, by developing countries and others, in the context of an ongoing fairness debate. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Bishop, Kirsten.</creator><contributor>Provost, Rene (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Climatic changes.</subject><subject>Environmental law.</subject><title>Fairness in international environmental law : accommodation of the concerns of developing countries in the climate change regime</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jw49k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77ft306</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fj95h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The United Nations Convention on Contracts for the International Sale of Goods (CISG), adopted in April 11, 1980, is an attempt to unify rules of international trade. A large number of states that represent a variety of legal systems and of degrees of development have adhered to this Convention. As a result of the divergence of approaches and rules in these systems, several issues were debated during the negotiations, among others the remedy of specific performance. This thesis examines the provisions regarding specific performance in the Convention in attempt to reveal the divergence of approaches between Common Law and Civil Law by means of a comparative study of the two systems. The purpose is to assess the extent to which uniformity is achieved in the Convention. The study shows that the solution adopted regarding specific performance was a compromise that threatens uniformity to a certain degree.</description><creator>Boghossian, Nayiri.</creator><contributor>Jutras, Daniel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Export sales contracts.</subject><subject>Specific performance.</subject><title>A comparative study of specific performance provisions in the United Nations Convention on contracts for the international sale of goods /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8910jw489.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fj95h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451k525</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Global Navigation Satellite System (GNSS) is the main element of the CNS/ATM system elaborated by the International Civil Aviation Organization (ICAO). The US GPS and Russian GLONASS are the two existing systems. Both of them were created by the military. Europe is currently developing a civil navigation satellite system: Galileo. This thesis will present some legal issues of the GNSS discussed in the framework of ICAO: sovereignty of States, universal accessibility, continuity and quality of the service, cost recovery and financing, certification and liability. It will also present some legal issues due to the creation of the European Galileo program. The financing, organizational framework, certification and liability will be examined. Finally, ICAO's Charter on the Rights and Obligations of States Relating to GNSS Services will be considered.</description><creator>Andries, Stephanie.</creator><contributor>Milde, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Navigation (Aeronautics)</subject><subject>Artificial satellites in navigation -- Law and legislation.</subject><title>The Global Navigation Satellite System (GNSS) and the European Galileo program /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bz60cz43c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451k525</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q524jq636</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Amongst other things, the 20th century can be seen as having been the century of aviation. Progress in the aviation industry can be measured through the evolution of aircraft, their performance, cargo volume and the number of passengers. In the shadow of such progress, one of the main characteristics to have developed is that of the modern airport, which has moved from a simple runway to a veritable enterprise with an identity of its own. It is also linked to other related sectors such as airlines companies and States, which still have a strong involvement in airports. The following study will focus on this modern airport as an individual entity, with a legal personality of its own developing its hopes and its fears.</description><creator>Berthou, Anaïs.</creator><contributor>Milde, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Airports -- Law and legislation.</subject><subject>Airports -- Safety measures.</subject><title>Les aéroports à l'aube du troisième millénaire /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hm085.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q524jq636</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20sv663</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Robots with four legs offer a good tradeoff between stability, load carrying capacity, and mechanical complexity when compared to bipeds and hexapods. In order to achieve the best mobility, speed, and energy efficiency, dynamic walking and running operation is preferable to static gaits. This requires leg compliance to reduce impact forces and energy consumption. At the Ambulatory Robotics Laboratory, (ARL), we have pursued an agenda of low mechanical complexity in our Scout I and II robots, in order to decrease cost and increase reliability. Research previously undertaken at the ARL group has accomplished walking and stair climbing with Scout I and walking with stiff legs with Scout II. In this thesis, we demonstrate that Scout II, with only an additional compliant prismatic joint per leg, is able to bound. We show that dynamic running is possible with very simple control strategies. Open loop control, where switching torque values at the hip during support or flight phases results in a stable bounding gait. We also investigate more elaborate controllers that control forward speeds. The bound controllers were first developed and validated in simulation. These strategies were then implemented on the Scout II robot yielding successful running at speeds of up to 1.2 m/s.</description><creator>Papadopoulos, Didier.</creator><contributor>Buehler, Martin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Stable running for a quadruped robot with compliant legs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956h792.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20sv663</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd375z25h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research examines some of the ways to design a digital control system with particular reference to the control of yaw plane dynamics of an air-to-air missile model. Specific attention is paid to compare two methods of global digital re-design of validated analogue closed loop control system. These two methods are the multi-input multi-output (MIMO) Plant Input Mapping (PIM) method and multi-loop PIM method. The thesis will first show how a specific class of closed loop MIMO feedback systems with a single-input multi-output (SIMO) plant can be re-structured as multi-loop control systems, which includes the closed loop missile control system. Some special characteristics pertaining to SIMO systems for control system design are explored. The aforementioned two methods of PIM global digital re-design are then applied to the MIMO analogue missile control system and its re-structured multi-loop counterpart. A comparison of the two methods is made on its design procedure, implementation structure and results from computer simulation. This thesis also touches upon the topic of controller order reduction, particularly in consideration of the PIM digital re-design of analogue feedback systems. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Ng, Chuk Man, 1974-</creator><contributor>Hori, Noriyuki (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><title>On the digital re-design of an analogue missile flight control system using PIM method</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591b233.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375z25h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sf52x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bioemulsifiers are biologically produced surfactants; of interest because of their ability to stabilize emulsions. Preference for microbial emulsifiers, over their synthetic counterparts, has been steadily increasing in recent years due to their environmentally friendly nature. Liposan is a polymeric bioemulsifier produced by the yeast Yarrowia lipolytica (ATCC 8662) when grown on hexadecane. The industrial production of bioemulsifiers is difficult because of low product concentrations and contamination by residual hydrocarbon, which is often used as a substrate to promote the production of the emulsifier. Self-Cycling Fermentor (SCF) has been shown to increase the yield of many biosurfactants, and improve the degradation of insoluble substrates. Fed-batch fermentation, with a hydrocarbon substrate, has been shown to result in better substrate utilization when applied to standard batch growth. In this work, the effects of continuous hydrocarbon addition on growth, liposan production, and residual hydrocarbon in a Self-Cycling fermentor are studied. Continuous hydrocarbon addition to the SCF is compared to the standard method of initial hydrocarbon addition. The continuous addition method is shown to increase the final concentration of liposan, and reduce the concentration of residual hydrocarbon over the initial addition method.</description><creator>Pinchuk, Robert.</creator><contributor>Cooper, D. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Liposan production in the self-cycling fermentor</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z2793.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sf52x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bk128c775</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The phase separation method is a practically important method for producing multicomponent materials. Particularly, many commercialized polymer blends, such as High-Impact Polystyrene (HIPS) and acrylonitrile-butadiene-styrene (ABS), are manufactured by the polymerization-induced phase separation (PIPS) method, polymerizing monomer compounds (styrene) in the presence of polymers (polybutadiene). In this thesis, rigorous mathematical models, describing the PIPS process, have been formulated using the nonlinear Cahn-Hilliard (C-H) theory and the Flory-Huggins (F-H) theory combined with a second-order reaction equation. In particular, this thesis analyzes and simulates for the first time the PIPS process for the case of a monomer polymerizing in the presence of a polymer. The model equations are solved using the numerical methods, and the simulation results are characterized to identify the main dynamical and morphological phenomena of the PIPS process. Lastly, the PIPS process under a temperature gradient is studied to produce functional composite materials exhibiting space-dependent microstructures and properties.</description><creator>Oh, Junsuk.</creator><contributor>Rey, A. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Computational simulation and morphological analysis of polymerization-induced phase separation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gj34b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128c775</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:th83m1258</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Both an electrochemical and an isopiestic methods were used to measure the mean activity coefficients of amino acids in water-electrolyte-amino acid systems. The electrochemical method used an electrochemical cell with an anion and a cation ion selective electrodes, each measured versus a double junction reference electrode. The activity coefficients of the electrolyte were obtained from the e.m.f measurements for four systems at 298.15K. The amino acids were glycine, DL-serine and DL-valine and the electrolyte were KNO3 and NaNO3. The isopiestic method was applied to measure the activity of water for the system water + DL-serine + KNO3 at 298.15K and the results were compared with those from electrochemical method. The activity coefficients of the amino acids in the ternary systems were obtained from those of the electrolyte measured by the electrochemical method or from those of the water measured by isopiestic method, according to the cross differential relation. Two models were used to correlate the measured data. First the excess Gibbs free energy model proposed by Khoshkbarchi and Vera (1996a) with the NRTL equation was used to correlate the activity coefficient data. A simple model derived from a modification of a more complex model based on the perturbation theory (Khoshkbarchi and Vera, 1996c) was proposed. The model was applied to correlate the activity coefficients and solubilities of amino acids in binary aqueous solutions and the activity coefficients in ternary systems with satisfactory results.</description><creator>Gao, Chongxia, 1963-</creator><contributor>Vera, Juan H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Activity coefficients of glycine, DL-serine and DL-valine in aqueous solutions containing nitrates at 298.15K</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397b10j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m1258</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0g354h16n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Metal and composite plates can be bonded together to form a joint known as the "single-lap" joint. The single-lap joint is studied under two different loading conditions: (i) out-of-plane load (bending) and (ii) in-plane load (tension). The different joint configurations are studied analytically and experimentally in order to achieve the optimum design. In configurations such as lap joints, the presence of stress singularities eliminates the possibility of using any stress-based failure criteria. A strain energy method is used to predict the strength of adhesively bonded joints because of its convergence with mesh refinement and it is found to be in good agreement with experimental results. Failure of single-lap joints is governed by the load case under consideration and the way in which the stress distribution varies at the joint ends. Failure varies with the taper angle (inner and outer), with or without additional epoxy beads. It is observed that designing the joint for one kind of load will not always be satisfactory because, for other load cases, different parameters will govern the design. It is shown that the optimum design for the single lap joint under bending loads will not be the optimum design for the tension case. Therefore, the optimum design can be chosen in a way that satisfies both loading conditions.</description><creator>Golubovic, Adnan.</creator><contributor>Lessard, Larry B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Analysis and optimization of adhesively bonded joints</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977w923.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0g354h16n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2b88qd917</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A plasma transferred arc furnace has been developed by Hydro-Quebec for the recovery of aluminum from dross. In an attempt to maximize the recovery of aluminum, static liquid holdup was investigated. Simulation experiments were conducted using a packed column of spherical glass beads and either water or mercury. It was expected that static liquid holdup would correlate with the dimensionless Eotvos number; and would therefore be a function of the density and surface tension of the wetting liquid, as well as the particle diameter. The effects of packed height, column diameter, particle size and size distribution, surface tension, and non-wetting liquid were investigated. The experimental results were compared with the existing correlations of Saez and Carbonell; and Saez, Yepez, et al. The experimental results were found to agree with the correlations within the applicable range. A new correlation was then developed from the experimental data based on the Eotvos number in the range of 0.003 to 1.2. The developed correlation is: H=11.25+65&amp;ast;Eo where H is the static liquid holdup in units of liquid volume per solid volume and Eo is the Eotvos number.</description><creator>Hanstead, Alison Rae.</creator><contributor>Munz, R. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Measurement of static liquid holdup at low EOTVOS numbers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bg96w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qd917</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924d57h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A large interest has been devoted to the use of optical interconnections in digital computer and digital telecommunication systems over the last few years. This interest is motivated by the promise of a greatly increased connectivity, lower power dissipation, and the compactness of interconnections that can be achieved with the use of this technology. This thesis examines the design and the implementation of a modular spot-array generator for a modulator-based free-space optical interconnect. Two cascaded diffractive optical elements produce 4 x 8 clusters on a 1600 mum x 800 mum pitch, where each cluster is a 4 x 4 array of (1/e 2) 13.1-mum-radius spots on a 90-mum pitch. The spot-array generator is kinematically aligned to the interconnect system in such a way that it can be removed and reinserted without realignment. Characterization results are presented.</description><creator>Filiatrault-Brosseau, Daniel.</creator><contributor>Kirk, Andrew G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Design, implementation and characterization of a kinematically aligned, cascaded spot-array generator for a modulator-based free-space optical interconnect</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k6990.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924d57h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rq578</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The common conception that the cemetery holds the memory of all who died and were buried before us is a false one. There were certain biases in who was being commemorated, a form of selectivity to the memorial process, that caused a great number of people to erode from the landscape. The argument is based on observations from a sample of seventeen hundred individuals from the latter half of the nineteenth century in Montreal and surrounding villages. A selection of twelve surnames from archival data includes the three main cultures present in Montreal in the nineteenth century (French Canadians, Irish Catholics and English Protestants) and allows me to reconstitute families, to identify their kinship ties, and to determine their situation in life. Records from the cemeteries on Mount Royal and from the parishes of three rural villages confirm the burial of individuals from the sample. The presence or absence of these individuals in the cemetery landscapes depends on different commemorative practices influenced by religion, culture, gender, status and age.</description><creator>Watkins, Meredith G.</creator><contributor>Olson, Sherry (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Cemeteries -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal Region -- History.</subject><subject>Mount Royal Cemetery (Montréal, Québec) -- History.</subject><subject>Notre-Dame des Neiges Cemetery (Montréal, Québec) -- History.</subject><subject>Montréal (Québec) -- History -- 19th century.</subject><title>The cemetery and cultural memory : Montreal region, 1860 to 1900</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kq039.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rq578</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cj453</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examined the efficacy of conjoint behavioural consultation (CBC) in the remediation of behavioural problems in children with cognitive disabilities. Further, this study sought to determine whether parents' knowledge of behavioural principles and behavioural management skills improved as a result of participating in CBC. An A/B design was utilized with 6 children (ages 7--10), their parents and teachers. Children evidenced improvements in their target behaviours from baseline to treatment at home or at school (effect sizes = -2.11 to +1.35). Overall, children evidenced improvements in social skills, problem behaviours, or externalizing behaviours (Reliable Change Indices [RCI] = -0.27 to 3.29). Moreover, knowledge of behavioural principles increased significantly for two parents at posttest when compared to pretest (RCI = 1.25 to 3.47). Also, parents used more praise statements, fewer critical statements, and fewer no-opportunity commands at posttest than at pretest. The theoretical and practical implications of these findings, limitations of this study, and future research directions are discussed.</description><creator>Viola, Teresa.</creator><contributor>Sladeczek, Ingrid E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Problem children -- Behavior modification.</subject><subject>Cognition disorders in children.</subject><title>Remediating behaviour problems in children with cognitive disabilities</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f542j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cj453</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6q182n08b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the symbolic use of space in the trilogy of Giorgio Bassani: Gli occhiali d'oro, Il giardino dei Finzi-Contini and Dietro la porta. All written in the first person, the novels are part of a continuum since in each one the same narrator remembers a different event from his past. All three novels recreate events which took place prior to the Second World War; two make direct reference to the grueling period of antisemitism under the Fascist regime. Through the spatial element we analyze the moral and psychological states of the various characters, in particular of the young Jewish protagonist who is suddenly a social outcast due to the racial persecutions. Furthermore, space in these novels reflects the emotional state of the most important character of the trilogy, the narrator, who still, after many years shows signs of unresolved issues.</description><creator>Tumino, Anna Maria.</creator><contributor>Kroha, Lucienne (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Space (Architecture) in literature.</subject><subject>Bassani, Giorgio -- Symbolism.</subject><title>La funzione simbolica dello spazio nella trilogia di Giorgio Bassani /</title><language>ita</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472z30m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182n08b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Italian</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f3148</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The first part of this master's thesis is a collection of twelve short stories which illustrates, in varying degrees, the same characteristics as the oriental travelogue. The second part is an analysis of the seraglio in 17th century travel literature, as a synecdote of oriental despotism. We focus on the works of Bernier, Chardin and Tavernier. Using these texts, we show how the various representations of the seraglio are constructed as a commonplace where converge notions of otherness. In conclusion we demonstrate that more than simple critical observations on the theme of love, the representation of the seraglio is a way of commenting on the fabric of various oriental societies while creating a political myth justifying absolutism.</description><creator>Vincelette, Mélanie.</creator><contributor>Rivard, Yvon (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Doiron, Normand (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Travel in literature.</subject><subject>Harem.</subject><title>Nomadismes, suivi de, Le sérail dans le récit de voyage en Orient</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hm106.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f3148</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2j62s6653</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Providing chronically ill patients with informational support is crucial for successful disease management. The effectiveness of educational interventions was examined utilizing three questionnaires which assessed glaucoma patients' health beliefs, disease knowledge and medication compliance. 60 chronic open-angle glaucoma patients either: watched a glaucoma film, read glaucoma information pamphlets, received instruction verbally from their ophthalmologist or proceeded with their regular check-up. Measures were taken pre-intervention, then 2 and 30 days later. A 3 x 4 mixed ANOVA found a significant interaction between time and intervention in the film group. The relationship between the degree of patient's visual field loss and measures on compliance, health beliefs, and knowledge was also assessed. The positive correlations indicate that patients with modest visual field losses are also those with the highest scores on the three dependent measures. Patients, who have less visual field loss, may possess the behavioral, affective and cognitive components required to successfully manage their illness regimens.</description><creator>Radcliffe-Branch, Deborah S.</creator><contributor>Lajoie, Susanne (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Glaucoma.</subject><subject>Patient education.</subject><title>Determinants of patient behavior in chronic illness : examining educational interventions for glaucoma patients</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732db84q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s6653</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87ps33x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:53:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis re-evaluates Inhumanism, the philosophy of twentieth-century American poet Robinson Jeffers, in light of the Christian eremitic tradition. Inhumanism continues to create controversy around Jeffers' life and work; charges of misanthropy and anti-Americanism have pushed him to the margins of American literature. My first chapter looks at how critics have tried to understand Inhumanism's influences and motives by contextualizing Jeffers' philosophy in many cultural, psychological, literary, and spiritual traditions. Chapter Two explores the main tenets of the eremitic ideal, as expressed in the lives and writings of hermits from the fourth to the twentieth centuries. Chapters Three, Four, and Five then situate Inhumamsm's themes, imagery, and purpose---as set down in Jeffers' poetry from 1903 to 1962---in this eremitic tradition. Looking at Jeffers' early work shows that Inhumanism is not politically-motivated, as many critics claim, but rather is a deep-rooted spiritual orientation, carried in his heart from boyhood. Recontextualizing Jeffers' work in the eremitic tradition shows Inhumanism to be, not an exceptional or dangerous philosophy, but part of the core of western spirituality.</description><creator>Reiswig, Amy.</creator><contributor>Ohlin, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Jeffers, Robinson, 1887-1962 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Robinson Jeffers, hermit of Carmel : recontextualizing inhumanism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655j490.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87ps33x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):38875</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>