<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:01:47Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):15475" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0v838406t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Vitamin A has been studied intensely in its application to the fields of animal and poultry nutrition. Over forty years of investigation have provided extensive data on the chemistry, analysis, deficiency symptoms and nutritional requirements of vitamin A. However, there is still a scarcity of information concerning its mode of action in the body, particularly regarding carotenoid conversion to vitamin A and its absorption, transport, storage and association with disease. As recently as twenty years ago, fish liver oils and alfalfa meals were the major sources for vitamin A supplementation. These natural concentrated sources varied in potency and activity from one batch to another. Some contained impurities which interfered with assays and contributed to the instability of vitamin A activity.</description><creator>Burgess, Paul. L.</creator><contributor>Nikolaiczuk, N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Animal Science.</subject><title>Efficacy of vitamin A sources for chick growth.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w9505396b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0v838406t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agriculture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892f549</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigates the living arrangements, housing, general health situation, economic circumstances and family and social relationships of older people. In particular it presents the results of interviews with 75 male pensioners living in private homes, who are retired from the same large company in the communications industry. It uses an interview schedule that was adapted from the one developed for cross-national research in 1959 by Peter Townsend and Brian Rees and it seeks to appraise this schedule in terms of its suitability for research on the aged across Canada. Most of the men studied seemed to be in good health, adequately housed and financially comfortable and they were experiencing frequent contacts with children and relatives. Notwithstanding the contribution that these factors made to the pensioners' satisfactory retirement situation, this study suggests that well-being in retirement is associated with steady preretirement employment, in which the retiree has had ample opportunity to save and to participate in a pension plan geared to both length of employment and to wages. The study pointed out several limitations in the schedule, but found that it was an effective instrument to probe the patterns of living, social relationships and material circumstances of older people.</description><creator>Budge, Peter. J.</creator><creator>Ferstman, Abraham. N.</creator><creator>Neilson, A. Jardine.</creator><creator>Norris, Garry. E.</creator><creator>Walker, John. R.</creator><contributor>Younge, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Social Work.</subject><title>A study of retired male pensioners in Greater Montreal, 1963-64.</title><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v630q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892f549</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j3860b31g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In his studies on the isolated cell envelope or a marine pseudomonad, Brown (1960, 1961) observed decreases in the turbidity or suspensions or the cell envelopes when these were incubated at low buffer concentrations. Turbidity changes did not take place when the buffer concentration was increased. These decreases in turbidity or the cell envelope suspensions he interpreted to being due to degradation or the cell envelopes. A number or soluble products were released when the cell envelopes were incubated. The nature or these suggested to Brown that their release was due to the action or an enzyme. Since the release or these compounds was prevented by high buffer concentration, Brown suggested that lysis of the whole cells was due to the action of an enzyme residing in the cell envelope. Prevention of lysis of the whole cells by high salt concentration would then be due to the inhibition by salts of the action of a lytic enzyme.</description><creator>Buckmire, Francis. L.</creator><contributor>MacLeod, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Agricultural Bacteriology.</subject><title>Role of the cell envelope in the lysis of marine bacteria.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72pb91s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j3860b31g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agriculture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207ts65k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The balsam woolly aphid, Adelges piceae (Ratz.), is an introduced pest of European origin. It was discovered in Maine and New Hampshire in 1908, in Nova Scotia in 1929, and in Newfoundland in 1949 (Balch, 1952). True firs, Abies spp., are the only hosts of the aphid which causes severe damage to balsam fir, A. balsamea (L.) Mill., the predominant fir species in the Atlantic Provinces. Severe damage is caused by high numbers of aphids feeding in the crowns and on the stems of trees. In Newfoundland, rapid deterioration of tree crowns predominates; stem attack occurs infrequently and in widely dispersed spots (Carroll and Bryant, 1960). The infested area in the Province bas increased from 300 square miles in 1949 to over 3500 square miles in 1962.</description><creator>Bryant, David. G.</creator><contributor>Morrison, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Entomology.</subject><title>Balsam woolly aphid, Adelges piceae (Ratz.), development on branches of balsam fir, Abies balsamea (L.) Mill.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655m00z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207ts65k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603r2107</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Anatomically the lung consists of two conducting systems to bring the inspired air and venous blood into contact. The effectiveness of gas exchange is largely dependent on the efficiency of these distribution systems. If parts of the lung are ventilated but not perfused, or perfused but not ventilated, no gas exchange will occur in these areas. Furthermore, ventilation in excess of perfusion, or perfusion in excess of ventilation are relatively inefficient. The optimum distribution is clearly when the quantities of ventilation and perfusion are matched, that is, the Ventilation/Perfusion ratio is equal in all lung units. To predict gas exchange it is therefore necessary to know not only the total quantities of alveolar ventilation and pulmonary capillary blood flow, but also their distribution.</description><creator>Bryan, Charles. A.</creator><contributor>Bates, D. V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Experimental Medicine.</subject><title>The distribution of ventilation and perfusion in the normal lung, studied with Xe133.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236581f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r2107</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Health Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f4756</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The nephrotic syndrome bas been defined as a "pathological state of divergent etiologies, characterized by hyperlipemia, proteinuria, hypoalbuminemia and edema." (1) The primary site of the disease process is in the glomerulus and under the light microscope thickened, frayed glomerular basement membranes can be seen. (2)Electron microscopy on the other band, reveals that the lesion is chiefly due to an alteration of the epithelial layers of the basement membrane, there is a fusion or smudginess of the podocytes to form broad plaques of epithelial cytoplasm. Several etiological agents have been known to induce a nephrotic syndrome: systemic diseases such as diabetes mellitus, lupus erythematous, amyloidosis; infectious diseases, syphillis, malaria; chemical agents, trimethadione, paradione, gold salts, penicillamine; allergic reactions to bee stings, poison oak; renal diseases, chronic glomerulonephritis, acute poststreptococcal glomerulonephritis and renal vein thrombosis.</description><creator>Brown, Nydia. D.</creator><contributor>Kalant, N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>Biosynthesis of cholesterol in experimental nephrosis.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np193d478.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f4756</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cn69m749j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A simple model is proposed for the description of the scattering of neutrons by a vibrational even-even nucleus employing a complex spheroidal well surface interaction. This model is particularly convenient since it allows an exact analytic solution, which can be written in the form of correction terms to the spherical optical model. The application of this model to the s wave strength function results in a splitting of the single peak at A= 55. The inclusion of the effect of octupole excitation introduces desirable but minor modifications. Determination of the total neutron cross sections with this model substantiates the view that the flattening of giant resonances away from closed shell regions can be attributed to the effect of quadrupole excitation. There is also some evidence from this model that the effect of collective excitations could account for the characteristic shift of the maxima associated with these resonances. The scattering and reaction cross sections as well as the differential shape elastic scattering are also calculated.</description><creator>Brown, Virginia. R.</creator><contributor>Margolis, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>The effect of collective excitations on the optical model.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gk97t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m749j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h5139</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In Western Newfoundland, erosion surfaces are recognised at the following elevations: 2350-2500', 2100-2300', 1900-2150', 1750- 1900', 1550-1700', 1250-1500', 1100-1350', 1000-1150', 850-1000' and 750-850'. Surfaces below 750' were not investigated. All are considered to be of subaerial origin. By inductive reasoning, based on a recent hypothesis of the evolution of the continental margin of eastern North America, it is tentatively concluded that the group of surfaces above 2000' developed during a Cretaceous - early Cenozoic erosion cycle, and that lower surfaces are of later Cenozoic age. Uplift occurred at the beginning of the Cretaceous, in the mid Cenozoic and in the late Cenozoic. Small vertical intervals between the surfaces are tentatively attributed to periodic positive isostatic responses of the earth's crust to the relief of load by denudation since at least the beginning of the Cretaceous.</description><creator>Brookes, Ian. A.</creator><contributor>Summers, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Geography.</subject><title>The upland surfaces of western Newfoundland.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fw15h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h5139</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d504rp759</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The title chosen for this study emphasizes the antithesis between political idealism and political realism in Polish political thought. Such a study goes beyond a mere intellectual exercise to touch upon the heart or political controversy in modern Poland. For in the opinion or the writer, amid the cross-crossing currents or international politics, social processes, and ideological trends--at least in the past two centuries the conflict between political idealism and political realism has represented the single most significant phenomenon in Polish political lire. The antonymy between political idealism and political realism in Poland is basically but a fragment, confined to a single nation, or an ancient dispute between these two schools or Western political thought. The conflict between Polish political idealists and political realists is in the first place a psychological one.</description><creator>Bromke, Adam.</creator><contributor>Frankel, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Political Science.</subject><title>Political idealism and political realism in modern Poland.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3t945v39g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rp759</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b951b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the past few years, the function of the thymus gland has been greatly clarified. It is now known to play an important role in the development of immunological competence. However, less is known about that role, if any, the thymus plays in the maintenance of immune function during adult life. Because of the bearing of immune function on tissue transplantation and because of the possible role of the thymus in immune function, this gland may be of importance in a better understanding of organ and tissue rejection. Similarly, modification or removal of the thymus, with or without other treatment, may be of value in modifying the homograft rejection phenomenon. If any rational attempt, to alter homograft rejection by manipulation or extirpation of the thymus, is to be made, a more thorough knowledge of the function of the adult thymus is necessary.</description><creator>Braunstein, Peter. M.</creator><contributor>MacLean, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Experimental Surgery.</subject><title>The functional of the thymus of the adult mammal.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311s97x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b951b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pk826</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the most striking characteristics of postwar economic thinking is the concern with economic growth. The reconstruction of Western Europe was but one example of the generalized interest in economic growth, although the one with which the world leadership was more directly concerned. In the far larger proportion of the world community generally known as "underdeveloped," the need to grow assumed undreamed-of strength. Many factors contributed to the upsurge of this "growth consciousness" in the underdeveloped areas: (1) Population "explosion." The spread of modern techniques of health and sanitation in the backward regions of the world brought about astounding results in the control of infant mortality and epidemic diseases.</description><creator>Branco, Raul. M.</creator><contributor>Mundell, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Economics.</subject><title>Brazil: a case study of government revenues under inflation.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73q061p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pk826</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x734n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>As an earth-bound being man is confronted by two landscapes; the natural and the man-made, and both are of interest to him as an intellectual creature. While both landscapes may cause feelings of awe, or peace, or in some cases apprehension, the emotion aroused by the sight of a man-made landscape is imbued with a deeper feeling of identification which flows from the recognition of the work of fellow creatures. A sign of man in an otherwise empty landscape can change an l-It attitude to an I-Thou attitude, even though the sign may be no more than a vehicle track on the dry surface of a barren desert. Natural and man-made landscapes are of primary interest to the geographer, but while study of the first is likely to be largely objective, aimed at a deeper understanding of nature, study of the second is more subjective and aimed at a deeper understanding of man.</description><creator>Brack, David. M.</creator><contributor>Hills, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Geography.</subject><title>Peasant agriculture in Barbados.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z1663.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x734n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j886r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recent electrophysiological studies of visual mechanisms in frogs have demonstrated that a high degree of selection of specific information occurs right at the retinal level (Barlow, 1953a and 1953b; Lettvin et al., 1959; Maturans et al., 1960). This research has important theoretical implications for the behavioral sciences, but there have been few systematic laboratory studies of the effects of specific visual stimuli on amphibian behavior. It has long been assumed that the retina transduces visual information into nerve impulse patterns, and that a faithful replica of the visual world is transmitted to the brain, where all information processing is believed to occur. Physiological studies of retinal processes have shown that the mechanisms are not as simple as this.</description><creator>Biersner, Robert. J.</creator><contributor>Melzack, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Psychology.</subject><title>Approach and avoidance responses in the frog to varying dimensions of visual stimuli.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dq69r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j886r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mn43q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The existence of a water-insoluble precursor or pectin has been known since 1848 when Fremy reported the occurrence or a "pectose” (1). This material was insoluble in water and even in cold concentrated hydrochloric acid but was transformed by heating in dilute acid solutions into a water-soluble pectin similar in properties to the pectin which bad been discovered in plant juices. Pectin has now been isolated from many sources, although its chemistry is not yet completely known. In addition to the well-know use of pectin as food and tor various industrial purposes, pectin is now rapidly finding more use in medicine (2). It can be employed directly as a therapeutic agent, as a supplement or potentiator of a drug. Pectin has the ability to inhibit the growth of certain viruses. It is injected with hormones, sulfa drugs, and antibiotics, and is also used in diarrhea therapy.</description><creator>Bhattacharjee, Shyam. S.</creator><contributor>Purves, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>A study of pectic material from the bark of amabilis fir (Abies Amabilis).</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z167c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mn43q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149t13h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, we study rational extensions of monoids with a zero element. This is essentially a generalisation of the corresponding theory for rings as developed in (7) and (6). (See bibliography at the end). For various reasons, we have decided to consider monoids with a zero element, henceforth called monoids, but most of the results can easily be generalised to general monoids. In the first chapter, we first introduce the notion of an M-set, which is essentially a representation of a monoid, and these M-sets play the same role as R-modules for rings. Then, through the rest of the chapter, we introduce all the tools needed to show that the injective hull of an M-set always exists, and we end the chapter by an example: more specifically, we show that the injective hull of the rationals, considered as a partly ordered set, is the set of reals.</description><creator>Berthiaume, Pierre.</creator><contributor>Lambek, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Rational completion of monoids.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vf966.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149t13h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nz191</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the living animal, brain often swells greatly following trauma. There are two types of brain swelling: 1. One occurs very rapidly and is probably due to a dilatation of blood vessels or an increase in the cerebrospinal fluid volume or both. This is what Elliott and Jasper have referred to as 'inflation' (Elliott and Jasper, 1949). 2. The other is more chronic and is brought about by an increase in the water content of the cerebral tissues. Many experimental studies of cerebral edema have been published yet little is known about the basic mechanisms responsible for its production. At the same time there is a great need to gain some understanding of the beneficial effects of cortisone which has been used on an empirical basis to relieve the symptoms commonly attributed to cerebral edema (Galicich and French, 1961; Rasmussen and Gulati, 1962).</description><creator>Berger, Paula. M.</creator><contributor>Pappius, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Biochemistry.</subject><title>The effect of cold injury on the water and electrolyte content of brain and on the uptake of thiocyanate by cerebral tissues.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924g22t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nz191</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r207ts66v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introductory statement - Prospecting for ore minerals is often carried on by examining the bedrock at or very near the earth’s surface. The bedrock, however, over large areas of the earth, is covered by layers of material called overburden. It has been demonstrated that under certain conditions the bedrock can be examined indirectly by chemical analyses of the soils or plants covering it. Canada, particularly in the north, has large areas covered by deposits in the form of peat bogs or muskegs. The examination of bedrock under peat bogs or muskegs by chemical analyses has not been practised in Canada, but it has been tried with some success in Finland. The present study was organized under the name “Operation Muskeg” to be carried out by a team of geologists and a botanist from McGill University.</description><creator>Bentley, Philip. A.</creator><contributor>Boll, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Botany.</subject><title>A biogeochemical study of bog plants.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fw16s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r207ts66v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2v23vx49r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The idea of the control of the sex ratio is not a recent one. According to Gordon (1958), men have been attempting to control or predict the sex of their offspring for thousands of years. This subject was discussed in a Chinese Manuscript about 4,400 years ago. An Egyptian papyrus of 2,200 B.C. noted that a pregnant woman with the use of greenish cast was certain to bear a son. Aristotle believed that the placing of the marriage bed in a north-south direction favored the conception of boys. These are examples of the many beliefs that have been reported regarding sex determination, which have since been demonstrated to be false. The scientific history of the subject of sex determination began with the discovery of the genetic mechanism by which sex is determined in mammals. According to genetic theory, the male mammal has a special pair of sex chromosomes made up of one X chromosome and one so-called Y chromosome.</description><creator>Belanger, Jean-Marc.</creator><contributor>Moxley, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Animal Science.</subject><title>Factors affecting the sex ratio of swine.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s382z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vx49r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agriculture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:08612s10n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In 1901 Baron Roland von Eötvös used gravimetric measurements to obtain the elevation contours of a lake bottom and thus established on an experimental basis, the value of this technique for indicating and mapping near-surface density variations in the earth's crust. Since then, the gravity method has been extensively used for outlining various geological structures. A series of typical applications of this method is discussed by Heiland (1940, p. 157) Because of the relatively high density contrast between rock and ice, gravimetric measurements have been used recently for determining subglacial elevation contours. This application of gravity measurements possibly originated with the Expeditions Polaires Francaises. (Martin 1948) Within the last few years, such measurements were used quite successfully on the Gilman (Weber 1960), Salmon (Russell 1960), and Athabaska (Kanasewich 1963) glaciers.</description><creator>Becker, Alexander.</creator><contributor>Pounder, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>On the determination of glacial depth.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n2032.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612s10n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z9033522</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The project investigates aspects of professional social work which derive from its association with bureaucratic organizations. This enquiry is based upon sociological evidence that the combination of professional and bureaucratic modes of occupational life contains mutually dysfunctional aspects. The published work by Blau and Scott, Formal Organizations, is the point of departure for the study. The data are the perceptions of social workers as obtained by a slightly modified 85 item questionnaire developed by W.R. Scott in his work on a Doctoral dissertation in Sociology at the University of Chicago. The questionnaire was distributed to 12 social work settings in Montreal. Coded data from the 128 respondents were used in IBM processing. Findings suggest that training and experience are associated with some opposition to supervision, but divergent findings and interpretations are reported on the theoretically non-professional aspect of supervision in social work as a nascent profession. Perceptions of the extent to which seven principles and standards are fulfilled in practice seem affected by respondents’ religious beliefs and by the extent to which a given principle corresponds to cultural values. Social work at present meets, in varying degrees, some of the criteria of a profession. For professional workers, informal norms of the social work community suggest occupational reinforcements via advancement to supervisory posts and by identification with medicine, especially psychiatry. The high proportion of women in social work practice and other topics are suggested for future investigation.</description><creator>Beavan, Ronald. P.</creator><creator>Herscovitch, Shirley.</creator><creator>Lustgarten, Sylvia. S.</creator><creator>Matlin, Eleanor.</creator><creator>Matthews, Judith. S.</creator><contributor>Kirk, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Social Work.</subject><title>Professional and bureaucratic perspectives in social work.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p8332.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z9033522</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vq27zr99h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In recent years a number of studies have revealed the existence of biochemical differences between the body fluids of schizophrenic patients and the body fluids of normal human subjects. In particular, differences have been reported in both urine constituents and blood constituents; and in blood constituents, not only in the plasma fraction, but also in the formed elements (or cells) fraction. While the nature of the association between such biochemical anomalies and the behavioral anomalies of schizophrenic patients remains to be investigated, evidence is accumulating that a factor, or factors in the blood substances of schizophrenic patients can disrupt the behavior of animals, ranging in neural complexity from planaria to Cebus monkeys.</description><creator>Beach, Bertram. L.</creator><contributor>Stern, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Psychology.</subject><title>Effects of schizophrenics’ blood on rat behavior.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mt39n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vq27zr99h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn00b2210</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Stress corrosion cracking in its simplest terms is metal failure resulting, over a period of time from the conjoint action of stress and corrosion. In reality, the problem is more involved than this definition might suggest for the reason that the two operating factors, namely, stress and corrosion do not act in a simple additive way. Stress corrosion cracking is not a mere case of metal corrosion in the presence of stress. Although it is true that corrosive attack is part of the mechanism, the extent or severity of corrosion is not a guiding criterion for susceptibility to cracking. Many mildly corrosive environments have been recognised as strongly potent in causing this type of failure. A classical example was noted (1,2) in an experimental alloy which was stressed and immersed in a mineral oil-Nujol-and which failed in 735 days.</description><creator>Baveja, Prem. I.</creator><contributor>Yates, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Metallurgical Engineering.</subject><title>Stress corrosion cracking in low alloy steels.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sx40c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b2210</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848v02k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Depuis 1940, la réputation littéraire de Paul Morand a subi une sérieuse éclipse. La politique en est en partie responsable, mais l'évolution des valeurs intellectuelles y est aussi pour beaucoup. Morand s'était identifié à une époque, celle de la génération de 1930. Elle lui avait reconnu un grand talent et l'avait placé presque au même niveau littéraire que Marcel Proust et André Gide. Nos aînés semblent avoir commis une monumentale erreur d'appréciation. Ils ont pris du strass pour du diamant, et se sont laissés éblouir par le "modernisme" de Morand. Cosmopolitisme, ésotérisme, snobisme, joints à une authentique élégance d'attitude, à une passion de la vitesse, à un élan vers le "dernier cri", à une coïncidence parfaite avec son époque, avaient fait de Morand le plus représentatif des écrivains grand' bourgeois de l'entre-deux guerres.</description><creator>Bartok, Maria.</creator><contributor>Launay, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>French.</subject><title>Procédés stylistiques de Paul Morand – portraits de New York et de Londres.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z4434.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848v02k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dw876</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A technique is devised for corona-pulse intensity calibration of the corona detection circuit employed in the experiments; this calibration scheme may be regarded as a modification of one of the three suggested ASTM calibration methods. The remaining two methods are found to have serious inherent disadvantages and are discarded oh those accounts. A method, developed for the measurement of the corona discharge rate, is extensively used to analyze the sequence of discharge behaviour within spark gaps of various spacings and under different vapour pressures. The discharge rate measurements, in conjunction with toe observations on the voltage waveforms across discharging gaps, show numerous deviations from the idealized hypotheses of Gemant and Whitehead -- the most conspicuous difference being the quasilinear increase of discharge rate with voltage instead of the abrupt jumps predicted by the idealized theory.</description><creator>Bartnikas, Ray.</creator><contributor>D’Ombrain, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Electrical Engineering.</subject><title>A study of the corona and dielectric losses in practical insulating systems.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tg530.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dw876</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2r36v200f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T19:49:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Housing is one of the most important basic necessities of human life next to food. The activity in housing does not meet the demands of increasing populations, with the result that today every country is facing a serious housing problem particularly in urban areas. It is an actual fact that the need for housing, particularly of people of low income in urban areas such as Bangkok, has reached a high level. The significance of this can be seen from the steady growth of housing projects, but most of them are not perfectly suited to satisfy the needs of the people sufficiently. In the country of Thailand as a whole this causes many problems, and especially in Bangkok where the problem has been more serious than in the other provinces.</description><creator>Bardhanabeadya, Chula.</creator><contributor>Hazeland, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Architecture.</subject><title>A low-rise, medium density housing project, Sapan Kwai, Bangkok.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w3253.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2r36v200f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):15500</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>