<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:34:23Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11675" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:73666789s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The control of apple pests In Nova Scotia has developed into an arduous and expensive process [...] The study of the effects of the spray program on the natural control of oystershell scale which forms the basis of this thesis is in turn a part of the whole general ecological approach to the study of orchard pests in Nova Scotia. During the course of these experiments it became very evident that time and space are two very important factors to be considered in the investigation of orchard insect problems. The spray program which has been followed in an orchard in the years before an experiment is started has an important conditioning effect on the experiment. This can only be overcome by using the experimental materials on the same trees for several years in succession. Single row plots are limited in long term studies by the differential ability of the various species to migrate from one plot to another. The importance of the failure to consider the over-all effect of a spray program is illustrated by the advocation of elemental sulphur sprays for commercial orchards on the sole basis of their fungicidal value without relation to their effects on all other organisms As a result of these investigations it is now known that sulphur sprays inhibit natural control of oystershell scale while bordeaux mixture, Fermate or no spray at all will allow natural control agents to eliminate oystershell scale.</description><creator>Lord, Frank Tennant.</creator><contributor>Brittain, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Entomology.</subject><title>The influence of the spray program on the natural control of oystershell scale, Lepidosaphes ulmi (L.).</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sd70z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666789s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r632h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A cold cathode proton source operating at about 300 volts and a pressure of a few microns is described. The discharge is essentially similar to that of a Philips vacuum gauge. The characteristics of the discharge, the ion extraction and the proton production have been investigated. The addition of 10% of oxygen to the hydrogen increased the proton content of the ion beam from 10% to 50% while introducing only about 1% of oxygen and other foreign ions. The ionization processes are discussed.</description><creator>Lorrain, Paul.</creator><contributor>Foster, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>A low-pressure glow-discharge proton source.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b423p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r632h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149s830</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Smith in 1899 (99) recognized the xylem inhabiting nature of parasites causing wilt diseases of cotton, watermelon and cowpea. A great many similar diseases of dicotyledonous plants have since been found attributable to fungi that are largely confined to the xylem vessels, and the condition produced referred to as a ‘vascular mycosis’. Bewley (8), who thought that these fungi interfered with the normal water relations of the plant, was the first to suggest that the term ‘hadromycosis’, used throughout this work, be applied. Six theories have been evolved to explain the mechanism by which hadromycotic fungi cause wilting. [...] The present work was undertaken in an attempt to clarify some of the phenomena associated with hadromycotic wilting, special attention being given to the water balance of plants attacked by vascular Fusaria. Studies were confined largely to tomato wilt, caused by Fusarium oxysporum f. lycopersici, because the tomato plant lends itself to this type of study and can be grown easily under greenhouse conditions.</description><creator>Ludwig, Ralph Anthony.</creator><contributor>Coulson, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Plant Pathology.</subject><title>The physiology of hadromycotic wilting in plants with special reference to tomato wilt.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237hv77h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149s830</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483n44s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Today industry is too competitive to remain the shuttlecock of supply and demand. Producing capacity has the potentiality of growing so much faster than its markets that there is the everpresent danger of overexpansion soon to result in the enormous wastes of excess capacity. In the past there was no real problem of coordinating supply and demand. The population was expanding rapidly and the markets growing even faster. Consumer tastes were not particularly discriminating, and by and large there was insufficient producing capacity to meet the needs of the market. You simply made what you wanted to make and consumers took i t . Over a period of years the supply never quite caught up to the demand; it was always slightly set back by periods of war and depression when equilibrium was in sight. The situation today is somewhat the same. The tremendous demand created by the curtailment of consumer production during the war is considerably in exfiess of the supply. This provides industry with great temptations of hugh immediate profits to be realized only by the immediate expansion of its productive equipment. [...]</description><creator>Cooper, Howard Bernard.</creator><contributor>Coote, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947. </date><subject>Mechanical Engineering. </subject><title>The engineering factors controlling the optimum size of a manufacturing enterprise.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bp81p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483n44s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78tg27c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ownership is defined by article 406 of the Civil Code of Lower Canada as "the right of enjoying and disposing of things in the most absolute manner provided that no use be made of them which is prohibited by law or by regulation". This right being, in theory, absolute, an owner cannot be forced to dispose of his property against his will. In order to make possible the erection and extension of public works and to prevent a recalcitrant owner from making public improvements Impossible by refusing to sell his property or exacting an exorbitant price it has been necessary in the public interest to temper the rule of article 406, because public interest must prevail over private interest. Hence in Quebec article 407 states that a person may be compelled to give up his property for public utility and in consideration of the previous payment of a just indemnity.[...]</description><creator>Challies, George Swan.</creator><contributor>Scott, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947. </date><subject>Eminent domain -- Canada.</subject><subject>Real property -- Canada.</subject><subject>Real property -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Eminent domain -- Québec (Province).</subject><title>Expropriation under the law of the Dominion of Canada and the Province of Quebec.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117s167.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78tg27c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Comparative Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kd86b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The annual production of wheat germ, as such, in the United States is estimated to be 30 to 50 million pounds. However, the present milling yield of about 0.5 per cent indicates a potential production of about 150 million pounds of germ (1). The wheat kernel is reported (2) to contain 2.2 - 3.0 per cent of germ, and, therefore, it is possible that, in the future, the milling yield and hence the potential production of wheat germ may be greatly increased. For Canada, assuming an annual production of 350 million bushels of wheat and a yield of only 0.5 per cent of germ, the potential production of wheat germ is about 100 million pounds per annum. Wheat germ, as a by-product of the milling industry, is used as animal feed, generally as component of the bran, and in limited amounts as a source of oil. [...] The laboratory conditions for the large scale isolation of ribonucleic acid from wheat germ have not been studied in detail. Ribonucleic acid of a high degree of purity has never been isolated in good yield from wheat germ. Therefore, it is proposed in this investigation to determine the optimum conditions for the extraction and isoelectric precipitation of a definite nucleoprotein fraction; to investigate the required degree of denaturation of nucleoprotein for the separation of nucleic acid; and to develop a satisfactory method for the purification of ribonucleic acid.</description><creator>Lusena, Charles Victor.</creator><contributor>McFarlane, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>Studies on the preparation of nucleoproteins and ribonucleic acid from wheat germ.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515r637.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kd86b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s4655k674</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present process employed in the manufacture of GR-3 type synthetic rubber is that of emulsion polymerization. This method has the advantage of being easily controlled as well as possessing a faster rate of reaction than either bulk phase or solution polymerization (1, 2). The GR-S system discussed herein is made up of monomer, water, catalyst, modifier and emulsifying agent, which, upon agitation at a moderate temperature, results in the formation of a heterogeneous mixture. This complicates investigation of the locus of polymerization. The ease of control is due, in part at least, to the heat transfer from one medium to the other. Since the GR-S reaction, as in the case of most vinyl polymerizations, is exothermic, rapid removal of heat is necessary in order that the reaction may proceed at an even rate. This is possible in an emulsion system, due to the fact that the monomer is present in the form of small particles, entirely surrounded by the water medium, and thus presents a large surface which permits rapid heat transfer. [...]</description><creator>Cabott, Irwin Marcus.</creator><contributor>Nicholls, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947. </date><subject>Chemistry. </subject><title>A study of mechanical factors in GR-S bottle polymerizations.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j67317206.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655k674</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1c18dj788</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>[...] Dans cette thèse nous voulons indiquer,démontrer, suggérer ces aspects de la vie "bourgeoise de la France que Hoger Martin du Gard présente si clairement dans le roman fleuve, ffLes Thibault11, les aspects familiaux, religieux, sociaux, psychologiques et historiques.</description><creator>Butterfield, Lee Edden.</creator><contributor>Furness, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947. </date><subject>Martin Du Gard, Roger, 1881-1958. Thibault.</subject><title>La peinture de la bourgeoisie dans "Les Thibault" de Roger Martin du Gard.</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g818f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1c18dj788</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s1619413</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Quite apart from World War II, the years following 1934 may well be the most important in the history of the British West Indies in general, and of Jamaica in particular A series of labour disturbances over the British Caribbean area led to the West India Royal Commission of 1938-39, and this Commission made an exhaustive examination of the whole range of conditions, social and economic, prevailing in the (1) British colonies. Subsequently, under provision of the Colonial Development and Welfare Act, 1940, His Majestyfs Government appointed a Comptroller to work out, in collaboration with the local governments, long term programmes of social reform and schemes of development and welfare.[...]</description><creator>Burgess, Charles Johnson.</creator><contributor>Beach, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947. </date><subject>Economics. </subject><subject>JAMAICA -- ECONOMIC CONDITIONS AND HISTORY.</subject><title>An appraisal of the report of the Economic Policy Committee of Jamaica, 1945.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322h82b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s1619413</identifier><degree><name>Master of Commerce</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zw12z834f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The colonies of North America have furnished endless sources of research material for historians, biographers, sociologists, economists, educationalists, and countless numbers of novelists. It is a rich field, as yet unexhausted by the pens of ardent students of its past. New Brunswick, one of the older colonies, offers vast opportunities to those who would delve into its background. Vibrant with the tales of exploration, adventure, political implications, expansion, interesting personalities, and culture, its story has intrigued the curiosity of men and women throughout the last century and a quarter. The publication of the first history of New Brunswick in 1825 by Peter Fisher marked the beginning of a flow of literature which, though abundant, has left much yet to be dusted off and set within the framework of the past. Particularly is this true of the educational aspect of the province’s story. [...] A chronological description of the development of all institutions of elementary and higher education in the province of New Brunswick during that period when the social, economic, and political outlooks were being transformed from the aristocratic to the democratic way of life, with particular emphasis on the internal developments and the influencing personalities which led to the final provision of free, non-sectarian education at all levels save the university in 1871. This, then, will be the object of this thesis.</description><creator>Lynam, Josephine Berteaux.</creator><contributor>Hughes, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Education -- New Brunswick -- History.</subject><title>Educational institutions in New Brunswick, 1830-1871.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pw993.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zw12z834f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4f16c5792</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Investigation of the effect of an electrical field on a chemical reaction involves the study of a system acting under the influence of an external perturbing force. It is of interest, therefore, to consider, in brief outline, the nature of this force, and the energy associated with it. Treatises on this subject are available in standard references (1, 2). The intensity of an electrical field is a measure of the force exerted on a unit charge when at rest in the field. The field intensity at any distance from a point charge is given by Coulomb's Law, and in practical units is measured in volts per cm. The difference in potential between two points in a field is given by the work necessary to bring a unit positive charge from one point to the other.[...]</description><creator>Bryce, William Alistair.</creator><contributor>Winkler, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947. </date><subject>Chemistry. </subject><title>The effect of alternating electrical fields on the polymerization of styrene.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149s848.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c5792</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924f85w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The necessity of choosing a theme for this report even before the experimental work was begun made it appear advisable to choose a relatively all inclusive title which would embrace all phases of any experimental work which might be carried out. Any attempt to investigate all of the factors affecting the thyroid gland and body metabolism in the space of one year would, of course, be impossible and we have centered our interest on a study of certain antithyroid and metabolo-depressant drugs, and, in order that the action of these drugs might be more efficiently investigated, certain environmental influences which give rise to a hypermetabolic state in laboratory animals. During the course of preliminary reading on this subject a multitude of interesting problems presented themselves which appeared to offer fertile fields for further investigation. Since at that stage it was impossible to predict which, if any of these avenues would lead to a field in which more intensive study would be indicated it was decided to begin a series of orientation experiments on a variety of topics. This procedure proved valuable in that a variety of experimental techniques and problems presented themselves but as time passed and we became more and more reticent about discarding any of the topics it became apparent that the various threads could not be woven into a well integrated whole but, to some extent at least, would require presentation as separate entities. [...]</description><creator>Macbeth, Robert A. L.</creator><contributor>Noble, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Endocrinology.</subject><title>Factors affecting the thyroid gland and body metabolism of small animals.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722hc97r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924f85w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Endocrinology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xw23v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It has been noted that in previous determinations of the velocity of sound in air, direct measurements of the velocity of sharp sound pulses, carried out over long distances, in the open, have yielded consistently lower values than indirect methods employing continuous sound of a definite frequency. The average of direct methods is about 330.8, and the average of indirect methods about 331«5im/s. Direct measurements of the velocity of sound in air have been made in the laboratory over a distance of 50 feet, using a high speed vacuum-tube counter-chronograph, microphones, and a spark discharge as a sound source. Since the measurements were made indoors, uncertainties due to meteorological conditions, which were inherent in previous direct determinations, have been eliminated.[...]</description><creator>Bercovitch, Mortimer.</creator><contributor>Marshall, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947. </date><subject>Physics. </subject><title>A new determination of the velocity of sound in air using counter-chronograph and microphones.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c379w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xw23v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8s45qc95d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Before the recent war, there was abroad a belief that because of the scientific development of weapons of destruction, the ordinary fighting man would play an increasingly smaller part in any future war. This, along with many other superficial judgements, was proved to be a fallacy by the campaigns of the war of 1939-1945. Although, in the early years of the war, there was a school of thought which disparaged the experiences and methods of the war of 1914-1918, it later became apparent to some that there were many similarities between this so-called modern war and the previous world struggle. Many a civilian-turned- soldier found that recruiting bulletins and magazine articles often did not give a true picture of the facts. [...] To go deeper, it became evident that there are basic human factors which must be the same in all wars. The great phenomena of fear, of hunger and fatigue, of discomfort and home-sickness, and of comradeship in arms - all of which are the common experience of soldiers - seem to be permanent and universal. It is because of this common quality that we feel the writings of the past concerning soldiers are relevant to our present understanding of them. The purpose of this paper is to see what our greatest poet and dramatist, Shakespeare, had to say about soldiers -, or rather, since he was a creator of character, what kind of soldiers we find in his works.</description><creator>MacDonald, Allister, 1922-</creator><contributor>Macmillan, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Shakespeare, William, 1564-1616 -- Characters -- Soldiers.</subject><title>Shakespeare’s treatment of soldiers.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xs55mg053.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qc95d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rs066</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It has long been known that fats and oils develop rancidity when exposed to the air. Atmospheric oxygen attacks the unsaturated triglyceride molecules with the formation of many oxidation products, among which peroxidic and carbonyl compounds are the most important. This deterioration of the fat results in the production of off-flavours and odours which render the fat unpalatable. Many chemical tests have been employed for the detection of rancidity which depend on the presence of these compounds. Recently a very sensitive method has been developed based on the oxidation of ferrous iron to ferric by the peroxides present in an oxidized fat. The ferric ion produced is determined colorimetrically as ferric thiocyanate. This method has recently been severely criticized by Lea, who stated that the method was subject to serious error owing to the interference of atmospheric oxygen. The presence of air in the reaction mixture has also resulted in high peroxide values of fats and oils when determined by other modifications of the ferrous salt method. It was the purpose of this study to investigate the ferric thiocyanate method, with a view to preventing this oxygen interference, and to compare the results given by several ferrous salt methods with those obtained by iodimetric procedures.</description><creator>Mackay, Kathleen Isabelle.</creator><contributor>Chapman, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>Studies on methods for the determination of peroxides in fats and oils.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43p144n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rs066</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806332b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les livres de M. Georges Duhamel ont eu du succès en France et à l’étranger, et un grand nombre de ses livres publies avant 1937 avaient été traduits en anglais. “Le Notaire du Havre”, le premier de la série des Pasquier, a été traduit pendant la même année (1934) en Angleterre par Beatrice de Holthoir, et publie par J.M, Dent &amp; Sons, London, sous le titre de “News from Havre”, et aussi aux Etats-Unis par Samuel Putman, publie par Harper Bros, New York et intitule “Papa Pasquier”. Ce sont ces deux traductions qui font l’objet de cette étude. Ce livre qui est très français d’esprit est difficile a bien rendre en anglais. Le nombre de fautes qu’une étude soigneuse a révélées témoigne de cette difficulté. L’étude comparative de ces deux traductions est faite surtout au point de vue des erreurs qui s’y trouvent et non pas au point de vue des qualités. II est peut-être dommage de procéder ainsi mais on constate que souvent le défaut de l’une sert a mettre en lumière la qualité de l’autre. La variété de ces erreurs, dont chacune semble être un cas particulier, rend très difficile la tache de les réunir et d’en faire un récit continu et bien organisé. Le but de cette étude sera de les classer, d’en montrer quelques exemples particulièrement caractéristiques ou intéressants, et d’en tirer des conclusions générales, dans la mesure ou cela est possible.</description><creator>MacNeill, Glorana Harding.</creator><contributor>Launay, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Duhamel, Georges, 1884-1966. Notaire du Havre.</subject><title>Etude comparative de deux traductions anglaise et américaine du roman de Georges Duhamel, Le notaire de Havre.</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sn52b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806332b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:js956k10j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This report presents the results of two summers of field work during which an area of approximately 140 square miles of previously unmapped country was systematically traversed. In addition it includes a correlation of all previous work in the Burlington Peninsula. The newly mapped areas include the north coast of the peninsula from Ming's Bight to Cape St. John and south to join the Tilt Cove - Bett's Cove area mapped by Snelgrove, (1931), and a strip about three miles wide along the coast from Nipper's Harbour to the south side of Middle .Arm, Green Bay. To assist in correlation, reconnaissance trips were taken into the previously described areas. Exploratory traverses were made along the shore of White Bay from Fleur de Lys to Bear Cove, inland from Burlington to the end of the new Bowater road at Flat Water Pond, along the trail from Burlington to Baie Verte, and a trans-peninsular traverse from Western .Arm, White Bay, to Middle .Arm, Green Bay.</description><creator>Baird, David McCurdy.</creator><contributor>Gill, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Geological Sciences. </subject><title>The geology of the Burlington Peninsula, Newfoundland.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mw22v8898.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956k10j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cf16m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis does not attempt to present any complete picture of the period 1760-1791 in Canada, even though the French party of Adam Mabane was an important influence in Canadian affairs throughout most of those years. It attempts, rather, to trace the growth of one political group, and many of the events of the period that did not seem to pertain directly to that growth have thus been omitted. More particularly, this thesis is subject to the same limitations from which the French party suffered throughout its career: Its emphasis is entirely upon the political, judicial, and religious aspects of the period, almost to the exclusion of economic and social aspects.[...]</description><creator>Arthur, Elizabeth.</creator><contributor>Adair, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Mabane, Adam, 1734-1792.</subject><subject>Canada -- Politics and government -- 1763-1791.</subject><subject>Canada -- History -- 1763-1791.</subject><title>Adam Mabane and the French party in Canada : 1760-1791.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qg448.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cf16m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988p099</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Throughout the apple growing areas in the Annapolis Valley, N. S. there has been, over the past years, an increase in the number of sprays applied to apple trees; together with this there has developed a steady increase in the complexity of the pest problem. Fruit growers now find that the keen competition in the markets available to them, together with the high cost of pest control, necessitates that no further increase in the cost of spraying take place and it is desirable that it be decreased. It was with these facts in mind that the staff of the Dominion Entomological Laboratory, Annapolis Royal began studies on the basic cause of the anomaly of more spraying creating still greater problems (Pickett et al 1946). In searching for the answers to this general problem it soon became apparent that insufficient attention had been given to the latent or long term effect of sprays. [...] Sufficient evidence has been gathered to show that the suppression of the natural control of a previously minor pest, by attempting to control some major pest, has led to the necessity for costly increases in the spray program. [...] A study of Haplothrips faurei was therefore begun as a basis for the study of thrips as predators in apple orchards, as well as for its morphological value. This morphological study has been supplemented by observations on its biology and as many records as possible on the effect of spray materials upon its abundance are included.</description><creator>MacPhee, Albert William.</creator><contributor>Brittain, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Entomology.</subject><title>The morphology and bionomics of the Predaceous Thrips Haplothrips faurei Hood.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vv05j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988p099</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m900nx819</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The practical and theoretical importance of membrane phenomena has long been recognized. The study of the passage of material into and out of living cells, and experimental techniques such as ultrafiltration and dialysis have long required the use of membranes. More recently, an intensive search has been in progress for membranes suitable for determination of molecular weights of high polymers by osmotic pressure measurements. The subject of this investigation Is the cellophane membrane. This material has been used as a membrane in osmotic pressure determinations of high molecular weight materials in organic solvents. The treatment of the cellophane and its accommodation to such systems has been semi-empirical and consequently certain anomalous results have been reported (1) (2). One of the purposes of this investigation is to establish a mechanism of permeability through cellophane consistent with the other known properties of cellulose such as swelling and sorption. Permeability rates, void volumes and electrical conductance measurements were made to establish the size and number of pores and the specific surface of the membrane. Based upon these observations, a mechanism for permeability through cellophane has been advanced.</description><creator>Madras, Samuel.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Cellophane as membrane material.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xm80n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m900nx819</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn9999830</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Prediction is one of the main objectives of scienoe, though this is not its sole aim nor, necessarily, the most important one. In any case, all sciences aspire to this refinement. In Psychology* however, prediction is much more difficult than in other disciplines. Psychologists deal in behaviour and, except in the simplest types, obstacles in the way of prediction are enormous. In general, such obstacles stem from the following conditions: 1) The variables involved usually are very difficult to isolate and define. 2) Control of many of these is impossible. 3) Many of the variables all but defy measurement. For example, there is a vast difference between the relatively straightforward problem of finding and controlling the variables involved in the activity of either an acid or base in the presence of the other and that of tracking down the factors contributing to the behaviour of the college student pursuing a course of study and attempting examinations. Nevertheless, this last is precisely the task which confronts those who are interested in the problems of forecasting and guidance for the college student. Their point of departure is the question: What are the factors governing success in school or college? The success of guidance and counselling programs depends on how fully and accurately this question can be answered.</description><creator>Mahoney, Gerald Maurice.</creator><contributor>Webster, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>VOCATIONAL EDUCATION.</subject><subject>PSYCHOLOGY -- MENTAL TESTS.</subject><subject>ABILITY.</subject><title>The relationship between general mental ability and university achievement.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qn052.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn9999830</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vm170</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Experiments entailing 256 guinea pigs were carried out to compare three methods of interpreting data obtained from the ‘Odontoblast Method’ of vitamin C bioassay using three types of tomato juice and two types of apple juice as the antiscorbutic test substances. All three methods led to approximately the same relative potencies. However, Bliss and Marks’ procedure (Method II) overcame some of the limitations of Coward’s dosage-response curve method (Method I), in that it introduced objective tests for the linearity of the response curves and for the existence of parallelism between the standard and the test substances, thus establishing a more valid assay. Method III, by isolating individual treatment effects using single degrees of freedom as illustrated by Snedecor, largely established the validity of the assay and in addition when applied in conjunction with Method II established the reliability of the estimated potencies.</description><creator>Manson, Mary Georgia.</creator><contributor>Crampton, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Nutrition.</subject><title>A comparison of three methods of interpreting data from vitamin C bioassay.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88ck858.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vm170</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv935612m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Rapid progress has been made in the last decade in the study of chemotherapy, “a subject concerning the properties and various interactions of drug, parasite and host,” (Mcllwain, 1944). In particular, many bacterial diseases which have so far failed to respond to immunization are now being more effectively treated with drugs which have only recently been recognized. The chemotherapeutic drugs include those prepared synthetically and the naturally occurring antibiotics produced by living organisms.  [...] Several important physical factors, such as permeability, oxygen tension and oxidation-reduction potentials have been shown to influence the overall antibacterial effect and must therefore be considered in studying the mode of drug action on bacteria. An attempt has been made in this project to investigate some of the fundamental factors which influence the action of chemotherapeutic drugs on bacteria. The results obtained in vitro would seem to indicate that a more effective chemotherapeutic action could be expected by the utilization of two inhibitory drugs simultaneously, resulting in a potentiated or synergistic action which cannot be accounted for by the arithmetic sum of the drug action per se. Accordingly, this latter aspect of synergism between antibacterial substances has also been studied.</description><creator>Marmur, Julius, 1926-</creator><contributor>Thatcher, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>Chemotherapy.</subject><subject>Microorganisms.</subject><title>A study of the mode of action of chemotherapeutic substances.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x694w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935612m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Bacteriology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b656b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Toute thèse scientifique doit être appuyée par des faits. C’est ce que j‘ai essayé de faire dans le présent ouvrage. Il y a des vérités que l‘on peut classifier comme dangereuses parce qu‘elles ne sont pas sanctionnées par l‘opinion publique. Quand une découverte met à nu un point faible du pouvoir en autorité, i l y a toujours danger de représailles. Tout au fond de notre subconscient, la peur d‘être ennuyé, tout aussi bien que la nouveauté du principe, agissant sur nous à notre insu nous représente des données véridiques comme invraisemblables. Nous serions tentés de les juger fausses si nous n‘y regardions pas à deux fois. Les premières découvertes scientifiques qui renversaient les idéologies acceptées par la masse ont été répétées d‘abord. Cette thèse appartient à l a catégorie des idées dangereuses. J‘ai été amenée par l a force des circonstances à douter des opinions auxquelles j‘avais d’abord adhéré religieusement. Mes recherches ont confirmé mes doutes et m’ont établie dans les convictions que j’exprime dans les chapitres qui suivent. Sans prétendre être un nouveau Galilée, je soutiens, en dépit de l‘opinion générale, que ce n‘est pas le français qui doit sa survivance à l‘église, mais bien que l‘église doit sa survivance à l a langue française, au Canada tout aussi bien que dans les deux comtés de Prescott et Russell.[...]</description><creator>Martineau, Gloriana J. (Gloriana Jeanne)</creator><contributor>D'Hauteserve, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1947</date><subject>French-Canadians -- Ontario.</subject><subject>Church and state -- Ontario.</subject><title>La survivance française dans les comtés de Prescott et Russell.</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h483s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b656b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603r184t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:07:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le roman historique fut popularise en Angleterre par Walter Scott. Ses romans eurent une influence tres profonde sur les romanciers trangais, surtout sur les jeunes romantiques. Dans les romans de Scott, on voit l’histoire, plus ou moins juste, comme un fond, et les vrais personnages comme les personnages de second plan, on y trouve le goüt de la violence, des conjurations, des longues descriptions qui donnent la couleur looale. Les jeunes romantiques, parmi qui on ne va considerer ici que Vigny et Dumas, trouverent dans les romans de Scott et les drames historiques de Shakespeare une tres grande Inspiration.[...]</description><creator>Matthers, Mary Catherine.</creator><contributor>Furness, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1948</date><subject>Vigny, Alfred de, 1797-1863 -- Characters.</subject><subject>Richelieu, Armand Jean du Plessis, duc de, 1585-1642 -- In literature.</subject><subject>Dumas, Alexandre, 1802-1870 -- Characters.</subject><title>Le cardinal Richelieu dans les romans de Vigny et les romans de Dumas.</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t532g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603r184t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):11700</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>