<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:53:57Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):750" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80hx43h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Shortly after returning to Moscow in 1936, Prokofiev composed his first Soviet opera, Semyon Kotko (Opus 81). The libretto was taken from Valentin Kataev's novel I am a Son of the Working People, a tale of revolution and war in a small Ukrainian village and one that adheres to the tenets of Socialist Realism. Kataev encouraged Prokofiev to set this text in a highly conservative song style. Prokofiev was also influenced in the project by Vsevolod Meyerhold, an innovative artist who advocated using continuous declamation as a means of achieving "dramatic truth" in music. This essay examines the extent to which Semyon Kotko can be considered a conformist opera. Part One is a survey of Socialist Realism and its manifestation in Soviet literature and music during the 1930's; Parts Two and Three examine the text and music of Semyon Kotko as representative of the doctrine. Consideration is given throughout the study to the opposing influences of Kataev and Meyerhold on Prokofiev, and to the political events surrounding the opera's composition.</description><creator>Morrison, Simon</creator><contributor>Cherney, Brian (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953. Semen Kotko</subject><subject>Socialist realism</subject><title>Sergei Prokofiev's Semyon Kotko as a representative example of socialist realism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999865v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hx43h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p6755</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis mainly studies the legal framework governing claims against the American government in the aviation field and circumscribes the specific instances in which negligent performance of air traffic control and negligent inspection of aircraft leading to certification give rise to the liability of the government. This analysis also compares the American legal principles applicable in these areas with the Canadian law. Even though the U.S. government has waived its sovereign immunity from civil liability, there remain, however, some exceptions. This thesis analyses the evolution of the jurisprudence and the applicability of these exceptions to the decisions of the federal employees in performing the control of air traffic and the inspection of aircraft. This thesis then analyses the question of whether the federal employee carrying out these activities owe a duty of care to the passengers and the crew members and tries to identify the specific instances in which his negligent performance is accountable. With regard to the controllers, it specifically tries to compare their duties with the duties of the pilots and to determine how the responsibility of each of these groups has been modified. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Desbiens, Caroline, 1965-</creator><contributor>Milde, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Political Science, Public Administration.</subject><subject>Transportation.</subject><subject>Law.</subject><title>Government's liability for the control of air traffic as well as the inspection and certification of aircraft</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mh52d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p6755</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8s45qb83d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dietary fats and animal proteins have been shown to exert different lipidemic responses in many animals, including humans. Oxidative stress has been associated with the development of several diseases including atherosclerosis. The hypotheses of this study were that: (1) the degree and type of dietary fatty acid unsaturation will influence the type of cholesterolemic responses via the induction of differential levels of oxidative stress; and (2) hyperlipidemia induced by casein in a butterfat-based diet is related to increased tissue lipid peroxidation. Male Golden Syrian hamsters were fed diets containing butterfat/casein (BF/CAS), butterfat/egg white (BF/EGG), safflower oil/egg white (SAFF/EGG) or menhaden oil/egg white (MHO/EGG) for 27 days. In comparison to the BF/EGG and SAFF/EGG diet groups, the MHO/EGG hamsters exhibited higher levels of total serum cholesterol, serum triglyceride, serum apolipoprotein B and serum lipid peroxides. These results suggest that MHO induced-hyperlipidemia could be exerted through increased concentrations of serum apolipoprotein B and increased serum lipid peroxidation. The BF/CAS diet, in comparison to the BF/EGG diet, increased serum total cholesterol and increased serum and hepatic levels of lipid peroxides. These results suggest that dietary casein-induced hypercholesterolemia could be related to increased oxidative stress. The protective effect of dietary egg white on lipid peroxidation may involve sulfur amino acids which are found in greater amounts in egg white than casein.</description><creator>Goyette, Nathalie</creator><contributor>Kubow, Stan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Proteins in nutrition.</subject><subject>Cholesterol -- Metabolism.</subject><subject>Lipids in nutrition.</subject><title>The effects of dietary protein and fat on cholesterol metabolism in the golden Syrian hamster</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jd32d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8s45qb83d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:td96k470v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The author analyses the copyright protection of musical compositions in the U.S.A. with regard to the development of new reproduction methods. He argues that the existing copyright law has to be reinterpreted or amended in order to control new technologies in an appropriate way. The possibility to analyze music with computers and to store and reproduce it digitally ("sampling") has not only opened a broad variety of possibilities to use compositions already published for new productions, it also poses new questions for the application of copyright law. The author interprets the existing legislation and adjudication with regard to the possibilities the new technologies offer and makes suggestions for an adaptation of the existing law to recent developments in technology. The author especially criticizes the so-called "audience test" to determine infringement and suggests, that in areas requiring a particular technical knowledge, the determination of copyright infringement should not be left up to the impression of a lay person, but rather depend on the testimony of an expert. The author argues, that the recent developments in the music business require a new definition of the scope of protection of musical works. Parts of music such as rhythm, harmony or the arrangement of a song should itself be protected by copyright law. For the area of digital sound sampling the author suggests the introduction of a statutory licensing scheme. The license fee should depend on the length of the part taken and the number of copies sold.</description><creator>Buerskens, Holger</creator><contributor>Baker, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Law.</subject><title>Copyright protection of musical compositions in the U.S.A.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wf83p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k470v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:08612q67c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study is designed to evaluate water diffusion parameters of clay based buffer material (mixture of clay and sand) used in nuclear fuel waste disposal vault for the following three cases: (a) No volume change in the soil fabric with no air loss. (b) No volume change in the soil fabric with air loss. (c) A complete change in the soil fabric with air loss. One dimensional diffusion type unsaturated flow equation was solved by finite difference method. Powell's optimization technique was used to minimize the material parameters in the proposed diffusion function. The adopted technique makes the use of both theory and experimental data. In this concern several tests have been performed for the three aforementioned conditions to measure the volumetric water content and the soil water potential distributions as a function of time and space. The calculated diffusion parameters were used to predict the volumetric water content and the soil water potential as a function of space and time for longer period of time.</description><creator>Shooshpasha, Issa</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Performance of clay based buffer material developed for use in a nuclear fuel waste disposal vault</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mh53p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612q67c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xp68kj300</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is an attempt to understand the views of Nawawi al-Banteni on the subject of Sufism, especially as they appear in his work Salalim al-Fudala', commentary on the Hidayat al-Adhkiya' ila Tariq al-Awliya' of Zayn al-Din al-Malibari By observing the existence and the development of Sufism in Indonesia and the career of Nawawi al-Banteni the thesis tries to achieve a better understanding of his contribution in the field. Earlier studies have tended to discuss him and his works in general, whereas this study concentrates more specifically on al-Banteni's Sufi thought through his comments on the subject. Another question that is raised is that of Nawawi al-Banteni's originality in his commentary on the Hidayat al-Adhkiya' of al-Malibari. Finally, the important point is made that Nawawi does not seem to have been influenced by either heterodox or pre-Islamic concepts, which were relatively powerful in Indonesia of his day. On the other hand he had a great influence on the people or his country, especially in his home town Banten, in terms of the development of both nationalism and Islamic education in Indonesia.</description><creator>Mulyati, Sri</creator><contributor>Landolt, Hermann A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Nawawi Banten, 1813-1898</subject><subject>Sufism -- Indonesia</subject><title>Sufism in Indonesia : an analysis of Nawawī al-Banteni's Salālim al-Fuḍalāʾ</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784n73t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xp68kj300</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150m11j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>CDKN2A/p16 is a cell cycle inhibitor which blocks abnormal cell growth and proliferation. The CDKN2A gene is frequently mutated or deleted in a wide variety of tumour types. Germline mutations have also been identified in familial atypical multiple mole melanoma (FAMMM) pedigrees. However, the role of CDKN2A in hereditary cancer is uncertain. To explore the relationship between CDKN2A germline mutations and risk of cancer, 75 families with cancers at multiple sites were analysed for germline mutations in the CDKN2A gene. A Met53Ile mutation was found in a non-FAMMM kindred with multiple cancers, including one case of melanoma. The Met53Ile mutation has been previously reported in three Australian FAMMM kindreds. A known Ala148Thr polymorphism was also detected in 5 individuals. No other families were found to have CDKN2A alterations. There were no reported CDKN2A mutations in families without cases of melanoma. Analysis of microsatellite markers adjacent to CDKN2A on chromosome 9p21 revealed that this family shares a common haplotype with one other family with this mutation, suggesting that Met53Ile is a founder mutation. These results suggest that while CDKN2A mutations are not restricted to FAMMM pedigrees, they are very rare or absent in families with individuals without melanoma.</description><creator>Sun, Sophie.</creator><contributor>Rosenblatt, David S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Cell cycle.</subject><subject>Cancer -- Genetic aspects.</subject><subject>Melanoma.</subject><title>CDKN2Ap16 and familial cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h650b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150m11j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf268713m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Treatment planning is recognized as a fundamental step in clinical radiotherapy. The increased availability and complexity of three dimensional (3D) computerized treatment planning systems necessitates a full verification protocol to be completed prior to the implementation of the treatment planning system in routine use. We have designed and performed a detailed experimental verification program aimed at evaluating each individual dosimetric aspect of our 3D computerized treatment planning system (Varian CADPLAN, version 2.62). The verification tests ranged in complexity from the most basic standard geometry to a simulation of a full treatment case. Results from each individual testing geometry are presented, and an overall evaluation is discussed. We have concluded that our 3D treatment planning system is acceptable for clinical use.</description><creator>Orfali, Anas</creator><contributor>Podgorsak, E. B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Physics, Radiation.</subject><title>Verification of a 3D external photon beam treatment planning system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429c32d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268713m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53k0093</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The World Wide Web provides the capability of delivering multi-media presentations to a wide audience. This thesis details the design and development of the site Psychoacoustical demonstrations and experiments at McGill University: it discusses site organization, selection of materials and development methods. In order to evaluate the utility of the site, site usage data, feedback from readers and data from experiments are analyzed and discussed. The thesis examines the success of the site in attracting a wide audience and holding its attention, as course material, in gathering data from psychoacoustical experiments, and in obtaining feedback from readers. Suggestions for future sites of this type are included. The test of the thesis should be read in conjunction with experiencing the World Wide Web site at http://www.music.mcgill.ca/auditory/Auditory.html.</description><creator>Welch, Norma, 1941-</creator><date>1996</date><subject>Auditory perception.</subject><subject>Psychoacoustics.</subject><subject>World Wide Web.</subject><title>Psychoacoustical demonstrations and experiments over the World Wide Web</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859h557.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53k0093</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gg01p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Food has a near-ubiquitous role in the fiction of Charles Dickens. From the action that does and does not take place, to the appearance and essence of the characters, and to the language and style in which they were written, virtually every aspect of Dickens's novels and short stories is, to some extent and at one time or another, connected with food. This thesis explores the nature and implications of food in Dickens and, in addition to its introduction and conclusion, it has been divided into three chapters: (a) Language, Style, and Subject/theme; (b) Plot and Setting; and (c) Characterization. As well, the parallel between food's omni-presence in Dickens's fiction and its centrality in the so-called 'real world' has meant that the literary concept 'realism' is a recurrent concern.</description><creator>Trefler, Caroline.</creator><contributor>McSweeney, K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Food in literature.</subject><subject>Dickens, Charles, 1812-1870 -- Knowledge -- Food.</subject><title>Dickens and food : realist reflections in a puddle of chicken grease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t4018.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gg01p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m3865</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is the aim of Part I of this thesis, the Introduction, to introduce David Zvi Hoffmann (1843-1921) in his capacity of a Bible scholar and a critic of 19th century German biblical criticism. Ample attention will be devoted to Hoffmann's own background, his German environment as well as that of Wellhausen. This will cover Sections I and III of the Introduction respectively. In order to be able to place Hoffmann's work within the proper context, Section II of the Introduction will explore the history of the general critical reception of the Hebrew Bible in the various cultures and eras where it played a role as well as its interaction with intellectual developments. Part II contains an annotated translation of Hoffmann's attack on Wellhausen's "documentary hypothesis."</description><creator>Sulzbach, Carla.</creator><date>1996</date><subject>Hoffmann, David, 1843-1921.</subject><subject>Wellhausen, Julius, 1844-1918.</subject><title>David Zvi Hoffmann's Die Wichtigsten Instanzen gegen die Graf- Wellhausensche Hypothese : ("The main arguments against the Graf-Wellhausen hypothesis"):</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jh343v072.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m3865</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Jewish Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nc580p59v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Historical conditions of colonialism, and more recently, the emergence of a post-colonial state and urbanization, have brought about rapid socio-cultural change in the Solomon Islands, characterized by heterogeneity and the influx of new cultural products. Throughout this process, notions of tradition have emerged, iterated largely through the multivocal category of kastom which is fundamentally construed in opposition to notions of Christianity and modernization. This thesis examines how these changes have affected stories, specifically a group of narratives called "kastom stories," told by students in the urban setting, and how these narratives have become a space for tradition to be stated and created. Notions of genre are explored to discover how such an amalgam of stories as that of the kastom stories regarded here could be considered as a group. I examine story structures to understand how elements from diverse sources could become integrated to the stories, and look at transformations which, in distanciating the stories from their original socio-cultural context of production, serve to recontextualize them in their present socio-cultural setting.</description><creator>Seller, Robbyn.</creator><contributor>Galaty, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Jourdan, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Tall tales -- Solomon Islands -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Oral tradition -- Solomon Islands.</subject><subject>Tales -- Solomon Islands -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Storytelling -- Solomon Islands.</subject><title>Tall tales of tradition : Solomon Island Kastom stories in transition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3f4627400.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580p59v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn9998664</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since its earliest appearance, the word $ tau upsilon rho alpha nu nu acute iota varsigma$ referred to absolute rule obtained in defiance of any constitution that existed previously. In early Greek lyric poetry, tyranny is represented as a divine blessing, but one that meets with opposition against the tyrant and puzzlement at the behaviour of the gods. In Archilochus and elsewhere tyrannical ambition is termed eros. The common property that makes both tyranny and beauty objects of eros is luminosity: As the 'radiance' $ rm( lambda alpha mu pi rho acute o tau eta varsigma)$ of beauty is to the lover, so the 'splendour' $ rm( lambda alpha mu pi rho acute o tau eta varsigma)$ of tyranny is to the tyrannical "lover". The major symbol of tyrannical luminosity is gold. Conspicuous use of wealth and women contributed to the visibility of tyrannical splendour.</description><creator>Samaras, Peter Panagiotis.</creator><contributor>Carson, Anne (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Despotism in literature.</subject><subject>Dictators in literature.</subject><subject>Greek poetry -- History and criticism.</subject><title>"Eros tyrannidos" : a study of the representations in Greek lyric poetry of the powerful emotional response that tyranny provoked in its audience at the time of tyranny's earliest appearance in the ancient world</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580p60m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn9998664</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Classics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6t053j13f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The primary objective of this M. A. thesis is to correct some false assumptions found in both older and more recent secondary literature on North American Indian narratives. Many folklorists base their folktale criteria on terms of cultural differences instead of similarities which results in an ethnocentric point of view that holds the Grimms' Kinder- und Hausmarchen as a standard against which all other folktale collections falls short. If we want to strive for a world view that will embrace all types of literature, while respecting the individuality of each culture, then we must focus on the essential similarities among world literatures and not the differences. The purpose of using another culture as a comparison, such as that of the North American Indians, is to question the ethnocentric definitions of folktales and fairy tales which have often been too rigid. Perhaps those cultural values exhibited by North American Indian folktales could prove to be beneficial to the world's multi-cultural society, in that these values could enrich and rejuvenate some Western values, such as respect for animals and the environment. These values may offer solutions to urgent contemporary world problems. Through a comparative analysis of the animal suitor motif found in the Grimms' fairy tales and North American Indian folktales, I hope to call attention to the stark cross-cultural similarities in universal folklore and to bring to light the multiplicity of cultural values which are deeply rooted in fairy tales and folklores around the world.</description><creator>Reiss, Nicole S. (Nicole Susanne)</creator><contributor>Schmidt, Josef (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Indians of North America -- Folklore.</subject><subject>Folk literature -- History and criticism.</subject><title>Universal fairy tales and folktales : a cross-cultural analysis of the animal suitor motif in the Grimm's fairy tales and in the North American Indian folktales</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935503f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6t053j13f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of German Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q811km67j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of the study was to examine francophone high school teachers' motivation and to test the Job Characteristics Model, a model of factors that affect the satisfaction and motivation of workers, to determine its possible utility as a diagnostic tool in the field of education. The study is based on a sample of 136 high school teachers from a francophone high school. The data collection instrument used in this study was the Job Diagnostic Survey developed by Hackman and Oldham (1980). The findings revealed that the Job Characteristics Model and the JDS instrument have some utility in the field of education. Proposed relationships between job characteristics and psychological states, between psychological states and motivation and satisfaction outcomes were found to exist. Psychological states appeared to mediate between job characteristics and outcomes. Among core job characteristics, task significance was the most important motivating factor for teachers followed by autonomy, skill variety, task identity, feedback from the job and feedback from agents. Among the critical psychological states, the most motivating factor is experienced meaningfulness of the work followed by experienced responsibility and, lastly, knowledge of the results. For the outcomes, internal work motivation was the best motivator followed by growth satisfaction and general satisfaction. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Proulx, Caroline.</creator><contributor>Barnabe, Clemkont (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Employee motivation.</subject><subject>Teachers -- Job satisfaction -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>High school teachers -- Québec (Province)</subject><title>La motivation des enseignants au secondaire /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892c911.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811km67j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Administration and Policy Studies in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:th83m1461</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis is focused on the Nueva Coronica y Buen Gobierno, by Felipe Guaman Poma de Ayala, written in the Peruvian highlands between the end of the sixteenth and the beginning of the seventeenth centuries. Although specifically designed to superficially appear innocuously and mildly complaining, the author disguises his transcendental subversive intentions by limiting the scope of the referential subject to the members of his cultural group. While the introduction explains in detail the objective of the thesis and reviews some literature on the subject, the first chapter provides a broad and summary overview of indigenous Andean cosmology, its constitutive elements and its main characteristics. In the second chapter these elements of cosmological philosophy are presented as the only available tools at the disposal of the indigenous population in order to understand that catastrophic event referred to as the Conquest and the inevitable conclusion to which it arrived. The third chapter explores the use of those cosmological tools and the understanding of the disaster in the subversive endeavour of cultural survival in the context of colonization. Finally, the fourth chapter examines the plurality of levels of subversive messages conveyed by the author and his hidden message of rebellious hope. Within the same frame of cosmologically oriented thought patterns and messianistic expectations, Guaman Poma alters one apparently insignificant historical detail, thereby making possible the cosmic regeneration and historical rebirth of the last Inca emperor and his entire people. A section of conclusions and a bibliography follow the fourth and last chapter.</description><creator>Passalacqua-Estremadoyro, W. Jorge.</creator><contributor>Michalski, Andre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Peru -- History -- Conquest, 1522-1548.</subject><subject>Guamán Poma de Ayala, Felipe, fl. 1613. Primer nueva coronica i buen gobierno.</subject><subject>Inca mythology.</subject><title>Cosmología y supervivencia en las crónicas de Felipe Guamán Poma de Ayala</title><language>spa</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472z40v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/th83m1461</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Hispanic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v7514</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is an examination of Muslim traditions concerning Muhammad's call to prophethood. Although Muhammad's initial prophetic call is one of the most crucial events in the history of Islamic religious tradition, Muslim records of the event are too inconsistent to be reconciled. At the expense of sound source criticism, some influential modern Islamicists, like Tor Andrae and W. M. Watt, have tried to reconstruct Muhammad's call from inconsistent hadiths. Drawing on the works of four Muslim traditionists, i.e. Ibn Ishaq, Ibn Sa'd, al-Bukhari and al-Tabari this thesis points out that, other than the fact that Muhammad must have gone through a fundamental religious experience, Muslim traditions do not permit a reconstruction of the historical event of Muhammad's call; they do provide, however, evidence of the complex ways in which Muslims understood the event, suited to their religio-theological interpretation of the Qur'anic allusions to the modes of Muhammad's religious experiences.</description><creator>Park, Hyondo.</creator><contributor>Little, Donald P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Muḥammad, Prophet, d. 632 -- Prophetic office.</subject><title>Muḥammad's call revisited : a critical approach to Muslim tradition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xk617.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v7514</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074x260</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Using regime theory, we consider in this thesis whether there is evidence of the gradual establishment of norms, principles, rules and regulations governing donor policies with regards to linking foreign aid to human rights practices. We hypothesize that, despite the constraints caused by the multiplicity of foreign policy objectives for any given donor, there is evidence of a developing human rights regime in the foreign aid policies and practices of donors of aid. Using a historical approach, we study the aid policies and practices of two international organizations (the United Nations and the Organization for Economic Co-operation and Development) and two aid donors (Norway and the United States). We investigate the donors' policy statements, monitoring mechanisms, policy implementation and changes in donor behavior for evidence of the presence of a regime. Our findings suggest regime development occurring over three distinct periods of time (1945-50; 1973-83; 1989-94), with the resulting regime operating at three distinct levels with varying degrees of efficiency and effectiveness.</description><creator>Noer, Kristin.</creator><contributor>Haskel, Barbara G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Economic assistance -- Political aspects.</subject><subject>Human rights -- Developing countries.</subject><title>Donor response to human rights violations : a regime in foreign aid?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bd64f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074x260</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ff3657276</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This master's thesis deals with the reification, or transformation into objects, of the female characters in Michel Butor's La Modification. It is our contention that the two female characters, Henriette and Cecile, function not as characters, but as objects: they are unable to take up subject positions, and they have the same roles as the other inanimate objects in Butor's work. The critical analysis is based in part on existentialist, psychoanalytic, and poststructuralist theories of subjectivity, as well as feminist rereadings of these theories. We have also used several critical and theoretical works on the object in the "Nouveau Roman", in the novels of Michel Butor, and, specifically, in La Modification. The first chapter deals with the work of several feminist theoreticians, who claim that woman is objectified in patriarchal society because she has no access to subjectivity, be it through the means of action, of vision, or of language. In the second chapter we discuss critical writings on the treatment and role of the object in Butor's work, writings which claim that these objects have a specific role to contribute to the characterisation of the main character, and to allow this main character to take up a position as subject. In the third chapter we examine the link between these two critical fields. The female characters in La Modification are objectified because they are not able to assume subject positions, they have no access to subjectivity through action, vision, or language. In addition, the female characters have the same narrative role as the other objects in the novel.</description><creator>Nodwell, Megan.</creator><contributor>Everett, Jane (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Butor, Michel -- Characters -- Women.</subject><subject>Butor, Michel. Modification.</subject><title>La réification du personnage féminin dans "La modification" de Butor /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fn73h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff3657276</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94hr69f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The current study was designed to examine sex differences in the importance of peer relations. Interviews were conducted with 85 elementary school children from grades one, four, and six. As documented in earlier studies, boys and girls showed a clear preference for same-age, same-sex peers. There were no sex differences in children's desire to marry or how often they thought about marriage. Sex differences were found in how much children desired to play with the popular girl and boy in their class. Females desired to play with the popular girl significantly more than with the popular boy in grade one. Males desired to play with the popular boy more than the popular girl in grades one and six. Finally, females did not differ in number of girls versus boys with whom they played in their favorite activities at any grade level. In contrast, in both grades four and six, males named significantly more boys than girls in their favorite activities. Results are discussed in terms of the importance of same-sex peer relationships for males and females.</description><creator>Morganstein, Tamara.</creator><contributor>Beneson, Joyce (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Sex differences (Psychology) in children.</subject><subject>Interpersonal relations in children.</subject><title>The importance of peer relations to boys and girls</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Tamara Morganstein, 1996</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pv695.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94hr69f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26z0411</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>While much has been written on the Yiddish poet Moyshe-Leyb Halpern, there is a paucity of critical material which deals with the issue of persona in his poetry. This is unfortunate since the use of persona takes centre stage in Halpern's oeuvre. This work will discuss the issue of persona in Halpern's poems, and will focus specifically on one of Halpern's personae: "Moyshe-Leyb." I will begin with an overview of the relevant literary criticism on Halpern, and a discussion of the major themes found in his poetry. Furthermore, I will discuss Halpern's connection to literary modernism, and this movement's paradigm of persona. Finally, I will examine Halpern's possible motivations for choosing a persona with his own name, and the themes and issues found in these poems.</description><creator>Miller, Marc, 1969-</creator><contributor>Ovenstein, Eugene (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Halpern, Moshe Leib, 1886-1932 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Persona (Literature)</subject><title>The persona "Moyshe-Leyb" in the poetry of M.L. Halpern</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q617t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z0411</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Jewish Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wm117q86h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Literature in art education suggests a link between aesthetic experiences and value awareness. The existence of such a link could have important implications for the role of art education in our schools, answering to the often expressed need to address values within our educational programs. However, most available work on this subject is theoretical, and often based on untested prior assumptions. Therefore claims to knowledge of this link cannot yet be explicitly made. It is my contention that an inquiry into the nature of aesthetic experiences is required before subsequent claims to knowledge of its relation to value awareness can be made. I also believe that phenomenology offers the best suited method for carrying out such an investigation. This thesis is therefore concerned with the rationale for the need of a phenomenological investigation into aesthetic experiences: justifications being provided on the basis of the available literature and the phenomenological method itself.</description><creator>McNeil, Isabelle.</creator><contributor>White, Boyd E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Aesthetics -- Study and teaching.</subject><subject>Phenomenology.</subject><subject>Values.</subject><title>General education, aesthetic education and value awareness : rationale for a phenomenological research</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784n743.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117q86h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r516x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Primarily, the thesis will reconsider the "minority report" position regarding Hemingway, and attempt to rationalize attendant charges that Hemingway's later fiction betrayed elements of self-parody (Across the River and Into the Trees. 1950), self-imitation (The Old Man and the Sea, 1952), and self-indulgence (A Moveable Feast, 1964). The minority report holds that the later writer had come to identify with the image of his public persona, and that subsequent attempts at fiction were as a result overcharacterized by self-congratulation, wish-fulfillment, and a crucial loss of ironic or otherwise aesthetic distance. The paper will dispute the biographical bias which advances much of this rationale by demonstrating that Hemingway's alleged decline as a writer is in any case incidental to his fame, and that his fame as a writer is incidental to the biographical fallacy in Hemingway criticism. The paper will propose instead that the Hemingway persona had become derivative, had ceased to offer a reliable alibi for fiction for which his readers, attracted in the first place by the author's much-publicized dictum of writing-after-experience, had come to expect a reasonable basis in autobiographical reality.</description><creator>McKendy, Andrew.</creator><contributor>Ohlin, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Hemingway, Ernest, 1899-1961 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Hemingway, Ernest, 1899-1961.</subject><title>The dead Hemingways : a rationale of the writer in decline</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f558f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r516x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hh679</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The "roadkill" films are part of a sub-genre of the more popular road film genre. Recently there has been a large number of extremely violent films featuring couples on the run. The reason behind the emergence and popularity of the "roadkill" genre can be understood through an aesthetic analysis. Chapter one examines the aesthetics and affective characteristics of the extreme violence within this sub-genre of film. This chapter refers to the works of Leo Bersani and Ulysse Dutoit, as well as Rene Girard. Chapter two explores the postmodern aesthetic of the roadside iconography by using authors such as Jean Baudrillard and Robert Venturi. The third chapter considers the aesthetics of contemporary youth as well as the soundtracks of four of the main "roadkill" films: Kalifornia, Love and a.45, Natural Born Killers, and True Romance. By considering the aesthetic elements of the "roadkill" film, one can understand the timely emergence of this genre.</description><creator>McDiarmid, Heather E. (Heather Elizabeth)</creator><contributor>Levin, Charles (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Road films.</subject><subject>Motion pictures -- Aesthetics.</subject><subject>Violence in motion pictures.</subject><title>The aesthetics of death, youth, and the road : the violent road film in popular culture</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r9753.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hh679</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Graduate Communications Program</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cj649</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-20T21:10:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Art and law. Is it possible to bring one and the other together? Is there a link between them? Art and law coexist and confront one another; the enigma of their true connection is the object of this research. The period being considered is essentially limited to the nineteenth and twentieth century, however, the analysis goes back to the medieval period and the Renaissance era. At the beginning of the twentieth century, the historical avant-garde marks a moment of tension between art and law, the author's traditional conception is significantly modified. In the realm of the industrial and the technological world, the author changes status and raises a considerable number of questions. The analysis is devoted to the elucidation of the contemporary author. Two necessary questions are at the heart of this deliberation: how have the fields of art and law been interrelated? How have they become distinct?</description><creator>Martinez, Cristina Sofia.</creator><contributor>Ross, Christine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Law and art.</subject><title>L' art et le droit : la rencontre de deux champs</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m1479.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cj649</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):775</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>