<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:49:10Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):24950" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bc16k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>2',3'-Cyclic nucleotide 3 '-phosphodiesterase (CNP) is an early  marker for oligodendrocytes, and it is suspected to be implicated in the expansion  of membranes during myelination. We have previously generated transgenic mice that  overexpress CNP. These mice showed altered oligodendroyte development, produced  aberrant myelination, and had less MBP accumulated in myelin. More interestingly,  ODCs isolated from those mice had a tremendous increase in the process extension  formation. The purpose of the present study is to compare the protein expression  pattern in the myelin isolated from control and CNP overexpressing mice (L191),  using two-dimensional gel electrophoresis. We found that CNP overexpression  increases HSC70, and HSP70, and decreases MAG expression in myelin. We also found  that the mRNA for MAG, in L191 brain was identical to control brain during all  stages of development. These findings suggest that CNP may be implicated with HSC70  in vesicular transport, and this may explain the mechanism of process extension  mediated by CNP.</description><creator>Malak, Ramez</creator><contributor>Braun, Peter E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>2D gel analysis on CNP-overexpressing mouse brain</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jm023.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bc16k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rf22n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The possible role of substance P in mediating inflammation in  inflammatory bowel disease (IBD) was evaluated by blocking the substance P (NK-1)  receptor in an acute animal model. Ethanol and zymosan were administered via the  rectum into the colon in anesthetized male Sprague-Dawley rats to induce the model.  To assess the role of substance P, 5mg/kg of CP-96,345 was administered  subcutaneously thirty minutes prior to induction of IBD and every hour for three  hours, at which time testing was begun. In another group of rats, 3 00mug/kg of an  antisense oligonucleotide targeted at NK-1 receptor mRNA was administered  intraperitoneally twice daily for seven days prior to induction of IBD. Histological  sections revealed an infiltration of inflammatory cells in the colons after  ethanol/zymosan treatment. Plasma extravasation values in rats treated with  ethanol/zymosan were significantly higher than in controls treated only with saline  (P &lt; 0.0001) or saline and ethanol (P = 0.0041). In ethanol/zymosan treated  rats, those administered CP-96,345 had plasma extravasation values which were  significantly less than in ethanol/zymosan treated controls (P &lt; 0.0001).  Administration of the antisense targeted at NK-1 receptor mRNA resulted in lower  levels of plasma extravasation compared with controls (P &lt; 0.01). NK-1  receptors may be involved in the expression of symptoms as a component of  inflammation in IBD.</description><creator>Landau, Anne M.</creator><contributor>Henry, James L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Effect of the substance P receptor antagonist, CP-96,345 on symptoms of inflammation in an acute rat model of inflammatory bowel disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429979w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rf22n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558d91x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Substantial evidence has accumulated indicating that a genetic  predisposition underlies suicidal behaviour, and that the mediating mechanism may  involve decreased serotonergic activity and/or low serum cholesterol level. Most  association studies have focused on genes involved in the serotonergic tophan  hydroxylase (TPH) gene has been extensively examined and conflicting findings have  been reported. The meta-analysis presented here was conducted to clarify the role of  the TPH gene in suicidal behaviour. No overall association between the TPH gene and  suicidal behaviour was found. A shift in focus to genes related to regulation of  cholesterol level may provide useful clues. Thus, five genes encoding proteins  involved in cholesterol biosynthesis and metabolism were investigated for a role in  suicidal behaviour. No association was detected between any of the genes examined  and suicide, suggesting that none of the genes investigated plays a major role in  the etiology of suicide. Further studies in a larger sample are necessary to exclude  possible small genetic effects.</description><creator>Lalovic, Aleksandra</creator><contributor>Turecki, Gustavo (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health.</subject><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>Genetic studies of suicidal behaviour : investigation of genes involved in the serotonergic system and cholesterol metabolism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w95051160.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558d91x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xd07gt28s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Three potential probiotics, Lactobacillus acidophilus,  Lactobacillus casei and the fungus Scytalidium acidophilum were prepared in  different ways. They were evaluated for their effects on performance and immune  responses in broiler chickens in two 6-week trials. In the first trial, probiotics  were orally administered at the ages of day 1 and day 8. There were no differences  between live and disrupted cells. However, cobalt-containing cells had improved  effects numerously in comparison with non cobalt-containing cells. As a result,  these three disrupted probiotics, each in two different concentrations, were sprayed  onto a mash basal feed before pelleting in the second trial. Improved feed intake  (up to 6%) and body weight gain (up to 7%) were observed in all probiotic  treatments. The anti-KLH IgA and IgG titers of probiotic-treated chickens were not  significantly different from the negative controls in both trials. In summary,  disrupted and cobalt-containing probiotics were proved to enhance the performance of  broiler chickens and are promising for commercial application. In addition, a new  fungal mycelium, Scytalidium acidophilum, was suggested to be a good probiotic to  improve the growth of broilers.</description><creator>Huang, Ming-Kuei, 1969-</creator><contributor>Zhao, Xin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Mycelium.</subject><subject>Broilers (Poultry) -- Feeding and feeds.</subject><subject>Broilers (Poultry) -- Immunology.</subject><subject>Lactobacillus casei.</subject><subject>Lactobacillus acidophilus.</subject><title>The effect of two Lactobacillus strains and an acidophilic fungus on production and immune responses of broiler chickens /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289j670.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gt28s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zb69d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tumor suppressor p53 is a mediator of stress-induced cell cycle  arrest and apoptosis. The kinase inhibitor 2-aminopurine (2-AP) is an adenine analog  shown to cause cells to bypass DNA damage-induced cellular arrest through unknown  mechanisms, and may potentially target p53. Although p53 plays vital roles in  adaptation to many stresses, its role in cellular response to endoplasmic reticulum  (ER) stress is unclear. Here, stress-induced p53 stabilization and checkpoint  control in the presence of 2-AP are examined, as well as p53 regulation upon ER  stress induction. I show that 2-aminopurine suppresses p53 stabilization in response  to different forms of DNA damage. Biologically, 2-AP exposure enables cells to  bypass adriamycin-induced G2/M arrest in a p53-dependent manner, but rescues the  clonogenic survival of cells exposed to adriamycin in a p53-independent manner.  Next, I show that pharmacological and physiological inducers of ER stress can  inhibit stress-induced p53 function by promoting p53 cytoplasmic  retention.</description><creator>Huang, Shirley Chien-Chieh, 1978-</creator><contributor>Koromilas, Antonis E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Control of tumor suppressor p53 by protein phosphorylation and ER stress</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161681f.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zb69d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322f01q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Little theoretical or empirical research has examined how an  animal that has found and exploited a new patch should determine whether and when it  will renew. A rapid series of visits to the patch should provide information  concerning the probability of a quick renewal. If a renewal is not encountered,  however, a subsequent decrease in the rate of visits should allow monitoring of the  patch at minimal cost. After a long period without renewal, a patch should not be  visited at all. By analogy with area-concentrated search, I propose the term  'time-concentrated sampling' (TCS) for this pattern of visits and suggest that it  should be widespread for species foraging on patchy prey in environments where the  probability of renewal and latency to renewal of patches are variable between  patches. In this study, I tested whether eastern chipmunks (Tamias striatus)  presented with a small number of peanuts followed by a small patch of sunflower  seeds exhibit TCS following their depletion of these and, if so, whether their  patterns of visits are influenced by potential indicators of patch value. (Abstract  shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Gibson, Keith W.</creator><contributor>Kramer, Donald L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Eastern chipmunk -- Food.</subject><subject>Eastern chipmunk -- Behavior.</subject><title>Time-concentrated sampling : a simple strategy for information gain at a novel, depleted patch</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698813j.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322f01q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m039k5560</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Visual censuses performed during the day underestimate cryptic  and nocturnal fish species, including large, carnivorous moray eels. This study  developed a census method for morays and used it to determine their density,  biomass, distribution and microhabitat use on coral reefs in Barbados. The five  species recorded varied in time of highest abundance. Therefore, densities were  based on the time when each species was most visible (day or night). Observed  densities were corrected for proportion of individuals not visible based on repeated  surveys of the same transects. Density (5--6 morays 125m-2 ) and biomass estimates  (1--3.7 kg 125 m-2) per site were much higher than those reported in previous  censuses and comparable to those of other predatory families. The relative abundance  of species varied among sites, and species and size classes also differed in their  shelter site use. The higher density and biomass found are believed to be due to the  improved method.</description><creator>Gilbert, Marianne</creator><contributor>Kramer, D. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Morays -- Ecology -- Barbados.</subject><subject>Morays -- Counting -- Barbados.</subject><title>Abundance, biomass and habitat use of moray eels in Barbados, West Indies, determined by a modified visual census method</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nm109.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m039k5560</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sg96n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Interest in flaxseed and products derived from flaxseed has  increased considerably in the past decade. In the development of nutraceutical  foods, several flaxseed components including lignans and alpha-linolenic acid, have  been recognized to have health benefits. There are many patents and health claims to  these components; however, relatively little research and information is found on  flaxseed proteins. The objective of the present study was to isolate and  characterize flaxseed proteins from defatted flaxseed meal. Proteins were extracted from defatted flaxseed meal with NaOH.  NaCl and NaCl/Papain. Protein solubility with these extractants ranged from 18 to  25%. Proteins were precipitated from the extracts using one or more of the following  precipitation techniques; isoelectric precipitation (IP) gave yields and protein  contents ranging between 22--25% and 67--73% respectively. Co-precipitation with soy  and whey proteins gave yields of 26.95 and 35.78% respectively for a NaOH extract.  Chemical hydrolysis of flaxseed meal with NaOH, NaCl and NaCl/Papain extraction and  IP increased protein solubilization (35--43%) and protein yields  (19--37%). Proteins in the extracts and isolates were characterized by  polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis (PAGE). Proteins extracted with NaOH and NaCl  gave two bands by native-PAGE with molecular weights (MW) of 320 and 514KDa;  proteins extracted with NaCl/Papain gave a single band at 188KDa. SDS-PAGE of  isolates extracted with NaOH, NaCl and NaCl/Papain gave subunits with MW ranging  from 6.5 to 56KDa. The major fractions isolated from NaOH-IP by RP-HPLC showed  subunits with MW ranging from 6.5 to 40.1KDa by SDS-PAGE and 5.9 to 42.5KDa by  ESI-MS. Subunits characterized by ESI-MS have not been reported previously in the  literature.</description><creator>El-Ramahi, Razan S.</creator><contributor>Alli, I. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Proteins -- Separation.</subject><subject>Flaxseed.</subject><title>Isolation and characterization of proteins from defatted flaxseed meal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644s15x.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sg96n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773w266</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The task of developing, tuning, and debugging compiler  optimizations is a difficult one which can be facilitated by software visualization.  There are many characteristics of the code which must be considered when studying  the kinds of optimizations which can be performed. These characteristics can include  large amounts of data which would be difficult to inspect without the appropriate  tools. Both static data collected at compile-time and dynamic runtime data can  reveal opportunities for optimization and affect code transformations. In order to  expose the behavior of such complex systems, visualizations should include as much  information as possible and accommodate the different sources from which this  information is acquired. This thesis presents a visualization framework designed to  address these issues. The framework is based on a new, extensible language called  JIL which provides a common format for encapsulating intermediate representations  and associating them with compile-time and runtime data. We present new  contributions which extend existing compiler and profiling frameworks, allowing them  to export the intermediate languages, analysis results, and code metadata they  collect as JIL documents. Visualization interfaces can then combine the JIL data  from separate tools, exposing both static and dynamic characteristics of the  underlying code. We present such an interface in the form of a new web-based  visualizer, allowing JIL documents to be visualized online in a portable,  customizable interface.</description><creator>Eng, David, 1978-</creator><contributor>Hendren, Laurie J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Combining static and dynamic data in code visualization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913q53k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773w266</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h128nf38s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study uses life cycle analysis to examine the net  greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions from the activities of the peat industry in Canada  for the period 1990 to 2000. GHG accounting is undertaken for (1) land use change,  (2) peat extraction and processing, (3) the transport of peat to market by truck,  train and ship, and (4) the in situ decomposition of extracted peat. The emission  estimates were based on results from GHG accounting models using data derived from  scientific literature, government and industry statistics, and the responses to a  questionnaire sent to Canada's peat establishments. The questionnaire, designed to  obtain information on peat extraction methods, land and fuel use, as well as the  transportation of peat, had a response rate representing 69% of Canada's total peat  production in the year 2000. Results indicate that 540 600 tonnes of greenhouse  gases were emitted in 1990 and 893 300 tonnes were emitted in the year 2000  (emission figures are measured in CO2 equivalents using a 100-year time horizon).  Peat decomposition was by far the largest source of GHG emissions, averaging 70.6%  of total emissions during the eleven-year period from 1990 to 2000. Greenhouse gases  from land use change averaged 14.7%. An average of 10.4% of total emissions resulted  from the transport of peat to market, while GHGs from extraction and processing  averaged 4.3%. Predictions of the annual GHG emissions from the peat industry,  assuming a "business as usual" context, were produced for the years 2001  to 2012. These figures were compared with those resulting from various greenhouse  gas reduction scenarios.</description><creator>Cleary, Julian</creator><contributor>Roulet, Nigel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Peat industry -- Environmental aspects -- Canada</subject><subject>Greenhouse gases -- Canada</subject><subject>Peatlands -- Canada</subject><title>Greenhouse gas emissions from peat extraction in Canada : a life cycle perspective</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w5412.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h128nf38s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dw16n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The influence of ionic strength (I), magnesium ions and reactive  surface area, on calcite crystal growth morphology and surface microtopography were  investigated by transmission electron microscopy (TEM) and atomic force microscopy  (AFM). Calcite overgrowths were precipitated from aqueous NaCl-NaHCO 3-CaCl2-MgCl2  solutions on reagent grade calcite seed powders and millimeter-size cleavage  fragments in a chemo-stat system at 25ºC for up to 6 days. Aliquots of the  reacting solutions were sampled regularly for analysis and the suspended seeds were  separated for the preparation of Pt-C replicas and TEM imaging. Most cleavage  fragments were recovered at the end of the experiments for AFM  imaging. In all experiments, the euhedral {101¯4} rhombohedron  of calcite seeds is modified at the same corners and edges within 24 hours of  growth. In the parent solutions seeded with a smaller amount of calcite  seed powders and at I = 0.13 m, the crystal morphology of calcite seed overgrowths  consists of {101¯4} and a new, prismatic form. The use of a smaller amount  of seeds translates into considerably higher precipitation rates per unit surface  area and leads to the development of fewer, new morphological growth features.</description><creator>Chien, Yung-Ching, 1974-</creator><contributor>Mucci, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Vali, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Geochemistry.</subject><title>The influence of ionic strength, magnesium ions and reactive surface area on calcite crystal growth morphology and surface microtopography /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pd57b.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dw16n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q237hs53h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Optimization of the culture conditions for the biomass  production of the alga Phaeodactylum tricornutum was investigated in relation to  chlorophyllase activity. To obtain the highest total chlorophyllase activity, the  biomass of P. tricornutum was harvested after a period of 7 days of incubation  during which the incubation temperature was maintained at 18°C for 18 h  during the day and 10°C for 6 h during the night. During culture incubation,  illumination was provided by fluorescent lamps projecting an incident intensity of  330 mumol/m2.s and the pH of the culture was maintained at 8.4, adjusted by a stream  flow of CO 2. The hydrolytic activity of a partially purified chlorophyllase  extract, obtained from the fresh biomass of P. tricornutum, was investigated in an  aqueous/miscible organic solvent system containing refined bleached deodorized (RBD)  canola oil, and chlorophyll or pheophytin as substrate. The effect of a wide range  of oil contents, chlorophyll and pheophytin concentrations, acetone concentrations,  incubation temperatures and agitation speeds on the enzyme activity was studied. The  optimum reaction conditions for chlorophyllase biocatalysis were determined to  consist of 20% oil, 10% acetone and a 200 rpm agitation speed with optimum  temperatures and substrate concentrations of 35°C and 12.6 muM for  chlorophyll, and 30°C and 9.3 muM for pheophytin. The presence of RBD canola  oil showed an inhibitory effect on chlorophyllase activity whereas acetone acted as  an activator at low concentrations and an inhibitor at higher ones. Moreover,  chlorophyllase showed a limited affinity towards pheophytin as substrate compared to  that obtained for chlorophyll. Selected samples of crude commercial canola oil were  analyzed for their green pigment content using high-performance liquid  chromatography and chlorophyllase biocatalysis was investigated on eight varieties  of crude commercial canola oil. The chlorophyllase activity was lower in th</description><creator>Bitar, Marianne</creator><contributor>Kermasha, Selim (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Plant enzymes.</subject><subject>Chlorophyll.</subject><subject>Diatoms.</subject><subject>Canola oil.</subject><title>Biotechnological approach for the removal of green pigments from Canola oil</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v8381201.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hs53h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f6506</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis we investigate if reinforcement learning (RL)  techniques can be successfully used to build automated trading  agents. We present two case studies in which we develop RL agents for  participating in auctions. The first case study focuses on the continuous double  auction (CDA), a market mechanism used in many electronic trading venues. There are  currently several automated bidding strategies for participating in the CDA, geared  both toward personal profit and toward increasing the efficiency of the entire  market. We use model-free reinforcement learning to construct a bidding strategy for  the CDA and empirically evaluates its performance against other well-known automated  strategies. The second case study deals with the larger but related problem of  interdependent electronic auctions. We describe an RL agent for the trading agent  competition (TAC), and analyze its performance. This competition features multiple  dependent auctions, and hence provides a much harder test-bed. The empirical results  did not show the same success for the RL strategy as in the CDA environment. We  attribute this problem to the difficulty of dealing with dependent auctions, in  which the optimal strategy in one auction depends on the state of the other auctions  as well.</description><creator>Boadway, John J.</creator><contributor>Precup, Doina (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Reinforcement learning in the continuous double auction and the trading agents competition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tp977.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f6506</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d504rk912</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The question of how to best organize the governance structure of  corporations in order to reconcile the various interests involved in a corporation  has a long history. Legal and economic scholars from around the world have debated  the issue since 1937, the year economists Adolf A. Berle and Gardener C. Means  identified the agency cost problem inherent in the structure of the modern  corporation (i.e. the separation of control from ownership rights). Nowadays this debate has gained an added dimension. The  consequences of the increasing globalization of economies raise the question as to  whether this will also lead to the harmonization of national systems of corporate  governance. More particularly, this thesis analyses the possibility and  consequently the direction of convergence between the German and the American system  of corporate governance, despite significant differences in their structure,  mechanisms and more generally, in the micro and macroeconomic  environment.</description><creator>Suppan, Susanne</creator><contributor>Smith, Lionel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Corporation law -- Germany</subject><subject>Corporation law -- United States</subject><title>Entrepreneurial spirit versus bureaucratic control : differences and tendencies of convergence between the American and German systems of corporate governance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773w27g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rk912</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816n16s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis analyses the interface between sustainable  development and trade openings and the liberalization of foreign investment in  Mexico. The position to be argued throughout this thesis is that the Mexican legal  framework, crafted to avoid further degradation of the environment as required by  sustainable development, has proven to be limited in meeting the objectives  established in the North America Free Trade Agreement and its side accord, the North  American Agreement on Environmental Cooperation. This thesis analyses the provisions  intended for the protection of the environment within the North American Free Trade  Agreement (NAFTA) and the outcome of NAFTA's Chapter 11 investors dispute resolution  mechanism and the North American Agreement on Environmental Cooperation (NAAEC)  citizens' submission process concerning Mexico.</description><creator>Solís Olivares, José Cuauhtémoc</creator><contributor>Blackett, Adelle (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Sustainable development -- Mexico</subject><subject>Free trade -- Mexico</subject><subject>Foreign trade regulation -- Mexico</subject><title>Trade and foreign investment liberalization and sustainable development in Mexico</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930bx78q.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816n16s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d791sg986</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The airline industry has undergone an unprecedented crisis in  the aftermath of the events of September 11th, 2001 in the United States. At that  time, the U.S. federal government rapidly moved to create and implement an important  rescue package to ensure the sustainability of the U.S. airlines. Contrarily, the  European Commission decided to keep the existing legislations and policies regarding  state aid, allowing limited support from the Member States to their national  carriers. For the Commission, the U.S. state-involvement in the air industry, as  well as similar developments in other countries, was bound to create distortions of  competition. This situation led the EU to submit a proposal to the Council and the  European Parliament for a Regulation with aims to protect the Community airlines  from the unfair pricing practices of state-aided non-Community air carriers. The  text, modeled after the legislation applicable in the field of trade of goods, would  fill a "legal void" and be a new efficient legislative tool for the  Commission. Questions did arise, however, about its political legitimacy as well as  its legal basis.</description><creator>Giard, Timothée M.</creator><contributor>Janda, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Competition, Unfair -- Europe</subject><subject>Subsidies -- Law and legislation -- Europe</subject><subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Law and legislation -- Europe</subject><subject>Airlines -- Europe</subject><title>The control of state aid to airlines by the European Commission /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827c34r.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d791sg986</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20st22t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This Master's Thesis is a comparative study of the regulation of  defensive measures in hostile takeovers. It consists of two main parts: In the  first, the subject is approached from a theoretical point of view. The relevant  factors for the regulation of defensive measures are outlined and analysed, followed  by a discussion of the different ways of drafting such rules. This part concludes  with a proposition concerning the most favourable form and content of a regulation.  The second part describes hostile takeover regulation in the US, the UK, Canada, the  EU and Germany, showing the diversity in that field of regulation in practice and  the underlying reasons. It highlights and assesses the characteristics of each  country and its regulation in the light of the considerations made in the first  part, and provides an outlook concerning the future development of the regulation of  defensive measures in hostile takeovers.</description><creator>Hanisch, Alexandra</creator><contributor>Smith, Lionel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Consolidation and merger of corporations -- Law and legislation</subject><title>The use of defensive measures in hostile takeovers : a comparative study of takeover regulation in the US, the UK, Canada, the EU and Germany</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79407x92s.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20st22t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tm65s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The increase of antidumping measures could represent a source of  mounting frictions in the trading systems among Canada, United States and Mexico.  Mexico is an active user of antidumping measures suggesting that both private sector  groups and government policy makers have found antidumping measures to be a  convenient response to the pressures of import competition. In the last two decades, Mexico has opened its economy to  international commerce. Nevertheless, its economy and legal system are not  comparable to those of the United States or Canada, although it has adopted  analogous antidumping laws. The Mexican antidumping practice is based today on  common law practices influencing civil law formalities. In the NAFTA context, more  specifically, in its Chapter 19, legal problems facing the binational panel review  system have arisen from Mexico's different legal tradition, notably in the areas of  transparency and procedural issues, standard of review, parallel amparo and the  power of panel vis-a-vis national courts. The procedural requirements of the  Antidumping Agreement prove a challenge for Mexico and will likely lead to trade  disputes concerning procedure because it lacks the tradition of administrative and  legal process.</description><creator>Ayuso Villaseñor, Horacio</creator><contributor>de Mestral, Armand (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Dumping (International trade) -- Law and legislation -- Mexico</subject><subject>Canada. Treaties, etc. 1992 Oct. 7.</subject><subject>Free trade -- North America</subject><title>Antidumping in North America : analysis from a Mexican perspective with emphasis on NAFTA Chapter 19</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zx144.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tm65s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xf86j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>International lawyers are increasingly interested in studying  NGOs ("NGOs") and their influence on state behavior, but few have studied  the impact that domestic NGOs can have on transforming and generating international  norms. This paper explores the links between Latin American NGOs and their aim of  changing international norms into more effective instruments against systematic  violations of human rights by states. I will aim to articulate the stages of the  processes that NGOs go through to change state behavior. I decided to write about NGOs and changes to human rights norms  because I have dedicated most of my life to trying to eliminate human rights  violations in Latin America. To the detractors that insist that such attempts are  futile, I would respond that every effort one can contribute to the human rights  movement is one step towards the goal of transforming beliefs and principles into  real changes to state practices.</description><creator>Baltodano Egner, Charlotte</creator><contributor>Provost, Rene (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Human rights advocacy -- Latin America</subject><subject>Human rights</subject><subject>Latin America -- Politics and government</subject><subject>Non-governmental organizations -- Latin America</subject><title>The process of transforming human rights practices in Latin America : NGOs and their quest to develop international human rights norms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732d9641.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xf86j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4f16c348n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Coming together to save the Earth. Ten years have passed since  the Earth Summit in Rio created such passion and expectations. Whether the  Convention on Biological Diversity has met those expectations or not vary from  person to person. Evidently, the Convention on Biological Diversity is complex,  not only in its language, but also in its attempt to balance between conservation  and sustainable use, and between the providers of and benefiters from biological  diversity. Subsequent to its conclusion, the Parties have strived to  achieve these objectives. This thesis attempts to assist in this process by  exploring the means of implementing the Convention on Biological Diversity and their  consequences. The scope of the thesis is limited to the matters of sovereignty  rights and access to genetic resources, in an effort to clear up the uncertainties  in the applications of these components. This thesis attempts to contribute a  pragmatic perspective to these matters, which, at their core, rely on the crossing  points in the implementation of the Convention on Biological Diversity and the  Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights. This thesis  focuses on ways to reconcile property rights in genetic resources with patent rights  in invention using genetic resources. It proposes one interpretation of property  rights in genetic resources so as to avoid any conflict with patent rights and  accordingly, avoid conflict between the requirements of the Convention on Biological  Diversity and those of the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual  Property Rights. I hope that the views and proposals expressed in this thesis  will be considered along with other diverse approaches to the implementation of the  Convention on Biological Diversity.</description><creator>Dajani, Ola Fouad</creator><contributor>Gold, E. R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Germplasm resources -- Law and legislation.</subject><subject>Biodiversity conservation.</subject><subject>Intellectual property (International law)</subject><title>Genetic resources under the CBD and TRIPS : issues on sovereignty and property</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ks65hc876.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4f16c348n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602126g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Spirobranchus sisanteus is a tropical serpulid (Annelida, Polychaeta, Serpulidae, sub-family Serpulines) (Grasse, 1959), of common occurrence throughout the British West Indies. The species has been reported from the Caribbean by Ehlers (1887) and Hullin (1923) and recently vas collected in Jamaica and Barbados by Marsden and desoribed by her in some detail (Marsden, 1900). The author became interested in two aspects of Spirobranchus giganteus: neurosecretion, and the eoological diversity shown by the Barbados population of the serpulid. Neurosecretion in the invertebrates is a relatively new field of research, of which polychaete neurosecretory investigation is a thriving branch. However, there was found in the literature only one reference to neurosecretion in serpulids. Studies to determine whether Spirobranohus sisanteus exhibits neurosecretory activity therefore held great interest for the author.</description><description> fr</description><creator>Pocock, Dorothy Margaret Elaine.</creator><contributor>Dr. Joan Marsden</contributor><date>1964</date><subject>Annelida</subject><subject>Serpulidae</subject><subject>Polychaeta</subject><title>Spirobranchus giganteus (serpulidae, polychaeta, annelida): neurosecretion, regeneration, larvae rearing, ecology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nm11k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602126g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Zoology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q463h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The complexes L(,2)Pt(SR)(,2), where L = PPh(,3), PMePh(,2), PMe(,2)Ph, were prepared in high purity and yield by treating the dichlorides with thiols and triethylamine under nitrogen atmosphere. Their geometry is cis for R = ('n)Pr, ('i)Pr, CH(,2)Ph and trans for R = 4-C(,6)H(,4)Me. Reactions of cis-L(,2)PtCl(,2) and H(,2)S/K(,2)CO(,3) or NaSH in the presence of dichloromethane afforded the complexes L(,2)Pt(S(,2)CH(,2)), containing the novel bidentate methanedithiolato ligand. The thiolato-bridged dimers {LPt(SR')(,2)}(,2), where R' = CH(,2)Ph, 4-C(,6)H(,4)Me, were isolated by fusion of the appropriate monomers in vacuo. The compound {(PMePh(,2))Pt(SCH(,2)Ph)((mu)-SCH(,2)Ph)}(,2) has the cis-symmetrical structure. Treatment of the complexes cis-L(,2)Pt(SCH(,2)Ph)(,2) with phtNSSNpht, where H-Npht = phthalimide, led to stepwise displacement of the phenylmethanethiolato ligands by phthalimido groups. The first platinadisulfanes, complexes of the type cis-(PPh(,3))(,2)Pt(Npht)(SSR''), where R'' = ('n)Pr, ('i)Pr, CH(,2)Ph, 4-C(,6)H(,4)Me and Npht, were synthesized in good yield by the oxidative addition of R''SSNpht to (PPh(,3))(,2)Pt(C(,2)H(,4)). Similarly, addition of R''SNpht gave cis-(PPh(,3))(,2)Pt(Npht)(SR'').</description><creator>Lai, Rabin Diwan.</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Platinum compounds.</subject><subject>Sulfur compounds.</subject><subject>Ligands.</subject><title>The synthesis and characterization of platinum complexes containing thiolate and catenated polysulfur ligands /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010q69r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q463h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bv237</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A theoretical treatment has been combined with practical methods to obtain quantitative measurements from the transient responses of electrically coupled cells. Communication via electrical synapses is characterized as a low resistance pathway, whereas membrane response is represented by a resistance in parallel with a capacitance. The validity and consequences of this model have been investigated using data from identified pairs of electrically coupled neurons in the freshwater snail, Helisoma trivolvis. An automated procedure has been developed to monitor the degree of coupling over extended periods of time and transform these measurements into equivalent electrical units. The model has been used to: functionally assess the coupled system employing a single micropipette; provide a spatial profile of cell load; monitor induced changes in coupling; examine the role of coupling in controlling the rate of spread of excitation; and evaluate electrical changes which occur within cells during axonal injury and subsequent recovery.</description><creator>Publicover, Nelson George</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Neural transmission.</subject><subject>Snails -- Physiology.</subject><title>Dynamic analysis of electrically coupled neurons in Helisoma Trivolvis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440t048.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bv237</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qs69b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The inoculation of Aspergillus flavus spores into a culture of Streptococcus lactis in LTB medium resulted in none or little aflatoxin production even though growth of the fungus was not hindered. The drop in pH and reduced nutrients in the medium as the result of S. lactis growth were not the cause of the observed inhibition. The inhibition was not eliminated by the addition of carbohydrate equal to the amount utilized by the bacterium prior to the inoculation with the fungus. Aflatoxin production was also inhibited when S. lactis was inoculated after A. flavus had grown. In addition to inhibiting the synthesis of aflatoxin, S. lactis also degraded pre-formed toxin. Aflatoxin, on the other hand, not only reduced the growth of S. lactis but also affected the morphology of the bacterial cell--the cells became elongated and formed long chains. S. lactis produced and excreted the inhibitor into the medium during the early stage of growth (4 h). The inhibitor was a heat stable low molecular weight compound (MW (LESSTHEQ) 500). Neither volatile (acetic) nor non-volatile (succinic and lactic) acids which were detected in extracts containing the inhibitor were responsible for this inhibition. Lactic acid was found in larger quantities in mixed cultures and its addition to mono fungus culture was found to stimulate aflatoxin production. Chloroform: methanol extraction of the S. lactis culture filtrate removed all the activity to the organic phase. Further, the active compound was insoluble in hexane, not extracted by sodium bicarbonate and was soluble in acetone, indicating a polar lipid. Autoradiographic studies showed that the inhibitor was a product of glucose metabolism. Further characterization indicated that the inhibitor was a phosphoglycolipid containing an aromatic ring structure. Filtrate extracts of A. flavus grown in presence of S. lactis were toxic to Bacillus megaterium but did not exhibit mutagenic or carcinogenic activity in the Salmonella/Mammalian microsome mutagenicity test.</description><creator>Coallier-Ascah, Josée.</creator><date>1981</date><subject>Mycotoxins</subject><subject>Aflatoxins</subject><subject>Lactococcus lactis.</subject><title>Effect of interaction between Streptococcus lactis and Aspergillus flavus on the production of aflatoxin.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jf399.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qs69b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5138jf402</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:12:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bone marrow continuously produces many B lymphocytes but the homeostatic mechanisms regulating this process are unknown. Two possible factors, the size of the B lymphocyte pool and antigenic stimulation, were examined, using radioautographic DNA-labeling with ('3)H-thymidine to quantitate lymphocyte turnover. In mice injected with anti-IgM antibodies from birth to delete all surface IgM-bearing B lymphocytes the rate of production of small lymphocytes per femur was indistinguishable from controls. In contrast, an injection of sheep erythrocytes (SRBC) in normal mice produced a transient increase in small lymphocyte turnover and increased numbers of both of immature B cells and of null small lymphocytes, as revealed by radioautographic labeling of surface IgM and Thy.1 antigen and of cytoplasmic (mu) chains. This response also occurred with other stimulants as well as in athymic and anti-IgM treated mice, but not in mice treated with silica to depress macrophage function. Chronic elevation or depression of extrinsic stimuli by repeated SRBC injection or feeding an elemental diet, respectively, produced corresponding changes in the level of the steady state of marrow lymphocyte production. The results indicate that the genesis of virgin B cells and other lymphocytes in bone marow is independent of feedback control from the peripheral B lymphocyte pool but may be amplified by environmental antigens, apparently an antigen non-specific effect mediated by macrophages.</description><creator>Fülöp, Gabrielle Maria Irene.</creator><date>1982</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Regulation of lymphocyte production in the bone marrow</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526c97g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5138jf402</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):24975</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>