<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:33:16Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):23975" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dz010q900</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>1945 marks the beginning of Soviet occupation in Eastern Germany. This was followed by the gradual implementation of a communist regime and its attendant atheist ideology in a region where over 80% of the population subscribed to protestantism. This thesis examines the policies of the SED towards the Protestant Church in Eastern Germany and attempts to define the various phases, motives, methods, and principles underlying that religious policy from 1945 to 1953. The SED's atheist ideology alone fails to explain all the measures taken with regard to the Church. The religious policy of the SED depended in large part on the overall political situation, on developments during the Cold War and Soviet projects aimed at Germany. While the SED ultimately sought to eliminate the Church, it was nonetheless prepared to solicit its support through compromise, when necessary for the stability of the regime.</description><creator>Räkel, Marie-Elisabeth</creator><contributor>Hoffmann, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Sozialistische Einheitspartei Deutschlands</subject><subject>Church and state -- Germany (East)</subject><title>Die Politik der Sozialistischen Einheitspartei Deutschlands gegenüber den evangelischen Kirchen in der Sowjetischen Besatzungszone und in der Deutschen Demokratischen Republik von 1945 bis 1953</title><language>ger</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g732d984h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010q900</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801ph04d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis deals with the political participation of Muslim women since the colonial period into the New Order period. It is a study of the Indonesian women's movement in its different trends: the roles of women in gaining and defending Indonesian independence as well as in Indonesia's politics in the Liberal Democracy, Guided Democracy, and New Order periods. It investigates the reasons for the relatively limited participation of women in politics. This low level of political participation is indicated by the ratio of women membership in the House of People's Representatives (DPR, Dewan Perwakilan Rakyat), in the Consultative Assembly (MPR, Majelis Permusyawaratan Rakyat), and in the central boards of political organizations. This thesis also focuses on the political career and discourse of Aisyah Aminy, and examines her involvement as a case study. The prominence of Aisyah Aminy lies in her ability to transcend the barriers which usually obstruct Muslim women from getting involved in politics.</description><creator>Rifai, Nurlena</creator><contributor>Turgay, A. U. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Muslim women -- Indonesia</subject><subject>Women in politics -- Indonesia</subject><title>Muslim women in Indonesia's politics : an historical examination of the political career of Aisyah Aminy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hj97n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801ph04d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k3569534j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis deals with in situ estimates of fish target strength distribution which are important in acoustic stock assessment. The data were gathered on Newfoundland's Grand Banks in 1992 using a dual-beam sonar system. In situ measures of target strength distribution are biased unless a correction is made for nonignorable missing data because high target strength fish can be detected more readily than low target strength ones. Two methods of correcting for the bias are described and implemented. Both methods use measured off-axis angle and rely on the accuracy of these angle measurements since they compare the distributions of measured and true off-axis angles. The first method involves varying the beam pattern threshold with the observed target strength of the fish. The second method uses a logistic model for the probability of detecting a fish given its target strength. The analysis in this thesis found several previously undocumented results. Firstly, it was demonstrated that off-axis angles measured with a dual-beam system do not correspond well with true ones, which makes the results of both methods dubious; secondly, measured off-axis angles are shown to be dependent on target strength, which suggests that the process of measuring off-axis angles could be improved by taking this into account, and finally, target strength measurements below about -34 dB are observed to be strongly dependent on characteristics of the dual-beam system.</description><creator>Hammond, Tim</creator><date>1993</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><subject>Statistics.</subject><title>Nonignorable missing data in acoustic fish stock assessment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pr76f425p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k3569534j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4x51hj98x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A water table management field experiment was established and conducted on a sandy loam soil in 1991 and 1992. The effects of two water tables levels, as well as conventional drainage, on nitrate levels in drainage outflow were studied. The controlled water table levels were 25 and 50 cm above the drain. The experimental setup consisted of 9 monitored drains and 6 buffer drains. Plots were centred over the drains and were 115 m long by 18.69 m wide. Drain outflow, nitrate concentration in the drainage water, soil temperature, rainfall, and water table elevations were measured during the 1992 growing season. In July a solid set sprinkler irrigation system was installed and operated for a period of 2 weeks, to raise water table levels and induce nitrate leaching. It was impossible to maintain the 25 and 50 cm controlled water table levels for the entire 1992 growing season. Controlled drainage had a significant effect on subsurface dynamic outflow. The 25 and 50 cm controlled water tables were effective in reducing total drainage volume by 60% and 77%, respectively, compared to conventional drainage. Controlled drainage also had a significant effect on nitrate loss. The 25 and 50 cm controlled water tables reduced nitrate loss by 85% and 58%, respectively, during the July irrigation period, compared to conventional free outlet drainage. This was due to the reduced drainage volumes associated with controlled drainage.</description><creator>Lalonde, Vincent</creator><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Agricultural.</subject><title>Some hydrologic and environmental benefits of water table management</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483k123.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hj98x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hm50ts383</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, the dynamics of a mathematical model for cell replication in which there is simultaneous proliferation and maturation is studied. The cell population dynamics are described by a first order nonlinear partial differential equation (PDE) in which there is retardation (delay) in both the temporal and maturation variables. The solution behaviour of the model is investigated for two different initial conditions $ varphi(x)$ = $x sp{n}$ for n $ gg$ 1 and n = 1, where x is the maturation variable. When n $ gg$ 1, the solutions are left moving fronts whose velocities are primarily dependent on the value of n and of the delay. Increasing the delay also causes oscillations to appear near the wave front. This type of solution behaviour can be associated with solitons. When n = 1 and other parameters are varied, the temporal solution goes through a period doubling route to chaos and exhibits crises and multistability while the spatial solution becomes increasingly structured.</description><creator>Crabb, Rebecca</creator><contributor>Mackey, M. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Oscillations, chaos, and crises in a model for cell replication</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w032387b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50ts383</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rh861</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The photodegradation of lignin has been investigated using milled wood lignin (MWL) as a model. Solutions of MWL were exposed to ultraviolet (UV) light under aerobic and anaerobic conditions. Changes in the molecular weight distribution (MWD) of the lignin were assessed by gel permeation chromatography (GPC). To elucidate the chemical changes induced in the lignin by irradiation, infrared (IR) and UV spectra of the irradiated solutions were also studied. Irradiation under nitrogen causes the formation of both high molecular weight (MW) condensation products and low MW fragments; whereas, irradiation under oxygen yields only low MW fragments, similar to those found under nitrogen. Since the formation of condensation products can be attributed to free radical coupling, it follows that oxygen is probably reacting with free radicals to form peroxyl free radicals thereby avoiding condensation to higher MW products. Finally, the chemical basis of the photoinduced changes in the MWD of the lignin are discussed.</description><creator>Destiné, Jean-Nicolas</creator><contributor>Manley, R. St. John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Photodegradation of milled wood lignin</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cf08n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rh861</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:js956g75r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Reggae is a popular musical form that originated in Jamaica in the late 1960's and soon came to be closely associated with the oppositional, Afrocentric Rastafarian movement. During the 1970's it achieved global popularity and is now produced in many locations around the world. In Montreal, reggae is produced by and for a cosmopolitan community; however, certain conceptions of the distinctiveness of this music as an effective intervention in social processes, derived from Rastafarian philosophy, are maintained by its performers. This thesis examines reggae song lyrics and elements of discourse about reggae music in relation to Rastafarian cultural practices, showing how the aesthetic conventions of the form involve a certain ritualization of musical activity that allows for the interpretation of aesthetic experience in terms of solidarity, resistance and historical progress.</description><creator>Macaulay, David E. (David Edward)</creator><contributor>Rousseau, Jerome (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Music -- Social aspects -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Rastafari movement -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Reggae music -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- History and criticism.</subject><title>Word, sound and power : Rastafari and conceptions of musical meaning in roots reggae music</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t722h970x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/js956g75r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f204t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Several current studies in language acquisition have focussed on the emergence of functional categories in first and second languages. The properties of functional categories can be exhibited through movement, inflections, case marking and the use of functional elements such as determiners and complementizers. This pilot study investigated the English second language of two groups of Inuktitut speaking schoolchildren at the beginning of the school year to see whether the properties of functional categories in English emerged in the same way as they do for first language speakers. While some of the Kindergarten children showed no access to these properties, others showed partial or complete access to them. Those children who had been in school one year demonstrated access to all of the properties under investigation. The results are discussed with respect to future research methodologies and studies of acquisition.</description><creator>Moss, Siobhan</creator><contributor>White, Lydia (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Second language acquisition</subject><subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Inuktitut speakers</subject><title>The acquisition of English functional categories by native speakers of Inuktitut /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977v73p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f204t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fh90x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is a study of the doctrine of maqamat (stations) and ahwal (states), the crucial doctrine of sufism, as described in two different books, al-Risalah al-Qushayriyah and Kashf al-Mahjub, by two different masters of Sufism: one Sunni-Shafi'i, al-Qushayri, the other Sunni-Hanafi, al-Hujwiri. After introducing their positions in the history of sufism, the thesis examines their backgrounds as well as their mystical inclinations. The thesis then analyzes al-Qushayri's and al-Hujwiri's doctrine of maqamat and ahwal through a comparison of concrete examples found in the two books. Through this comparison, the thesis attempts to show the differences and the similarities of their concepts of maqamat and ahwal. The conclusion discovers that the differences which appear in al-Qushayri's and al-Hujwiri's views concerning identification of a virtue as a state or a station pertain to theoretical differences only.</description><creator>Muhaya, Abdul</creator><contributor>Landolt, Hermann (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Sufism -- Doctrines.</subject><title>Maqāmāt (stations) and aḥwāl (states) according to al-Qushayrī and al-Hujwīrī : a comparative study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zf376.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fh90x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1j92g8372</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In Nunavik, the question of self-determination in health care is becoming increasingly embedded in the community health discourse, which is used by both health planners and Inuit alike to negotiate diverging positions. While health planners envision northern health care as a subset of the Quebec system, Inuit perceive it as a vehicle to ends that transcend conventional health issues. This thesis will provide an overview of the development of Nunavik health services since the James Bay agreement, focusing on how the use of the community health discourse serves to promote, but also shapes and limits regional and community self-determination.</description><creator>Lavoie, Josée G. (Josée Gabrielle)</creator><contributor>Lock, Margaret (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Community health services -- Québec (Province) -- Nunavik -- Citizen participation.</subject><subject>Inuit -- Medical care -- Québec (Province) -- Nunavik.</subject><title>Public health politics in Nunavik health care : shared concepts, divergent meanings</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f658d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g8372</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vd66w074d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Full-scale exterior beam-column-slab sub-assemblages were tested under reversed cyclic loading to investigate the role or the spandrel beam in the overall response. Results from specimens having different spandrel beam sizes and different amounts of torsional reinforcement in the spandrel beams provided a better understanding of their behaviour. The test specimens were heavily instrumented to enable detailed strain measurements in the slab bars, the joint region and the spandrel beam. These strains together with the crack pattern provide some insight into the flow of forces from the slab and spandrel beam into the joint region. The tests show that the effective width of the slab contributing to the negative bending of the main beam is affected by the torsional yielding of the spandrel beam. However, after this yielding, a different force mechanism, involving concrete compressive struts, and tension ties in the slab and spandrel beam bars, provides means of transferring additional forces from the slab bars to the joint region. It is important to consider the effect of these forces since they increase the negative moment capacity of the beams, and hence, they may affect the hierarchy of yielding between the columns and the beams. This effect may in turn alter the failure mode of the structure. Tentative design proposals, accounting for the flow of forces through the spandrel beam, are presented. The application of these proposals are illustrated for a number of different specimens having varying spandrel beam dimensions.</description><creator>Di Franco, Marco Alfio</creator><contributor>Mitchell, Denis (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Effect of spandrel beam on seismic response of concrete frames</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h036t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w074d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wh246s88m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The presence of homologues to the signal sequence receptor (SSR) and associated proteins, gp25L and calnexin was evaluated in yeast. Yeast genomic DNA was explored by Southern blotting, genomic DNA and lambda-gt11 libraries were screened with various DNA probes, lambda-gt11 expression libraries were immunoscreened, and degenerate oligonucleotides synthesized from putative conserved peptide regions, were used to prime polymerase chain reactions. These techniques failed to identify yeast genes with significant sequence homology to the mammalian DNA coding regions of SSR-alpha, SSR-beta, and gp25L. However, a 60-kDa protein of yeast microsomal membranes cross-reacted with anticalnexin antiserum. SSR-alpha DNA coding region was cloned from cDNA obtained from MDCK cells. Gp25H (SSR-beta) and gp25L were expressed in E. coli as fusion protein with glutathione S-transferase (GST), and purified by chromatography. The consequences of a pp90 deletion on the ultrastructural organization of yeast cells was evaluated by electron microscopy. The respective roles of the SSR and its associated proteins in the secretory pathway are discussed.</description><creator>Fréchette, Claude</creator><contributor>Bergeron, John J. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Lack of detection of signal sequence receptor but not Calnexin in yeast</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79407z10h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246s88m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r652f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A decision feedback (DFB) equalizer is used to correct for the effects of inter-symbol interference in digital communications systems. The order of the DFB filter is reduced to a bare minimum and studied when it is insufficient to equalize the channel, i.e., when the filter does not have enough poles to cancel all the zeroes of the channel. The error surfaces produced by the DFB filter in the symbol-by-symbol, frame-by-frame, and aggregate sense are investigated. A genetic algorithm is then applied to the problem of adapting the DFB filter coefficients. The performance of the genetic algorithm is compared to that of the conventional gradient search algorithm for both the sufficient and insufficient order cases with varying levels of noise. It is found that the genetic algorithm outperforms the gradient algorithm in the insufficient cases.</description><creator>Iacoviello, Vincenzo</creator><contributor>Morgera, S. D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Genetic algorithms and decision feedback filters</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zx390.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r652f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21tg23q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In both Prometheus Unbound and Hellas Shelley used the drama of Aeschylus as the model for composition. Accordingly, the plays' subtitle "Lyrical Drama" refers to the two major components of Aeschylean drama: the lyrics recited by the chorus and the drama of character dialogue. In taking up this specific literary genre, the poet also inherited a complex model of the socio-political system of ancient Greece, with which the dramatists had been able to explore contemporary issues. Through various means, Shelley adapted Aeschylean drama to his own language and style, using the genre's inherent capacity for social critique to examine the concerns of his time.</description><creator>Carpenter, Roy</creator><contributor>Heppner, Christopher (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Hellas</subject><subject>Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822. Prometheus unbound</subject><title>The question of genre in Shelley's lyrical dramas /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/js956g761.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21tg23q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445cf11z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The focus of this thesis is an AIDS education programme targeting prostitutes in the industrial town of Thika, Kenya. The thesis challenges three key assumptions underlying the programme, namely: (1) prostitutes in Kenya form a readily identifiable, homogenous social category; (2) medically, they are a source of HIV-infection, and a risk group due to their sexual activity; (3) once provided with knowledge about AIDS transmission and prevention, they have the incentive, and the means to modify their risk behaviour. The notions of "prostitution", "risk", and "responsibility", as assumed in the medical discourse of the programme, are contrasted with those found in the narratives of local health workers and the women involved in the programme. The incongruences in these sets of understandings have implications for the interpretation of epidemiological findings and the planning of AIDS prevention programmes in general. By lending an overall priority ranking to the risk factor of sexual behaviour, the epidemiological paradigm informing the programme masks social and economic co-factors placing women at risk, as well as the role of men in transmission of the HIV-virus. Further, the paradigm ignores important factors in the motivation of health behaviour, namely, the relative significance that women attribute to the risk of AIDS, as well as their envisaged control over health.</description><creator>Kielmann, Karina</creator><contributor>Lock, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Working class women -- Kenya -- Thika -- Social conditions.</subject><subject>Medical anthropology -- Kenya -- Thika.</subject><subject>AIDS (Disease) -- Kenya -- Thika -- Prevention.</subject><subject>Prostitutes -- Health risk assessment -- Kenya -- Thika.</subject><title>"Prostitution", "risk", and "responsibility" : paradigms of AIDS prevention and women's identities in Thika, Kenya</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pb24p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cf11z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f206c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The 19th century French novel has a well-know model called Bildung Novel. The inspiration for this name comes from Wilhem Meister by Goethe published in 1795. In this type of writing we witness the education (Bildung) of a hero or a heroin who has to face and overcome a series of difficulties. In this memoire we will analyze the theme of education in the works of two authors Stendhal and George Sand. We have chosen two novels from each author, one dating back to the beginning of their career, and the other to the end. For Stendhal we have selected Le Rouge et le Noir (1830) and Lucien Leuwen (posthume publication 1894); Mauprat (1837) and La Ville Noire (1861) by Sand. In each novel we will analyze family education, intellectual and moral training, life experience and sentimental education successively in the same way the heros experience them. To do this we use thematic method which, as Jean Starobinski puts it, considers the theme as a unit of meaning of the novel. In the conclusion we will compare the results of our analyses in the works of Stendhal and George Sand.</description><creator>Désilets, Nathalie</creator><contributor>Smith, Gabrielle Pascal (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Stendhal, 1783-1842 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>Sand, George, 1804-1876 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><title>La thématique de l'éducation chez Stendhal et chez Sand /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225b890.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f206c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pg15bf84w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research wanted to test if the Job Characteristics Model was good to study school principals' motivation in the province of Quebec. To run the study, the Job Diagnostic Survey created by Hackman and Oldham was used to collect school principals data. To this questionnaire, a part was added to collect sociodemographic data. Using these data, one way analysis of variance was used to find out if there were significant differences between the means of school principals. The results obtained indicate that the Job Characteristics Model is not exactly the right means to study school principals' motivation. But the analysis of variance revealed some significant differences between the means of the school principals.</description><creator>Roy, Réal, 1944-</creator><contributor>Barnabe, Clermont (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>School principals -- Québec (Province)</subject><title>Une vérification empirique de la théorie des caractéristiques des emplois appliquée aux directions d'école du Québec /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fm365.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bf84w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hh63sw69v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores Jurgen Habermas's dualist, system and action methodology of the social sciences as a continuation of Frankfurt School critical theory. It also interprets it as a reworking of this tradition. First, it lays out the criteria and models Habermas uses for a theory of rational modern progress, and relates these ideals to his empirical political theory of practice in the public sphere (Chapter One). Then, it looks for positivisms and objectivisms in the project that threaten its critical function (Chapter Two). Finally, it illustrates these positivisms at work in Habermas's dualist theory of new social movements (Chapter Three). Habermas's dialogue with new social movement theory illuminates some hidden instrumentalisms in his critical theory of society.</description><creator>Burkart, Patrick</creator><contributor>Meadwell, Hudson (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Habermas, Jürgen.</subject><title>Critical distance : politics between the Habermasian dualisms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pn74m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sw69v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75dd21j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis analyzes the dialectical relations of economic liberalism and nationalism. Four arguments are made: (1) the international economic order is the product of the intercourse between liberalism and nationalism; (2) world trade expansion is conditioned by the rise of protectionism; (3) the formation of regional trading blocs sets up a bridge between regional liberalism and GATT (General Agreement on Trade and Tariff); (4) the success of development is determined by the results of the crystallization of the nation-state. The arguments of this paper develop from abstract to specific. In the first part, the philosophical foundations of liberalism and nationalism are given attention. Both forces are regarded as the foundations of modern international relations, the success of one side depending on the other. In this connection, Ruggie's (1982) "embedded liberalism" is extended to the whole range of modern history. The three theories are also reviewed with respect to their ideologic commitments. The rapprochement of nationalism and liberalism implies that their originally one-sided standpoints need modification. In the second part of this thesis, empirical analyses are introduced. The different state patterns, such as free capitalism and state socialism, are regarded as the results of crystallization (Mann, forthcoming). The rise of protectionism and regionalism reflect the erosion of the existing international relations. Successful nationalism could set up the foundation for the solid development of liberalism under the political framework of democracy, which could alter the existing international relations.</description><creator>Lin, Zeng, 1953-</creator><contributor>Su, Tieting (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>International trade.</subject><subject>Nationalism -- Economic aspects.</subject><subject>Liberalism -- Economic aspects.</subject><title>Liberalism and nationalism in the world trade market</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kh28r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75dd21j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05fc48c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In recent decades, hazardous waste generation has increased in industrialized countries, and disposal facilities, especially landfill spaces, have become scarce and therefore more expensive. As a result, exports of hazardous waste to developing countries, especially to Africa grew considerably due to low cost of "disposal". African countries lack the legal and industrial set-ups and technical capacity to dispose of the waste safely. In an attempt to control such exports, African countries adopted the Bamako Convention in January, 1991. The Convention was modelled on the Basel Convention, an instrument adopted earlier on the same subject, but at a global level. Except with respect to certain issues like clean production methods, non-polluting technology and inter-African trade in hazardous waste, the Bamako and Basel Conventions are identical and contain similar shortcomings. On account of Africa's reality, however, the Bamako Convention should have approached the problem of transboundary movements of hazardous waste within the context of a comprehensive legal, economic, political, ethical and environmental strategy. Reliance on people's participation, regional environmental assessment and co-operation with industrialized countries should have been emphasised. Furthermore, African countries should have sought solutions at global, regional and national levels.</description><creator>Amlak, Mehari Gebre</creator><contributor>Brunnee, Jutta (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>African countries and the conventions on the control of transboundary movements of hazardous wastes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182m02g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05fc48c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75r8722</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An efficient and productive radiation treatment planning (RTP) system must make use of both appropriate visualization techniques and good user interface design. The suitability of several visualization techniques have been examined in the context of 3-D radiation treatment planning. These techniques include wire frame, surface rendering, volume rendering and a subset of volume rendering: reformatting of data. A rudimentary computerized RTP system was written using the most appropriate visualization techniques examined earlier. These techniques were used to display the anatomical data acquired from computed tomography (CT) scanners, the beam position within the anatomy, and finally, the dose distributions resulting from the entered plan. The program was written in ANSI C and runs on a Silicon Graphics Personal Iris UNIX workstation. The system makes use of effective user interface tools and efficient code which results in an efficient and interactive system. The accuracy of the system is verified by comparing dose profiles obtained with film dosimetry and from the computer calculations.</description><creator>Comeau, Roch</creator><contributor>Fallone, B. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><title>The design and implementation of a three dimensional computerized treatment planning system /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w820n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75r8722</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r388r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Iran Air Flight 655 was terminated by two missile attack on July 3, 1988. The aim of this study is to analyze the aeronautical incident of July 3, 1988 (IR655) from the point of view of general international law and air law. Specific attention is given to the consideration of the case by the Council of ICAO, the legal coordination of civil/military flight operation and the legal status of NOTAM. The study also comments on the concept of self-defense in international law and responsibility of state. The conclusion outlines the scope of the decision of the Council and compares it with the Council's previous decisions.</description><creator>Jabbari Gharabagh, Mansour</creator><contributor>Milde, M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>Use of weapons against civil aircraft : case study of IR655 in the light of international law</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qm83z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r388r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2b88qd03m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Walters, A. Vivienne</creator><date>1976</date><subject>Great Britain. Ministry of Health.</subject><title>The paradox of the British National Health Service : an analysis of its source and impact</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m738h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2b88qd03m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pn77f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Welch, Cecil A.</creator><date>1976</date><subject>Interviewing.</subject><subject>Counseling.</subject><title>Counsellor training in interviewing skills : interpersonal process recall in a microcounselling model</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kr283.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pn77f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Counselor Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fb4949370</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:06:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Vines, S. Martin</creator><date>1976</date><subject>Organosulfur compounds.</subject><subject>Organic compounds -- Synthesis.</subject><title>Studies in synthetic organosulfur chemistry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644s298.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb4949370</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):24000</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>