<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:25:49Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):9275" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848t56p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>[...] Ce que je présente dans les pages qui suivent n'est pas, à la rigueur une thèse. C'est plutôt une analyse dont le but est de faire réfléter comme dans un miroir les moeurs du quinzième siècle, et surtout la question féminine. Je m'en excuse à l'avance, comme Martin Le Franc lui-même s'excuse d'entreprendre une telle tâche, disant que son "engin" est trop petit. Avec lui, je prie qu'on p'e se mon oeuvre "non pas selon la quantité du don mais en la balance du courage et du coeur."</description><creator>Ratelle, Ruth M.</creator><contributor>D'Hauteserve, L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Le Franc, Martin, ca. 1410-1461. Champion des dames.</subject><title>Défense et illustration des femmes au quinzième siècle :le champion des dames de Martin Le Franc.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6m311s37g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848t56p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50h0142</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Canada is still a young country with a comparatively small population of about eleven millions scattered over a very large territory of 3,690,043 square miles. This is approximately three persons per square mile. Spread over this large area, natural resources of many different kinds are to be found and it is upon this abundant wealth that Canada's economy is based. For, the exploitation of these resources has led to the output of commodities of many kinds and far in excess of the consuming power of the existing population. This excess production has to be disposed of, and therefore, Canada has had to find markets abroad for a considerable proportion of her production. This is a condition common to all young and growing countries which are in the process of development. Peoples engaged in the exploitation of natural resources must concentrate on the production of foodstuffs and raw materials and only the early stages of manufacture. The production of highly manufactured goods is of necessity postponed for a later period of development. Hence, during a country's youth these latter must be imported and their cost, as well as the interest and dividend charges on foreign borrowing, must be met largely by an export trade which necessarily must be in quite a large proportion. [...]</description><creator>Ross, Charles Alexander.</creator><contributor>Day, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>MONEY</subject><subject>EXCHANGE</subject><subject>CANADA -- COMMERCE</subject><subject>DOLLAR</subject><title>The Canadian dollar : its valuation and control.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92gb277.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50h0142</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gh93h2570</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The research of the past thirty or forty years has revealed the true importance of the justices of the peace in the growth of the government of England. Historians have therefore devoted a good deal of attention to the development of the office of these county magistrates; Miss Putnam and Dr. Kimba11 have dealt with the early part of their history, Mr. Beard has traced their evolution up to the reign of James I., and the Webbs have described the ascendancy of the squires in the 18th and 19th centuries. This study is an attempt to fill in a part, though only a part, of the gap that is thus left between 1603 and 1660. Exigencies of space and time have made it necessary for me to omit the Civil War and Commonwealth periods, as well as all reference to the odd and interesting position of the borough justices. [...]</description><creator>Ross, Dorothy Jean.</creator><contributor>Adair, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>ENGLAND -- LAW -- HIST. &amp; ANTIQUITIES</subject><subject>JUSTICES OF THE PEACE</subject><title>The country justice in English local government during the first half of the seventeenth century.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mq54c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h2570</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3r074z088</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The plays of Euripides have led to far more discussion concerning their merit and interpretation than those of either Sophocles or Aeschylus. Controversies have especially been provoked by his expression of religious thought, for in this respect he at times appears to be exceedingly radical. A consideration of this side of his writing will become an essential part of the following dissertation. The present topic chosen can include, according to definition, a wide range of material, since the general meaning for aetiology is given in the Oxford Dictionary as "the assignment of causes." But the particular application to be considered chiefly will be the many attempts at scientific explanations of the names of peoples and places, and of customs. [...]</description><creator>Scotcher, Charles William Dixon.</creator><contributor>Woodhead, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Classics.</subject><title>The aetiological interest of Euripides.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bm30b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3r074z088</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Classics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6395wb47g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The detailed geology of an area south of Cote des Neiges road in Westmount, P. Q. was mapped and correlated with that of two adjoining areas, which had been already studied. The major plutonic rock is essexite, which represents the south-west extention of the main Mount Royal intrusive. On the western contact, between the essexite and the Trenton limestone, an intrusion of syenite outcrops, which is cut by younger syenite dikes. The Trenton limestone, essexite, and older syenite are cut by numerous lamprophyre dikes such as camptonite, monchiquite, fourchite, and leuco-lamprophyres. Aplite dikelets and dikes of a composition similar to essexite were found intruding the essexite rock. A short description of the St. Lawrence Lowlands Province and the Monteregian Petrographic Province is given in the first part of tile thesis, as both are represented in the area. This is followed by a discussion of the process of intrusion and the origin of the Mount Royal plutonics. Samples were taken of all rock types and studied in thin section. The megascopic end microscopic description of the rocks as well as their field relations is given in the second part on petrography.</description><creator>Selmser, Calbert Byron.</creator><contributor>Osborne, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>The petrology of a part of Mount Royal near Côte des Neiges village.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237hv59k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395wb47g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ft848t57z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>On account of the inclination of the earth's axis of rotation the latitudes nearer the poles are annually and alternately subjected to temperatures below the freezing point. This periodicity of temperature is reflected in the seasonal rhythm in the physiology of the living organisms indigenous to these latitudes. It is not better portrayed than in plants, which on account of their poikilothermic and hydrated nature freeze when exposed to temperatures slightly below the freezing point. Thus in temperate regions the trees and exposed parts of shrubs and herbs are frozen solid for some time during the cold season and the vast majority survive this treatment regardless of the extremes of low temperature reached with slight if any injury; the slightest exposure of these plants to a few degrees of frost in the warm season, providing it is sufficient to cause freezing, is fatal. [...]</description><creator>Siminovitch, David.</creator><contributor>Scarth, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Frost.</subject><subject>Plant physiology.</subject><subject>Plants -- Effect of cold on.</subject><title>Studies on the mechanism of frost injury to plant cells.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tx31qm84h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ft848t57z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Botany</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bf73m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A number of studies of the properties of cellulose and of the cellulose-water system have been made in this laboratory. The general aim of this investigation was to obtain further information by means of heats of wetting measurements. Several different studies were made and for purposes of clarity are presented in separate sections. A new technique for the determination of the heat of wetting of bone dry cellulose was developed; using this method the value for the heat of wetting of standard cotton was measured. A study of the hysteresis effect observed in water sorption was made by measuring the heats of wetting of cellulose containing various amounts of water, left both as the result of adsorption from the dry state, and as the result of desorption from saturated conditions. Measurements were made of the heat of wetting of sulphite pulp at different temperatures between 9° and 30ºC. Further measurements were made in the same temperature range using pulp containing a small amount of adsorbed water. The heats of wetting of standard cellulose that had been subjected to severe mechanical treatment were determined. The treatment included compressing, pounding and shredding. The heats of wetting of a number of different pulp sample B were measured.</description><creator>Skey, Arthur James.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Measurement of the heats of wetting of cellulosic materials.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4q77fv57t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bf73m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mm88v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A knowledge of the processes governing the intake of water and food substances by parasites from the tissues of their hosts is essential for a full understanding of parasitism, but the study of this aspect of the nutrition of phytopathogens is decidedly incomplete. The more destructive parasites which manifest the phenomenon of "action in advance" are considered to be able to satisfy their nutritiona1 requirements from materials liberated from host cells which are killed by some toxin or enzyme secreted by, and diffusing in advance of, the parasitizing mycelium; but the more highly specialized parasites such as the rust fungi employ no such drastic action. The delicate relationship which exists between this latter group of parasites and their hosts has been the subject of voluminous comment, but the physiological mechanism by which these fungi are able to obtain the necessary nutrients from the host cells without causing any marked injury has received little attention or explanation. [...]</description><creator>Thatcher, Frederick Sidney.</creator><contributor>Coulson, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Plant Pathology.</subject><title>The water and permeability relationships in the parasitism of certain phytopathogenic organisms.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pg90s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mm88v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290d56g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'éducation anglaise, telle que la conçoit Edmond Demolins, s'occupe plus de la formation du caractère que du développement du savoir scolaire. En Angleterre, il admire, surtout, deux 'écoles nouvelles', fondées à la fin du dix-neuvième siècle. Celles-ci renoncent à l'enseignement traditionnel des grandes écoles publiques pour le remplacer par une éducation moderne, adaptée aux exigences de la vie actuelle. L'instruction qui s'y donne, embrasse une variété d'occupations pratiques et artistiques telles que l'agriculture, la menuiserie, le jardinage, le modelage, la peinture, à part les études ordinaires. Les principes qui régissent les études --de ne jamais séparer la théorie de la pratique, de développer les tendances et les aptitudes naturelles, d'habituer les enfants à la liberté afin qu'ils sachent plus tard en faire l'usage, de cultiver, surtout, des qualités d'initiative, d'indépendance et d'ingéniosité -- sont celles qui forment la base de tout essai sur 'l'éducation nouvelle' d'aujourd'hui. [...]</description><creator>Thompson, Helen Muriel.</creator><contributor>Du Roure, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Demolins, Edmond.</subject><subject>ENGLAND -- EDUCATION.</subject><subject>Education -- France.</subject><title>Edmond Demolins: propagateur de l’éducation anglaise en France.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236519z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290d56g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149s67m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>"Comme pour les tableaux" - a dit Eugèn Mel choir de Vogüé - "il y a pour chaque homme un point, le seul d'où l'observateur puisse saisir la vraie valeur de l'ensemble."1 Si cette règle de perspective est vraie pour le psychologue qui cherche à définir le caractère d'un homme, elle l'est tout autant pour le critique en face de l'oeuvre d'un auteur. Car, si cette oeuvre est valable, on peut être assuré qu'elle s'organise autour d'un foyer central où elle puisse sa style et sa signification. [...]</description><creator>Urbain, Joseph V.</creator><contributor>Du Roure, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Bazin, René, 1853-1932.</subject><title>Le traditionalisme de René Bazin.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580q699.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149s67m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483n15b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Genetics and Cytology have, in the past twenty years, combined to place the chromosome in the important role of chief physical link between parent and offspring. Through this body the parent bequeaths its potentialities in the form of determiners which have been called genes. Any portion of an organism which has a function of such significance is obviously a subject for considerable investigation. The study of chromosomes is definitely a part of the somewhat wider study of cell processes. The phenomena of mitosis and cell division certainly involve changes in cell physiology and a knowledge of these changes may well be expected to throw some light on the more intimate nature of protoplasm. The study of chromosome structure, therefore, falls logically into its place as one of the many ramifications of the biologists' main problem, the establishment of the laws governing living matter. The problem of chromosome morphology is, therefore, of general biological significance. [...]</description><creator>Wilson, G. B. (George Bernard), 1914-</creator><contributor>Huskins, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Chromosomes.</subject><title>The structure and behaviour of chromosomes during meiosis in Trillium erectum L.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s789w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483n15b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vp017</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Hydroeaia immanis Gn., the hop-vine borer, is a species indigenous to eastern North America. In the larval stage it is a pest of hops boring in the stems and roots of this plant. The first mention of what was probably this insect was made by Bethune (1872) who gave a description of a number of larvae taken from the roots of hops at Fort Credit, Ontario, and also described their work. He attempted to rear these larvae but was unsuccessful and, accordingly, gave the insect no name. However, his description of the larvae and the injury that they did to the hop roots undoubtedly fits that of Hydroecia immanis Gn. [...]</description><creator>Gilbert, Harold Adrian.</creator><contributor>DuPorte, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Entomology.</subject><title>The external morphology of the adult of Hydroecia Immanis Guenee.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sd49q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vp017</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82kb309</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>"Power always corrupts, and absolute power absolutely corrupts. All great men are bad." Such was the final judgment of Lord Acton concerning the possession of unlimited authority and the character of those outstanding personalities who occasionally arise to assume the unconditional leadership of the society in which they live. Bat the once unquestioned conclusions of many Victorian thinkers are now the object of considerable doubt. The fields of economics and political science have perhaps been most fertile in producing significant challenges to formerly accepted doctrines. [...]</description><creator>Godine, Morton Robert.</creator><contributor>Forsey, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Totalitarianism.</subject><subject>Fascism.</subject><title>The origin and development of fascist political theory.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h415pd56c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82kb309</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75dg67k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The air-bladder of bony fish, or Osteichthyes, has aroused the interest of scientists for a very long time. According to Goodrich, Ronde1et studied the bladder of the Actinopterygii in 1554 and concluded that it helps the fish to swim. In the following century (1667) Needham suggested that it might serve one of several purposes: as a float, as a respiratory reservoir or as an organ to secrete gas to help in digestion. During the seventeenth century Mayow, Ray, Boyle and Borelli studied it by various experimental methods. Discussion on the functions of the bladder continued throughout the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries, and indeed are still carried on to-day. [...]</description><creator>Graham, Annie Philathea.</creator><contributor>Wynne-Edwards, V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Fishes -- Physiology.</subject><subject>Osteichthyes.</subject><title>The air-bladder and pulmonary and systematic circulation of Amia Calva L., together with a general description of the fish.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rp28x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75dg67k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Zoology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9880vt87t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the past twenty-five years the taxonomy of the Nematoda has received much consideration and the classifications which have resulted have been of great value in the proper understanding of the group. Much progress has been made in the arrangement of the parasitic forms and several systems have been proposed for the free-living individuals. However, since the systems of classification of the two groups are so widely differentiated, a consideration of these two as one, cannot yet be adopted. It is, however, generally agreed that the nematodes are forms of very primitive organization and that they do not possess any very close relatives in the animal kingdom. [...]</description><creator>Griffiths, Henry Joseph, 1910-</creator><contributor>Cameron, T. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Parasitology.</subject><title>Studies on the Nematode Genus Strongyloides Grassi.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xp68h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vt87t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kw825</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The course of world economic activity has not been steady; indeed, it has been subject to continual fluctuations, some of which have been·very sweeping. History records many periods of great economic expansion and recession. Such long trends, however, have been brought about, for the most part, by structural changes in economic conditions as, for example, by the discovery of new lands and consequent waves of migration, and, as such, they have been beyond the control of human influence. For that reason they are not the subject of consideration here; we are concerned, rather, with the familiar short-term fluctuations that are superimposed on these broad swings. [...]</description><creator>Hall, George Birks Alexander.</creator><contributor>Day, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>MONEY -- CANADA</subject><subject>CREDIT -- CANADA</subject><subject>Finance -- Canada.</subject><title>The demand for, and the supply of, currency in Canada : as bearing on ultimate credit control.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z603r1586.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kw825</identifier><degree><name>Master of Commerce</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547v50p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The discovery of a large copper-zinc ore-body on the Waite-Amulet property in Northwestern Quebec has been an important development of 193S. This deposit, known as the lower 'A' ore-body, is interesting not only because of its large size but also because of the possibility of discovering similar deposits near it. The author believes that a brief description of the mineralogy and the rock alteration about the ore-body, as disclosed by the diamond-drill core, is of interest. [...]</description><creator>Hall, James Dickie.</creator><contributor>Osborne, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>The geology of the lower ’A’ orebody, Waite-Amulet, as disclosed by diamond drilling.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd473042s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547v50p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bv73c352g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>While the structures of the solid and gaseous states of aggregation are fairly well understood, statements are frequently found in current physical chemical literature deploring the inadequacy of our present knowledge of the liquid state. Mathematical attempts to clarify the situation have been made recently with considerable success. Consequently, experimental data becomes doubly important in that it serves to test mathematical prediction, and forms a basis for further calculation, and in addition presents a clearer mental picture of the constitution of the liquid state. Investigations of the phenomena occurring during the transition of substances or states of matter from one form to another frequently reveal important information concerning the original substance or state of matter. Hence, we might expect that a study of the physical properties of liquids at their critical temperature would be a fruitful means of enriching our ideas of the liquid state. [...]</description><creator>Holder, Clinton Howard.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>An investigation of reaction velocity and solubility in the critical temperature region.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v405sd50g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bv73c352g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wg59t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Historical settlement in Canada was conditioned by water accessibility. As a result, population units became located on the coasts and along navigable rivers. In New Brunswick this general pattern was carried out on the north and east coasts, and along the banks of the St. John River. Thus, two areas within the Province evolved independently of one another. The North Shore, as it is now called, was isolated overland from the valley of the St. John by the central wilderness, and the out-thrust province of Nova Scotia was a barrier to water communication between the two regions. [...]</description><creator>Lewis, James Neilson.</creator><contributor>Dawson, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Saint John River Valley (Me. and N.B.)</subject><subject>Human ecology -- Saint John River Valley (Me. and N.B.)</subject><title>The human ecology of the St. John River valley.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nt89d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wg59t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977x954</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the major problems facing the United States Government at the present time is that of the coordination and consolidation of the various types of transportation facilities throughout the country. The largest single factor of transportation is that of the railroads. That railroads and the Government are mutually interdependent goes without saying. In order to have a healthy nation, it is necessary that the nation have healthy arteries of commerce and communication. This work is not intended to forward any type of solution to the problem, but to emphasize the need for coordination and cooperation on the part of all types of carriers and that cooperation and coordination can best be carried out under a system of private ownership supervised by strict government control. It is the intention of the author to chart the course of the governmental relations to railroads in recent times. Railroads were selected to show the causal relationship between the government and transportation because it is felt that railroads are still the largest factor in transportation, and will continue to be indefinitely. As such, the railcarriers typify the transportation system. [...]</description><creator>Lipman, Julian A. I.</creator><contributor>Culliton, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>UNITED STATES -- TRANSPORTATION</subject><subject>UNITED STATES -- RAILWAYS</subject><subject>RAILWAYS -- STATE CONTROL AND OWNERSHIP</subject><title>The relation of the American government to railroads in recent times.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88ck65s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977x954</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w9505341r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Interest in the critical temperature phenomena was stimulated in this laboratory some ten years ago when Maass and Sutherland (60), in an investigation of the influence of molecular forces and orientation upon reaction velocity, made an interesting observation. They found that the velocity coefficient of the reaction between propylene and hydrogen chloride in the liquid state increased with rise in temperature but suddenly dropped off to zero at the critical temperature of the mixture. This was the fillip of a number of investigations on various phases of the critical temperature phenomena, of which the present is one. [...]</description><creator>Mason, Stanley George.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Transition phenomena in the critical region.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988n955.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w9505341r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2n49t510f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sulfur metabolisms leave behind a record of their activity in the sulfur they utilize. This thesis seeks to advance our understanding of some of these processes with a particular focus on dissimilatory sulfate reduction. The multiple sulfur isotope composition of two porewater sulfate profiles in the anoxic marine sapropel of Mangrove Lake, Bermuda was investigated. The porewater sulfate profiles exhibit the distinct isotopic signatures of microbial sulfate reduction and sulfur reoxidation which simple diagenetic models can reproduce. The reoxidative cycle includes sulfide oxidation to elemental sulfur followed by the disproportionation of the elemental sulfur to sulfate and sulfide, and this process turns over from 50 to 80% of the sulfide produced by sulfate reduction. We suggest that the reoxidative S cycle in any environment can best be identified within two regions of the multiple sulfur isotope fractionation spectrum. Paper 1 is titled Mass-dependent sulfur isotopefractionation during reoxidative sulfur cycling: A case study from Mangrove Lake, Bermuda. The process of evolutionary adaptation has largely been assumed inconsequential on the sulfur isotopic fractionation produced during dissimilatory sulfate reduction and recorded in the isotope rock record. Yet, the diversity of sulfur isotope phenotypes displayed by species of sulfate reducing microorganisms isolated from modern environments amounts to strong evidence that evolutionary adaptation does matter. If this is the case, important information about the evolutionary history of DSR may be preserved in the rock record. However, the relationship between evolutionary adaptation and isotope phenotype is unexplored. To begin addressing this gap in knowledge, the impact of evolutionary adaptation on the fitness and sulfur isotopic phenotype of the dissimilatory sulfate reducer Desulfovibrio vulgaris Hildenborough (DvH) was investigated. The increases in fitness that were observed did not result in a change of the isotopephenotype. At least in the conditions of the experiment this result indicates that the isotopephenotype is not very sensitive to evolutionary adaptation on the hundreds of generations timescale. This suggests that lengthier timescales are necessary for evolutionary-driven divergence of the isotope phenotype. Paper 2 is titled Evolutionary adaptation of a sulfate reducing bacterium and its sulfur isotope phenotype. To address the issues raised in paper 2, pure cultures of Desulfomicrobium baculatm were evolved in batch culture for 300 generations. A greater than two fold increase in growth rate over the course of the experiment was measured as well as a change in isotope phenotype (??) from 15 to 12 %. The response of ?? to evolutionary adaptation resembles in some ways the isotopic response of physiological adaptations to changing environmental conditions. While in the narrow context of the environment where the evolutionary adaptation took place, the change in isotope phenotype is incontestable, it remains to be seen if this difference in isotope phenotype ismaintained across different growth environments. Paper 3 is titled "Evolutionary response of S isotope fractionation is predicted by phenotypic plasticity".</description><description>L'évidence des processus biogéochimiques qui utilisent le soufre dans leur métabolisme est préservée dans les signatures isotopiques du soufre. Cette thèse tente de mieux comprendre certains de ces processus. La composition isotopique multiple du soufre dans les sulfates des eaux interstitielles des sédiments de Mangrove Lake Bermuda sont l'objet de la première section de cette thèse. Le sulfate dans ces eaux a la signature isotopique diagnostique de l'effet combinée de la sulfato - réduction et de la réoxidation. Ces processus peuvent êtres reproduits par de simple modèles diagénétiques. Le cycle du soufre dans les sédiments de Mangrove Lake comprend un composant d'oxidation du sulfure en soufre élémentaire suivie par la disproportionation en sulfure et sulfate. Ces processus vont recycler jusqu'à 50 a 80% du soufre passant par la sulfato réduction. Nous suggérons que le cycle du soufre peut être facilement identifié dans deux regions du spectrum des isotopes multiples du soufre. Le premier article est intitulé "Mass dependent sulfur isotope fractionation during reoxidative sulfur cycling. A case study from Mangrove Lake, Bermuda". Le processus d'évolution a largement été assumé comme sans consequences sur le fractionnement isotopique produit par la sulfato reduction et preservé dans les sediments. Par contre, la diversité des phénotypes d'isotopes du soufre des différentes espèces capables de faire la sulfato réduction semblen sugéré que effectivement, l'évolution a un impact sur le phénotype isotopique. Si ceci est vrai, de l'information important à propos de l'histoire évolutionnaire de la sulfato reduction est peut etre preserve dans les sediments. Par contre la relation entre l'adaptation évolutive et le phenotype isotopique n'est pas documentée. Pour addresser cette lacune de connaissances, l'impact de l'adaptation évolutive sur le phenotype isotopique de la bacteria sulfato réductrice Desulfovibrio vulgaris Hildenborough (DvH) a été mesurée. Des augmentations de l'aptitude évolutive de DvH ont été mesurées mais n'ont pas été corrélés avec des changements dans le phenotype isotopique. Dans les conditions de croissance de l'expérience, le phenotype isotopique ne semble pas être très sensible à l'adaptation évolutive sur l'échelle des centaines de générations. Ceci suggère qu'il est nécessaire d'avoir de plus longues échelles de temps pour que la divergence évolutive ait un impact sur le phénotype isotopique. Le deuxième article est intitulé Evolutionary adaptation of a sulfate reducing bacterium and its sulfur isotope phenotype".??Pour tenter de documenter la réponse évolutive du phénotype isotopique, une experience d'évolution avec une espèce (Desulfomicrobium baculatm) ayant un taux de croissance plus lent fût entrepris pour 300 générations. Un doublement du taux de croissance fût observer pendant l'expérience ainsi qu'un changement du phenotype isotopique de 15 à 12 %. La réponse évolutive de l'adaptation semble ressembler à la réponse isotopique d'un changement des conditions environnementales sur une population à court terme. Malgré que dans le context restraint de l'expérience évolutive, un changement du phénotype isotopique n'est pas contestable, il reste à voir dans d' autre conditions environnmentales ce changement de phénotype isotopique serait toujours évident. Le troisième article s'intitule "Evolutionary response of S isotope fractionation is predicted by phenotypic plasticity".</description><creator>Pellerin, André</creator><contributor>Boswell Wing (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Biogeochemistry</subject><title>The consequences of evolutionary adaptation on the sulfur isotope fractionation of sulfate reducing microorganisms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gk39x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2n49t510f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451m69j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le développement de nouveaux matériaux à l'échelle nanométrique et des techniques de fabrication d'électrodes TiO₂ Li-ion de hautes performances est étudiée dans cette thèse. Le développement et l'étude des méthodes de fabrication sont abordés du point de vue d'une électrode sans liant et comparés à des électrodes à base de liants standard, faisant usage du produit commerciaux P25 TiO₂ comme matière active. La caractérisation de l'oxyde de titane synthétisé en manipulant les paramètres d'un procédé aqueux, est effectuée pour deux phases de TiO₂, à savoir l'anatase et la brookite, la morphologique nanocristal et les propriétés électrochimiques sont évaluées. Enfin, l'application du protocole de fabrication novateur pour l'anatase synthétisé aqueuse pour concevoir des électrodes 3 dimensions sans liant est étudié, ainsi que leur performance d'intercalation Li-ion. La fabrication des électrodes P25 nanotitania/carbone composites sans liant est continuée par la formulation de pâtes et frittage contrôlé pour un rendement amélioré de la performance électrochimique par rapport aux méthodes à base de liant standard en utilisant les mêmes composants actifs et conductrices. (...)</description><description>The development of novel scalable nanoscale materials and fabrication techniques for high performance TiO₂ Li-ion electrodes is investigated in this thesis. The development and study of the novel fabrication methods is approached from the stand point of a binder-free electrode, and its comparison to standard binder-basedelectrodes, making use of commercial P25 TiO₂ product as active material. The characterization of novel titania synthesized by manipulating the parameters of anaqueous process, is performed for two phases of TiO₂, namely anatase and brookite, based on comprehensive nanocrystal morphological and electrochemical property assessment. Finally all is brought together by investigating the application of the novel fabrication protocol to the aqueous synthesized anatase to engineer binderfree 3-dimensional electrodes, and studying their Li-ion intercalation performance. The fabrication of binder-free P25 nanotitania/carbon composite electrodes is pursued via formulating pastes and controlled sintering yielding enhanced electrochemical performance in comparison to standard binder-based methods using thesame active and conductive components. The new paste formulation and sintering sequence provides a significant increase in dispersion of carbon due to smaller agglomerate size resulting in enhanced inter-particle (active-conduction) mixing and packing density than standard binder-based electrodes. [...]</description><creator>Sussman, Micah</creator><contributor>George Demopoulos (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Engineering - Materials Science</subject><title>Novel mesoporous nano-titania/carbon composite electrodes for electrochemical energy storage</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m326m4853.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451m69j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52jb859</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La musique est un support d'information contenant des signaux hautement structurés. La complexité de la musique découle de la richesse informative de sa structure qui lui permet de se conformer à l'imaginaire de chaque créateur, quelle que soit l'époque ou la localisation géographique. La présente thèse examine la richesse informative dissimulée dans la structure temporelle de la musique. Cette thèse envisage le rythme comme une progression de la durée d'événements musicaux (une note ou un silence) et utilise les similarités dissimulées dans les différentes couches de rythme musical pour construire une identité structurelle (caractéristiques temporelles libres d'échelle). Ces structures temporelles libres d'échelle sont utilisées pour une analyse longitudinale d'un échantillon des compositions faisant partie de d'oeuvre d'un compositeur. Elles sont également appliquées comme des descripteurs de l'oeuvre d'un compositeur en vue d'une classification des compositions en deux grands répertoires, occidental et non-occidental. C'est-à-dire, ce travail présente les caractéristiques structurelles libres d'échelle du rythme comme un ensemble de caractéristiques universelles riches en information. Plus précisément, ces exposants de la corrélation temporelle libre d'échelle sont calculés dans deux catégories: compositions occidentales et non-occidentales. Ces catégories, contenant respectivement 1165 et 1498 pièces musicales, sont ensuite divisées en sous-catégories, par nom du compositeur (collection occidental) et sa région ou son pays d'origine (collection non-occidentales). Cette analyse fournisse une validation plus granulaire, compositeur par compositeur, de la structure rythmique libre d'échelle dans le répertoire occidental. Cela indique que de tels exposants varient pour les compositeurs de différentes époques musicales, différentes périodes et différents pays d'origine. De plus, malgré l'existence de similarités majeures entre les exposants temporels libres d'échelle des compositions d'un compositeur, ces exposants varient d'une manière significative au cours de la vie professionnelle. Ces variations peuvent expliquer la grande précision des résultats de la classification pour (1) les compositeurs occidentaux venant de différentes époques ou présentant des styles de composition différents (par ex., Gershwin versus Mozart); (2) les régions non-occidentales caractérisées par un style et un héritage musical particulier (par ex., musique chinoise versus musique perse); et (3) les morceaux de musique occidentale versus non-occidentale. Dans la deuxième partie de la présente thèse, la richesse informative de la musique et les caractéristiques particulières de la cognition musicale humaine sont utilisées afin d'élargir le paradigme CAPTCHA existant. Dans ce paradigme, des problèmes facilement résolus par les humains, mais que les programmes informatiques ne parviennent pas encore à résoudre, sont utilisés pour distinguer la manière dont ces problèmes sont résolus par les humains et les programmes d'analyse de la musique automatisés (test de Turing). L'ubiquité de la musique à travers toutes les cultures, la structure très complexe des différentes couches qui la constituent, ainsi que nos connaissances des caractéristiques et des limitations de la perception auditive humaine permettent aujourd'hui de construire des tests de Turing plus accessibles, plus agréables esthétiquement et mieux sécurisés. Je présente les mCAPTCHAs, CAPTCHAs basés sur la musique pour répondre à plusieurs objectifs: améliorer l'accessibilité au Web pour les individus souffrant de handicaps visuels, diminuer la vulnérabilité des CAPTCHAs audio existants aux brèches de sécurité, et améliorer l'expérience générale de l'utilisateur. Le schéma mCAPTCHA génère des flux musicaux pouvant être décomposés en 2 pièces musicale distinctes par ségrégation auditive chez les humains, tout en étant considérés comme des unités musicales monolithiques par les programmes automatisés actuels. Un utilisateur reçoit une question contextuelle basée sur une chanson populaire incluse dans ce flux musical généré (défi). La sécurité du schéma réside dans le fait que les programmes actuels les plus sophistiqués ne sont pas encore capables de résoudre correctement le défi avant l'expiration du mCAPTCHA. L'évidence empirique de la sécurité de ces schémas est présentée pour plus de 2000 mCAPTCHAs, tandis que sa convivialité a été testée par environ 500 individus sur le marché en ligne Amazon MechanicalTurk. Ces résultats démontrent que les humains peuvent efficacement et correctement résoudre les défis musicaux générés, là où les logiciels les plus sophistiqués échouent.</description><description>Music is an information-bearing medium, containing highly structured signals. Its complexity derives from its information-rich structure and enables music to be molded to the imagination of any creator, regardless of time or geography. This thesis investigates the rich information encoded in the temporal structure of music. It represents rhythm as a progression of musical event durations (a note or a silence), and uses similarities hidden in different layers of musical rhythm to construct a structural identity (temporal scale-free features). These temporal scale-free structures are used for longitudinal analysis of compositions in a composer's oeuvre, and are applied as composer descriptors for classification in two large Western and non-Western music score repertoires. That is, this work presents the scale-free structural features in rhythm as a universal, information-rich feature set. More precisely, temporal scale-free correlation exponents are computed for two major music categories: Western and non-Western compositions. Collections containing these categories --- 1165 and 1498 music pieces respectively --- are further sub-categorized by composer name (Western Collection) and geographical region or country of origin (non-Western Collection). The analysis provides a more granular, composer-by-composer validation of the scale-free structure of rhythm in the Western collection. This indicates that such exponents vary for composers of different musical eras, distinct time periods and various countries of origin. Moreover, for a particular composer, though there are key similarities between different compositions' temporal scale-free exponents, they exhibit non-negligible variation during the course of the composer's professional life. These variations can account for the high accuracy in the classification results for (1) Western composers from disparate eras or with distinct compositional styles (e.g., Gershwin versus Mozart); (2) non-Western regions of distinct musical style and heritage (e.g., Chinese versus Persian music); and (3) Western versus non-Western pieces. In the second part of this thesis, rich information in music and particular features of human musical cognition are used to expand the existing CAPTCHA paradigm --- wherein problems that are easy for humans but which cannot yet be solved efficiently by computer programs are used to distinguish between humans and automated music analysis programs (computational Turing test). The ubiquity of music across all cultures, its complex structure at different layers, and the perceptual characteristics and limitations of the human auditory system are leveraged to construct more accessible, aesthetically pleasing and secure computational Turing tests. Music-based CAPTCHAs, called mCaptchas, are introduced to improve Web accessibility for individuals with visual impairments, to help avoid susceptibility to security flaws of existing audio CAPTCHAs, and to improve the overall user experience. The mCaptcha scheme generates musical streams which can be heard as two by humans, but which appear as a single inseparable unit of music to the state-of-the-art automated programs. A user is presented with a contextual question based on a popular song which the user can identify in the composite music stream (challenge). The security of the scheme lies in the fact that state-of-the-art music analysis programs cannot yet solve the challenge correctly before the mCaptcha expires. Empirical evidence of the scheme's security is presented for over 2000 mCaptchas, while its usability is tested by approximately 500 individuals on the Amazon Mechanical Turk (AMT) online market. These results demonstrate that humans can efficiently and accurately solve the generated music-based challenges while sophisticated computer programs fail.</description><creator>Mahabadi, Ladan</creator><contributor>Doina Precup (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Daniel Levitin (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>Music as an information-bearing medium: extracting latent structure for theoretical and practical purposes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kd763.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52jb859</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322h59j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:12:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le carcinome canalaire infiltrant (CCI) représente le type de cancer du sein le plus fréquent et agressif chez les canadiennes. Parmi les procédures diagnostiques, les pathologistes doivent classer les propiétés microscopiques du cancer en suivant la modification Nottingham du system Scarff-Bloom-Richardson. Malgrè que le système soit assez fiable, il existe un intérêt croissant pour une méthode qui le reproduit de façon automatisée afin de pouvoir offrir du soin constant envers tous les patients. Notre thèse présente une solution pour détecter la présence de CCI dans les images de tissue microscopique, ou lames virtuelles. Cela représente la première étape d'une solution plus complète avec l'objectif de classifier le CCI automatiquement. D'abords, le détecteur réduisit les lames virtuelles en petits morceaux pour lesquels les caractéristiques de l'image furent extraites, notamment la couleur, les motifs binaires locaux, et les histogrammes de gradients orientés. Ceux-ci ont étés analysés par une forêt d'arbres décisionnels, qui fut formée et mise à l'épreuve en utilisant 66 cas diagnostiqués de CCI. Lorsqu'il a été formé avec 50 cas, le détecteur fut 85% sensible et 92% spécifique. De manière générale, les résultats semblaient assez convaincantes pour pouvoir intégrer notre détecteur au sein d'une solution plus compléte et équipée de composants capables d'analyser la tissue cancéreuse à une amplification plus élevée afin d'obtenir un classement histopathologique de façon automatique.</description><description>Invasive ductal breast carcinomas (IDBC) are the most frequent and aggressive subtypes of breast cancer, affecting a large number of Canadian women every year. Part of the diagnostic process includes grading the cancerous tissue at the microscopic level according to the Nottingham modification of the Scarff-Bloom-Richardson system. Although reliable, there exists a growing interest to automate the grading process, which will provide consistent care for all patients. Our thesis presents a solution for automatically detecting regions expressing IDBC in images of microscopic tissue, or whole digital slides. This represents the first stage in a larger solution designed to automatically grade IDBC. The detector first tessellated the whole digital slides and image features were extracted, such as color information, local binary patterns, and histograms of oriented gradients. These were presented to a random forest classifier, which was trained and tested using a database of 66 cases diagnosed with IDBC. When trained with 50 cases, the detector sensitivity and specificity were 85% and 92% respectively. Overall, the results seemed strong enough to integrate our detector to a larger solution equipped with components that analyze the cancerous tissue at higher magnification, automatically producing the histopathological grade.</description><creator>Balazsi, Matthew</creator><contributor>Martin D Levine (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Miguel Noel Burnier (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2015</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>An automated approach for segmenting regions containing invasive ductal breast carcinomas in whole digital slides</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xh82v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322h59j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):9300</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>