<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:53:03Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):42300" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9306t336g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In public space in the seventeenth century, etiquette reigned supreme; it determined the being's seeming. And yet, we can nevertheless see, when we look back, that an interest in interiority developed---however slowly---as the century progressed. In the margins of a saturated social sphere, a process of interiorization began. My dissertation shows that Arlamene ou le Grand Cyrus (1649-1653) by Madeleine de Scudery presents, through the places and spaces that it constructs, an interesting view of interiorization. I aim to shed light on the idea that interiority unveils itself in places that favour its discovery. Drawing on works on topography, on scenography, on rhetoric of the passions, and on the semiotics of the body, my analysis of Grand Cyrus shows the link between spatial interiority and human interiority in a network of real, symbolic, and metaphoric correspondences. The Scuderian subject is obliged, when in the presence of others, to conceal feelings; he or she is not able to indulge these feelings on the public stage. So, instead, this subject holds in, and keeps for him or herself, the secret of his or her reflections. Thus, only isolation and retreat to the margins of the external world seem, to such a subject, favourable to exploration of the inner life---which life is something that distinguishes the self from the other. I identify, in my thesis, the characteristics, the components, and the role of this particular sphere inhabited by the subject of Grand Cyrus when he or she tries to enjoy a few instants of solitude. Responding to the image of the castle "closet", I show how this sphere is available everywhere, as an extension of public spaces. When necessary, these islets that favour interiority can be imagined in nature as well as in constructed (architectural) space. There, the Scuderian subject is sheltered from the inquisitive gaze, folded in on itself. While the many heroic romances of the first half of the seventeenth century mainly emphasized events and action, and the second half of the century saw the emergence of the psychological novel, in Scudery's Le Grand Cyrus we see a watershed moment. Located between two points of interest, this work has exterior live with interior, exteriority with interiority, seeming with being.</description><creator>Ducharme, Isabelle.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Scudéry, Madeleine de, 1607-1701. Artamène.</subject><title>Le Grand Cyrus de Scudéry et ses cabinets, une rhétorique de l'intériorité /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Isabelle Ducharme, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qr30r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9306t336g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q237hw908</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this program of research was to determine the value of autonomy for ethnic minorities. Self-determination theory (SDT; Deci &amp; Ryan, 2000) has argued that the need for autonomy is universal. Subsequently, it was expected that, across a broad range of ethnicities, autonomous internalization of cultural norms would be associated with well-being. Furthermore, how multicultural individuals integrate their identities was also anticipated to impact on their well-being and their daily functioning. The present thesis is comprised of four studies. Study 1 assessed ethnic minorities' internalization of their host and heritage cultures. The results indicated that autonomous internalization was associated with cultural competence and context specific well-being. Furthermore, coming from an egalitarian heritage culture was associated with greater cultural internalization. Cultural adaptation in both heritage and English-Canadian cultures combined to predict psychological well-being. Finally, the ability to integrate one's heritage and host cultural identities was associated with well-being. Study 2 and 3 examined the impact of parental autonomy support on heritage culture internalization. Study 2 was comprised of a sample of ethnic minorities living in Canada. Regression analyses revealed that parental autonomy support was related to autonomous internalization of the heritage culture and to higher self- and peer-reported well-being. Study 3 used a sample of Chinese-Malaysian sojourners. The results of study 3 replicated study 2. Sojourners were more likely to have autonomously internalized their heritage culture when they had autonomy supportive parents. Parental autonomy support was also associated with increased well-being. Study 4 used an event-contingent daily recording strategy to examine the relation of perceived evaluations of a multicultural person's heritage group to the nature and quality of their social interactions. Hierarchical linear modeling analyses revealed that the valence of the evaluation of one's heritage culture impacted on the characteristics of the interaction. Moderator analyses revealed that how a person conceptualized their multicultural identity and their level of public collective self-esteem influenced how reactive they were to how their heritage group was being evaluated. Together, these results demonstrate the significance of autonomy and cultural integration for minorities' well-being.</description><creator>Downie, Michelle.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Minorities -- Cultural assimilation.</subject><subject>Minorities -- Psychology.</subject><title>The influence of cultural internalization and integration on the well-being of ethnic minorities /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Michelle Downie, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698c96x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hw908</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vd66w404j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Myelin simultaneously increases the speed of action potential conduction while decreasing the energy consumed. It also contributes to axon stability and myelin perturbations underlie several debilitating diseases. One myelin component shared by central and peripheral myelin is Myelin Basic Protein (MBP) and in the central nervous system, MBP is necessary for the formation of the compact myelin sheath. To characterize the mechanisms controlling myelin elaboration, maintenance and repair, several recent investigations focused on the regulation of genes encoding the prominent myelin proteins. Multiple hormones, neurosteroids and transcription factors have been shown to play an important role in myelin gene regulation, but at this date none have been shown to directly activate myelin genes in a cell specific and developmentally regulated manner. On the other hand, multiple cell specific enhancers have been described for myelin genes such as mbp, plp and CNP. The mbp locus appears to be regulated at the level of transcription by four evolutionarily conserved modules. Module 1 and 2 constitute the proximal promoter and drive expression in the oligodendrocytes of juvenile transgenic mice bearing reporter constructs. Module 3 is both sufficient and necessary for expression in mature and remyelinating oligodendrocytes, but also drives expression in juvenile mice where myelin is being elaborated. Finally, module 4 confers expression in Schwann cells. In this investigation I used a multifaceted approach to characterize the structure and functional organization of module 3, an oligodendrocyte enhancer. Bioinformatics and both in vivo and in vitro assays were applied. In one focus of my investigations I used a controlled strategy of transgenesis in which constructs are docked, in single copy, at a predetermined site; a circumstance supporting high-resolution qualitative and quantitative the structure/function analysis. I also evaluated the activity of various reporter constructs during remyelination and showed that expression during remyelination requires module 3 activity while modules 1 and 2 are sufficient during primary myelination. Finally, using a variety of in vitro preparations, I demonstrated that much of the mechanism controlling mbp expression is shared by oligodendrocytes matured in vitro and in vivo.</description><creator>Dionne, Nancy.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Structure and function of module 3, a conserved enhancer of the Myelin Basic Protein gene</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Nancy Dionne, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wm461.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w404j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q237hw91j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The promise of gene therapy, once hailed as the medical treatment of the future, has yet to be achieved. Problems related to the safety and efficacy of gene therapies have checked the enthusiasm once surrounding this field. The future of gene therapy relies on the development of safe and effective non-viral vectors for gene delivery. This doctoral thesis describes the development and evaluation of a novel nanoparticle system that demonstrates characteristics suitable for gene delivery purposes. The work presented in this thesis is divided into three main phases: (1) Development of a novel delivery system. The development of a novel carrier was undertaken with the goal of producing a system that is biocompatible, biodegradable and non-toxic. The alginate-chitosan polyelectrolyte system, chosen for development due to its desirable characteristics at the macro- and micro-scales, was successfully used to prepare nanoparticles of appropriate size for delivery purposes. (2) Evaluation of the delivery system as a gene carrier. Alginate-chitosan nanoparticles were shown to complex DNA and effectively protect it from degradation. The inclusion of alginate in the system was confirmed to reduce the strength of binding between chitosan and DNA, thereby facilitating its release intracellularly. Cell viability studies confirm the non-toxicity of the system, while in vitro studies confirm the ability of alginate-chitosan nanoparticles to mediate efficient transfection. (3) Investigation of the transfection process. The cell line-dependent transfection ability of these nanoparticles, as observed with many non-viral vectors, led to the investigation of the processes involved in successful transfection. The intracellular trafficking of the non-viral vectors to the endosomal-lysosomal pathway, determined to be critical for efficient transfection, was found to be directly dependent on the internalisation mechanisms of the complexes. The development and evaluation of the alginate-chitosan nanoparticle system confirms their suitability for gene delivery applications. The additional information provided by the thorough investigation of the cellular internalisation and intracellular trafficking pathways of the alginate-chitosan nanoparticles can be exploited to further develop the system to allow tailoring to improve transfection.</description><creator>Douglas, Kimberly L.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Non-viral gene therapy : design and characterisation of novel non-viral vectors for improved cellular transfection</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Kimberly L. Douglas, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wm45r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q237hw91j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87pv607</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Many statistical models involve three distinct groups of variables: local or nuisance parameters, global or structural parameters, and complexity parameters. In this thesis, we introduce the generalized profiling method to estimate these statistical models, which treats one group of parameters as an explicit or implicit function of other parameters. The dimensionality of the parameter space is reduced, and the optimization surface becomes smoother. The Newton-Raphson algorithm is applied to estimate these three distinct groups of parameters in three levels of optimization, with the gradients and Hessian matrices written out analytically by the Implicit Function Theorem it' necessary and allowing for different criteria for each level of optimization. Moreover, variances of global parameters are estimated by the Delta method and include the variation coming from complexity parameters. We also propose three applications of the generalized profiling method. First, penalized smoothing is extended by allowing for a functional smoothing parameter, which is adaptive to the geometry of the underlying curve, which is called adaptive penalized smoothing. In the first level of optimization, the smooth ing coefficients are local parameters, estimated by minimizing sum of squared errors, conditional on the functional smoothing parameter. In the second level, the functional smoothing parameter is a complexity parameter, estimated by minimizing generalized cross-validation (GCV), treating the smoothing coefficients as explicit functions of the functional smoothing parameter. Adaptive penalized smoothing is shown to obtain better estimates for fitting functions and their derivatives. Next, the generalized semiparametric additive models are estimated by three levels of optimization, allowing response variables in any kind of distribution. In the first level, the nonparametric functional parameters are nuisance parameters, estimated by maximizing the regularized likelihood function, conditional on the linear coefficients and the smoothing parameter. In the second level, the linear coefficients are structural parameters, estimated by maximizing the likelihood function with the nonparametric functional parameters treated as implicit functions of linear coefficients and the smoothing parameter. In the third level, the smoothing parameter is a complexity parameter, estimated by minimizing the approximated GCV with the linear coefficients treated as implicit functions of the smoothing parameter. This method is applied to estimate the generalized semiparametric additive model for the effect of air pollution on the public health. Finally, parameters in differential equations (DE's) are estimated from noisy data with the generalized profiling method. In the first level of optimization, fitting functions are estimated to approximate DE solutions by penalized smoothing with the penalty term defined by DE's, fixing values of DE parameters. In the second level of optimization, DE parameters are estimated by weighted sum of squared errors, with the smoothing coefficients treated as an implicit function of DE parameters. The effects of the smoothing parameter on DE parameter estimates are explored and the optimization criteria for smoothing parameter selection are discussed. The method is applied to fit the predator-prey dynamic model to biological data, to estimate DE parameters in the HIV dynamic model from clinical trials, and to explore dynamic models for thermal decomposition of alpha-Pinene.</description><creator>Cao, Jiguo.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Statistics.</subject><title>Generalized profiling method and the applications to adaptive penalized smoothing, generalized semiparametric additive models and estimating differential equations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Jiguo Cao, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021k362.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87pv607</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04dt651</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Alcohol abuse is the second most prevalent lifetime psychiatric disorder. However, individuals do not face an equal risk of developing problematic alcoholrelated behaviors. Alcohol use disorders are heterogeneous conditions whose development may be caused by a variety of factors and vulnerabilities. The identification of markers of risk is necessary in order to identify individuals at higher risk for addiction early on as well as to help develop treatment interventions which target an individual's specific risk factors. The goal of the present dissertation is to increase our understanding of the role that one putative risk factor, an exaggerated cardiac response to alcohol, may play in the development of addictive behaviors. Five studies are reported. The first study revealed that an exaggerated heart rate response to alcohol is associated with subjective reports of increased alcohol-induced stimulation. In a second study, the relationship between the cardiac response to alcohol and personality characteristics was examined. Individuals who demonstrated the elevated cardiac response to alcohol displayed a distinct personality profile characterized by high sensation-seeking and sensitivity to reward. Two separate studies followed investigating the relationship between this physiological response to alcohol and other addictive behaviours. One study found that individuals with an exaggerated cardiac response to alcohol were more likely to obtain superior scores on a measure of pathological gambling, while the next study found that users of psychostimulants (e.g., cocaine) also displayed heightened alcohol-induced cardiac responses. A final study examined the impact of conditioned cues of reward and non-reward on alcohol-induced cardiac responses. Individuals who had previously displayed elevated cardiac responses to ethanol showed reduced cardiac reactivity when alcohol ingestion occurred in a non-rewarding environment. Overall, these findings suggest that the cardiac response to alcohol is a marker of a pathway that may lead to addictive behaviors through increased sensitivity to incentive reward.</description><creator>Brunelle, Caroline.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Alcohol -- Physiological effect.</subject><subject>Heart beat.</subject><subject>Alcoholism.</subject><title>The role of alcohol-induced cardiac reactivity in addiction : investigations into a positive reinforcement pathway</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Caroline Brunelle, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sx61dr354.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dt651</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sj03m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis investigates the characteristics of the corrections to the initial state of the atmosphere. The technique employed is the key analysis error algorithm, recently developed to estimate the initial state errors responsible for poor short-range to medium-range numerical weather prediction (NWP) forecasts. The main goal of this work is to determine to which extent the initial corrections obtained with this method can be associated with analysis errors. A secondary goal is to understand their dynamics in improving the forecast. In the first part of the thesis, we examine the realism of the initial corrections obtained from the key analysis error algorithm in terms of dynamical balance and closeness to the observations. The result showed that the initial corrections are strongly out of balance and systematically increase the departure between the control analysis and the observations suggesting that the key analysis error algorithm produced initial corrections that represent more than analysis errors. Significant artificial correction to the initial state seems to be present. The second part of this work examines a few approaches to isolate the balanced component of the initial corrections from the key analysis error method. The best results were obtained with the nonlinear balance potential vorticity (PV) inversion technique. The removal of the imbalance part of the initial corrections makes the corrected analysis slightly closer to the observations, but remains systematically further away as compared to the control analysis. Thus the balanced part of the key analysis errors cannot justifiably be associated with analysis errors. In light of the results presented, some recommendations to improve the key analysis error algorithm were proposed. In the third and last part of the thesis, a diagnosis of the evolution of the initial corrections from the key analysis error method is presented using a PV approach. The initial corrections tend to grow rapidly in time and can thus modify significantly the trajectory of a forecast over a relatively short period of time. The results shed light on different mechanisms about the evolution of small and fast growing initial perturbations.</description><creator>Caron, Jean-François, 1977-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Atmospheric Sciences.</subject><title>The characteristics of key analysis errors /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Jean-François Caron, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/70795c990.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sj03m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290f790</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation comprises two essays. The first essay develops and tests a theoretical model that provides new insights when markets are partially segmented and the purchasing power parity (PPP) is violated which seems to be the case for the majority of national markets. The theoretical part derives closed form solutions for asset prices and portfolio holdings. Particularly, we show that deviations from PPP in mildly segmented markets induce a new form of systematic risk, termed segflation risk, and in equilibrium investors require compensation for this risk. A strong feature of the model is that it provides a theoretical framework for testing important issues; such as, pricing of foreign exchange risk and world market structure. The model also nests several existing international asset pricing models and thus provides a framework to distinguish empirically between competing models. The empirical part of the essay provides an empirical validation of the model for eight major emerging markets. The results give support to the model and point to the importance of the segflation risk which is statistically and economically significant. The second essay uses our theoretical model to address the question of whether the IFC investable indices are priced globally or locally. Indeed S&amp;P/IFC provides two emerging market indices: the IFC global index (IFCG) and its subset the IFC investable index (IFCI). Since the IFCI is fully investable, both the academic and practitioners implicitly assume that this subset of emerging markets is priced in the global context. This is a critical assumption for corporate finance decisions and portfolio management. Hence, this essay investigates the pricing behavior of the IFCI index returns using a conditional version of our model that allows for segmentation and PPP deviations. The results suggest that local factors are important in explaining returns of the IFC investable indices and that the return behavior of IFCI indices is similar to that of the IFCG.</description><creator>Chaieb, Ines.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Capital assets pricing model.</subject><subject>Foreign exchange -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Purchasing power.</subject><title>Essays on international asset pricing under segmentation and PPP deviations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Ines Chaieb, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hk82t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290f790</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q811kp87f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation explores the legal issues raised by the participation of private persons in the settlement of international economic disputes, using the potential enlargement of legal standing in the World Trade Organisation (WTO) as a case study. In the first part, a typology of the special regime of responsibility of WTO Members is drawn, to serve as a "normative bridge" between the twin phenomenon of legalisation of international trade relations and judicialisation of international trade dispute settlement. In the second part, a comparative study of the participation of private persons in the settlement of international economic disputes is conducted, using the doctrine of diplomatic protection from general international law as the analytical framework. This permits an inventory of the various means of private participation in the current practice of States, as well as shedding light on the main systemic problems that are raised, notably in the field of foreign direct investment, where important developments have taken place. In the third part, a study de lege feranda on the enlargement of legal standing in the WTO dispute settlement mechanism is undertaken. The study is rooted in the previous analysis of the special regime of responsibility of WTO Members and the comparative survey on the participation of private parties in the settlement of international economic disputes. The dissertation demonstrates that the problems concerning private persons in the current mechanism should not be answered by offering them direct access to the WTO, but rather by refocusing attention on the central role of the State in the mediation of diverging interests in the governance of the world trading system. It proposes as a conclusion that WTO Members should instead look into formalising the process of handling private complaints at the domestic level.</description><creator>Côté, Charles-Emmanuel.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Dispute resolution (Law)</subject><subject>World Trade Organization.</subject><subject>Public-private sector cooperation.</subject><subject>Foreign trade regulation.</subject><title>La participation des personnes privées au règlement des différends internationaux économiques : le cas de l'élargissement du droit de porter plainte à l'Organisation mondiale du commerce</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Charles-Emmanuel Côté, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k228q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811kp87f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z709190k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Within the framework of international trade liberalization which has given rise to considerable thought about the fundamental contribution of cultural diversity to sustainable development, we explore the upholding of the educational rights of recognized linguistic minorities and of the aboriginal and treaty rights of First Nations under the Constitution Act, 1982. We examine these rights in the light of relevant judgments of the Supreme Court of Canada in order to confirm our initial hypothesis that the highest court in the land can show governments here and abroad the steps to take to ensure that the cultural rights specific to some communities and the citizenship common to the population as a whole can coexist in a free and democratic nation. Our analysis shows that, while relying on the historical, equality and cultural-based justification of the existence of these rights, the Court favours an approach centred on three fundamental principles: the duty of the State to act equitably in the "best interest" of cultural minorities through a flexible approach to the interpretation of established rights; a fair participation in the management of and access to resources by minority groups; and finally, the fostering of social cohesion in order for unity in diversity to be maintained through a reconciliation of existing rights which must be achieved, first and foremost, by political discussion aimed at finding durable solutions. From a cultural sustainable development perspective, the specific cultural rights of minority groups must thus favour a common citizenship within a context of respect for cultural diversity, while still being compatible with and promoting the values of a liberal democracy.</description><creator>Rousselle, Serge.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Multiculturalism -- Canada.</subject><subject>Constitutional law -- Canada.</subject><subject>Indigenous peoples -- Legal status, laws, etc. -- Canada.</subject><title>La diversité culturelle et le droit constitutionnel canadien au regard du développement durable des cultures minoritaires /</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Serge Rousselle, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/79408232b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z709190k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s4655m60d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, I focus on the relationship between gender and nation in post-colonial India, through the lens of Muslim women, who are located on the margins of both religious community and nation. The contradictory embrace of a composite national identity with an ascriptive religious identity, has had critical consequences for Muslim women, to whom the state has simultaneously granted and denied equal citizenship. The impact is felt primarily in the continuing disadvantage of women through the denial of gender equality within the family. The state's regulation of gender roles and family relationships in the 'private sphere', inevitably has determined women's status as citizens in the public sphere. In this context, the notion of citizenship becomes a focus of any exploration of the legal status of Muslim women. I explore the idea of citizenship as a space of subaltern secularism that opens up the possibility for Indian women of all faiths, to reclaim a selfhood, free from essentialist definitions of gender interests and prescripted identities. I evaluate the realm of constitutional law as a counter-hegemonic discourse that can challenge existing power structures. Finally, I argue for the need to acknowledge the hybridity of culture and the modernity of tradition, to emphasise the integration of the colonial past with the postcolonial present. Such an understanding is critical to the feminist emancipatory project as it reveals the manner in which oppositional categories of public/private, true Muslim woman/feminist, Muslim/Other, Western/Indian, and modern/traditional, have been used to deny women equal rights.</description><creator>Narain, Vrinda.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Constitutional law -- India.</subject><subject>Women (Islamic law) -- India.</subject><subject>India -- History -- British occupation, 1765-1947.</subject><subject>Feminist theory -- India.</subject><subject>Women's rights -- India.</subject><title>Anxiety and amnesia : Muslim women's equality in postcolonial India</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Vrinda Narain, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vh53x117v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655m60d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fn35p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Learning happens informally and incidentally in social struggle, yet it has not been the focus of many studies. When critical adult education scholars research the role of learning and education in transforming society, their analysis is centred on the role of capitalism, or the role of civil society. Critical adult education theory is caught in a debate between radical pluralist and socialist traditions---traditions that guide the role of education and educators in transforming society. Addressing this polemic, I draw on antiracist feminist scholarship to propose an analytical framework that takes into consideration the interdependence of systems of domination; namely, white supremacy, patriarchy and capitalism. In this study, I focus on young female activists' experiences and learning in social struggle. I rely on interviews and a participatory research project conducted with a group of young facilitators working with girls in an elementary school. The role of oppression and domination in social movements and in emancipatory projects is explored. Learning is found to be situated in particular historical contexts and to be influenced by underlying social dynamics inherent to social struggle. It is also found to be contradictory---it both inhibits and fosters change. This study is my praxis. It is a back and forth between grassroots practice and research. It engages activists in thinking critically about their actions and uses various written texts to reflect their stories back to them, and to broader audiences. In the tradition of feminist and participatory research, I use this study as a catalyst for learning and for transforming practice.</description><creator>Gouin, Rachel.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Adult education.</subject><subject>Women political activists.</subject><title>Gendering resistance : young women's learning in social action</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Rachel Gouin, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289p18w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fn35p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52jd00d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Using a theoretical model incorporating recent work in the field of historical epistemology and Michel Foucault's concept of governmentality this dissertation reconsiders key moments in the history of Canadian audiovisual policy as sites for examining the production of knowledge about national cultural activity. Drawing upon archival records, interdisciplinary research and a discursive analysis of policy documents, I argue that the resolution of questions regarding the nature of cultural expertise and the evidentiary value of different forms of knowledge accompanied changing state rationale towards film and broadcasting and foreshadowed the refashioning of Canada's audiovisual sector. To illustrate, I focus on a period between the establishment of the first Royal Commission on Radio Broadcasting in 1928 and the institution of Canadian content regulations for television in 1960. During this period there are important shifts in the ways the federal government conceived of and administered the audiovisual sector. In the 1920s and 30s, broadcasting and film production were nationalized and placed within publicly funded institutions such as the CBC and NFB. However, less than twenty-five years later, policy rationale towards the audiovisual sector had shifted, with measures put in place to support the development of the cultural industries. The CBC's dominance over broadcasting and regulation had been replaced by a new structural arrangement involving both public and private broadcasters regulated by independent agencies using content quotas to ensure Canadian programming on the airwaves. In Canada's film sector, the NFB's expansion into feature film and television production was halted through policy shifts encouraging the development of the independent film production sector. Using case studies that explore the historical context behind the emergence of key administrative techniques I document the declining influence of cultural nationalists and humanistic approaches to cultural issues and the rising influence of accountants, statisticians, and scholars from the nascent field of communication studies in the policy process. These developments run concurrently to shifting government rationale towards the audiovisual sector away from developing "national consciousness" towards the creation of a "national economy" for broadcasting and film drawing on previous industrial development models borrowed from the automotive sector and 19th century National Policy. Although scholarly attention in the field of cultural policy studies has generally focused upon understanding why these shifts occurred, this thesis is devoted primarily towards understanding how such shifts took place. Attention to these questions moves the field of study away from the pragmatic issues of policymaking and towards larger questions surrounding the triangulation between knowledge, state, and cultural production.</description><creator>Wagman, Ira.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Television broadcasting -- Canada -- History.</subject><subject>Radio broadcasting -- Canada -- History.</subject><title>From spiritual matters to economic facts : recounting problems of knowledge in the history of Canadian audiovisual policy, 1928-61</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Ira Wagman, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vn15n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52jd00d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290f80r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Studies were conducted using cultured immortalized wild type (non-CF) and mutant (CF) DeltaF508 cystic fibrosis transmembrane conductance regulator (CFTR) tracheal epithelial cells on the anti-inflammatory impact of agents that may alter ceramide and glutathione (GSH) metabolism. The CF cells demonstrated abnormally high levels of GSH and glutathione disulfide (GSSG), which could diminish intracellular production of ceramide, a key modulator of inflammation and apoptosis. Hence, additional cell culture studies were carried out with a known inducer of in situ ceramide synthesis, N-4(4-hydroxyphenyl) retinamide (fenretinide) on interleukin (IL)-8 release, intracellular ceramide content, and cellular proliferation in both the basal state and following the inflammatory stimuli of tumor necrosis factor (TNF) -alpha. Fenretinide treatment was associated with a dose-dependent increase in the cellular content of ceramide in both CF and non CF cells. Also, an inhibition of IL-8 release in the inflammatory condition of TNF-alpha treatment was observed following fenretinide treatment in the CF cells. As hyperbaric treatment of whey proteins was previously associated with improved survivability and higher GSH content in a Pseudomonas aeruginosa murine model of cystic fibrosis (CF), the anti-inflammatory role of low molecular weight peptides (&lt; 1kDa) generated from enzymatic hydrolysis of native and pressurized whey protein isolates (WPI) was examined. Pressure treatment of WPI was associated with an enhanced protein digestibility and an altered peptide profile following in vitro digestion. The whey peptides were tested CF and non-CF lung epithelial cells to identify for their effects on GSH metabolism. The impact of the combined treatment of fenretinide and WPH was also tested in terms of apoptosis and cytokine release in cell culture. As opposed to non-CF cells, CF cells showed a strong downtrend in release of IL-8 following the combined fenretinide and whey peptide treatment. In addition, whey peptides protected wild type epithelial cells from the apoptotic effect of fenretinide. Our results suggest the usefulness of these agents as a pharmacological treatment in CF.</description><creator>Vilela, Regina Maria.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Fenretinide.</subject><subject>Milk proteins.</subject><subject>Glutathione -- Metabolism.</subject><subject>Whey.</subject><subject>Cystic fibrosis -- Treatment.</subject><subject>Retinoids.</subject><title>The influence of whey peptides and fenretinide on inflammation and apoptosis in immortalized wild type and mutant [delta]F508 CFTR human tracheal epithelial cells /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Regina Maria Vilela, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p460c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290f80r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d504rq50n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The primary purpose of the present study was to evaluate the effectiveness of a highly individualized conjoint behavioural consultation model with group videotape therapy as a means of decreasing externalizing behaviour problems of children with developmental disabilities. The effects of the intervention were examined via changes in children's target behaviors throughout the course of the intervention, along with pre-intervention and postintervention changes of problem behaviors on standardized measures, and during parentchild play observations. Parent outcome was evaluated by changes in parental knowledge of behavioural principles, changes in parental management skills, and parental discipline approaches. Finally, parental acceptability of the intervention was examined as well as the relationship between intervention acceptability and outcome. A multiple baseline research design was used with 22 children, their parents, and teachers. Results indicated that children's target behaviors improved from baseline to intervention. Moreover, parental knowledge of behavioral principles, parental discipline strategies, and behavioral management skills improved from pre-intervention to post-intervention. Further, high acceptability ratings were reported by parents at post-intervention. Finally, a positive relationship was found between intervention effectiveness and acceptability. Results are discussed in light of their implications and contributions to the literature in school psychology.</description><creator>Viola, Teresa.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Problem children -- Behavior modification.</subject><subject>Cognition disorders in children.</subject><title>Remediating behaviour problems in children with developmental disabilities</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Teresa Viola, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52jd01p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d504rq50n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cn69m8280</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this paper, we first theoretically revise the traditional particle modeling (PM) by means of mathematical derivation in that, adopting of Lennard Jones (LJ) format equations, four conservative rules are satisfied in order to determine the four unknown in a LJ equation, such as the mass, the elastic energy, the Young's modulus and the tensile strength conservations in the PM and molecular dynamic (MD) models. This enables the new developed PM to uniquely define a material's properties to be studied and promisingly become a predictive tool in mining industries. A safe time increment scheme is also defined and a new modification to the model to avoid giving a pseudo-dynamic solution. Consequently, we test this new PM by simulating fracture response of an elastic-brittle material---epoxy, with randomly distributed holes, in tension and then comparing the model results with the experiments. Then, we use this developed PM to many applications, such as (i) simulating dynamic fragmentation of minerals encountered in comminution and blasting processes in the mining industry. In particular, we simulate single as well as multi-phase materials in two dimensions (2-D) and 3-D. We redefine the interactive particle relationship by which material impact-collision problems are realistically simulated and computational time is saved as well; (ii) investigating cracking propagation of a plate with crack-tip under mode-I loading.</description><creator>Wang, Ge, 1965-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Particle modeling of dynamic fragmentation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Ge Wang, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zn04m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m8280</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945w14t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Electrochemically-induced changes in surface stress at the solid-liquid interface are measured using a differential cantilever-based sensor. The simultaneous, in situ measurements of the current (charge) and interfacial stress changes are performed by employing an AFM cantilever as both the working electrode (in a conventional three-probe electrochemical cell configuration) and as the mechanical transducer (bending of the cantilever). The custom-built instrument achieves a surface stress sensitivity of 1x10-4 N/m and a dynamic range of 5x105. Combining electrochemistry with cantilever-based sensing provides the extra surface characterization capability essential for the interpretation of the origin of the surface stress. The objective of the present study is to gain a better understanding of the mechanisms responsible for the nanomechanical motion of cantilever sensors during adsorption and absorption processes. The study of these simple model systems will lead to a general understanding of the cantilever-based sensor's response and provide insights into the physical origin of the measured surface stress. The surface stress generated by the electrochemically-controlled absorption of ions into a thin polypyrrole film is investigated. A compressive change in surface stress of about -2 N/m is measured when the polymer is electrochemically switched between its oxidized and neutral (swollen) state. The volume change of the polymer phase with respect to the gold-coated cantilever is shown to be responsible for the mechanical motion observed. The potential-induced surface stress and surface energy change on an Au(111)-textured cantilever, in a 0.1 M HClO4 electrolyte, are simultaneously measured. These measurements revealed that for solid electrodes these two thermodynamic parameters are significantly different. In the double layer region, a surface stress change of -0.55 +/-0.06 N/m is measured during ClO4- adsorption whereas the surface energy variation is smaller by one order of magnitude. The origin of the surface stress change at the metal-electrolyte interface is understood by the variation in electron density at the surface which alters the inter-atomic bonds strength between surface atoms, while the specificity of adsorption of ions is found to be mostly responsible for the fine structure of the surface stress profile.</description><creator>Tabard-Cossa, Vincent.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Microcantilever actuation generated by redox-induced surface stress</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Vincent Tabard-Cossa, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214t429.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945w14t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xg94ht74q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although Great Powers are often thought to be the most influential actors in terms of international arms control efforts, during the 1990s Canada showed itself capable of successfully leading several arms control initiatives. This research sets out to (a) explain why Canada has been able to enjoy these successes while other recent Canadian arms control leadership efforts have failed, and (b) further the abstract thinking around Canadian foreign policy. This is done by introducing the Identity Management model of arms control to explain the process by which Canadian arms control processes succeed or fail, and testing it against four post-Cold War Canadian-led initiatives: the Open Skies initiative, the landmines initiative, the MOX fuel initiative, and the small arms initiative. Within the Identity Management model, Canada is classified as an Activist State, a categorisation that rejects and improves upon the popular, yet heavily flawed, Middle Power concept. Blending together critical insights from realism and constructivism, the Identity Management model focuses on the foreign policy preferences of states, distinguishing between the preferences of Great Powers, such as the United States, and the preferences of Activist States. The foreign policy preferences of Activist States are designed and promoted by important elite domestic actors, and expressed as the country's chosen identity on a given arms control issue. The Identity Management model thus postulates that while states such as Canada can express independent policy initiatives, these identities are offered up into the international system, the character of which is defined by the foreign policy preferences of Great Powers. Overall, the Identity Management model establishes that Canadian arms control initiatives are successful only when Canada's chosen identity accurately reflects the constantly changing character of the international system.</description><creator>Stern, Gabriel M. A.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Arms control.</subject><subject>Canada -- Foreign relations -- 1945-</subject><subject>Arms control -- Canada.</subject><title>Forging new identities : explaining success and failure in Canadian arms control initiatives 1990-2004</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Gabriel M. A. Stern, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kz06r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xg94ht74q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r967777j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The proposed thesis comprises two essays on international investment. Each essay proposes a new theory and provides empirical evidence. The first essay develops a three-moment international asset-pricing model (TM-IAPM) under full integration and deviations from purchasing power parity (PPP) that prices coskewness. The model also embeds the standard IAPMs as special cases when explicit restrictions are imposed. We further apply the model to investigate the time-series behavior of market, size, value, and momentum premiums in the United States, Japan, and the United Kingdom equity markets. We find that the model explains most of the variation of these premiums during the 1980s and 1990s and that the coskewness risk is more important than covariance risk. We also find that the model performs well out-of-sample. The direct implication of our result is that linear IAPMs are misspecified and that investors should use nonlinear models to price international assets. The second essay proposes a way to disentangle the test of market efficiency from the test of the postulated equilibrium model. Indeed, the efficient market hypothesis, which stipulates that prices fully reflect available information, is one of the most important building blocks in finance and economics. Unfortunately, there is no consensus on this important issue since the methodologies used to test market efficiency are subject to the well-established joint-hypothesis problem. We derive three propositions that build on the well-known Sharpe ratios with the specific aim to split the test from the joint-hypothesis into two separate tests. We apply the new approach to examine the efficiency of the United States, Japan, and the United Kingdom markets over the period 1981-2000. Our results suggest that the rejection of the efficient market hypothesis may be premature. We thoroughly discuss the bias underlying the traditional approaches and propose a way to solve the problems.</description><creator>Sy, Oumar.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Investments, Foreign.</subject><title>Essays on international investment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Oumar Sy, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jg47f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r967777j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mr60q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is devoted to the studies of self-assembled InAs quantum dots (QD) by low-temperature Atomic Force Microscopy (AFM) in frequency modulation mode. Several spectroscopic methods are developed to investigate single electron charging from a two-dimensional electron gas (2DEG) to an individual InAs QD. Furthermore, a new technique to measure the absolute tip-sample capacitance is also demonstrated. The main observables are the electrostatic force between the metal-coated AFM tip and sample as well as the sample-induced energy dissipation, and therefore no tunneling current has to be collected at the AFM tip. Measurements were performed by recording simultaneously the shift in the resonant frequency and the Q-factor degradation of the oscillating cantilever either as a function of tip-sample voltage or distance. The signature of single electron charging was detected as an abrupt change in the frequency shift as well as corresponding peaks in the dissipation. The main experimental features in the force agree well with the semi-classical theory of Coulomb blockade by considering the free energy of the system. The observed dissipation peaks can be understood as a back-action effect on the oscillating cantilever beam due to the fluctuation in time of electrons tunneling back and forth between the 2DEG and the QD. It was also possible to extract the absolute value of the tip-sample capacitance, as a consequence of the spectroscopic analysis of the electrostic force as a function of tip-sample distance for different values of the applied voltage. At the same time, the contact potential difference and the residual non-capacitive force could also be determined as a function of tip-sample distance.</description><creator>Stomp, Romain-Pierre.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Dissipative and electrostatic force spectroscopy of InAs quantum dots by non-contact atomic force microscopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Romain-Pierre Stomp, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zj76h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mr60q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rn42s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One third of drugs in development are water insoluble, and one half of all drugs fail in trials because of poor pharmacokinetics. Block copolymer micelles are nanosized particles that can solubilize hydrophobic drugs and coincidentally alter their kinetics in vitro and in vivo. In using such micelles it is important that the drug is not lost due to premature vehicle disassembly and that its effectiveness is not diminished by unfavorable distribution of the micelles. Disintegration of micelles depends on a number of environmental conditions, with consequent variation in drug release rates; these rates, however, are always faster than those which occur by simple diffusion from intact micelles. When these thesis studies began no data was available on integrity of micelles in cells and in vivo, and in vitro studies of distribution of micelles were scarce. This thesis begins by providing a detailed account of the distribution of model block copolymer micelles in live cells using fluorescent-labeled polymer and confocal microscopy. Next, the evidence for endocytosis of micelles, and their effectiveness in delivering a model micelle-incorporated agent anthra[1,9-cd]pyrazol-6(2H)-one (SP600125) is presented. The thesis ends with an account of the disruption of integrity of micelles in vitro and in vivo, made possible by a novel application of a fluorogenic-based assessment that enables the monitoring of the integrity of micelles under complex biological conditions. Block copolymer micelles were made from Food and Drug Administration approved polymers poly(caprolactone) and poly(ethylene oxide). In vitro studies were done in cell lines (PC12, NIH/3T3, T24) and primary cultures (human islets of Langerhans). In vivo studies were done in hairless SKH-1 mice. The in vitro studies demonstrated the uptake of micelles by all investigated cells. The micelles were confined to the cytoplasmic compartment, with no detectable nuclear localization. Detailed studies in PC12 cells revealed co-localization of micelles with several organelle selective dyes (mitochondria, Golgi apparatus, endoplasinic reticulum). Pharmacological manipulations (sucrose, FK506, wortmannin, horseradish peroxidase, methyl-beta-cyclodextrin) revealed an endocytotic uptake of micelles and suggested a significant contribution of clathrin-mediated endocytosis. The effectiveness of c-Jun NH2-terminal kinases (JNK)---micelle-incorporated inhibitor, SP600125, was demonstrated in human islets of Langerhans challenged with cytokines. Micelle-incorporated SP600125 prevented the cytokine induced cell death of islets at a lower starting concentration (1.5 $M in the medium) compared to free drug (20 muM). Lastly, a graded loss of integrity of micelles was demonstrated in media with increasing biological complexity, in cells, and, as a proof of principle, in vivo. Taken together, the results presented in this thesis suggest (i) a need for assessment of the integrity of micellar drug carriers under biological conditions to further improve the micelle-based drug delivery systems, (ii) the identification of the contribution of micelles with disrupted integrities to the internalization and effectiveness of micelle-incorporated drugs, (iii) an assessment of cellular retention and degradation of internalized polymers. That the pharmacokinetics of micelle-incorporated drugs reported in recent clinical trials showed only modest improvements over non-micelle delivered agents may at least in part be due to disruption of micelle integrity. Additional studies are needed to understand exactly where the delivery system goes, when and where is the drug released, and how recent advances in vehicle design and targeting can be harnessed to overcome the present challenges and realize the full potential of polymeric micelles.</description><creator>Savić, Radoslav.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Nanosized micellar drug carriers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Radoslav Savić, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zz343.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rn42s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ff365930x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Eukaryotic cells are divided into subcellular organelles that generate appropriate molecular environments for the functions they harbour. As such, subcellular localization is a key characteristic that provides valuable clues regarding protein function and, when studied globally, a better understanding of cellular processes. The organelles of the secretory pathway are responsible for the processing of all proteins destined for secretion, the plasma membrane as well as their own resident proteins. This group of organelles is difficult to study experimentally because they are difficult to purify to homogeneity. To facilitate the investigation of the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) and more generally, the secretory pathway, we have created Hera, a publicly accessible protein localization database. Originally designed to house characteristics of ER proteins, it currently contains tens of thousands of proteins from different organisms and subcellular compartments. Hera was originally used to investigate features of ER proteins, providing insight into the extent of usage of various localization mechanisms, including both well-studied but also non-classical and novel mechanisms. Hera was subsequently used to create Bayesian network type localization predictors. By considering the combinatorial presence of motifs, domains, targeting signals and using in some cases, protein interaction information, our predictors achieve high accuracy and coverage. When our predictions are compared with localization annotations from high-throughput studies in both human and yeast, we find that disagreements mainly involve proteins in the secretory pathway. Our predictors can be used to independently validate these large-scale studies. We further refined the localization prediction of the whole yeast proteome by distinguishing proteins localized to the lumen or membrane of various organelles from cytosolic proteins peripherally associated with these organelles. Hera was also used to investigate efficient and informative approaches to interrogate interaction networks in order to gain insight into the relationship between proteins/genes of interest. By combining interaction and refined localization information, we constructed localizome-interactome networks of whole organelles. Such models provide insight into global organellar characteristics and inter-organellar mechanisms of communication. The research presented in this thesis demonstrates that the integration, in an appropriate framework such as Bayesian networks, of widely available information such as localization and interaction data allows to gain deep insights into cellular processes.</description><creator>Scott, Michelle.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Protein subcellular localization : analysis and prediction using the endoplasmic reticulum as a model organelle.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Michelle Scott, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd473148n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff365930x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb397d516</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Complementary computational and experimental investigations of steady, laminar, mixed convection in a heated vertical pipe, with slurries of a microencapsulated phase-change material (MCPCM) suspended in distilled water as the working fluid, are presented in this thesis. The MCPCM consists of particles composed of a core of phase-change material (PCM) surrounded by a solid shell: The effective diameter of the particles is 2.5 mum; the melting and freezing temperatures of the PCM in the particles are in the ranges 27°C to 31°C (mean value 29.94°C) and 12°C to 16°C (mean value of 14.64°C), respectively; the latent heat of fusion during melting is 131.8 kJ/kg. Experimental apparatus and procedures for measurements of the effective density, the effective viscosity, the effective thermal conductivity, and the effective specific heat of the MCPCM slurries are presented along with results and correlations that apply to temperatures in the range 5ºC to 60ºC. In the presentation of the computational investigation, a homogenous mathematical model is shown to be applicable and proposed; procedures for incorporation of correlations for the effective properties of the MCPCM slurries are discussed; difficulties with the standard definition of bulk temperature when the specific heat of the fluid changes significantly with temperature are elaborated; a modified bulk temperature that overcomes these difficulties is proposed; a finite volume method is described; and its validation and use in the computer simulations are discussed. An apparatus that was designed, constructed, benchmarked, and used in the mixed-convection experiments is described. Details of this experimental investigation, conducted with slurries of mass concentration 0% (pure distilled water), 5%, 10%, 15%, and 20%, temperatures in the range 20°C to 60°C, and volume flow rates in the range 1.78 mL/s to 2.69 mL/s, are presented. The experimental and numerical results are presented, compared, and discussed. They show that the proposed homogenous model, with input of correlations that give the variation of the effective properties of the MCPCM slurries with temperature, provides a cost-effective and accurate foundation for computer simulations of the problems of interest.</description><creator>Scott, David A., 1972-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Heat transfer in pipes conveying slurries of microencapsulated phase-change materials in water</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© David A. Scott, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zj77s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397d516</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pm394</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cyclins are short-lived proteins that "cycle" through the cell cycle and determine the timing of activity of cyclin-dependent kinases (Cdks). Cyclin/Cdks regulate the progression through each phase of the cell cycle, presumably by phosphorylating key proteins. To date, only a few Cdk targets have been identified and it is not clear how Cdk complexes differ from one another. I have discovered that the CDP/Cux protein can bind to, and be phosphorylated by, several cyclin/Cdk complexes. Yet, my evidence demonstrates that each complex regulates CDP/Cux differently. The goal of my thesis is to document the interaction of CDP/Cux with several cyclin/Cdks and to characterize the effects of these interactions on CDP/Cux. I investigated three separate cyclin/Cdk complexes that interact with CDP/Cux. I determined that CDP/Cux is a target of the cyclin A/Cdk1 and cyclin A/Cdk2 complexes. However each kinase differentially regulated CDP/Cux. Phosphorylation of CDP/Cux by cyclin A/Cdk1 inhibited its DNA binding and transcriptional activities in G2 phase of the cell cycle. Although both cyclin A/Cdk1 and cyclin A/Cdk2 were recruited to CDP/Cux in a similar fashion, cyclin A/Cdk2 did not phosphorylate the same sites in CDP/Cux as cyclin A/Cdk1. Furthermore cyclin A/Cdk2 did not inhibit CDP/Cux DNA binding or transcriptional activities. Cyclin A/Cdk2 allowed CDP/Cux activity in S phase. CDP/Cux is the first physiological target of cyclin A/Cdk identified that is differentially regulated depending on the Cdk present in the complex. Finally, I determined that cyclin D1/Cdk4 negatively regulates the generation of the activated, proteolytically processed, CDP/Cux isoform. This regulation is achieved by phosphorylation and inhibition of proteolytic processing in the G1 phase. The processed CDP/Cux isoform accelerates cell cycle progression, and consequently generates cells that are small in size. Therefore, cyclin D1/Cdk4 may play a role in cell growth (the size of cells) by delaying the timing of CDP/Cux proteolytic processing. Overall, my work demonstrates that several cyclin/Cdk complexes interact with CDP/Cux and regulates CDP/Cux in a distinct manner. The control of CDP/Cux activity by cyclin/Cdk complexes in G1, S and G2/M phase contributes to a greater understanding the regulation of CDP/Cux and its role in the cell cycle.</description><creator>Santaguida, Marianne Theresa.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Distinct regulation of CDPCux : by cyclinCdk complexes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Marianne Theresa Santaguida, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429f65c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pm394</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54ks279</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:15:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study was designed to examine the most common characteristics, best practices, and gaps in service delivery at Early Intervention (EI) centres across Canada. A 29-item survey designed to investigate services, funding, waitlists, satisfaction, and perceptions of success was completed by 184 service providers. Provinces and territories were grouped according to time zone and five resulting samples were compared. Samples were comparable in terms of waitlists, perception of success and government contributions. Significant differences were found in terms of the number of professionals working at the centre, with the Mountain and Eastern samples having the most multidisciplinary centres. In addition to making cross-province comparisons, Canadian findings were also explored. As the proportion of government funding decreased and private funding increased, ratings of satisfaction significantly increased. Findings were discussed in relation to the relevance to Canadian EI centres and directions for future research were explored.</description><creator>Saracino, Jennifer L.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Developmentally disabled children -- Services for -- Canada.</subject><title>Early intervention for children with developmental delays : a national inventory</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Jennifer L. Saracino, 2007</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580r81s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54ks279</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):42325</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>