<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:57:43Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):27050" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w0323349</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of this study is to compare, with regard to volume maintenance and viability of the grafted bone, three different types of autogenous bone grafts. The three types of autografts with different embryonic origin and cellularity are; cancellous endochondral, cortical endochondral and cortical membranous bone. The endochondral bone was harvested from the ilium and the membranous bone from the cranium, of New Zealand White rabbits. The grafts were applied to the mandible in an onlay fashion and were stabilized by a titanium mesh. The control group consisted of a blood clot under the titanium mesh. Micro CT and histologic analysis were performed at 6 and 12 weeks after grafting. The cortical membranous bone graft had a greater volume of bone compared to both endochondral groups. The difference in volume between the two endochondral groups was not statistically significant. These results suggest a role for the embryonic origin of bone in the volume maintenance of the grafts. The osteoblast and osteoblast counts were used to assess the viability of the grafts. The cancellous endochondral group had the highest number of cells followed by the cortical endochondral and then the cortical membranous. The cortical bone grafts seem to be less viable compared to the cancellous group.</description><creator>El-Hakim, Michel.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Health Sciences, Dentistry.</subject><title>Autogenous onlay bone grafts to the mandible : an experimental evaluation of graft cellularity and embryonic origin</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Michel El-Hakim, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17ct14p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w0323349</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rf55z804f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This secondary data analysis used a cross-sectional survey of 1771 Yukon First Nations, Dene/Metis, and Inuit women. The aims were to evaluate access to traditional food (TF) and market food (MF), identify perceived advantages of TF and MF, and explore under-studied characteristics of FS in Arctic Canada. Results indicate considerable regional variation in ability to afford adequate food, varying between 26 and 58%. Similarly, regional variation was reflected in the percentage of women who had access to hunting or fishing equipment. Participants described culturally relevant FS indicators: food needed to be natural, fresh, tasty, varied, healthy, safe, accessible, and convenient. Between 10 and 38% of participants noticed recent changes in the quality or health of TFs. Caribou, moose, and seal were popular TFs and considered particularly healthy. This study emphasizes the importance of TF for Arctic indigenous women's FS and the dynamic nature of FS in this population.</description><creator>Lambden, Allison Jill.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Inuit women -- Food -- Yukon.</subject><subject>Tinne Indians -- Yukon -- Nutrition.</subject><subject>Inuit women -- Yukon -- Nutrition.</subject><subject>Tinne Indians -- Food -- Yukon.</subject><subject>Métis women -- Food -- Yukon.</subject><subject>Métis women -- Yukon -- Nutrition.</subject><title>Food security of Canadian Arctic indigenous women</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Allison Jill Lambden, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j9602092v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55z804f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514nk812</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objectives were (1) to establish a profile of total fatty acids and cholesterol in amniotic fluid (AF) as well as (2) to determine possible associations between AT fatty acids (micromolar and relative proportion) with gestational age and birth weight. A total of 208 AF samples collected between 12 and 22 weeks of gestation during routine amniocentesis were analyzed using tandem column gas chromatography (GC). Smoking increased AF polyunsaturated fatty acid (PUFAs) levels while developmental stage and storage time decreased AF fatty acid quantities. AF trans fatty acids (TFAs) were negatively associated with both birth outcomes, whereas specific fatty acids including stearic acid (C18:0) and gondoic acid (C20:1n-9) were identified as negative predictors for gestational age and birth weight respectively. This study demonstrated novel relationships between fatty acids and fetal growth and gestational age in early midgestation AF, suggesting a possible role of AF fatty acids in predicting birth outcomes.</description><creator>Enros, Erin.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Birth weight.</subject><subject>Fatty acids.</subject><subject>Cholesterol.</subject><subject>Fetus -- Growth.</subject><subject>Amniotic liquid -- Analysis.</subject><title>Amniotic fluid fatty acids and cholesterol and their association with pregnancy outcomes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Erin Enros, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qc50s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nk812</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv935321z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Haemonchus contortus is a nematode parasite that infects sheep and goats, and other ruminants, causing substantial economic loss throughout the world. Anthelmintic drugs are the primary method to control these parasites; however, resistance to all broad spectrum anthelmintics, including the newer avermectins and milbemycins, has been developing rapidly in nematode parasites. The mechanism of avermectin resistance is unknown, but previous studies indicate that at least four genes are involved. A single nucleotide polymorphism (SNP) in the Haemonchus contortus HG1 gene has been linked to ivermectin (IVM) and moxidectin (MOX) resistance. This gene encodes a GABA-gated chloride channel thought to control body muscle movement in H. contortus and mediates IVM and MOX paralysis. The present study was designed to determine whether there is an association between variation in this gene and the ability of H. contortus larvae to move in the presence and absence of MOX. The present study also investigated the difference between a laboratory strain (PF23) and an ivermectin resistant field strain (VHR29). Fourteen different MOX concentrations (ranging from 0.078nm to 156uM) and at least 200 third stage (L3) larvae for each concentration were investigated for each strain. An L3 larval motility assay was used to determine the movement phenotype of individual larva. Pyrosequencing was used to identify the genotype of each individual larva. The present study found that in the PF23 strain, the resistant heterozygote genotype GA protected against the effects of MOX, and that the protection was dose dependent. This was not the case, however, in the VHR29 field strain. For this strain, no protective effect of the HG1 variation was observed with moxidectin treatment. One reason for this may be that field strains are selected under higher drug pressure which favors a monogenic response. The present study has shown that while the HG1 variation does play a role in larval movement and resistance to MOX, this effect may be minor compared to other effects selected in the field.</description><creator>Zhou, Shufeng, 1965-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Drug resistance.</subject><subject>Haemonchus contortus -- Molecular genetics.</subject><subject>Avermectins.</subject><subject>Haemonchus contortus -- Larvae.</subject><title>Role of the HG1 gene in larval movement and response to moxidectin in Haemonchus contortus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Shufeng Zhou, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qm30x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv935321z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd375w45k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Natural ecosystems are dynamic and complex, with many being threatened by human activity. However, humans can also be at the root of a solution to this problem by developing ecosystem engineering which can be used to design, construct, modify, upgrade, repair, remediate, and maintain ecosystems. The aim of this project was to improve virtual ecosystems that can be used to increase the knowledge base for ecological engineering by studying adaptability as a factor for the success of species. This was done by analysing adaptive species in a virtual ecosystem, a computer application with which various configurations can be designed and studied in a closed environment. The virtual ecosystems used in this project represent ecosystems in general rather than any specific ecosystem, and allow for repeatable test cases to be run so that ecosystem dynamics can be studied. Adaptability was defined as the ability of an individual to adjust to a short term environmental pressure according to two factors: the adaptation speed, which is how fast an individual can respond to a change in environment, and the adaptive capacity, which is a quantitative indicator of how much the individual is able to adapt. In this project, experiments were performed to determine the effects of adaptability when applied to one aspect of individuals in an ecosystem. From the results of the experiments it was seen that the adaptation speed value could affect the success of a producer species in an ecosystem both positively and negatively. It was also found that ecosystems with both a consumer and producer species could persist longer when adaptability was incorporated into the individuals of the consumer species.</description><creator>Abbyad, Marc P.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Ecosystem management -- Computer simulation.</subject><subject>Adaptation (Biology) -- Computer simulation.</subject><title>Examining adaptability of individuals in complex, virtual ecosystems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Marc P. Abbyad, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676v88r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375w45k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb397859k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, I mainly study the forms of a smooth projective variety over a finite field k and the attached Hasse-Weil zeta functions. I also study the forms of a scheme. The study begins with understanding the relationship between etale cohomology and the Hasse-Weil zeta function of a smooth projective variety over k. In order to classify forms of a quasi-projective variety V over a perfect field K, I study nonabelian cohomology and Galois descent to give a proof of the bijection between the equivalence classes of K'/K-forms of V and H1 (Gal(K'/K), AutK' (V)), where K'/K is some Galois extension. I also present explicitly forms of elliptic curves and their corresponding Hasse-Weil zeta functions. The second part of my thesis is focused on forms of a scheme, especially in the affine case. This is a generalization of forms of a variety. I define an etale form of a scheme and generalize Milne's definition of the first Cech cohomology of a non-abelian sheaf to any (not necessarily abelian) presheaf. I prove there exists an injective map in the affine case from the set of equivalence classes of affine etale forms into the first Cech cohomology of a contravariant functor. I prove that the definition of an etale form of a scheme is compatible with the definition of a form of a variety over a perfect field. I also prove that the first Galois cohomology can be canonically identified with the first Cech cohomology when the base is Spec k for some perfect, field k.</description><creator>Zhao, Yu, 1970-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Forms of smooth projective varieties and their zeta functions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Yu Zhao, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17ct15z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397859k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80hv58q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:25:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Measurements of absorbed dose to water in megavoltage electron beams are carried out with cylindrical or plane-parallel ionization chambers. The perturbation factor associated with plane-parallel ionization chambers that have sufficiently large guard rings is assumed to be unity. The NACP-02 chamber is one such chamber that we have investigated in order to determine if this assumption is valid. By performing Monte Carlo simulations with the EGSnrc code, water-to-air Spencer-Attix stopping powers and perturbation factors were calculated in water with a detailed model of the NACP chamber that was validated through results obtained from measurements and simulations. These were determined for electron beam energies between 4 MeV and 19 MeV for a clinical and PSDL linear accelerator. The overall perturbation factor was found to decrease with energy at dref from 1.015 at 4 MeV to 1.004 at 19 MeV and increase with depth for a fixed beam quality.</description><creator>Zakikhani, Ramtin.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Biophysics, Medical.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Radiology.</subject><subject>Physics, Radiation.</subject><title>Calculated perturbation factors for the NACP-02 plane-parallel ionization chamber irradiated in water by megavoltage electron beams</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Ramtin Zakikhani, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr171x51k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80hv58q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21tf64r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:55:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Inflationary power spectrum plays an important role in modern cosmology. In this thesis, we studied both the experimental and theoretical aspects of the inflationary spectral index. By exploring the recent WMAP data, we found that the evidence for the running of the spectral index mainly comes from multipoles near l = 40. This fact allows a partial running spectrum to give as good a fit as the WMAP running spectrum. We gave some simple formulae for the inflationary spectral indices based on the Hamilton-Jacobi formulation of inflation. These simple formulae agree with the exact solutions in some special cases. The Hamilton-Jacobi formulation of inflation was also applied to reconstruct inflaton potentials from a given power spectrum. A simple and accurate reconstruction formulation was presented. All analytic potentials giving a constant spectral index are derived, which show that a nearly scale-invariant spectrum can give rise to slow-roll inflation during 60 e-foldings within sub-Planckian inflaton field values and a potential energy V1/4 ~ 1015GeV. Potentials for large running of the spectral index and large tensor-to-scalar ratio were also constructed, which need super-Planckian field values and require that the slow-roll approximation breaks down before reaching 60 e-foldings. We have shown that for the cosmologically interesting scales, a renormalizable potential fits the reconstructed potential for a large running spectrum very well. Our reconstruction formulation also produces a self-consistent tensor spectrum once a scalar spectrum and the tensor-to-scalar ratio are given. Higher order corrections to the slow-roll approximation are also considered. We showed that they can be incorporated straightforwardly into our formulae for spectral indices and the reconstruction formalism.</description><creator>Hoi, Loison.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>Inflationary spectral indices and potential reconstruction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Loison Hoi, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zt526.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21tf64r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b383m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:55:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Objectives. This study was undertaken to evaluate whether the effects of hyperbaric oxygen (HBO) therapy could alter the critical size for spontaneous healing of a bone defect in the rabbit calvarial model. Study design. An animal trial of 12 weeks duration was conducted using 20 New Zealand White rabbits, which were randomly divided into 2 groups of 10 animals each. Calvarial defects were created in the parietal bone of each animal bilaterally. Defects were critical sized, 15mm on one side and supra critical sized, 18mm on the contralateral side. Group 1 received 90 minutes HBO treatment sessions at 2.4 ATA per day for 20 consecutive days. Group 2 served as a control without any HBO treatment sessions. Five animals in each group were sacrificed at 6 and 12 weeks. Data analysis included qualitative assessment of the calvarial specimens, post sacrifice radiographs as well as histomorphometric analysis to compute the amount of regenerated bone within the defects. Two way ANOVA was used for statistical analysis. Results. Both radiographic analysis and histomorphometric analysis demonstrated that HBO treated animals had significantly more new bone within defects compared with the control group. There was no statistically significant difference between the percentage of new bone forming in the 15mm and 18mm HBO treated defects. There was no difference between the 6 week and the 12 week HBO treated groups. Conclusion. HBO is effective in enhancing the bone healing of full thickness critical sized as well as supra-critical sized defects in the rabbit calvarial model. Bone regeneration was significantly greater in the HBO treated animals regardless the defect size. HBO may have increased the diameter of the rabbit critical sized calvarial defect to more than 18mm.</description><creator>Iera, Deborah.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Health Sciences, Dentistry.</subject><title>Hyperbaric oxygen (HBO) and its influence on critical size defects in rabbit calvaria</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Deborah Iera, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p059s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b383m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Dentistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p2676v891</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:55:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We present a study of the time evolution of the elastic properties of colloidal depletion gels. Silica colloids were suspended in NaCMC solutions and homogenized. Both the colloid volume fraction and the interaction strength (polymer concentration) were varied. The time evolution of the elastic properties of the suspensions was studied with a bulk rheometer in a double-wall Couette cell throughout the gel lifetime. The early lifetime is characterized by an elastic shear modulus that increases logarithmically with time, following which the gels experience catastrophic failure and the elastic modulus drops dramatically. As the gel collapses, various complex behaviors are seen, including a temporary stabilization against collapse, and reformation of a new gel with its own elastic properties which then follows its own trajectory to collapse. Time-lapsed images were taken of identical samples in a separate transparent cell of identical dimensions and the gel height was used to calibrate the measured shear modulus values. The visual cell also allows us to see the sample-spanning collective rearrangement involved in the collapse.</description><creator>Kamp, Stephen W.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><title>Time evolution of colloidal depletion gels</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Stephen W. Kamp, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t204p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676v891</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fb494874x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:55:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis introduces three new tools for studying the evolution of different organisms given the evolutionary, or phylogenetic, tree that relates them. First, we show how posterior state probabilities can be used for exploring phylogenetic uncertainty, through posterior entropy of ancestral states. Second, we derive an explicit formula for the expected number of substitutions on a branch in a phylogeny, given the pattern at the leaves. Algorithms were implemented, as part of the ATV software, to calculate these values. They are used, in conjunction with SplitsTree4, to assess variation in rates over sites and lineages, and to predict model violations. Third, we show how techniques for spline interpolation and function approximation can be applied to estimate functions defined on a tree. We also present an example of the usage of interpolations on phylogenetic trees, by analyzing continuous traits on a phylogenetic tree through fossil data sets.</description><creator>Jetté, Migüel.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Reconstructing functions on phylogenetic trees</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Migüel Jetté, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rd76r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494874x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:td96k284s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:55:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main objective of this thesis is to analyze the bilateral air services agreements of Sri Lanka under the existing legal, regulatory and the infrastructural framework of civil aviation in Sri Lanka. In order to achieve this objective, this thesis is divided into following chapters, Chapter One - Deals with the history and evolution of bilateral air services agreements in the history of world civil aviation. Chapter Two - This Chapter has two sections. Section one addresses briefly the history and evolution of the air transport industry of Sri Lanka. Section two looks into the legal and regulatory framework within which the air transport industry works in Sri Lanka. Negotiation and Conclusion of bilateral air services agreements is also explained in this section. Chapter Three - Contains a detailed analysis of the main provisions of the bilateral air services agreements concluded by Sri Lanka. Chapter Four - The existing infrastructure and the prospects for the future is discussed in this chapter along with the challenges faced and to be faced in the future. Finally, the findings of this research are presented with recommendations for the betterment of air transport industry of Sri Lanka.</description><creator>Wickramasinghe, Anusha.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Law and legislation -- Sri Lanka.</subject><title>Bilateral air services agreements of Sri Lanka</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Anusha Wickramasinghe, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w95050856.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/td96k284s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ms35t8859</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:55:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is composed of major parts, as well as the introduction and conclusion. The second part of this thesis provides an overview the offence of aircraft hijacking, providing the foundation for this thesis. This part defines and introduces the terminology of aircraft hijacking, the relationship between hijacking and aerial terrorism, the categories of aerial terrorism, a comparative analysis of the concept of aircraft hijacking, the historic evolution of hijacking, and the present situation and characters of hijacking. Next, the third part will conduct a comprehensive study of the international Conventions available for combating hijacking, including the Tokyo Convention, The Hague Convention and the Montreal Convention. The fourth part will study domestic laws available for combating aircraft hijacking, including those of the United States of America, the United Kingdom, Canada, France, the Russian Federation, and the People's Republic of China. Finally, the fifth part of this thesis will analyze the concerted enforcement of international Conventions for combating hijacking.</description><creator>Wang, Xin, 1966-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Hijacking of aircraft.</subject><subject>Hijacking of aircraft -- Law and legislation.</subject><title>Study on aircraft hijacking from the perspective of legal mechanism</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Xin Wang, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752g98r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35t8859</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj139226h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:55:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is generally accepted that spirituality can play an important role in the end stage of the life of a person. Spirituality can provide a source of comfort and guidance and in so doing be a coping strategy. Social workers should take into account this spiritual component of their work particularly with clients who use spirituality as a form of social support. This thesis provides a theoretical understanding of spiritual based practice. It identifies the principles and competencies central to this practice, including the need for worker self awareness. It then illustrates how certain social work students have applied these principles in their practice with dying clients. The author's own identification as an individual from a religiously oriented Muslim country is used to illustrate the importance of understanding and working from the world view of clients. The author concludes that spirituality should not be ignored by social workers in their practice.</description><creator>Andayani.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Psychiatric social work.</subject><subject>Medical social work.</subject><subject>Terminal care.</subject><subject>Death -- Religious aspects -- Islam.</subject><title>Spiritual sensitive social work : a descriptive analysis of working with the dying</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Andayani, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p060j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139226h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042t39j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:55:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study explores the role of exercise and nutrition in burnout rates of social workers. Through convenience and snowball sampling 100 workers were asked to complete a questionnaire, with 82 returned. Burnout was assessed on three subscales, Emotional Exhaustion (EE), Depersonalization (DP) and Personal Accomplishment (PA), using the Maslach Burnout Inventory (MBI). The exercise questions were adapted from Canada's Physical Activity Guide of Healthy Living. The nutrition questions were adapted from Healthy Eating Worksheet from the Canadian Cancer Society. Those employed in child welfare had significantly higher levels of EE and DP and significantly lower levels of PA. Results of a multiple regression analysis indicated that higher exercise scores were significantly related to lower levels of EE. Higher nutrition scores were significantly related to lower levels of EE, and DP, and higher levels of PA. These effects were found even when setting was controlled for.</description><creator>Armbrust, Kirsten.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Social workers.</subject><subject>Exercise.</subject><subject>Burn out (Psychology)</subject><subject>Nutrition.</subject><title>Social worker burnout : the effects of exercise and nutrition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Kirsten Armbrust, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g541m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042t39j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1831ck22g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:55:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is about the possibility of addressing power disparities in divorce mediation in order to maximize the benefits that this alternative practice offers. It describes the development of Alternative Dispute Resolution (ADR) in general and of divorce mediation in particular, primarily through a feminist lens. In doing so it discusses the promise that feminist proponents saw in mediation initially, and then proceeds to describe the breaking of the promise that developed into some of the harshest critique of this process. The thesis explores a critical element of this critique, namely the problematic nature of utilizing mediation in the face of existing power imbalances generally, and in the context of divorce specifically. In order to facilitate the address of incongruities of power, it delves into an examination of the concept of power from several angles. To enhance and deepen the analysis of this concept, it describes Foucault's definitions and understanding of the term, and applies these towards advancing the discussion regarding the possibility of addressing existing inequality in power between parties to a dispute. Finally, it offers some tools that can be used in addressing power disparities in order to ameliorate the mediation process and its results. To this end it describes the ethical guidelines that can be utilized, comprised of internal tools to address power imbalances through mediation styles, as well as external ethical guidelines inherent to the process. Additionally, it suggests legal boundaries that may be utilized to offset possible power discrepancies. It ends with a hopeful message of the possibility of transformation in the face of conflict, thereby entertaining the prospects of a promising future for this alternative to resolving disputes.</description><creator>Cotler-Wunsh, Michal.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Foucault, Michel -- Views on law.</subject><subject>Feminist theory.</subject><subject>Divorce mediation.</subject><title>Understanding and addressing power disparities in divorce mediation : family, feminism &amp; Foucault</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Michal Cotler-Wunsh, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78tc256.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831ck22g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j129x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:55:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This Thesis deals with the national legal aspects of a particular space application: remote sensing by satellites, also referred to as earth observation systems. Governments have been the leading providers and users of satellite imagery data since the advent of earth observation satellites (i.e. almost 40 years ago). However, this has changed, particularly in the United States, with several private companies having acquired and launched their own imaging satellite systems. This new trend towards commercialization and privatization of the remote sensing industry, which appeared firstly in the United States and which is now being extended to Canada, required a change in policy. The role played by the government policies and regulations in shaping the prospects for the emerging commercial remote sensing satellite firms is of critical importance. In this context, these policies and regulations will determine the conditions that will enable commercial firms to realize their competitive potential in both the domestic and international marketplace. In this Thesis, a brief overview of the technical and historical legal backgrounds of remote sensing is provided. Then, the international legal framework of remote sensing is briefly analyzed. Finally, a thorough analysis of the policies, laws and regulations applicable within the United States and Canada is presented.</description><creator>Chouinard, Vicky.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Privatization -- Law and legislation -- Canada.</subject><subject>Artificial satellites in remote sensing -- Law and legislation -- Canada.</subject><subject>Privatization -- Law and legislation -- United States.</subject><subject>Artificial satellites in remote sensing -- Law and legislation -- United States.</subject><subject>Artificial satellites in remote sensing -- Law and legislation.</subject><subject>Space industrialization -- Government policy -- United States.</subject><title>The legal framework related to the privatization and commercialization of remote sensing satellites in the United States and in Canada /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Vicky Chouinard, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zt53g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j129x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x427m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:55:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aviation industry is undeniably playing a very significant role in our day-to-day life. A vast and inter-connected web of flights ensures swift passenger travel and cargo traffic. However, in the name of security, otherwise intrinsic technicalities tend now not only to hinder on further development of aviation facilitation but also take over and lead towards the exact opposite result. What are the current measures taken by the international community to streamline passenger travel? What are the new initiatives which ought to be implemented? How is the future of aviation facilitation going to look like? How is it going to affect air travel and what legal implications is it rising? Throughout this thesis we will present the legal framework applicable to aviation facilitation and discuss the main initiatives that are being considered by ICAO and IATA in this respect. While Facilitation and Security should be considered as "two faces of the same coin", in reality they appear to "compete" against each other. Hence, we will provide our arguments in support of this theory.</description><creator>Cioranu, Adrian Gabriel.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Security measures.</subject><subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Passenger traffic.</subject><subject>Airline passenger security screening.</subject><subject>Aeronautics, Commercial -- Freight -- Security measures.</subject><title>Facilitation versus security</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Adrian Gabriel Cioranu, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644r89h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x427m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p0967292</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:55:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since 1994, when the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) began functioning as a mechanism that aims to reduce trade barriers between Canada, the United States, and Mexico, it has become apparent that the differences and formalities inherent in the Member Countries' legal and notarial systems constitute significant obstacles to trading, particularly in terms of the rendering of services. This paper seeks to elucidate the difficulties that Member Countries commonly face when they attempt to apply foreign notarial documents to their own legal system, to discuss the requirements for the notaries to render services in the NAFTA territory, and to propose modifications that the notarial function must adopt in order to adapt to the technological and cybernetic tendencies that the modern world demands.</description><creator>Cardenas Montfort, Emilio.</creator><date>2004</date><subject>Notaries -- North America.</subject><title>The notarial services in the NAFTA /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Emilio Cardenas Montfort, 2004</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569476v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p0967292</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vx021f46g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:55:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dynamic analysis programs and empirical formulae are often used to compute the period of vibration of single-storey steel buildings. Recent ambient vibration tests of buildings in Quebec and British Columbia have shown that the predicted period of vibration is typically much longer than that measured. Software and empirical formulae do not usually take into account the stiffening effects of the non-structural components; this could be the source of the discrepancy between the results in the field and the results obtained by computational methods. This research project concentrates on the roof diaphragm system of single-storey steel buildings and the contribution of the non-structural components to diaphragm stiffness. It is believed that the non-structural components, roofing materials such as gypsum board and fibreboard, add to the overall stiffness of the system. A roofing system called AMCQ SBS-34 consisting of gypsum board, ISO insulation board and fibreboard, all hot bitumen adhered, was studied. The full roof system, as well as its individual components and connections, were first studied through laboratory testing. The flexural and shear stiffness of the fibreboard and gypsum panels, as well as the shear stiffness and equivalent flexural stiffness of the complete roof system and shear stiffness of the roofing connections were determined. Linear elastic finite element models, using the SAP2000 software, were developed to replicate the behaviour of bare sheet steel and clad diaphragm test specimens. The test based properties of the roofing components and connections were incorporated into the definition of the elements. The models were then calibrated based on the results of large-scale diaphragm tests by Yang. Once the elastic behaviour of the diaphragms had been matched, a parametric study was performed in order to assess the importance of the contribution of the roofing assembly relative to the roof deck panel thickness. It was shown that as the deck thickness increases, the relative contribution of the non-structural components decreases on a percentage basis, but does not become non-negligible. The increase in shear stiffness of the diaphragm ranges from 58.6% for the 0.76 mm deck panel to 4.7% for the 1.51 mm roof deck panel, dependent on the sidelap and deck-to-frame connection configuration.</description><creator>Mastrogiuseppe, Simon.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Numerical linear elastic investigation of steel roof deck diaphragm behaviour accounting for the contribution of non-structural components</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Simon Mastrogiuseppe, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wn14d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021f46g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cg84c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:55:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Vector Quantization (VQ) is a lossy data compression technique that is often applied in the field of speech communications. In VQ, a group of values or vector is replaced by the closest vector from a list of possible choices, the codebook. Compression is achieved by providing the index corresponding to the closest vector in the codebook, which in general can be represented with less data than the original vector. In the case of VQ applied to speech signals, the input signal is divided into frames of a given length. Depending on the particular technique being used, the system either extracts a vector representation of the whole frame (usually some form of spectral representation), or applies some processing to the signal and uses the processed frame itself as the vector to be quantized. The two techniques are often combined, and the system uses VQ for the spectral representation of the frame and also for the processed frame. A typical assumption in this scheme is the fact that the frame size is fixed. This simplifies the scheme and thus reduces the computing-power requirements for a practical implementation. In this study, we present a modification to this technique that allows for variable size frames, providing an additional degree of freedom for the optimization of the Data Compression process. The quantization error is minimized by choosing the closest point in the codebook for the given frame. We now minimize this by choosing the frame size that yields the lowest quantization error---notice that the quantization error is a function of the given frame and the codebook; by considering different frame sizes, we get different actual frames that yield different quantization errors, allowing us to choose the optimal size, effectively providing a second level of optimization. This idea has two caveats; we require additional data to represent the frame, since we have to indicate the size that was used. Also, the complexity of the system increases, since we have to try different frame sizes, requiring more computing-power for a practical implementation of the scheme. The results of this study show that this technique effectively improves the quality of the compressed signal at a given compression ratio, even if the improvement is not dramatic. Whether or not the increase in complexity is worth the quality improvement for a given application depends entirely on the design constraints for that particular application.</description><creator>Moreno, Carlos, 1965-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Variable frame size for vector quantization and application to speech coding</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Carlos Moreno, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p061t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cg84c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rt58m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:55:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Tethered helium aerostats are receiving renewed attention in the scientific and surveillance communities. However, conventional aerostats cannot consistently survive high winds. The goal of this research was to design an aerostat that could be deployed for very long periods, thus reducing operating costs and interruptions in data acquisition. Existing designs and fabrication techniques were first reviewed and replicated in the construction of a 2.5 m diameter spherical aerostat. The constructed balloon was then flown outdoors to observe its operational qualities. A low-cost data acquisition system was assembled to characterize the balloon's dynamics. The results were used to inform a Finite Element Analysis model evaluating the critical stresses in a 10.15 m diameter balloon's envelope and its tendency to "dimple" when subjected to high wind speeds. A second model was created to appraise the performance of an aerostat with a partially hard shell, made of carbon fiber, in highly loaded areas.</description><creator>Miller, Jonathan I.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>The design of robust helium aerostats /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Jonathan I. Miller, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q659t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rt58m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nv9353227</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:55:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The planning and provision of equitable urban transportation services is critical to ensure both equitable societies and sustainable urban forms. To achieve these, planners and decision-makers must acknowledge the diversity of issues resulting from the heterogeneity in socio-demographic segments. While the transportation needs of these groups are comparable within social strata, they greatly differ across them. The goal of this dissertation is to determine the level to which these differences exist and investigate the elements that engender them at the individual level. The analysis, conducted in various demographic segments in the Montreal census metropolitan area, is based on econometric models of commuting modes and distances, which have been developed using 1996 Canadian Census data.</description><creator>Merissa, Rahel.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Sociology, Public and Social Welfare.</subject><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Urban journeys unveiled : a study of work commutes among the Montreal disadvantaged</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Rahel Merissa, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vd66w010v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nv9353227</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149q13w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:55:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>With increasing bandwidth requirements of individual users, fibre-to-the-home systems are promising candidates for last mile communication. In case of local area networks, optical CDMA with nonorthogonal spreading sequences has emerged as an attractive technology that can manage quickly varying user requirements, while enabling total bandwidth utilization, avoiding network congestion and preventing denial of service. However, powerful error-control codes have to be utilized within optical CDMA systems to prevent errors caused by multiuser interference. Due to data rates common in optical communication, dedicated hardware is required to run such error-control codes at very high speeds, e.g., 155 Mbps or 652 Mbps. This work presents a rapid system prototyping platform for error-control codes which are to be incorporated into the above mentioned optical CDMA systems. The platform consists of a design methodology, an extensive library of modules and an environment for testing designed specifically for optical CDMA systems but applicable to other communication systems as well. It is built on System Generator from Xilinx, a Matlab/Simulink based visual design tool, and enables a "push of a button" transition from code specification to real-time implementation on an FPGA chip. Initially, both the hardware specifics of this platform and the details of the developed modular design methodology are presented. Consequently, implementation of a custom design construct (a Generate block) and a library of communication system modules are described together with blocks and methodology for testing the developed algorithms. Finally, design and evaluation of three different communication systems are presented. These designs show that the platform can be used for prototyping and evaluation of error-control algorithms running at the required processing speeds mentioned above.</description><creator>Irman, Martin.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Rapid system prototyping for error-control coding in optical CDMA networks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Martin Irman, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rf55z8060.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149q13w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r591x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:55:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) is extensively used in brain imaging research and clinical diagnostics. Increasingly, automated image processing algorithms are used for identification of tissue types within the image, such as gray matter, white matter and cerebro-spinal fluid. There is a wide range of algorithms, which vary in speed and accuracy, and it is often difficult to compare their performance in any objective and controlled fashion. The goal of this research was to design an automatic, generic, standard, extensible pipeline for objective and quantitative validation of MRI tissue classification algorithms and their processing pipelines. The main issues and requirements, for objective validation of different algorithms, are the use of common terminology, methodology, standard validation data sets, corresponding ground truth, validation metrics and statistical foundation. Based on those requirements, an automatic Brain Analysis Testbed (BAT) was developed to determine an objective evaluation score for MRI processing method. BAT supports Montreal Neurological Institute on-site or off-site processing of MRI data, accessible by a web interface (http://www.bic.mni.mcgill.ca/validation/). Validation results are stored in the BAT database permanently, allowing the comparison of newly developed processing methods with existing ones. Furthermore, BAT can be used to determine the optimal classification parameters, or the best classifier algorithm for a specific MRI classification purpose, simply by searching the BAT database. The main purposes and principles of BAT are demonstrated with some practical MRI processing examples.</description><creator>Ivanov, Oleg, 1970-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>MRI brain analysis testbed (BAT) : methodology and automatic validation pipeline</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Oleg Ivanov, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q4228.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r591x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):27075</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>