<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dc xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
    xmlns:ualterms="http://terms.library.ualberta.ca"
    xmlns:vivo="http://vivoweb.org/ontology/core"
    xmlns:marcrel="http://id.loc.gov/vocabulary/relators"
    xmlns:bibo="http://purl.org/ontology/bibo/"
    xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
    xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
   <dcterms:creator>Hammal, Fadi</dcterms:creator>
   <dcterms:format xsi:type="dcterms:IMT">application/pdf</dcterms:format>
   <dcterms:language xsi:type="dcterms:ISO639-3">eng</dcterms:language>
   <dcterms:subject>Waterpipe</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Hookah</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Canada</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Policy</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:subject>Qualitative</dcterms:subject>
   <dcterms:title>Waterpipe Use in Canada:  Evidence, Perceptions, and Policy Implications</dcterms:title>
   <dcterms:type>Thesis</dcterms:type>
   <dcterms:abstract>Canadian research on the phenomenon of waterpipe (WP) use has been slow to develop.  Significant knowledge gaps have hampered tobacco control efforts in this area.  This thesis presents results from three multidisciplinary studies that were designed to provide fundamental knowledge about WP use.  Study 1 provided the first Canadian assessment of the chemical contents of commercially available, so-called ‘herbal’ shisha.  Study 2 described knowledge of Canadian medical students about WP (and other tobacco) use.  Study 3 explored young adults’ current knowledge and attitudes toward WP use.  Collectively, the findings have important implications for designing appropriate education and prevention strategies to address the spread of WP use in Canada, and support an evidence-based approach to developing appropriate policies to address the phenomenon.  For years, research interest in smoking WPs in Canada was limited.  This created a knowledge gap in tobacco control efforts, which will require further efforts to increase our understanding of the determinants of WP smoking. The present research will help to increase awareness about its health hazards, to design special prevention and treatment interventions, and to incorporate WP use control policy within national and provincial tobacco control policies.</dcterms:abstract>
   <dcterms:dateaccepted xsi:type="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-10-21T11:50:01Z</dcterms:dateaccepted>
   <dcterms:datesubmitted xsi:type="dcterms:W3CDTF">2014-10-21T09:25:08Z</dcterms:datesubmitted>
   <dcterms:extent>2243806 bytes</dcterms:extent>
   <ualterms:fedora3uuid xsi:type="string">uuid:f90ded0b-e83d-47f6-b388-be939d838e78</ualterms:fedora3uuid>
   <ualterms:fedora3handle xsi:type="anyURI">http://hdl.handle.net/10402/era.39931</ualterms:fedora3handle>
   <dcterms:isversionof>Hammal F, Chappell A, Wild TC, Kindzierski W, Shihadeh A, Vanderhoek A, Huynh CK, Plateel G, Finegan BA. 'Herbal' but potentially hazardous: an analysis of the constituents and smoke emissions of tobacco-free waterpipe products and the air quality in the cafés where they are served. Tob Control. 2013 Oct 15. doi: 10.1136/tobaccocontrol-2013-051169.</dcterms:isversionof>
   <dcterms:isversionof>Vanderhoek AJ, Hammal F, Chappell A, Wild TC, Raupach T, Finegan BA. Future physicians and tobacco: An online survey of the habits, beliefs and knowledge base of medical students at a Canadian university. Tob Induc Dis. 2013 Apr 4;11(1):9.</dcterms:isversionof>
   <ualterms:graduationdate xsi:type="gYearMonth">2015-06</ualterms:graduationdate>
   <ualterms:specialization>Health Policy Research</ualterms:specialization>
   <marcrel:ths>Wild, T. Cameron</marcrel:ths>
   <ualterms:thesiscommitteemember>Wild, T. Cameron (Department of Public Health Sciences)</ualterms:thesiscommitteemember>
   <ualterms:thesiscommitteemember>Nykiforuk, Candace (Department of Public Health Sciences)</ualterms:thesiscommitteemember>
   <ualterms:thesiscommitteemember>Finegan, Barry (Department of Anesthesia and Pain Medicine)</ualterms:thesiscommitteemember>
   <vivo:AcademicDepartment>Department of Public Health Sciences</vivo:AcademicDepartment>
   <marcrel:dgg>University of Alberta</marcrel:dgg>
   <ualterms:thesislevel>Doctoral</ualterms:thesislevel>
   <bibo:ThesisDegree>Master of Science</bibo:ThesisDegree>
</dc>