<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:06:48Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):4325" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214r50k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Des jeunes garçons présentant des retards de langage sans étiologie connue et leurs parents ont été étudies dans ce projet. Dans la première partie, les enfants ayant des retards de langage ont été compares à un groupe contrôle constitue de garçons normaux du même âge, afin d'investiguer les corrélatifs comportementaux des retards de langage. Compare au groupe contrôle, les enfants ayant des retards de langage furent décrits par leurs parents comme manifestant plus de problèmes de comportements intériorises et extériorises. De plus, ils se montrèrent moins coopératifs pour de simples requêtes maternelles sur une tache standardisée. Les groupes étaient semblables pour ce qui est de la proportion de refus verbal. Cependant les groupes se sont montres différents quant à la proportion de refus non verbal, particulièrement en ce qui a trait à la forme passive. Les corrélations effectuées sur l'échantillon total révélèrent que les indices de développement (verbal et non verbal) étaient associés de façon négative avec le refus nonverbal et avec les problèmes de comportement intériorises. […]</description><description>This three-part study involved male toddlers with developmental language delays of unknown etiology and their parents. In order to document the behavioral correlates of language delay, the language-delayed sample was first compared to an age-matched group of normally developing boys. The language-delayed children were rated by their parents as having more internalizing and externalizing behavior problems than the control group. They also displayed less compliance to simple maternal requests on a standardized task. There was no group difference in verbal noncompliance. Rather, nonverbal noncompliance, particularly the passive form, differentiated the groups. […]</description><creator>Lalinec-Michaud, Constance</creator><date>1995</date><subject>Child development.</subject><subject>Children -- Language.</subject><subject>Parent and child.</subject><title>Impact of a 6-month parent-implemented behavioral intervention for children with developmental language delays of unknown etiology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kn079.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214r50k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jn84s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Spirals of Sense est une œuvre inspirée du poème "Universe And: The Electric Garden" de la poète canadienne Gwendolyn MacEwan. Les spirales perpétuelles sont les images centrales du poème dans lequel elle décrit leur existence entrelacée à tous les niveaux de l'univers. Les processus de conjonction de ces spirales A niveaux multiples sont les points de départ de cette œuvre. Les images de spirales peuvent être décrites mathématiquement par une fonction exponentiellement décroissante. Cette fonction a été utilisée pour générer les agrégats d'hauteurs, les durées, et les textures de cette œuvre. Les images du poème de MacEwan ont été évoquées par les structures ainsi obtenues. Spirals of Sense a été écrite pour un orchestre de chambre (15 musiciens). L'œuvre a une durée de 10 minutes. </description><description>Spirals of Sense is a composition inspired by the poem "Universe And: The Electric Garden" by Canadian poet Gwendolyn MacEwan. Perpetual spirals are the central image of her poem in which she describes their interrelated existence at all levels of the universe. The processes of conjunction of these multilevel spirals are the departure points for this musical composition. A spiral may be mathematically described with an exponentially decreasing function. This function generates the pitch content, durations, and textures of this work. The resulting structures evoke the imagery of MacEwan's poem. Spirals of Sense is scored for chamber orchestra (15 players) and has a duration of 10 minutes.</description><creator>Krausas, Veronika J.</creator><contributor>Rea, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Chamber orchestra music -- Scores.</subject><title>Spirals of Sense: For Chamber Orchestra</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547t831.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jn84s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10ws73v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Genetic variants of milk proteins were used as genetic markers for production traits during three lactations in Ayrshire, Jersey, Brown Swiss, and Canadienne. Frequency distribution of genetic variants was first investigated for the analysis of production traits. At the asè-casein locus, the B variant accounted for more than 97.0% in Ayrshire, Brown Swiss and Canadienne compared to 56.9% in Jersey. The A2 variant of B-casein was highest among Jersey (49.9 %) and Brown Swiss (51.8 %) While the A1 constituted 60.1 % in Ayrshire and 58.5 % in Canadienne. The A variant of K-casein occurred in 88.1% of Ayrshire and in only 26.0% of Jersey. K-Casein C was detected only in Brown Swiss and Canadienne with vecy low frequencies (&lt;0.1 %). Only 2 variants, A and B of B-lactoglobulin were detected in the cow population with following distributions; 0.240 A: 0. 760 B in Ayrshire, 0.442 A: 0.558 B in Jersey, 0.417 A: 0.583 B in Brown Swiss, 0.424 A: 0.576 B in Canadienne. […]</description><creator>Kim, Sungwoo</creator><contributor>Ng-Kwai-Hang, K. F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Genetic polymorphisms.</subject><subject>Milk proteins.</subject><subject>Dairy cattle -- Genetics.</subject><title>Genetic Polymorphism of Milk Proteins and Their Association with Production Traits in Ayrshire, Jersey, Brown Swiss, and Canadienne</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w0325368.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10ws73v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77ft837</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The problem addressed in this dissertation is whether it is possible to make meaningful comparisons between significant concepts in two different religious traditions. Charles J. Adams, over two decades ago, pointed out that historians of religions have in the main neglected to include Islam in their comparative studies, while drawing attention simultaneously to the fact that the categories devised by historians of religion did not necessarily fit the Islamic tradition. This neglect has begun to be addressed in recent years, mostly in the form of targeted studies such as that of Toshihiko Izutsu's 1966 study titled A Comparative Study of the Key Philosophical Concepts in Sufism and Taoism and Henry Corbin's studies comparing Ismacifi and Mazdaean notions of time and gnosis. […]</description><creator>Kassam-Hann, Zainool Rahim</creator><contributor>Young, Katherine K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Imamate.</subject><subject>Rāmānuja, 1017-1137.</subject><subject>Ṭūsī, Naṣīr al-Dīn Muḥammad ibn Muḥammad, 1201-1274.</subject><title>Imām and Avatāra : a study of divine-human configurations in Naṣīr al-Dīn Ṭūsī (d. 1274 CE) and Rāmānuja (d. 1137 CE)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vd83x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77ft837</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:12579v64x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La grossesse est associé à des changements dans la régulation de la balance liquidienne, des volume et pression sanguins, qui sont accompagnés d'élévations du facteur auriculaire natriurétique (FAN) plasmatique comme nous l'avons démontré auparavant. Pour mieux comprendre les changements possibles dans les mécanismes qui contrôlent la sécrétion du FAN, des études ont été complétées pour examiner la réponse du FAN aux changements de pression des oreillettes droite et gauche, induits par l'inflation graduelle d'un ballon. Ensuite, un stimulus modère de pression auriculaire gauche a été utilisé pour évaluer les réponses rénales à la distension auriculaire gauche par ballon en comparant l'expansion de volume avec solutions saline normale et hypertonique a 1.8%. […]</description><description>Pregnancy is associated with alterations in the regulation of fluid balance, blood flow and blood pressure which, according to repeated findings from our laboratory, are accompanied by elevations in plasma atrial natriuretic factor (ANF). To better understand possible changes in the mechanisms that regulate ANF secretion, a first series of studies were conducted to assess the ANF response to changes of right (RAP) and left atrial pressure (LAP) induced by graded balloon inflation. Secondly, a moderate LAP stimulus was chosen with which to assess the renal responses to left atrial balloon distension (AD) in comparison to normal saline (NS) and 1.8% hypertonic saline volume expansion (HS). […]</description><creator>Javeshghani, Danesh</creator><contributor>Quillen, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Atrial natriuretic factor</subject><title>Secretory Control and Renal Actions of ANF in Pregnancy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w3763930r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/12579v64x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sx61dp734</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this dissertation is to propose a conceptual framework that can guide assessing and reporting on sustainability. The framework is rooted in a particular value set, is consistent with systems theory, and serves to focus indicator choice. Its development is influenced by a literature review that includes 220 state of- environment reports, several key aspects of economic thought, and thirtytheoretical models that address the human-ecosystem relationship. Four strategic elements that serve as areas of diagnosis or indicator domains are identified including (I) ECOSYSTEM; (11) INTERACI'ION; (Ill) PEOPLE; and (IV) SYNTHESIS. Each domain is linked to a set of goals and objectives. For each domain, an assessment hierarchy is mapped out and example indicators are provided. The reporting system must be tailored to the needs of different decision-making groups. […]</description><description>Dans cette thèse nous présentons le cadre vsh à paradigmes multiples pour la conception graphique d'interfaces utilisateur. vsh offre un cadre puissant et flexible permettant la programmation en C++ ainsi qu'en Tel. Tcl est un langage de scripts qui peut être incorpore à C ou a C++. Tk est une collection d'outils pour fenêtres et graphiques basée sur XII, accompagnée d'un interpréteur appelé wish. La bibliothèquevsh comprend des classes permettant un accès pratique et flexible aux outils de Tcl/Tk et à ses extensions. Inclue dans ce cadre de développement se trouve wish+ +, une extension orientée-objet de la coquille de fenêtre wish, elle-même basée sur Td/Tk. La bibliothèque a pour but de subvenir tant aux besoins des programmeurs (de fenêtres) expérimentes qu’à ceux de programmeurs débutants.</description><creator>Jain, Vipul</creator><date>1995</date><subject>User interfaces</subject><title>VSH: A Multiparadigm Framework for Graphical User Interfaces</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xn999.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sx61dp734</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924f01v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'objet de la présente thèse est de proposer un cadre conceptuel permettant de guider l'élaboration des rapports faisant état des progrès vers la pérennité. Fonde sur un ensemble particulier de valeurs, ce cadre s'inspire de la théorie des systèmes et sert à orienter le choix des indicateurs. Le développement de l'étude est influencé par une revue des écrits qui englobe quelque 220 rapports sur l'état de l'environnement, plusieurs aspects clés de la pensée économique et 30 modèle de relations entre les humains et l'écosystème. Quatre éléments stratégiques servent à tracer les grandes lignes du diagnostic ou séries d'indicateurs: I. l'ECOSYSTEME, II. l'INTERACTION, III. les INDIVIDUS, et IV. la SYNTHESE. Chacune de ces séries d'indicateurs est reliée à un ensemble de buts et d'objectifs. Une hiérarchie de l'évaluation et des exemples d'indicateurs sont alors établis pour chaque série. Dans son application, le système de rapports doit être adapte aux besoins des différents groupes décisionnels. […]</description><description>The purpose of this dissertation is to propose a conceptual framework that can guide assessing and reporting on sustainability. The framework is rooted in a particular value set, is consistent with systems theory, and serves to focus indicator choice. Its development is influenced by a literature review that includes 220 state of- environment reports, several key aspects of economic thought, and thirtytheoretical models that address the human-ecosystem relationship. Four strategic elements that serve as areas of diagnosis or indicator domains are identified including (I) ECOSYSTEM; (11) INTERACI'ION; (Ill) PEOPLE; and (IV) SYNTHESIS. Each domain is linked to a set of goals and objectives. For each domain, an assessment hierarchy is mapped out and example indicators are provided. The reporting system must be tailored to the needs of different decision-making groups. […]</description><creator>Hodge, Robert A. L.</creator><date>1995</date><subject>Great Lakes Region (North America)</subject><subject>Sustainable development.</subject><subject>Ecosystem management.</subject><title>Assessing Progress toward Sustainability: Development of a Systemic Framework and Reporting Structure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w6634606x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924f01v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Urban Planning</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rf55zb06d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Over the last two decades, increasing numbers of investigators have reported marked differences in rates of use of health services, surgical procedures and hospitalizations in different jurisdictions. Despite the rapid growth in the volume of such reports, children's use of health services has received relatively little attention. In addition, statistics used in studies of this geographic variation differ and are often the basis for inference despite little or no consideration of how well these methods perform. […]</description><description>Un nombre croissant de chercheurs ont reporté des différences marquées entre les taux d'utilisation des services de santé de différentes juridictions. Diverses statistiques sommaires sont utilisées dans de telles études de variations géographiques malgré le peu d'attention accordée a leur performance. […]</description><creator>Hodge, Matthew</creator><contributor>Pless, Barry (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Health services</subject><title>Methods for Analyzing Geographic Variation in Health Services Use</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j67316375.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55zb06d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gq630</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Elevated environmental concentrations of toxic metals can occur due to leaching, anthropogenic sources and industrial activity. Organisms can survive elevated exposure to toxic metals by reorienting their cellular physiology to cope with metal-induced stress, and this often includes changes in gene expression. In order to identify metal-induced changes in Escherichia coli chromosomal gene expression, a library of 3000 single-copy luxAB gene fusions was prepared and screened for increased luminescence in the presence of aluminum and nickel. Two clones were found which displayed increased luminescence in the presence of aluminum (strains LF20110 and LF20111), and one was found to increase luminescence in the presence of nickel (strain LF20112). […]</description><description>De fortes concentrations de métaux toxiques peuvent être retrouvées dans l'environnement dû au phénomène de lessivage et aux activités tant humaines qu'industrielles. En cas d'exposition a de fortes concentrations de métaux toxiques, les organismes peuvent survivre en réorientant leur physiologie cellulaire afin de surmonter le stress cause par les métaux. Cette réorientation physiologique implique souvent des changements dans l'expression des gènes chromosomiques chez Escherichia coli. Une banque de clones comptant 3000 gènes de fusion, entre les gènes luxAB et I'ADN de E. coli, a été préparée. Chaque gène de fusion est retrouvé en une seule copie. Cette banque de clones a été testée pour détecter une augmentation de la luminescence, résultant de l'expression de luxAB, en présence d'aluminium et de nickel. […]</description><creator>Guzzo, Angelina</creator><contributor>DuBow, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Toxic metals</subject><title>Molecular Approaches to Identify Genetically Programmed Reponses to Toxic Metal Exposure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j3860926d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gq630</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wg11n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les cellules NK ont la capacité de détruire des cellules tumorales ou infectées de virus par un procédé dont les bases moléculaires sont à peine caractérisées. Les résultats publiés au cours des dernières années suggèrent que les cellules NK exprimeraient deux types de récepteurs; un déclenchant l'activité lytique des cellules NK suite à la reconnaissance d'une structure glucidique sur la cellule cible, et un inhibant cette activité lorsqu'il se lie à certaines molécules de classe I du CMH, présents sur la cellule cible. Notre laboratoire a produit un AcM (4LO3311) définissant un antigène de surface des cellules NK murines et a démontré qu'il était possible d'augmenter l'activité lytique des cellules NK via cet antigène.Dans ce travail, nous avons établi que l'AcM 4LO3311 reconnait en fait l'antigène NK2.1, originalement identifie par un sérum NZB anti-BALB/c. […]</description><description>Natural killer (NK) cells can kill tumor and virally infected cells in a manner that is only beginning to be characterized at the molecular level. Results reported in the last few years support the concept that NK cells may display two types of receptors; one triggering NK cell lysis upon recognition of target cell carbohydrate structures, and one inhibiting cytotoxicity when engaged by particular target cell MHC class I molecules. Our laboratory produced a mAb (4LO3311) identifying a murine NK cell surface antigen, and provided evidence that this antigen is an activating receptor. In this work, we established that, in fact, mAb 4LO3311 recognizes the NK2.1 antigen, formerly defined by an NZB anti-BALB/c antiserum. We characterized NK2.1 as a probably transmembrane disulfide-linked dimer of highly glycosylated 65 kDa subunits. […]</description><creator>Gosselin, Pierre</creator><contributor>Lemieux, Suzanne (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Murine</subject><title>Analysis of the Structure and the Modulation of a Specific Alloantigen of Murine Natural Killer Cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj2364507.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wg11n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p5547t849</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We selected for Human Immunodeficiency Virus type 1 (HIV-1) resistance in cell culture. In order to do this, each of a wild-type laboratory strain (IIIB) or a clinical isolate was passed in MT -4 cells in the presence of drug. At initial passage, the drug concentrations employed were subinhibitory for HIV -1 replication; these were gradually increased in subsequent passages. Using this system, we were able to select variants of HIV-1 that possessed up to 100-fold resistance in comparison to wild-type viruses. The drug resistance phenotype remained stable even after propagation of these variants in the absence of drug pressure for over 2 months. […]</description><description>Nous avons sélectionné pour la résistance contre le VIH-1 en culture de tissue. Pour effectuer cette expérience, nous avons développé soit des isolats cliniques du VIH ou la souche de laboratoire IIIB sur cellules MT -4 en présence de différentes drogues antivirales. Initialement, les concentrations utilisées ont été sous-inhibitrices. Ces concentrations ont été augmentés au passage subséquent. En utilisant ce système, nous avons sélectionné des variants du VIH-1 montrant une résistance allant jusque 1000 fois contre différents médicaments en comparaison avec les virus de type sauvage. Le phénotype de résistance est resté stable après propagation des virus en absence de drogues pendant deux mois. […]</description><creator>Gao, Qing</creator><contributor>Wainberg, Mark A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>HIV-1</subject><title>In Vitro Selection and Characterization of Drug-Resistant Variants of HIV-1</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x920fz985.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p5547t849</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451k93d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'architecture vernaculaire est le résultat de facteurs socio-culturels et environnementaux variés. Elle représente une collection d'outils, qui ont résiste au passage du temps et qui peuvent nous aider à développer une approche vers une architecture durable et énergétiquement efficace. Le centre d'intérêt de cette thèse est sur le produit physique de l'architecture vernaculaire -l'artefact -- comme réponse a l'environnement dont il fait partie. L’object d'étude se porte sur différentes solutions vernaculaires de ventilation naturelle dans des climats chauds et humides. […]</description><description>Vernacular architecture is a result of various social, cultural and environmental factors. It represents a collection of efficient responses that have passed the test of time, and is very relevant today in helping us develop an approach towards sustainable and energy efficient architecture. The focus of this thesis is on the physical product of vernacular architecture -- the artefact -- as an efficient response to the environment of which it is a part. This thesis entails the study of different vernacular responses with respect to natural ventilation in hot and humid climates. […]</description><creator>Ganapathi, Sriram</creator><date>1995</date><subject>Vernacular architecture -- India -- Madras.</subject><subject>Vernacular architecture.</subject><subject>Ventilation.</subject><title>A Study of Vernacular Ventilation Techniques in Hot Humid Climates :an opportunity for an appropriate transfer of technology to Madras, India</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623f91g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451k93d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j349t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Des calculs de champ auto-consistant utilisant la méthode de l 'Approximation Locale de la Densité corrigée d’Auto-Intéraction ont été effectués afin d'étudier différentes séries de composes organo-métalliques qui présentent des situations de liaisons particulières: i) les structures [1.1.1] propellane avec différents éléments du groupe IVa (Si, Ge, Sn et Pb), formant des stuctures squelettiques très tendues; ii) des couronnes de thio-éthers avec des différents métaux de transition de la première période: Fe, Co, Ni et Cu en état d’oxidation II. Les structures moléculaires obtenues pour les [1.1.1] propellanes ont été comparées aux résultats obtenus pour les structures bicycliques [1.1.1] pentane qui leur correspondent ansi que leurs dérivées. Une analyse plus appronfondie des distributions de densité électronique et des graphes de contour des fonctions d'ondes a révélé comment cette structure tendue se maintenait: les liaisons dans les [1.1.1] propellanes ainsi que leurs dérivés semblent avoir le même comportement: l'atome central est lie par une interaction a entre les atomes pont et une interaction (pi) avec les trois atomes périphériques. […]</description><description>Self-consistent field calculations using the Self-Interaction corrected Local Density Approximation method (SIC-LDA) were performed to study different series of organometallic compounds that present peculiar bonding situations: i) [1.1.1] propellane structures with different elements of Group Na (Si, Ge, Sn) forming a very strained skeleton of five atoms; ii) crown-thioethers compounds with first-row transition metal ions, Fe, Co, Ni and Cu in oxidation state ll. The molecular structures obtained for [1.1.1] propellanes were compared to the results obtained for the corresponding bicyclic structures of [1.1.1] pentanes and derivatives. A further analysis of the electronic density distributions and wavefunction contour maps revealed how this strained structure was held together: the bonding in all [1.1.1] propellane derivatives seemed to follow the same trend, the central atom being bonded by a o interaction between the bridgehead atoms and 7t to the three peripheral atoms. […]</description><creator>Gallego-Planas, Núria</creator><contributor>Whitehead, M. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Approximation</subject><title>Calculations on Metal Organic Compounds Using the Self-Interaction Corrected Local Density Approximation Method</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t442h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j349t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278w61q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chlorisondamine, a bisquaternary amine, is an autonomic ganglion blocking drug. However, the administration of chlorisondamine, either centrally or in a large systemic dose, results in a persistent blockade of centrally-mediated behavioural responses to nicotine in the rat. The objective of this thesis was to elucidate the mechanism(s) underlying the central nicotinic antagonism exerted by chlorisondamine in rats. […]</description><description>Une amine biquaternaire, la chlorisondamine, est une drogue qui bloque les ganglions autonomes. Cependant, l'administration de la chlorisondamine, qu'elle soit centrale ou a dosage systémique élevé, produit un blocage à long terme des réactions du comportement médié centralement par la nicotine chez le rat. L'objectif de cette thèse était de déterminer les mécanismes de l'antagonisme nicotinique central produit par la chlorisondamine chez le rat. […]</description><creator>El-Bizri, Hiba Hassib</creator><contributor>Clarke, P.B.S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Chlorisondamine</subject><title>An Investigation of the Mechanism(s) Underlying Central Nicotinic Blockade Exerted by Chlorisondamine in Rat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j778v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278w61q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214r51v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse examine la conjecture abc, une inégalité diophantine conjecture qui fait un rapport entre les operations d'addition et de multiplication (spécifiquement, decomposition en facteurs premiere) dans l'anneau des nombres entier et les corps de nombres. D'abord, nous examinons le contexte et motivation de la conjecture, et puis nous prouvons deux imlications tres differente d'elle- une algebraique et une analytique. </description><description>This thesis examines the abc-conjecture, a conjectured diophantine inequality which makes a connection between the operations of addition and multiplication (specifically, prime factorization) in number fields. After examining the context and motivation of the conjecture, we go on to prove two very different implications of it - one algebraic and one analytic. </description><creator>Drudge, Keldon W.</creator><contributor>Murty, Ram (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Conjecture</subject><title>On the abc-conjecture</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kj653.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214r51v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jh343v28t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les pays en voie de développement se sont en général prononces contre la protection de la propriété intellectuelle a un niveau international, les pays industrialisés soutenant plutôt qu'il serait avantageux pour les pays en voie de développement d’offrir un tel degré de protection. Bon nombre de pays en voie de développement ont récemment mis en branle des reformes visant à assurer la protection des droits d'auteur; ces mesures résultent surtout des pressions exercées par les pays industrialisés dans le cadre des négociations bilatérales et des négociations commerciales multilatérales. […]</description><description>Developing countries have generally argued against securing intellectual property protection at an international level, whereas developed countries have argued that it would be beneficial for developing countries to offer this level of protection. Many developing countries have recently embarked on processes of reform for copyright protection and have done so mainly in response to pressure from developed countries, channelled through the fora of bilateral negotiations and multilateral trade negotiations. […]</description><creator>Daley, Dianne Andrea</creator><contributor>Glenn, H. Patrick (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Copyright -- Developing countries.</subject><subject>Copyright, International.</subject><title>International Copyright and Developing Countries: The Impact of Recent Developments from a Jamaican Perspective</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544br823.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jh343v28t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:r494vn26w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines the transfer of [14C]-Gal from UDP-[14C] Gal by membranes from pea epicotyls to products with solubility characteristics of polysaccharides, with the particular aim of testing for the incorporation of galactose into xyloglucan (XG). Incorporation into products that were water- and TCA-soluble, but 67% (w/v) ethanol-insoluble was stimulated by the presence of added XG acceptor. Ethanol-insoluble products were fractionated by gel filtration and found to elute in part (60%), along with tam XG at a very high mol mass(&gt; 1 M). Treatment with Trichoderma cellulase degraded tarn XG and about half of the [14C] products to a low mol mass, the rest was degraded by protease. […]</description><description>Pour cette étude, nous avons examiné le transfère du [14C]-Gal par des membranes d'épicotyles de pois entre le UDP-[14C] Gal et des produits ayant des caractéristiques de solubilité similaires aux polysaccharides, dans le but précis de vérifier l'incorporation du galactose dans les xyloglucans (XG). L'incorporation aux produits qui sont solubles à l'eau et au TCA, mais non-solubles à l'éthanol à 67% était stimulée par l'addition d'accepteur de XG. Les produits non-solubles a l'éthanol ont été fractionés par filtration de gel, et l'élution a menée à leur récupération partielle (60%) simultanément avec les tam XG, a une très hautes masse moléculaire (&gt; 1 M). Un traitement à l'aide de cellulase de Trichoderma a dégradé les tam XG, ainsi qu'environ la moitié des produits [14C], le reste fut dégradé par I'action d'une protéase. </description><creator>Chileshe, Chinga</creator><contributor>Maclachlan, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Plant membranes.</subject><subject>Galactose.</subject><subject>Peas.</subject><title>Galactosyl-transfer Reactions from UDP-[ 14 C] Galactose, Catalysed by Enzyme from Pea Epicotyl Membranes in the Presence of Xyloglucan</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4f16c503q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/r494vn26w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj236451h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A high yield synthesis of cyclic(aryl ether ketone) oligomers containing a 1, 2- dibenzoylbenzene moiety via the nucleophilic aromatic substitution route has been developed. Chemical transformation of the 1,2-dibenzoylbenzene moiety of these cyclic(aryl ether ketone)s leads to the preparation of novel cyclic(aryl ether phthalazine)s and cyclic(aryl ether isoquinoline)s. Matrix assisted laser desorption ionization- time of flight- mass spectrometry, which enables the detection of oligomers with mass up to 5000 Da, was shown to be a very powerful tool for the analysis and proof of the cyclic nature of the oligomers. A preliminary rheology study on selected cyclic(aryl ether ketone)s shows that the viscosity of the cyclic oligomers is orders of magnitude lower than the high molecular weight polymers. […]</description><description>Des oligomères cycliques contenant les groupements aryl, éther et cétone, écrit généralement cyclique(aryl éther cétone)s, et contenant spécifiquement le groupement dibenzoyl-1,2-benzène ont été synthétisés en haut rendement par une substitution aromatique nucléophile. La transformation chimique du groupement dibenzoyl-1,2-benzène par la réaction de ces cycliques avec l'hydrazine et lebenzylamine donne les cyclique(aryl éther phtalazine)s et cyclique( aryl éther isoquinoline)s. La nouvelle technique de spectrométrie de masse, MALDI-TOF (Matrix Assisted Laser Desorption Ionization-Time Of Flight) nous a aidé à détecter les oligomères cycliques avec une masse jusqu'à 5000 Da. Cette technique a démontré d'être un outil puissant pour l'analyse et la confirmation de la structure cyclique. Des études préliminaires de rhéologie sur certains cyclique(aryl éther cétone)s ont démontres qu'ils ont une viscosité plus basse d'ordres de magnitude de celle correspondante aux polymères de haut poids moléculaire et de même composition.</description><creator>Chan, Kwok Pong</creator><contributor>Hay, Allan S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Polymers</subject><title>Cyclic Aryl Ethers: New Intermediates for High Performance Polymers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v838286b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236451h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225d45b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Afin de mieux comprendre l'interaction entre l'antigène grand T du virus du polyome et les ARN polymérases bloquées dans la région intergenique du virus du polyome, nous avons décidé de localiser précisément la position sur le génome à laquelle les molécules D'ARN polymérase sont bloquées. Nous avons décidé de localiser la position des ARN polymérases en analysant les chaines d'ARN naissantes synthétisées par les polymérases bloquées. […]</description><description>In order to gain Insight into the interaction between polyomavirus large T antigen and stalled RNA polymerase 11 at the intergenlc region of polyomavirus DNA, we set out to map precisely the position on the template DNA where RNA polymerases stall In vivo. We chose to define the location of these RNA polymerases indirectly, by analysis of the nascent RNA chains associated with them. […]</description><creator>Brabant, Francois</creator><contributor>Acheson, Nicholas H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>RNA</subject><title>Mapping of Stalled RNA Polymerase II in the Intergenic Region of Polyomavirus DNA by Analysis on Nascent RNA Chains</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494b62j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225d45b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26z0675</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In an effort to find new genes affecting developmental processes in the nematode Caenorhabditis elegans, a screen for viable maternal-effect mutations was performed. Wild type worms were mutagenized with ethyl methane sulfonate and the F3 generation was screened. Thirty-thousand animals were screened and those which exhibited defects in morphology and behaviour were kept. Forty-two mutations defined 25 genes. Only two of these genes, sdc-1 and tra-3, had been previously defined. The preliminary mapping results presented here indicate that the other mutations found in this screen will likely define new genetic loci. A detailed analysis of the mode of inheritance of these novel genes and a basic description of the phenotypes of mutant animals is also presented here. It has been found that in all cases but one, there is zygotic rescue of the phenotype. Only mal-2 was found to exhibit a strict maternal-effect. Also, all genes but two, mau-2 and mud-1, exhibit complete maternal rescue of the mutant phenotype. None were found to exhibit a paternal effect. </description><description>Dans le but de trouver de nouveaux gènes affectant des processus développementaux chez le nématode Caenorhabditis elegans, un criblage pour des mutations a effet maternel a été effectué. Des vers sauvages ont été mutagenizés avec du éthyl métane sulfonate et la génération F3 a été criblée. Trente mille animaux ont été crible, et ceux montrant des défauts morphologiques et comportementaux ont été gardé. Quarante-deux mutations contribuèrent à la définition de 25 gènes, dont seulement deux, sdc-1 et tra-3, avaient été définis précédemment. Des résultats préliminaires de liaison et cartographie génétiques sont rapportés ici, et il semble que les mutations trouvées dans ce criblage, définiront de nouveaux loci génétiques. Une analyse détaillée de l'héritabilité de ces nouveaux gènes, ainsi qu'une description de base des phénotypes des mutants, sont également présentées ici. Dans la majorité des cas, il a été trouvé que le génome zygotique est capable de secourir le phénotype mutant. Un seul gène, mal-2, montre un effet maternel stricte. De plus, tous les gènes exceptés deux, mau-2 et mud-1, montrent un secour maternel complet du phénotype mutant. Aucun gène a effet paternel n'a été trouve.</description><creator>Boutis, Paula</creator><contributor>Hekimi, Siegfried (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Caenorhabditis elegans -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Animal mutation.</subject><title>Viable maternal-effect mutations in the nematode Caenorhabditis elegans</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h192c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z0675</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b573s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La simulation par ordinateur est largement utilisée dans l'analyse des systèmes tels que les grands réseaux d'ordinateurs, la conception assistée par ordinateur (CAO), la manufacture des semi- conducteurs, et de nombreuses applications militaires et aéro-spatiales. Les ressources de calcul et fou en temps réel exigées pour de telles simulations pourraient inhiber l'utilisation de la simulation dans ces domaines. La simulation parallèle offre une solution prometteuse à ce problème, en créant toutefois un nouvel ensemble de problèmes et de compromis.  […]</description><description>Simulations are widely used in analyzing systems such as large communication networks, computer-aided design (CAD) circuits, semiconductor manufacturing line, and many aerospace and military applications. The computational expense and/or the real time required to run significant simulation may inhibit the use of simulation in these areas. Parallel simulation offers a promising solution to this problem, but not without creating a new set of issues and trade-offs. […]</description><creator>Boukerche, Azzedine</creator><contributor>Tropper, Carl (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Simulations</subject><title>Parallel Simulation with Clustered Processes: Principles and Practice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k7490.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b573s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2801pj67w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Four pairs of selection lines of Chlamydomonas reinhardtii were each founded by mt+ and mt- spores from the same zygote. They were cultured asexually under light (photoautotrophic) and dark (heterotrophic) conditions for several hundred generations. The light and dark lines derived from each spore had by then diverged, each becoming adapted to its selection environment Sister lines were then crossed. Crosses between lines selected in the same environment (mt+light x mt-light and mt+dark x mt-dark) showed that adaptation was heritable and generally additive; however, some lines showed substantial epistasis. Crosses between lines selected in different environments (mt+light x mt-dark and mt+dark x mt-night) suggested that chloroplast and mitochondrial genomes contributed to adaptation, genes evolving in the light being borne on the chloroplast and those evolving in the dark on the mitochondrion. </description><description>Quatre paires de lignées de Chlamydomonas reinhardtii ont été dérivées de spores mt+ et mt- issues d'un même zygote. Chacune de ces lignées a ensuite été soumise à selection, d'une part à la lumière (croissance autotrophe), d'autre part à l'obscurité (croissance hétérotrophe), pendant plusieurs centaines de générations. Les lignées "lumière" et "obscurité" issues de chaque spore ont ainsi divergé, chacune s'adaptant à son environnement Des croisements entre lignées sélectionnées dans le même environnement (mt+ "lumière" x mt- "lumière" et mt+ "obscurité" x mt- "obscurité") montrent que l'adaptation est héritable et généralement additive; néanmoins, certaines lignées présentent des effets épistatiques non négligeables. Les croisements entre lignées sélectionnées dans des environnements différents (mt+ "lumière" x mt- "obscurité" et mt+ "obscurité" x mt- "lumière") suggèrent une contribution du génome chloroplastique a l'adaptation à la croissance autotrophe, et du génome mitochondrial a l'adaptation à la croissance hétérotrophe. </description><creator>Bernhardt, Torsten</creator><contributor>Bell, Graham (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Chlamydomonas reinhardtii -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Chlamydomonas reinhardtii -- Adaptation.</subject><title>The Genetic Basis of Adaptation to Novel Environments in Chlamydomonas Reinhardtii</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w9788.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2801pj67w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z316q382t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Lattice Gas Cellular Automata method is a useful approximation for modeling fluids. It deals with systems of particles that move with a discrete set of velocities from site to site on a regular lattice. Such systems show fluid-like behavior in the appropriate limit. We first study the theory of LGCA using the conventional methods of Statistical Mechanics. We start from the microcanonical description of LGCA and investigate the conditions for fluid-like macroscopic behavior. We consider the most important quantities for the description of fluids, namely the kinetic propagator, and the dynamic structure factor which is the power spectrum of density fluctuations. […]</description><description>La méthode des automates cellulaires sur réseau (ACR) est une approximation très utile à la modélisation des fluides. Les ACR sont des systèmes de particules qui se déplacent avec une gamme de vitesses discrètes d'un site à l'autre sur un réseau régulier. De tels systèmes présentent un [[comportement de fluide dans la limite appropriée. La théorie des ACR est d'abord étudiée en utilisant les méthodes habituelles de la mécanique statistique. Nous commençons par une description microcanonique des ACR et nous examinons les conditions nécessaires pour reproduire le comportement d'un fluide. Nous considérons les quantités les plus importantes pour la description des fluides, à savoir le propagateur cinétique et le facteur de structure dynamique qui est le spectre de puissance des fluctuations de densité. […]</description><creator>Baran, Oleh</creator><contributor>Harris, Richard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Fluids</subject><title>Athermal and Thermal Lattice Gas Cellular Automata</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cj93r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q382t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wg12x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, we study two topics concerning the analytic properties of automorphic L-functions. First, we study mean values of twisted L-functions of unitary automorphic cuspidal forms of GLr over the rational number field and then, the Langlands' reciprocity law for finite Galois extensions of algebraic number fields. We prove an asymptotic formula, and a bound of the mean value of L-functions twisted by some sort of quadratic characters at critical points and at 1/2 respectively. As a corollary of the asymptotic formula, we prove a nonvanishing result for GL2. We also establish the Langlands' reciprocity law for certain Frobenius extensions of algebraic number fields. </description><description>Dans cette thèse, nous étudions deux sujets concernant les propriétés analytiques des L-fonctions automorphiques. D'abord, nous étudions des valeurs moyennes des L-fonctions tordues de formes cuspitales automorphiques unitaires de GLr sur le corps rationnel de nombre et ensuite la loi de réciprocité de Langlands pour les extensions finies de Galois des corps algébriques de nombre. Nous démontrons une formule asymptotique et une limite de la valeur moyenne des L-fonctions tordues par un certain genre de caractères quadratiques aux points critiques et a 1/2 respectivement. Comme un corollaire de la démontrons un résultat non-trivial pour GL2. Nous établissons aussi la loi de réciprocité de Langlands pour certaines extensions de Frobenius des corps algébriques de nombre. </description><creator>Zhang, Yuanli</creator><contributor>Murty, Ram (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>L-functions</subject><title>Some Analytic Properties of Automorphic L-functions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xd07gw00h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wg12x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v5208</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T05:16:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La synthèse diastéréosélective de phosphoramidites nucléotidiques cycliques a été étudiée. Nous avons démontré que le phosphoramidite cyclique 13, forme d'un cycle a six chainons, est un intermédiaire relativement stable pour la synthèse d'oligonucléotides. La thermodynamique donne la préférence au diastéréoisomère comportant la thymidine en position axiale dans ce type de cycle a six chainons. Une série de triazoles et d'imidazoles ont été testes pour la réaction de couplage stéréosélectif du phosphoramidite cyclique avec différents alcools. Alors que certains catalyseurs plus acides permettent un couplage plus rapide, les plus encombres stériquement ont pour résultat une meilleure diastéréosélectivité. Un nouveau catalyseur, le 2-bromo-4,5-dicyanoimidazole (21), nous a permis de générer les deux diastéréoisomères dans un rapport de 50 à 1, lorsque le methanol est utilisé pour le couplage. Le couplage du phosphoramidite 13 avec la thymidine protégée sur la position 3' a produit le triester de phosphite 19 avec 50% d'excès diastéréomérique. Le mécanisme de la réaction de couplage est également discuté. </description><description>The diastereoselective formation of cyclic nucleoside phosphoramidites has been studied. It has been found that six-membered cyclic nucleoside phosphoramidite 13 is a relatively stable intermediate for the synthesis of oligonucleotides. Thermodynamic driving force favors the diastereomer with an axial thymidine substituent in six-membered cyclic phosphoramidites. A group of triazoles and imidazoles have been tested as activators for stereoselective coupling reaction of nucleoside phosphoramidites with alcohols. While some catalysts with stronger acidity lead to more rapid coupling, those with larger sizes gave higher stereoselectivity. A new designed catalyst, 2-bromo-4,5-dicyanoimidazole (21), generated two diastereomers in a ratio of 50:1, when methanol was used as the coupling alcohol. Coupling of phosphoramidite 13 with 3 '-protected thymidine gave phosphite triester 19 with 50% de. The mechanism of the coupling reaction is discussed. </description><creator>Xin, Zhili</creator><contributor>Just, George (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1994</date><subject>Phosphite triesters</subject><title>Steroselective Syntheses of Phosphite Triesters</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh92n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v5208</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):4350</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>