<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:06:59Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):29525" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dj52w634v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A protocol is presented for the rapid (28 days) induction of microtubers on micropropagated layered potato plantlets of 'Kennebec', 'Russet Burbank' and 'Superior' in medium devoid of growth regulators. With this method the addition of coumarin, 6-(2-chloroethyl)-trimethylammonium chloride and 6-benzylamino-purine to the microtuberization medium either had no effect or significantly reduced microtuber weight per plantlet. Increasing the incubation period from 28 to 56 days significantly increased the weight of microtubers per plantlet and the proportion of microtubers heavier than 1 gram. Increasing the volume of microtuberization medium from 50 to 100 ml significantly increased the number of microtubers per plantlet. Microtuber dormancy periods were cultivar-specific and microtubers $ le$250 mg had longer dormancy periods as compared to microtubers $&gt;$250 mg. A positive correlation was established between endogenous abscisic acid levels and microtuber dormancy periods. Microtubers $ le$250 mg had lower specific gravity, fewer eyes and produce fewer sprouts than microtubers $&gt;$250 mg. Microtuber-derived plants were generally single-stemmed. Severe physiological ageing treatment ($&gt;$2500 degree-days) had no effect on microtuber sprout development, stem number, tuber number and only minimally influenced tuber weight of microtuber-derived plants. Decreasing field in-row planting density from 30 to 10 cm reduced tuber weights and numbers per plant but increased them on a per hectare basis. Economic analysis indicated that optimum planting density varied depending on plantlet cost. The optimum planting density was 10 cm if the cost of the plantlet was $0.10 or less, 20 if plantlet cost were from $0.10 and $0.20 and 30 cm for plantlet cost greater than $0.20. A potato seed tuber certification program adapted to the needs and constraints of Egypt is presented.</description><creator>Leclerc, Yves</creator><contributor>Donnelly, D. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Seed potatoes -- Certification.</subject><subject>Potatoes -- Micropropagation.</subject><title>The production and utilization of potato microtubers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78td65c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w634v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:73666611p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chromogranin A (CgA) is the major member of a family of acidic secretory glycoproteins (collectively known as granins) that are expressed in all endocrine and neuroendocrine cells. Granins have been proposed to play multiple roles, both intracellular and extracellular, in the secretory process. The regulation of synthesis and secretion of CgA in primary cultures of bovine parathyroid cells was studied and compared to that of parathyroid hormone (PTH). The effects of both extracellular calcium and the active metabolite of vitamin D$ sb3$, 1,25-dihydroxyvitamin D$ sb3$ (1,25(OH)$ rm sb2D sb3$) were shown to modulate CgA synthesis and secretion in the parathyroid. Whereas a reduced medium calcium level stimulated both CgA and PTH secretion, it had no effect on CgA mRNA levels. In contrast, 1,25(OH)$ rm sb2D sb3$ stimulated CgA mRNA levels by increasing the CgA gene transcription rate. Thus, 1,25(OH)$ rm sb2D sb3$ had opposite actions on the CgA and PTH genes in the parathyroid cell. The relationship between 1,25(OH)$ rm sb2D sb3$-stimulated CgA mRNA levels and total CgA protein levels (intracellular and extracellular) was not simple. Although 1,25(OH)$ rm sb2D sb3$ increased CgA mRNA levels several-fold, there was only a modest increase in CgA protein. This was the result of a specific effect of 1,25(OH)$ rm sb2D sb3$ on decreasing the translational efficiency of CgA mRNA as demonstrated by an increased ribosome transit time for CgA mRNA. To better understand the functional domains of CgA, and its evolution, and to study the basis of its neuroendocrine cell-specific gene expression, the human CgA gene was cloned and characterized. It spans 15 kb and contains eight exons. There is high conservation between the human, mouse, and bovine CgA genes with respect to exon number and placement of exon/intron borders. Transient transfection studies with constructs containing portions of the 5$ sp prime$ gene flanking region upstream of a chloramphenicol acetyl transferase rep</description><creator>Mouland, Andrew</creator><contributor>Hendy, Geoffrey N. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Structural and functional analysis of the chromogranin a gene and study of the regulation of expression in the parathyroid</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j0380.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666611p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059c9063</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Limb salvage in patients with advanced peripheral vascular disease or effective nonoperative therapy for patients with limited disease still remains a challenge in modern vascular surgery. Based on recent advances in the area of angiogenesis as well as our previous studies of alternative approaches for limb ischemia, we have presented herein the step-by-step experimental investigations that are directed toward the development of a novel therapy, angiogenic stimulation, for the revascularization of ischemic limbs. An animal ischemic hindlimb model has been developed suitable for testing our hypothesis and further understanding of this potential therapy. We have demonstrated that an angiogenic factor, ECGF, when administered intramuscularly into the ischemic limb, markedly enhances revascularization of the limb in the models of unilateral as well as bilateral hindlimb ischemia. In addition, we have also demonstrated that the angiogenic effect of ECGF is dose dependent and is demonstrable only when it is administered directly into the limb in the presence of ischemia. Therefore, we conclude that angiogenic therapy may have the potential for the treatment of patients with chronic limb ischemia.</description><creator>Pu, Li-Qun</creator><contributor>Sniderman, Allan D. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Symes, James F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Evaluation of angiogenic stimulation for revascularization of ischemic limbs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p864g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059c9063</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ng451k151</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main objective of the present work is to investigate the nature of the cognitive processes responsible for the problem-solving operations of novices, intermediates, and experts in a semantically rich and complex domain, i.e. electronics trouble shooting, in relation to their knowledge of the task. The performance for each group of subjects shows a varying degree of knowledge integration (theoretical and procedural). The results show (1) that novices lack theoretical knowledge and make theoretical errors, (2) that intermediates do not lack theoretical knowledge but they have some difficulty in applying it, and (3) that experts have well-integrated knowledge and troubleshooting procedures for circuits and that they are able to apply procedures and correctly interpret the results to identify the reasons for failure in the circuits. Expertise in troubleshooting circuits is an ability to adaptively apply debugging procedures and interpret the results in terms of a mental model of the circuit's behavior and structure.</description><creator>Bédard, Denis, 1960-</creator><contributor>Frederiksen, Carl H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Problem solving</subject><title>Compréhension et utilisation des connaissances dans la résolution de problèmes en électronique</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515p839.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ng451k151</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zp38wf30n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The expression of different myosin heavy chain (MHC) isoforms is under the control of several factors, including the state of innervation and thyroid hormone levels. Muscle regeneration following injection of venom from the snake Notechis scutatus scutatus into rat soleus was used to study the role of innervation and excess thyroid hormone in influencing MHC gene expression. MHC protein and mRNA content was determined in muscles regenerating in the presence/absence of innervation or in the hyperthyroid state. In summary, MHC production appears to be primarily controlled at the level of transcription or mRNA stability; however, translational or post-translational control may play a role for IIA MHC protein production. The results also suggest that satellite cells are not preprogrammed to express a particular MHC isoform, but rather are capable of expressing either fast or slow MHC. Subsequent expression of MHC isoforms is modified by factors such as innervation and thyroid hormone.</description><creator>Bockhold, K. (Kathryn)</creator><contributor>Whalen, R. G. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Davis, H. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Control of myosin heavy chain expression in regenerating rat soleus K. Bockhold.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p5547t06x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zp38wf30n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1r66j2693</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Technology adoption has been seen as key to the development of more productive agriculture in lesser developed countries. But the adoption and adaptation of new agricultural technology occurs at the level of farm families where decisions are made based on perceived risks and benefits of the new technology, and its fit within the knowledge and practices of existing agricultural system. The processes and consequences of household decision-making are investigated using unidisciplinary methods of decision analysis involving statistical, mathematical, psychological, anthropological and econometric techniques brought together in a holistic manner. The study is focused in the Ada and Selale regions of the Central Ethiopian Highlands. The technologies studied are fertilizer, improved crop varieties, pesticides and cross-bred cows. Differences in goals and strategies of households are caused by inequalities in ownership of physical resources, and access to local institutions and indigenous knowledge. Village and regional institutions greatly influence access to physical (e.g. land) and non-physical (knowledge and information) resources. Successful intervention strategies are those that recognize region- and experience-specific potentials. When compared with physical resources, non-physical resources exert greater influence on decisions to adopt technologies and on the efficiency with which inputs are used in the production of grain and milk outputs. Producers are willing to take risks in enterprises in which they have the advantages of favourable location or experience. The degree of risk-averse behaviour of households reduces the probability of adopting technologies in both study sites. Natural factors (e.g. rainfall) and policy variables (e.g., land tenure and market) increase production risk. Indigenous production knowledge and schooling consistently reduce variability in production.</description><creator>Kebede, Yohannes</creator><contributor>Coffin, Garth (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Galaty, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Agricultural innovations -- Economic aspects -- Ethiopia.</subject><subject>Households -- Decision-making -- Ethiopia.</subject><subject>Farm management -- Decision making -- Ethiopia.</subject><title>Household decision-making : the adoption of agricultural technologies in Ethiopia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s4655j14w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1r66j2693</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214q579</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this thesis is to characterize the time-frequency representation (TFR) of the Doppler blood flow signal in order to improve the detection and quantification of arterial stenoses. First of all, we studied the statistical behavior of the Doppler blood flow signal and found that the signal is Gaussian and inherently nonstationary. However, the usual assumption of stationarity during a short time interval ($ leq$10 ms) is acceptable. The signal was then modeled as a complex autoregressive (AR) process to provide directional information about the blood flow. It was shown that the TFR based on AR modeling is less sensitive to window length and sampling frequency than the spectrogram. In order to obtain a more precise Doppler TFR, a new distribution based on a Bessel kernel was proposed. This Bessel distribution can suppress the cross-terms effectively and has many desirable properties with high resolution in time and frequency. A numerical alias-free implementation of this distribution was also developed. A realistic model of the Doppler blood flow signal of the femoral artery was proposed and used to simulate signals for comparing five TFR techniques: the short-time Fourier transform, AR modeling, the Bessel distribution, the Choi-Williams distribution, and the Choi-Williams Reduced Interference Distribution. The results showed that the Bessel distribution is the best, but the Choi-Williams distribution and AR modeling are also good techniques to compute Doppler TFRs. The short-time Fourier transform, AR modeling, and the Bessel distribution were then applied to clinical data to derive diagnostic features for a pattern recognition system to assess lower limb arterial stenoses in 37 patients. A total of 379 arterial segments were classified into three stenotic classes. The results were in agreement with those based on computer-simulated signals, and confirmed that the Bessel distribution and AR modeling improve the Doppler spectral estimates and thus provide better classification of arterial stenosis.</description><creator>Guo, Zhenyu, 1963-</creator><contributor>Lee, H. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Durand, L.-G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Time-frequency representation and pattern recognition of doppler blood flow signal for stenosis classification</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mr42j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214q579</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60cz05z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents three studies on the regulation of externalities. In the first chapter we use a two-period model to analyse the reform of environmental policy when enforcement is incomplete. We show that in evaluating such reforms it is important to differentiate between two types of non-compliers which react to regulatory reform in qualitatively distinct ways. In Chapter 2 we show the problems caused by using the 'ALARA' criterion when the supply of new technologies of environmental protection is endogenous. The difference between the ALARA rule and the socially optimal rule is characterised and it is shown that the difference depends upon whether the source of technical change is R&amp;D effort or learning-by-doing. In the third chapter we examine the externalities which are created by a particular type of regulation, and show the gains from self-regulation which are thus generated. Though each chapter discusses a particular industry or class of industries, the results obtained are argued to have more general validity.</description><creator>Heyes, Anthony G.</creator><contributor>Cairns, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Environmental protection -- Standards</subject><title>Three essays on the theory and practice of environmental standard-setting</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mp48sf28v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cz05z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q560w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines the situation and activities of Hindu temple women (devadasis) in the 9th-13th centuries, as revealed in Tamil inscriptions. These temple women, unlike their male counterparts or the devadasis of more recent times, were not primarily identified as temple servants, with professional expertise or ritual responsibilities, but were instead defined with reference to a particular status, predicated on relationship with a temple. This relationship was secured through the donations that temple women made to temples. In the course of the Chola period, the status of "temple woman" became increasingly well-defined and the numbers of temple women increased, while other types of women disappeared from public view. Temple women's strengthening links with--but marginal positions in--the temple are analyzed in this study with reference to the changes that occurred during this period in the structure of the temple and in the temple's position within the social environment.</description><creator>Orr, Leslie C.</creator><contributor>Young, Katherine K. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Women in Hinduism -- History</subject><subject>Hindu women -- India, South -- Religious life -- History</subject><subject>Devadāsīs -- India, South -- History</subject><title>Hindu temple women of the Chola period in south India</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jn011.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q560w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97ks00m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The literature of disturbance ecology reveals that, under present climatic conditions, non-native plants have little or no role in high arctic tundra revegetation. Rather, it has been suggested that indigenous flora, especially long-lived perennial graminoids, are crucial to recovery. However, few long-term data are available on past impacts within productive sedge-meadows in the High Arctic, and none which consider the non-vascular flora. This thesis combines biogeographical and patch dynamics perspectives to focus on $ geq$21 yr of natural and assisted recovery of vegetation and soils from a wide range of dated anthropogenic surface disturbances at three Canadian Arctic sites. Empirical, experimental and archival investigations were made among climatically similar, but widely disjunct, coastal lowlands of contrasting geologies on Baffin, Devon, and Cornwallis Islands. These data encompass minerotrophic and oligotrophic wetlands in which the vascular floras show minimal differentiation yet the sampled bryofloras share only 31.8% of their total taxa. The occurrences chosen for study are representative of the most widespread, small-scale human impacts in the North, including vehicular, pedestrian, construction, and pollution disturbances. It was determined that rutting from even a single passage of a tracked vehicle in summer resulted in significant reductions in species richness and biomass. On slopes $ geq$2$ sp circ$, these same small ruts have drained large areas of peatlands, a serious cumulative impact. Long-term effects of drainage include the local extinction of populations of Sphagnum spp. and rhizomatous vascular aquatics, and changes in the chemistry and thermal regime of drained mineral soils. Other effects include significant changes in biomass and the concentrations of macronutrients in the leaves of dominant species. These effects were magnified in peatlands drained where multi-pass vehicle movements occurred. Species richness displayed an inverse relationship with trampling intensity and the soils of heavily trampled ground remained severely compacted after 21 years. These patches were dominated by dense swards of ruderal grasses. Nutrient concentrations in the leaves of the latter and other colonizing and surviving species tended to increase with trampling intensity. Trampled patches and archaeological sites appeared selectively grazed by several herbivores. Although humans initiated the disturbances within these patches, it is the animals which are responsible for many of the dynamics of patch change over the long-term. Classification and ordination procedures revealed linkages between the floristic associations of trampled meadows on Baffin Island and archaeological sites on Devon and Cornwallis Islands. One critical implication is that even low levels of human impact may give rise to ruderal plant communities which are extremely persistent. These patches are poor in terms of species richness, but contribute to habitat heterogeneity at the landscape level and comprise preferred forage for local vertebrate herbivores. Archaeological excavation and restoration revealed that at least some stores of viable seed exist in both mesic and wet tundra soils and point to the importance of initial floristic composition (sensu Egler 1954). From a long-term perspective, the data establish that mesic tundra vegetation and soils are easily disturbed and recover much more slowly than their low arctic counterparts under similar disturbance regimes.</description><creator>Forbes, Bruce Cameron</creator><contributor>Wenzel, George W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Tundra plants -- Ecology -- Canada, Northern</subject><subject>Vegetation dynamics -- Canada, Northern</subject><subject>Plant succession -- Canada, Northern</subject><subject>Revegetation -- Canada, Northern</subject><title>Anthropogenic tundra disturbance and patterns of response in the eastern Canadian Arctic</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f7623f21s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97ks00m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rj582</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Groundwater quantity allocation and quality protection in Canada largely proceed in a fragmented fashion. Each jurisdiction pursues the management of its water resources and the aquatic environment separately as well as independently of other jurisdictions. This approach is at odds with the unity of the natural environment and the inter-connectedness of groundwater resources. The challenge facing Canada is to make the law recognize and be more responsive to the unity of the aquatic environment and water resources. An active federal role in uniting and coordinating the efforts of the provinces in this regard is crucial if this challenge is to be met. However, since the constitutional division of powers in Canada encourages a fragmented approach to managing environment and water resources, the federal government is incapacitated, purely on a legal score, with respect to pulling together the efforts of the provinces. A cooperative approach, based on political rather than legal coordination, is therefore, the most realistic option for the federal government to meet the challenge. In this work, the writer examines the various areas for federal-provincial cooperation regarding groundwater allocation and protection. Such institutional integration or cooperation cannot be effective unless groundwater is addressed together with the other component of the hydrologic cycle, namely: surface water and the ecosystem they support. At the same time, in adopting an integrated hydrologic cycle approach, specific groundwater management strategies canvassed in this work must be taken into account if groundwater is to be more efficiently allocated and protected. Pursuant to these considerations, this writer is of the opinion that groundwater resources in Canada should be managed in a way that meets both present and future needs of Canadians, thus in a sustainable fashion. This can best be achieved if resource management relies upon a combination of contaminant-focused and resource-focused approaches adopted under unified federal-provincial efforts as well as under an integrated hydrologic cycle management.</description><creator>Orie, Kenneth Kanu</creator><contributor>Brunnee, Jutta (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><subject>Law.</subject><title>Legal aspects of groundwater quantity allocation and quality protection in Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290c07b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rj582</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p186w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A novel and simple "constant-addition" technique was used to study calcite precipitation kinetics and the partitioning of REE between calcite overgrowths and their parent seawater solutions under steady state conditions. As a consequence of solute interactions in solution and at the growing mineral surface, the calcite precipitation mechanism in seawater is complex. It is dominated by the following reversible overall reaction: $ rm Ca sp{2+}+CO sbsp{3}{2-} rightleftharpoons CaCO sb3.$ A kinetic expression is proposed which describes the precipitation rate according to this reaction. A partial reaction order of 3 with respect to CO$ sb3 sp{2-}$ is obtained. REE have a strong affinity for calcite and substitute for Ca$ sp{2+}$. REE partition coefficients in calcite overgrowths were calculated from their concentrations in the overgrowths and their parent solutions using a non-thermodynamic homogeneous model. The concentrations were determined by chelation and gradient ion chromatography (CGIC) using a revised procedure. REE partition coefficients decrease gradually with increasing REE atomic number. They are sensitive to changes in (REE): (Ca$ sp{2+}$) and the presence of O$ sb2$ in solution, but unaffected by the precipitation rate, $ rm lbrack CO sb3 sp{2-} rbrack$ or Pco$ sb2$ of the solution. The partitioning behaviour of REE is negatively correlated to the solubility of their respective carbonates and influenced by speciation, adsorption, and subsequent surface reactions (e.g., dehydration).</description><creator>Zhong, Shaojun</creator><contributor>Mucci, Alfonso (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Physical Oceanography.</subject><subject>Geochemistry.</subject><title>Precipitation kinetics and partitioning of rare earth elements (REE) between calcite and seawater</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7m01bn32j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p186w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r261d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Verification of compliance has been and will continue to be an essential component of arms control and disarmament agreements. Following a brief historical survey of verification, this study examines in detail verification provisions in all major multilateral and bilateral disarmament agreements, in force and in the drafting stage, from the perspective of monitoring compliance by satellites. The feasibility of verification from space is examined from technical and legal points of view. Important differences are noted between bilateral and multilateral agreements in terms of verification requirements. The effectiveness of, as well as confidence in, the verification process, it is suggested, will be significantly enhanced if the monitoring is carried out by an organization in which all contracting states have a say in the planning and conduct of monitoring and participate in decision-making. This study analyzes various official and private recommendations for the establishment of such an organization, with special emphasis on the proposed International Satellite Monitoring Agency (ISMA) whose constitution, structure and functions are set out in a comprehensive report prepared by a United Nations group of experts. The ISMA could play, in the opinion of the author, an important auxiliary role in monitoring compliance with many existing disarmament agreements as well as with those currently in the drafting phase.</description><creator>Ushioda, Setsuko</creator><contributor>Vlasic, Ivan A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>Satellite-based multilateral arms control verification schemes and international law</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3n2040700.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r261d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cc42t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Previous results indicated that lactic acid bacteria (LAB) and Bacillus spores were the predominant spoilage microorganisms in minimally processed products after 35 days storage at 15$ sp circ$C. Furthermore, most packages were swollen due to carbon dioxide production by the LAB. The fact that spores survived mild heat treatment is of concern since it implies that other more pathogenic spores, e.g. Clostridium botulinum would also survive and may pose a public health problem in products stored at 15$ sp circ$C. As such, the influence of combination treatments (viz., mild heat processing treatment, pH, water activity, storage temperature, lactic acid bacteria) were evaluated through challenge studies with selected strains of C. botulinum type A, B, and E spores. The shelf life and safety of the products following a 13D process at 75$ sp circ$C, could be extended to $ ge$42 days by a combination of pH $ le$ 5.0 and storage at 5$ sp circ$C. Other combination treatments were also effective in controlling growth of, and toxin formation in the products by C. botulinum. For instance, botulinum toxin was not detected until day 35 in inoculated spaghetti and meat sauce products (pH 5.25 and a$ sb{w}$ 0.992) with type A and B spores and stored at 15$ sp circ$C. Shelf life extension and inhibition of toxin production was also possible through reductions in a$ sb{w}$ levels achieved by addition of 1-3% salt (w/w) to the products. Water activity levels of $ le$0.983 prevented botulinum toxin production in the minimally processed spaghetti and meat sauce product for $ ge$42 days during storage at 15$ sp circ$C. Similar trends were observed in sous-vide rice and salmon products. Furthermore, when sodium lactate was used as the humectant to lower the a$ sb{w}$ of this product, toxin production was also delayed, but not to the same extent as achieved with NaCl. When two strains of bacteriocin-producing lactic acid bacteria were co-inoculated separately in the sous-vide rice and salmon products that had been challenged with C. botulinum type E spores, toxin formation was only slightly delayed in products with added NaCl (1%), while toxin formation was neither delayed nor prevented in similarly lactic acid bacteria-treated samples with no added NaCl. Furthermore, in most of the products in which botulinum toxin was detected, spoilage preceded toxigenesis, however, in some samples stored at 5$ sp circ$C toxigenesis preceded spoilage. Addition of $ alpha$-2-macroglobulin at a level of 2.7 ppm did not delay or prevent toxin formation in the product. Microwave heating of products at half-power or full power (800 Watts) for 5 to 10 min proved effective in inactivating all of the pre-formed toxin in toxic samples. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Simpson, Marian V.</creator><contributor>Smith, J. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Food -- Packaging.</subject><subject>Protective atmospheres.</subject><subject>Food spoilage.</subject><subject>Food -- Cooling.</subject><title>Shelf life and microbiological safety studies on minimally processed, refrigerated "sous-vide" products</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kv41q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cc42t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97ks01w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents numerical studies of phase behavior for both thermotropic and lyotropic liquid crystals. The nature of the orientational transition in the Lebwohl-Lasher model for the nematic-isotropic phase transition is found to be weak first-order with the stability limits of the nematic and isotropic phases being extremely close to the equilibrium transition temperature. It is also found that the director fluctuations in the nematic phase correspond to fractional Brownian motion whereas the fluctuations in the isotropic phase follow ordinary Brownian motion. The Pink model is extended to give an accurate description of the main phase transition in lipid bilayers by introducing hydrophobic mismatch interactions between acyl chains and also direct inter-monolayer attractive interactions. The lateral density fluctuations and the resulting dynamic bilayer heterogeneity are studied. Lipid-protein interactions are further included to describe the phase separation of lipid-protein mixtures, gramicidin channel formation and the effects of protein on the lipid bilayers. A model is also proposed for phase transitions involving hydrogen bonding between the polar heads in lipid bilayers.</description><creator>Zhang, Zhengping, 1957-</creator><contributor>Zuckermann, Martin J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><title>Numerical studies of phase behavior in thermotropic and lyotropic liquid crystals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k0698900p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97ks01w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z708z25p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Thymidine dinucleoside 58 (TsT) and 62 containing a dialkyl sulfide or sulfone backbone, as well as thymidine and 2$ sp prime$-O-methyluridine dinucleoside 76 containing a dialkyl sulfide backbone have been synthesized. Dimer 58 has been shown to be easily incorporated into DNA by standard automated methodology giving oligomer 2. The synthesis of "5$ sp prime$-end unit" 49, "repeating unit" 33 and "3$ sp prime$-end unit" 54 and 71 are described. The 2-(trimethylsilyl)ethoxymethyl chloride (SEM) was used for the protection of imide group of uridine. The removal of the SEM group is similar to that of other silyl protecting groups and only needs a somewhat higher temperature. (Abstract shortened by UMI.) ftn*Please refer to the dissertation for diagrams.</description><creator>Wang, Daguang, 1958-</creator><contributor>Just, George (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Chemistry, Inorganic.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Synthesis of oligonucleotides containing a sulfide or sulfone backbone for binding &amp; nuclease stability studies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kv420.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708z25p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0z708z26z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Various generalizations of the Artin's Conjecture for primitive roots are considered. It is proven that for at least half of the primes p, the first log p primes generate a primitive root. A uniform version of the Chebotarev Density Theorem for the field ${ cal Q}( zeta sb{l},2 sp{1/l})$ valid for the range $l &lt; { rm log} x$ is proven. A uniform asymptotic formula for the number of primes up to x for which there exists a primitive root less than s is established. Lower bounds for the exponent of the class group of imaginary quadratic fields valid for density one sets of discriminants are determined.</description><creator>Pappalardi, Francesco</creator><contributor>Murty, Ram (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1993</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>On Artin's conjecture for primitive roots</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773x24v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0z708z26z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hh63sx403</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Application of potassium chloride (KCl) to a brain surface, a procedure which consistently elicits spreading depression, resulted in a marked induction of the proto-oncogene c-fos in the treated cerebral cortex in a rapid and transient manner. Most of the cerebral cortex throughout the treated hemisphere showed an increase in c-fos-like immunoreactivity (IR). The only area spared was that immediately below the exposed surface. On the other hand, ubiquitin-like IR appeared to increase in pyramidal-shaped cells in the damaged area as early as 90 minutes and persisted up to 2 days after treatment. Mechanical cortical brain injury was accompanied by a similar widespread expression of c-fos protein(s) throughout the wounded cortex even far from the lesion site. Rats with a mechanical cortical injury, which were sacrificed 1.5 hours later, showed an increase in c-fos immunoreactive nuclei in the piriform cortex ipsilateral to the lesion at post-natal day (PD) 22, but not PD 10 or 15. This pattern was maintained up to at least PD 90. Similarly, the presence of c-fos IR cells was observed in the ipsilateral cingulate cortex since PD 22. The pattern of c-fos expression after mechanical wound was compared with topical potassium application to a cortical surface. Though both models generated c-fos expression far from the lesion site, K+ application resulted in a higher number of c-fos immunoreactive cells, particularly in the cingulate cortex. High potassium concentrations are generally used to induce neurotransmitter release. In order to establish a possible link between c-fos expression and stimulating conditions for neurotransmitter release in microdialysis procedures, we administered KCl (100 mM) into the hippocampus. C-fos-like IR was up regulated in the dentate gyrus and pyramidal cells of the hippocampus. The expression of c-fos induced by KCl was not altered in the animals with fimbria-fornix (FF) lesions despite the marked decrease of ACh releaae in the hippocampus. Glutamate concentrations measured in the same superfusates showed that a significantly greater glutamate release occurs in denervated hippocampi. Administration of pentobarbital (1ml/kg i.p.) in order to abolish any seizure-like activity induced by KCl, did not alter expression of c-fos IR in the K$ sp+$-stimulated hippocampi. The topical application of high K$ sp+$ concentrations to a brain surface (parietal cortex), which induced c-fos expression, preceded an increase in both NGF mRNA and NGF-like protein(s). A maximal increase in c-fos was detected within 3 hours, whereas NGF mRNA levels peaked at 12 hours and NGF-like protein(s) reached its maximum at 24 hours after KCl application. The most prominent increase in NGF mRNA was measured in the entorhinal cortex (50 fold) but it was also moderately increased in other cortical areas (2-3 fold). Application of K+ to the cortex induced the expression of glial fibrillary acidic protein (GFAP) in astrocytes, as assessed by immunohistochemical techniques, throughout the cortex ipsilateral to K+ exposure. Administration of the non- competitive NMDA antagonist MX-801 (4mg/kg i.p.) prior to the injury prevented the rise in GFAP IR at 2 but not 7 days after the treatment. GFAP IR was also studied after disruption of a restricted area of the pia-arachnoid which compromises vascular irrigation of the underlying cortex. GFAP+ cells were present in the ipsilateral remaining cortex, distant from the wound, between days 4 and 15. These findings suggest selective changes in gene expression following different types of cortical brain injury. The interpretation of these observations is given in the discussion of this thesis.</description><creator>Herrera, Daniel Gustavo</creator><contributor>Cuello, A. Claudio (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Neurochemical correlates of cortical brain injury in the rat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w901n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hh63sx403</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v703g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We have shown that nine cDNA clones, which were derived from an oligo (dT) primed cDNA library of human embryonic lung fibroblast (IMR90), are capable of supporting autonomous replication of bacterial plasmid in mammalian (HeLa) cells. Two of these cDNA clones contain a region homologous to "O"-family middle repetitive sequences; the other seven clone hybridize with neither "O"-family nor Alu family sequences and are called NOA clones. Oligo (dT) primed cDNA of IMR90 has been demonstrated to be an enriched source for autonomously replicating sequences. Two out of three "O"-family homologous cDNA clones and seven out of ten NOA clones were capable of autonomous replication. In contrast, none of the five clones, which contained Alu repetitive sequences, demonstrated replicative potential. The two autonomously replicating, "O"-family homologous cDNA, 343 and 363, were characterized in the greatest detail. In particular, sequence and structural features of a 448 bp fragment of cDNA 343, which was capable of supporting autonomous replication activity, were: extensive asymmetrical A/T-rich regions; 10/11 match to yeast ARS consensus; scaffold attachment region consensus of Drosophila; bent DNA; a DNA unwinding element and an in vitro matrix binding activity. We have used a PCR-based mapping strategy to identify an in vivo initiation zone located in a region of approximately 1.6 kb which is inclusive of cDNA 343. The 343 sequence has been localized to the long arm (6q22-6qter) of human chromosome 6 by both Southern analysis of hamster-human cell hybrids and in situ hybridization. Transcripts homologous to 343 have been detected in both poly(A$ sp+$) and non-poly(A$ sp+$) RNA fractions to be 1.3 kb and 5 kb, respectively; the 1.3 kb transcript is greatly enriched in poly(A$ sp+$) RNA fraction, and the 5 kb transcript is present predominantly in non-poly(A$ sp+$) RNA fraction. The detailed characterization of 343 genomic locus demonstrated that the 343 sequence is conserv</description><creator>Wu, Cunle</creator><contributor>Price, Gerald B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>cDNA clones contain autonomously replicating sequences</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v4598.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v703g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977w58s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The under-representation of women in science-related fields has serious economic and social implications as Canada is confronted by a shortage of scientists especially in engineering and the applied sciences. The purpose of this study was to investigate similarities and differences between second-year female college students (N = 79) who intend to pursue pure and applied sciences (PAS), and their male counterparts (N = 81), and between PAS females and females who intend to pursue health sciences (HS) (N = 85). The study investigated the relative importance of motivational, self-concept-related, and sociopsychological variables on women's science college majors. The following measures were administered once: (1) Educational Aspiration Questionnaire, (2) Mastery Scale (Farmer, 1981), (3) Strong-Campbell Interest Inventory (Hansen &amp; Campbell, 1985), (4) Ability and Effort Attribution Measure (Farmer, 1981), (5) Attitudes Toward Women Scale (Spence, Helmreich &amp; Stapp, 1973), (6) Parent, Teacher, and Counsellor Support Scales, respectively (Farmer, 1981). The Stated Occupational Questionnaire was administered twice, three months apart. Results indicated that females in PAS had more liberal attitudes toward women, had more interests in medical sciences and services, and had fewer interests in mechanical activities and physical sciences than the males. However, the overall statistical analyses indicated far more similarities than differences between females and males in PAS, and also between females in PAS and HS except in the area of measured interests. While further research on the above variables over time is warranted, these findings have important implications for counselling psychologists.</description><creator>Tarquinio-Mammone, Susan</creator><date>1992</date><subject>Counseling in higher education</subject><subject>Women in science</subject><title>Factors influencing women's selection of science college majors : a counselling perspective</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tt44pp46n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977w58s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fj68m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The surface properties of quaternized poly(styrene-block-4-vinylpyridinium) AB block copolymers in monolayers spread at the air/water interface were thoroughly studied using the Langmuir film balance technique and microscopy techniques (i.e. transmission electron microscopy and atomic force microscopy). The effects of both molecular structure (i.e. chain lengths of the two blocks, alkyl chain length, and the counterion of the quaternizing agent) and the experimental parameters (i.e. measurement temperatures, salt species and salt concentrations in the aqueous subphase, compression rates, and hysteresis) on interfacial behaviour of the ionic block copolymers were explored. Optimum conditions for the deposition of polymer monolayers from a water surface to a solid substrate for the microscopy studies were also investigated. Evidence for novel surface micelle formation is presented. Three morphologies of surface micelles (i.e. plane, rod, and starfish) are identified for the block copolymers. The appearance of each morphology is found to be related only to the relative chain lengths of the two blocks. Methods of calculating aggregation numbers in starfish micelles are developed. A phase transition phenomenon is observed in surface pressure-area isotherms of the polymer monolayers. This phase transition is found to be related to the pressure-induced solubilization process of the quaternized poly(4-vinylpyridinium) hydrophilic block chains. A model of a starfish-to-jellyfish transition is introduced to describe this phase transition phenomenon.</description><creator>Zhu, Jiayi</creator><contributor>Lennox, R. Bruce (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Eisenberg, Adi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1992</date><subject>Chemistry, General.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>Interfacial behaviour of ionic block copolymers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jz784.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fj68m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cf95jc903</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Oil was extracted from chicken and pork fat discards by microwave assisted extraction and soxhlet extraction for comparison. Protease enzyme and pulsed electric field were used as a pretreatment prior to extraction by either soxhlet or microwave assisted extraction by hexane. Conditions for both the enzyme pretreatment and the microwave extraction were optimized for the extraction of the oils from the discards. The fat discards were pretreated with papain enzyme in a phosphate buffer solution (pH 7.0) and incubated at 45oC in a water bath and incubated at various time intervals (30 min, 1 h, 2 h and 3 h). Enzyme pretreatment at 2 h produced the highest oil yield increase of 20.1% when compared to the control samples (P=0.0003) in chicken samples and an oil yield increase of 16.6% in comparison to control samples (P=0.0179) in pork samples. There was a decrease in oil yield at 3 h and no significant difference in oil yield when compared to control in both chicken samples (P=0.217) and pork samples (P=1.0000). Optimization of microwave assisted process shows that microwave irradiation for 7.5 min produced the best oil yield and was the most effective in oil extraction from the animal discards. There was no significant difference in oil yield produced when the irradiation time was increased to 10 min, 12.5 min, and 15min. The results obtained from optimization of microwave assisted extraction were comparable to those obtained by soxhlet extraction for 3 hr. There were significant difference between oil yield obtained from both extraction methods (P=&lt;0.05). There were no differences in the FAME profile when compared to the literature. Pulsed electric field pretreatments were carried out on pork samples at electric field strength of 2 kV cm-1, 4 kV cm-1, 6 kV cm-1. The oil yields obtained were compared to values obtained from control samples after extraction using microwave assisted extraction for 3 min. Pulsed electric field at 4 kV cm-1 produced an oil yield increas</description><description>Les matières grasses des déchets associés au parage provenant des industries porcine et avicole ont été extraites par l’utilisation d’une extraction assistée par les microondes et par une méthode standard, la méthode Soxhlet. Deux prétraitements, l’hydrolyse enzymatique et le champ pulsé, ont été utilisés avant l’extraction à l’hexane des matières grasses. Les conditions d’application du prétraitement enzymatique et de l’extraction assistée par les microondes ont été optimisées pour maximiser l’extraction à partir des matières grasses rejetées par l’industrie. Les déchets gras ont été prétraités avec une protéase, la papaïne, dans un tampon phosphate (pH 7.0) et incubés à 45oC dans un bain-marie pour des intervalles de temps variés (30min, 1 h, 2 h et 3h). Les augmentations les plus importantes de l’extraction des matières grasses ont été obtenues avec le prétraitement enzymatique des échantillons de volaille (20.1%, P=0.0003) et de porc (16.6%, P=0.0179) pour une durée de 2 h lorsque comparé aux échantillons témoins. Une diminution du rendement de l’extraction a été notée lors du traitement enzymatique d’une durée de 3h sans que ces valeurs montrent des différences significatives avec les échantillons témoins de volaille (p=0.217) et de porc (P=1.000). L’optimisation du procédé d’extraction par microonde a montré que l’irradiation avec les microondes pendant 7.5 min a produit les meilleurs rendements d’extraction. Aucune différence significative n’a été retrouvée lorsque les échantillons ont été soumis à l’irradiation pour des temps accrus à 10 min, 12.5 min et 15 min. Les résultats obtenus pour l’optimisation de l’extraction assistée par les microondes sont comparables à ceux obtenus par l’extraction pendant 3 h avec la méthode Soxhlet. Des différences significatives de rendement en matières grasses ont été obtenues avec les deux méthodes d’extracti</description><creator>Amusan, Anuoluwapo</creator><contributor>Benjamin K Simpson (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Leroy E Phillip (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Agriculture - Food Science and Technology</subject><title>Optimization of oil extraction procedures from animal tissue</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nz806143f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jc903</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x346d578c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>RÉSUMÉ Nous avons déterminé la localisation de l'actine ainsi que de la myosine I (Myo5) et de la septine (Cdc12) modifiées avec la protéine fluorescente verte (GFP) chez Candida albicans en phase opaque (reproductive) et blanche (végétative). Plus particulièrement, nous avons porté notre attention sur les processus associé à la reproduction tel le bourgeonnement et l'expansion cellulaire (shmoo), la conjugaison et la fusion cellulaire, le bourgeonnement et le développement des zygotes (cellules -filles issues de la conjugaison). Nous avons aussi observé la configuration subcellulaire de Myo5p, Cdc12p et de l’actine lors de la migration et de la division nucléaire en phase blanche. Que ce soit en phase opaque ou en phase blanche, la localisation de Myo5p, Cdc12p et de l'actine reste similaire lors du bourgeonnement. Lors d’une stimulation à la phéromone, en phase opaque, ces trois protéines ont le même patron d’organisation cellulaire que lors de la formation d'hyphes en phase blanche. Les cellules de type MTLa produisent des shmoo entre 5 et 7 heures plus tôt que les cellules de type MTLα dans une population mixte. Dans les zygotes, Cdc12p, Myo5p et l'actine ont la même localisation que celle observée dans les cellule-filles issues du bourgeonnement en mode végétatif. Étonnamment, l'isogénicité du locus génétique déterminant le type sexuel de la cellule influence la position du noyau lors de la division; Ainsi, dans 70% des cas, le noyau des cellules de type MTLa se divise à l'intérieur de la cellule-mère plutôt qu'au travers du col entre la cellule-mère et le bourgeon.</description><description>ABSTRACT  We followed the localization of GFP-tagged myosin I (Myo5), septin (Cdc12) and  rhodamin-stained actin during bud and shmoo formation in opaque-phase cells of  Candida albicans, and monitored the mating-associated processes of cell fusion, zygote  budding, septum formation, daughter cell development and the dynamics of nuclear  migration and division. The localization of Myo5p, Cdc12p and actin during budding in  opaque and white cells is similar.  In pheromone-stimulated cells, these proteins localize  in shmoos in patterns consistent with hyphal formation in white-phase cells. MTLa cells  generate shmoos 5-7 hours earlier than MTLα cells in mixed populations.  In the daughter  cell generated after mating, Cdc12p, Myo5p and actin localize as they do under  vegetative budding conditions. Intriguingly, isogenicity for the mating type locus is  involved in the positioning of the nuclear division; in MTLa cells the nucleus divides  within the mother cell up to 70% of the time, rather than across the mother-bud neck.</description><creator>Kachurina, Nadezda</creator><contributor>Monique Zetka (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Malcolm Whiteway (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Cell</subject><title>Morphogenesis of opaque form «Candida albicans» cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mg74qn550.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d578c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cv57p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The design and mechanical performance of a helicopter horizontal stabilizer slat made by resin transfer moulding (RTM) can be evaluated with finite element analysis (FEA). To verify the validity of the assumptions used in the modelling of the slat structure, static mechanical tests were performed on prototype slats which were half of the full-size length. The slat complex boundary conditions were simplified to make static mechanical testing possible. Two fixtures were designed and built to introduce simplified loads in specimens with two different bracket configurations: a full and a half bracket. A finite element (FE) model of the specimens was made with shell elements and the finite element solution was compared with the experimental results. In most cases, comparison between the finite element analysis solution and experimental results showed good agreement in terms of structure stiffness, strength, strain and damage location. It is believed that out-of-plane stresses should be considered to improve the finite element solution accuracy.</description><description>Le design et la performance mécanique d’un bec de bord d’attaque de stabilisateur horizontal d’hélicoptère fabriqué par moulage par injection sur renfort (« resin transfer moulding ») peuvent être évalués par des analyses par éléments finis. Pour vérifier la validité des hypothèses utilisées dans la modélisation du bec de bord d’attaque, des essais mécaniques ont été effectués sur des prototypes demi-longueurs. Les conditions frontières complexes ont été simplifiées pour rendre les essais mécaniques possibles. Deux gabarits ont été conçus et construits pour introduire les chargements simplifiés dans les pièces d’essai possédant deux configurations de support: un support complet et un demi-support. Un modèle par éléments finis des pièces d’essai a été réalisé avec des éléments de type membrane et la solution est comparée avec les résultats expérimentaux. Dans la plupart des cas, la comparaison entre la solution par éléments finis et les résultats expérimentaux coïncide concernant la rigidité de la structure, la résistance, l’allongement et la localisation de l’endommagement. Les contraintes hors du plan devraient être considérées pour améliorer la précision de la solution par éléments finis.</description><creator>Roy, Steven</creator><contributor>Larry Lessard (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Aerospace</subject><title>Mechanical modeling and testing of a composite helicopter structure made by resin transfer moulding</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cf88k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cv57p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bd279</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:12:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We establish a criterion on potential energy functions which, when satisﬁed, asserts the existence of an inﬁnite number of periodic orbits in a dynamical system deﬁned by two particles moving on the two-dimensional (or “ﬂat”) torus. The original system is reduced to that of a single point-mass moving about the torus, for which we ﬁnd a continuum of tra jectories satisfying a particular symmetry relation. Using a system of Poincar´e maps, we obtain addition information about a particular subset of these tra jectories in order to describe their behaviour in a linear portion of the space. Finally, we show under certain additional assumptions that, for any suﬃciently large two-dimensional torus, a countably inﬁnite subset of these tra jectories are periodic.</description><description>On établisse un critère sur les fonctions d’énergie potentielle qui, quand satisfait, aﬃrme l’existence d’un nombre inﬁni d’orbites d’un système dynamique de deux particules en se déplaçant autour du tore de deux dimensions. On réduit le système d’origine au système d’un point de masse qui se déplace autour du tore, duquel on trouve un continuum de tra jectoires qui satisfait à un rapport particulier de symétrie. En utilisant un système de cartes de Poincaré, on apprend davantage d’un sous-ensemble particulier de ses trajectoires pour décrire leur comportement dans une partie linéaire de l’espace. Enﬁn, on démontre, selon certaines hypothèses, que pour n’importe quel tore assez grand de deux dimensions, un sous-ensemble inﬁni dénombrable est périodique.</description><creator>Maye, Steven</creator><contributor>Paul Frederick Tupper (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Pure Sciences - Mathematics</subject><title>Periodic orbits in systems of two non-rigid particles on the torus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257g64v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bd279</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):29550</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>