<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:40:26Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):39350" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514nn23k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, we have attempted to bring to the fore the existence of a tacit or explicit link between the descriptions of works of art and the love relationships depicted in several of Marguerite Yourcenar's works of fiction. We start with the premise that the work of art with which the protagonist associates his beloved represents either the perception he has of the latter, or the power relationship implicit in their union. In that perspective, we explore the use of simile and metaphor as well as that of mythological figures and certain elements of neoplatonic philosophy. Each of the three chapters is dedicated to a specific form of art (statuary, painting, and music) with which the protagonist establishes a connection either between the person he is emotionally involved with, or the love he feels for him/her. For the purposes of our analysis, we have referred to studies on narcissism, as well as critical texts dealing with the relationship between writing and painting and with the function of music in literature; for the analysis of narrative point of view and focalization, we are primarily indebted to the work of Gerard Genette.</description><creator>Di Giorgio, Virginie.</creator><contributor>Everett, Jane (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Yourcenar, Marguerite -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Art in literature.</subject><title>L'art comme reflet des relations amoureuses chez Yourcenar</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913r70f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nn23k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4q77ft331</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Investigating the concepts of qi and mai and their functions in the oldest extant, recently excavated, second century BCE practice-oriented guides to pulse taking, moxibustion, and needling practices, this thesis aims to show the prominent influence of water imagery and suggests a way to conceptualize its significance. These texts can be seen as transitional in the development of acupuncture, whose later practice would involve use of metal needles and be almost exclusively associated with the cosmological concepts of yin yang and wu xing and circular movements of qi that reached popularity in the Qin and Han dynasties and attested in the oldest and most famous Chinese medical compilation, also of the Han, the Huangdi neijing . In contrast, the paradigm of water, with its unidirectional free flows, is what informs these early medical manuscripts' understanding of qi and mai and their physiological movements.</description><creator>Daly, Nigel Peter.</creator><contributor>Yates, Robin D. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>History, Asia, Australia and Oceania.</subject><subject>History of Science.</subject><title>Hybridizing the human body : the hydrological development of acupuncture in early Imperial China</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5138jg76n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4q77ft331</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of East Asian Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k643b306t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to determine whether the ability to perceive pitch direction across a variety of melodic contours differs across grade levels. In addition, differences between responses to ascending versus descending patterns and between responses to two- versus three- versus four-note patterns were examined. The main study involved two experiments; Experiment 1 examined children's ability to identify pitch direction using a visual aid; Experiment 2 examined children's spontaneous notations of the same melodic contours. The results showed a subsequent increase in mean scores from grades 1 to 6 across both tests. The clearest increase in ability occurred within the first three grades with a plateau reached by grade four. Same-pitch patterns received the highest overall means. The ability to identify direction using a visual aid was easier for children than to write spontaneous notations. Melodic contours with larger intervals were more easily perceived.</description><creator>Descombes, Valérie.</creator><contributor>Costa-Giomi, Eugenia (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Musical ability -- Testing.</subject><subject>Musical pitch.</subject><title>Discrimination of pitch direction : a developmental study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wf64g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b306t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kc54v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In recent years, home modification has played an increasingly important role in the housing industry. Expenditures on renovation have consistently exceeded those spent on new home construction during the 1990s. And it has huge potential to continuously increase in the years to come. Renovators' do-it-yourself activities are efficient ways to fulfill homeowners' psychological and physical needs and save expensive labour costs. This research investigates not only the technology evolution of ten products and the installation processes that are frequently used by renovators, but also the fundamental reasons that drive the development of these innovations. It covers the technology from the beginning of this century to the latest innovations developed by manufactures in the 1990s. Additionally, it documents recent national and Quebec renovation market trends, together with three post-occupancy studies which had been conducted in the Montreal Area. The study reveals that many of the products and installation process have been greatly simplified and innovations in the renovation market could benefit renovators by allowing them to undertake modifications themselves. Also, the author suggests certain guidelines for increasing housing affordability and new products development.</description><creator>Ou, Yangli, 1968-</creator><contributor>Friedman, Avi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Dwellings -- Remodeling -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal -- Case studies.</subject><subject>Building materials -- Technological innovations.</subject><subject>Dwellings -- Remodeling.</subject><title>The evolution of prefabricated interior components for post-occupancy modification /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q607k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kc54v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p223t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis investigates how female-headed households solve their housing needs. Housing is an important resource for them: first because women spend more time in the house and home conditions are of great concern to them because these determine the time and difficulties in fulfilling their domestic responsibilities and, second, because the home is the site of production and economic activities that help increase women's low incomes. The study is based on the analysis of different women's lives in three different neighborhoods in Medellin, Colombia. This is a qualitative study aimed at providing insight into household patterns, and determining housing alternatives. The prevalence of female-headed households varies greatly among countries, particularly in the developing regions, and, in recent years, these have emerged as the subject of social concern. As the availability of data increases it becomes clear that these households are heterogeneous and not a uniform group (as previously assumed) in terms of marital status, life cycles and socioeconomic conditions. For this reason, their heterogeneity needs to be taken into consideration in policy formulation.</description><creator>Restrepo R., Jannette.</creator><contributor>Bhatt, Vikram (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Women heads of households -- Housing -- Colombia -- Medellin -- Case studies.</subject><title>Female-headed households and their homes : the case of Medellin, Colombia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r2914.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p223t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hf03k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Walden (1854), by the American author Henry David Thoreau (1817--1862), is explored as a work of literature with significant implications for environmental ethics in contemporary architectural practice. This reading challenges ethical models which depend for their legitimacy on determining a static representation of the world around us. Thoreau's literary discussion of the construction of his shelter and the subsequent revealing of a view of nature is offered as a more complete approach to finding a significant discourse concerning the relationship between humanity and the earth. The relevance of the poetic imagination is asserted through exploring the many aspects of the metaphors of verticality and flight in Walden . Thoreau's effort is extended into a brief discussion of Australian architect Glenn Murcutt (born 1936) and a consideration of the natural world in light of the phenomenon of a gift.</description><creator>Sandstra, Theodore.</creator><contributor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Murcutt, Glenn -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Architecture -- Environmental aspects.</subject><subject>Thoreau, Henry David, 1817-1862. Walden.</subject><title>A framework for the love of nature : Henry David Thoreau's construction of the Wild in Walden and the gift as an ethos for architecture</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kq05v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hf03k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m371j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A study of Salomon de Caus' manuscript commentary on the first book of Jean Martin's French translation of Vitruvius (c. 1622--1624) which takes the form of a dialogue between an Architect, an Engineer and a Mathematician. The removal of music and natural philosophy from the Vitruvion program of education; the need for the updating of Vitruvius' classical theory of founding cities and building their fortified walls; the emphasis on convenience in the planning of buildings and the separation of engineering and architecture within the Vitruvion corpus all point to a reduction in the role of architecture as cosmic analogy. A comparison with de Caus' treatises on perspective, mechanics, musical harmony, solar clocks and mensuration reveal that for de Caus, it is the engineer whose making can reconcile human and divine through a form of technical know-how that although it cannot be considered true knowledge, reveals the wonder of God to the senses.</description><creator>Spriggs, Megan.</creator><contributor>Perez-Gomez, Alberto (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Caus, Salomon de, d. 1626.</subject><subject>Vitruvius Pollio. Architecture, ou, Art de bien bastir, de Marc Vitruue Pollion ...</subject><title>Fabrique et discours : Salomon de Caus and the Vitruvian ideal of architecture</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580p42p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m371j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Architecture</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Architecture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:707959572</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Activation of the cystic fibrosis transmembrane regulator (CFTR) chloride channel by protein kinases has been studied intensively. The mechanism of deactivation by protein phosphatases has received less attention, although it is equally important for physiological regulation of the channel. Characterization and identification of the phosphatases that regulate CFTR has become a priority in CF research because they are potential targets for pharmacotherapies. The first goal of this project was to characterize the effects of purified phosphatases on single CFTR channels. I found that PP2A, PP2C and alkaline phosphatase all reduced channel activity in excised patches. PP1 and PP2B did not deactivate CFTR, despite having comparable phosphatase activity when assayed biochemically using a standard substrate. Deactivation by exogenous PP2C closely resembled the spontaneous rundown induced by endogenous phosphatase in CHO, BHK, and T84 cells. Genistein and bromotetramisole (Br-t) have been proposed to activate CFTR by inhibiting phosphatases. The second goal of this project was to assess the role of phosphatases in CFTR activation by these drugs. Genistein did not affect phosphatase activities. By contrast Br-t inhibited all four types phosphatases (PP1, PP2A, PP2B and PP2C). Thus Br-t may activate the channel by inhibiting its dephosphorylation whereas genistein probably acts directly on CFTR. These studies provide functional evidence that PP2C is the predominant phosphatase regulating CFTR, and clarify the role of phosphatases in CFTR activation by genistein and bromotetramisole.</description><creator>Luo, Jiexin, 1968-</creator><contributor>Hanrahan, John W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Regulation of the CFTR CI- channel by protein phosphatases</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021h10h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/707959572</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42n980g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The case-crossover design is a new epidemiological method that evolved around binary exposures and the binomial distribution. We develop a new approach of data analysis for this design based on the actual exposure occurrence times, such as those available from computerized prescription databases. Assuming an exponential distribution for the inter-exposure onset times, we derive two new matched-paired estimators of the odds-ratio, one weighted the other unweighted. A simulation study demonstrates that both new estimators based on the exponential distribution are more efficient than the classical estimator based on the binomial distribution and that the unweighted estimator appears to be the most valid. These new estimators of the odds-ratio are also more flexible and amenable to verifying some of the assumptions behind the case-crossover design. We illustrate this approach with data on 54 asthma deaths identified from the Saskatchewan Health databases, to assess the association with the use of inhaled beta-agonists.</description><creator>Cai, Bing.</creator><contributor>Suissa, Samy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacy.</subject><title>The case-crossover design : an efficient rate ratio estimator based on prescription times</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dr454.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42n980g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322g22p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The technology that governs the Telecommunications today is based on the Intelligent Networks (IN). But we can see that the Internet Telephony is emerging rapidly and that it has good chances to become the basis for the next generation telecommunication networks. There are two major competing standards for Internet Telephony - H.323 protocol stack and SIP. This thesis focuses on SIP and the Value Added Services in the SIP based Internet Telephony. It describes and analyzes two existing SIP based approaches to the VAS implementation and presents new hybrid SIP-IN approach based on the concept of reusing the existing IN nodes. The major part of the study is devoted to the design of a lightweight protocol, built as SIP extension, providing for VAS in the hybrid SIP-IN environment. To illustrate the hybrid SIP-IN approach to VAS implementation and the SIPext protocol operation the execution of the Freephone and the Call Distribution services is described. Finally the functional modules supporting the SIPext communication in a hybrid SIP-IN architecture are outlined.</description><creator>Evloguieva, Evelina.</creator><contributor>Dini, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Githo, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Light-weight SIP protocol for internet telephony services</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322g23z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322g22p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf268703c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study shows that mice homozygous for the disrupted renal sodium-phosphate (Na+-Pi) cotransporter, Npt2, (Npt2 KO) failed to show an age-dependent decrease in renal Na+-Pi cotransport or an adaptive increase in renal Na+-Pi cotransport in response to dietary Pi restriction. None of the other known renal Na+ -Pi cotransporters could compensate for the loss of Npt2. Additionally, Npt2 gene ablation resulted in a marked decrease in osteoclast number that persisted with age. Although mineral apposition rate was normal at 25- and 115-days of age in Npt2 KO mice, bone formation rate was increased at 115-days of age. These data demonstrate that Npt2 gene expression is necessary for an age-dependent decrease in renal Na+-Pi cotransport and for the renal adaptive response to dietary Pi deprivation, and that Npt2 expression is essential for normal osteoclast function and influences bone formation.</description><creator>Hoag, Hannah M.</creator><contributor>Tenenhouse, Harriet S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Sodium cotransport systems.</subject><subject>Mice -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Hypophosphatemia, Familial.</subject><title>Characterization of the renal and the bone phenotypes of the Npt2 knock out mouse</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r507z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf268703c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278w132</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation (APEC) is a regional economic forum composed of 21 member economies of diverse cultural heritage and varying levels of economic development. By deliberately avoiding to become a formalized free trade arrangement like the EU or the NAFTA, APEC has committed to the principle of "open regionalism", meaning that liberalization achievements are not preferential to APEC members only. APEC has evolved rapidly since its formation in 1989. Begun as an informal dialogue group, APEC has expanded to become the primary vehicle for promoting open trade and economic cooperation in the Asia-Pacific region. APEC is also one of the few multilateral economic organizations that actively embraces China as a committed partner in the global trade and investment dialogue. Economic reform and open door policies implemented over the last two decades have transformed China from a closed economy into a major trading power. China, which for more than a decade has unsuccessfully sought to join the GATT/WTO, finds APEC to be of immense symbolic and practical value. As a major member of APEC, China has made constructive role in the APEC process. With its dynamic economic growth and continuing economic reforms, China is poised to play an even greater role in APEC in the near future.</description><creator>Shen, Hong, 1967-</creator><contributor>de Mestral, A. L. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>Economic integration in APEC and the role of China</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p0969090.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278w132</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vm40xt667</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the moral, ethical and legal aspects of reproductive human cloning. After examining the facts about cloning, this thesis tackles the difficult question of whether humans should be cloned. This is explored through an in-depth analysis of the moral and ethical acceptability of human cloning. The author concludes that human cloning should never be attempted and that consequently such a practice should be permanently prohibited by a legal norm. This thesis then surveys national legislation and international law to see if there presently exists a prohibition of human cloning. This thesis then examines possible future legal action regarding human cloning and suggests a legislative scheme. Finally, possible constitutional challenges to future Canadian legislation prohibiting human cloning are analyzed. This analysis focuses on the right to liberty and the right to security of the person entrenched in section 7 and the right to equality embodied in section 15 of the Canadian Charter of Rights and Freedoms. The author concludes that such challenges would likely be unsuccessful.</description><creator>Yiannakis, Eleni.</creator><contributor>Somerville, M. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Philosophy.</subject><subject>Law.</subject><title>Human reproductive cloning community, identity, stability : reinventing creation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q8155.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vm40xt667</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns0647694</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Private international law stipulates that copyright is subject to the so-called principle of territoriality. Substantive conflicts of laws as well as procedural conflicts of jurisdictions regulating copyright are said to operate territorially; i.e., confined to the jurisdiction where protection is claimed. Copyright, however, is a universally valid proprietary right acquired in the legal regime of the country of the literary or artistic work's origin. The "monopolies of exploitation" that ultimately protect copyright are territorially confined because they are the result of the territoriality of laws and statutes. This thesis, therefore, introduces a new reading of the private international law of copyright. Copyright, like any other property right, should be understood in systems of real rights transpositions, which adapt its underlying proprietary title to the terms of the respective legal order of protection.</description><creator>Wiese, Volker.</creator><contributor>Glenn, H. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Political Science, International Law and Relations.</subject><title>Deconstructing the dogma of territoriality: a new approach to the private international law of copyright through the theory of transposition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wp988m98s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns0647694</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225c90z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Containerization, a technical innovation for transport initiated in late 1950s, has invigorated the evolution of the shipping industry. The shipping rules hence need to be restructured to keep abreast of the times, especially those enacted prior to the era of containerization (the Hague Rules 1924). The thesis presents and discusses the carrier's liability in containerized transport under the current shipping rules, comparing particularly the regimes of the United States and Taiwan, both of which still apply the Hague Rules. A subsidiary examination is extended to the MTO's liability in multimodal transport, which has an essential correlation with containerization.</description><creator>Wei, Chia-Lee, 1971-</creator><contributor>Tetley, William (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Law.</subject><subject>Transportation.</subject><title>Changes in the sea carrier's liability for cargo as a result of containerization and multimodalism (U.S. and Taiwanese law)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gm79k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225c90z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vd66w162t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is estimated that approximately 80% of all persons with DM2 are obese, and the prevalence of diabetes increases With increasing age and body weight. Intensive control resulting in near-normal glycemia in obese DM2 holds great potential for reducing morbidity and mortality, but is associated with weight gain. In turn, modest weight loss improves glycemia considerably. Current weight loss programs, with decreasing frequency of interventions over time, result in a weight loss pattern of a U-shaped curve indicating an inability in maintaining the lower weight. We hypothesized that increasing vs decreasing frequency of treatment visits over time would result in better weight loss and metabolic control. Forty-eight DM2 subjects (28 F, 20 M; wt = 98 +/- 3 kg; BMI = 35 +/- 2 kg/m2; DM duration = 11 +/- 8 yrs) were stratified according to weight and level of glycated hemoglobin (HbA1c), and randomized to one of two protocols: decreasing frequency (DF) of visits, seen weekly (for 2 mos), bimonthly (for 3 mos) and monthly (for 3 mos) and increasing frequency (IF) of visits seen in the reverse order. Visits included 18 lifestyle, behaviour modification, group sessions and 5 individual evaluations at 0, 2, 4, 8 and 12 months. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Venuta, Tina.</creator><contributor>Yale, Jean-Fracois (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Gougeon, Rejeanne (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Weight loss.</subject><subject>Non-insulin-dependent diabetes.</subject><subject>Obesity.</subject><title>Influence of visit frequency in a group intervention for weight loss in obese persons with type 2 diabetes mellitus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d183p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w162t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5m60qt94w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fifteen mutants of Sinorhizobium (Rhizobium ) meliloti unable to utilize acetate as a sale carbon source (Ace-) were characterized in this study. Merodiploid complementation tests showed that nine of these mutations were in loci distinct from previously described gluconeogenic loci. The chromosomal locations of the mutations were determined, and complementing clones were isolated from the cosmid library of S. meliloti genomic DNA. The mutants were placed into four groups (I--IV) based on genetic linkage in phage co-transduction. None of the mutations were in glyoxylate shunt enzyme-encoding genes. Nucleotide sequence analysis of ace mutants from Groups III and IV showed mutations in genes encoding acetyl-CoA synthetase ( acsB) and anaerobic coproporphyrinogen III oxidase (hemN ) respectively. Cell extracts of the hemN mutant exhibited double the isocitrate lyase levels of the wild type. The acsB mutant lacked acetyl-CoA synthetase activity and had an interesting growth phenotype; it was able to grow on low concentrations of acetate only. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Thaha, Fathuma Zuleikha.</creator><contributor>Charles, Trevor C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Acetates -- Metabolism -- Genetic aspects.</subject><subject>Rhizobium meliloti -- Molecular genetics.</subject><subject>Rhizobium meliloti -- Metabolism.</subject><title>Characterization of acetate metabolism genes in Sinorhizobium (Rhizobium) meliloti</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859h48t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5m60qt94w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72p902p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Amadori and Heyns rearrangement products are currently produced as crude Maillard reaction mixtures, due to lack of convenient procedures for their synthesis. The objective of this study was to develop a synthetic strategy based on polymer-supported synthesis that allows the production of different derivatives of these sugar-amino acid conjugates. The strategy involved coupling of poly(ethyleneglycol) mono methyl ether (PEGME) with N-protected (t-BOC) amino acid through catalysis by DCC (dicyclohexylcarbodimide) to form a polymer bound ester of the amino acid (89% yield with beta-alanine), followed by deprotection of the t-BOC group through a novel microwave-assisted hydrolysis process in high yields (98%). After the deprotection, the polymer-based amino acid was neutralized by triethyl amine treatment, followed by room temperature reaction with selected reducing sugars or sugar analogs, for 48 hrs to produce polymer bound ARP in 75% yield (using acetol). The final product was cleaved by methanolysis using sodium methioxide in 65% yield. The reactions were monitored by spectroscopic analysis and the intermediates were identified by FTIR, Py/GC/MS and 1H NMR.</description><creator>Tateyama, Miho.</creator><contributor>Yaylayan, V. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Maillard reaction.</subject><title>Development of polymer-supported synthetic procedure for Heyns rearrangement products</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cj46c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p902p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7m01bn63j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Secondary peritonitis is a significant cause of morbidity and mortality in the ICU and ICU patients as a group have the highest rate of nosocomial infections. Once recruited to the site of injury, the PMN interacts with endothelial cells (ECs) via rolling adhesion, firm adhesion, and transendothelial migration. Using a murine cecal ligation and puncture peritonitis model and either skin or cremaster injury as the secondary site in a two-front injury model, we examined the role of injury severity on the triage of PMNs to competing sites of injury. We demonstrated that a finite pool of PMNs was recruited to tissues in numbers correlating to the severity major injury. With intravital microscopy we demonstrated that numbers of PMNs involved in rolling adhesion, rolling velocity and stationary adhesion in the presence of one or more sites of injury were predictable, consistent and likely mediated by changes in surface adhesion molecule expression.</description><creator>Swartz, Daniel E.</creator><contributor>Christou, Nicolas V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>Alterations of Polymorphonuclear neutrophil (PMN) recruitment in a murine model of peritonitis and a secondary injury</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j3036.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bn63j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of General Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816p381</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study was designed to compare pain intensity during a clinical event (fingerstick) in children with Sickle Cell Disease (SCD) who have experienced recurrent episodic pain, against those children without SCD who have not experienced recurrent pain. A convenience sample of sixty-six 7--12 year old children was obtained, 33 with SCD from the sickle cell clinic and a matched (age, sex, ethnic origin) group of 33 children without SCD from the community. Pain intensity using the Coloured Analogue Scale (McGrath et al., 1996) and, medical fears using the Child Medical Fears Scale (Broome &amp; Hellier, 1987) were measured following the fingerstick. The number of hospitalisations and the number of experiences with needles were examined for their relationship to pain intensity or medical fears. Multivariate analysis of variance revealed no significant differences in either pain intensity or medical fears between the two groups. There was a moderate, significant correlation between pain intensity and medical fears for the entire sample (r = .269, p &lt; .03). Among children with SCD, those who had more than the median number of hospitalisations (6), reported lower medical fear scores (p &lt; .01). This finding suggests adaptation on the part of these children to their chronic illness and to hospitalisations.</description><creator>Meredith, Patricia.</creator><contributor>Johnston, Celeste (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Health Sciences, Nursing.</subject><subject>Psychology, Physiological.</subject><title>Response to acute pain among children with and without sickle cell disease</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644t464.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816p381</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Nursing</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m613n056p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The first part of this study concerns the examination of tetrahydrofuran ring-opening polymerization mediated by the palladium insertion polymerization catalysts, (bipy)Pd(CH3)(L)+ OTf- (L = NCCH3, PhN=C(H)Tol, tBuN=C(H)Tol, CH3 N=C(H)Tol). Mechanistic studies reveal a series of metal-based reactions prior to ring-opening, which can be utilized to control polymer molecular weights and end-groups. The feasibility of combining this ring-opening reaction to insertion polymerization to generate new block co-polymers is subsequently investigated, and it forms the primary objective of the study. The dual-functional palladium(II) complex (bipy)Pd(CH3)(NCCH 3)+OTf- is found to mediate a novel, single-step coupling of insertion and ring-opened monomers (CO, norbornene, THF) into new polymers. This coupling process follows an unusual route, involving enol lactone as an intermediate, and facilitated by weak Lewis acid. Similar coupling chemistry has been applied to the synthesis of polyTHF end-capped with a small polynorbornene fragment.</description><creator>Lim, Ngiap Kie, 1972-</creator><contributor>Arndtsen, Bruce A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Chemistry, Inorganic.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>Coupling of insertion and ring-opening polymerizations on a Pd(II) Center : a potential route to novel block co-polymers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xt67h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613n056p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f3173</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>I propose a new approach, based on time-dependent covariates, to assess the impact of within-subject changes in predictors on subsequent mortality, and apply it to reevaluate the impact of changes in serum cholesterol and smoking status on the coronary heart mortality in the Framingham Heart Study. Time-dependent covariates, representing updated risk factor value or its changes from either the baseline or the most recent measurement are included in two types of multivariable Cox regression analyses. The results reveal that in order to avoid confounding of the effects of changes in risk factor, the model should include a time-dependent variable identifying subjects who developed coronary disease during the follow-up. After adjusting for this variable, a within-subject decrease in cholesterol was associated with a significant reduction of corollary mortality, in contrast to the results of previous studies that did not prevent such confounding.</description><creator>Li, Guilin, 1973-</creator><contributor>Abrahamowicz, Michal (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><title>Re-analyses of Framingham data using time-dependent covariates</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hm12r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f3173</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pg15bg99q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Members of the Dlg/PSD-95 protein family have a modular organization with multiple protein interaction domains and are thought to be important in the organization of synapses. A degenerate primer PCR strategy was used to screen for members of this family in the central nervous system of Apteronotus leptorhynchus, which possesses an electrosensory system that is well-suited for the study of synaptic organization and the subcellular localization of proteins. A. leptorhynchus was found to express at least four Dlg/PSD-95 family genes as in mammals, and the full coding sequences of the homologues of mammalian PSD-95 and SAP102 were determined. In situ hybridization experiments performed for the A. leptorhynchus Dig/PSD-95 family members in brain showed that they have a differential pattern of expression.</description><creator>Lee, Sang, 1972-</creator><contributor>Dunn, Robert J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Protein kinases.</subject><subject>Brown ghost knifefish.</subject><subject>Synapses.</subject><title>Molecular analysis of the DlgPSD-95 family of membrane-associated guanylate kinases in the weakly electric fish, Apteronotus leptorhynchus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720f81g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bg99q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:47429c15r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The transformation of 45 tropical cyclones into extratropical cyclones over the western Noah Atlantic Ocean between 1963 and 1996 is studied. Cases are selected from the National Hurricane Center's "best track" archive. National Centers, for Environmental Prediction (NCEP) reanalyses of geopotential height data are used to construct a synoptic-dynamic climatology of extratropical transition, or "ET". The Forecast Systems Laboratory (FSL) upper-air archive of six near-track stations is used to produce sounding composites. Primary results of the study follow. (1) A statistically-significant 1000--500-hPa warm anomaly (with respect to the 1963--96 climatology) persists for the one-week period prior to the passage of the tropical systems into the Canadian Maritime provinces. (2) A northwestward extension of the surface subtropical anticyclone exists over the Canadian Atlantic Provinces during the two-day period prior to the arrival of the cyclone. (3) The tropical cyclone's warm core and conditionally-unstable tropical airmass are maintained after transition. (4) The presence of quasi-geostrophic forcing for ascent, typically seen in extratropical cyclones, is observed during periods in which the systems are still classified as tropical cyclones. This forcing for ascent continues during the extratropical transformation, and typically occurs ahead and to the left of the storm track.</description><creator>Fogarty, Christopher T.</creator><contributor>Gyakum, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><title>A study of tropical to extratropical cyclone transition in the western north Atlantic Ocean, 1963-1996 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fq76h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/47429c15r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vj614</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:56:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A mouse model of resistance and susceptibility to a pulmonary infection with Pseudomonas aeruginosa (PA), was used to study the inflammatory profile early following infection. This study allowed the identification of the mechanisms responsible for the resistant phenotype. We have first determined the pivotal role of the neutrophil recruitment in the alveolar space in the host defense against PA. This influx occurred earlier in the resistant BALB/c mice than in susceptible DBA/2 mice and occurred concommitantly with the beginning of the bacterial clearance. Furthermore, levels of TNFalpha were found to be higher in BALB/c mice than in DBA/2 mice. TNFalpha appears to mediate the production of chemokines responsible for neutrophil recruitment in the lungs. However, treatment of susceptible mice with TNFalpha led to an increase of neutrophil recruitment without any improvement in bacterial clearance. Lung homogenates from resistant mice also showed an increase in IL-10 and GM-CSF content. This was not seen in susceptible mice. This may lead to a more efficient neutrophil activation due to their effect on bacterial exotoxins and apoptotic gene regulation (via Fas pathway). TNFalpha, IL-10 and GM-CSF may represent valuable targets for treatment of lung infection with PA in patients unresponsive to antibiotherapy.</description><creator>Francoeur, Caroline.</creator><contributor>Gervais, Francine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>Comparison du profil inflammatoire des soiris résistantes et sensibles à une infection endobronchique à Pseudomonas aeruginosa</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pz50gz00b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vj614</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):39375</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>