<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:09:30Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):5000" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8p58pg35q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The experimental value of the fracture toughness of 7075-T651 aluminum was obtained, using the ASTM E399 test standard, to serve as a reference for the testing of a new fracture toughness specimen under development at McGill University. The fracture toughness obtained was 24.5 ± 0.2 Ksi/in, which is in agreement with the literature. As part of this study, three different finite element techniques for determining the stress intensity were reviewed: 1. Displacement Extrapolation, 2. Strain Energy Release Rate, 3. Virtual Crack Extension. To this end a FORTRAN program was transcribed from Owen (1983), but errors within the code prevented meaningful results from being obtained. […]</description><creator>Berger, Robert M.</creator><contributor>Professor Provan</contributor><date>1987</date><subject>Aluminum</subject><title>The fracture toughness of 7075-T651 aluminum</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mp791.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pg35q</identifier><degree><name>Bachelor of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wm117r382</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The dynamics of an orbiting tether attached at one end to a flexible space platform, and at the other to a subsatellite are investigated. The tether has a uniform mass and its longitudinal, transverse, and swing motions are all studied. This thesis concentrates on the natural frequencies of motion, and the response behaviour subject to the forcing due to the platform’s flexibility, and its pitch vibrations. Only effects in the orbital plane are considered. It is found that the location of the tether attachment on the platform does not have a large effect on the natural frequencies of motion. The tension in the tether can be expressed as a function of the tether-subsatellite mass ratio, and the tether attachment offset distance from the system center of mass. It is also found that particular numerical values for the parameters describing the platform, will cause resonance with the longitudinal motion of the tether. </description><creator>Torchinsky, Stephen A</creator><contributor>Fekete, G. I.</contributor><date>1986-11</date><subject>Tether</subject><title>On the dynamics of an orbiting tether-platform system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977x35p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117r382</identifier><degree><name>Bachelor of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rg943</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A complex potential model is developed for ideal flow over a two-dimensional hill. With the aid of this model, multiplicative composite matching is used to correct the velocity profiles computed by a program for boundary layer development. The main goal of this thesis is to see if multiplicative composite matching, which multiplies computed velocity values by a correction factor, can account for the speed up effects of the flow as well as more complicated methods. This is done by comparing the corrected velocity profiles to those obtained by wind tunnel tests. The program for boundary layer development proves to be difficult to use. The program gives unusually shaped - velocity profiles making it uneasy for us to judge the merits of composite matching. There is however a closer match made to the actual profiles when using composite matching. </description><creator>Paquin, André</creator><contributor>Fekete, G. I.</contributor><date>1986-11</date><subject>Turbulent airflow</subject><title>A study of the merits of multiplicative composite matching for turbulent airflow development over a two-dimensional hill</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v091g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rg943</identifier><degree><name>Bachelor of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:736667168</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The geometry of the facet joints of the human lumbar spine has long been postulated as an important factor in the etiology of disc degeneration. In the present study, a procedure to accurately quantify the three dimensional geometry of the lumbar facet joints, using catscans, has been developed and a set of geometric parameters has been proposed. The experimentally determined axial torque rotation characteristics of 18 L 2 – 3 intervertebral joints have been correlated with the respective facet   geometry, as determined by the aforementioned procedure. A previously developed nonlinear three dimensional finite element program has been used to analyze the response of a lumbar L 2 – 3 intervertebral joint subjected to axial torque combined with compression. The facet joint geometry in the finite element model has been systematically modified to determine the effect of facet geometry upon the intervertebral joint motion. […]</description><creator>Duncan, Neil</creator><date>1986-04</date><subject>Disc degeneration</subject><title>The role of the geometry of the human lumbar facet joints in disc degeneration</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sq87bw89j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/736667168</identifier><degree><name>Bachelor of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322g81v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Haitian literature always had a national vocation. As presented in Sociality in the haitian novels of exile, which examines the revolutionary ethics of an author through his aesthetics process, it is mainly under the dictatorship of the Duvaliers (1957-1986), that the militant intellectuals defended the cause of the outcasts. Formed into the revolutionary thoughts of the era, these intellectuals, who escaped the· horror of dictatorship by going into exile, have tried to make out of the novelistic art, an instrument of awareness. Within the scope of a quest of the self and a search for identity, the authors studied here established their novels as models of analysis and synthesis of social reality. By transforming the themes of the literary subject matter and the formal structure of traditional haitian novel, they highlighted the aporia struggle. This element of is haitian society through class indeed the focus of socialist realism pertaining to a socio-historical aesthetics. Sociality in the haitian novels of exile proves in fact that the novelistic art of exile fulfilled the historical mission assigned to novels. This mission consists in coalescing mysticism to history, in order to illustrate an integral human being. Through the ethics and aesthetics cultivated in a semiotics world relating social reality to its own linguistic signs, we have given a global interpretation of haitian social life, background to our semiotics reflection.</description><description>La littérature haïtienne a toujours eu une vocation nationale. Comme le montre La socialité dans  e roman haïtien de la diaspora, qui examine 1'éthique révolutionnaire du romancier à travers  on  processus d’esthétisation, c’est surtout sous la dictature duvaliériste (1957-1986), que des intellectuels militants ont défendu la cause des démunis. Après avoir fui la dictature en se jetant  sur les routes de 1’exil, ces . Intellectuels, façonnes par la pensée révolutionnaire de l'époque,  n ressentent encore l'horreur, et se servent du genre romanesque comme instrument de conscientisation. Dans le cadre d’une quête de soi et d • une recherche d'identité en terre  étrangère, les écrivains étudies ici ont institué le roman en modèle d'analyse et de synthèse de la réalité sociale. Renouvelant la thématique et la structure formelle du roman haïtien traditionnel,  ils ont mis en relief les apories de la société haïtienne, en utilisant le concept de la lutte des  classes. Cet élément constitue justement le noyau central du réalisme socialiste relevant d • une  esthétique socio-historique. La socialité dans le roman haïtien de la diaspora démontre en fait que  l'art romanesque de 1' exil remplit la mission fondamentale du roman. Celle-ci consiste à  fusionner le mythique a 1 ‘histoire1 en intégrale de l'homme. En faisant ressortir la figure vertu  e l'éthique et de l'esthétisme cultives dans un univers sémiologique reliant la réalité aux signes linguistiques qui la traduisent, nous avons interprète de façon globale la vie sociale haïtienne, toile de fond de notre réflexion sémiologique.</description><creator>Charles, Judith</creator><contributor>Maugey, Axel (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1995</date><subject>Haitian literature -- Foreign countries -- History and criticism.</subject><title>La socialité dans le roman haïtien de la diaspora</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999906w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322g81v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6q182n560</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sous bien des rapports la ville de New York est la vraie capitale des Etats-Unis.  Et Washington? On ne suarait en effet nier son titre, car c'est là en effect qu'on trouve tous les diplomates, politiciens, fonctionnaires et édifices qui consitutent ke siège du gourvernement, et il n'y a pas d'état ou de bon citoyen qui ne la reconnaisse comme telle.  En ce qui  concerne les affaires gouvernementales ces étatset ces bons citoyens on incontestablement raison, mais il n'en est pas moins vrai que, à par tla politique et la Diplomatie, c;est New York qui donne le ton à ce vaste pays. [...]</description><creator>Jennings, Thomas Joseph</creator><contributor>Du Roure, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1935</date><subject>Theater -- New York (State) -- New York.</subject><title>L'Histoire du Nouveau Théâtre à New York</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214r58s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182n560</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>French Department</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720g349</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Au cours d'une série d'expériences, les enfants sourds et les enfants normaux durent discriminer ou reproduire des séquences rythmiques. Ces rythmes étaient présentés d'une manière visuelle, auditoire (beaucoup amplifiés pour les sourds), et, à une des expériences, d'une manière tactile. Quoique les sourds, aussi bien que les enfants normaux, aient pu discriminer d'une manière visuelle et tactile les séquences qu'on leur avait présentées, il apparut que ces sourds firent preuve d'une insuffisance, par rapport aux enfants normaux, à reproduire des rythmes, même présentés visuellement. Alors que les normaux accomplissaient mieux la tache auditive que la tache visuelle (et la tache tactile), les sourds n'obtinrent pas de différences appréciables en fonction de la modalité te. Ces résultats sont discutées par rapport aux difficultés avec la mémoire a court-terme chez les sourds, ainsi que les problèmes du contrôle moteur, et la structure temporelle de la parole. On tient compte de quelques différences individuelles et on fait des recommendations pour l'utilisation du rythme dans t’enseignement de la parole aux sourds.</description><description>In a series of experiments, deaf and hearing children were required to discriminate or to reproduce rhythmic patterns. Rhythms were presented visually, auditorily (greatly amplified for the deaf), and in one experiment, tactually. It was found that although deaf subjects discriminated visually and tactually presented patterns as well as hearing subjects, deaf subjects were deficient in comparison to the hearing in their abilities to reproduce rhythms, even when presented visually. While hearing subjects performed consistently better in the auditory than inother modalities, performance of deaf subjects did not vary greatly as a function of modality. The results are discussed in relation to difficulties the deaf may have with short-term memory, motor control, and the timing of speech. Some individual differences are considered, and  certain recommendations are made concerning the use of rhythm in speech training with the deaf.</description><creator>Wolff, Anthony B.</creator><contributor>Bregman, Albert S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1979-02</date><subject>Rhythm -- Psychological aspects.</subject><subject>Deaf children.</subject><subject>Perception.</subject><title>Recognition and reproduction of rhythmic patterns by the deaf</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dr26z0721.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720g349</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5h73pz48r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Une nouvelle méthode de calcul pour les filtres linéaires et pour la prédiction est présentée. Elle fait usage des deux approches mathématiques de filtrage d'information et de covariance, en une formulation générale. Les méthodes préconisées nous permettent de continuer la reserche afin de développer des algorithmes qui produisent des estimation utiles dans le cas dégénéré de matrices de rangs déficients. Ces résultats représentant une appproche unifiée à l'évaluation d'états de systèmes linéaires dynamiques et à l'évaluation récursive de paramètres pour l'identification de systèmes et de commande adaptive. </description><description>A new computational approach to linear filtering and prediction is presented. It combines the two usual mathematical approaches of covariance and information filtering in one generalized formulation. The methods advocated provide a framework for future research into algorithms which produce useful estimates for the degenerate case of rank deficient covariance matrices. These results represent a unified approach to state estimation in linear dynamic systems and recursive parameter estimation for system identification and adaptive control.</description><creator>Thomas, Stephen J.</creator><contributor>Paige, Chris</contributor><date>1986-02</date><subject>Stochastic processes.</subject><subject>Digital filters (Mathematics)</subject><subject>Kalman filtering.</subject><title>A Unified Approach to Linear Filtering Using a Generalized Covariance Representation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zz95j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5h73pz48r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b8515q916</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this study is to examine a) the contractual regime of licensing arrangements and b) the impact of domestic laws and policy in Eastern Africa on the transfer of technology through licensing. In connection with the contractual regime of licensing arrangements, the study makes certain major findings and recommends for a reorientation of the contractual framework in order to take into account the legitimate interests of host states end technology recipients. Having examined the existing laws end policy that effect the transfer of technology through licensing in Eastern Africa, the paper also recommends for a review of the existing juridical environment in order to enhance the process of technology transfer. A section is also devoted to the study of national objectives in these countries behind the importation of foreign technology and the extent to which such objectives have been realised with respect to technology licensing.</description><description>L'objectif de cette étude est d'analyser le régime de contrat des licences de technologie ainsi que l'impact des lois et politiques de l'Afrique de l’est sur les transferts de technologie. En relation avec le régime de contrat, cette étude apporte des conclusions et fait des recommandations pour une réorientation des contrats en tenant compte des intérêts légitimes pour les pays bénéficiaires. Après l’analyse des lois et politiques existantes qui influencent directement ou indirectement le transfert de technologie, l'étude recommande une révision de ces lots et politiques afin d'accélérer le processus du transfert de technologie. Dans cette recherche une section a été consacrée à l’étude des besoins particuliers des pays concernant l'importation des technologies étrangères ainsi qu’au degré de succès dans la réalisation de ces mêmes objectifs. </description><creator>Seyoum, Belaynehe</creator><contributor>de Mestral, A.</contributor><date>1986</date><subject>Technology transfer -- Law and legislation -- Sudan.</subject><subject>License agreements -- Kenya.</subject><subject>Technology transfer -- Law and legislation -- Kenya.</subject><title>Technology Licensing in Eastern Africa : A Critical Analysis and Exposition of Industrial Transfers of Technology under License Arrangements to Kenya, Sudan, and Tanzania</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6969z334z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515q916</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Civil Law</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qp57r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dans le but d'étudier l'absorption et l'interconvertion de différentes sources de carbone, du fructose, glucose, sorbitol (D-glucitol) et saccharose ont été fournis à des explants depommiers de trois différents génotypes: un porte-greffe Ottawa-3 (0-3), un greffon de type Macspur (MA) et des plantules issues de graines de Macspur (SM). L'étude a porté au stade de multiplication et au stade de racinement des explants cultivés in vitro. Après une periode d'incubation de deux heures sur les milieux contenant une source de carbone radioactive, le comptage par scintillation liquide n'a pas révèlé de différences significatives entre l'absorption du sorbitol, du fructose, du glucose, ou du saccharose, par les explants. Le sorbitol, représentant en moyenne une proportion de 93.1% pour tous 1 es génotypes et stades de propagation, a été interconverti par les explants dans la plus faible mesure, suivi dans un ordre décroissant par le glucose (80.5%), le fructose (63.0%) et le saccharose (62.4%).</description><description>Radioactive fructose, glucose, sorbitol (D-glucitol), and sucrose were supplied to explants of three apple cultures, Ottawa-3 apple rootstock (0-3), scion cultivar of Macspur apple (MA), and seedlings of Macspur (SM), at both the shoot multiplication (Stage II) and rooting (Stage III) stages of in vitro micro-propagation to study the uptake and interconversion of the carbon source fraction by these cultures. Using a labelling incubation period of 2 hours, liquid scintillation indicated no significant difference in the uptake of sorbitol compared to the uptake of fructose, glucose or sucrose. Sorbitol, found at an average proportion of 93.1% over all genotypes and stage of culture, was interconverted to the lowest extent, followed in order by glucose (80.5%), fructose (63.0%) and sucrose (62.4%). </description><creator>Renaud, Jean Pierre</creator><contributor>Chong, C.</contributor><date>1986-05</date><subject>Apples.</subject><subject>Carbohydrates -- Metabolism.</subject><subject>Sorbitol -- Metabolism.</subject><title>Metabolism and Interconversion of Labelled Sorbitol and Related Carbon Sources by Apple Tissue Cultures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xv192.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qp57r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cw50z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les résultats obtenus lors d'essais sous charges cycliques renversées sur des assemblages poutre-poteau extérieurs grandeur nature connus et détailles selon les normes du Code canadien du beton 1984 sont présentés. Les spécimens étudiés consistaient en une dalle avec poutre de contour, et ont été conçus pour deux niveaux: de ductilité, soient K = 1.3 et K = 0.7.Les rôles de la dalle et de la poutre de contour ont été examines. Il est démontré comment la poutre de contour limite la largeur efficace de la dalle et comment elle influence le cisaillement dans la zone du joint entre la poutre principale et le poteau. Les résultats expérimentaux sont comparés aux résultats théoriques. La présente étude fournit une information générale sur l'amortissement hystérétique, la dégradation de la rigidité, la capacité de soutenir la charge, la ductilité, les étapes de plastification, les contributions de la courbure en flexion, les déformations dues au cisaillement, ainsi que les déformations du joint dues au cisaillement.</description><description>The results of reversed cyclic load tests on two full-scale exterior beam-column connections designed and detailed according to the 1984 Canadian concrete code are presented. These test specimens included a slab together with a spandrel beam and were designed for two different levels of ductility, K = 1.3 and K = 0.1. The role of the slab and the role of the spandrel beam are investigated. It is demonstrated how the spandrel beam limits the effective width of the slab and how it affects the shear in the joint region between the main beam and the column. The responses are compared with predicted behaviour. The research provides general information on the hysteretic damping and stiffness degradation, the ability to maintain load, ductility, the sequence of yielding and the contributions of flexural curvature, shear deformation and joint shear distortion.</description><creator>Rattray, Suzanne</creator><date>1986-05</date><subject>Earthquake resistant design.</subject><subject>Strains and stresses.</subject><subject>Concrete beams.</subject><title>Reversed Cyclic Load Tests of Reinforced Concrete Frame Subassemblages</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hs13s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cw50z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5138jh01s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis attempts to analyse the problem of national integration in the Sudan. The study presents an analysis of the Addis Ababa Agreement (1972), which had facilitated the cessation of a civil war that had lasted for seventeen years. In spite of its ultimate breakdown, theAgreement illustrated the premise that the north-south conflict in the Sudan was not completely without a solution. This study examines the extent to which economic development of the south and the promise of equal access to the scarce resources of the state formed substitute arrangements for 'national integration' in the sense of creating a homogenous society. The findings of this thesis, however, do not discredit the importance of ethnic differences in the Sudan, but seek to explain a relatively unexplored aspect of the conflict.</description><description>Cette thèse tente d'analyser le problème de l'intégration nationale au Soudan. L'étude présente une analyse de l'Entente d'Addis Abeba (1972), contribuant à la cessation d'une guerre civile qui s'est prolongée durant 17 ans. Malgré la rupture définitive de l'Entente, cette dernière a pu énoncer que le conflit nord-sud au Soudan n'était pas complètement sans solution. Cette recherche examine aussi à quel point le développement économique du sud et l’espérance d'un accès égal aux rares ressources de l'État constituent des dispositions de relève pour "l'intégration nationale" dans le sens de la création d'une société homogène. Cependant, les conclusions de cette thèse ne discréditent en rien l'influence des différences ethniques au Soudan, mais cherchent plutôt à interpréter, de façon relative, un aspect inconnu du conflit. </description><creator>Raghavan, Nandini</creator><contributor>Kunz, F. A.</contributor><date>1986-06</date><subject>Assimilation (Sociology)</subject><subject>Sudan -- History -- Civil War, 1955-1972.</subject><subject>Addis Ababa, Treaty of, 1972.</subject><title>The Addis Ababa Agreement and the Problem of National Integration in the Sudan</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720g35k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5138jh01s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rw87g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Sex hormone-binding globulin ( SHBG) is a plasma protein which binds testosterone and estradiol in vitro with high affinity and specificity. There is conflicting evidence as to the role of SHBG in the transport of estradiol under in vive conditions. Studies describing the distribution of estradiol and testosterone into SHBG-bound, albumin-bound and unbound fractions were carried out using equilibrium dialysis of whole serum at 37°C under isosmotic conditions. The results showed that SHBG was an important binder of estradiol in both pregnant and non-pregnant women, but of minimal significance in men and in newborn infants. Testosterone was significantly bound to SHBG under all circumstances. In order to characterize previously unrecognized substances that may bind to SHBG in pregnancy, maternal serum was fractionated on Sephadex LH-20. A substantial part of the SHBG-bound material eluted as 4 major peaks which did not correspond to any of the steroids thought to bind to SHBG. Comparison of levels in maternal, fetal and placental compartments suggested that all 4 peaks were of placental origin. Three were identified as 5 a-pregnane-3, 20-dione, progesterone and 2-methoxyestrone on the basis of elution pattern on Sephadex LH-20, binding characteristics, high performance liquid chromatography, and gas chromatography-mass spectrometry. The fourth peak was identified as a 19-nor androgen, i.e. 17B-hydroxy-1, 5-estradiene-3-one, on the basis of similar kinds of evidence and in addition, solubility characteristics and ultra-violet absorption spectrum. Since its level fell in association with premature and term labour, its decrease may be involved in the initiation of labour.</description><description>La globuline liant les hormones sexuelles (Sex Hormone Binding Globulin, SHBG) est une protéine plasmatique qui se lie spécifiquement à la testostérone et a l'estradiol in vitro. Cette liaison est de haute affinité. Toutefois, le rôle de la SHBG dans le transport de l'estradiol in vivo est mal connu. Nous avons procédé à l'étude des fractions d'estradiol et de testostérone liées à la SHBG ou à l'albumine ou simplement libres en effectuant une dialyse a l'équilibre du sérum à 37°C en conditions isosmotiques. Les résultats ont démontré que la SHBG constitue un facteur important dans la liaison de l'estradiol sérique chez la femme gravide et non gravide. Toutefois, la liaison à l'estradiol s'est avérée minime chez l'homme et chez le nouveau-né. La testostérone était liée à la SHBG en quantité significative dans toutes les conditions que nous avons étudiées. Afin de procéder à la caractérisation de substances liées à la SHBG durant la grossesse et jusqu'à présent non identifiés, le sérum maternel a été fractionné sur Sephadex LH-20. Une proportion importante du matériel lie à la SHBG éluait en 4 principaux pies lesquels ne correspondaient à aucune des stéroïdes que l'on pense se lient à la SHBG. La comparaison des niveaux des quatres pies dans les compartiments maternel, fétal et placentaire suggérait que ces derniers étaient d'origine placentaire. Trois de ces pies représentaient la 5 a-pregnane-3,20-dione, la progestérone et la 2-methoxyestrone, ce, sur la base du profil d'élution, des caractéristiques de liaison, et de l'analyse par chromatographie à haute performance, par chromatographie gazeuse et spectrographie de masse. Le quatrième pie representait une 19-nor androgene i.e. 17B-hydroxy-1,5-estradien-3-one, ce, selon le type d'évidence décrit ci-dessus en plus des caractéristiques de solubilité et d'absorption des rayons UV. Comme les niveaux de cette substance diminuaient avec le travail prématuré et à terme, sa diminution peut être responsable pour l'initiation du travail de l'accouchement. </description><creator>Philip, Anie</creator><contributor>Pearson, Beverley E. </contributor><date>1986-08</date><subject>Pregnancy</subject><title>Steroid Binding to Sex Hormone-Binding Globulin: Studies on Relative Binding of Estradiol and Testosterone, and Characterization of Certain Previously Unrecognized Ligands in Pregnancy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dj061.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rw87g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w0325457</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pendant son règne l'empereur Néron s'est marié successivement a trois femmes. Avec l'avènement à Rome d'un certain nombre de femmes politiquement actives au cours de cette époque, il est permis de prétendre que les épouses de Néron ont été dans la position d'exercer sur celui-ci des pressions politiques. Basée principalement sur la plus importante source issue du principat de Néron, soit les Annales XIII-XVI de Tacite la présente thèse a pour objet de faire un exposé sur l'évidence de la vie de Claudia Octavie et celle-là de Poppée Sabina qui étaient les seules épouses de Néron, que Tacite a traitée dans son oeuvre. De plus, la thèse offre une opinion sur le jugement de Tacite concernant ces deux épouses dans le contexte général de son idée des femmes. A cette fin, il démontrera que même si les deux femmes ont eu les moyens d'exercer des pressions politiques, ce n'est que Poppée qui a profité de son pouvoir. […]</description><description>In the course of his reign, the Emperor Nero was married to three wives in succession. Since a number of women are known to have been politically active during the late Republic and early Empire, it is possible that Nero's wives also exerted political pressure on him. Relying primarily on the best source for the Neronian Principate, Tacitus' Annals XIII-XVI, this thesis will give an account of the evidence presented for the lives of the only two wives of Nero with whom Tacitus deals, Claudia Octavia and Poppaea Sabina. There follows, in addition, an estimation of Tacitus’ judgment of their lives in light of his general view of women. It will be demonstrated that although both women had the necessary means to mount political pressure, only Poppaea took advantage of her position. […]</description><creator>Parker, Robert N. S.</creator><contributor>Woloch, Michael</contributor><date>1986-07</date><subject>Rome -- History -- Nero, 54-68.</subject><subject>Rome -- Politics and government -- 30 B.C.-68 A.D.</subject><title>Two Wives in Nero: A Political and Prosographical Study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xx31g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w0325457</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Classics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290c98s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse trouve les états de base du modèle symplectique pour le comportement collectif nucléaire. Nous trouvons une base complète I d'états pour Sp(6), le plus important groupe de mouvements collectifs dans les noyaux. Parmi la multitude d'états propres possibles, nous ne sommes intéressés que dans ceux de type vibrationnel, dits de Bohr-Mottelson, qui forment en même temps une base dans le sous-groupe Sp(2) x 0(3) de Sp(6). La base que nous trouvons n'est pas orthonormale mais elle est complète et nonredondante et nous montrons comment l'utiliser pour calculer des éléments de matrices des générateurs entre ces états. Puisque le Hamiltonien du problème obéit a l'algèbre enveloppante de Sp(6), il peut s'exprimer comme un polynôme de bas rang dans les générateurs de Sp(6) et le spectre vibrationnel des royaux peut donc être calculé. Ces résultats peuvent être appliqués pour tout noyau (tout Z). Nous parvenons à résoudre le problème compliqué de trouver les états de base en utilisant les méthodes de la fonction génératrice. Nous obtenons premièrement la fonction génératrice donnant des règles d'embranchement pour la chaine Sp(6), Sp(2) x 0(3) et nous interprétons les termes apparaissant dans la fonction génératrice comme des produits allongés d'un ensemble fini de diagrammes élémentaires permissibles qui forment une base d'intégrité. Les états de base de ce groupe et de ce sousgroupe sont définis en termes de cette base intégrité. […]</description><description>This thesis finds the basis states of the symplectic model for nuclear collective behaviour. We are able to find a complete set of states for Sp(6), the most important group of collective motions in nuclei. From the multitude of possible eigenstates we are interested in vibrational type ones, or Bohr-Mottelson type, which are at the same time a basis in the subgroup Sp(2) x 0(3) of Sp(6). The basis we find is not orthonormal but complete and nonredundant and we how to use it to determine generator matrix elements between these states. Since the Hamiltonian of the problem is in the enveloping algebra of Sp(6) it can be expressed as a low rank polynomial in the Sp(6) generators and the actual vibrational spectrum of nuclei is then calculable. The results are applicable to all nuclei (any Z). We are able to exactly solve the difficult problem of finding the basis states using generating function methods. We first obtain the generating function giving branching rules for the chain Sp(6), Sp(2) x 0(3) and we interpret the terms appearing in the generating function as stretched products of a finite set of elementary permissible diagrams which form the integrity basis. The basis states of the group and subgroup are defined in terms of this integrity basis. […]</description><creator>Niculescu-Sanielevici, Mihaela</creator><contributor>Sharp, R. T.</contributor><date>1986-02</date><subject>Nuclear collective models.</subject><subject>Generating functions.</subject><subject>Nuclear models.</subject><title>Generator Matrix Elements for Noncompact Sp(6) in a Sp(2) X 0(3) Basis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jn93r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290c98s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4m90dx815</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents the French remote-sensing system SPOT operational since February 1986.The first chapter examines the international legal framework of remote-sensing activities and especially the development, scope and limits of the text of the fifteen principles on remote-sensing worked out at the United Nations Committee on the Peaceful Uses of Outer Space. Furthermore, the importance of international co-operation in this field is underlined. The second chapter is concerned with the commercialization of the SPOT system. The reasons for its success are examined as well as the commercialized products such as the "société SPOT IMAGE" and its commercial contracts. Then, for the system to be viable, legal protection for data and commercialized products is required. It is seen that in the absence of statutory laws and jurisprudence the application of copyrights to all remote-sensing data remains problematic.</description><description>Cette thèse présente le système français de télédétection spatiale SPOT opérationnel depuis février 1986. Le premier chapitre examine le cadre juridique international des activités de télédétection et particulièrement le développement, le champ d'application et les limites du texte des quinze principes relatifs à la télédétection élaboré au sein du Comité des Utilisations Pacifiques de l'Espace Extra-Atmosphérique des Nations-Unies. De plus, nous soulignons l'importance de la coopération internationale dons ce domaine. Le second chapitre s'intéresse à la commercialisation du système SPOT. Nous examinons les conditions de sa réussite ainsi que les moyens mis en place pour assurer la diffusion des produits commercialises comme la société SPOT IMAGE et ses contrats commerciaux. Enfin, pour que le système soit viable, il faut qu'existe une protection juridique des données et des produits commercialisés. Nous voyons qu'en l'absence de textes réglementaires et de jurisprudence, l'application du droit d'auteur o toutes les données de télédétection reste problématique.</description><creator>Le Gall, Antoinette</creator><contributor>Magdelénat, J. L.</contributor><date>1986-08</date><subject>SPOT (Artificial satellite)</subject><subject>Artificial satellites in remote sensing -- Law and legislation -- France.</subject><subject>Space law.</subject><title>La France et la Teledetection par Satellite des Ressources de la Terre : Le Système Spot</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676z20q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4m90dx815</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Air and Space Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62fb741</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In a greenhouse study, eight month old plants of red clover cvs Arlington and Florex were evaluated for resistance to Fusarium root rot. Four hundred and fifty genotypes were inoculated with one of three isolates of Fusarium roseum (814, 927, 959) using a cut-root application technique. The degree of Fusarium root rot incidence was evaluated by measuring the vertical discoloration in the taproot from the point of inoculation, and by means of the Horsfall-Barratt scale. Isolate 814 produced a greater degree of infection than isolates 927 and 959. Genetic difference in resistance between and within the two red cultivars were found using isolate 814 and 959, but no difference was found using the less pathogenic isolate 927. […]</description><description>Dans une étude en serre, des plants de trèfle rouge ont été évalués quant à leur résistance au pourridié fusarien. Ces plants âgés de huit mois provenaient des cultivars Arlington et Florex. Au total, quatre cent cinquante (450) génotypes ont été inoculé avec l'une des trois races de Fusarium roseum (814, 927 et 959) en utilisant une technique d'application directe du champignon sur les racines coupées. Le degré de sensibilité au champignon a été évalué en mesurant la hauteur d'infection des tissus de la racine pivotante à partir du point d'inoculation, et par l'usage de l'échelle Horsfall-Barratt. La race 814 a provoqué plus d'infection que les   races 927 ou 959. Des différences génétiques ont été trouvées entre, et à l'intérieur des deux cultivars de trèfle rouge, avec les races 814 et 959. Aucune différence n'a été observée pour la race 927, la moins virulente. […]</description><creator>Lambert, Micheline</creator><contributor>Coulman, Bruce</contributor><date>1986</date><subject>Root rots.</subject><subject>Fusarium.</subject><subject>Red clover -- Breeding.</subject><title>A Study of Variation and Inheritance of Resistance to Fusarium Root Rot in Red Clover (Trifolium Pratense L.)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xp09b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fb741</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn00b1290</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A cause du bruit de fond, de la distorsion et des caractéristiques de réponse de fréquence des bandes audio similaires sur le marché des magnétophones vidéo, le potentiel de création dansCette gamme de production vidéo est très limité. La mise au point de processeurs audio digitaux à modulation de code à faible cout et de synchronisateurs de cadence offre un moyen de contourner ce problème et de réalise une réponse audio de très haute qualité. Des tests sond décrits dans ce rapport qui indiquent qu'il est possible d'utiliser ces composants avec un système d’édition vidéo programmable pour enregistrer, éditer et repasser un audio digital synchronisé avec une image vidéo. Nous donnons également une description de la première production vidéo complète utilisant ce système. Nous donnons également les détails de l'enregistrement d'un audio digital synchronisé et de tous les aspects de post-production, y compris le système de branchement électrique, l'utilisation d'un magnétophone similaire synchronisé multi-pistes, le retour à un audio digital et l’édition en résultant sur la matrice audio digitale de la production.</description><description>Due to the inadequate noise, distortion, and frequency response characteristics of the analog audio tracks found on video tape recorders, the creative potential of this side of a video production is extremely limited. The development of low-cost pulse code modulation digital audio processors and time code-based synchronizers offers a means to bypass this limitation and achieve very high-quality audio response. Described in this report are tests which indicate the feasibility of using these components in conjunction with a programmable video editing system to record, edit, and replay digital audio in synchronization with a video image. A description is also given of the first complete video production using this system. This details the recording of synchronized digital audio and all aspects of postproduction, including interconnection wiring, use of a synchronized multitrack analog recorder, layback to digital audio, and subsequent editing onto the digital audio master of the production. </description><creator>Kelln, David W.</creator><date>1986-03</date><subject>Audio-visual equipment -- Design and construction.</subject><subject>Sound -- Recording and reproducing -- Equipment and supplies.</subject><subject>Sound -- Recording and reproducing -- Digital techniques.</subject><title>The Development of a Low-Cost Synchronized PCM Digital Audio system for Video Production</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b5831.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn00b1290</identifier><degree><name>Master of Music</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v525n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Acid rain has received a considerable attention in the past decade, following numerous studies linking the emissions of the oxides of sulfur and nitrogen with the profound environmental deterioration. Recognizing the seriousness with which this issue is currently dealt with, this thesis attempts to shed some light on the subject of potential long term alterations in the engineering properties of a bonded, sensitive clay, undergoing leaching by the acid rain. A simulation of the acid rain action is conducted on a group of natural soil samples, representative of a sensitive clay. The results seem to indicate -that the clay soil exhibits a substantial immunity from the influence of dilute solutions of a sulfuric acid.</description><description>Les études sur les pluies acides sensibilisent de plus en plus les gens à la gravité de ce problème. Les résultats de la majorité de ces recherches révèlent un lien entre la détérioration environnementale et les émissions d’oxydes de sulfure et de nitrogène. Reconnaissant la gravité de ce problème, cette thèse tente d’explorer les altérations que peuvent subir l’argile naturelle attaquée par les pluies polluées. Les tests de simulation de l’effet des pluies acides sur les sois naturels, représentatives d’une argile sensible, ont été conduits. Les résultats semblent indiquer que l’argile n’est pas très affectée par les solutions diluées d’acide sulfurique.</description><creator>Hoppe, Edward</creator><contributor>Yong, Raymond</contributor><date>1986-02</date><subject>Clay soils -- Environmental aspects.</subject><subject>Clay soils -- Effect of acid rain on.</subject><subject>Soil acidity -- Environmental aspects.</subject><title>The Influence of Acid Rain on the Engineering Properties of a Sensitive Clay</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859j04z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v525n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2f75rb24t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Transposable elements are stretches of discrete DNA segments capable of rec-A independent translocation while maintaining their physical and functional integrityThe DNA of temperate bacteriophage Mu embodies the properties of both a tnasposable element and a phage. Its 37 kilobase linear double-stranded DNA is capable of catalysing and undergoing the full spectrum of DNA rearrangements characteristic of prokaryotic mobile elements. Mu DNA transposition requires the presence of the Mu encoded A and B gene products act upon sequences at the extremities of the Mu genome and catalyse the concerted nicking-ligation reactions inherent to most current models of DNA transposition. […]</description><description>Les éléments de transposition sont des segments de DNA capables de translocation indépendante du gène recA et gardent leur integrité physique et fonctionnelle durant ces mouvements. Le bactériophage tempéré Mu accomplit les fonctions de phage ainsi que d'élément de transposition. Son DNA est linéaire, double-brin et est long d'environ 37 kilobase. Le DNA de Mu peut accomplir toute la gamme de réarrangements génétiques caracteristiques des éléments mobiles de transposition. Les produits des gènes A et B codés par Mu, des enzymes codés par des gènes de le région semi-essentielles du génome de Mu ainsi que des enzymes de la cellule hôte sont nécessaires pour que Mu transpose. Les enzymes de transposition interagissent avec des séquences aux extrémités du génome de Mu et ainsi catalysent des réactions de 'bris et ligations’ proposées dans plusieurs modèles de transposition. […]</description><creator>Harel, Josee</creator><contributor>DuBow, M. S.</contributor><date>1986-03</date><subject>DNA transposition</subject><title>The CIS-Required DNA Sequences for Bacteriophage Mu DNA Transposition and Maturation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j38609343.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2f75rb24t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn9999075</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The production of housing underwent significant change in Canada's metropolis during the nineteenth century. Montreal's building permit records of one building cycle (1866-1880) constitute the basic source of data. An architectural history of the essentially British origins of Montreal's duplex housing (superposed flats) leads to a new typology of multi-family housing which dominated construction by 1880. The spatial patterns of a dichotomous market, of single-family houses versus flats, are examined. The participation in housing development by French-Canadian and secondarily by British-Canadian builders, and the absence of the Irish, is highlighted. Building activity was extremely small scale although some large-scale and corporate developers were active. Building trade artisans and entrepreneurs, local shopkeepers and skilled workmen, elements of traditional petit-bourgeois, artisanal and working-class society, were the chief builders. Through Notarial records and Government. Statutes, the methods of mortgage financing and the role of building societies and individual lenders are exposed. </description><description>Au cours du siècle dernier, la construction domiciliaire à Montréal subit une transformation remarquable, comme en font foi les permis de construction émis entre 1866 et 1880, source fondamentale de nos données. L'histoire de l'architecture montréalaise témoigne d'une évolution pendant cette période du quadruplex aux origines britanniques vers une nouvelle typologie domiciliaire de logements superposés qui en vint à dominer le marché vers 1880. Le présent travail examine les caractéristiques spatiales de ce marché à deux pendants, où la maison unifamiliale s'oppose au duplex et au triplex. Il souligne la prépondérance des constructeurs Canadiens français, le rôle secondaire des Canadiens britanniques et l’absence des Irlandais. La construction domiciliaire se poursuivit a une échelle très modeste en dépit de l'activité déployée par certains promoteurs d'envergure, car les entrepreneurs se recrutaient principalement dans la petite bourgeoisie traditionnelle, chez les artisans et boutiquiers, et même dans la classe ouvrière. Le rôle des sociétés de construction, les sources du capital hypothécaire et l'intervention des prêteurs privés sont mis à jour, grâce au dépouillement d'actes notariaux et de statuts gouvernementaux. </description><creator>Hanna, David B.</creator><contributor>Olson, Sherry</contributor><date>1986-03</date><subject>Real estate development -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Housing -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>City planning -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>Montreal, A City Built by Small Builders, 1867-1880</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v8382984.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn9999075</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hm50tv05z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Raw fuel-grade peat was treated with a surfactant, one of three inorganic salts or one of three cationic polymers. The pretreated peat was then pressed to determine the effect of these additives on water removal. Pressed peat samples treated with these compounds were resuspended in water and the weight percent of particles settled after one hour was measured. This data was correlated with the water removal data and provided insight into the effect of each additive on peat dewatering. Using a batch heating system, raw peat was heated to temperatures below 200C before mechanical dewatering. Variations were made in heat up time, residence time and holding temperature. After heat treatment, dewatering could be further enhanced by the addition of one of the cationic polymers, chitosan hydrochloride.The effect of several pretreatment processes on the quality of the expressed peat water was monitored. Toxicity tests showed that growth of microorganisms was uninhibited by the peat waters.</description><description>La tourbe energetique a été tratee avec un surfactant, un des trois seis inorganiques ou des trois polymeres de charge positive. La tourbe, preablement traitee, a ete comprimee pour ensuite determiner l’effect des additifs sur l’extraction d’eau. Apres une heure, le pourcentage de poids des particules deposees a ete mesure. Les resultats obtenues ont été compares avec les resultats d’extraction d’eau donnant plus d’information sur l’effet d chaque sur la deshumification de la tourbe. Utilisant un systeme de bain chaud, la tourbe est shauffee a une temperature inferieure a 2000C avant la heshumification mecanique. Des variations ont ete faites avec des parametres thermiques. Apres traitement thermiques, la deshumification peut etre encore plus augmente par l’addition de chitosan hydrochlorique, un des trois polymeres de charge positive. L’effet de plusiers traitement sur la qualite de l’eau de tourbe  a ete observee. Des test pour contamination ont montre que le developpement de microorganismes n’a pas ete affecte par l’eau de tourbe. </description><creator>Glass, David S.</creator><contributor>Cooper, D.G.</contributor><date>1986-03</date><subject>Peat -- Drying.</subject><subject>Peat -- Effect of surface active agents on.</subject><title>A Chemical/Thermal Pretreatment Process for the Dewatering of Fuel-Grade Peat</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qf442.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hm50tv05z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t722hc247</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Anne Hebert, qui, dans "le Torrent", dépeint des fermiers, n’a jamais fait de concession à l'école du terroir. Elle n’a pas non plus conféré de fonction éthique a son écriture qui conteste (toujours davantage) les valeurs religieuses -- entreprises amorcée dès 1942 dans Les Songes en équilibre. L'indépendance de l'écrivaine par rapport aux instances moralo-nationalistes qui prétendaient régir les arts, s'accompagne d'une sacralisation de la littérature. La vie dans la famille de Maurice Hebert, les connaissances inculquées dans les nombreux établissements d’enseignement religieux qu’elle a fréquentés, les influences littéraires avouées et même l'expérience professionnelle acquise à l'ONF permettent de reconstituer en partie la genèse de sa vocation poétique. […]</description><description>Despite the fact that she does, in "Le Torrent", depict some farmers, Anne Hebert never made any concessions to the école du terroir. Nor has she endowed her writing with any ethical- function. To the contrary, her texts become increasingly critical of religious values – an undertaking begun in 1942, in les Songes en équilibre. To her independence vis-a-vis contemporary moral and nationalist authorities who claimed to govern the arts, the author allied the notion of the sacralisation of literature. We have taken into consideration the following factors, which permit a partial reconstitution of the genesis of Anne Hébert's poetical vocation: "Life in the Maurice Hébert family; knowledge acquired in the numerous confessional- schools Anne Hébert attended; attended literary influences as well as the professional- experience she gained at the National Film Board of Canada. […]</description><creator>Fortin, Marcel</creator><date>1986-08</date><subject>Hébert, Anne -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Anne Hérbert ou la Sacralisation de l’Écriture</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214r592.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t722hc247</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fq977x36z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Neurological ~rehabilitation emphasizes gait retraining, however, poor patterns often persist. Interactive training (partial progressing to full weight beading (FWB) combined with treadmill stimulation) allowed recovery of locomotion in spinalized cats. Normal ~espouses to partial weight should be known, before applying this strategy to patients. Thus, 10 normal males walked on a treadmill with 0, 30, 50 and 70% of their body weight supported (BWS). At each BWS, the subjects walked slower than normal. To dissociate speed from weight changes each subject walked at the same speed FWB and with BWS.  […]</description><description>La réhabilitation neurologique accentue la rééducation de la marche, mais souvent un patron anormal persiste. Les chats ayant une lésion spinale complète récupèrent leurs fonctions locomotrices à la suite d’entrainements interactifs [(stimulation du tapis roulant combiné au support de poids progressif (SPP)]. Les réactions normales au support de poids partiel doivent être connues avant d’être utilisés sur le patient. Lorsque 10 males normaux marchent sur le tapis roulant à 30, 50 et 70% du poids du corps supporté (PCS), ils ralentissent à chaque PCS. Pour dissocier la vitesse aux changements de poids, chaque individu marche à la même vitesse avec SPP et PCS. […]</description><creator>Finch, L.</creator><contributor>Arsenault, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Barbeau, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1986</date><subject>Gait retraining</subject><title>The Influence of Partial Weight Bearing on Normal Gait: A Novel Approach for Gait Retraining in Neurological Patients</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644t96b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fq977x36z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j789c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T13:37:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L’immunité anti-tumorale chez les patients atteints de cancer est mesureé in vitro par un test d’inhibition d’adhérence leukocytaire (IAL) dirigé centre un composé de surface de cellules tumorales identifié comme étant un neoantigène spécifique à un organ (NSO). Un NSO provenant d’un cancer du poumon a été purifié à partir du milieu de culture ayant servi à la culture d'une lignée cellulaire obtenue à partir d'un cancer du poumon. L'étape de purification était contrôlée par un test IAL. Suite au développement d'une technique de séparation physicochimique en quatre étapes, incluant séparation par échange d'ion, filtration par gel et affinité Bleu Sepharose, on a pu obtenir une activité NSO enrichie d'un facteur de 100 à 1000 fois plus. […]</description><description>Antitumor immunity in cancer patients as measured by the in vitro assay of leukocyte adherence inhibition (LAI) is directed to a tumor cell surface component known as an organ-specific neoantigen (OSN). A lung cancer OSN was purified from the spent medium of a lung cancer cell line grown in chemically defined medium. The purification of the OSN was monitored with the LAI assay. A four-step physicochemical separation procedure was developed which included ibn-exchange, molecular-sieve and Blue Sepharose affinity separations and gave an enrichment of OSN activity of between 100- and 1000-fold. […]</description><creator>Dubois, Anthony E. J.</creator><contributor>Thomson, David M. P. </contributor><date>1986-09</date><subject>Human lung cancer cells</subject><subject>Neoantigen</subject><title>The Isolation and Characterization of an Organ-Specific Neoantigen from a Human Lung Cancer Cell Line Grown in Tissue Culture</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580q04g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j789c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):5025</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>