<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:58:36Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43450" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290999n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:22:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In flotation, bubbles are the transport medium of mineral  particles and water. The recovery of fine hydrophilic gangue is related to the  recovery of water, which impacts the grade of the concentrate. In the solution  (pulp) phase, water is transported as a layer on the bubble surface and as a  trailing wake. The amount of water depends on bubble size, gas rate and, it is  hypothesized, frother type. Frothers are surface-active reagents that reduce bubble size by  retarding coalescence. To isolate the effect of frother type (chemistry) on water  transport from that of bubble size and gas rate an appropriate independent variable  had to be established. Bubble surface area flux and gas holdup were proposed and  correlated against the overflow rate of water from a bubble column at a given foam  depth which was used as a measure of water carrying rate. Gas holdup is established as the independent variable and it is  shown that the common frothers can be grouped into families based on the gas  holdup-carrying rate relationship. No relation was found between water carrying rate  and bubble surface area flux. Possible reasons are considered.</description><creator>Moyo, Pamela</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Characterization of frothers by water carrying rate</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zh38m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290999n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s1784m32c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Life signal detection is an old concept with contemporary  applications, including predicting cardiac arrhythmia from heart signals, and  helping in the search for lost survivors. The underlying principle of the microwave  heart monitoring is based on detecting the changes in the reflected microwaves  caused by the movement of the chest wall in response to respiration and ventricular  activities. This thesis seeks to analyze the induced current distribution and  specific-absorption rate (SAR) using the finite-difference time-domain (FDTD) method  on an accurate two-dimensional thoracic model provided by the Visual Human Project  (VHP). Additional test cases are analyzed which model the  two-dimensional heart model in different media, such as air, water, and lungs. The  signal used in all simulations is a 1V/m 10GHz TM plane wave. The discussion of the  two-dimensional results yields a preliminary assessment of microwave-tissue  interaction in the process of heart monitoring at microwave  frequencies.</description><creator>Yak, Nicolas</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Finite-difference time-domain analysis of microwave heart monitoring</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494902w.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s1784m32c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:37720d30s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Under the Treaty Establishing the European Community,  corporations are entitled to free establishment. Recently, the European Court of  Justice's Inspire Art decision has clarified its scope and has in principle  introduced place of incorporation doctrine as choice-of-law rule, thus granting  corporations free choice of the Member State of incorporation. In the US, free  choice has caused the "Delaware Effect". This paper analyzes if Inspire  Art will cause a similar development in the EU. The EU and US contexts will be  compared. Germany will serve as an example. As different circumstances exist in the  EU, free choice is more limited and fraught with uncertainties. The thesis of this  paper is that regulatory competition in the EU is unlikely and not desirable because  of cultural differences. Therefore, minimum harmonization is  preferable.</description><creator>Bettinger, Nicole</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Corporation law -- European Union countries</subject><subject>Corporation law -- United States.</subject><subject>Jurisdiction -- European Union countries.</subject><subject>Jurisdiction -- United States.</subject><title>Europe's inspired journey : destination Delaware?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p2909973.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/37720d30s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k35695117</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Attempts by the international community to establish a  comprehensive global framework for protection of foreign investment have not yet  succeeded. The Russian Federation has remained aloof from these efforts. Its  attention instead has been focused on the need to redesign its internal legal  framework to accommodate the transition to a market economy. The first aim of this thesis is to identify the major policy  issues that inform the multilateral investment protection debate and to identify the  motives that have influenced Russia not to participate. The second aim is to provide  an analysis of the progress that the Russian Federation has made in reforming its  internal legal framework to better accommodate and protect foreign investment and  identify the deficiencies that still have to be addressed.</description><creator>Belevici, Stanislav</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Investments, Foreign -- Law and legislation -- Russia (Fedeeration).</subject><subject>Investments -- Law and legislation -- Russia (Federation)</subject><title>The legal framework for investment protection in [the] Russian federation /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010q55d.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k35695117</identifier><degree><name>Master of Laws</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Comparative Law</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn106z68b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Disorders of feeding and swallowing are thought to impact up to  60% of residents of long-term care facilities. Traditional methods of evaluating  feeding are inappropriate for use with an elderly population or have poor  reliability and validity. The objective of this project was to create a new  assessment of feeding skills, that could be administered during the observation of a  meal in the patient's own environment. Potential items for inclusion in the McGill Ingestive Skills  Assessment (MISA) were generated from a review of the literature. A focus group of  10 professionals actively involved in dysphagia was recruited to select the items,  generate additional items based on clinical expertise, divide the items into scales  and develop a method for scoring each item. At the end of this process, the MISA had  190 items in 7 scales. Each item was scored using a 2, 3, 4, or 5 point ordinal  scale. A field test on 50 elderly individuals provided data on which inter-rater  reliability, item-total and item scale correlations could be evaluated. A second  focus group eliminated all but 50 items from the assessment using the results of  these statistical analyses as a guide. The scoring was made uniform, with four  descriptors per item. A small field test of 33 patients indicated that the MISA  showed signs of sufficient psychometric rigor to warrant large-scale reliability and  validity testing. One hundred and two individuals were tested in the psychometric  study. The analysis of inter-item correlations and item reliability permitted the  removal of an additional 8 items and the collapse of the scoring to 3 points per  item. The inter-rater and intra-rater reliability, the stability of scores over  time, the concurrent validity and predictive validity of the MISA were analysed  using the data from the remaining 42 items, on the 3 point scale. MISA scale and  total scores were related as hypothesized to measures of related constructs. Linear  and flexible survival analyses indicated that the MISA total score and the score on  selected scales is predictive of time to death and time to pulmonary infection. It  was determined that the MISA has sufficient psychometric rigor to permit the  evaluation of, and treatment planning for, individual patients. The availability of  this important assessment tool will improve the quality of care that professionals  can offer to elderly persons with ingestive skill loss.</description><creator>Lambert, Heather Christine</creator><contributor>Wood-Dauphinee, Sharon (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Gisel, Erika G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Gerontology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><title>The development, validation and reliability testing of an assessment of functional ingestive skills of elderly persons with neurogenic dysphagia /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c534fp47v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn106z68b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x920fx39s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>As of September 1999, all donated units of blood in Canada  undergo a process known as pre-storage leukoreduction. This process removes a  significant proportion of white blood cells from blood at the time of donation. The  decision to implement universal leukoreduction was based on fairly strong evidence  that leukoreduction was beneficial in some adult populations such as cardiac and  colorectal surgical patients. However, very little information exists on its  effectiveness in other populations such as the neonatal population. The purpose of  this thesis was three fold: (1) to conduct a systematic review of the literature to  assess the effectiveness of leukoreduction; (2) to undertake a methods paper  outlining the optimal design to study the effectiveness of leukoreduction given its  universal nature; and (3) to conduct a study assessing the effectiveness of  leukoreduction in the neonatal population. The results of the systematic review elucidate the paucity of  well-conducted, methodologically sound studies evaluating the effectiveness of  leukoreduction in the neonatal population. The current evidence suggests that  leukoreduction may be effective. However, further studies are needed especially with  respect to clinically important outcomes. The lack of convincing data and the  significant cost of leukoreduction mandate evaluations to determine its clinical and  economic impact. The methods manuscript describes important methodological issues  confronted in the design of the before/after evaluation. Because of the universal  application of many transfusion interventions, one has to consider, carefully, the  methodological rigor with which these interventions are evaluated. The  methodological considerations discussed are: (1) threats to internal validity; (2)  precision; and (3) generalizability. Properly conceived, designed, conducted, and  analyzed, such a before/after study design can yield informative  associations. The final paper presents the results of the before/after study.  The study included a total of 515 infants &lt;1250 grams from three sites across  Canada. The effect of leukoreduction on our primary outcome of nosocomial bacteremia  was an odds ratio of 0.59 (95%CI: 0.34--1.01). Crude and adjusted rates for all  major neonatal morbidities suggest that leukoreduction improved all outcomes. The  adjusted odds ratio for a composite measure of any major neonatal morbidity was 0.31  (95%CI: 0.17--.56). Based on the results of this study, it is concluded that the  implementation of universal prestorage leukoreduction significantly improved  clinical outcomes in premature infants requiring blood transfusions.</description><creator>Fergusson, Dean Anthony</creator><contributor>Hebert, Paul C. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Shapiro, Stan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>Effectiveness leukoreduction in neonates</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472w98v.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fx39s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f6396</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Drugs of abuse are thought to have the common action of  increasing dopaminergie transmission in the mesolimbic dopamine (DA) pathway,  specifically in the nucleus accumbens (NAc). However, sedative-hypnotics, including  the barbiturates, are anomalous in that they appear to stimulate DA release from the  NAc at doses that are generally lower than their reinforcing doses. The fact that  barbiturates have a long history of abuse in humans and are potent reinforcers in  laboratory animals, but are behaviourally reinforcing only at doses that decrease DA  release from the NAc, raises questions about the neuropharmacological mechanism of  reinforcement in these drugs. Indeed, of the numerous studies that have examined the  reinforcing properties of barbiturates, none have examined the pharmacological basis  of their reinforcing effects. The conditioned place preference (CPP) paradigm is a widely used  behavioural test that assesses the reinforcing capacity of stimuli by the ability of  conditioned stimuli to evoke an approach response. Using this paradigm, systemic  administration of pentobarbital (15 mg/kg) induced a significant place preference.  Furthermore, pretreatment with GABAA, DA, and opioid receptor antagonists blocked  the pentobarbital-induced place preference. Sodium barbital, a longer-acting  barbiturate also induced a significant CPP when systemically administered (8 and 24  mg/kg). Moreover, the reinforcing effect of this place preference is centrally  mediated, assessed by the significant CPP obtained with intracerebroventricular  (ICV) injections of barbital (240 and 480 mug). A number of different brain sites are involved in the  reinforcing effects of drugs of abuse. Microinjections of barbital into the  periaqueductal gray (25 mug) or posterior ventral tegmental area (VTA; 15 mug), but  not into other areas, such as the amygdala and anterior VTA, produced a place  preference. Furthermore, opioid (naloxone methiodide) and GABAA receptor (SR 95531)  antagonists administered into these areas blocked the ICV barbital place preference.  Given these findings, barbiturate reinforcement appears to be mediated by the same  neural substrates and neurochemical systems as other drugs of abuse, such as opiates  and ethanol. The implications of these results and the use of barbital in the place  preference paradigm to investigate the neuropharmacological mechanisms of  barbiturate reinforcement are discussed.</description><creator>Bossert, Jennifer Marie</creator><contributor>Franklin, Keith B. J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Psychology, Physiological.</subject><title>Investigation of the neuropharmacological mechanisms of barbiturate reinforcement using the conditioned place preference paradigm</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w0323595.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f6396</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149q44w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this dissertation, we investigate the relationship between  visual attention and eye movement programming mechanisms in the brain. As a first  step in this investigation, we demonstrate a link between microsaccades, or tiny eye  movements that occur during periods of fixation, and covert attention shifts.  Specifically, we employ psychophysical tasks that involve covert spatial attention  shifts to peripheral cues, and we correlate the time courses of microsaccade  occurrences in these tasks with the time courses of attention shifts, as revealed by  the effects of these shifts on behavioral performance. Our results suggest that  microsaccades, rather than being randomly distributed, have directions that are  directly correlated with the directions of covert attention shifts. These results  therefore suggest that microsaccades occur because of subliminal activation of the  oculomotor system by covert attention. Besides providing a plausible explanation for much of the known  phenomenology associated with microsaccades, the above link between microsaccades  and covert attention means that the first may be used to track the latter. We  demonstrate an example of such tracking by using microsaccades as a psychophysical  tool to analyze the patterns of covert attention shifts that take place in typical  visual tasks. In addition to revealing expected covert attention shifts in our  tasks, microsaccade analysis reveals shifts that were previously unreported,  including ones that are tightly synchronized with manual response execution. This  analysis also shows that the patterns of attention shifts to task-relevant stimuli  that are observed in visual tasks are identical whether overt saccades are allowed  during task execution or not. The above results lead to an investigation of the implications  of overt and covert spatial attention shifts on feature processing. We present a  post-motor theory of attention whose main thesis is that feature salience is  modified in anticipation of the sensory consequences of a motor act, even if this  act is eventually suppressed. We provide psychophysical evidence for such salience  modification and show that a spatial attention shift to a location gives rise to a  feature-based attention shift to the features at that location. We also show that  such a feature-based attention shift outlasts a saccade and therefore aids the  visual system in handling the consequences of such a saccade on target  appearance.</description><creator>Hafed, Ziad M.</creator><contributor>Clark, James J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Motor theories of attention : how action serves perception in the visual system</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569512h.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149q44w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8w32r6141</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Synthetic methods were developed for the preparation of several  structurally diverse aromatic peptide nucleic acid (APNA) monomers containing all  four natural DNA bases. This set of building blocks was useful for the preparation  of oligomers designed to evaluate the hybridization properties of novel peptide  nucleic acid (PNA) analogues, which incorporate aromatic rings into their backbone.  Protocols for the solid-phase synthesis of APNA-PNA chimeras and APNA homopolymers  were also developed. Thermal denaturation experiments involving APNA-PNA chimeras  demonstrated that APNA backbones comprised of N-(2-aminomethylphenyl) glycine and  N-(2-aminobenzyl) glycine as the backbone moiety exhibited good binding affinity for  DNA and RNA. Further studies with PNA oligomers composed partly of repeating  N-(2-aminobenzyl) glycine APNAs showed that these analogues displayed good sequence  recognition for DNA and RNA. Furthermore, continuous tracts of APNA units were well  tolerated in both the triplex and duplex binding modes. The binding of APNA modified  oligomers was investigated using UV, circular dichroism spectropolarimetry (CD) and  complex formation with the cyanine dye  3-ethyl-2-[5-(3-ethyl-3H-benzothiazol-2-ylidene)-penta-1,3-dienyl]-benzothiazol-3-ium  iodide (DiSC2(5)). In the latter experiments, binding of the dye to complexes formed  between APNA modified oligomers and DNA or RNA suggested that the minor grooves of  these complexes were not drastically different from those formed in the  corresponding PNA:DNA or PNA:RNA complexes. Finally, fully modified APNA homopolymers were prepared in order  to investigate their physicochemical properties. These oligomers were found to be  essentially insoluble in aqueous buffers, which prohibited study of their binding  affinity to nucleic acids. However, a short homothymine oligomer was synthesized  which was modified at the C- and N-terminals so that it can be dissolved in water in  sufficient quantities to allow for evaluation of its recognition and binding to DNA  and RNA. Complex formation was confirmed by CD and DiSC 2(5) binding experiments.  These studies indicated that the APNA homopolymer bound to DNA and RNA, apparently  through Watson-Crick base pairing, and formed a complex that was more stable than  those formed by the corresponding homothymine DNA oligomer with complementary DNA  under similar conditions.</description><creator>Fader, Lee David, 1974-</creator><contributor>Tsantrizos, Youla (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Design, synthesis and physicochemical properties of aromatic peptide nucleic acids</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gf06g326c.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8w32r6141</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rf10v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Centenarian population studies are one of several approaches  currently used to study the aging process and characterize successful aging. I have  described a methodology permitting the simultaneous generation of RNA, DNA, protein,  and plasma samples, as well as fixed peripheral blood mononuclear cells (PBMC) and  frozen blood aliquots, from a single 10- to 30-ml sample of peripheral blood  obtained from donors of any age, and showed that although extremely old individuals  are somewhat anemic, it is possible to obtain enough biological material from their  blood to conduct aging studies. I investigated the possibility of immortalizing B-lymphocytes  from extremely old individuals, using the Epstein-Barr virus (EBV), and found that  although extremely old individuals (90+ years) possess low levels of circulating  B-lymphocytes, it is possible to immortalize B cells present in less than one  milliliter of their blood using EBV. Using biological material obtained from blood samples of  individuals of all ages by the method for blood sample processing I have described,  I studied the mRNA expression of cell death (specifically caspase) genes in  nonagenarians and centenarians, successful models of aging who have survived or  avoided age-associated diseases, as well as in their younger counterparts, to  determine whether apoptotic genes may be part of the genetic determinants of  longevity. I found that a population of extremely old individuals (90+) shows a  unique pattern of caspase mRNA expression, characterized by high levels of caspase-1  and -3, and low levels of caspase-8, mRNA, while slightly less aged individuals  (70--89) are characterized by high levels of caspase-8 mRNA expression. Furthermore,  I showed that these changes in caspase mRNA do not appear to result from age-related  changes in PBMC composition, such as decreases in CD24. Therefore, I suggest that  unique patterns of caspase mRNA result from the regulation of message abundance on a  per cell basis, via a putative regulation of caspase genes at the transcription or  RNA processing level, rather than age-associated changes in immune  profiles.</description><creator>Lacelle, Chantale</creator><contributor>Wang, Eugenia (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Aging -- physiology.</subject><subject>Blood -- cytology -- Aged.</subject><title>Blood sample processing for the study of aging, and characterization of caspase mRNA expression in peripheral blood mononuclear cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472w97k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rf10v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10wq74q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, we are examining the structural poetics of the  short story in The Comedie humaine. We first of all analyze three internal elements  of the story: narration, description and dialogue. We then study the composition of  the collections which form The Comedie humaine. Without challenging the principles of concision and  concentration, accepted since the XIXth century in regard to the short narrative,  this dissertation focuses on strategies pertaining to narration, description and  dialogue, which embrace these principles, and which enable the short narrative to  distinguish itself from the novel. Within our study of internal components, we  analyze how texts are grouped together into a collection. This is one aspect which  is an integral part of any study of the short story. Everything indicates that the short narrative favours  concentration, while the novel tends to digress. We will establish the truth of this  assertion by studying the proliferation of this narrative and narrative strategies,  by examining the functions of description and the components of the portrait, and by  analyzing discursive transgressions and the functions of dialogue. What follows will  be a study of the composition which will begin by focusing on the "Catalogue  des oeuvres de 1845", representing a state of intermediate assembling. What  concerns us here is the structure of the collection in The Comedie humaine and of  the various ways Balzac explored grouping his works together. In Balzac's work, the structural differences which exist between  the short story and the novel contribute to the actual development of the short  narrative's poetics. This dissertation therefore forms an invaluable part of  Balzacian criticism and certainly finds a place for itself in genre  theory.</description><creator>Daoust, Isabelle</creator><contributor>Lane-Mercier, Gillian (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Duquette, Jean-Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Balzac, Honoré de, 1799-1850. Comédie humaine</subject><subject>Short story</subject><title>Poétique du récit court dans La comédie humaine</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bf46g.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wq74q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k0698800g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The secretory pathway of dog pancreas, liver parenchyma,  cultured CHO cells and yeast has been analyzed with reagents focusing on the p24  family of membrane proteins. The results show that at least one of the p24s is  ribosome associated in a nascent chain dependent manner. The cell free  reconstitution of the endoplasmic reticulum (ER) cargo exit sites has demonstrated  that the p24s are involved in the generation of both the cargo exit sites and  vesicular tubular clusters (VTCs) in a COPI dependent manner. Work done in situ and  in isolated subcellular fractions has indicated that the p24-enriched cis Golgi  compartment is the primary site of retrieval of Golgi resident enzymes during  membrane maturation as well as being the boundary for the major site of cargo  (albumin) concentration. The morphogenic properties of the p24s were studied in  yeast, with DNA chip analysis revealing 160 genes whose expression was altered  coincident with the perturbation of members of the p24 family. Over expression of  one of the members of the p24 family has led to the increase in ER membranes and a  p24 enriched VTC compartment. Taken together, these data indicate that the p24s are  present both when newly synthesized cargo enter and exit the ER and that the p24s  are involved in the morphological transitions of the early secretory  pathway.</description><creator>Gushue, Jennifer Nicole</creator><contributor>Bergeron, John (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Characterization and regulation of the early secretory pathway by the p24 proteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p8418n73m.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698800g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97kq95r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In recent years, heated debates about the definition and  evolutionary role of simple, egalitarian hunter-gatherer societies have assumed a  central place in hunter-gatherer studies. Since household dynamics are bound to be  fundamental in arguments about these issues, the present study examines social  change in terms of household integration in Air Bah, a resettlement village of newly  sedentary Lanoh hunter-gatherers and forest collectors of Peninsular Malaysia. The  Lanoh have accepted inequality more readily than cooperation and binding  relationships. Household integration has remained partial because, even in  households of self-aggrandizers, younger men retain their individual autonomy. This  incomplete household integration, in turn, continues to affect kinship group and  village integration, preventing Air Bah from developing into a centralized  "village community." These findings suggest substantial revisions in our  understanding of the sociality and evolutionary significance of the  "simplest" hunter-gatherer societies.</description><creator>Dallos, Csilla</creator><contributor>Rousseau, Jerome (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2003</date><subject>Indigenous peoples -- Malaysia</subject><subject>Hunting and gathering societies -- Malaysia</subject><subject>Households -- Malaysia</subject><title>Identity and opportunity : asymmetrical household integration among the Lanoh, newly sedentary hunter-gatherers and forest collectors of Peninsular Malaysia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d025k.PDF</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kq95r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fn106z558</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis features two essays that aim to establish the foundations for a multidisciplinary approach to the study of the more visceral, motivational, and emotional bases for consumer decision making. The first essay tests the hypothesis that approach and avoidance motivations influence decision making through the process of subjective valuation. Using two versions of the Iowa Gambling Task, we find evidence supporting the view that asymmetry in the systems regulating approach and avoidance leads to systematic biases that translate to differences in performance. Specifically, we find that high sensitivity in the Behavioral Activation System (BAS) translates to valuation by feeling and insensitivity to scope in the domain of gains, while high sensitivity in the Behavioral Inhibition System translates to valuation by feeling and insensitivity to scope in the domain of losses. The second essay presents a multilevel latent variable modeling approach designed to select optimally psychophysiological measures for further analysis of within- and between-subject differences. Specifically, a multilevel structural equations model is used to illustrate the approach with data from electrodermal activity obtained from 97 subjects who completed 80 trials on the Iowa Gambling Task. Results indicate that measures based on the area under the curve of a processed waveform are well-suited to explore within- and between-subject differences in the task. I find the interpretation of these measures to be questionable in late blocks, due to a cross-level interaction with the age of participants. In the conclusion, I present explorations of consumer decision making using the conceptual framework developed in this thesis. Specifically, I use physiological data to uncover the psychological processes involved in subjective valuation, and suggest that scope insensitivity may play a role in the development of trust. Future research and implications for these findings are discussed.</description><description>Cette thèse présente deux essais dont le but commun est d'établir les fondations d'une approche multidisciplinaire pour l'étude des bases viscérales, motivationnelles et émotionnelles de la prise de décision des consommateurs. Le premier essai teste l'hypothèse que les motivations d'approche et de retrait influencent la prise de décision par l'entremise du processus d'évaluation subjective. En utilisant deux versions de la «tâche de jeu de l'Iowa», nous trouvons du support pour la position que l'asymétrie dans les systèmes régissant les motivations d'approche et de retraite crée des biais systématiques qui mènent à des différences de performance dans les tâches. Spécifiquement, nous trouvons qu'une haute sensibilité dans le système motivationnel relié à l'approche mène à une évaluation par les émotions et une insensibilité à la magnitude dans le domaine des gains, tandis qu'une haute sensibilité dans le système motivationnel relié au retrait mène à une évaluation par les émotions et une insensibilité à la magnitude dans le domaine des pertes. Le deuxième essai présente une approche de modélisation par variables latentes à deux niveaux dont le but est de choisir de façon optimale les mesures psychophysiologiques qui pourront être utilisées dans des analyses ultérieures de différences aux niveaux intra- et inter-individus. Un modèle d'équations structurelles à deux niveaux est utilisé pour illustrer l'approche avec des données électrodermales obtenues de 97 sujets ayant complété 80 sélections dans la «tâche de jeu de l'Iowa». Les résultats indiquent que les mesures basées sur l'aire sous la courbe combinées à un traitement des données brutes sont les plus appropriées pour l'exploration des différences intra- et interindividuelles qui apparaissent dans la tâche. L'interprétation de ces mesures doit par contre être remise en question pour les dernières sélections, puisqu'une interaction existe entre l'âge des participants et la progression de ces mesures au cours de l'expérience. En guise de conclusion, j'utilise le cadre conceptuel développé dans cette thèse pour présenter des explorations de la prise de décision des consommateurs. J'utilise des données physiologiques pour déterminer le processus psychologique qui mènent aux évaluations subjectives, et je suggère que l'insensibilité à la magnitude pourrait jouer un rôle dans l'établissement d'une relation de confiance. La thèse conclut avec des pistes de recherches futures, ainsi qu'une discussion des implications des résultats contenus dans la thèse.</description><creator>Desmeules, Remi</creator><contributor>Laurette Dube (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Business Administration - Marketing</subject><title>A multilevel approach for the study of consumer decision making</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000043s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fn106z558</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Desautels Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712m695x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Despite advances in neuro-oncological research and treatment strategies, malignant brain tumors remain diseases with devastating outcome. Glioblastoma multiforme (GBM) is the most common malignant brain tumor in the adult population, whereas medulloblastoma (MB) is the most prevalent brain tumor in the pediatric population. This thesis explored determinants of aggressive tumor behaviour in these tumors.  The main determinant of morbidity and mortality in GBM is the invasion of glioma cells into healthy brain parenchyma. Glioma cell invasion recapitulates the cell motility mode of neural precursor cells. In order to further understand glioma invasion, our group has performed a functional screening assay to identify effectors of glioma invasion. In chapter 2, we biologically validate one of the candidate genes identified in the aforementioned screen: downregulated in renal cell carcinoma-1 (drr-1). Results from invasion assays performed in the 3D collagen matrix model show that hDRR-1 overexpression in glioma cells leads to a hyperinvasive phenotype, whereas downregulation of hDRR-1 causes hypoinvasion of these cells. We show that hDRR-1 is highly expressed at the edge of invasive gliomas. Interestingly, hDRR-1 knock-down prevents cell rear retraction by affecting focal adhesion disassembly. Taken together, these results identify hDRR-1 as a novel effector of glioma cell invasion and a potential therapeutic target in the field of glioma oncology.  While glioma invasion is analogous to neural progenitor cell motility, MB tumorigenesis has been associated with deregulation of signaling pathways known to control neural progenitor development in the cerebellum. In the final chapter, we explore the role of the Wnt pathway in the biology of MB. Our results showed that activation of the canonical Wnt pathway was not mitogenic in the context of MB cell lines. We demonstrate that cells that undergo nuclear translocation of β-catenin exhibited striking cell morphology chang</description><description>Malgré les progrès réalisés dans la recherche en neuro-oncologie et les développements de nouvelles thérapies, les tumeurs cérébrales malignes demeurent des maladies avec un mauvais pronostic de survie. Le glioblastome multiforme (GBM) est la tumeur cérébrale maligne la plus commune chez l'adulte, tandis que le médulloblastome (MB) est la tumeur cérébrale plus répandue chez les enfants. Cette thèse vise à comprendre les éléments qui déterminent l'aggressivité de ces tumeurs.   Le principal déterminant de morbidité et de mortalité du GBM est l'invasivité du gliome dans le parenchyme cérébral normal. Afin de mieux comprendre l'activité invasive du gliome, nous avons effectué un crible fonctionel afin d'identifier les effecteurs de ce processus. Nous avons identifié un gène potentiellement impliqué dans l'invasion du gliome dont hDRR-1 (human downregulated in renal cell carcinoma-1). Des essais en matrice de collagène en trois dimensions montrent que la surexpression de hDRR-1 dans des cellules de gliome promouvoit l'invasivité de ces cellules tumorales, alors qu'une diminution d'expression de hDRR-1 réduit l'invasivité tumorale. Nous montrons aussi que hDRR-1 est fortement exprimée à la périphérie des gliomes invasifs et  que la diminution de l'expression de hDRR-1 affecte le désassemblage des adhésions focales et contrevient à la migration cellulaire.  Nos résultats démontrent que hDDR-1 est un effecteur dans l'activité invasive des cellules de gliome et suggérent ainsi que hDRR-1 constitute une nouvelle cible thérapeutique contre le GBM.  Alors que le prognostic d'un GBM est associé à l'invasivité de la tumeur, celui du MB est relié la dérégulation des voies de signalisation contrôlant la prolifération des cellules progénitrices du cervelet. Dans le dernier chapitre de cette thèse, nous explorons le rôle de la voie Wnt dans la biologie du MB. Nos résultats ont montré que l'activation de la voie canonique</description><creator>Guimaraes de Oliveira, Roberta Maria</creator><contributor>Rolando Fausto Del Maestro (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Cell</subject><title>Targeting determinants of aggressiveness in malignant brain tumours: the role of hDRR-1 in glioma invasion and Wnt signaling in medulloblastoma biology</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059c787w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712m695x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z316q1882</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les pulsars, des  étoiles à neutrons tournant rapidement sur elles-mêmes, sont reconnus pour leur vitesse de rotation très régulière. Les jeunes pulsars, par contre, présentent fréquemment des comportements qui dévient du ralentissement uniforme de leur vitesse de rotation: des glitchs, variations brutales de la fréquence de révolution qui nous aident à comprendre l'intérieur des plusars, et le bruit chronométrique, une variation stochastique de la phase de rotation sur une longue échelle de temps. Les pulsars les plus jeunes nous offrent aussi un aperçu de la physique qui gouverne le ralentissement de la vitesse de rotation par l'indice de freinage, un paramètre qui relie la fréquence de rotation d'un pulsar au torque qui agit sur lui, et dont la valeur diminue graduellement.  Cette thèse discute du chronométrage à long terme de deux jeunes pulsars. Tout d'abord, nous présentons des observations de PSR J0205+6449 acquises avec l'Observatoire de  Green Bank, l'Observatoire Jodrell Bank ainsi que le Rossi X-ray Timing Explorer. Nous présentons l'analyse du chronométrage à phase cohérente montrant du bruit chronométrique ainsi que deux glitchs. Nous présentons aussi une analyse du profil du pulse en rayons X montrant que le pulsar est détectable jusqu'à ~40 keV et ne varie pas significativement sur quatre ans. Nous rapportons une mesure de la différence de phase entre le pulse radio et le pulse en rayons X, montrant que le pulse radio précède le pulse en rayons X par 0.10+/-0.01. Une compilation des différences de phase pour ce pulsar et d'autres qui émettent en rayons X et en rayons gamma montre qu'il n'y a aucune relation entre la période de rotation et la différence de phase.  Ensuite, nous présentons 10 années de suivi de PSR J1846-0258 avec le Rossi X-ray Timing Explorer. Nous rapportons la première mesure de l'indice de freinage pour ce pulsar, n=2.65+/-0.01, le sixième indice mesuré à ce jour, et montrons que ce pul</description><description>Pulsars are rapidly rotating neutron stars which are often noted for their very regular rotation rates. Young pulsars however, frequently exhibit two types of deviations from steady spin down, ``glitches'' - sudden jumps in spin frequency, which provide insight into pulsar interiors, and ``timing noise,'' a smooth stochastic wander of the  pulse phase over long time periods. The youngest pulsars also offer a window into the physics that govern pulsar spin down via the measurement of the "braking index'' - a parameter that relates the observable spin frequency of the pulsar with the slowing down torque acting on the neutron star.  This thesis discusses long-term timing observations of two young pulsars. First, we present observations of  PSR J0205+6449, acquired with the Green Bank Telescope, the Jodrell Bank Observatory and the Rossi X-ray Timing Explorer. We present phase-coherent timing analyses showing timing noise and two spin-up glitches. We also present an X-ray pulse profile analysis showing that the pulsar is detected up to approximately 40 keV and does not vary appreciably over four years. We report the phase offset between the radio and X-ray pulse, showing that the radio pulse leads by 0.10+/-0.01 in phase. We compile measurements of phase offsets for this and other X-ray and gamma-ray pulsars and show that there is no relationship between pulse period and phase offset.  Next, we present 10 years of monitoring of PSR J1846-0258 with the Rossi X-ray Timing Explorer. We report the first measurement of the braking index for this pulsar, n=2.65+/-0.01, only the sixth such measurement ever made, and show that the pulsar experienced a small glitch in 2001.  In May 2006, PSR J1846-0258 was briefly transformed: it exhibited a series of X-ray bursts, a dramatic increase in the source flux, and significant softening of its X-ray spectrum - behaviours best explained in the context of the magnetar model.  PSR J1846-0258 was thus identified as the first rotation-po</description><creator>Livingstone, Margaret Anne</creator><contributor>Victoria Kaspi (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Physics - Astronomy and Astrophysics</subject><title>Timing young pulsars: challenges to standard pulsar spin-down models</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83kz69r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z316q1882</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fh50z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'objectif principal de l'étude a été d'examiner les taux de prévalence des problèmes émotionnels et comportementaux parmi les enfants Pakistanais. L'effet dû à l'âge et au sexe ont également été étudié. La cohérence interne et la validité conceptuelle du CBCL de l'Ourdou ont été examinées. De plus, un prélevé des échantillons de Pakistanais fut comparé à celle d'une démographique Américaine. Les parents de 600 enfants âgés de 6 à 16 ans ont complété le CBCL en Ourdou, avec l'échantillon divisé également entre garçons et filles. Les données ont été recueillies parmi les écoles privées et publiques dans la ville Pakistanaise de Lahore.  Une plus haute prévalence de problèmes d'internalisation comparée aux problèmes d'externalisation a été trouvée dans l'échantillon. Dans le cadre de syndrome empirique, soucieux/déprimé était la plus répandue mais parmi l'échelle DSM, les problèmes somatiques ont été la plus répandue. Semblable aux autres cultures, il y avait d'importantes différences entre les sexes avec un degré plus élevé de problème d'extériorisation parmi les garçons comparativement aux filles. L'inverse était vrai pour les problèmes d'internalisation.  Les problèmes d'internalisation augmentent avec l'âge mais les problèmes d'extériorisation diminuent avec l'âge. Malgré les ressemblances interculturelles dans les tendances du développement, il y avait un effet accordé par la culture. Fondé sur les critères de Cohen (1988), l'effet de la Culture était moyenne (0.06) pour les résultats totale. La comparaison interculturelle a indiqué que les enfants Pakistanais avaient de meilleurs résultats sur toutes les échelles sauf ceux des problèmes qui font réfléchir. Les résultants peuvent être attribués à l'augmentation de la violence et du terrorisme à Lahore. Les constatations actuelles soutiennent le model écologique-transactionnel. Il y avait également des interactions signif</description><description>The first objective of the present study was to investigate the prevalence rates of emotional and behavioural problems among Pakistani children. Age and gender effects were also investigated. The internal consistency and construct validity of the Urdu Child Behavior Checklist (CBCL) were examined. In addition, the Pakistani sample was compared to a demographically similar American sample. Parents of 600 children ranging in age from 6 to 16 years completed the Urdu CBCL, with the sample divided equally between boys and girls.  Data were collected from private and public schools in the Pakistani city of Lahore. A higher prevalence of Internalizing Problems as compared to Externalizing Problems was found in the overall sample. Within empirical syndromes, Anxious/Depressed was the most prevalent whereas among the DSM-oriented scales, Somatic Problems were the most prevalent. Similar to other cultures, there were significant gender differences with a higher degree of Externalizing Problems scores among boys as compared to girls. The converse was true for Internalizing Problems. Consistent with other cultures, Internalizing Problems increased with age whereas Externalizing Problems decreased with age. Despite the cross-cultural similarities in developmental trends, there was a significant effect of culture. Based on Cohen's criteria (1988), the effect size for Culture was medium (.06) for Total Problems scores. Cross-cultural comparisons indicated that Pakistani children had higher scores on all the scales except Thought Problems. The high Pakistani scores may be attributed to the current increase in violence and terrorism in Lahore. Current findings support the ecological-transactional model. There were also some significant interactions. Findings also indicated that the Urdu CBCL has adequate internal consistency in the current sample. With regard to construct validity, there is good convergent validity whereas discriminant validity needs to be improved. The theoreti</description><creator>Haider, Mariam</creator><contributor>Ingrid Sladeczek (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Education - Psychology</subject><title>Emotional and behavioural problems among Pakistani children</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2v23vt736.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fh50z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x346d4628</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Près de la surface terrestre, la réfraction atmosphérique affecte la propagation des ondes radars. Cette caractéristique de l'atmosphère, qu'on nomme la réfractivité, est spatialement complexe et mal connue. Dans cette thèse, la structure de la réfractivité ainsi que ses erreurs sont caractérisés. La réfractivité est mesurée à partir du déphasage des échos radars provenant de cibles terrestres. Ce déphasage est une fonction de la complexité du terrain ainsi que des conditions de propagations. Ces deux facteurs sont analysés statistiquement afin de simuler l'incertitude attendue (le bruit) de la phase des échos radars affectant les mesures de réfractivité. Les simulations ainsi conduites possèdent un niveau de bruit sur la phase beaucoup plus petit que celui des mesures instrumentales. Cette observation suggère que le bruit sur la phase causé par le terrain et les conditions de propagation a un impact limité sur les mesures de réfractivité comparé au bruit provenant d'autres sources tel que les cibles mobiles. Dans un deuxième temps, la structure verticale de la réfractivité est étudiée afin de déduire les conditions de propagation en basse altitude. L'étendue des échos de sol observés à faibles élévations est affectée par la trajectoire des ondes radars qui à son tour est affectée par le gradient vertical de la réfractivité. Cette étude simule l'étendue des échos de sols en supposant différents gradients de réfractivité. Les gradients qui mènent à la meilleure ressemblance entre l'étendue des échos simulée et observée sont utilisés pour estimer les gradients réels de l'atmosphère. La validation des résultats est ensuite faite par comparaison avec d'autres instruments. Malgré le fait que les échos de sols doivent être identifiés pour une performance optimale, cette nouvelle technique démontre la possibilité d'inférer de nouvelles informations sur l'atmosphère en basse altitude à partir d'éch</description><description>Near-surface atmospheric refraction, often characterized by the quantity refractivity, affects the propagation of the radar beam, yet it is poorly measured due to its complex pattern. The aim of this thesis is to characterize the structure of near-surface refractivity and its errors.  The refractivity retrieval in the horizontal is obtained from the radar phase measurements that can be affected systematically by the variability of ground target heights over complex terrain coupled with propagation conditions. This study characterizes such factors statistically and reproduces the expected uncertainty (noisiness) by simulating phase for the assessment of the radar refractivity retrieval. However, the noisiness of simulated phase is much smaller compared with that of observations suggesting that such factors are incapable of characterizing moving ground targets and thus insufficient to fully explain the phase noisiness.  The vertical structure of refractivity is, on the other hand, characterized in order to inform about low-level propagation conditions. The coverage of radar ground echo observed at low elevation angles is affected by the path of the radar beam determined with the vertical gradient of refractivity. Hence, this study simulates the coverage of ground targets with given vertical gradient of refractivity and compares it with the observed one. The best match between the simulation and observation is used to determine the radar estimate of refractivity changes in the vertical. The results are validated with the estimates from several sounding instruments. Although the identification of ground targets is required for better performance, this novel technique shows certain skill in extracting additional low-level atmospheric information out of radar measurements from ground targets. In both studies, the characterization of ground targets observed by radar plays a critical role: on one hand, it allows us to extract the structure of the near-ground refractivity</description><creator>Park, Shinju</creator><contributor>Frederic Fabry (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Atmospheric Sciences</subject><title>On the estimation of near-surface atmospheric refraction uing scanning radar</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j140x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d4628</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405s974f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse présente un procédé à plasma hybride permettant la synthèse en une seule étape de nanoparticules métalliques fonctionnalisées en surface. Le procédé utilise une décharge pulsée par arc cathodique pour assurer la synthèse de nanoparticules à partir d'une cible métallique. Ces particules sont ensuite revêtues et fonctionnalisées en vol au moyen d'une polymérisation par plasma dans une décharge radio fréquentielle. Cette dernière décharge a été soutenue dans une variété de précurseurs organiques, le choix duquel affectera les propriétés de surface des particules. Lorsque l'éthane est utilisé comme gaz plasmagène, une surface super hydrophobe est engendrée. En contrepartie, lorsque l'éthylène glycol est utilisé comme monomère pour la polymérisation par plasma, une surface super hydrophile en résulte. Ce dernier traitement améliore notamment les propriétés de dispersion des particules dans des solvants polaires.  De plus, les nanoparticules modifiées en surface à l'aide d'éthylène glycol peuvent être collectées dans un liquide à même le réacteur pour former un nanofluide. Les suspensions nanométriques formées de cette façon sont stables sur une plus grande plage de température que les suspensions de nanoparticules stabilisées au moyen d'un surfactant. Aussi, la nature hydrophile du revêtement organique à base d'éthylène glycol (lorsqu'il est déposé sur des nanoparticules de titane) peut aider à réduire le caractère thrombogénique d'implants en acier inoxydable, sans diminuer leur résistance à la corrosion. Une investigation détaillée de la production en phase gazeuse des radicaux utilisés pour la fonctionnalisation est présentée, ainsi qu'une caractérisation approfondie de la morphologie et de la chimie de surface des nanoparticules produites.</description><description>This thesis presents a dual plasma process allowing for the single-step synthesis of surface functionalized metal nanoparticles. The process uses a pulsed cathodic arc discharge to erode a metal target and form nanoparticles. These nanoparticles are then coated in flight through plasma polymerization in a radio-frequency glow discharge. This discharge was sustained in a wide range of organic precursors to affect the resulting surface properties of the nanoparticles. Using ethane as the plasma polymerizing monomer, a super-hydrophobic surface is formed. Alternatively, the use of ethylene glycol to modify the particle results in the formation of a super-hydrophilic surface. This treatment is shown to improve dispersion of the nanoparticles into polar media.   Surface-modified nanoparticles were collected in situ in a liquid flowing inside the dual plasma reactor to form a nanofluid. Suspensions formed via this process are shown to be stable over a wide temperature range, compared to suspensions stabilized using surfactants that can be thermally unstable. Moreover, the hydrophilic nature of the ethylene glycol-based plasma polymer coating (when deposited onto titanium nanoparticles) is demonstrated to reduce the expected thrombogenicity of blood-contacting stainless steel implants, without adversely affecting the implants' corrosion resistance. A detailed investigation into the gas phase reactions that lead to these hydrophilic surface properties is presented, along with an in-depth characterization of the morphology and surface chemistry of the nanoparticles.</description><creator>Tavares, Jason</creator><contributor>Sylvain Coulombe (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Engineering - Chemical</subject><title>Dual plasma synthesis of functionalized metal nanoparticles: from enhanced surface properties to stable nanofluids</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wq62x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405s974f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pg15bf31v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduced exotic predators can restructure biotic communities and alter the functioning of ecosystems. The round goby Neogobius melanostomus, a Eurasian fish, has spread throughout the lower Great Lakes and, in recent years, has colonized the upper St. Lawrence River. A few studies have recorded the impacts of this predator on benthic communities in the Great Lakes, highlighting its negative effects on zebra mussels and other macroinvertebrates. In this thesis, I investigate the direct and indirect effects of the round goby on benthic macroinvertebrate communities and algae in the upper St. Lawrence River. Through an analysis of the goby's diet, I link its prey selection to observed changes in mollusc size structure and the composition of macroinvertebrates on rocky substrates. I also quantify post-invasion changes in macroinvertebrate functional feeding groups, body size of dominant taxa, and community richness, evenness and abundance. Finally, I present evidence of a trophic cascade – an increase in algal biomass driven by the negative impacts of gobies on algivorous macroinvertebrates. These changes have significant implications for benthic community stability, ecosystem functioning, and native fishes that rely on benthic macroinvertebrates in the upper St. Lawrence River.</description><description>Les prédateurs exotiques introduits peuvent restructurer les communautés biotiques et modifier le fonctionnement des écosystèmes. Le gobie à taches noires Neogobius melanostomus, un poisson eurasien, s'est répandu à travers les Grands Lacs inférieurs et, plus récemment, a colonisé la partie supérieure du Fleuve Saint-Laurent. Quelques études ont décrit les impacts de ce prédateur sur les communautés benthiques dans les Grands Lacs, en mettant l'accent sur ses effets néfastes sur les moules zébrées et les autres macroinvertébrés. Dans ce mémoire, j'étudie les effets directs et indirects du gobie à taches noires sur les communautés benthiques de macroinvertébrés et sur les algues dans la partie supérieure du Fleuve Saint-Laurent. À travers d'une analyse du régime alimentaire du gobie, je relie sa sélectivité de proies aux changements observés à la structure de taille corporelle des mollusques et à la composition des macroinvertébrés associés aux substrats rocheux. Je quantifie aussi les changements après l'invasion aux guildes alimentaires de macroinvertébrés, à la taille corporelle des taxons de macroinvertébrés dominantes, et à la richesse taxonomique, à l'égalité taxonomique et à l'abondance des communautés, suite à l'invasion du gobie. Finalement, je présente des preuves d'une cascade trophique – une augmentation de la biomasse des algues causée par les impacts néfastes des gobies sur les macroinvertébrés algivores. Ces changements ont des implications importantes pour la stabilité des communautés benthiques, le fonctionnement de l'écosystème, et pour les poissons indigènes qui dépendent des macroinvertébrés benthiques dans la partie supérieure du Fleuve Saint-Laurent.</description><creator>Kipp, Rebekah</creator><contributor>Anthony Ricciardi (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Ecology</subject><title>Impacts of an invasive benthic predator on macroinvertebrate communities in the St. Lawrence River</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cg93b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bf31v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vb69p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A novel vacuum (&lt; 20 mTorr) encapsulation technology for the packaging of micro-electromechanical systems (MEMS) at the wafer level is presented. Because of its low temperature budget (&lt; 350°C), as well as material and chemical compatibility, it supports monolithic integration with CMOS electronics for system-on-chip (SoC) designs. The packaging flow is also suitable for a large range of surface micromachining processes. Hermetic device encapsulation is performed by anodic wafer bonding, while bulk-etched transverse through-wafer vias are used to connect electrically with the encapsulated system. Silicon carbide (SiC) is successfully utilized as a means to membrane stress cancellation and hermeticity improvement. Experimental results are presented, and the versatility of the technology proposed in this work is illustrated through a comparison with various other state-of-the-art wafer-level packaging technologies. Other applications of the technology beyond packaging, i.e. film bulk acoustic resonators (FBAR) and pressure sensors, are also discussed.</description><description>Une nouvelle technologie sous vide (&lt; 20 mTorr) au niveau de la tranche pour l'encapsulation de systèmes microélectromécaniques (MEMS) est présentée. Grâce à son faible budget thermique (&lt; 350°C), ainsi que sa compatibilité tant au niveau chimique que des matériaux, elle convient pour l'intégration monolithique avec de l'électronique de type CMOS, afin de réaliser des systèmes mono-puce (SoC). La séquence d'encapsulation est compatible avec une grande variété de procédés de micromachinage en surface. L'encapsulation hermétique des dispositifs est accomplie par collage anodique de tranches, alors qu'on utilise la gravure en profondeur pour la création de vias à travers la tranche, afin d'établir un contact électrique. Du carbure de silicium (SiC) est utilisé avec succès pour minimiser les contraintes mécaniques des membranes et améliorer leur herméticité.  On présente les résultats expérimentaux, tout en soulignant l'utilité de la technologie développée lors de ce travail en la comparant avec d'autres technologies récentes pour l'encapsulation au niveau de la tranche. D'autres applications de la technologie au delà de l'encapsulation sont également présentées, soit le FBAR et le capteur de pression.</description><creator>Lemoine, Dominique</creator><contributor>Mourad N El-Gamal (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Engineering - Electronics and Electrical</subject><title>Vacuum packaging at the wafer level for monolithic integration of MEMS and CMOS</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fh496.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vb69p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:q811kk017</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Abstract  The environment is now changing much faster than in recent geological time, causing increasing population extinctions. Experiments have shown that extinction can be avoided by adaptation through natural selection leading to evolutionary rescue. I first determined the response of Chlamydomonas to stressful environments by growing populations over a range of salinity.  The population growth is halved at 5 g/L salt (NaCl), and 8 g/L is lethal. In this experiment, the genetic correlation between environments increases with environmental similarity. I then manipulated the genotypic diversity in experimental populations and cultured them by serial transfer at 5 g/L salt. The outcome of adaptation is not influenced by initial genetic variation.  Instead, populations adapted mainly through the spread of new beneficial mutations. These results suggest that populations have a greater chance of adapting when new environments are similar to current conditions and that adaptation is sometimes dominated by the spread of new mutations, even in the presence of a substantial amount of standing genetic variation.</description><description>Résumé Notre environnement change maintenant beaucoup plus rapidement que dans le passé géologique récent, précipitant l'extinction de plus en plus d'espèces.  Des chercheurs ont démontré que, grâce à l'adaptation par la sélection naturelle, des espèces peuvent éviter l'extinction, un processus nommé sauvetage évolutif.  J'ai d'abord étudié la capacité de Chlamydomonas  à croitre dans des environnements dont la salinité augmente.  J'ai trouvé que 5 g/L de sel diminue la croissance de moitié tandis que 8 g/L est suffisant pour empêcher toute croissance.  Ici, la corrélation génétique entre environnement augmente avec la similarité des environnements comparés. J'ai ensuite soumis des populations contenant différentes quantités de diversité génétique initiale à une salinité de 5 g/L.  La diversité génétique initiale ne semble pas influencer la capacité d'adaptation.  Cependant, les populations semblent plutôt s'adapter en utilisant de nouvelles mutations dont l'effet est bénéfique.  Ces résultats suggèrent que les populations s'adapteront plus facilement à des environnements similaires aux conditions présentes.  De plus, ce processus sera dominé par la fixation de nouvelles mutations, même dans des populations contenant de la diversité génétique.</description><creator>Moser, Chase</creator><contributor>Graham Bell (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Ecology</subject><title>Experimental evolution of «Chlamydomonas reinhardtii » under salt stress</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mf91p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/q811kk017</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:73666492g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette thèse se concentre sur l'étude de la transformation des matériaux d'un état isotrope à une phase cristalline liquide ordonnée lamellaire de type smectique A par l'entremise de modélisations et de simulations de multi-échelles. Cette approche s'appuie sur le modèle phénoménologique de Landau-de Gennes qui est capable de faire le lien entre les observations expérimentales de phénomènes macroscopiques et la croissance nanoscopique associé à la structure inhérente d'un cristal liquide. L'un des attraits principaux de cette thèse basée sur les simulations provient du fait qu'elle vérifie directement des données expérimentales observées par le passé. Dans la même optique, les apports majeurs de ce travail de thèse se répartissent en trois principaux systèmes expérimentaux: la croissance libre d'un domaine isolé, la formation de texture/défauts, l'évolution de l'interaction entre les textures/défauts à mesure que le système atteint l'équilibre . fr Les études de la croissance libre réalisé au moyen de simulations ont tout d'abord été effectuées dans des conditions où l'ordre liquide cristallin est très prononcé et dans laquelle les effets non-isothermaux peuvent être négligés. L'étude de la cinétique de croissance durant laquelle se forme des sphérulites texturés et homogènes se développant dans une matrice de isotrope instable a pu être mettre en évidence les processus de changement morphologie à une échelle nanoscopique ainsi que les instabilités de croissances, phénomènes inaccessibles sur le plan expérimental. Les ondulations instables des sphérulites de phase smectique A découvertes dans ce travail ont permis de mettre en évidence un possible mécanisme responsable des morphologies anisotropiques de type bâtonnets et des défauts de structure en deux-dimensions de type coniques focaux observés expérimentalement. Un phénomène de cinétique de croissance pré-ordonné en nématique metastable, phénomène qui a été récemment observé expérimentalement, a ensuite été étudié, démontrant qu'un modèle d'ordre supérieur à la fois prédit ce phénomène et les mécanismes sous-jacents régissant aux tendances morphologiques déterminées expérimentalement. Une extension non-isothermale au modèle d'ordre supérieur a été dérivée et employée pour l'étude de la croissance libre dans des conditions de faible congélation, où la chaleur latente et la diffusion thermique anisotropique sont non-négligeables. Les lois de croissance, en accord avec les observations expérimentales, sont déterminées et une nouvelle cinétique de croissance de diffusion et de non-diffusion est développée. fr Les effets de surfaces, et plus particulièrement la géométrie expérimentale/industrielle prédominante des films fins, ont été étudiès à l'aide d'un modèle de surface de de-Gennes permettant une auto-sélection énergétique. Les phénomènes de transition de couches et de croissance de surface augmentée gérés par les dèfauts ont été étudiés et utilisés afin de simuler un équilibre dans la structure des défauts (les dislocations des bordures du smectique A), non-accessible via les anciennes théories et expériences. Finalement, les dernières étapes de transformation de phase, de formation de texture et d'alignement de texture ont été étudiées. Les résultats obtenus de la simulation ont été directement comparés aux données expérimentales issues d'études similaires, démontrant les mêmes symétries que des blocs cylindriques de co-polymères auto-assemblés. Les interactions entre les défauts de différents corps sont à la fois comparés aux résultats expérimentaux obtenus à une échelle macroscopique et analysés à une échelle nanoscopique, tel qu'obtenu par les simulations. La formation, la structure, et les interactions complexes entre les dislocations de bordures à noyaux divisés, structure composite formée à la fois de défauts orientationnels et translationnels, sont présents et validés par des observations expérimentales de ce phénomène.</description><description>This thesis is focused on the study of material transformations from the disordered state to the lamellar-ordered/smectic-A liquid crystalline state via multi-scale multi-transport modeling and simulation. This approach utilizes a high-order Landau-de Gennes phenomenological model able to bridge the gap between experimentally observed macro-scale phenomena and the nano-scale growth and structure inherent to liquid crystalline ordering. A unique feature of this simulation-based thesis is the direct verification of predictions with past experimental observations. In this context, the main contributions of this thesis work focuses on three experimental systems: free growth of an isolated domain, defect/texture formation, and the evolution of texture/defect interactions as the system approaches equilibrium. Simulation studies of free growth were first performed under conditions of deep undercooling, where non-isothermal effects can be neglected. The growth/shape kinetic evolution of initially textured and homogeneous spherulites growing into an unstable isotropic matrix phase was found, elucidating nano-scale morphology/texture processes and growth instabilities inaccessible experimentally. Undulation instabilities in growing smectic-A spherulites discovered in this work shed light on a possible mechanism for the formation of experimentally observed anisotropic "batonnet" morphologies and two-dimension focal conic defect structures. Recent experimental observations of growth kinetic phenomena of meta-stable nematic pre-ordering was studied, showing that the high-order model both predicts this phenomenon and explains the underlying mechanisms for experimentally determined morphological trends. A non-isothermal extension to the high-order model is derived and applied to study free growth under shallow undercooling conditions, where latent heat and anisotropic thermal diffusion are non-negligible. Growth laws, agreeing with experimental observations, are determined and novel diffusional/diffusionless growth kinetics found. The effects of surfaces, focusing on the experimentally/industrially prevalent thin-film geometry, were studied using a de Gennes surface model allowing for energetic self-selection. Layer transitions and defect-mediated surface-enhanced growth phenomena were studied and used to simulate equilibrium defect core structure (of the smectic-A elementary edge dislocation), inaccessible via previous theory and experiment. Finally, the last stages of phase transformation, texture formation and coarsening, are studied. The obtained simulation results are compared directly to relevant experimental data of a system with the same symmetries, self-assembled cylindrical block copolymer films. Multi-body defect interactions are studied and both compared to experimental macro-scale results and analyzed at the nano-scale, as is resolved by the simulations. The formation, structure, and complex interactions of "giant" split-core edge dislocations, composite structures composed of both orientational and translational defects, are presented and validated by experimental observations of this phenomena. The models, computational techniques, and predictions developed in this thesis work provide a substantial basis on which to further develop the computational material science of anisotropic soft matter.</description><creator>Abukhdeir, Nasser</creator><contributor>Alejandro D Rey (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Engineering - Chemical</subject><title>Growth, dynamics, and texture modeling of the lamellar smectic-A liquid crystalline transition</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999713w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/73666492g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cj82k7662</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Contexte: Plus de 15 millions d'enfants sont devenus orphelins dès suites du SIDA. D'un côté, un nombre grandissant d'études suggèrent que les orphelins sont désavantagés, tandis que de l'autre, plusieurs études n'ont pas été capables de démontrer des inégalités au niveau de la santé et de l'éducation. Cette contradiction dans la littérature suscite le débat à savoir si les orphelins devraient être ciblés de façon spécifique ou s'ils devraient être inclus dans des programmes d'aide englobant d'autres enfants vulnérables. Objectifs: Cette étude a pour objectif de: 1) estimer les inégalités au niveau de l'éducation des orphelins par rapport à celle des autres enfants affectés par le SIDA; 2) estimer les inégalités au niveau de la santé des orphelins par rapport à celle des autres enfants affectés par le SIDA; et 3) décrire l'étendue du support communautaire et public destinés aux ménages hébergeant des orphelins. Méthodologie: Les données proviennent du Malawi Integrated Household Survey de 2004-5, une base de données nationale et représentative de 52 707 individus répartis dans 11 280 ménages dans 564 communautés. Les modèles multiniveaux étudient l'association entre le statut d'orphelin et d'autres impacts liés au SIDA et 1) l'éducation des enfants de 6 à 14 ans; et 2) les conditions de santé des enfants de 6 à 17 ans. Des données descriptives pondérées et des modèles de régression sont utilisés pour étudier si les ménages ayant au moins un orphelin reçoivent plus de soutien des milieux privé, communautaire et public que les autres ménages. Résultats: Les orphelins dont la mère ou les deux parents sont décédés sont plus susceptibles d'avoir décroché de l'école (OR=2.2, 2.5 respectivement) ou d'accuser un retard au niveau scolaire (différence de niveau = -0.3); ces inégalités ne sont pas expliquées par la pauvreté. Même si d'un côté aucun résultat ne prouve que les orphelins ont un taux de morbidité plus élevé, les enfants qui ont des parents atteints du SIDA ou d'autres maladies connexes ont un niveau plus élevé de maladies chroniques ou graves (ORs= 1.5-1.9). Finalement, les amis et la famille procurent de l'aide dans 75% des ménages, et ce soutien est plus souvent présent dans les ménages avec des orphelins ayant perdus leurs deux parents. Les organismes communautaires venant en aide aux personnes atteintes de maladies chroniques sont présents dans 40% des communautés et plusieurs incluent des programmes s'adressant spécifiquement aux orphelins. Conclusion: Il y a un engagement international croissant afin de freiner l'impact du SIDA sur les enfants, mais le débat demeure à savoir comment allouer les ressources le plus efficacement. Les orphelins et les enfants pauvres dénotent tous les deux des retard en éducation ce qui suggère qu'une aide devrait être octroyée simultanément pour les programmes destinés aux orphelins et pour ceux visant l'élimination globale de la pauvreté. Il a été démontré que les enfants vivant avec des parents malades ont une mauvaise santé; les programmes communautaires de soins à domiciles sont les mieux placés pour identifier ces enfants et freiner les risques. Finalement, bien qu'il y ait plusieurs ménages qui reçoivent déjà de l'aide, la valeur et l'étendue de cette aide est inadéquate et ne répond pas au besoin; du soutien de l'extérieur devrait être ajouté.</description><description>Background: Over 15 million children have been orphaned by AIDS. While a growing literature suggests orphans are disadvantaged, other studies have failed to find health or educational disparities. This contradictory evidence has fueled debate over whether orphans should be targeted for assistance, or whether the response should be expanded to other vulnerable children. Objectives: This study sought to: 1) to estimate educational disparities for orphans relative to other AIDS-affected children; 2) to estimate health disparities for orphans relative to other AIDS-affected children; and 3) to describe the extent of community and public support available to households fostering orphans. Methods: Data are drawn from the 2004-5 Malawi Integrated Household Survey, a nationally-representative survey of 52,707 individuals in 11,280 households in 564 communities. Multilevel models examine the association between orphanhood and other AIDS-related impacts and 1) education for children 6-14 years; and 2) health status for children 6-17 years. Weighted descriptives and regression models are used to examine whether orphan households receive greater private, community and public support. Results: Double and maternal orphans are more likely to be out of school (OR=2.2, 2.5 respectively) and behind in attainment (grade difference = -0.3); these disparities are not explained by poverty. While there is no evidence that orphans suffer greater morbidity, children whose parents have an AIDS-related illness have higher burdens of both acute and chronic morbidity (ORs=1.5-1.9). Finally, friends and relatives provided assistance to 75% of households, and this support was more likely to be targeted to households with double orphans. Community-based organizations for the chronically ill were present in 40% of communities and many included orphan-specific programming. Conclusion: There is growing international commitment to mitigate the impact of AIDS on children, but debate remains around how to best target resources. Orphans and poor children both demonstrate educational disadvantage, suggesting a simultaneous need for orphan-specific programming and general poverty alleviation. Children living with sick parents demonstrated poor health; community home-based care programs are best situated to identify these children and mitigate their risk.  Finally, while many households with vulnerable children are already receiving assistance, the value and coverage is inadequate to match the need and needs to be drastically scaled-up.</description><creator>Kidman, Rachel</creator><contributor>S Heymann (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</subject><title>Child welfare in the context of HIV/AIDS epidemic: identifying vulnerable populations and shaping an effective response</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nr41t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cj82k7662</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z603qx905</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:23:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les antibiotiques sont couramment utilisés dans l'industrie du bétail pour prévenir les maladies et améliorer l'efficacité flux. Beaucoup d'antibiotiques ne sont pas complètement absorbés par les animaux et ils sont excrétés dans les urines et fèces. Lorsque le fumier contenant des antibiotiques est utilisé comme un engrais, il peut affecter la dégradation des pesticides puisque les antibiotiques contenus inhiber l'action de bactéries dans le sol ou tuer ces bactéries. Une étude de lysimètre de champ de quatre-vingt-dix-jour a été effectuée pour évaluer les effets des antibiotiques sur la dégradation de trois herbicides, atrazine, métribuzine et métolachlore, dans un sol sableux. Trois traitements des fumiers de volaille contenant monensine, narasine et salinomycine ont été utilisés pour étudier les effets des antibiotiques sur la dégradation des herbicides, et ont été comparés avec un traitement de contrôle de fumier sans antibiotiques. Herbicides étaient appliqués une fois à la surface de sol de lysimètres aux taux recommandés localement, suivie par l'application de fumiers de volaille. Les lysimètres ont été protégés des précipitations naturelles, et les précipitations simulées ont été appliqués sept fois. Des échantillons de sol et des échantillons d'eau ont été recueillis et analysées à intervalles de temps prédéterminés. Dans l'expérience, tous les trois herbicides ont été trouvés à s'infiltrer à travers les profils de sol et leurs concentrations ont diminués avec la profondeur du sol et de temps. L'analyse statistique des résultants ont montré que tous les trois traitements antibiotiques ont donnés une dispersion des niveaux d'herbicide sensiblement plus lent par rapport au traitement nonantibiotic. L'étude du bilan massique a révélé que les demi-vies des herbicides ont été significativement plus long avec l'utilisation d'antibiotiques comme par rapport au ce traitement de contrôle s</description><description>Antibiotics are widely used in the livestock industry for preventing disease and improving feed efficiency. Many antibiotics are not completely absorbed by animals and they are excreted in urine and feces. When manure containing such antibiotics is used as a fertilizer, it can affect the degradation of pesticides since antibiotics inhibit the action of bacteria in soils or kill the bacteria. A ninety-day field lysimeter study was conducted to assess the effects of antibiotics on the degradation of three herbicides, atrazine, metribuzin and metolachlor, in a sandy soil. Poultry manures, respectively containing monensin, narasin and salinomycin, were used to investigate the effects of antibiotics on the degradation of herbicides, and were compared with a control treatment of manure without antibiotics. Herbicides were applied once to the soil surface of lysimeters at the locally recommended rates, followed by the application of poultry manures. The lysimeters were protected from natural rainfall, and the simulated rainfall was applied seven times. Both soil and leachate samples were collected and analyzed at predetermined time intervals. In the experiment, all the three herbicides were found to leach down through the soil profiles, and their concentrations decreased with soil depth and time. The statistical analysis of the results shows that all the three antibiotic treatments yielded a significantly slower dissipation of herbicide levels compared with the non-antibiotic treatment. The mass balance study reveals that the half lives of the three herbicides were significantly longer in the presence of antibiotics as compared to the control treatment without antibiotics. These results indicate that antibiotics in poultry manures can significantly slow down the degradation of the three herbicides in soil and therefore, increase the threat of herbicide pollution in the environment.</description><creator>Fan, Min</creator><contributor>Shiv Prasher (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2010</date><subject>Biology - Microbiology</subject><title>Fate and transport of herbicides in a sandy soil in the presence of antibiotics in poultry manures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dg131.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z603qx905</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):43475</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>