<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:51:55Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):25725" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f1332</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Due to the complex characteristics of tunneling problems, tunneling engineering is perhaps one of the areas in which numerical methods are more frequently adopted in practice. One important application is to examine the influence of an excavation and construction procedures on the stress distribution and deformation in the ground surrounding the opening and on the tunnel lining. Another important aspect of tunneling problems that can be accounted for in a numerical analysis is the complex geometry associated with typical applications. This is not only related to the shape of the opening, but also to the presence of non-homogenous or non-isotropic soil strata. A constitutive model that is suitable for the analysis of structured clays has been developed in this study based on the multilaminate framework. The model takes into account the elastic unloading-reloading, inherent and induced anisotropy, destructuration and bonding effects. The model is implemented into Plaxis finite element program, successfully calibrated and used to investigate the response of structured sensitive clay to the construction of the Gatineau tunnel in Gatineau, Quebec and the Ottawa sewer tunnel in Ottawa, Ontario. Numerical results were compared to the field measurements taken during the tunnel construction. To improve the performance of the numerical model, an implicit integration algorithm is implemented and proven to be very effective as compared to the conventional explicit integration methods. The effect of different soil parameters including bonding and anisotropy on the tunneling induced displacements and lining stresses is also examined using a comprehensive parametric study. The results indicated that soil bonding and anisotropy have significant effects on the shape of the settlement trough as well as the magnitudes of surface displacements and lining stresses induced by tunneling.</description><creator>Dang, Hoang Kien, 1981-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Anisotropy -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Clay soils.</subject><subject>Tunneling -- Mathematical models.</subject><title>The application of a multilaminate model to simulate tunnelling in structured clays : a dissertation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Hoang Kien Dang, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b382b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f1332</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988k074</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The formation of gas hydrates in the oil and gas industry causes numerous problems that require costly solutions and operation downtime. A great deal of hydrate research has focused on their prevention either through kinetic or thermodynamic inhibitors. Recently, antifreeze proteins (AFPs) produced by cold adapted organisms have been found to have a kinetic inhibitory effect on clathrate hydrates. Kinetic experiments were conducted on the methane-water system in the presence of AFPs by measuring the gas uptake during the formation of methane hydrate in a 610 cc high pressure crystallizer. These experiments were performed at temperatures ranging from 277.15 K to 280.65 K, pressures of 5800 KPa to 8100 KPa and at an AFP concentration of 0.01 mM. The results of these experiments showed that the presence of AFPs affect methane hydrate formation in multiple ways. They were shown to increase the nucleation time, reduce the initial growth rate of methane hydrate at the time of nucleation and there was evidence to suggest that they also have an anti-agglomerating effect on hydrate crystals.</description><creator>Dick, John Alexander Gordon.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Methane.</subject><subject>Antifreeze proteins.</subject><subject>Hydrates.</subject><title>The effect of type-I antifreeze proteins on the kinetics of methane hydrate formation /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© John Alexander Gordon Dick, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pv63g0499.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988k074</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb3978571</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The catalytic partial oxidation of methane to produce synthesis gas using a platinum/nickel dual bed reactor has been shown to have high conversions and selectivity of synthesis gas products, hydrogen and carbon monoxide. In this work the relative length of the platinum and nickel in the dual bed reactor is investigated experimentally and a model describing the nickel portion of the dual bed catalyst is developed. The model uses simplified flow conditions, experimentally determined temperature profiles and an elementary reaction mechanism to describe the nickel bed of the reactor. The rate parameters of the elementary reaction in the mechanism are determined using theoretical methods. Unity Bond Index - Quadratic Exponential Potential (UBI-QEP) is used to determine the activation energy and thermodynamic consistency is forced to produce a set of preexponential factors.</description><creator>Bell, Christa.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Catalysis.</subject><subject>Chemical reactors.</subject><subject>Methane.</subject><subject>Oxidation.</subject><title>Investigation of catalytic partial oxidation of methane using platinumnickel dual bed reactors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Christa Bell, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zt51x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb3978571</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:41687h68w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les nanotubes de carbone sont considérés comme ayant un potentielénorme pour assurer le rôle de renforts dans la prochaine génération de matériauxcomposites. Dans les décennies précédentes, les effets des nanotubes surl'amélioration des propriétés mécaniques, électriques et multi-fonctionnelles despolymères ont été révélés. Par contre, dans la plupart des cas, les études réaliséespar différents groupes de recherche et portant sur les mêmes composites faits depolymère renforcé de nanotubes ne présentent pas toutes des résultatscomparables. La cause majeure de cette variabilité est la méthodologie utiliséelors du procédé de fabrication de ces composites. Avant que quiconque ne suggèreune méthodologie idéale et systématique, il est impératif de comprendre les basesfondamentales de l'effet des nanotubes sur le procédé de fabrication. Dans cetterecherche, les effets des nanotubes de carbone à paroi simple sur les propriétésthermo mécaniques et thermo chimiques d'une résine époxy de gradeaéronautique ont été investigués. Les caractéristiques étudiées comprennent ladégradation thermique, le comportement rhéologique, la cinétique depolymérisation, ainsi que l'expansion thermique. L'effet de l'application d'unfilm de nanotube/époxy sur la résistance interlaminaire au cisaillement aégalement été étudié avec un préimprégné conventionel de fibre de carbone etd'époxy. Les résultats de caractérisation montrent que les nanotubes ont un effetsignificatif sur certaines propriétés physiques et chimiques inhérentes à l'époxy.La présence des nanotubes crée un délai dans la température de dégradation del'époxy. La viscosité de la résine est 7 fois plus élevée à la température de la pièceet sa température de gélification est inférieure. De plus, la chaleur totale deréaction est diminuée. Par contre, les tests mécaniques montrent que l'applicationd'un film de nanotube/époxy ne cause pas de changement dans la résistanceinterlaminaire au cisaillement d'un préimprégné de fibre de carbone et d'époxy.Par ailleurs, cette valeur de résistance est dépendante de l'alignement desnanotubes et de la méthode d'application du film sur les interfaces du laminé.Finalement, il a été observé que les nanotubes n'ont aucun effet sur les propriétésthermo mécaniques.</description><description>Carbon Nanotubes are thought to have tremendous potential as reinforcements for the next generation of composite materials. In the past decade, the enhancing effects of the nanotubes on the mechanical, electrical as well as multi-functional properties of polymer composites have been reported. However, the same nanotubes/polymer composites investigated by different research groups, in many cases, do not show a good agreement with one another. The root cause of this variability is believed to lie in the processing methodology employed to prepare the composites. Before one can propose an ideal and systematic processing condition, it is imperative to have a fundamental understanding of the effect of these nanotubes on the processing of the nanotube-based composites. In this study, the effect of 0.2wt.% functionalized single walled carbon nanotubes on the various thermo mechanical and thermo chemical properties of aerospace grade epoxy was investigated. Namely, the thermal degradation, rheological behavior, cure kinetics as well as the thermal expansion behavior of the epoxy were addressed. In addition, the effect of the application small quantity of nanotube/epoxy composite film on the interlaminar shear strength (ILSS) of a conventional laminated carbon fibre/epoxy prepregs was also investigated. The characterization results show that the presence of the nanotubes has a very significant effect on some of the inherent physical and chemical properties of the epoxy. The presence of these nanotubes leads to a delay in the degradation temperature of the epoxy. The viscosity sees a seven-fold increase at room temperature and the resin also gels at a lower temperature in the presence of the nanotubes. At the same time, the total heat of reaction is also lowered on addition of the nanotubes. The mechanical test, however, shows that the addition of the nanotube/epoxy film does not affect the ILSS of the laminated carbon fibre/epoxy composite. This ILSS value is also found to be dependant on the controlled alignment of the nanotubes and the method of application of the film at the interfaces of the laminates. Finally, it was observed that the nanotubes, when used in such low contents, also had no effect on the thermo mechanical properties of the epoxy.</description><creator>Adhikari, Kamal.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Nanotubes.</subject><subject>Epoxy resins -- Thermomechanical properties.</subject><subject>Fibrous composites -- Thermomechanical properties.</subject><subject>Carbon composites -- Thermomechanical properties.</subject><title>Effects of functionalized single walled carbon nanotubes on the processing and mechanical properties of laminated composites</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Kamal Adhikari, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f1881m17h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/41687h68w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8910jt88v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis traces the roots of women's honor killings in the tribal areas of Pakistan from the British rule in South Asia. The British colonial presence gave the tribal areas autonomy through landmark colonial legislations. The colonizers needed a harmonious relationship with tribal and rural notables in order to gain from the land. Thus, the British gave precedence to the tribal legal structure and as a result we see the beginnings of tribal autonomy in today's Pakistan. Women's honor was also dictated by tribal laws thus tribal councils dictated women's mobility and rights. After the creation of Pakistan in 1947 much colonial legislation was preserved in the Constitution. The tribal areas maintained autonomy and their legal systems also gained legitimacy on a national level. Therefore, cases of women's honor killings were dealt with in the rural areas but moreover, were justified in Pakistani law as well. Thus this thesis seeks to trace this legacy to the modern period and look at the evolution of the relationship between tribal autonomy and women's rights in the context of the pre and post-independence periods.</description><creator>Wasti, Nadia Syeda.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Honor killings -- Pakistan -- History.</subject><subject>Muslim women -- Pakistan -- Social conditions.</subject><title>Muslim women's honor and its custodians : the British colonizers, the landlords and the legislators of Pakistan : a historical study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Nadia Syeda Wasti, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3r074v32q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jt88v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gf06g299p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the past decade, self-assessment has become a major research area; however, contradictory findings have been reported. This study investigated the effectiveness of self-assessment and examined some possible factors that might influence the accuracy of self-assessment. Participants were 32 English as a second language (ESL) graduate students and an experienced ESL teacher at McGill University. The student participants were divided into a control group and an experimental group while the researcher and the ESL teacher served as raters. Both quantitative and qualitative data were generated. The results indicated that the experimental group outperformed the control group. Some possible causes of the differences or similarities between student and teacher assessors' rating were identified. The findings of this study provide evidence on the effectiveness of self-assessment and offer ESL students and teachers an alternative way to participate in the learning process and to assess the learning outcomes.</description><creator>Wei, Xuelian, 1978-</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Self-evaluation.</subject><subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Foreign speakers.</subject><title>Does self-assessment with specific criteria enhance graduate level ESL students' writing?</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Xuelian Wei, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qj72p738n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gf06g299p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Second Language Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cb046</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores the education of women in the pre-modern Middle East, particularly in legal matters. The goal of the work is to show that women in the pre-modern Middle East not only had access to education but were also learned in jurisprudence (fiqh). The work begins with a detailed discussion of the pre-modern system of learning. The first chapter explores not only the educational institutions and methods of instruction, but also the avenues and opportunities for education available to and utilized by women. The second chapter concentrates on the lives of two female jurists (faqihat). The purpose of this chapter is to explore in detail the methods by which these women acquired a legal education and obtained their status as female jurists. This work is a rudimentary effort at investigating the role of women in the pre-modern system of learning and their access to and acquisition of a legal education.</description><creator>Yacoob, Saadia.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Women lawyers -- Middle East -- History.</subject><subject>Women -- Education -- Middle East -- History.</subject><title>Women and education in the pre-modern Middle East : reconstructing the lives of two female jurists (faqīhāt)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Saadia Yacoob, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870w11t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cb046</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644r86p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines nationalism and colonialism in the Israeli-Palestinian conflict and asks the questions: What is the relationship between these ideologies and "national narratives" constructed of collective historical memory? How do these ideologies produce recognizable, sexualized, national bodies? What are the defining characteristics of these national bodies and how do they perform roles from the national narratives? These questions are addressed through a discussion of the role of masculinity in modern Zionism and the state of Israel, in particular how it relates to the land of Palestine and the Palestinian "other". This thesis also addresses anti-colonial resistance movements in Palestine and argues that performative nationalism produces a fetishized commodity that can me labeled "militancy". This militancy is found institutionalized in the popular culture of everything from poetry to political posters. Finally, Palestinian female suicide bombers, like women nationalists before them, do little to challenge how specific nationalist acts of resistance are defined by patriarchal nationalists and sexualized within a "gendered space of militancy".</description><creator>Sanagan, Mark.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Gender identity -- West Bank.</subject><subject>Gender identity -- Gaza Strip.</subject><subject>Arab-Israeli conflict.</subject><subject>Gender identity -- Israel.</subject><subject>Nationalism -- Arab countries.</subject><title>The social construction of militancy in the Israeli-Palestinian conflict : masculinity, femininity and the nation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Mark Sanagan, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429944s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644r86p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50gw458</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis comprises two sections. The first proposes a discursive analysis of forty journalistic reports written by Louis-Gilles Francoeur and published in 2005 in Le Devoir daily newspaper. Its author aimed to demonstrate that Francoeur promotes a conservationist progressive view of the relation that man should maintain with its natural environment, an ideological position favouring flora and fauna's conservation as well as their wise and sustainable management. The studied texts will, at first, be placed in their socio-historical context, among the emergence of a wider discourse: the environmental discourse in the Western civilization, in Quebec and in the medias. The reports' discursive strategies shall then be explored. The second part of this thesis presents the author's own creative writing, a play intitled Contes orduriers, which can be formally and thematically linked with the critical section of the present study.</description><creator>Henri, Dominique, 1982-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Francoeur, Louis-Gilles.</subject><subject>Environmentalism.</subject><title>Intentionnalité, point de vue et effets de discours dans les chroniques de Louis-Gilles Francoeur : suivi de, Contes orduriers -- texte dramatique</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Dominique Henri, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207tp59t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gw458</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75dc72t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Isolation, death, rebirth: the rites of passage experienced by the main characters in La nuit (Ferron), La notte (Antonioni) and Le Grand Yaka take place in the course of the night, which prompts the search for their own identity. "Tell me about your nights, and I will tell you who you are" could be the motto of Francois, Lidia, Giovanni and Lepetit. Whether in the realm of dreams or reality, these three stories depict a universe devoid of humanity, where lost souls try to surmount crises and seek truth in their nightly adventures. Gradually, the night---a world of infinite possibilities---will allow them to relive their past and illuminate their future. But is there still hope for them? The anguish, the inability to communicate and urban solitude are at the core of these tales of borderline insanity which all end with the dawn of a new day.</description><creator>Ryneczko, Christophe.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Ferron, Jacques. Nuit.</subject><subject>Antonioni, Michelangelo. Notte.</subject><subject>Night in literature.</subject><title>Le Grand Yaka : suivi de FerronAntonioni : La nuitLa notte</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Christophe Ryneczko, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jx24m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75dc72t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26xx64r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this thesis is to examine the way in which Job 38-42 develops and defends a new theodicy through language of creation and of the created order. This thesis will posit that through the course of the divine speeches, divine justice is shown to be an element of divine rule where chaos is limited and confined to specific boundaries, but not entirely eliminated or defeated. Inherent in this justice is compassionate divine care for all parts of creation, including the farthest reaches of the cosmos and uninhabited lands of exile. The social, political and economic conditions of the fifth century B.C.E. are examined as the context for this critique of retributive justice and the singularly juridical understanding of justice that is represented by Job and his friends. The theodicy presented in Job 38-42 defines for Israel a divine justice, which is boundless, and provides a model for human action that upholds empathy and compassion for the outcasts of society.</description><creator>Hildebrand, Nicole Marie.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Justice -- Biblical teaching.</subject><subject>Theodicy -- Biblical teaching.</subject><title>The language of creation and the construction of a new concept of theodicy : Job 38-42</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Nicole Marie Hildebrand, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v118rd73x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26xx64r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sd07w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le mouvement expressionniste viennois (1909-1913) recouvre des courantsparallèles dans les disciplines picturales et musicales. Les idées provenant des milieuxintellectuels du fin-de-siècle viennois ont inspiré le réveil de l'artiste moderne, depuis leUr-schrei jusqu'à la formulation d'une nouvelle théorie esthétique. Ce mémoire examinel'origine des valeurs esthétiques chères au mouvement expressionniste, ainsi que lestechniques utilisées pour exprimer ces valeurs dans les oeuvres d'Arnold Schoenberg,d'Egon Schiele, d'Oskar Kokoschka, et de Wassily Kandinsky. Les thèmes abordés sontdivisés en deux grandes catégories dont les fondements centraux émanent depréoccupations reliées, d'une part, à une compréhension croissante de l'inconscient et dela psychopathologie, et, d'autre part, aux aspects métaphysiques de l'art et de l'existencehumaine: la maladie et la spiritualité. Bien qu'il ne soit pas possible de comparerdirectement des oeuvres picturales et musicales, l'existence de principes et de thèmescommuns entraîne une confluence conceptuelle qui unifie ces disciplines dans laréalisation d'une vision artistique collective.</description><description>Viennese Expressionism 1909-1913 encompasses parallel evolutions in the disciplines of visual arts and music. Ideas from fin-de-siecle Vienna's intellectual milieu inspired the awakening of the Modern artist, from Ur-schrei to the formation of a new aesthetic theory. In this thesis, I examine the origin of iconic Expressionist aesthetic values and their technical expression in works by Arnold Schoenberg, Egon Schiele, Oskar Kokoschka, and Wassily Kandinsky. Topics covered are divided into two broad thematic categories whose central tenets originate in preoccupations with, on the one hand, an emerging understanding of the unconscious and psychic pathology; and on the other hand, the metaphysical components to art and the human experience: sickness and spirituality. While it is not possible to compare directly art and musical works, common ideas and principles provide conceptual intersections that unify the disciplines in the realization of a collective artistic vision.</description><creator>Adamowicz, Emily.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Expressionism (Art) -- Austria -- Vienna.</subject><subject>Expressionism (Music) -- Austria -- Vienna.</subject><title>Viennese Expressionism : from sickness to spirituality in the new aesthetic theory 1909-1913</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Emily Adamowicz, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x633f134b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sd07w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g732d9196</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of this study is to revise existing theories of the Imamite turn towards rationalism. In the first chapter I discuss trends in Imamite thought during the period of the presence of the Imams; explore the impact of the Occultation on the Imamite community; and assess the character of the Imamite traditionism in the century after the Occultation. The bulk of the second chapter comprises a comparison of two texts: I`tiqadat al-imamiyya by Ibn Babuya, which represents Imamite traditionism during the first century of the Occultation, and Tas&amp;dotbelow;h&amp;dotbelow;ih&amp;dotbelow; i`tiqadat al-imamiyya, which is a correction to Ibn Babuya's creed by his student al-Shaykh al-Mufid, considered the founder of the rationalist school in Imamism. Finally, in the conclusion I will address the conceptual problems found in the intellectual history of this stage of development in Imamite thought with reference to the recent work of Quentin Skinner.</description><description>Le but de cette étude est de réviser les théories existantes au sujet de la tournéeimamite vers le rationalisme. Dans le premier chapitre, je discute les tendances dans lapensée Imamite pendant la présence des Imams, en éxaminant l'impact de l'Occultationsur la communauté imamite, et considérant le caractère du traditionisme imamite dans lesiècle suivant l'Occultation. La plupart du deuxième chapitre est composée d'unecomparison de deux textes: l'tiqiidiit al-imiimiyya par Ibn Babuya, qui représente letraditionisme imamite pendant le premier siècle après l'Occultation, et Ta~lJiJl i'tiqiidiital-imiimiyya, qui est une correction du credo d'Ibn Babuya, par son étudiant al-Shaykhal-Mufid, qui est considéré le fondateur de l'école rationaliste de l'Imamisme. Enfin,dans la conclusion, j' adresse les problèmes conceptuels trouvés dans l'histoireintellectuelle de cette étappe du développement de la pensée imamite, en référant àl'oeuvre récente de Quentin Skinner.</description><creator>Ali, Aun Hasan.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Rationalism -- History.</subject><subject>Shīʻah -- History.</subject><title>Imamite rationalism in the Buyid Era</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Aun Hasan Ali, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p056z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732d9196</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xw42n818s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Canadian language training sector is a booming industry for those interested in capitalizing on the worldwide demand for English, such as private language schools. Thus, this study analyzed the websites of two Montreal-based private language schools to elucidate how these schools use discursive and visual resources to advance their ideology. Defined as a form of social practice (Fairclough, 1992; Pare, 2002), ideology is the way in which the schools are acting discursively in order to serve their for-profit interests. Specifically, the study investigated how both schools manage the tension between their claims to educational legitimacy and their business concerns. The study used analytical strategies from Fairclough's (1992, 2003) Critical Discourse Analysis (CDA) and Kress and van Leuuven's (2006) visual grammar. Findings revealed that the schools further their ideology by positioning and legitimating themselves as educational institutions, and commercializing non-educational services (e.g., sightseeing tours) promoted as having second language (L2) developmental value.</description><creator>Abrile, Juan.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Web sites.</subject><subject>Language schools -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>Ideology in the discourse of Montreal-based private language schools' websites</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Juan Abrile, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bh506.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xw42n818s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Second Language Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6w924c02q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fedor Dostoevskii and Petr Verkhovenskii, the author and one of the main protagonists of the novel Demons, exhibit the same communication style and pursue similar propagandistic purposes in their public communication. Both figures function in the framework of public relations, employing mass communication for the sake of publicizing their political messages to broad audiences. In the process of their public communication, the author and the hero of the novel merge literature and journalism, fictional and factual discourse, subvert a critical analysis of their respective messages and encourage an unconditional, if unwarranted, acceptance of their communication. Relying on the theoretical findings of John Austin, Jurgen Habermas, as well as using the theoretical models of mass communication, the present study shows the underlying bond between Dostoevskii and Petr Verkhovenskii in terms of their communication style despite the ideological gulf that separates the two seemingly irreconcilable sides.</description><creator>Aliev, Baktygul.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Literature, Slavic and East European.</subject><title>The author and protagonist in Demons : similarities in communication style and functions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Baktygul Aliev, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w95050813.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6w924c02q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Russian and Slavic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644r87z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Natural communication between humans is not limited to speech, but often requires simultaneous coordination of multiple streams of information---especially hand gestures---to complement or supplement understanding. This thesis describes a software architecture, called CLAVIUS Whose purpose is to generically interpret multiple modes of input as singular semantic utterances through a modular programming interface that supports various sensing technologies. This interpretation is accomplished through a new multi-threaded parsing algorithm that co-ordinates top-down and bottom-up methods asynchronously on graph-based unification grammars. The interpretation process follows a best-first approach where partial parses are evaluated by a combination of scoring metrics, related to such criteria as information content, grammatical structure and language models. Furthermore, CLAVIUS relaxes two traditional constraints in conventional parsing---namely, it abandons forced relative ordering of right-hand constituents in grammar rules, and it allows parses to be expanded with null constituents. The effects of this parsing methodology, and of the scoring criteria it employs, are analyzed within the context of experiments and data collection on a small group of users. Both CLAVIUS and its component modules are trained on this data, and results show improvements in performance accuracy, and the overcoming of several difficulties in other multimodal frameworks. General discussion as to the linguistic behaviour of speakers in a multimodal context are also described.</description><creator>Rudzicz, Frank.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Clavius : understanding language understanding in multimodal interaction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Frank Rudzicz, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k752q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644r87z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vb53s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Measurement of image quality plays a central role in optimization and evaluation of imaging systems. The most straight-forward way to assess image quality is subjective evaluations by human observers, where the mean value of their scores is used as the quality measure. However, objective (quantitative) measures are needed because subjective evaluations are impractical and expensive. The aim of this thesis is to develop simple and low-complexity metrics for quality assessment of digital images. Traditionally, the most widely used quantitative measures are the mean squared error and measures that model the human visual system. The proposed method uses the Discrete Cosine Transform and the Discrete Wavelet Transform to divide images into four frequency bands and relates the visual quality of the distorted images to the weighted average of the mean squared error between original and distorted images within each band. The performance of the metrics presented in this thesis is tested and validated on a large database of subjective quality ratings. Simulations show that the proposed metrics accurately predict visual quality and outperform current state-of-the-art methods with simple and easily implemented processing steps. Extensions of the proposed image quality metrics are investigated. More particularly, this thesis explores image quality assessment when the reference image is only partially available (reduced reference settings), and presents a method for successfully quantifying the quality of distorted images in such settings.</description><creator>Sendashonga, Mireille.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Image quality assessment using frequency domain transforms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Mireille Sendashonga, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096725z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vb53s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj139224z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One important area for application of space robotics is autonomous on-orbit servicing of failed or failing spacecraft. An important aspect of these operations is the autonomous capture of the client satellite based on information obtained from a vision system. In this work, we describe laboratory experiments that verify the feasibility of autonomous capture of a slowly spinning non-cooperative satellite by a redundant serial manipulator. The main autonomous capture problem is divided in two separate tasks: the generation of a Cartesian trajectory to achieve the capture and the control of a manipulator to realize the generated Cartesian trajectory. Strategies that utilize the redundancy of a manipulator to optimize its posture are analyzed, implemented and used in the experimental validation of the autonomous capture. An online vision-based trajectory generation algorithm that generates a task-space velocity command to safely approach the target satellite and match its motion has been developed. The redundancy resolution and the trajectory generation algorithms are implemented and tested on two seven degree-of-freedom redundant manipulator systems: one located at McGill University and the other at the Canadian Space Agency. At both facilities, a scenario emulating the capture of a free-floating satellite have been created and used to validate the efficiency of the developed capture algorithm.</description><creator>Rouleau, Guy.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Robotics.</subject><title>Vision-guided capture of a free-flying object using a redundant serial manipulator</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Guy Rouleau, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d682v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139224z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k930bx46f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Endothelial cell dysfunction has been linked to atherosclerosis through their response to hemodynamic forces. Flow in stenotic vessels creates complex spatial gradients in wall shear stress. In vitro studies examining the effect of shear stress on endothelial cells have used unrealistic and simplified models, which cannot reproduce physiological conditions. Endothelial cells were grown and exposed for different times to physiological steady flow in straight dynamic control and in idealized asymmetric stenosis models. Cells subjected to 1D flow aligned with flow direction and had a spindle-like shape when compared to static controls. Endothelial cell morphology differed in the spatial wall shear stress gradient regions, being randomly oriented and of cobblestone shape. No other study to date has described this morphology in the presence of a positive wall shear stress gradient or gradient of significant shear magnitude. This technique provides a more realistic model to study endothelial cell response to spatial and temporal shear stress gradients that are present in vivo and is an important advancement towards a better understanding of the mechanisms involved in coronary artery disease.</description><creator>Rouleau, Léonie.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Endothelial cell response to shear stress in an asymmetric stenosis model</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Léonie Rouleau, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s274t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k930bx46f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52j8309</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The interaction of an oxidized form of nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide, NAD+, with a polycrystalline gold electrode surface was investigated using a range of electrochemical and spectroscopic techniques. It was shown that the reduction of NAD+ on gold is irreversible and occurs at cathodic overpotentials larger than -0.2 V. The NAD+ reduction reaction was found to be mass-transport controlled, and of first order with respect to NAD+. A set of kinetic parameters was calculated and verified independently using various experimental techniques: the apparent transfer and diffusion coefficients, the apparent formal heterogeneous electron-transfer rate constant, and the apparent Gibbs energy of activation. It was determined that the adsorption of NAD+ in the double layer region (-0.5 to 0.4 V) of the Au electrode is irreversible. The adsorption process of NAD+ was well described by the Langmuir adsorption isotherm. The corresponding thermodynamic parameters were determined: Gibbs free energy, enthalpy and entropy of adsorption. Their values indicate that the NAD+ adsorption process is spontaneous and endothermic under the conditions applied. The driving force for the adsorption represents a positive gain in entropy, which is related predominantly to the water displacement from the double layer, and also to conformational changes of NAD+ on the gold surface. The kinetics of NAD+ adsorption was found to be both surface charge and mass-transport controlled. Based on ex situ PM-IRRAS measurements, a surface-charge-dependent conformation model for the adsorbed NAD+molecule was proposed. Experiments done in a batch electrochemical reactor confirmed that an amount of enzymatically active NADH produced on a bare Au surface depends on the regeneration potential, and varies from 28 % at high overpotentials (higher conversion, faster kinetics) up to 78% at low overpotentials (low conversion, slow kinetics). In order to increase the amount of enzymatically active NADH formed at high (industrially relevant) overpotentials, the Au surface was modified with Pt nano-islands, which resulted in an increase in the amount of NADH from 28 % to 63 %. A reaction mechanism taking into account the influence of Pt nano-islands was proposed.</description><creator>Damian, Alexis.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>An electrochemical study of NAD+ interaction with a polycrystalline gold surface /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Alexis Damian, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290960f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j8309</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mk61rh26k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The flotation process is designed to collect hydrophobic particles by attachment on to bubbles dispersed in slurry. The effectiveness of the flotation process depends on the properties of the bubble dispersion. For example, the ability of a machine to form small bubbles at a given flow rate of air will control the quantity of surface area available for bubble-particle collision. The gas dispersion, defined for the purposes of this thesis as bubbles suspended in slurry, is quantified by a group of "so-called" gas dispersion parameters including: superficial gas velocity (gas rate, Jg), gas holdup (epsilong), bubble size (Db) and bubble surface area flux (Sb). Cell characterization is a commonly used term in the study of gas dispersion parameters referring to any test designed specifically to increase understanding of the gas dispersion inside a particular machine, including how the dispersion can be manipulated by adjusting the operating variables and how the dispersion parameters vary with location inside a machine. Industrial tests were done to study mechanisms of manipulating the gas dispersion in forced air and self-aerated mechanical flotation machines, demonstrating that gas rate can be used to manipulate the gas dispersion in forced air machines, while froth depth, impeller speed and impeller submergence can be used to manipulate the dispersion in self-aerated machines. Facilitated by the development of the multi-Jg sensor, a technique based on gas rate mapping was developed for down-the-bank sample point selection. Experience using the sensor is described. Based on industrial tests, recommendations regarding sample point selection for down-the-bank optimization are offered. The development of an axial pressure profile sensor is described, facilitating axial investigation of variation in gas dispersion parameters. The proposed technique can be used to evaluate machine operating conditions and to resolve previously unexplained results.</description><creator>Doucet, Jason S.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Characterization of gas dispersion in industrial flotation machines</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Jason S. Doucet, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xm23r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mk61rh26k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hc46z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An experimental study of turbulent forced convection from the plates in the spatially-periodic fully-developed region of air flows in a straight rectangular duct fitted with interrupted-plate inserts is presented. These flows have features akin to those produced in the cores of offset-fin compact heat exchangers. A technique based on the lumped parameter analysis was proposed to determine average heat transfer coefficients on the surfaces of specially designed and instrumented test plates installed in the spatially-periodic fully-developed flow region. This technique was validated using complementary numerical simulations of unsteady three-dimensional heat conduction inside the plates. The results were obtained for Reynolds number (based on the average velocity in the minimum cross-sectional area and a hydraulic diameter) in the range 2,000 to 30,000. The main goal of this experimental research was to obtain reliable heat transfer results that could be used to check and refine corresponding mathematical models and numerical solution methods.</description><creator>Camargo, Lorena.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Spatially-periodic turbulent forced convection in interrupted-plate rectangular ducts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Lorena Camargo, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r338j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hc46z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b8515n63m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A computational methodology for the optimization of the thermal performance of straight ducts with non-twisted, uninterrupted, longitudinal internal fins is formulated and demonstrated in the context of steady, laminar, fully-developed forced convection, accounting for conjugate heat conduction in the fins. The fluid flow and heat transfer problems are solved using control-volume-based finite difference and finite element methods. The optimization is done using a gradient method. The fins shapes are approximated using non-uniform rational B-splines (NURBS). The control points of the NURBS curves are among the design variables. In the demonstration problems, the objective was to maximize the total rate of heat transfer to the fluid per unit length of the duct, subject to the constraint of keeping the corresponding pumping power constant. Results pertaining to four sample ducts with fins made of stainless steel, aluminum, and copper, and air as the working fluid, are presented and discussed.</description><creator>Duplain, Eric.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>Computational optimization of the thermal performance of internally finned ducts</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Eric Duplain, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913q17q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515n63m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:70795798w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis explores alternative ways for English literature students in Taiwanese Science Universities to choose more culturally accessible works in addition to the canonical English and American literature. Currently, many students consider their experience of reading Western literature to be both perplexing and frustrating because of inadequate language capability as well as unfamiliarity with Western culture. The rationale for introduction to works emerging from the Chinese diaspora is to enable students to situate their personal experiences within the context of different cultures, but ones that nonetheless have accommodated Chinese communities and values. Bearing this in mind, choosing English language works from within the Chinese diaspora is a natural progression and is based on the assumption that its content shares the same cultural identity that Taiwanese students are already familiar with. My hope is to provide teaching strategies for literature teachers of Taiwan to consider. The learning culture in Taiwan tends to dissociate the self and sentiments from the learning experience. Accordingly, it is hard for them to express their own feelings within the learning environment. In this thesis I try to address these problems through examination of Rosenblatt's transactional theory (1995), and exemplification of the theory through Nussbaum's literary exegesis of Henry James' Golden Bowl. I then attempt a parallel study of Wayson Choy's The Jade Peony (1995) as an example of how a work from the Chinese diaspora might be used in a Taiwanese classroom. I argue that the application of transactional theory could enhance meaning making in English literature classes for Taiwanese students. The thesis concludes with a discussion of strategic emphases for teachers of English literature in Taiwan.</description><creator>Lu, Liang-Yuan, 1962-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Taiwan.</subject><subject>Canadian literature -- Chinese-Canadian authors -- Study and teaching -- Taiwan.</subject><title>Teaching Chinese-Canadian literature to Taiwanese students : an educational strategy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Liang-Yuan Lu, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g7783.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/70795798w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ks65hc477</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:17:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In 1995, fiddler Ashley MacIsaac released the album Hi, How Are You Today? that featured MacIsaac performing traditional Celtic tunes accompanied by modern rock instruments. The musical genre transformation on the album (notable because people who were not fans of Celtic music bought this album, tracks were released for airplay, and music videos accompanied the singles) can be studied according to the types of genre transformation outlined by Alastair Fowler in Kinds of Literature. If MacIsaac's goal was to offer a popular rock album while playing traditional tunes on the fiddle, critics and members of his audience inevitably questioned his motivation, from which charges of pandering and exploitation followed. Alternate interpretations stressed that MacIsaac was merely adapting traditional music to reflect a changing musical climate. This thesis examines such perspectives, along with the global phenomenon of modernizing folk music amidst the ambiguous boundary between popular and folk musical genres.</description><creator>MacDonald, Jennifer Marie.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Fiddle tunes -- Nova Scotia -- Cape Breton.</subject><subject>Folk music -- Nova Scotia -- Cape Breton.</subject><subject>Rock music -- Analysis, appreciation.</subject><subject>MacIsaac, Ashley.</subject><subject>Celtic music -- Nova Scotia -- Cape Breton.</subject><subject>Rock music -- Nova Scotia -- Cape Breton.</subject><title>&amp;quot;Devil on the fiddle&amp;quot; : the musical and social ramifications of genre transformation in Cape Breton music</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Jennifer Marie MacDonald, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rk599.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ks65hc477</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):25750</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>