<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T00:52:36Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):12975" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9s161951b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Consensus on physical mechanisms linking work posture to discomfort and disorder risk has not been reached. The objective of this dissertation was to use a series of laboratory studies to identify measurements associated with discomfort and disorder risk in lower limb, back and neck/shoulder regions, and assess how these measurement outcomes differ between standing, seated and sit-standing postures. Participatory intervention methods were also used to investigate workplace factors that impact on posture selection and rotation. In the core set of investigations, healthy participants performed an industrially-modelled box-folding task over three 34-minute sessions in standing, seated and sit-standing postures (developed using a novel foot stand) while lower limb vascular parameters, trunk and upper limb muscular parameters, postural kinetics and discomfort were measured. Links between discomfort in various body regions and changes in the vascular, muscular and kinetic outcomes were investigated within and between postures. Investigation at a partner enterprise was conducted using 'participatory ergonomics' investigation methods and establishment of an "Ergonomics Team". Results show that during standing work, increases in blood volume and postural sway are associated with lower limb discomfort, and initially higher levels of shared activation between bilateral hip musculature are associated with higher levels of back discomfort. In comparison to standing, seated work leads to improved lower limb vascular and discomfort outcomes, but increases muscular demands and discomfort in the back and neck/shoulder regions. Also in comparison to standing, the sit-standing posture led to improved lower limb outcomes, with no significant differences in back and neck/shoulder outcomes. Together, findings reveal that each posture has positive and negative consequences. Data suggests that frequent (15-20min) rotation between postures may prevent onset of unwanted effects. Meanwhile, early investigations at the workplace revealed key policy, work organization and design issues that influenced the choice of appropriate laboratory methods and may affect knowledge uptake related to posture selection and rotation in the plant. As such, an integrated, participatory ergonomics approach may be optimal in ensuring that relevant laboratory methods are developed to produce usable knowledge for the workplace, and key knowledge translation strategies are in place for dissemination back to the workplace.</description><description>Les mécanismes reliant la posture de travail à l'inconfort et au risque de maladie ne sont toujours pas bien compris. L'objectif de cette dissertation était d'utiliser une série d'études de laboratoires afin d'identifier ces mécanismes pour les régions des membres inférieurs, du dos et des membres supérieurs, et d'évaluer comment ces mesures diffèrent entre les postures debout, assis, et assis-debout. Des méthodes d'intervention participative ont aussi été utilisées afin d'investiguer les facteurs de travail ayant un impact sur la sélection et la rotation des postures.Dans la majorité des investigations, des participants en santé ont effectué une tâche de pliage de boites modélisée d'après l'industrie durant trois séances de 34 minutes en posture debout, assis et assis-debout (à l'aide d'un support de pieds nouvellement développé) alors qu'étaient enregistrés des paramètres vasculaires aux membres inférieurs, des paramètres musculaires à la colonne et au membre supérieur, la cinétique de posture et l'inconfort. Des liens entre l'inconfort à diverses régions corporelles et les changements des mesures vasculaires, musculaires et cinétiques ont été évalués pour chaque posture et entre elles. Une investigation à une entreprise partenaire a été effectuée en utilisant des méthodes d'ergonomie participative et en établissant une 'Équipe Ergo'. Les résultats démontrent que durant le travail debout, des augmentations de volume sanguin et d'oscillation de la posture étaient associés à l'inconfort au membre inférieur, et une élévation initiale des niveaux d'activation mutuelle entre la musculature bilatérale des hanches était associée à des niveaux plus élevés d'inconfort du dos. En comparaison à la posture debout, la posture assis-debout a mené à des améliorations des mesures du membre inférieur, sans différences significatives des mesures du dos et de la région cou-épaules. Ensemble, ces résultats démontrent que chaque posture a des effets positifs et négatifs. Les données suggèrent qu'une rotation fréquente (15-20min) entre les postures pourrait prévenir l'apparition d'effets indésirables. Par ailleurs, les investigations préliminaires en entreprise ont révélé des aspects-clés de nature politiques, d'organisation du travail et de design qui ont influencé le choix des méthodes de laboratoire appropriées et qui pourront influencer l'utilisation des connaissances en lien avec le choix et la rotation des postures à l'usine. De surcroit, une approche intégrée d'ergonomie participative serait optimale pour assurer le développement de méthodes de laboratoire pertinentes afin de produire des connaissances applicables en milieu de travail et d'implanter des stratégies de courtage de connaissances pour la dissémination en milieu de travail.</description><creator>Antle, David</creator><contributor>Julie Cote (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health Sciences - Occupational Health and Therapy</subject><title>The use of laboratory and participatory ergonomic research models to investigate working posture in industry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77st281.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9s161951b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nc580q966</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Microfluidic systems open up new possibilities for in vitro cell biology research, mainly due to their ability to control the cellular microenvironment at physiologically relevant spatiotemporal scales. As such, several microfluidic systems have been introduced for the generation of concentration gradients and have been used for cell chemotaxis studies. However, these methods typically involve a trade-off between temporal control of the gradient and minimizing the applied shear stresses on the cells, and often require culturing cells in micro-channels. In this dissertation, we develop microfluidic quadrupoles (MQs) and demonstrate their first use in a laboratory setting. Two MQs with different configurations are presented; a lateral MQ that is associated with a stagnation point at its center, and a linear MQ with a stagnation zone bounded by two hydrodynamically confined streams. We also introduce "floating" concentration gradients of biochemicals that can be produced using MQs by injecting a solute through one of the poles. Floating gradients are controllable, associated with minimal shear stresses, can be applied to any flat substrate in a channel-less microfluidic system, and can be rapidly adjusted and moved. We used the lateral MQ to apply floating gradients of Interleukin-8 to cultured human neutrophils in a culture dish, and developed novel chemotaxis assays with stationary and moving gradients. Furthermore, we observed the real-time dynamics of neutrophils during adhesion, polarization, and migration, and showed that neutrophils migrate longer distances when following moving gradients in comparison to stationary gradients.The work presented in this dissertation introduces a new area of research in the field of fluidic multipoles and floating gradients, as well as their applications in the biomedical sciences. Furthermore, this work sets the foundation for developing novel biological and cell chemotaxis assays using moving concentration gradients. These assays can then be combined with pharmacological studies and help to further understand the mechanisms of cellular polarization, migration, and desensitization.</description><description>Les systèmes microfluidiques ouvrent de nouvelles possibilités pour la recherche in vitro en biologie cellulaire, notamment par leur capacité à contrôler le microenvironnement cellulaire à des échelles spatiotemporelles physiologiquement pertinentes. En ce sens, plusieurs systèmes microfluidiques ont été introduits pour la génération de gradients de concentration et ont été utilisés pour des études sur la chimiotaxie cellulaire. Cependant, ces méthodes font face à un compromis entre le contrôle temporel du gradient et la minimisation de la contrainte de cisaillement appliqué  sur les cellules. De plus, elles requièrent souvent de mettre les cellules en culture dans des microcanaux. Dans cette dissertation, nous démontrons la première utilisation des quadripôles microfluidiques (QM) dans un contexte expérimental. Nous présentons deux QM avec des configurations différentes : un QM latéral associé à un point de stagnation en son centre, et un QM linéaire avec une zone de stagnation reliée par deux flux hydrodynamiquement confinés. Nous présentons aussi des gradients de concentration « flottants » de produits biochimiques réalisés à l'aide de QM en injectant un soluté à travers un des pôles. Les gradients mobiles sont réglables, associés à une contrainte de cisaillement minimale, peuvent être appliqués à n'importe quel substrat plat dans un système microfluidique sans canal, et peuvent être rapidement ajustés et déplacés. Nous avons utilisé le QM latéral pour appliquer des gradients de concentration mobiles de l'Interleukin-8 à des neutrophiles humains dans une plaque de culture, et avons développé de nouveaux tests pour mesurer la chimiotaxie avec des gradients fixes et mobiles. De plus, nous avons observé la dynamique des neutrophiles en temps réel durant l'adhésion, la polarisation, et la migration, et avons démontré que les neutrophiles migrent sur de plus longues distances lorsqu'ils suivent des gradients mobiles plutôt que des gradients fixes.Les travaux présentés dans cette dissertation ouvrent un nouveau champ de recherche dans le domaine des multipôles fluidiques et des gradients mobiles, ainsi que leur application dans les sciences biomédicales. De plus, ces travaux sont une base pour le développement de nouveaux tests biologiques et mesurant la chiomiotaxie utilisant des gradients de concentration mobiles. Ces tests peuvent ensuite être combinés à des études pharmacologiques pour aider à mieux comprendre les mécanismes de polarisation, migration, et désensibilisation cellulaire. </description><creator>Qasaimeh, Mohammad Ameen</creator><contributor>David Juncker (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Biomedical</subject><title>Microfluidic quadrupoles and their applications in cell chemotaxis studies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0g354j56t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nc580q966</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:05741v87t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background: Kyphoplasty and Vertebroplasty are important tools for stabilizing spine fractures due to osteoporosis or cancer.  However, cement leakage during these procedures, especially in the cases of posterior vertebral wall defects, is a major source of morbidity and degraded outcome.  Aim: The goal of this work is twofold: 1) To create a reproducible and standardized posterior vertebral wall defect, cement leakage model and 2) To create and test an intravertebral membrane and placement system that is capable of blocking cement egress from cement injected into the vertebral body during vertebroplasty and kyphoplasty procedures.  Materials and methods: Thirty artificial individual lumbar vertebrae models, made from polyurethane, were used for this study. Sawbones were divided in three groups of 10. Group A consisted of sawbones without posterior wall defect. Sawbones of group B and C, consisted of  sawbones specially modified to represent vertebrae with posterior wall defect. Part 1: Using a custom made wooden jig standard kyphoplasty procedures were done in sawbones of group A and B under fluoroscopic control.  The volume of injected cement was calculated using two methods. Firstly, by calculating the weight of the sawbone, before and after cement injections.Secondly, we calculated the volume of injected cement, using 3D CT volumetric study. Part 2: In ten sawbones with posterior wall defect (group C), the standard kyphoplasty procedure was modified. A new vertebroplasty system has been designed based on the existing Kyphoplasty™  instruments, which included a new membrane-trocar component. During the kyphoplasty procedures the membrane remained in situ, preventing cement leakage through the posterior wall defect. Following the cement injections, the sawbones were weighed and a blinded radiologic evaluated results using volumetric 3D CT scan. Results were analyzed using non parametric  statistics for differences in amount of cement injected and the cement leakage between the vertebrae with and without the membrane. Results: Part 1: Macroscopically and under fluoroscopic control, cement leakage occurred through the posterior wall defect in all sawbones of group B. The mean volume of injected cement in group A sawbones was 3.10±0.623 cm3. In group B the mean volume of injected cement was 2.48±0.434 cm3. Statistical analysis, revealed that difference of the mean volume of injected cement in two groups reached statistical significance (P=0,0189). Part 2: In all tested analogs, the intravertebral membrane succeed on stopping posterior wall cement leakage, as confirmed fluoroscocpically and under direct vision. The mean volume of injected cement as calculated by measuring the weight of the sawbones before and after cement injection (minus the weight of the occlusion membrane), was 2.68±0.578 gr. We further investigated the differences of the volume of injected cement between the three groups of sawbones; One way ANOVA revealed that difference between the three groups was not statistical significant (P=0.025). 3D CT volumetric study  revealed that the volumes of cement injected to the three groups of sawbones were 5.542±0.99, 5.240±1.22 and 5.209±1.304 cm3 for groups A, B and C respectively. Conclusions: We have successfully created a posterior vertebral wall defect model for the testing of the posterior leakage during the kyphoplasty procedures. Additionally, the newly developed occlusion membrane effectively prevented the cement leakage in all the tested analogs. Further testing is necessary before applying its use to the clinical practice. </description><description>Contexte:La kyphoplastie et la vertébroplastie sont des outils importants pour stabiliser les fractures vertébrales dues à l'ostéoporose ou le cancer. Cependant, des fuites de ciment au cours de ces procédures, en particulier dans les cas de défauts de la paroi vertébrales postérieures, est une source majeure de morbidité et des résultats dégradés.But: Le but de ce travail est double: 1) Créer un  modèle reproductible et normalisée de la postérieure paroi vertébrale, modèle du ciment fuites et 2) Créer et tester une membrane intravertebral et de placement qui est capable de bloquer l'évacuation de ciment , injecté dans le corps vertébral, pendant des procédures de vertébroplastie et cyphoplastie. Matériaux et méthodes: Trente modèles artificiels individuels lombaires de vertèbres, fabriqués à partir de polyuréthane, ont été utilisés pour cette étude. Sawbones ont été divisés en trois groupes de 10. Groupe A se composait de sawbones sans postérieure défaut. Sawbones du groupe B et C, se composaient de sawbones spécialement modifiés pour représenter vertèbres à défaut de la paroi postérieure. Partie 1: Utilisation d'un gabarit en bois sur mesure,les procédures standards de cyphoplastie ont été appliquées aux sawbones du groupe A et B, sous contrôle fluoroscopique. Le volume de ciment injecté a été calculé en utilisant deux méthodes. Tout d'abord, en calculant les poids de la sawbone, avant et après l' injection du ciment Deuxièmement, nous avons calculé le volume de ciment injecté, en utilisant l'étude volumétrique 3D CT. Partie 2: En dix sawbones avec défaut paroi postérieure (groupe C), la procédure de kyphoplastie a été modifiée. Un nouveau système de vertébroplastie a été conçu basé sur les KyphoplastyTM instruments qui existaient déjà, et qui inclurent un nouveau composant, la membrane trocart. Pendant les procédures d'cyphoplastie la membrane reste in situ, ce qui empêche les fuites de ciment à travers le défaut de la paroi postérieure. Après les injections du ciment, les sawbones ont été pesés et évalués en aveugle radiologique résultats en utilisant volumétrique 3D CT scanner. Les résultats ont été analysés à l'aide des statistiques non paramétriques pour détecter des différences à la quantité du ciment injecté entre les vertèbres avec et sans la membrane. Résultats:Partie 1: macroscopiquement et sous contrôle fluoroscopique, les fuites de ciment ont eu lieu à travers le défaut de la paroi postérieure dans tous sawbones du groupe B. Le volume moyen de ciment injecté dans le groupe A était de 3,10 ± sawbones 0.623 cm3. Dans le groupe B, le volume moyen du ciment injecté était de 2,48 ± 0,434 cm3. L'analyse statistique a révélée que la différence du volume moyen du ciment injecté en deux groupes atteint une signification statistique (p = 0,0189). Partie 2: Dans tous les analogues testés, la membrane intravertebral réussit à arrêter la fuite du ciment de la paroi postérieure, comme il a été confirmé radioscopiquement et sous vision directe. Le volume moyen du ciment injecté, tel que calculé en mesurant le poids des sawbones avant et après l'injection de ciment était de 2,68 ± 0,578 gr. Nous avons également étudié les différences de volume du ciment injecté entre les trois groupes de carabin; ANOVA a révélée que la différence entre les trois groupes n'était pas statistiquement significative (P = 0,025). Une étude volumétrique 3D CT a révélée que les volumes du ciment injecté dans les trois groupes de sawbones étaient 5.542 ± 0.99, 5.240 ± 1.22 et 5.209 ± 1.304 cm3 respectivement pour les groupes A, B et C. Conclusions: Nous avons réussi à créer un modèle de défaut de la paroi vertébral postérieur pour l'évaluation de la fuite postérieure, pendant les procédures de cyphoplastie. En outre, la membrane d'occlusion, récemment développée, a efficacement empêché la fuite du ciment dans tous les analogues testés. Des analyses complémentaires sont nécessaires avant d'appliquer son utilisation à la pratique clinique.</description><creator>Nikolaou, Vasileios</creator><contributor>Peter Jarzem (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Jean Albert Ouellet (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery </subject><title>Development of a new vertebral defect occlusion membrane for use in vertebroplasty and kyphoplasty</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fq13g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741v87t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k0698b99j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The occurrence of microbial pathogens in drinking water sources is recognized as a significant threat to public health. A better understanding of the key processes governing the fate of microbial pathogens in groundwater aquifers can help mitigate the risk of drinking water contamination. The attachment of pathogens to aquifer surfaces and the inactivation of attached and suspended pathogens are key processes that attenuate the concentration of viable pathogens in potable water supplies. Although substantial research effort has been aimed at elucidating the role of various physical, chemical and biological factors on the inactivation rate of microbes suspended in the aqueous phase, our understanding of microbe inactivation when attached to grain surfaces is limited. Thus, the first objective of this work was to develop a fluorescence-based experimental technique for evaluating the inactivation kinetics of bacteria adhered onto a surface in an aqueous environment. The technique was sensitive enough to distinguish between the inactivation kinetics of different representative bacteria attached to either a negatively or a positively charged surface. The new method was then used to characterize bacterial inactivation kinetics when attached to environmentally relevant surface chemistries such as metal oxides over a broad range of groundwater chemistries. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) characterization of bacterial-surface bonding was used to interpret inactivation behavior. It was observed that attachment of cells to metal-oxide surfaces can lead to formation of covalent bonds, specifically O- and C-metal bonds, between the cell and the surface, resulting in reduced bacterial viability (i.e., cell membrane integrity). Surface and near-surface soils in cold climate regions experience low temperature and freeze-thaw (FT) conditions in the winter. Microorganisms that are of concern to groundwater quality may have the potential to survive low temperature and FT in the soil and aqueous environments. Although there is a large body of literature on the survival of pathogenic bacteria at different environmental conditions, little is known about their transport in groundwater environments in low temperatures and after FT. Thus, in the second part of the project, the effect of cold temperature and repeated FT on survival, survival strategies such as motility and biofilm formation, and virulence of selected Gram-negative and Gram-positive bacteria was investigated. The adhesion properties and transport of bacteria exposed to FT were studied using quartz crystal microbalance with dissipation monitoring (QCM-D) and water saturated sand-packed columns. The expression levels of different genes encoding synthesis of flagellin, extracellular matrix production, and virulence factors were measured using quantitative reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction (qRT-PCR). Our findings demonstrate that bacteria exhibited greater retention onto sand grains after exposure to FT. Moreover, bacteria tend to survive for longer periods of time and may become more virulent at low temperature in higher ionic strength waters thereby posing a potential threat to drinking water supplies.</description><description>L'apparition d'agents pathogènes microbiens dans les sources d'eau potable est reconnu comme une menace importante pour la santé publique. Une meilleure compréhension des processus fondamentaux qui régissent le sort des pathogènes microbiens dans les aquifères d'eau souterraine peut contribuer à atténuer le risque de contamination de l'eau potable. L'attachement des agents pathogènes aux surfaces des nappes phréatiques et leur inactivation lorsqu'ils sont attachés et suspendus, sont les processus clés qui atténuent la concentration des pathogènes viables dans l'approvisionnement en eau potable. Bien qu'un effort substantiel de recherche ait été réalisé, visant à élucider le rôle de divers facteurs physiques, chimiques et biologiques sur le taux d'inactivation des microbes en suspension dans la phase aqueuse, notre compréhension de l'inactivation du microbe lorsqu'il est attaché à la surface des grains est limitée. Ainsi, le premier objectif de ce travail était de développer une technique expérimentale basée sur la fluorescence pour évaluer la cinétique d'inactivation de bactéries collées sur une surface dans un environnement aqueux. La technique est suffisamment sensible pour faire la distinction entre la cinétique d'inactivation de différentes bactéries représentatives, montées soit sur une surface chargée négativement ou positivement. La nouvelle méthode a ensuite été utilisée pour caractériser la cinétique d'inactivation bactérienne lorsqu'elle est reliée à la chimie de surface environnementale telle que les oxydes métalliques et ceci sur une large gamme de produits chimiques des eaux souterraines. La caractérisation de la liaison bactérienne de surface par spectroscopie photoélectronique X (XPS) a été utilisée pour interpréter le comportement de l'inactivation. Il a été observé que l'attachement des cellules aux surfaces métal-oxyde peut conduire à la formation de liaisons covalentes, plus précisément des liaisons  O- et C-métal, entre la cellule et la surface, ce qui entraîne une réduction de la viabilité bactérienne (i.e. une perte de l'intégrité de la membrane cellulaire).Dans les régions à climat froid,  les sols de surface ou proches de la surface  subissent de basses températures et des périodes de gel-dégel (GD). Les micro-organismes qui sont des sources de préoccupation pour la qualité des eaux souterraines peuvent avoir le potentiel de survivre à basses températures et aux périodes de GD, dans le sol et les milieux aqueux. Bien qu'il existe une littérature abondante sur la survie des bactéries pathogènes à différentes conditions environnementales, on possède peu d'informations au sujet de leur transport dans les environnements d'eau souterraine à des températures basses et après GD. Ainsi, dans la deuxième partie du projet, l'effet de la température froide et l'effet des périodes GD répétés ont été étudiés sur les stratégies de survie telles que la mobilité et la formation de biofilms ainsi que la virulence des bactéries sélectionnées à Gram négatif et Gram positif . Les propriétés d'adhérence et le transport des bactéries exposées à des périodes de GD ont été étudiés à l'aide d'une microbalance à cristal de quartz avec mesure de la dissipation  (QCM-D) et de l'eau contenue dans des colonnes saturées de sable. Les niveaux d'expression des différents gènes codant pour la synthèse de la flagelline, la production de la matrice extracellulaire et des facteurs de virulence ont été mesurés en utilisant la transcription par réaction en chaîne par polymérase inverse quantitative (qRT-PCR). Nos résultats démontrent que les bactéries présentent une plus grande rétention sur les grains de sable après l'exposition aux périodes de GD. En outre, les bactéries ont tendance à survivre pendant de longues périodes de temps et peuvent devenir plus virulent à basse température dans des eaux à plus grande force ionique posant ainsi une menace potentielle pour l'eau potable.</description><creator>Asadishad, Bahareh</creator><contributor>Nathalie Tufenkji (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Subhasis Ghoshal (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</subject><title>Transport and survival of bacteria in model aquatic environments: role of water chemistry, surface geochemistry, and temperature</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1g05fg15f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698b99j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:df65vb948</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A basic framework for sustainable community-based drinking water systems (CBDWS) is studied in this research program; it is based on the performance of existing water supply systems and on the responses to a survey by the various stakeholders. A model for overall sustainability was developed and validated through its application to about 70 CBDWS in rural settings of northern areas of Pakistan (as part of a developing country case study). In addition, analyses and scenario projections of environmental component of sustainability were made along with detailed analyses and syntheses of statistical surveys to gauge stakeholder perspectives and priorities and to incorporate the results in overall sustainability. The study concluded that sustainable CBDWS can be developed and operated only with active participation of stakeholders (grouped by experience as technical, environmental, economic, social, and institutional). The system must maintain safe and drinkable water resources (environmental considerations) and also maintain the potential for renewability through technically optimized design, high quality execution and regular infrastructure maintenance in an economically beneficial and self-reliant set-up. Social and institutional involvement must also be an integral part of the system. Failure of any of these components can affect the sustainability of the entire system. A relevant definition for sustainable CBDWS was formulated, along with the development of a new model for CBDWS sustainability. The model showed that properly maintained sources, proper infrastructure, aware society, stable economy, and effective institutions are linked components of a sustainable CBDWS, and failure of any of these components can affect the sustainability of the entire system. Scenarios for population that would be without access to improved drinking water in 2015 were also projected on the basis of the field studies. The field studies concluded that environmental sustainability in terms of capacity, quality, reliability and protection of drinking water sources is critical. Projection of these findings to a broader level shows that unless urgent measures are undertaken, serious "fallbacks" may occur in the established Millennium Development Goals (MDG) of the United Nations.  In the context of the relevant MDG, such fallbacks can reverse the situation to a previously unsustainable condition.The stakeholder subjectivities and priorities for the various elements of CBDWS were examined and quantitatively incorporated into the system. The environmental and institutional components appeared as higher priorities among the various group stakeholders. The environmental component is a higher priority among stakeholders with natural sciences and engineering backgrounds, whereas institutional component (related to community institutions) is the foremost priority for stakeholders with social sciences backgrounds. Finally, for monitoring and evaluating CBDWS, a cost-effective and user-friendly applied framework capable of accommodating field data with varying levels of quality was developed.</description><description>Un cadre de base pour les systèmes d'eau potable communautaires durables (CBDWS) est étudié dans ce programme de recherche, il est basé sur la performance des systèmes d'approvisionnement en eau existantes et sur les réponses à une enquête menée par les différents intervenants. Un modèle de durabilité globale a été développée et validée par son application à environ 70 CBDWS en milieu rural des régions du nord du Pakistan (dans le cadre d'une étude de cas de pays en développement). En outre, les analyses et les projections du scénario de composante environnementale du développement durable ont été faites ainsi que des analyses et des synthèses détaillées des enquêtes statistiques pour évaluer les perspectives et les priorités parties prenantes et d'intégrer les résultats en matière de durabilité globale. L'étude conclut que CBDWS durables peuvent être développés et exploités uniquement avec la participation active des parties prenantes (défini dans l'étude: techniques, environnementales, économiques, sociales et institutionnelles). Le système doit conserver des ressources en eau salubre et potable (considérations environnementales) et aussi de maintenir le potentiel de renouvellement grâce à une conception techniquement optimisé, l'exécution de haute qualité et un entretien régulier de l'infrastructure d'une manière économiquement avantageuse et autonomes set-up. L'engagement social et institutionnel doit également faire partie intégrante du système. Défaillance d'un de ces composants peut affecter la durabilité de l'ensemble du système. Une définition pertinente pour CBDWS durable a été élaboré, avec le développement d'un nouveau modèle de durabilité CBDWS. Le modèle indique que les sources sont bien entretenus, infrastructures adéquates, la société consciente, une économie stable et des institutions efficaces sont des éléments nécessaires et liés d'une CBDWS durables, et l'échec de l'un de ces composants peut affecter la durabilité de l'ensemble du système. Scénarios pour la population qui seraient sans accès à l'eau potable en 2015 ont également été projetées sur la base d'une étude de terrain. L'étude de terrain a conclu que la durabilité de l'environnement en termes de capacité, la qualité, la fiabilité et la protection des sources d'eau potable est essentielle. Projection des conclusions de l'étude sur le terrain à une plus grande échelle montre que si des mesures urgentes ne sont pas prises, solutions de repli graves peuvent survenir dans les Objectifs du Millénaire pour le développement établis (OMD) des Nations Unies. Dans le contexte des OMD pertinents, ces solutions de repli peuvent inverser la situation d'un état précédemment insoutenable. Les subjectivités des parties prenantes et des priorités pour les différents éléments de CBDWS ont été examinés et quantifiable incorporés dans le système. Les composantes environnementales et institutionnelles sont apparues comme des priorités plus importantes entre les différentes parties prenantes du groupe. La composante environnementale est une priorité plus élevée chez les intervenants en sciences naturelles et en génie milieux, alors que composante institutionnelle (par rapport aux institutions communautaires) est la priorité pratique pour les parties prenantes avec les sciences sociales milieux. Enfin, pour suivre et évaluer CBDWS, un cadre appliqué rentable et convivial, mais bien définie et systématique capable de recevoir des données de terrain avec différents niveaux de qualité a été développé.</description><creator>Aslam, Muhammad Sagheer</creator><contributor>Dominic Frigon (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>M Saeed Mirza (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Civil</subject><title>Sustainability of community-based drinking water systems in developing countries</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sj139533j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/df65vb948</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53x009z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Underground mines are valuable sources of geothermal energy. The present study aims to understand the heat transfer phenomenon that takes place during heat extraction from underground mines using two distinctive techniques. In the first technique, geothermal heat is extracted from abandoned mine tunnels by circulating water through the tunnels, which are usually flooded after the mine is decommissioned. The second technique is based on the novel idea of installing geothermal heat exchange tubes in backfilled mine stopes prior to backfill placement in the stope. This second technique is patented by researchers at McGill University. To study geothermal heat extraction from abandoned mine tunnels, a numerical heat transfer model is developed, which takes into account forced convection inside the tunnel, conduction in the rock mass surrounding the tunnel and heat load intermittency. After development, the heat transfer model is validated by comparing its results against results from existing heat transfer models. Effects of various geometric and physical parameters on heat extraction from mine tunnels are studied using the newly developed heat transfer model, and the parameters that have the first-order effect are identified. To investigate the feasibility of the novel technique of heat extraction from backfilled mine stopes, numerical and experimental heat transfer studies are conducted. To assess the performance of a stope-coupled geothermal heat exchanger system, a numerical model is developed. The model is capable of considering the effect of heat conduction as well as natural convection. The results of the developed model are compared with those from existing ground-coupled heat exchanger models. To further validate the developed numerical model, a series of experimental tests are conducted using a small-scale laboratory test setup built for this purpose. By introducing information gathered from a number of Canadian mines into the developed heat transfer model, effects of hydraulic conductivity, thermal conductivity, rate of heat extraction and arrangement of heat exchanger tubes are investigated.</description><description>Les mines souterraines sont des sources précieuses d'énergie géothermique. Cette étude vise à comprendre le phénomène de transfert de chaleur qui a lieu lors de l'extraction  de chaleur à partir des mines souterraines, en utilisant deux techniques distinctes. Pour la première technique, la chaleur géothermique est extraite à partir des tunnels des mines abandonnés. Le mécanisme d'extraction est fait par la circulation d'eau à travers ces tunnels qui sont habituellement submergés après que la mine est déclassée. La deuxième technique est basée sur l'idée nouvelle de l'installation des tubes qui peut échanger la chaleur géothermique dans les chantiers miniers remblayés avant le placement du remblai. Cette technique est brevetée par des chercheurs de l'Université McGill. Un modèle numérique de transfert de chaleur a été développé pour étudier l'extraction de chaleur géothermique des tunnels de mines abandonnés. Ce modèle tient compte de la convection forcée  à l'intérieur du tunnel, la conduction dans la masse rocheuse qui entour le tunnel et l'intermittence de la charge thermique. Après son développement, le modèle est validé en comparant ses résultats aux ceux des modèles existants. Les effets de plusieurs paramètres géothermiques et physiques sur l'extraction de la chaleur à partir des tunnels des mines sont étudiés en utilisant le nouveau modèle développé. Les paramètres qui ont l'effet du premier-ordre sont ainsi identifiés. Pour étudier la faisabilité de la technique nouvellement développé pour l'extraction de chaleur par des chantiers des mines remblayés, les études numériques et expérimentales sont menées. Un modèle numérique a été développé pour évaluer la performance d'un chantier couplé avec un système d'échangeur de chaleur géothermique.   Le modèle est capable de tenir compte l'effet de la conduction ainsi que la convection naturelle. Les résultats du modèle développé sont comparés à ceux des modèles d'échangeurs de chaleur géothermique existants. Pour une validation plus concrète sur le modèle numérique développé, une série de tests expérimentaux est effectuée en utilisant une configuration dans le laboratoire à petite échelle construite à cet effet. En introduisant  l'information recueillie à partir de nombreux mines canadiennes dans le modèle de transfert de chaleur, les effets de la conductivité hydraulique, la conductivité thermique, la vitesse d'extraction de chaleur et la disposition des tubes de l'échangeur de chaleur sont étudiés.</description><creator>Ghoreishi Madiseh, Seyed Ali</creator><contributor>Faramarz P Hassani (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Peter Henry Radziszewski (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical </subject><title>Numerical and experimental study of geothermal energy extraction from underground mines</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zs25xc923.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53x009z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pr17m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les petits ARN interférents (siARN) et les oligonucléotides antisens (OA) se servent de mécanismes cellulaires naturels pour inhiber l'expression de l'ARN messager (ARNm) de manière spécifique à la séquence. Le développement des oligonucléotides synthétiques (ON) comme agents efficaces et spécifiques de l'inhibition de l'expression de gènes cibles a permis de fournir des outils d'importance majeure dans les domaines de la biologie moléculaire, de la génomique fonctionnelle et pour la recherche en biochimie. Les acides nucléiques inhibiteurs de l'expression de gènes font l'objet de nombreux tests cliniques en vue d'être utilisés pour le traitement d'un grand nombre de maladies. Cependant, ces résultats encourageants doivent être contrebalancés par plusieurs difficultés auxquelles les thérapies à ON doivent faire face. siARN et OA sont rapidement métabolisés dans le corps, ils peuvent déclencher des effets secondaires indésirables et le transport d'ON actifs dans les cellules cibles demeure un important problème. Modifier chimiquement la structure naturelle d'un acide nucléique peut permettre de résoudre certaines de ces difficultés. Cette thèse décrit la réalisation d'un ensemble d'études visant à développer des analogues fluorés d'acides nucléiques aux propriétés chimiques et biologiques améliorées et à les employer comme agents inhibiteurs de l'expression de gènes.</description><description>Small interfering RNAs (siRNAs) and antisense oligonucleotides (AONs) use natural cellular machinery to enact sequence-specific mRNA inhibition. The development of synthetic oligonucleotides (ONs) as potent and specific agents for silencing the expression of target genes has provided incredibly useful tools for molecular biology, functional genomics, and biochemistry research. Gene silencing nucleic acids are under active investigation in the clinic for the treatment of a wide variety of diseases. While promising, ON therapeutics face several challenges. siRNAs and AONs are rapidly degraded in the body, may cause undesired side effects, and the delivery of active ONs to target cells remains a significant challenge. Chemical modification of the natural nucleic acid structure can address several of these shortcomings. This thesis describes a series of studies directed towards the development of fluorinated nucleic acid analogues as gene silencing agents with improved biological and chemical properties. A screen of chemically modified siRNA constructs revealed that 2′F-ANA, a fluorinated DNA analogue, can be combined with 2′F-RNA or LNA, rigid RNA analogues, to produce potent gene silencing agents devoid of natural RNA. Several rules were developed to optimize the potency of these chemically modified siRNAs, including a method for creating duplex binding asymmetry within 21mer duplexes through alternating 2′F-ANA and 2′F-RNA inserts along the siRNA passenger strand. These active siRNAs have enhanced nuclease stability, and reduced immunostimulatory properties.Thermal stability studies revealed that 1-1 alternations of 2′F-ANA and 2′F-RNA are destabilizing in siRNA duplexes, whereas 3-3 alternations are neutral. siRNAs incorporating 3-3 and 1-1  2′F-ANA/2′F-RNA motifs produce potent gene silencing. Experiments suggest that the gene silencing cellular machinery, the RISC complex, readily binds the 5′ terminus of siRNA guide strands modified with 2′F-ANA and 2′F-RNA. Gene silencing siRNAs chemically modified with 2′F-ANA, 2′F-RNA, and LNA were applied towards silencing the expression of several endogenous and therapeutically relevant genes, demonstrating the versatility and therapeutic potential of these constructs. Genes linked to antiviral (4E-BP1 and 4E-BP2) and anticancer (Bcl-2 and DRR) applications were readily silenced with chemically modified siRNAs and AONs in a variety of disease models.Phosphorothioated (PS) 2′F-ANA oligonucleotides were investigated as AONs targeting the cancer-linked Bcl-2 and AR genes. Results demonstrate that PS-2′F-ANA oligonucleotides are fully compatible with gymnotic cellular delivery, a carrier-free method for achieving cellular uptake in tissue culture. In a second delivery approach, chemically modified siRNAs and AONs were conjugated with maleimide, alkyne, and cyclooctyne functionalities to allow straightforward and robust coupling to the exterior of an antibody-targeted nanoparticle delivery system (Her-NP). This novel delivery system features an enzyme-mediated ON release approach, and an antibody-targeted cellular uptake mechanism allowing specific cell targeting. Results demonstrate that siRNAs and AONs delivered on Her-NPs enact gene silencing as efficiently as siRNAs delivered with Lipofectamine, but without the associated cellular toxicity. The first synthesis of novel difluorinated nucleoside analogues 2′,4′-difluorouridine (DiF-U) and 2′,4′-difluorocytidine (DiF-C) is described. In-depth NMR-based structural characterization reveals that these nucleoside analogues adopt rigid North sugar conformations. DiF-U was incorporated in a variety of oligonucleotide duplexes, demonstrating several interesting effects on duplex stability. DiF-U is highly destabilizing in the DNA strand of DNA:RNA and DNA:DNA duplexes, mildly destabilizing in the RNA strand of a DNA:RNA duplex, and neutral in the RNA strand of an RNA:RNA duplex.</description><creator>Deleavey, Glen</creator><contributor>Masad J Damha (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Chemistry - Organic</subject><title>Modified nucleic acids for the regulation of gene expression: an investigation of synthetic 2' and 4' fluorinated oligonucleotides</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128f327.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pr17m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5999n666k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les expériences de stress psychologique constituent d'importants déterminants de la santé physique et mentale ; ainsi, un intérêt central de la recherché actuelle vise l'élucidation des relations entre la santé et le stress. Un système physiologique particulier fait l'objet d'un examen approfondi en ce qu'il serait fondamental à cette relation complexe, l'axe-hypotalamo-hypophyso-surrénalien. Bien qu'étant un système central de stress, la réponse de l'axe HHS varie considérablement parmi les individus. Les dernières décennies de recherche démontrent que certains facteurs individuels contribuent aux différentes réponses de stress et aux questions de santé. L'étude de ces facteurs devient conséquemment cruciale à notre compréhension des mécanismes sous-jacents liants les expériences du stress à la santé. Un facteur important, sinon majeur, influençant fortement la réponse de stress via l'axe HHS réside dans le fait d'être de sexe féminin ou masculin. Afin de poursuivre l'élucidation de ces différences de sexe quant à la réponse de stress, le travail présenté dans cette thèse vise l'éclaircissement des interactions entre les facteurs biologiques et situationnels d'un stress expérimental. Ainsi, l'effet des phases du cycle menstruel et une variation des genres au sein d'un comité d'évaluation ont été proposés pour l'étude du stress psychosocial. Les résultats nous révèlent que ces différences dans les réponses de stress entre les femmes et les hommes sont influencées par la variation des hormones sexuelles et le genre du comité d'évaluation. La considération de l'importance des phases du cycle menstruel de la réponse de stress des femmes nous a fait poursuivre, dans une seconde étude, notre questionnement concernant son effet sur l'association entre les réponses physiologiques et affectives du stress. Suite à un stress d'ordre psychosocial, les résultats pointent vers un effet significatif des phases du cycle menstruel sur l'association entre la réponse affective de stress et la réponse endocrine du stress (cortisol). À notre connaissance, il s'agit de la première démonstration de l'effet modulateur du cycle menstruel sur l'association entre les réponses affectives et endocrines du stress. Dans notre dernière étude, nous avons étudié les effets des phases du cycle menstruel sur les réponses physiologiques, affectives et neurales durant un stress psychosocial. Confirmant les résultats de la seconde étude, ils incluent à présent les aspects neuronaux de la réponse de stress, démontrant que les phases du cycle menstruel influence significativement l'association entre les aspects physiologiques et neuronaux du stress psychosocial. Cette thèse se termine par une discussion quant à la pertinence de ces résultats pour notre compréhension des réponses de stress psychosocial chez la femme et l'homme, ainsi que des hypothèses explicatives de l'association différentielle entre les aspects affectifs et physiologiques de la réponse de stress durant les phases du cycle menstruel. Les limites de la présente étude accompagnées de recherches futures sont aussi indiquées. </description><description>The experiences of psychological stress are important determinants of one's physical and mental health; therefore, a central focus of today's research is to unveil the relationship between health and stress.  One physiological system that has been thoroughly investigated as underlining this complex relationship is the hypothalamic pituitary adrenal (HPA) axis. Although it is a central stress system, the HPA axis response varies greatly across individuals. Research of the past decades demonstrated that certain individual factors contribute to these different stress responses and health outcomes. Indeed, investigation of these factors is central to our comprehension of the underlying mechanisms that link the experience of stress to health. An important, core, factor that shows a strong influence on the HPA axis response to stress, is whether one is a man or a woman. To further comprehend differences between men's and women's stress response, the work presented in this thesis aimed to investigate how the interaction between biological and situational factors affects physiological and psychological stress response in men and women. Therefore, I investigated the effect of variation of women's menstrual cycle phases (biological factor) and that of variation in the gender of an evaluative committee (situational factor) on male and female stress response to a social evaluative stress (giving a speech in front of an evaluative committee). Our results revealed that differences typically observed between men and women regarding their stress response are particularly influenced by women's hormonal milieu and the gender of an evaluative committee. Considering the importance of women's menstrual cycle phase to women's stress response, in the second study, we further examined its effect on the association between the physiological and affective responses to stress. This study was the first demonstration of the moderating effect of menstrual cycle phase on the association between the affective and physiological stress responses. Finally, in the last study for this thesis, I investigated effects of variation in menstrual cycle phase on women's physiological, affective, as well as neural responses to a social evaluative stress. The results from this study replicated the effects from our previous findings, and extended them to include an impact on the neural responses to stress. Specifically, we demonstrated that variation in menstrual cycle phases also significantly influences the association between the physiological and neural responses to a social evaluative stress. The thesis then concludes with a general discussion that addresses some of the questions that the findings from the three studies raise. I also discuss how these current findings expand our understanding of the psychophysiological stress responses in men and women. Study limitations and future directions are also highlighted.</description><creator>Duchesne, Annie</creator><contributor>Jens Pruessner (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Physiological, neural and affective responses to social evaluative stress in men and women: a question of context and menstrual cycle phases</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b435g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n666k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g158bm688</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents experimental and numerical investigations on the control of aeroacoustic and quasi-static pressures within the air column constituted by the player-instrument system in trombone performance.The core of this work tackles the nature of the interaction between a player's vibrating lips and his/her vocal tract. Firstly, a measurement method was developed in order to assess important characteristics of the acoustical coupling between the lips, the downstream resonator and the upstream airways. Subjects able to play over the full range demonstrated significant upstream influence in the higher register of the instrument. These players were categorized in two groups according to their ability to control the phase of the upstream impedance and their ability to generate powerful downstream acoustic energy. In order to further investigate the influence of the vocal tract on the behaviour of the lips of a trombone player, different conditions of upstream coupling were simulated on an artificial player system. This experiment demonstrated the importance of phase tuning on the behaviour of the lips; results particularly suggest the ability of a vocal-tract resonance to displace the playing frequency close to a lip mechanical resonance, hence producing maximal efficiency of the lip-excitation system. Numerical simulations involving different physical models of the lips and various conditions of upstream coupling lend support to experimental results; an upstream coupling at the fundamental frequency influences the playing frequency and hence the combined effect of the varying total impedance loading the lips and lip mobility at the playing frequency. It then results in different degrees of efficiency of the sound production mechanism with respect tothe acoustic energy produced. Finally, a quantitative analysis of chest-wall dynamics was conducted on a trombone player. Different standard tasks where analyzed with respect to the pressure developed by rib-cage and abdominal muscles, diaphragmatic activity, as well as embouchure and glottal resistance. This study aims to address the characteristics of physiological control and its relation to the management of the quasi-static mouth pressure. It also intends to provide further material to the discussion on physiological factors involved in the acoustical control of the vocal-tract.</description><description>Cette thèse présente une étude expérimentale et numérique sur le contrôle des pressions aéroacoustiques et quasi-statiques au sein de la colonne d'air formée par le musicien et son instrument dans le jeu du trombone.L'axe principal de ce travail s'articule autour de l'étude de l'interaction entre les lèvres du musicien et son conduit vocal. En premier lieu, une méthode de mesure est développée dans le but de quantifier les caractéristiques de couplage acoustique entre les lèvres, le résonateur formé par l'instrument, et les voies respiratoires en amont. Chez les sujets pouvant jouer sur le registre complet de l'instrument, le conduit vocal contribue de façon significative à la productiondu son dans le registre aigu. Deux catégories de stratégies sont proposées en fonction des caractéristiques de phase de l'impédance du conduit vocal à la fréquence fondamentale, ainsi que de la capacité à générer un maximum d'énergie acoustique. Afin d'étudier plus précisément l'influence du conduit vocal sur le comportement mécanique des lèvres d'un tromboniste, différentes conditions de couplage en amont sont simulées sur un système de bouche artificielle. Cette expérience permet de démontrer l'importance de l'ajustement de la phase de l'impédance en amont sur le comportement mécanique des lèvres. Les résultats obtenus mettent particulièrement en évidence les capacités d'une résonance de conduit vocal à déplacer la fréquence de jeu afin de potentiellement la rapprocher d'une fréquence de résonance mécanique des lèvres, produisant ainsi une efficacité maximale du système d'excitation. Des simulations numériques utilisant différents modèles physiques de lèvres et différentes conditions de couplage acoustique avec le conduit vocal confirment les hypothèses formulées; un couplage avec le conduit vocal à la fréquence fondamentale influence la fréquence de jeu. En conséquence, ces variations induisent des changements, d'une part de l'impédance acoustique chargeant les lèvres, et d'autre part de leur mobilité mécanique. Il en résulte différents degrés d'efficacité du mécanisme de production sonore en ce qui concerne l'énergie acoustique générée. Pour terminer, une étude quantitative de la dynamique du thorax est conduite sur un tromboniste. Différentes tâches musicales sont analysées en termes de pression développée par les muscles intercostaux et abdominaux, de l'activité du diaphragme, ainsi que de la résistance des lèvres et de la glotte à l'écoulement pendant le jeu. Cette étude a ainsi pour but d'évaluer les caractéristiques physiologiques du contrôle de la production du son et leurs relations à la gestion de la pression quasi-statique dans la cavité buccale. Elle suggère également de nouveaux éléments quant à l'influence du contrôle respiratoire sur l'effet acoustique du conduit vocal.</description><creator>Freour, Vincent</creator><contributor>Isabelle Cossette (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Gary Scavone (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Physics - Acoustics</subject><title>Acoustic and respiratory pressure control in brass instrument performance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w562d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bm688</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816q77x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Receptor tyrosine kinases (RTKs) are transmembrane cellular receptors that respond to growth factor stimulation and promote cellular proliferation in normal biological processes, such embryogenesis and wound healing.  RTK activation and signalling are tightly regulated processes; their dysregulation promotes unrestrained cellular proliferation and is associated with cancer initiation and progression.  As such, RTKs are targets of many therapeutic strategies for the treatment of cancer.  However, despite initial success, both innate and acquired resistance hinders the efficacy of many of these inhibitors.    Active signalling by the Met RTK plays a role in melanomas, osteosarcomas, breast carcinomas, gliomas, non-small cell lung cancers (NSCLC), and cancers of the gastro-intestinal (GI) tract.  Multiple mechanisms of Met oncogenic activation have been identified, including autocrine/paracrine stimulation, Met overexpression, genomic amplification, point mutation and alternative splicing.  Inhibitors of Met are currently in all phases of clinical trials for multiple tumour types, thus there exists a need to better understand the mechanisms through which Met promotes tumourigenesis, and how cells respond to Met inhibitors, and how resistance can occur.In my thesis, I establish that in four different MET-amplified gastric cancer cells there is a Met-dependent loss of its negative regulator, the E3 ligase, Cbl.  I utilized structure-function analysis to demonstrate that this loss of Cbl levels requires Met kinase activity, Cbl E3 ligase activity, and recruitment of Cbl to Met.  Where Met is active, Cbl is recruited and subsequently ubiquitinated, and degraded through the proteasome.  I also observed that EGFR, which is also negatively regulated by Cbl, is less efficiently degraded upon stimulation in the presence of active Met and low Cbl levels.  Thus, I demonstrate that Met-driven Cbl loss not only promotes dysregulation of Met, but of other Cbl target proteins as well.As much of what is known with respect to Met signalling has been identified in the context of activation by its ligand, hepatocyte growth factor (HGF), I investigated the Met-dependent pathways and transcriptional program in gastric cancer cells where Met is chronically active via amplification.  I observed that activation of the Ras/Mek/Erk, PI3K/AKT and STAT3 pathways all require Met kinase activity, with STAT3 signalling required for Met-dependent cell proliferation. Interestingly, upon treatment with Met inhibitor, Erk becomes reactivated at later time points (16-24h) in 2/4 cell lines tested.  This correlated with loss of Erk negative regulators, DUSP4 and DUSP6, upon Met inhibition.  Dual inhibition of Met and Mek decreased cell viability as compared to inhibition of either alone.  Hence loss of Erk negative regulators upon Met inhibition, allows for reactivated Erk to promote cell survival and may contribute to innate resistance to targeted Met therapeutics. Next, I established Met inhibitor-resistant cells and utilized gene and protein expression arrays to identify the mechanisms of resistance.  I observed that resistant cells were still MET-amplified, but Met kinase activity remained inhibited. Met-independent cell proliferation is, in part, mediated by Erk signalling.  Further, I also provide evidence that cell survival signals, in the presence of Met inhibition, may be mediated by a mesenchymal-to-epithelial transition.  Altogether, the reactivation of Erk signalling under conditions of innate and acquired resistance to Met inhibitors suggests that combinatorial therapy targeting both Met and Mek may lead to better efficacy and response.</description><description>Les récepteurs à activité kinase (RTK) sont des protéines transmembranaires situées à la surface des cellules qui, une fois activés par des facteurs de croissance, induisent la prolifération cellulaire durant des processus biologiques normaux. La signalisation  par les RTKs est un processus devant être hautement régulé étant donné qu'une signalisation aberrante des RTKs induit une prolifération cellulaire incontrôlée typique au développement et à la progression de tumeurs. Les RTKs constituent donc une cible thérapeutique de choix pour le traitement du cancer et plusieurs inhibiteurs de RTKs sont maintenant utilisés en clinique. Par contre, malgré des résultats initiaux prometteurs, il appert que de multiples tumeurs développent des mécanismes de résistance aux inhibiteurs de RTKs. Le RTK Met joue un rôle important dans de multiples cancers. Plusieurs mécanismes d'activation oncogénique du récepteur Met ont été identifiés. Des inhibiteurs de Met sont présentement testés en essais cliniques pour le traitements du cancers. Il est donc essentiel de mieux comprendre comment le RTK Met promeut la formation de tumeurs, comment les cellules cancéreuses répondent aux traitements ainsi que les mécanismes de développement de résistance aux inhibiteurs. Dans cette thèse, j'établis que dans des lignées de cellules cancéreuses gastriques où le gène MET est amplifié, il y a une perte de la protéine ligase E3 Cbl qui est un inhibiteur de Met. À l'aide d'une analyse structurelle et fonctionnelle, je démontre que cette perte de Cbl requière l'activité kinase de Met, l'activité ligase de Cbl et le recrutement de Cbl à Met. L'activation de Met mène au recrutement de Cbl, à son ubiquitination et sa dégradation via le protéasome. J'ai observé que le RTK EGFR, qui est aussi régulé négativement par Cbl, est moins efficacement dégradé suite à sa stimulation en présence d'un récepteur Met actif et de bas niveaux de Cbl. Ainsi, je démontre que la perte de Cbl suite à l'activation de Met mène à la dérégulation de Met, ainsi que d'autres cibles de Cbl.Étant donné que la majorité de ce qui est connu concernant la signalisation en aval de Met a été étudiée dans le contexte de l'activation du RTK par son ligand, le facteur de croissance hépatocytaire HGF, j'ai décidé d'étudier les signaux et programmes de transcription activés en aval de Met quand le récepteur est activé de manière chronique, suite à son amplification. J'ai observé que l'activation des voies de signalisation Erk, AKT et STAT3 requièrent toutes l'activité kinase Met, la signalisation par STAT3 contribuant à la prolifération cellulaire. Curieusement, suite au traitement des cellules cancéreuses avec un inhibiteur de Met, Erk devient réactivé à des temps subséquents (16-24h) dans deux des quatre lignées cellulaires analysées. Ceci corrobore avec la perte des régulateurs négatifs de Erk, DUSP4 et DUSP6, suite à l'inhibition de Met. L'inhibition combinée de Met et Mek diminue la viabilité cellulaire comparée à l'inhibition de Met ou Mek seulement. Par conséquent, la perte des régulateurs négatifs d'Erk suite à l'inhibition de Met permet la réactivation d'Erk et la survie des cellules, et peut contribuer à la résistance innée de certaines cellules cancéreuses aux inhibiteurs de Met.Suite à ces résultats, j'ai établi des lignées cellulaires résistantes à un inhibiteur de Met et analysé l'expression des gènes et protéines à l'aide de matrices pour identifier les mécanismes de résistances. J'ai observé que le gène MET est toujours amplifié dans les cellules résistantes, mais que l'activité kinase reste inhibée en présence de l'inhibiteur. La prolifération cellulaire indépendante de Met est en partie assurée par Erk. Sur la base de ces résultats, la réactivation de la voie de signalisation Erk dans des conditions de résistance innée ou acquise aux inhibiteurs de Met implique qu'une thérapie combinatoire ciblant Met et Mek puisse être plus efficace que les monothérapies.</description><creator>Lai, Andrea</creator><contributor>Morag Park (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Characterization of oncogenic signalling and mechanisms of resistance to inhibitors of Met in Gastric Cancer</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514np659.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816q77x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s4655k75t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The primary purpose of this study was to investigate education and science undergraduate students' conceptions of inquiry and their relationship to epistemic beliefs and to fields/programs of study. The secondary purpose was to examine differences in the students' perceptions of strategic demands of inquiry learning and instruction based on their levels of inquiry conception as well as fields of study. Data were obtained from 145 education and 67 science majors using three questionnaires: an open ended questionnaire, McGill Strategic Demands of Inquiry Questionnaire (MSDIQ), and Schommer's Epistemological Beliefs Questionnaire. Open coding and constant comparison analysis of the participants' inquiry definitions yielded 13 categories of inquiry conceptions which could be grouped into three superordinate categories: inquiry as a learning process (three subcategories), inquiry as an instructional process (five subcategories), and inquiry as a research/scientific process (five subcategories). Frequency counts revealed inquiry as a learning process as the most prevalent and inquiry as a research/scientific process as the least prevalent of the superordinate categories. Data analysis also revealed that participants with sophisticated epistemic beliefs have well informed and multidimensional conceptions of inquiry compared to those with naive epistemic beliefs. Moreover, more indistinct definitions (vague and/or ‘I don't know' responses) were found in the naïve epistemic belief group's definitions than in the sophisticated epistemic belief group's definitions. Field of study related differences were also observed in inquiry conceptions. While education majors emphasized on describing inquiry as an instructional process and mostly as an endeavor in a school/classroom context, those of the science majors emphasized on describing it as a learning process and mostly as an out of school/classroom endeavor. The students' perceptions of strategic demands of inquiry learning and instruction were measured using the three sub-scales of the MSDIQ: planning, enactment, and reflection which respectively comprised of six, six, and two factors. Series of one-sample t-tests revealed that the students had in general a good deal of awareness as they perceived 11 of the 14 factors as highly important strategic demands. Further ranking of the means of the factors indicated time and task organization, expanding data or information search, and social context of the solving the problem as the top ranked and co-construction, linking ideas including view of the future, and communication of results as the bottom ranked strategic demands. From MANOVA analysis, no differences in the participants' perceptions of strategic demands were evident for students at different levels of inquiry conceptions. But, MANOVA analysis based on the participants' fields of study revealed that education majors had better perception of strategic demands pertaining to the factors of the enactment and the reflection sub-scales than the science majors. The study has implications for the practice of inquiry-based teaching and learning in higher education in general and for teacher education programs in particular.</description><description>Le but de cette étude était d'examiner les conceptions des étudiants de premier cycle en pédagogie et en sciences vis-à-vis l'enquête et la relation de leurs conceptions à leurs croyances épistémiques et aux champs/programmes d'études qu'ils poursuivaient. Elle a également étudié les différences dans les perceptions des exigences stratégiques de l'apprentissage et de l'enseignement par enquête en fonction des degrés de conception de l'enquête ainsi que les domaines d'études des étudiants. Les données ont été obtenues auprès de 145 en concentration d'éducation et 67 en concentration de sciences à l'aide de trois questionnaires: un questionnaire à réponse libr, le Questionnaire sur les Exigences Stratégiques de l'Enquête de McGill (MSDIQ) et le Questionnaire sur les Croyances Épistémologiques de Schommer. L'analyse des définitions des participants en utilisant une stratégie de codage ouvert et de comparaison constante a produit 13 catégories de conceptions de l'enquête qui ont été regroupées en trois catégories super-ordonnées: l'enquête comme un processus d'apprentissage (trois sous-catégories), l'enquête comme un processus pédagogique (cinq catégories), et l'enquête comme un processus de recherche/scientifique (cinq catégories). L'examen de la fréquence des catégories démontra que la plus fréquente était l'enquête comme un processus d'apprentissage et que l'enquête comme un processus de recherche / scientifique était la moins fréquente. L'analyse des données a également révélé que les participants avec des croyances épistémiques sophistiquées ont des conceptions de l'enquête plus informées et multidimensionnelles par rapport à ceux qui ont des croyances épistémiques naïves. En outre, plus de définitions indistinctes  ont été trouvées dans les définitions du groupe de croyances épistémiques naïves que dans les définitions du groupe de croyances épistémiques sophistiquées. Des différences liées aux domaines d'études ont également été observées dans les conceptions de l'enquête. Alors que les étudiants en éducation ont mis l'emphase dans leurs descriptions sur l'enquête comme un processus d'enseignement et surtout comme une activité dans le contexte de l'école/salle de classe, les étudiants en sciences ont mis l'emphase sur le processus d'apprentissage et surtout l'activité à l'extérieur de l'école/salle de classe. Les perceptions étudiantes des exigences stratégiques de l'apprentissage et de l'enseignement de l'enquête ont été mesurées à l'aide des trois sous-classements de l'MSDIQ: la planification, l'intégration et la réflexion qui sont composés par six, six, et deux sous-groupes. Une série de tests-t d'un échantillon simple a révélé que les étudiants étaient en général sensibles aux exigences stratégiques car ils considéraient comme très importants 11 des 14 facteurs. En outre, le classement des exigences stratégiques par le biais de la moyenne des facteurs démontra que le temps et l'organisation des tâches, la collecte de données supplémentaire ou la recherche d'informations et le contexte social de la résolution de problèmes étaient les premiers classés et la co-construction, reliant des idées notamment en vue de l'avenir, et la communication des résultats les derniers classés. Trois résultats MANOVAs séparés n'ont révélé aucune différence dans la perception des exigences stratégiques des participants résultant de différences dans le degré de leurs conceptions de l'enquête. Toutefois, les MANOVAs avec domaines d'études comme variable indépendante ont révélé que les étudiants en éducation avaient une meilleure perception des exigences stratégiques relatives aux facteurs des sous-groupes d'intégration et de réflexion que les étudiants en sciences. Aucune différence n'a été observée vis-à-vis les facteurs de planification. L'étude a des implications pour la pratique de l'enseignement et de l'apprentissage par enquête dans l'enseignement supérieur en général et pour les programmes de formation des enseignants en particulier.</description><creator>Getahun, Dawit</creator><contributor>Mark Wesley Aulls (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Alenoush Saroyan (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Education - Psychology </subject><title>Education and science undergraduate students' conceptions of inquiry: relationship to perceptions of strategic demands of inquiry learning and instruction, and epistemic beliefs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t261m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s4655k75t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gh19b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The latch-state is the capacity of smooth muscle to maintain force for long periods of time with low energy consumption. The prevalent theory to explain the latch-state suggests that if myosin gets deactivated (dephosphorylated) while attached to actin, it remains attached and maintains force. Other theories suggest that dephosphorylated and detached myosin can bind to actin to maintain force and that actin regulatory proteins participate in the force maintenance. All theories of the latch-state were based on measurements performed at the whole muscle level and were never confirmed at the molecular level. Verifying the latch-state theories at the molecular level was the main goal of this thesis.To further our understanding of the latch-state, the role of calponin in the binding of unphosphorylated myosin to actin was determined. The laser trap assay was used to measure the average force of unbinding (Funb) in the absence and presence of calponin. Calponin enhanced the Funb. Phosphorylation of calponin with Ca2+-calmodulin dependant protein kinase II, which detaches calponin from actin, decreased the Funb to the unregulated actin level. Performing the measurements at high ionic strength, which detaches calponin from myosin, had the same effect on the Funb. These later two measurements demonstrate that calponin enhances the Funb of unphosphorylated myosin to actin by crosslinking them together. Next, the effect of caldesmon on the Funb was studied; caldesmon enhanced the Funb. Because tropomyosin is known to potentiate biochemical and mechanical effects of caldesmon, its action on the Funb in combination with caldesmon was also measured. Tropomyosin enhanced the Funb on its own but had no synergistic effect with caldesmon. Phosphorylation of caldesmon with the extracellular signal-regulated kinase (ERK) decreased the Funb below the unregulated actin level. Because ERK phosphorylation of caldesmon occurs late in the contraction, this last result suggests a relaxation mechanism from the latch-state. Examination of the force traces revealed a visco-elastic behavior of myosin in the presence of ERK phosphorylated caldesmon which either prevents binding or promotes detachment from actin, thus leading to muscle relaxation. Finally, the ultimate molecular level demonstration of the latch-state requires dephosphorylation of myosin during molecular force measurements with a laser trap assay. However, addition of myosin light chain phosphatase cannot be done without disturbing the single molecule level mechanics measurements. Thus, a microfluidic device was designed and developed to allow the addition of chemicals to a molecular mechanics flow-through chamber without creating any bulk flow. A micro-channel chamber was created by standard photolithography on silicon wafers with the patterns transferred to polymethylsiloxane (PDMS). The chamber was then bound to a polycarbonate membrane which itself was bound to the molecular mechanics chamber. The micro-channels assured rapid distribution of the chemicals whereas the membrane assured efficient delivery but prevented bulk flow. The device was tested by injection of adenosine triphosphate to initiate the propulsion of actin by myosin. The proof of principle of this microfluidic device concludes this thesis.</description><description>Le muscle lisse possède la capacité unique de maintenir une force élevée tout en consommant peu d'adénosine triphosphate (ATP); cette propriété est appelée 'latch-state'. La théorie la mieux connue pour expliquer cet état suggère que si la myosine est désactivée (déphosphorylation de sa chaîne légère) pendant qu'elle est attachée à l'actine, elle reste attachée et maintient la force. D'autres théories suggèrent que la myosine désactivée et détachée peut s'attacher à l'actine pour maintenir la force et que les protéines régulatrices de l'actine participent aussi à cet effort. Toutes les théories sur l'état 'latch' ont été extrapolées à partir de mesures réalisées sur la totalité du muscle sans jamais être confirmées au niveau moléculaire. Le but principal de cette thèse était de vérifier les théories de l'état 'latch' au niveau moléculaire. Afin de mieux comprendre l'état 'latch', le rôle de la calponine, dans l'attachement de la myosine non-phosphorylée à l'actine, a été déterminé.  Des pinces optiques ont été utilisées pour mesurer la force moyenne de leur détachement (Funb) en l'absence et en présence de la calponine. La calponine a augmenté la Funb. La phosphorylation de la calponine avec l'enzyme protéine kinase II (Ca2+-calmoduline dépendante), qui a pour effet de détacher la calponine de l'actine,  a diminué la Funb jusqu'au niveau de l'actine non-régulée.  De plus, des  mesures de force  ont été  réalisées  à haute force ionique,  détachant  cette fois-ci  la calponine de la myosine. Ceci a aussi diminué la Funb jusqu'au niveau de l'actine non-régulée. Ces résultats  montrent que la calponine augmente la Funb de la myosine non-phosphorylée à l'actine par liaison croisée (myosine-calponine-actine). Ensuite, l'effet de la caldesmone sur la Funb a été étudié; la caldesmone augmente aussi la Funb. Puisque la tropomyosine est connue pour promouvoir les actions biochimiques et mécaniques de la caldesmone, son action sur la Funb en combinaison avec la caldesmone  a aussi été mesurée. La tropomyosine augmente la Funb lorsqu'elle est seule mais n'a pas d'effet synergétique avec la caldesmone. La phosphorylation de la caldesmone avec la kinase régulatrice des signaux extracellulaires (ERK) a diminué la Funb en dessous du niveau de l'actine non-régulée. Ce dernier résultat suggère un mécanisme de relaxation à partir de l'état 'latch' étant  donné que la phosphorylation de la caldesmone par  ERK se produit tard dans la contraction. D'autre part, l'examen des traces de force a révélé un comportement viscoélastique de la myosine en présence de la caldesmone phosphorylée, ce qui semble soit  prévenir l'attachement, soit promouvoir le détachement de l'actine, menant ainsi à la relaxation du muscle à partir de l'état 'latch'. Finalement, la démonstration ultime de l'état 'latch' au niveau moléculaire requiert la déphosphorylation de la myosine pendant les mesures de forces moléculaires faites à l'aide de pinces optiques. Cependant l'addition de la phosphatase de la chaîne légère de myosine ne peut se faire sans perturber les mesures de mécanique au niveau moléculaire. A cet effet, un appareil micro-fluidique a été conçu et développé pour permettre l'ajout de solutions biochimiques à la chambre de mesure de micromécanique sans créer de débit net. Des micro-canaux ont été créés par photolithographie sur substrats de silicium suivie d'un transfert des formes sur polymethylsiloxane (PDMS). La chambre des micro-canaux a ensuite été collée à une membrane de polycarbonate qui elle a ensuite été collée à la chambre de micromécanique. Les micro-canaux assurent la livraison rapide et uniforme tandis que la membrane assure le transfert efficace des produits biochimiques tout en empêchant un débit net. Le fonctionnement de l'appareil a été vérifié en injectant de l'ATP en présence d'actine et de myosine phosphorylée.  La propulsion de l'actine par la myosine a été observée validant ainsi le principe de l'appareil microfluidique.</description><creator>Roman, Horia Nicolae</creator><contributor>Anne-Marie Lauzon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biophysics - Medical</subject><title>Smooth muscle molecular mechanics in the latch-state</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j96024327.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gh19b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s357m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>"There is growing international interest in space exploration. Going back to the moon where we will build a sustainable long-term human presence with new spacecraft, robotics and life-sustaining technologies, will prepare humans for future exploration of other planets in our solar system and asteroids and for space mining" [1]. The moon will serve as a base to develop and test new technologies, experience living on an extraterrestrial surface and will provide clues about the origin of the universe. Returning to the moon however, is not easy. The harsh lunar environment, solar radiation, the large amplitude of the temperature fluctuation and the negligible atmosphere and therefore low atmospheric pressure will challenge future manned and unmanned missions. One of the most pervasive limits to lunar surface exploration is the presence of lunar dust, which is electrostatically charged and adheres to everything with which it comes into contact. Lunar dust is very fine and also highly abrasive [2]. In this work, two abrasive wear test devices were designed and manufactured to study the volume wear rate of different materials when subjected to lunar dust simulant of different size ranges. There were three additional objectives to this research. First, the potential of using electrostatic and dielectrophoretic forces to remove and transport small particles away from surfaces was investigated by manufacturing several devices comprising series of parallel electrodes connected to single or multiple AC power source(s). The traveling electric field created then served as an invisible brush to clean surfaces and prevent dust from entering joints in space applications (e.g. bearing, solar panels, camera, etc.). Second, discrete element models were created and calibrated based on the experimental results to study the capacity of this technique to clean dust from surfaces in the lunar environment. Third, evaluated the idea of sorting and transporting regolith (i.e., the loose, heterogeneous material covering solid rock) into the journal bearing (i.e., a plain bearing designed to reduce friction by supporting radial loads) and  employing it as a solid lubricant. Experimental outcomes demonstrate satisfactory performance of the electric curtain in terms of dust removal from surfaces, with low power consumption. They also indicate the need for standardization of wear and abrasion tests for space applications at low temperature and pressure. One recommendation resulting from this research is investment by the Canadian Space Agency on infrastructure and equipment such as "dirty chambers" to enable performance of similar experiments in dusty moon-like environments. This research was conducted with support from an NSERC Collaborative Research and Development Grant involving Neptec Design Group, the Canadian Space Agency, and McGill University.</description><description>"L'exploration spatiale est en pleine expansion dans la communauté internationale. En retournant à la lune où nous construirons une présence humaine à long terme qui soit durable avec des nouveaux vaisseaux spatiaux, des robots et des technologies pour maintenir  la vie durable. C'est aussi à nous préparer pour future exploration des autres planètes de notre système solaire, des astéroïdes, et l'exploitation minière spatial" [1]. La lune servira comme une base pour développer et tester des nouvelles technologies, faire l'expérience de vivre dans un environnement extraterrestre, et fournir des indices sur l'origine de l'univers. Cependant retourner sur la Lune n'est pas une tache facile. Les conditions extrêmement difficile de l'environnement lunaire, les dangereuses rayonnements solaire, les variations de températures et l'espace vide mettra nos futures missions, avec ou sans astronautes, en danger. L'un des plus grands défis que nous rencontrerons au cours de l'exploration de la surface de la lune est la poussière lunaire qui est éléctrostatiquement chargé et adhérera tout ce qui entre en contact avec. La poussière est très fine et très abrasif aussi [2]. Dans cette étude, trois appareils ont été conçus et deux d'entre eux ont été construites afin d'examiner la quantité de particules qui retire du matériel pendant l'expérience d'abrasion par la poussière lunaire a diamètre variable. Également la possibilité d'utiliser des forces électrostatiques et diélectrophoetique pour enlever et transporter des petites particules des surfaces ont été étudié par plusieurs dispositifs en fabricant des compositions  d'électrodes parallèles qui sont connecté à une source d'alimentation unique ou multiple AC. Le champ électrique qui se déplace sert alors comme un pinceau invisible pour nettoyer les surfaces et évite la poussière de pénétrer dans les joints des applications spatiales (par exemple les instruments qui roulent, les panneaux solaires, les appareils photo, etc.). En plus de cela, des modèles DEM ont été créés et calibrés sur la base des résultats expérimentaux pour étudier la capacité de cette technique pour nettoyer la poussière des surfaces dans l'environnement lunaire. En outre, l'idée de regrouper et de transporter le régolithe dans un palier lisse et l'employer comme un lubrifiant solide a été souligné. Les résultats des expériences montrent une performance satisfaisante du rideau électrique en termes de dépoussiérage des surfaces avec une faible consommation électrique. Ils suggèrent également la nécessité d'une standardisation des expériences abrasive pour les applications spatiales à faible température et pression. Une proposition par rapport aux résultats obtenu dans cette recherche est l'investissement de l'Agence Spatiale Canadienne sur les infrastructures et les équipements tels que "Les chambres sale" afin d'être en mesure de réaliser des expériences similaires dans des environnements poussiéreux comme la surface de la lune. Cette recherche est menée dans le cadre d'une subvention du CRSNG CRD entre Neptec Design Group, l'Agence Spatiale Canadienne et l'Université McGill.</description><creator>Gharib, Nima</creator><contributor>Peter Henry Radziszewski (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Mechanical </subject><title>Investigating regolith induced wear and dust mitigation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52jc20p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s357m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dr26z146m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mild Traumatic Brain Injuries (mTBI) and concussions are complex injuries with high incidence rates in children and adolescents. There currently exists no 'gold standard' for the diagnosis of concussions, and detection and monitoring are made challenging by highly variable clinical presentations. There is growing evidence that mTBI is associated with oculomotor impairment in adults, and that this type of deficit may serve as a marker for the injury. The literature indicates the question has never been addressed in pediatric mTBI. The research presented here sought to address this knowledge gap by first evaluating smooth pursuit and fixational eye movement integrity in a cohort of children and adolescents suffering from mTBI, and then comparing their performances to control participants not having sustained a head injury. The research yielded mixed findings. On the one hand, we found that fixational eye movements are not impaired in pediatric mTBI; measures of fixational eye movement integrity were comparable across groups. On the other hand, selective deficits in smooth pursuit eye movements were found. Synchronization of eye movement with target motion was significantly poorer for mTBI patients. Their abilities to trace target trajectory accurately and to match target velocity, however, were not found to be impaired. It remains unclear whether the observed deficits were caused by disrupted function of the smooth pursuit system proper, by damage to areas that modulate smooth pursuit through top-down influence, or by a combination of both. These preliminary results suggest that select smooth pursuit paradigms could play a role for diagnosing pediatric mTBI, and reinforce the need for further studies in this novel area of research. </description><description>Les Traumatismes Crâniens Légers (TCL) et les commotions cérébrales sont des blessures complexes auxquelles les enfants et les adolescents sont particulièrement à risque. Il n'existe pas actuellement d'outil objectif pour le diagnostic et le monitorage de ces blessures, qui sont difficiles à gérer en raison de la grande hétérogénéité clinique qui les caractérise. Un nombre grandissant d'études indique que les TCL peuvent engendrer une dysfonction au niveau des mouvements oculaires chez les adultes, et que ces troubles visuels pourraient servir de marqueurs efficaces pour la détection. La question n'a jamais été posée chez les enfants. Ce projet tente d'apporter une réponse préliminaire, d'abord en évaluant l'intégrité des Mouvements de Poursuite Visuelle (MPV) et de fixation chez des enfants et adolescents atteints d'un TCL, puis en comparant leur performance à celle de sujets contrôles n'ayant pas subi de blessure à la tête. Les résultats obtenus sont mixtes. Aucune dysfonction au niveau des mouvements de fixation n'a été décelée; toutes les mesures utilisées pour évaluer les capacités de fixation étaient comparables par groupe. En revanche, des troubles sélectifs ont été détectés au niveau des MPV. Les patients atteints de TCL éprouvaient en moyenne plus de difficulté à synchroniser le mouvement de leurs yeux avec le mouvement d'une cible. La précision et la vélocité du mouvement ne semblaient pas toutefois affectées. Les résultats ne permettent pas de trancher sur la nature exacte du trouble observé, ce dernier pouvant être causé à la fois par une dysfonction au niveau des circuits visuo-moteurs propre, et par une dysfonction au niveau de structures de plus haut niveau modulant les MPV. Ces résultats préliminaires indiquent que l'évaluation des MPV pourrait contribuer au diagnostic et au monitorage de TCL pédiatriques, et renforcent le besoin d'investigations additionnelles dans ce domaine.</description><creator>Sheppard-Jones, Nicolas</creator><contributor>Alain Ptito (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Neuroscience </subject><title>Ocular impairment in pediatric mild traumatic brain injury</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nc580q97g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dr26z146m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Integrated Program in Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2j62s817v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le succès de régénération du tissu ostéochondral requiert le développement des matrices stratifiées afin d'imiter la composition biophysiquechimiques du cartilage et l'os sous-chondral. Les hydrogels de collagène de type I (Coll) reconstitués in vitro sont grandement utilisés en tant que matrices biomimétiques pour le génie tissulaire (GT). En raison de leur nature hautement hydratée s'affaissent à cause des forces gravitationnelles (auto-compression; SC). La compression plastique (CP) est un procédé rapide qui génère des matrices denses avec un pourcentage massique de solide que se rapprochant du taux de solide des tissus naturels. Cette recherche de doctorat a pour but de développer et caractériser un modèle à deux couches pour des applications en GT ostéochondral basés sur l'incorporation de GAGs analogiques (i.e. chitosan; CTS) dans un hydrogel Coll dense afin de reproduire de près la matrice extra-cellulaire (MEC) naturelle de l'interface ostéochondrale. Le premier objectif était de développer et d'optimiser un système co-gélifiant pour la génération de gels hybrides de Coll/CTS hautement hydraté avec diverses proportions de CTS. In a été démontré que la CP est un procédé rapide capable de générer des gels hybrides de Coll/CTS dense avec un taux de solide accru, un module de compression et une résistance à la dégradation enzimatique, le tout dicté par la teneur en CTS.Comme second objectif l'effet de l'incorporation de CTS sur la modulation de la fonction de cellules ensemencées pré-ostéoblastes MC3T3-E1 à l'intérieur de gels Coll denses a été étudié. Les hydrogels de Coll/CTS dense ont permis la viabilité et la prolifération de cellules ainsi que leur différentiation dans des conditions ostéogéniques. Ces résultats démontrent que les hybrides de Coll/CTS denses sont une approche pour l'assemblage de structures de type ostéoïdes en tant que modèle in vitro pour GT. En tant que troisième objectif l'effet de l'incorporation de CTS à des disques de gel Coll dense afin de supporter la différentiation de chondro-progéniteurs RCJ3.1C5.18 (RCJ) a été étudié. L'immunohistochimie du colagène de type II, combiné avec la coloration avec du Safranin O et la quantification des GAGs, ont indiqué que la différentiation des chondro-progéniteurs est meilleures avec les matrices de Coll/CTS. Les résultats ont démontré la pertinence de les hybrides de Coll/CTS denses pour être utilisé comme modèles in vitro pour la réparation du cartilageLe quatrième objectif était de développer une structure à deux couches d'hydrogel de Coll/CTS denses avec des ratios se rapprochant celui de Coll/GAGs se retrouvant dans l'interface ostéochondrale. De plus l'optimisation des conditions de co-culture permettant de supportent les réactions concurrentes de chondrogénèse et d'ostéogénèse. Les résultats démontrent la possibilité d'utiliser les hydrogels de Coll/CTS denses à deux couches en tant que modèles ostéochondraux in vitro. En tant que cinquièmes objectif l'effet des CTS sur la consolidation du gel de colagène a été étudié en surveillant la distribution spatiotemporelle de billes fluorescentes par microscopie confocale. Le modèle de Happel a été utilisé afin de prédire la perméabilité hydraulique des hydrogels. Aussi l'effet de la charge fixe des CTS sur les hydrogels Coll/CTS a été étudié par leur caractérisation structurelle, mécanique et de gonflement dans des conditions isotoniques et hypertoniques. Les résultats ont indiqué la capacité d'un analogue de GAG chargé à s'adapter aux propriétés biophysicochimiques des hydrogels Coll, offrant un modèle de tissus in vitro pour diverses applications de GT. En conclusion la structure à deux couches de Coll/CTS dense développée et caractérisée dans le cadre de ce doctorat a procuré un milieu de culture de cellules in vitro reproduisant la MEC complexe. Cette structure pourrait potentiellement être utilisé cliniquement en tant qu'implant biomimétique avec des capacités régénératrices ostéochondrales.</description><description>Success of osteochondral tissue engineering (TE) requires stratified scaffolds that mimic the biophysicochemical composition of the cellular environment of both the cartilage and subchondral bone. In vitro reconstituted collagen type I (Coll) hydrogels are widely used as biomimetic scaffolds for TE, however due to their highly-hydrated nature they collapse due to gravitational forces (self-compression; SC). Plastic compression (PC) is a method that rapidly enables the generation of dense scaffolds with solid weight percent approaching native tissues values.The aim of this doctoral research was to develop and characterize a bilayered model system for osteochondral TE applications based on the incorporation of a GAG-analog (i.e. chitosan; CTS), within a dense Coll hydrogel, to closely mimic the native extracellular matrix (ECM) of the osteochondral interface. The first objective was to develop and optimize a co-gelling system for the generation of highly-hydrated Coll/CTS hybrid gels with different CTS proportions. PC was shown to be an effective and rapid process able to generate, within minutes, dense Coll/CTS hybrid gels with increased solid weight percent, compressive modulus and resistance to enzymatic degradation, as dictated by CTS content. As a second objective, the effect of CTS incorporation on modulating MC3T3-E1 pre-osteoblast seeded-cell function within dense Coll gels was investigated. Dense Coll/CTS hydrogels supported MC3T3-E1 cell viability, proliferation, and differentiation under osteogenic-inducing conditions. These findings demonstrated that dense Coll/CTS hybrids provide an osteoid-like structure as an in vitro model for bone TE.As a third objective, the effect of CTS incorporation into dense Coll gel discs was investigated to support RCJ3.1C5.18 chondroprogenitors (RCJ) differentiation. Immunohistochemistry for collagen type II, in combination with Safranin O staining and GAG quantification, indicated greater chondroprogenitor differentiation within Coll/CTS scaffolds, compared to Coll alone. The results demonstrated the suitability of dense Coll/CTS scaffolds to be used as in vitro models for cartilage repair. The fourth objective was to develop a bilayered dense Coll/CTS hydrogel with ratios approaching those of Coll/GAGs found in the ECM at the osteochondral interface. In addition, the optimization of the co-culturing conditions to maintain the simultaneous chondro- and osteogenesis was investigated. The results demonstrated the potential of bilayered dense Coll/CTS hydrogels to be used as effective in vitro osteochondral models.  As the fifth objective, CTS effect on Coll gel consolidation was investigated by monitoring the spatiotemporal distribution of fluorescent beads using confocal microscopy during Coll/CTS hydrogels consolidation. The Happel model was used to predict the hydraulic permeability of the hydrogels. In addition, the effect of CTS fixed charge on Coll hydrogels was investigated through structural, mechanical and swelling characterizations under isotonic and hypertonic conditions. The results indicate the ability of a charged GAG-analog to tailor the biophysicochemical properties of Coll hydrogels, thus providing a reliable 3D in vitro tissue model for various TE applications. In conclusion, the integrated bilayered dense Coll/CTS construct developed and characterized in this doctoral research effectively provided a tailored in vitro cell culture milieu that closely mimics a complex physiologic ECM to be used as a three-dimensional model and with the potential for clinical use as a biomimetic implant with osteochondral regenerative capacity.</description><creator>Chicatun, Florencia</creator><contributor>Showan Nazhat (Supervisor1)</contributor><contributor>Marc D McKee (Supervisor2)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Materials Science</subject><title>In vitro generation of a bilayered dense collagen / chitosan hydrogel scaffold as an osteochondral model</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/76537429k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2j62s817v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf2688585</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La plupart des modèles de dynamique de glace marine en Arctique présentement utilisés dans la communauté scientifique sont basés sur une formulation des déformations correspondant aux matériaux viscoplastiques (VP). Les modèles VP font l'approximation que les petites déformations élastiques (réversibles) peuvent être remplacées par des déformations visqueuses (irréversibles), ce qui représente un nouveau puits d'énergie fictif dans les modèles. L'énergétique des modèles de glace est affectée par la résolution spatiale du réseau, ainsi que par le nombre d'itérations requises pour la résolution des équations non-linéaires gouvernant le système. Plus le nombre d'itérations et la résolution sont élevés, plus les lignes de fractures (déformations plastiques) sont bien définies. Les points de maille auparavant en régime plastique migrent donc vers le régime visqueux (non physique) en augmentant ainsi l'énergie perdue dans ce mode de déformation. Nous formons l'équation de la conservation de l'énergie cinétique pour étudier la dissipation d'énergie dans les modèles VP de glace marine. La dissipation d'énergie dans les déformations est séparée en deux puits distincts pour la dissipation d'énergie par les déformations visqueuses et par les déformations plastiques, afin d'évaluer la contribution du mode non physique à la balance énergétique. Pour toutes les échelles spatiales et temporelles étudiées, la dissipation par les déformations visqueuses est négligeable par rapport à la dissipation par les déformations plastiques, ce qui confirme la validité l'approximation VP d'un point de vue énergétique. </description><description>In viscous-plastic (VP) sea-ice models, small deformations are approximated by irreversible viscous deformations, introducing a non-physical energy sink. As the spatial resolution and the degree of numerical convergence of the models increase, linear kinematic features (LKFs) are better resolved and more states of stress lie in the viscous regime. Energy dissipation in the non-physical viscous regime therefore increases. We derive a complete kinetic energy (KE) balance for sea ice, including separate plastic and viscous energy sinks to study energy dissipation. The main KE balance is between the energy input by the wind and the dissipation by the water drag and the internal stresses (dissipating respectively 87\% and 13\% of the energy input on an annual average). The internal stress term is mostly important in winter when ice-ice interactions are dominant. The energy input that is not dissipated locally is redistributed laterally by the internal stresses in regions of dissipation by small scale deformations (LKFs). Of the 13\% dissipated annually by the internal stress term, 93\% is dissipated in friction along LKFs (14\% in ridging, 79\% in shearing) and 7\% is stored as potential energy in ridges. For all time and spatial scales tested, the frictional viscous dissipation is negligible compared to the frictional plastic dissipation (between 10 to 1000 times smaller). This conclusion remains valid when the spatial resolution and the numerical convergence of the simulations are increased. Overall, the results confirm the validity, from an energy point of view, of the VP approximation.</description><creator>Bouchat, Amélie</creator><contributor>Bruno Tremblay (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Physics - Atmosperic Science </subject><title>Energy dissipation in viscous-plastic sea-ice models</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zw12z8492.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf2688585</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x059cb70b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les aminosides sont une classe d'antibiotiques à large spectre qui affectent  l'efficacité de la synthèse protéique. Parmi les mécanismes de résistance contre cette classe d'antibiotique, l'inactivation enzymatique est le plus souvent fréquenté. Il existe trois classes d'enzymes capable d'inactiver les aminosides: les N-acetiltransferases (AAC), les O-phosphotransferases (APH), et les O-adeniltransferases (ANT). Cette thèse discutera les familles ANT et APH. Spectinomycin kinase (SpcN), aussi nommé APH(9)-Ib, catalyse la phosphorylation et l'inactivation de l'aminoside spectinomicin exclusivement. Il partage cette spécificité du substrat avec APH(9)-Ia, pour lequel la structure cristallographique à déjà été caractérisée (Fong et al., 2010). Étant donné que les éléments structurels reliés à la liaison du substrat et au site de reconnaissance sont largement conservés parmi les membres de la famille APH, les études sur la configuration tridimensionnelle des APH fournissent des informations importantes sur la relation entre structure et fonction, dont la spécificité du site de reconnaissance par exemple. Cette thèse explique les démarches prisent pour exprimer, solubiliser et purifier SpcN.L'aminoside nucleotidilstransferase 2"-Ia (ANT(2")-Ia) est parmi les enzymes de résistance contre les aminosides les plus souvent fréquentés (Ramirez &amp; Tomalsky, 2010). Il catalyse le transfert de adénosine monophosphate à la position 2" des aminosides 4,6-bisubstituées, ce qui les empêchent de se lier au sous-unité  30S du ribosome. Son importance dans le milieu clinique fait en sorte qu'il et un cible intéressant pour la recherche et le développement d'antibiotiques basée sur les structures tridimensionnelles. À date, les études sur ANT(2")-Ia on été limitées par le fait qu'il s'exprime de façon non soluble (Ekman et al., 2001). Nos études, décrient  dans cette thèse, propose une nouvelle forme soluble et active de ANT(2")-Ia qui serait la version plus physiologiquement exacte. Nous avons pu obtenir 17 mg de protéine pure, soluble et active à partir d'un litre de culture. Nous avons fait l'attribution séquentielle des déplacements chimiques des atomes de la chaîne principale par RNM en utilisant des expériences bi- et tri-dimensionnelles, dont HSQC et HNCACB et CNCAcoNH. Nous avons complété l'attribution de 144 des 176 résidus (excluant les prolines). Nous avons aussi fait des analyses de titration avec les substrats de ANT(2")-Ia, ATP et  tobramicin séparément, à une concentration de 1:1. Ces analyses démontrent des perturbations globales des déplacement chimiques uniques pour chaque interaction, ce qui suggère que les sites de reconnaissances pour chaque substrat sont différents. </description><description>Aminoglycosides are broad-spectrum antibiotics that corrupt normal protein synthesis by acting on the coding and translocation mechanisms of the 30S ribosomal subunit. The most common mechanism of resistance to this class of antibiotics is enzymatic modification. There are three families of aminoglycoside modifying enzymes: the N-acetyltransferases (AAC), the O-phosphotransferases (APH), and the O-adenyltransferases (ANT). The focus of this thesis is on the APH and ANT families. Spectinomycin kinase (SpcN), also referred to as APH(9)-Ib, catalyzes the phosphorylation of spectinomycin exclusively, rendering it inactive. It shares its substrate specificity with APH(9)-Ia, for which the crystal structure has been described (Fong et al, 2010). Structural elements related to substrate binding remain largely conserved within the APH family, and the structural characterization of various APHs can provide valuable insight into structure-function relationships, such as substrate spectrum. Here, we report initial overexpression and purification methods for SpcN and explore solubilization methods to improve protein overexpression.  Aminoglycoside nucleotidyltransferase (2”)-Ia (ANT(2”)-Ia) is among the most prevalent and widespread AMEs in North America (Ramirez &amp; Tomalsky, 2010). It catalyzes the transfer of adenosine monophosphate to the 2” position of 4-6-disubstituted aminoglycosides, preventing binding to the 30S ribosomal subunit. Its clinical relevance makes it an important target for structure-based drug design. Previous studies of ANT(2”)-Ia were limited due to the formation of inclusion bodies during ANT(2”)-Ia overexpression (Ekman et al., 2001).  Here, we report the increase in protein solubility and stability as a result of cleaving 50 extraneous amino acids from the N-terminus.  Overexpression and purification of this construct yields 17 mg of soluble, stable, and active protein per liter of culture. We used heteronuclear single quantum correlation (HSQC) and HNCACB, CBCAcoNH triple resonance NMR experiments to characterize the protein. We sequentially assigned 144 of the 176 non-proline amide backbone residues of ANT(2”)-Ia. Titration analyses of ANT(2”)-Ia with tobramycin and ATP separately at 1:1 concentration ratios show unique global chemical shift perturbations for each, suggesting different binding pockets for both substrates. </description><creator>Sabet-Kassouf, Nilufar</creator><contributor>Albert Berghuis (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biophysics - Medical</subject><title>Preliminary studies on the structural characterization of aminoglycoside nucleotidyltransferase ANT(2")-la and spectinomycin kinase SpcN</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r207ts38p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x059cb70b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h496v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Wheel-legged hybrid robots are known to be extremely capable in negotiating different types of terrain as they combine the efficiency of conventional wheeled platforms and the rough terrain capabilities of legged platforms. The Micro-Hydraulic Toolkit (MHT), developed by Defence Research and Development Canada at the Suffield Research Centre, is one such quadruped hybrid robot. Previously, a velocity-level closed loop inverse kinematics controller had been developed and tested in simulation on a detailed physics-based model of the MHT in LMS Virtual.Lab Motion (VLM). The controller was employed to generate a variety of posture reconfiguration and navigation maneuvers in simulation, such as achieving minimum or maximum chassis height at specific wheel separations, orienting the chassis to a desired pitch angle, or negotiating simulated rough terrain. In this thesis, the aforementioned inverse kinematics controller was improved upon, optimized and adapted to function on the physical MHT vehicle, located in Suffield, Canada. In addition, as a first step towards identifying the deficiencies of the VLM model and, ultimately, validating the model, actuator performance was measured for open loop step and ramp inputs and compared to the simulation results. With the controller implemented on MHT, a subset of the posture reconfiguration and navigation maneuvers previously performed in simulation were tested on the MHT and the robot performance was evaluated. Furthermore, a parametrized algorithm for statically stable step-climbing was developed and successfully verified on the MHT for different step heights.</description><description>Les robots à locomotion articulée sur roues ont la capacité de circuler sur différents types de terrain avec aise, puisqu'ils combinent l'efficacité énergétique des véhicules conventionnels munis de roues et la capacité de se déplacer sur une surface irrégulière des systèmes équipés de pattes. Le Micro-Hydraulic Toolkit (MHT) est un robot quadrupède développé par Recherche et développement pour la  défense Canada au centre de recherches de Suffield qui se situe dans cette catégorie. Cette machine est dotée de quatre pattes articulées qui se terminent chacune par une roue.  Précédemment, un  mécanisme de contrôle cinématique inverse à boucle fermée a été développé et testé en simulation sur un modèle détaillé du MHT à l'aide du logiciel LMS Virtual.Lab Motion (VLM). L'objectif de ce contrôleur était de générer des commandes cinématiques aux joints du robot afin de reconfigurer la posture de celui-ci et d'effectuer des manœuvres de navigations. Dans cette thèse, le contrôleur cinématique inverse est adapté et optimisé pour fonctionner avec le robot MHT. Afin d'identifier les erreurs du modèle du robot sur VLM et de contribuer à la révision du modèle, des expériences ont été effectuées à boucles ouvertes sur les joints du robot en utilisant des commandes en échelon et en rampe. Les résultats de ces tests ont par la suite été comparés avec ceux obtenus en simulation. Puis, après que le contrôleur fut implémenté sur MHT, une séquence de reconfigurations de posture précédemment testée en simulation a été testée sur le robot, et la performance de celui-ci a été évaluée. Finalement, un algorithme paramétré visant à permettre à MHT de monter une marche a été développé et testé avec succès sur le robot avec différentes hauteurs de marches.</description><creator>Wong, Christopher</creator><contributor>Inna Sharf (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Robotics</subject><title>Posture reconfiguration and step climbing maneuvers for a wheel-legged robot</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04ds82g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h496v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kp78gk75s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le fer est un nutriment essentiel à de nombreuses fonctions biochimiques du corps. Cependant, son potentiel redox flexible est une épée à double tranchant qui rend le fer à la fois essentiel à la vie mais aussi potentiellement toxique. Alors que l'excrétion du fer est limitée, son absorption est amplement régulée. L'homéostasie systémique du fer est contrôlée par l'hormone hépatique hepcidine. Le fer et d'autres stimuli contrôlent la transcription de l'hepcidine. Une fois produite, l'hepcidine circule dans l'organisme et se fixe à la ferroportine,  exporteur cellulaire du fer, qui est exprimé à la surface des entérocytes duodénaux, des macrophages et des hépatocytes causant son internalisation et ensuite sa dégradation. En conséquence, l'hepcidine fonctionne pour contrôler l'efflux du fer de ces cellules dans la circulation sanguine. Le métabolisme cellulaire du fer est contrôlé par les protéines de régulation du fer 1 et 2 (IRP1 et IRP2). Les IRP répriment ou stabilisent la traduction d'ARNm codant les protéines responsables de la capture, l'utilisation, et le stockage du fer, lesquels contiennent des éléments de réponse au fer (IRE) dans leurs régions non traduites. Ce travail examine la régulation in vivo du facteur inductible de l'hypoxie 2 alpha (HIF2α) par IRP1. HIF2a est un facteur de transcription impliqué dans la transcription de nombreux gènes incluant, le plus notable, l'érythropoïétine l'hormone responsable de l'érythropoïèse. Dans le chapitre II, l'hypothèse est que la dérépression traductionnelle de l'ARNm de HIF2α par l'absence de IRP1 conduit à la polyglobulie à travers l'induction de l'érythropoïétine. Ici il est démontré que IRP1, et non IRP2, est impliqué dans la dérépression traductionnelle de HIF2α qui mène à l'accumulation de la protéine HIF2α dans les reins des souris IRP1-/-, aboutissant à  l'augmentation de l'érythropoïétine dans le sérum et conséquemment à la polyglobulie dans ces souris. Dans le chapitre III, L'hypothèse est que les souris IRP1-/- exhibent des anomalies métaboliques. Ici nous établissons que les souris IRP1-/- présentent un phénotype d'hypoglycémie. Il est ensuite observé que ce phénotype est partiellement secouru à travers l'élimination globale de IRP1 couplée à la délétion spécifique de HIF2α dans les hépatocytes.</description><description>Iron is an essential nutrient for many biochemical functions within the body.  However, its flexible redox potential is a "double edged" sword that makes it both essential for life but also renders it potentially toxic. As iron excretion is limited, iron absorption is tightly regulated. Systemic iron homeostasis is controlled through the hepatic hormone hepcidin. Iron and other stimuli control hepcidin transcription.  When produced hepcidin circulates through out the body and binds to the cellular iron exporter ferroportin (FPN1) expressed on duodenal enterocytes, macrophages, and hepatocytes causing FPN1's subsequent internalization and degradation. Ergo hepcidin function to control the efflux of iron from duodenal enterocytes, hepatocytes, and macrophages in to the blood stream. Cellular iron metabolism is controlled through iron regulatory proteins 1 and 2 (IRP1 and IRP2).   IRPs repress or stabilize translation of mRNAs, encoding proteins of iron uptake, utilization, and storage, which contain iron responsive elements (IRESs) within their untranslated regions.This work examines in vivo regulation of hypoxia inducible factor 2 alpha (HIF2α) by IRP1.  HIF2α is a transcription factor involved in the transcription of many genes involved in the body's response to hypoxic stress including, most notable, erythropoietin the hormone responsible for erythropoiesis. In chapter II it is hypothesized that translational de-repression of HIF2α mRNA by the absence of IRP1 leads to polycythemia through the induction of erythropoietin.  Here it is demonstrated that IRP1 but not IRP2 is involved in the translational de-repression of HIF2α which subsequently leads to an accumulation of HIF2α protein in the kidneys of IRP1-/- mice.  It is further demonstrated that the accumulation of HIF2α protein in the kidneys leads to an increase serum erythropoietin and subsequent polycythemia in IRP1-/- mice.      In chapter III it is hypothesized that IRP1-/- mice will demonstrate a metabolic phenotype.  Here it is demonstrated that IRP1-/- mice exhibit hypoglycaemia. Through the global knock out of IRP1 couple with the hepatocyte specific deletion of HIF2α we observe a partial rescue of the hypoglycaemic phenotype seen in IRP1-/- mice. </description><creator>Wilkinson, Nicole</creator><contributor>Konstantinos Pantopoulos (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Health Sciences - Medicine and Surgery </subject><title>Regulation of murine erythropoiesis and metabolism by the iron regulatory protein1/hypoxia inducible factor 2 alpha pathway</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n009w563p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kp78gk75s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:f4752m18n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The fundamental biological functions of spermatogonial stem cells (SSCs) is to support sperm generation and as such the propagation of genetic material to future generations. Like other stem cells, SSCs are defined by their ability to self-renew and also generate daughter cells which are committed to differentiation (J. M. Oatley &amp; Brinster, 2008). It has been shown that retinoic acid (RA) is quintessential in spermatogenesis; its role is most clearly seen in its absence which results in infertility (Snyder, Small, &amp; Griswold, 2010). In vivo RA acts on undifferentiated spermatogonia transitioning them into differentiating spermatogonia, consequently RA can serve as a key inducer of spermatogonial differentiation in vitro (Zhou et al., 2008). The objectives of my study were to assess the effects of RA on aggregates of undifferentiated spermatogonia in vitro (clusters), elucidate genes implicated in RA induced differentiation of SSCs and determine markers that coincide with the transition for SSC commitment to differentiation. I hypothesize that RA induces the differentiation of SSCs in vitro and further that SSCs can respond rapidly to RA. Results obtained support the hypothesis that RA rapidly induces SSC differentiation in vitro. These results included: observation of distinctive cell chain morphology in vitro post-treatment that is reflective of spermatogonia differentiation, SSC quantification confirms a decrease SSCs post-treatment and gene expression analysis reveals an increase in spermatogonial differentiation markers and a decrease of SSC specific markers following treatment. In addition to providing insight into RA directed SSC differentiation, gene expression analysis also revealed genes which were upregulated rapidly following RA treatment. These genes included LRPAP1 and Stxbp5; two genes have not been previously described in the context of SSC differentiation and may be novel markers for early SSC differentiation. These results indicate that the SSC-based, in vitro experimental paradigm that I used in this study provides an effective platform to further dissect the process of early SSC differentiation and its mechanisms.</description><description>La fonction biologique fondamentale des spermatogonies (SSCs) est de soutenir la production de sperme et la propagation du matériel génétique aux générations futures. Comme les autres cellules souches, SSCs sont définies par leur capacité de se renouveler et de générer des cellules filles ayant débuté leur  différenciation (J. M. Oatley &amp; Brinster, 2008). Il a été démontré que l'acide rétinoïque (RA) est essentiel à la spermatogenèse, car son absence cause une infertilité (Snyder et al., 2010). RA peut agir sur les spermatogonies indifférenciées pour induire leur différenciation et donc peut servir comme un inducteur clé de la différenciation des spermatogonies in vitro (Zhou et al., 2008). Les objectifs de mon étude étaient d'évaluer les effets de la RA sur les agrégats de spermatogonies indifférenciées in vitro (clusters), d'élucider les gènes impliqués dans la différenciation des SSCs induite par RA et de valider des marqueurs qui permettraient de déterminer la transition de différenciation. Mon hypothèse est que l'RA induit la différenciation des SSCs in vitro et aussi que les SSCs peuvent répondre rapidement à l'RA. Ce qui peut suggérer que les SSCs existent comme une population cellulaire hétérogène contenant une proportion de cellules déjà prédisposée pour répondre à l'induction de la différenciation. Les résultats obtenus supportent l'hypothèse que l'RA induit rapidement la différenciation in vitro des SSCs. Les résultats obtenus après le traitement incluent: une morphologie distincte des chaînes de cellules, une perte de SSCs, une augmentation des marqueurs de différenciation des spermatogonies et une diminution des marqueurs spécifiques des SSCs. En plus de confirmer que l'RA dirige la différenciation des SSCs, l'analyse globale de l'expression des gènes a également démontré que certains ont une expression accrue après le traitement avec l'RA. Ces gènes incluent LRPAP1 et Stxbp5; deux gènes qui n'ont pas été décrits précédemment dans le cadre de la différenciation des SSCs et peuvent être de nouveaux marqueurs montrant le début de la différenciation des SSCs.</description><creator>Sicilia, Sabrina</creator><contributor>Makoto Nagano (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Cell</subject><title>The effects of retinoic acid on spermatogonial stem cell differentiation in vitro</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn9999962.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/f4752m18n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r6449</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The diversity and community composition of birds and seven insect taxa: butterflies and skippers (Lepidoptera); Carabidae (Coleoptera); Dolichopodidae, Syrphidae, Sphaeroceridae, Chloropidae (Diptera); Apoidea (Hymenoptera) were studied in old field habitats surrounded by different intensities of urbanization in the Montreal region. A total of 386 breeding birds of 42 species as well as 2255 migrating birds of 31 species were surveyed. More than 7000 insect specimens of 264 species were identified. Results indicate that, in terms of studied taxa, old field biodiversity remains fairly constant despite different surrounding land use. The exceptions were that butterfly and skipper species richness and number of Syrphidae specimens collected were both higher in suburban than periurban sites, and breeding birds were more abundant in rural areas compared to suburban ones. Breeding bird communities in suburban areas were most similar to one another. Despite these findings, the overarching pattern was that the diversity and community composition of birds and insects did not differ between old fields in suburban, periurban, or rural areas. Chloropidae was the only taxon influenced by surrounding land use, particularly by amounts of residential, industrial/commercial/transportation areas, and green space. Because of the differences in responses, none of the taxa were reliable bioindicators of diversity patterns in all the other taxa, however, some significant correlations between individual taxa were established.</description><description>Cette étude visait  à comprendre la diversité et la composition des communautés d'oiseaux et d'insectes présentes dans des champs abandonnés par rapport à l'intensité d'urbanisation des terres adjacentes dans la région de Montréal. Les sept taxons d'insectes  choisis étaient: les papillons et les hespéries (Lepidoptera); Carabidae (Coleoptera); Dolichopodidae, Syrphidae, Sphaeroceridae, Chloropidae (Diptera); Apoidea (Hymenoptera). Au total, 386 oiseaux nicheurs représentant 42 espèces, ainsi que 2255 oiseaux migrateurs représentant 31 espèces ont été répertoriés. Plus de 7000 spécimens d'insectes comprenant 264 espèces ont été identifiés. Les résultats indiquent que la diversité des champs abandonnés reste stable, malgré des différences dans l'urbanisation des terres adjacentes, du moins dans les groupes étudiés. Toutefois, il y avait quelques exceptions : la diversité des papillons et des hespéries ainsi que l'abondance des syrphes étaient plus élevées dans les sites suburbains comparé aux sites periurbains; de plus, les oiseaux nicheurs étaient plus abondants dans les sites ruraux que les sites suburbains. Les assemblages d'oiseaux nicheurs dans les sites suburbains démontraient le plus grand degré de similitude les uns par rapport aux autres. Malgré ces résultats, le patron global indique que la diversité et les assemblages d'oiseaux et d'insectes dans les champs abandonnés diffèrent peu malgré des alentours suburbains, périurbains ou ruraux. Chloropidae serait le seul taxon influencé par l'urbanisation des terrains adjacents, particulièrement par la quantité de terrains résidentiels et industriels  et d'espaces verts.  Étant donné ces variations, aucun des taxons choisis n'a pu être utile en tant qu'espèce indicatrice des patrons de diversité des autres taxons; cependant, quelques corrélations significatives ont été établies entre certains taxons.</description><creator>Barrie, Christine</creator><contributor>Terry A Wheeler (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Entomology</subject><title>Bird and insect diversity along an urban disturbance gradient</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dj88h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r6449</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6q182p388</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Un grand nombre d'aberrations génétiques contribuent au phénotype virulent du glioblastome multiforme (GBM), un cancer hétérogène en quatre sous-types principaux qui présentant des caractéristiques moléculaires distinctes. L'activité différentielle des réseaux suppressifs oncogènes et tumoraux complique le traitement ciblé puisque il n'aura pas la même effet sur chacun des sous-types. De même, la complexité génétique du GBM permet une signalisation compensatrice favorisant l'entretien de la tumeur et une résistance à l'apoptose.Au cours de la dernière décennie, plusieurs données probantes ont été recueillies portant sur l'importance de l'initiation de la traduction des ARNm dans la tumorigenèse. Plus de 10 facteurs d'initiation de la traduction, agissant comme proto-oncogènes ou suppresseurs de tumeur, interviennent dans l'oncogenèse. De ces facteurs, le complexe d'initiation eIF4F, qui est  composé de l'eIF4E, de l'eIF4G et de l'eIF4A est le mieux décrit. La formation accrue de complexes entraîne une discrimination de l'ARNm, ce qui augmente la traduction d'un sous-groupe d'ARNm oncogènes « faibles » dotés de séquences 5' non traduites (5'UTR) très structurées. Par conséquent, l'inhibition de l'initiation de la traduction peut simultanément cibler de nombreuses voies oncogènes. Toutefois, le rôle de l'initiation de la traduction dans la biologie du GBM est incertain tout comme les propriétés anti-néoplastique que pourraient entraîner son inhibition. Lors de cette étude, nous avons utilisé le 4EGI-1 et le silvestrol, inhibiteurs des molécules eIF4E et eIF4A, respectivement, afin de cibler l'initiation de la traduction dans les trois lignées cellulaires du GBM, soit U87, U251N et la plus virulente U87ΔEGFR. Ici, nous montrons que le 4EGI-1 inhibe l'intéraction eIF4E/eIF4G qui est essentielle à la formation du complexe eIF4F dans les cellules U87. Cette inhibition entraîne une diminution de la prolifération et de la survie cellulaires en fonction de la dose et du temps traitement. Moins de 1 % des cellules U87 et U251N et de 17,5% des cellules U87∆EGFR étant toujours présentes après un traitement de 4EGI-1 à 80 µM d'une durée de 96 heures. Une induction marquée de l'apoptose est observée après 48 heures,  ainsi qu'une augmentation du marquage à de même qu'une l'annexine V+/7AAD et le clivage de la capsase-9/PARP. Ceci est s'accompagné d'une diminution de l'expression des protéines de plusieurs oncogènes dotés de 5'UTR très structurées, qui sont impliquées dans la prolifération et la survie, tels que c-Myc, cycline D-1, Bcl-2, Bcl-xL, Mcl-1 et survivine. De plus, le 4EGI-1 inhibe la migration des cellules U87 et U87∆EGFR en réponse aux stimuli chimioattractifs ainsi que la prolifération des trois lignées cellulaires dans un milieu en suspension solide. Les effets du silvestrol sont similaires à ceux de 4EGI-1 à l'égard de l'inhibition de la prolifération cellulaire, de la survie, de l'expression des protéines oncogènes et de l'induction de l'apoptose, bien qu'à des concentrations nanomolaires et à des points d'analyse différent, ce qui indique une pharmacocinétique supérieure.Nos résultats montrent la sensibilité du GBM en ce qui concerne l'inhibition de l'initiation de la traduction et sa capacité de déclencher une réponse apoptique solide. Ceci corrobore que la maîtrise de la régulation de la traduction constitue un élément puissant du traitement du cancer, particulièrement du GBM, où les options thérapeutiques sont limitées.</description><description>Many genetic aberrations contribute to the aggressive phenotype of Glioblastoma Multiforme (GBM), a heterogenous tumor which consists of four major subtypes with distinct molecular characteristics. The differential activity of oncogenic and tumor suppressive networks between these subtypes makes targeted therapy difficult as not all subtypes will be affected to the same degree. As well, the genetic complexity of GBM allows for compensatory signaling to sustain malignancy and resist apoptosis. During the last decade evidence has accumulated about the importance of mRNA translation initiation in tumorigenesis. Over 10 translation initiation factors are implicated in oncogenesis, acting as either proto-oncogenes or tumor suppressors, the most well described being the eIF4F initiation complex, consisting of eIF4E, eIF4G and eIF4A. Increased complex formation results in mRNA discrimination, leading to an increased translation of a subset of "weak" oncogenic mRNAs with highly structured 5'UTRs. Thus, inhibition of translation initiation can simultaneously target many oncogenic pathways. However it is unclear what role translation initiation plays in GBM biology, and whether its inhibition may have anti-neoplastic properties. In this study, we used 4EGI-1 and silvestrol, small-molecule inhibitors of eIF4E and eIF4A respectively, to target translation initiation in three GBM cell lines U87, U251N and the more aggressive U87ΔEGFR. Here, we show in U87 cells that 4EGI-1 blocks the eIF4E/eIF4G interaction which is necessary for eIF4F complex formation. This coincides with a reduction in cell proliferation and survival, in a dose and time-dependent manner, with &lt;1% of U87 and U251N cells and 17.5% of U87∆EGFR cells remaining after a 96 hour treatment with 80µM 4EGI-1. There is marked induction of apoptosis at 48 hours, with increased annexin V+/7AAD- staining and Capsase-9/PARP cleavage, accompanied by a decrease in the protein expression of several oncogenes, with highly structured 5'UTRs, involved in proliferation and survival such as c-Myc, Cyclin D-1, Bcl-2, Bcl-xL, Mcl-1 and Survivin.  Additionally 4EGI-1 inhibited the migration of U87 and U87∆EGFR cells in response to chemotactic stimuli, as well as anchorage –independent growth of all three cell lines. Silvestrol showed similar effects as 4EGI-1 in inhibiting cell proliferation, survival, oncogenic protein expression and inducing apoptosis, although at nanomolar concentrations and at earlier time points, indicating superior pharmacokinetics.Our results demonstrate the sensitivity of GBM towards inhibition of translation initiation and its ability to induce a robust apoptotic response. This further highlights translation regulation control as a strong force in cancer therapy, particularly in GBM where therapeutic options are limited.</description><creator>Rajakumar, Arjuna</creator><contributor>Josephine Nalbantoglu (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Characterizing the anti-tumor effects of inhibiting translation initiation in glioblastoma multiforme</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xj10t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6q182p388</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311s75w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'énergie géothermique est une technologie renouvelable émergente importante qui a le potentiel de fournir de l'énergie d'une source pratiquement illimitée. Le désavantage de l'énergie géothermique est l'ampleur du capital des forages qui sont requis pour accéder aux ressources plus chaudes. Utiliser les forages de pétrole abandonnés est une opportunité originale pour circonvenir ce désavantage. Cette thèse propose un modèle sophistiqué qui est capable de simuler le flux de chaleur à travers un échangeur de chaleur à tube double et le flux de chaleur à travers la masse rocheuse autour du forage. Le modèle sophistiqué est comparé avec le modèle analytique de source cylindrique, et deux autres modèles numériques et arrivent aux résultats comparables. Le but de cette modèle sophistiqué est de fournir une représentation précise et réaliste du flux de chaleur et la distribution de la température pour un échangeur de chaleur situé dans un forage de pétrole abandonné.  Les effets de la température d'entrée de fluide, l'isolation, la conductivité thermique de la masse rocheuse, le taux de débit massique du fluide actif, et le mouvement vertical de l'eau souterraine sur la durabilité et performance de la conception sont enquêtés. Un modèle de puissance constante est aussi proposé pour l'extraction de l'énergie géothermique encore plus durable.</description><description>Geothermal energy is an important emerging renewable technology that has the potential to provide power from a virtually unlimited reserve worldwide. The downside to exploiting geothermal energy is the capital intensive drilling of the borehole needed to access relatively hot resources located deep under the ground. However, abandoned petroleum wells present an interesting opportunity to circumvent the capital costs associated with drilling. This thesis proposes a sophisticated heat transfer model that is capable of realistically simulating the heat flow through a double pipe heat exchanger and the surrounding rock mass. The sophisticated model is compared with the analytical cylindrical source model, and two numerical models and reaches comparable results. The purpose of this model is to provide an accurate and realistic representation of heat flow and temperature distribution for a heat exchanger retrofitted to an abandoned well. The effects that inlet fluid temperature, insulation, thermal conductivity of the rock mass, mass flow rate of the working fluid, and vertical movement of groundwater have on the sustainability and performance of the double pipe heat exchanger are investigated. A constant power model is also proposed in order to assess the sustainable rate of heat extraction from a geothermal resource. </description><creator>Templeton, Jeffrey</creator><contributor>Faramarz P Hassani (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Engineering - Mining</subject><title>Abandoned petroleum wells as sustainable/renewable sources of geothermal energy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237hv902.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311s75w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Materials</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988p188</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le stress oxidatif, causé par un excès des espèces réactives de l'oxygène et/ou une diminution de la capacité anti-oxydante, est associé à une infertilité masculine. Un des conséquence du stress oxydatif est la formation de modifications, telles que la nitration des tyrosine (Nitro-Y) ou la S-glutathionylation (GSS-R) de protéines pouvant être impliquées dans la balance réduction-oxydation. Notre hypothèse est que l'excès de Nitro-Y et GSS-R induit des anomalies de la motilité et de la capacitation des spermatozoïdes. Cette étude a donc pour but de 1- Déterminer les effets des espèces réactives de l'oxygène sur la motilité, la capacitation et la production de Nitro-Y et GSS-R dans le spermatozoïde humain; 2- Localiser les protéines ayant des Nitro-Y et/ou GSS-R dans le spermatozoïde humain. Des spermatozoïdes de donneurs sains, sélectionnés après gradient de Percoll ont été incubés 30 minutes à 37oC en présence de différentes concentrations de H2O2, tert−butyl hydroperoxide (tBHP) ou de Da-NONOate (un donneur de NO•). Les protéines modifiées sont analysées par immuno-buvardage (SDS-PAGE) et immunocytochimie. Nous avons montré une augmentation dose-dépendante des protéines associées au GSS-R en présence de H202 et de tBHP (0.1 to 1 mM). Ces protéines sont localisées dans le cytosol et la fraction soluble au triton du spermatozoïde. D'autre part, nous avons montré une augmentation dose-dépendante des protéines associées au Nitro-Y en présence de DaNONOate (0.1 to 1 mM). Ces protéines sont localisées dans la fraction insoluble au triton du spermatozoïde. De plus, en présence d'espèces réactives de l'oxygène, nous avons observé, une diminution de la motilité des spermatozoïdes et un niveau de réaction acrosomique et de phosphorylation des protéines similaires à des spermatozoïdes non capacités, même après induction de la capacitation. Nos résultats suggèrent qu'un excès de protéines ayant des Nitro-Yet GSS-R peuvent être à l' origine d'anomalies de la motilité et du pouvoir fécondant des spermatozoïdes chez certains hommes infertiles. Dans la préparation de cette thèse, j'ai participé à la conception expérimentale, réalisée toutes les expériences et analysé les données résultantes.</description><description>Oxidative stress, generated by excessive reactive oxygen species (ROS) and/or decrease in antioxidant defences, is associated with male infertility. A consequence of oxidative stress is the generation of excessive redox dependent protein modifications, such as tyrosine nitration (Nitro-Y) and S-glutathionylation (GSS-R). We hypothesize that excessive Nitro-Y and GSS-R levels impair sperm motility and capacitation (process by which sperm gain fertilizing ability). The aims of this study were to determine: 1) the effect of different ROS on motility, capacitation and the production of Nitro-Y and GSS-R in human spermatozoa and 2) the subcellular localization of Nitro-Y and GSS-R modified proteins. Percoll washed spermatozoa from healthy donors were incubated for 30 minutes at 37oC with increasing concentrations of either hydrogen peroxide (H2O2), tert−butyl hydroperoxide (tBHP), or DaNONOate (a nitric oxide (NO•) donor). Modified sperm proteins were analysed using SDS-PAGE immunoblotting and immunocytochemistry. Levels of GSS-R modified proteins increased dose dependently after exposure to H2O2 and tBHP (0.1 to 1 mM), and were localised mainly in the cytosolic and Triton-soluble fractions of the spermatozoa. Levels of Nitro-Y modified proteins increased dose dependently after exposure to DaNONOate (0.1 to 1 mM), and were mainly localized in the Triton-insoluble fraction. ROS-treated spermatozoa showed a dose dependent decrease of motility and had tyrosine phosphorylation and acrosome reaction levels similarly to that of non-capacitated spermatozoa following incubation under capacitating conditions. These results suggest that excessive Nitro-Y and GSS-R modified sperm proteins may be a culprit for the motility and fertilization failure observed in some conditions of male infertility.In the preparation of this thesis, I participated in the experimental design, performed all experiments and analyzed the resulting data.</description><creator>Morielli, Tania</creator><contributor>Cristian Marcel O'Flaherty (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Reactive oxygen species promote redox-dependent protein modifications and impair motility and capacitation in human spermatozoa</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z029p803b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988p188</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Surgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602433h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T18:26:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'objectif de ce mémoire est d'étudier la façon dont la circularité structure le dernier roman de Réjean Ducharme, Gros mots, dans son ensemble. Les multiples jeux de miroirs et procédés d'autoreprésentation dans Gros mots, tels que la mise en abyme, créent une circularité qui se déploie à plusieurs niveaux, de la narration aux idées. Nous observerons les divers effets de ressassement et de réduplication causés par cette circularité, ainsi que leurs répercussions sur le personnage principal et narrateur du roman. L'analyse de l'intertextualité (notamment l'intertextualité ducharmienne) révèle que celle-ci participe également à la circularité globale du roman, reflétant certains de ses aspects et introduisant une réflexion sur la littérature, l'écriture et la lecture. L'autopastiche qu'est le cahier de la mise en abyme est l'occasion pour Ducharme de commenter sa propre pratique et le personnage d'écrivain qu'il est devenu dans le champ littéraire. </description><description>This thesis seeks to study the ways in which circularity structures Réjean Ducharme's last novel, Gros mots. Circularity takes many forms in the novel: from narration to ideas, by way of multiple mirror effects and processes of self-representation (such as mise en abyme). I will study how circularity generates effects of reiteration and reduplication, as well as the repercussions of those effects on the novel's main character/narrator. This analysis of intertextuality (notably of Ducharmian intertextuality) highlights its contribution to the novel's circularity, which reflects certain aspects of the novel's construction even as it formulates a commentary on the acts of reading and writing and on literature itself. The autopastiche created by the novel's mise en abyme enables Ducharme to comment on his own writing and the writer-character position that he has come to occupy in the literary field.</description><creator>Renaud, Catherine</creator><contributor>Michel Biron (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2014</date><subject>Literature - Canadian (French) </subject><title>«Gros mots»: le récit circulaire de Réjean Ducharme</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mn12q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602433h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):13000</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>