<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:28:55Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):22725" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn009z81n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Internet is a tremendous success and is an indispensable part of our everyday    activities. However, Internet does not provide sufficient integrity to ensure the end hosts    accountable for the communication. In this thesis, we present a new social accountable framework    for the Internet that leverages the trusted links found on online social networks to hold the    people and organizations accountable for their actions. Our framework is incrementally deployable    without modifying the operating systems or applications running on the hosts. We provide the full    design and discuss how different types of applications can be mapped onto the proposed framework.    A prototype of this social accountable framework is partially implemented to evaluate the    performance of the framework.</description><description>L'Internet est un succès extraordinaire et est une pièce    indispensable de notre vie quotidienne. Cependent, l'Internet ne fourni pas assez    d'integrité pour assurer que les hébergeurs finaux soient responsables pour les    communications. Dans cette thèse, nous présentons un nouveau cadre social responsable pour    l'Internet qui exploite les liens de confiance trouvés sur les réseaux sociaux pour    tenir les utilisateurs et les organisations responsables pour leurs actions. Notre cadre se    déploit de facon itérative sans la modification du système d'exploitation ou les    applications qui y exécutent. Nous présentons le plan complet et élaborons comment différent    types d'applications peuvent s'adapter au cadre proposé. Un prototype de ce    cadre social responsable est partiellement mis en application pour évaluer sa    performance.</description><creator>Han, Chunhui</creator><contributor>Muthucumaru Maheswaran (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Applied Sciences - Computer Science</subject><title>Social gate: a new social accountable framework for computer networks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zv28b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn009z81n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x346d508p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recent studies by Health Canada have shown its public service announcements    (PSAs) and tobacco warning labels are increasingly ineffective. This thesis questions whether    public communication is the best course of action for health promotion. I analyze texts by health    promotion scholars and professionals that emphasize community and economically redistributive    approaches – approaches that have been taken up on only a limited basis by health agencies in    Canada. Added to this, smoking rates are significantly higher in working class, poor and mentally    ill populations; in this way, it makes sense economic redistribution should be one component of    plans to achieve better health for all. Further, the widespread adoption of neoliberal economic    policies since the 1980s have overwhelmingly disadvantaged these populations; because of this, I    suggest the pleasures smoking provides trump information-based prevention efforts for these    populations, which happen to mostly model idealized, middle-class normatively gendered and    heteronormative situations as reason to quit. To conclude, I contrast two recent programs for    addiction control in Canada: the Smoke-Free Ontario Act, which introduced legal prohibitions that    limit public spaces in which cigarettes can be consumed in order to encourage smoking cessation,    and InSite, the supervised injection site in Vancouver's Downtown Eastside that uses a    harm-reduction approach that helps clients address the multiple challenges in their lives without    requiring drug abstinence as a precondition for access.</description><description>Des études récentes effectuées par Santé Canada ont démontré que    ses publicités d'intérêt public et ses avertissements sur les produits de tabac sont de plus en    plus inefficaces. Ce mémoire soulève la question à savoir si la communication publique est le    meilleur type d'intervention pour la promotion de la santé. Je ferai l'analyse de textes écrits    par des érudits et professionnels en matière de promotion de la santé qui mettent l'emphase sur    l'approche communautaire et de redistribution économique, approches qui ont n'été repris que de    manière limitée par les agences de santé canadiennes. De plus, le taux de tabagisme est plus    élevé parmi les groupes de population de la classe ouvrière, les pauvres, et ceux atteints de    maladie mentale. En ce sens, il suit que la redistribution économique devrait être une composante    de tout plan visant à améliorer la santé de la population. De plus, l'adoption de politiques    néolibérales à partir des années 1980 ont désavantagé ces groupes; à cause de cela, je suggère    que le plaisir qu'apporte l'acte de fumer fait obstacle aux efforts de prévention basés sur    l'information, qui le plus souvent proposent comme modèle des situations idéalisées issues de la    classe moyenne et présentant une norme de genre et de sexualité hétérosexuelle comme étant des    raisons de cesser de fumer. Pour conclure, je ferai un contraste entre deux programmes récents    pour le contrôle de la dépendance au tabac et de la toxicomanie: La Loi favorisant un Ontario    sans fumée, qui a introduit des prohibitions légales limitant les lieux dans lesquels le tabac    peut être consommé afin d'encourager la cessation de l'usage du tabac ainsi que InSite, le site    d'injection supervisé dans le « Downtown Eastside » de Vancouver qui fait usage d'une approche de    réduction des dommages en aidant sa clientèle à faire face aux multiples défis dans leur vie sans</description><creator>Sutton, Paul</creator><contributor>Barney, Darin (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Communications And The Arts - Mass Communications</subject><title>Smoking is a socialist issue: health promotion and neoliberal politics in Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pc289j955.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d508p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gq67js09h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis attempts to address the issue of religious freedom and public    service by specifically examining the policy implemented by the Government of Saskatchewan    towards its civil marriage commissioners in 2004. This work takes a critical look at four key    aspects: first, reasonable accommodation – its history, its application in the Canadian context    and the academic debates pertaining to religious accommodation; second, the policymaking process    employed by the Province of Saskatchewan; third, Canadian jurisprudence on freedom of religion    cases; and finally, contemporary academic approaches to the role of religion in the public    sphere. Taken together, these issues suggest that the contemporary shift in understanding and    applying norms of reasonable accommodation, in conjunction with the current judicial trend to    assign religious belief to the private sphere, reinforces the notion that the religious rights of    private citizens are limited when they assume a public role.</description><description>Cette thèse examine la question de la liberté de religion et la    fonction publique, en analysant spécifiquement la politique mise en place par le Gouvernement de    la Saskatchewan vis-à-vis les commissaires aux mariages civils en 2004. Cet ouvrage jette un    regard critique sur quatre aspects principaux: le premier, l'accommodement raisonnable -    son histoire, son application dans le contexte canadien et les débats académiques liés à    l'accommodement religieux; le deuxième, le processus d'élaboration des politiques    utilisé par la province de la Saskatchewan; le troisième, la jurisprudence canadienne sur la    liberté de religion; et finalement, les approches académiques contemporaines vis-à-vis le rôle de    la religion dans la sphère publique. Ensemble, ces enjeux suggèrent que le changement    contemporain dans la compréhension et l'application des normes d'accommodement    raisonnable, en conjonction avec la tendance judiciaire actuelle d'assigner des    croyances religieuses à la sphère publique, renforcent la notion que les droits religieux des    citoyens privés sont limités lorsqu'ils adoptent un rôle public.</description><creator>Harwood, Philip</creator><contributor>Daniel M Cere (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Political Science - General</subject><title>Civil marriage commissioners in the province of Saskatchewan: religious freedom and public service</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/44558f22q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gq67js09h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0r9674611</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La prévalence du diabète à l'échelle planétaire atteint maintenant    des proportions épidémiques. Environ 90-95% des cas de diabète sont de type 2 et cette maladie    affecte de manière disproportionnée les populations défavorisées. Afin d'examiner l'association    de facteurs biographiques reliés à la position socio-économique (PSE) et l'incidence du diabète    de type 2, une étude prospective portant sur 1,895 participants de la 'Framingham Offspring    Study' a été menée. Trois cadres conceptuels épidémiologiques ont été utilisés pour abstraire la    PSE : l'accumulation du risque, les périodes critiques et la mobilité sociale. Les résultats    démontrent que l'exposition cumulée à une basse PSE accroît le risque de développer un diabète de    type 2 chez la femme mais non chez l'homme. De plus, l'âge adulte est une période critique chez    la femme durant laquelle l'exposition a une basse PSE (éducation et/ou occupation) augmente le    risque de développer un diabète de type 2.</description><description>The global prevalence of diabetes has achieved epidemic proportions and is    expected to continue to climb. Approximately 90-95% of diabetes cases are type 2 diabetes, a    disease that disproportionally affects disadvantaged populations. To assess the associations of    timing and duration of socioeconomic position (SEP) across the life course on incidence of type 2    diabetes, we conducted a prospective analysis of 1,895 participants from the Framingham Offspring    Study. We used three life course epidemiology frameworks to conceptualize SEP: accumulation of    risk, sensitive periods and social mobility. We found that cumulative exposure to low SEP across    the life course increased risk for developing type 2 diabetes in women and not men. In addition,    adulthood may be a sensitive period where if exposed to low SEP (education and/or occupation),    women have increased risk for developing type 2 diabetes.</description><creator>Smith, Brendan</creator><contributor>Eric Loucks (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health Sciences - Epidemiology</subject><title>Life course socioeconomic position and type 2 diabetes: the experience of the Framingham Offspring Study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r8829.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0r9674611</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zf41s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description> Les supercordes cosmiques correspondent a des concentrations    linaires d'energieemprisonnee de taille macroscopique. Les supercordes cosmiques, sont celles    resultant de la theorie des cordes et peuvent former des jonctions. L'introduction deﬁnit plus    precisement les cordes, leur formation et les principales proprietes des cordes ou des    supercordes droites. Ensuite, on se focalise sur ces dernieres en etudiant les principales    proprietes des jonctions. Un premier pas consiste a trouver la metrique proched'une jonction de    cordes dans l'approximation de champ faible. Ensuite on trouverades possibles signatures qui    reveleraient leur presence : L'eﬀet de lentilles qu'ellescreent et le decalage dans la longueur    d'onde des photons passant aux alentours(ce qui mene a l'eﬀet Kaiser-Stebbins) au chapitre 2, et    la radiation gravitationellequ'elles peuvent emettre au chapitre 3.</description><description> Cosmic strings are linear concentrations of energy of macroscopic size. Cosmic    superstrings come from string theory and can form junctions. In the introduction, we deﬁne more    precisely the strings, their formation and the main properties of single straight cosmic strings    or superstrings. Then, we focus on those latter and study some major properties of junctions. As    a ﬁrst step, we ﬁnd the metric close to a junction of strings in the weak-ﬁeld approximation. We    then ﬁnd some signatures that would reveal their presence : Namely, the lensing that they create    and the shift in photon wavelength passing through (leading to the Kaiser-Stebbins eﬀect) in    chapter 2, and the gravitational radiation they can emit in chapter 3.</description><creator>Karouby, Johanna</creator><contributor>Robert Brandenberger (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Physics - Elementary Particles and High Energy</subject><title>Some properties of cosmic string junctions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jd472x39w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zf41s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f213s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le niveau d'expression d'un transcrit et les processus de    maturation de celui-ci en ARN messager (ARNm) se révèlent être des mécanismes augmentant la    complexité du transcriptome des eucaryotes. Ces processus permettent au même locus génomique de    produire plusieurs ARNm et protéines ayant des propriétés distinctes qui affectent leurs    fonctions, leur stabilité et leurs localisations intra cellulaire en contrôlant la vitesse de    transcription, en variant le site d'initiation ou de terminaison de la transcription et en    modulant l'inclusion d'exons (épissage) dans les ARNm matures. Il est donc primordial de    déterminer l'ampleur de ces types de variations afin de mieux comprendre leur impact sur la    diversite des oraganismes. Les études décrites dans cette thèse fournissent les premières    estimations de la façon dont les variations de polymorphism nucléotidique simple (SNP) peuvent    affecter la régulation de l'expression d'un transcrit et ses processus de maturation à l'échelle    du génome entier. Ces processus sont examinés dans une population humaine et entre humain et    chimpanzé en utilisant une méthode basée sur les puces à ADN. Nous démontrons d'abord l'existence    d'un nombre important de variations d'isoformes d'ARNm entre deux individus non apparentés et    nous démontrons que ces variations sont héritées ce qui leur révèle une composante génétique. Par    la suite, nous avons déterminé quelle proportion et quel type de variation au niveau de l'isoform    était sous contrôle génétique dans une population humaine. En réalisant une analyse d'association    entre l'expression des transcrits du génome entier et les SNPs présents dans cette population,    nous avons observé que 50-55% de la variation était à l'échelle de l'isoforme du transcrit. Nous    avons aussi étendu cette comparaison au chimpanzé en utilisant les profils d'expression mesurés    lors de l'analyse précédente. N</description><description>Transcript expression and pre-mRNA processing are emerging as important    mechanisms that increase the complexity of eukaryotic transcriptomes. These processes allow a    genomic locus to produce a number of mRNAs and proteins with distinct properties that affect    function, stability, and sub-cellular localization by controlling the rate of transcript    expression, by varying the initiation or termination of transcription and by modulating the    inclusion of exons (alternative splicing) in mature mRNAs. Thus, it is crucial to determine the    extent of these types of variations to better understand their importance in creating organism    diversity. The studies described in this thesis provide the first genome-wide estimations of how    single nucleotide polymorphisms (SNPs) affect the regulation of transcript expression and    pre-mRNA processing in a human population as well as between humans and chimpanzees using a    microarray-based approach. We first demonstrated that transcript expression changes at the    isoform level are common between two unrelated individuals and that these changes are heritable    and therefore have an underlying genetic component. We then investigated what proportion was    under genetic control in a normal human population by conducting a genome-wide association    analysis between single nucleotide polymorphisms and transcript isoform variants. We found that    50-55% of transcript expression variation is isoform based. We also extended our comparison of    human transcript isoform variation to chimpanzee. We showed that genetic substitutions in    regulatory sequences are responsible for some of the isoform variations observed between these    two closely related species. We ascertained that in our study these isoform variations are    responsible for certain phenotypic differences mostly related to immune responses. These results    constitute an important change in the way genetic variations are viewed in humans and chimpa</description><creator>Benovoy, David</creator><contributor>Jacek Majewski (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>Characterization of transcript isoform variations in human and chimpanzee</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jz032.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f213s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bz60cx303</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'hiver pose un défi énergétique pour les endothermes dans les    climats tempérés et nordiques. La nourriture est souvent moins disponible et les couts de    thermorégulation sont plus élevés. Les animaux peuvent utiliser des adaptations physiologiques et    du comportement pour diminuer leur demande énergétique. J'ai exploré l'effet de niveau de    nourriture et de la tempérture de l'air (Ta) sur les profils de température corporelle (Tb; 1er    chapitre), ainsi que les profils d'activité et les taux métaboliques sur le terrain (FMR; 2e    chapitre) d'une population nordique d'écureuil roux (Tamiascirus hudsonicus) en hivers. Les    écureuils qui avaient accès a la nourriture supplémentaire maintenaient une Tb élevée comparés    aux animaux témoin. Ta avait un effet positif sur Tb durant le jour mais pas la nuit. J'ai mesuré    FMR durant trois années avec différent niveaux de nourriture naturelle, et pendant deux de ces    années (une de nourriture elevée et une de nourriture basse) j'ai aussi mesuré des profils    d'activité. Pendant les deux années de faible taux de nourriture Ta avait un effet positif sur    FMR, tandis que durant l'année de taux élevé de nourriture Ta avait un effect négatif sur FMR.    Les différences de profils d'activité expliquent la différence de la relation entre Ta et FMR. La    proportion du temps passé a être actif ne différait pas entre les différents taux de nourriture    et de Ta. Par contre, les écureuils exposés à des taux de nourriture plus bas étaient actif    durant la partie la plus chaude de la journée pour diminuer leur demande de thermorégulation,    particulièrement par journées froides. Ces résultats démontrent que les écureuils ajustent leur    demande énergétique en réponse au niveau de ressources, et que l'effet de Ta sur la dépense    d'énergie est dépendante des taux de ressources.</description><description>Winter is an energetically challenging season for endotherms in temperate and    northern climates because seasonally low food availability is paired with high costs for    thermoregulation. In response to this apparent energetic mis-match, animals can use both    physiological and behavioural adaptations to decrease energy requirements. I investigated the    effects of resource levels and air temperatures (Ta) on body temperature patterns (Tb; chapter    1), as well as activity patterns and field metabolic rate (FMR; chapter 2) of a northern    population of red squirrels (Tamiasciurus hudsonicus) in winter. Squirrels provided with    supplemental food maintained consistently elevated Tb compared to control animals. Tb was    positively related to Ta during the day, but not at night. FMR was measured over three years with    varying levels of natural resources, and in two of these FMR was paired with activity patterns    (time spent out of their well-insulated nest). During the two years of low resource abundance Ta    had a positive effect on FMR, whereas in the one year of high resources Ta had a negative effect    on FMR. This difference may be explained by differences in activity patterns. Time spent active    was equal across both resource levels (one year of each low and high food), and all Ta. However,    animals under low resources timed activity such to be exposed to the warmest part of the day,    thereby decreased thermoregulatory requirements, particularly at cold Ta. Collectively, these    results show that squirrels adjust energy requirements as a response to resource abundance, and    that the effect of Ta on energy expenditure is resource-mediated.</description><creator>Woods, Sarah</creator><contributor>Murray Mitchell Humphries (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Ecology</subject><title>Resource-mediated thermoregulation and energetics of a northern population of red squirrels «Tamiasciurus hudsonicus)» in winter</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773w65w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bz60cx303</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gh93h047b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description> Le but du présent programme de recherche était d'examiner la    nature et les fonctions de l'intimité dans les relations sexuelles romantiques. Plus précisément,    je me suis intéressée à comprendre comment les gens ordinaires définissent et comprennent le    concept de l'intimité sexuelle par rapport au concept général de l'intimité, et comment    l'intimité à l'intérieur des relations romantiques influence strictement le bien-être à travers    le temps. Pour comprendre le premier, six études ont examiné la nature de l'intimité sexuelle et    ses liens avec l'intimité; pour comprendre le dernier, une étude longitudinale à grande échelle a    examiné l'impact de l'intimité au niveau de trois domaines du bien-être à travers une période de    huit mois, tout en contrôlant d'autres concepts pertinents (tels que la satisfaction reliée à la    relation, l'attachement, la proximité, et l'intimité sexuelle). Dans les études 1 et 2, des    prototypes de l'intimité et de l'intimité sexuelle ont été générés, et bien qu'il se trouvait un    chevauchement significatif entre ces deux prototypes, chacun d'eux possédait aussi des attributs    centraux uniques. L'étude 3 a fourni davantage de preuves quant à la nature prototypique de ces    deux concepts en démontrant que les attributs centraux des deux concepts étaient plus saillants    en mémoire que les attributs périphériques. Les études 4 et 5 ont démontré que les perceptions    d'intimité et d'intimité sexuelle à l'intérieur de relations romantiques fictives étaient    fortement reliées, mais aussi que ces deux concepts pouvaient être fidèlement différenciés. Plus    précisément, dans l'étude 4, l'amorçage de l'intimité sexuelle a fait augmenté l'activation du    concept de l'intimité, mais non l'inverse; et dans l'étude 5, la présence de l'intimité (mais pas    de l'intimité sexuelle) était associée avec une perception plus grande de la qualit</description><description> The purpose of this program of research was to explore the nature and function    of intimacy in romantic sexual relationships. More specifically, I was interested in how    laypeople define and understand the concept of sexual intimacy as it relates to the broader    concept of intimacy, and how intimacy in romantic relationships uniquely influences well-being    over time. In regards to the former, six studies examined the nature of sexual intimacy and its    relationship to intimacy; in regards to the latter, a large-scale longitudinal web survey    examined the impact of intimacy on three domains of well-being over a period of eight months,    controlling for other relevant constructs (i.e., attachment, relationship satisfaction,    closeness, and sexual intimacy). In studies 1 and 2, prototypes of intimacy and sexual intimacy    were generated and although there was significant overlap between the two prototypes, each also    included unique central attributes. Study 3 provided further evidence for the prototypical nature    of both concepts by demonstrating that central features of both concepts were more salient in    memory than peripheral features. Studies 4 and 5 showed that perceptions of intimacy and sexual    intimacy in fictional romantic relationships are highly related, but that the two concepts could    also be reliably differentiated. In Study 4, priming sexual intimacy increased activation of the    concept of intimacy, but the reverse was not true; and in Study 5, the presence of intimacy (but    not sexual intimacy) was associated with greater perceived relationship quality. Study 6 showed    that intimacy and sexual intimacy were positively correlated in real romantic relationships; and    that although prototypes of intimacy and sexual intimacy corresponded in meaningful ways to    theoretical models of intimacy, the endorsement of central intimacy and sexual intimacy    attributes in real romantic relationships was associated with relatio</description><creator>Birnie, Carolyn</creator><contributor>John Lydon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Psychology - Social</subject><title>The nature and function of intimacy in romantic sexual relationships</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2801ph166.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h047b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88ch422</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Les professeurs d'université croient que leurs recherches peuvent    être bénéfiques à leur enseignement bien que cette croyance n'ait pratiquement pas de preuves    empiriques. Nous croyons que les définitions de la recherche et de l'enseignement proposées dans    les études antérieures ont été trop simplistes pour établir un tel lien. Basée sur les interviews    de 25 professeurs de chimie, notre étude fait la lumière sur leurs croyances au sujet des effets    de leurs activités de recherche sur leur enseignement. Les professeurs interviewés relatent    plusieurs effets positifs. Leurs recherches leur permettent de conserver leurs connaissances    scientifiques à jour, de stimuler l'intérêt des étudiants, de tirer des exemples de la recherche,    de donner des meilleures explications et de situer l'information dans un contexte plus large. Ces    affirmations ont été classées en utilisant le modèle de Shulman (1987). Nos résultats sont    évalués en tenant compte des théories pédagogiques contemporaines et des recommandations du    rapport Boyer.</description><description>Academics believe in a symbiotic relationship between research and teaching,    though evidence challenges its existence. Previous studies may have defined these constructs too    narrowly to detect the perceived relationships. This study used a qualitative approach to    investigate chemistry professors' beliefs about the effects of their research activities on    teaching practice. Semistructured, in-depth interviews were conducted with 25 chemistry    professors from a large research-intensive university. Professors' contended that research    affects teaching subject-matter knowledge in the forms of knowledge currency, examples,    domain-thinking, and pedagogical knowledge through student interest, as well as pedagogical    content knowledge in terms of contextualization and explanation. Findings are contextualized    within Shulman's (1987) theory of teacher knowledge as well as current learning theories.</description><creator>Hua, Olivia</creator><contributor>Bruce M Shore (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Education - Higher</subject><title>How does faculty research activity affect undergraduate instruction in chemistry? An exploration of the perceived impacts of inquiry on pedagogy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50ts54g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88ch422</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vx021g134</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The available antibodies against CFTR are not sensitive enough to detect CFTR at    endogenous or near endogenous levels making detection at native levels difficult. We raised two    monoclonal antibodies, 22E8 and 23C5, against the R domain of human CFTR with the goal of    identifying an antibody sensitive enough to detect CFTR in native airway cells. These antibodies    were characterized for their ability to detect over-expressed as well as endogenous levels of    CFTR in immunoblotting, immunoprecipitation and immunofluorescence. Their ability to detect CFTR    was also compared with commercial antibodies M3A7 and 24-1. We show that 23C5 and 22E8 are more    sensitive than the commercial antibodies and are able to detect CFTR in over-expressed and    endogenous cells by immunoblotting. However, only 23C5 is able to immunoprecipitate CFTR and    neither is able to detect CFTR in native airway cells by immunoblotting or are suitable for    immunofluorescence. These antibodies will enable studies of CFTR biogenesis in endogenous cells.</description><description>A l'heure actuelle les anticorps dirigés contre la protéine CFTR    ne sont pas suffisamment sensibles pour détecter cette protéine de facon endogène rendant ainsi    l'étude de cette protéine difficile dans les tissus. Notre laboratoire a fabriqué deux anticorps    monoclonaux , nommés 22E8 et 23C5, dirigés contre le domaine R de la protéine CFTR. L'abilité de    ces anticorps à détecter l'expression de CFTR que ce soit de façon endogène ou lorsque la    protéine est surexprimée a été testée à l'aide des techniques d'immunoblotting,    d'immunoprécipitation et d'immunofluorescence. Afin de verifier leur sensibilité et leur capacité    à détecter la protéine CFTR, ces anticorps ont été comparés aux anticorps M3A7 et 24-1 qui sont    disponibles dans le commerce et connus pour détecter de facon optimale la protéine CFTR. Les    resultats obtenus dans les lignées cellulaires à l'aide de la technique d'immunoblotting ont    permis de montrer que les anticorps 23C5 et 22E8 sont plus sensibles que les anticorps    commerciaux, de plus ils sont capables de détecter à la fois les protéines endogènes et    sur-exprimées. Bien que l'anticorps 23C5 soit capable d'immunoprécipiter la protéine CFTR, aucun    des deux anticorps n'a permis la detection de la protéine CFTR par immunoblotting dans les    cellules de culture primaire. De plus, ces anticorps n'ont pas permis la detection de la protéine    CFTR par immunofluorescence. Ainsi l'utilisation de ces anticorps nous donnera l'opportunité    d'étudier la protéine CFTR dans les cellules l'exprimant de facon endogène afin de mieux    comprendre sa regulation et son traffic.</description><creator>Mirza, Myriam</creator><contributor>David Thomas (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Microbiology</subject><title>Characterization of new CFTR monoclonal antibodies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j193z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021g134</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s1109</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description> Une môle hydatidiform (MH) est une anomalie de la grossesse    caractérisée par soit l'absence de l'embryo ou du développement embryonnaire ainsi que    la dégénérescence des villosités choriales. Au Canada et aux États-Unis, l'incidence des MH est 1    sur 1000 naissances. Récemment, NLRP7 a été trouvé responsable des môles hydatidiform à    répétition, après l'identification de différentes mutations dans le gène. Pour étudier les    conséquences fonctionnelles des mutations de NLRP7 sur la maturation et la sécrétion de IL-1β,    j'ai utilisé le site de mutagenèse dirigée pour introduire les différentes mutations trouvées    chez les patientes atteintes de môles recurrentes. Des cellules HEK293 ont été cotransfectées    avec la copie normale de WT-NLRP7, procaspase-1, pro-IL-1β, avec et sans Cardinal (CARD-8.). Mes    résultats démontrent que WT-NLRP7 inhibe la sécrétion de IL-1β d'une manière dose-dépendante. De    plus, j'ai trouvé que Cardinal (CARD8), une composante importante d'autres inflammasomes, n'a pas    d'effet sur l'inhibition de WT-NLRP7. Mes constatations renforcent l'idée que NLRP7 peut    fonctionner comme un régulateur de la sécrétion de l'IL-1β.</description><description>Hydatidiform mole (HM) is an abnormal human pregnancy characterized by the    absence of, or abnormal, embryonic development and hydropic degeneration of the chorionic villi.    In both Canada and the United States, the incidence of HM is 1 in every 1000 pregnancies.    Recently, NLRP7 has been found to be responsible for recurrent hydatidiform moles (RHM) after the    identification of various mutations in this gene. To investigate the functional consequences of    NLRP7 mutations on IL-1β maturation and secretion, I used site-directed mutagenesis to introduce    the various mutations found in patients with RHM into WT-NLRP7. HEK293 cell lines were    cotransfected with WT-NLRP7, procaspase-1, and pro-IL-1β, as well as with or without Cardinal    (CARD-8.). My results demonstrate that WT-NLRP7 inhibits IL-1β secretion in a dose-dependent    manner. Furthermore, I found that Cardinal (CARD8), an important component of other    inflammasomes, has no impact on the inhibitory effect of WT-NLRP7. My findings strengthen the    idea that NLRP7 may function as a feedback regulator of IL-1β secretion.</description><creator>Bukhari, Ebtihaj</creator><contributor>Slim, Rima (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>Elucidation of the functional consequences of «NLRP7» mutations</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67js108.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s1109</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb397928s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Protein disulfide isomerase (PDI) is the most abundant and best characterized    member of the extensive PDI family of proteins found in the endoplasmic reticulum. PDI plays an    important role in protein folding. It is composed of four thioredoxin-like domains denoted as    a-b-b'-a'. Recent studies have identified a hydrophobic surface on the b' domain as the main    binding site for the unfolded protein substrates of PDI. Here, the main hydrophobic residues of    the b' domain were mutated in a bb' construct and tested for their ability to bind to the    14-residue mastoparan peptide. Most of the mutants had a significant effect on the binding    affinity. In reverse experiments the mastoparan peptide was mutated and NMR titrations used to    determine the orientation of the peptide on the bb' binding surface. Finally, the catalytic a and    a' domains were individually tested for binding to unfolded RNaseA by NMR. Neither catalytic    domain exhibited any direct interaction with the unfolded substrate.</description><description>La protéine disulfure isomérase (PDI) est le membre le mieux connu    et caractérisé de la nombreuse famille de PDI qui se trouve dans le réticulum endoplasmique. PDI    joue un rôle important dans le repliement des chaînes protéiques. Elle est composée de quatre    domaines désignés a-b-b'-a' de type thiorédoxine. Des études récentes ont identifié une surface    hydrophobe dans le domaine b' comme étant le lieu principal d'interaction avec les substrats    déroulés de la PDI. Ici, les résidus hydrophobes principaux du domaine b' ont été mutés et testés    pour leur interaction avec un peptide de quatorze résidus nommé mastoparan. La plupart des    mutants ont eu un impact important sur l'affinité de la PDI pour son substrat. Dans des    expériences contraires où le peptide mastoparan a été muté, des titrations par RMN ont révélé    l'orientation du peptide sur la surface d'interaction du domaine b'. Finalement, les domaines    catalytiques a et a' ont été individuellement testés par RMN pour leur affinité envers l'ARNase A    déroulée. Les deux domaines n'ont montré aucune interaction avec le substrat    déroulé.</description><creator>Dabrowski, Christian</creator><contributor>Kalle Burgess Gehring (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Cell</subject><title>Mutagenesis of the substrate binding site of protein disulfide isomerase</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w828v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397928s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vx021g12v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The theatre of Alexandre Hardy (1572-1632), is of notable importance not only    with regards to the transformations of the sensibility in the 17the century, but also because it    discredits on all levels that which will form the psychology of modern man. By refusing poetic    modernity in the name of the free inspiration inherited from the poets of the Pléiade, the author    opposes the constraints which were henceforth exerted on the stage, and which relate as much to    censure and psychology as to the theatre and its language. In attacking the preciosity, he takes    on the entire court, such that his plays will sometimes test the morals of honesty and at other    times the philosophy of appearances. Thus the theatre of Alexandre Hardy, who presents himself as    the agent of an ancestral tradition, is defined by a moral of virility, all the more obsolete at    court because it is opposed to the grace and the ease displayed by the    courtier.</description><description>Le théâtre d'Alexandre Hardy (1572-1632), non seulement est d'une    importance notable en ce qui concerne les transformations de la sensibilité au XVIIe siècle, mais    encore discrédite à tous les niveaux ce qui doit former la psychologie de l'homme moderne. En    refusant la modernité poétique, au nom de la libre inspiration héritée des poètes de la Pléiade,    l'auteur s'oppose aux contraintes qui dorénavant s'exercent sur scène, et qui concernent tout    autant la censure et la psychologie, que le théâtre et sa langue. En s'attaquant à la préciosité,    il s'en prend à toute la cour, de manière que ses pièces éprouveront tantôt la morale de    l'honnêteté, tantôt la philosophie des apparences. Ainsi le théâtre d'Alexandre Hardy, qui se    veut le dépositaire d'une tradition ancestrale, repose sur une morale de la virilité,    apparaissant d'autant plus désuète à la cour, qu'elle s'oppose à la grâce et à la désinvolture    dont fait montre le courtisan.</description><creator>Dupuis, Vincent</creator><contributor>Normand Doiron (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Literature - General</subject><title>Fortune du théâtre d'Alexandre Hardy : la cour et la tradition poétique à l'aube du classicisme</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78td01t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vx021g12v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483k22b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Le système urogénital accomplit des fonctions essentielles pour la    vie et la reproduction de tous les vertébrés. Chez l'humain, les malformations du système    urogénital sont parmi les plus fréquentes anomalies congénitales et peuvent entraîner de graves    complications chez l'adulte. Afin d'améliorer le diagnostique, les interventions médicales ainsi    que le pronostique chez les patients, une meilleure connaissance de la pathogénèse de l'appareil    urinaire et génital est nécessaire. Ainsi, l'objectif de mon programme de recherche de thèse    s'est basé sur l'étude du développement embryonnaire du système urogénital chez la souris, dans    le but d'améliorer notre compréhension des processus biologiques sous-jacents à la morphogénèse    ainsi qu'à la pathogénèse rénale.Les facteurs de transcription Pax sont des protéines qui    régulent le développement de plusieurs organes, tels que ceux du système urogénital. Les    résultats de recherche présentés ici, traitent des fonctions de Pax2/8 ainsi qu'un de leur    effecteur principal Gata3, à différents stades de développement du système génito-urinaire.    Pax2/8 régulent la croissance du rein définitif (métanéphros) et la différentiation des néphrons.    D'un point de vue moléculaire, ceci est en partie dû à l'activation de la transcription de gênes    cibles comme Wnt11 et Lim1, ainsi qu'à l'effet positif exercé par les gênes Pax sur la survie    cellulaire de l'appareil rénal. Dans le rein embryonnaire (pro/mésonephros), Pax2/8 activent    l'expression du facteur de transcription Gata3, qui lui-même contrôle plusieurs processus    cellulaires, comme la prolifération, la morphogénèse, le guidage et la différentiation.    Notablement, en tant que médiateur en aval de la signalisation Wnt/beta-catenin, Gata3 assure une    induction métanéphrique adéquate en empêchant une réponse cellulaire excessive aux facteurs de    croissance locaux. L</description><description>The urogenital system performs essential functions for life and reproduction in    all vertebrate species. In humans, congenital malformations of the urogenital system rank among    the most common birth defects and can cause life-threatening complications in adults. Therefore,    understanding urogenital system pathogenesis is imperative in order to provide more accurate    diagnoses and better medical interventions to ultimately improve clinical outcome in patients. In    this regard, my thesis research projects focused on the development of the mouse urogenital    system with the aim of advancing our current knowledge of the biological processes underlying    both its normal morphogenesis and disease. Pax transcription factors are critical regulatory    proteins involved in the development of many organs, including the urogenital system. Hence, the    results presented here, address the role of Pax2/8 along with one of their important effectors,    Gata3, at different stages of urogenital system morphogenesis. In the definitive (metanephric)    kidney, Pax2/8 regulate both kidney growth and nephron differentiation. Interestingly, from a    molecular perspective, this is partly achieved by Pax2/8 inducing the transcription of potent    target genes, such as Wnt11 and Lim1, as well as the positive effect of Pax genes on nephric cell    survival. In the embryonic (pro/mesonephric) kidney, Pax2/8 activate the expression of the    transcription factor Gata3, which in turn controls several important cellular processes, like    cell proliferation, morphogenesis, guidance and differentiation. Importantly, as a downstream    mediator of Wnt/beta-catenin signaling, Gata3 assures proper metanephric kidney induction by    preventing an excessive cellular response to local growth factors. The search for Gata3-regulated    genes in the mesonephros identified the Ret receptor tyrosine kinase and the transcription factor    Lim1, as critical downstream effectors and suggested</description><creator>Grote, David</creator><contributor>Maxime Bouchard (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Genetics</subject><title>The role of Pax2/8 and Gata3 transcription factors during mouse urogenital system development</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zx518.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483k22b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999762t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La croissance de cellules ayant une paroie cellulaire est due \'a    la collaboration de processus physiques et chimiques menant \'a une déformation    mécanique contrôlée de ces cellules. Les cellules    végétales, par exemple, doivent augmenter la surface de leur paroie afin de    croître. Ceci peut être accompli de façon uniforme appellée croissance diffuse    ou par croissance apicale. La croissance apicale est caractérisée par une    déformation mécanique qui est confinée à une région    spécifique de la cellule, soit l'apex. La croissance apicale méne    générallement à des paroies cellulaires de forme cylindrique. Elle est    observée chez des cellules végétales telles que le tube    pollinique ou des racines mais aussi chez des algues ou des hyphes fongiques. Le tube pollinique    est une protubérance qui croît sur un grain de pollen. Lors de la fertilisation, son    rôle est de s'allonger jusqu'à ce qu'il atteigne l'ovule    de la plante hôte et de permettre le passage d'une cellule de sperme contenue dans le    grain de pollen.Cette thése étudie les principes physiques qui contrôlent la    croissance apicale d'une cellule végétale. Elle    s'applique plus spécifiquement à la croissance d'un tube    pollinique. Les trois systémes particuliers que nous étudierons concernent les    effets élastiques et les potentiels électriques sur la diffusion    d'ions, l'aggrégation de protéines et le flot visqueux    dans les tubes de pollen en croissance. Un premier phénoméne, observé il    y a une décennie, est l'oscillation dans le temps de la vitesse de croissance    ainsi que de la concentration de calcium et de l'épaisseur de la paroie    cellulaire d'un tube pollinique. Bien que les interactions entre toutes les composantes    du tube pollinique sont complexes, nous avont démontré que quelles    composantes, lorsque couplées de maniére adéquate, produisent    l'oscillation stable observée en laboratoire.La c</description><description>The growth of walled cells is due to the cooperation of physical and chemical    mechanisms leading to the controlled mechanical deformation of the cells. Plant cells, for    example, need to expand the surface area of their cell wall in order to grow in size. This can be    done in a uniform manner called diffusive growth or through tip-growth. Tip-growth is    characterised by a mechanical deformation that is confined to a specific region of the cell wall,    namely its tip. Tip-growth generally leads to tubular cell wall shapes and has been observed in    plant cells such as pollen tubes and root hairs but also in fungal hyphae, algae and neuronal    growth cones. The pollen tube is a protuberance growing on the pollen grain. As part of plant    fertilisation, its purpose is to extend until it reaches the ovule of a host plant and allow for    the passage of a sperm cell contained in the pollen grain. This thesis studies how physical    principles direct and control the tip-growth of a pollen tube. The three particular phenomena    that were addressed concern the effects of elastic forces and short-range electrical potentials    on ion diffusion, actin protein aggregation and the viscous flow in growing pollen tubes. A very    intriguing phenomenon, observed a decade ago, concerning growing pollen tubes is the oscillation    in time of the growth rate, the concentration of signalling molecules such as calcium and the    thickness of the cell wall. While the total interaction of the components of such a complex    system is hard to asses, I show that a few key elements, when coupled adequately, lead to the    steady oscillation similar to that observed experimentally. The growing cell was modelled as a    fluid finger in the viscous regime with elastic properties depending on the material delivery to    the growing region. The difference between the material delivered and the material required for    growth led to the stable oscillation of the growth rate. A se</description><creator>Kroeger, Jens</creator><contributor>Martin Grant (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Anja Geitmann (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Physics - General</subject><title>Diffusion and flow in growing pollen tubes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237hs81p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999762t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h5394</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There is a growing recognition among many who work with society's most    disadvantaged cultural groups that cultural identity might be a primary issue related to their    psychological adjustment. From his experience with Aboriginal peoples in Canada and inner city    African American communities in the United States, Taylor (1997, 2002) theorizes that without a    clear cultural identity, a person has no normative template with which to construct a clear    personal identity, and by extension, to achieve positive self-esteem and well-being. The program    of research I describe in the present thesis represents the first attempt to empirically    investigate the extent to which the clarity of an individual's cultural identity is predictive of    their experience of personal self-esteem and psychological well-being. In Manuscript 1, I present    a series of studies that were conducted with undergraduate students, Anglophone Quebecers,    Francophone Québécois, Chinese North Americans, and Aboriginal Canadians. In these five studies,    the results demonstrate consistently positive associations among cultural identity clarity,    personal identity clarity, and self-esteem and markers of subjective well-being. Beyond this, the    results confirm that personal identity clarity mediates the relationship between cultural    identity clarity and both self-esteem and well-being in all cultural groups. Having clear and    confident beliefs about one's cultural group is associated with having clear and confident    beliefs about one's personal self, which in turn predicts markers of psychological adjustment. In    Manuscript 2, I explore the causal direction of the relationship between cultural identity    clarity and self-esteem and well-being. A novel methodology involving computer-mediated    communication is used to manipulate cultural identity clarity in a laboratory context. In two    experiments, negotiating a computer-mediated social interaction with a clear cul</description><description>Parmi les chercheurs et les professionnels qui travaillent avec    les membres des groupes sociaux les plus désavantagés, il existe un consensus grandissant :    l'identité culturelle est au cœur de l'ajustement psychologique. Inspiré par ses expériences avec    les groupes Autochtones du Canada et par celles avec les Afro-Américains aux États-Unis, Taylor    (1997, 2002) a proposé une nouvelle théorie de l'identité. Cette théorie stipule que sans une    identité culturelle claire, il est impossible de posséder les assises normatives nécessaires à la    construction d'une identité personnelle claire. Ainsi, posséder une identité culturelle claire    est ce qui permet aux individus d'acquérir une estime de soi positive ainsi qu'un niveau de    bien-être psychologique élevé. Dans le programme de recherche mit de l'avant par la présente    thèse, je propose d'étudier empiriquement, et pour la première fois, le lien prédictif entre la    clarté de l'identité culturelle, l'estime de soi et le bien-être psychologique. Dans le premier    manuscrit, je présente une série d'études qui ont été effectuées auprès de différentes    populations, soit des étudiants universitaires de premier cycle, des Québécois anglophones, des    Québécois francophones, des Nord-Américains de descendance chinoise et finalement, des Canadiens    autochtones. Dans ces cinq études, les résultats démontrent que la clarté de l'identité    culturelle est positivement associée à la clarté de l'identité personnelle, à l'estime de soi, et    aux différentes mesures de bien-être psychologique. Par ailleurs, les résultats obtenus    confirment le rôle médiateur de la clarté de l'identité personnelle entre la clarté de l'identité    culturelle et 1) l'estime de soi et 2) le bien-être psychologique. Ainsi, posséder des croyances    claires à propos de son groupe culturel permet de posséder des croyances claires à propos de soi,    ce qui$</description><creator>Usborne, Esther</creator><contributor>Donald M Taylor (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Psychology - Social</subject><title>The primary role of cultural identity clarity for self-esteem and psychological well-being</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c146x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h5394</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m613mz40d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La perception visuelle d'un objet mène souvent à la formation de    sa représentation dans la mémoire. Dans ce cas, le rôle de la perception visuelle est importante,    mais il demeure possible que la mémoire est impliquée dans le traitement d'un stimulus visuel    d'une manière descendante. Une façon d'étudier l'influence de la mémoire sur la perception    visuelle est d'utiliser la méthode d'adaptation sélective conçue pour produire des effets    consécutifs. Lors d'une expérience d'adaptation sélective typique, un stimulus est présenté pour    une période prolongée (stimulus d'adaptation) et ceci mène à une distorsion temporaire de la    perception des stimuli subséquents (effets consécutifs). La méthode d'adaptation sélective est    surtout utilisée pour élucider au niveau du comportement les mécanismes neuronnes impliqués dans    le traitement du stimulus d'adaptation. Cependant, c'est aussi un outil utile pour étudier les    influences possibles du procesus de la mémoire sur la perception visuelle. Ceci mène à    l'hypothèse que des stimuli d'adaptation avec des effets mnémoniques différents et similaires    devraient produire des effets consécutifs différents et similaires, respectivement. Les résultats    de cette thèse montrent que le traitement visuel de la motion et des visages, qui implique des    régions spécialisées du cortex visuel, est soumis à l'influence mnémonique.</description><description>Perceiving a visual object often leads to the formation of its representation in    memory. In this case, the role of visual perception in memory is emphasized, but it is also    conceivable that memory plays a role in the processing of a visual stimulus in a top-down manner.    One way to study whether memory does influence visual perception is to make use of the selective    adaptation method designed to produce aftereffects. In a typical selective adaptation experiment,    a stimulus is presented for an extended period of time (adapting stimulus) and this results in a    temporary distortion in the perception of subsequent stimuli (aftereffects). The selective    adaptation method has mainly been used to behaviorally elucidate neural mechanisms involved in    the processing of the adapting stimulus. However, it also is a useful tool to study possible    influences of memory processes on visual perception, because it leads to the hypothesis that    adapting stimuli with different and similar mnemonic contents should produce different and    similar visual aftereffects, respectively. Results described in the current thesis show that    visual processing of motion and faces, both believed to recruit specialized areas in the visual    cortex are subject to mnemonic influences.</description><creator>Ryu, Jae-Jin</creator><contributor>Avijit Chaudhuri (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Psychology - Behavioral</subject><title>Mnemonic influences on perception as revealed by visual aftereffects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rm28h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m613mz40d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21tg29c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Drug development is a time-consuming, expensive area of research that requires   the collaboration of different fields of expertise. In this context, computer-aided methods have   the potential to critically shorten the times and monetary expense required for preclinical   development. Very early in a drug discovery effort, docking programs are used to virtually screen   large libraries of compounds searching for a lead compound that can be developed into an   efficient and safe drug. One of the critical components of a docking program is the one providing   an estimate of the binding affinity of the formed complex: the scoring function. The central goal   of this work was to develop methods to predict the binding affinity of potential drugs for   application in virtual screening campaigns. Towards this goal, we first examined the current   status of docking programs and scoring functions applied to a metalloprotein target relevant for   medicinal chemistry, Golgi α-mannosidase II. This triggered a more in-depth analysis of scoring   functions, which led us to assemble a set of protein complexes and analyze the performance of   different available scoring functions in flexible and solvated proteins. We then set out to   develop a scoring function based on molecular mechanical force fields and additional parameters   accounting for entropic costs and solvation. We also reached into the development of molecules   binding to nucleic acids by developing a hybrid docking/molecular dynamics method to study   transition metal complexes binding to G-quadruplexes. Our docking program, FITTED, was prepared   for the application to virtual screening campaigns with the implementation of the developed   scoring functions and the development of additional tools to manipulate, select and prepare large   libraries of ligands. With this goal, we developed a module for FITTED, termed SMART, to prepare   ligands prior to the docking. The core of SMART was used to build two other modules, REACTOR and   SELECT, that have applications in the preparation and clustering, respectively, of virtual   libraries of ligands.</description><description>Le développement de médicaments est un domaine de recherche   exigeant une quantité considerable de financement et de temps, ainsi que la collaboration étroite   de spécialistes dans diverses disciplines des sciences de la vie. Dans ce contexte, les méthodes   assistées par ordinateur ont le potentiel d'améliorer la situation. Par exemple, des programmes   de docking moléculaire sont souvent utilisés pour faire des criblages virtuels sur de grandes   bibliothèques de molécules, à la recherche de candidats qui peuvent être convertis en médicaments   efficaces et sécuritaires. L'une des composantes critiques d'un programme de docking est celui   chargé de faire l'évaluation de l'affinité du complexe formé entre le ligand et la cible: la   fonction de score. L'objectif central de ce travail est d'étudier des méthodes pour estimer   l'affinité de médicaments potentiels pour des biopolymères, avec l'intention de les utiliser pour   le criblage virtuel. Nous avons tout d'abord examiné la performance des fonctions de score   appliquées à une métalloprotéine importante pour le développement de médicaments, la   α-mannosidase II du Golgi. Ensuite, nous avons approfondi cette analyse en sélectionant un groupe   de complexes de protéines qui a été utilisé pour prédire leur affinité tout en considérant la   flexibilité conformationelle et le solvant. Nous avons ensuite développé une fonction de score   sur la base des calculs de mécanique moléculaire et de paramètres additionnels prenant en compte   l'entropie et la solvatation. De plus, nous avons étudié des molécules que interagissent avec des   acides nucléiques en développant une méthode hybride de docking/dynamique moléculaire pour   l'étude des complexes de métaux de transition avec des G-quadruplexes. Notre programme de   docking, FITTED, a été modifié pour entreprendre des études de criblages virtuels avec les   nouvelles fonctions de score et le développement de nouveaux outils pour la manipulation,   sélection et préparation de grandes bibliothèques de molécules. À cet effet, nous avons préparé   les programmes SMART, pour préparer les ligands avant le docking, et REACTOR et SELECT, qui   peuvent préparer et filtrer, respectivement, des bibliothèques virtuelles. </description><creator>Englebienne, Pablo</creator><contributor>Nicolas Moitessier (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Chemistry - Organic</subject><title>Development and application of computational methods for the design of bioactive molecules</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Pablo Englebienne, 2009</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9p290b39d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21tg29c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f2142</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>CEACAM1 (CarcinoEmbryonic Antigen-related Cell Adhesion Molecule    1) est exprimé à la surface de nouveaux vaisseaux sanguins de tissus en prolifération ou de    tumeurs humaines, et est associé aux stades précoces de l'angiogenèse. De plus, CEACAM1 semble    être un puissant facteur angiogénique en potentialisant l'activité du VEGF in vivo. Malgré de    nombreuses observations, le rôle de CEACAM1 dans l'angiogenèse normale reste à définir. Dans ce    contexte, nous avons réalisé des essais de cicatrisation cutanée dans des souris Ceacam1-/-. Des    plaies de 6 mm ont été effectuées sur le dos des souris. La vitesse de cicatrisation a été suivie    sur 10 jours, et les plaies ont été examinées en histologie 3, 7 et 10 jours après l'essai. D'un    point de vue macroscopique, la délétion de CEACAM1 n'a pas d'effet sur la cicatrisation des    plaies. En revanche, des analyses plus précises en histologie montrent que la cicatrisation des    souris Ceacam1 -/- est différée. En effet, le mécanisme de re-épithélisation des plaies des    souris Ceacam1 -/- est retardé aux points 3 et 7 jours après blessure. De plus, l'inflammation    des plaies des souris Ceacam1 -/- est également affectée : l'infiltration des macrophages F4/80+    au sein des plaies 7 et 10 jours après blessure, ainsi que celle des mastocytes au point 7 jours    après blessure sont significativement diminuées. Enfin, la densité vasculaire des plaies    Ceacam1-/- est également réduite de façon significative. En revanche, l'expression de VEGF au    sein des plaies ne semble pas altérée. Les résultats de cette étude confirment le rôle de CEACAM1    dans l'angiogenèse, mais présentent de façon plus importante CEACAM1 comme un facteur clé dans le    mécanisme de cicatrisation des plaies cutanées.</description><description>CEACAM1 (CarcinoEmbryonic Antigen-related Cell Adhesion Molecule 1), is    expressed at the surface of new blood vessels of tissues undergoing proliferation. In human    tumors, CEACAM1 expression is associated with early stages of angiogenesis. CEACAM1 is a known    pro-angiogenic factor, increasing VEGF activity in vivo; however, the role of CEACAM1 in    angiogenesis warrants further investigation. Excisional wounds were used as an experimental    model, as many of the processes that occur in healing wounds also take place in tumor growth -    epithelial hyperproliferation, inflammation, and angiogenesis. 6-mm diameter skin wounds were    inflicted on the dorsal side of Ceacam1-/- and wild-type mice. Upon histological examination, it    was shown that wound healing in Ceacam1-/- mice is indeed delayed. In Ceacam1-/- wounds,    re-epithelialization is decreased significantly at 3 and 7 days post-injury. Inflammation in    Ceacam1-/- wounds is also altered: the infiltration of F4/80+ macrophages into the wound at 7 and    10 days post-injury is significantly decreased, as is the influx of mast cells at 7 days    post-injury. Vascular density in Ceacam1-/- wounds is also significantly decreased at 7 and 10    days post-injury; however, VEGF expression in the wound is not altered. The results of this study    not only confirm CEACAM1's role as an important factor in angiogenesis, but further expand its    role as a mediator of epithelial growth and inflammation.</description><creator>LeBlanc, Sarah</creator><contributor>Nicole Beauchemin (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Cell</subject><title>CEACAM1 deficiency delays cutaneous wound healing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6w924c73p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f2142</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6108vc33h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>La progranuline est un facteur de croissance sécrété de haut poids    moléculaire. Tandis qu' une sur-expression inappropriée du gène codant la progranuline est    observé dans de nombreux cancers de différentes origines, l'haploinsuffisance, quant à    elle, est responsable de l'atrophie des lobes fronto-temporaux et du développement    d'une forme de démence (FTLD-U). Nous avons démontré que la progranuline est exprimée    abondamment dans les neurones moteurs murins in vivo et in vitro dans un modèle de culture    primaire. La localisation subcellulaire de la progranuline a été examinée en microscopie    confocale par immunofluorescence indirecte et confirmé par l'étude de la distribution    subcellulaire d'une progranuline marquée a la eGFP. La progranuline se distribue ainsi    le long des voies de secrétions. La surexpression de gène humain de la progranuline dans les    cellules NSC34 stimule l'apparition de structures dendritiques et protège contre la mort    cellulaire induite par la carence en sérum du milieu tandis que les cellules ne surexprimant pas    la progranuline demeurent sensibles à ce stimulus. En conclusion, ce travail souligne    l'importance de la progranuline comme facteur de croissance neuroprotecteur et peut    représenter une cible thérapeutique de choix pour les maladies    neurodégénératives.</description><description>Progranulin is a secreted high molecular weight growth factor. While    inappropriate over-expression of the progranulin gene has been associated with many cancers,    haploinsufficiency leads to atrophy of the frontotemporal lobes and development of a form of    dementia (FTLD-U). We have demonstrated that progranulin is abundantly expressed in mouse motor    neurons in vivo and primary cultures in vitro. The cellular location of progranulin was examined    using confocal microscopy. Progranulin was localised to organelles using immunocytochemistry and    by examining the intracellular fate of exogenously expressed flu orescently-labelled progranulin.    Taken together these studies revealed progranulin to be located within compartments of the    secretory pathway. Stable transfection of the human progranulin gene into the NSC-34 cell line    stimulates the appearance of dendritic structures and provides protection against apoptosis.    Control cells, while expressing basal levels of progranulin do not survive in serum free    conditions. This work highlights the importance of progranulin as a neuroprotective growth factor    and may represent a therapeutic target for neurodegenerative diseases including FTLD-U and    ALS.</description><creator>Ryan, Cara</creator><contributor>Hugh P J Bennett (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Cell</subject><title>Progranulin is expressed within motor neurons, promotes neuronal cell survival, and is secreted at least in part via the constitutive secretory pathway</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tb09j655b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6108vc33h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v631f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Watershed Evaluation of Beneficial Management Practices (WEB's) project is    funded by Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada (AAFC). This study addresses the issue of non-point    source agricultural pollution in the Bras d'Henri sub-watershed. It estimates the economic impact    on the farm of an increased environmental constraint and the environmental and economic    performance of Best Management Practices (BMPs) to satisfy this environmental constraint. The    model's objective was to maximize net farm income subject to an environmental constraint, farm    characteristics, and animal nutrient requirements. Results indicate that increasing the pollution    emission constraint: (1) Reduces agricultural non-point source (NPS) pollution, (2) forces    cropping patterns and farming practices to change, (3) reduces profit, and (4) induces average    abatement cost and marginal abatement cost to increase at an increasing rate. Also, with    comparable environmental constraints, farms are economically better off when the environmental    constraint was set at the watershed scale as opposed to being set at the farm    scale.</description><description>Le projet d'Évaluation des pratiques de gestions bénéfique à    l'échelle du basin versant (EBB) est financé par Agriculture Canada (AAAC). Cette étude met    l'emphase sur la problématique de pollution diffuse agricole présente dans le sous-bassin versant    du Bras d'Henri. Cette étude fait l'estimation de l'impact à la ferme d'une contrainte    environnementale croissante et de la performance environnementale et économique des Pratiques de    Gestions Bénéfiques (PGB) pour satisfaire une contrainte environnementale. Les objectifs du model    était de maximiser les revenus nets agricoles en ce conformant à une contrainte environnemental,    à l'utilisation unique des champs, et au respect des besoins nutritionnels des animaux. Les    résultats indiquent que la présence d'une contrainte environnementale croissante : (1) réduit    l'émission de pollution diffuse agricole, (2) force les habitudes de production à changer, (3)    réduit les revenus nets agricole, et (4) fait en sorte que les coûts moyens d'abattement et les    coûts marginaux d'abattement augmentent et accélèrent. De plus, soumis à des contraintes    environnementales similaires, les fermes sont économiquement gagnantes lorsque la contrainte    environnemental est fixée à l'échelle de du bassin versant contrairement à une contrainte    environnementale fixée à l'échelle de la ferme.</description><creator>Rivest, Sébastien</creator><contributor>Paul Thomassin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</subject><title>Watershed evaluation of beneficial management practices: the Bras d'Henri watershed-on-farm economics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gp23t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v631f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2227mq790</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Des aspects fondamentaux sur la chimie surfacique des minéraux    carbonatés dans des solutions aqueuses ont été examinés par des approches expérimentales et    théoriques ainsi que par des méthodes d'optimisation numérique et de modélisation moléculaire.Un    algorithme génétique (GA, selon son sigle anglais) a été implémenté et testé pour la calibration    de modèles de complexation à la surface (SCMs, selon son sigle anglais). Le GA peut optimiser de    façon stochastique et simultanée des nombreux paramètres tout en minimisant des problèmes de    convergence ou de stabilité numérique. Cet algorithme est très avantageux par rapport aux    techniques déterministiques conventionnelles adoptées par des codes d'optimisation de constantes    d'équilibre tel que FITEQL. Le GA a donc été utilisé de façon routinière dans cette étude, pour    estimer les constantes de formation des espèces chimiques se formant à la surface des minéraux    carbonatés. En utilisant la calcite comme modèle, nous avons réévalué de façon critique la    définition de sites réactifs à la surface hydratée des minéraux carbonatés rhomboédriques. Ceci    nous a permis de définir un site d'adsorption générique neutre pour ce type de minéraux, qui est    compatible avec les résultats d'études théoriques et expérimentales ainsi qu'avec des hypothèses    associées à la formulation de SCMs. Des nouvelles réactions, basées sur un seul site générique,    ont été formulées pour la magnésite et dolomite et calibrées en utilisant des données publiées de    charge surfacique et, par la suite, testées avec des données électrocinétiques et    spectroscopiques disponibles dans la littérature.Le comportement acide-base à la surface de la    gaspéite (NiCO3(s)), dans des solutions de NaCl, à été examiné par des techniques    conventionnelles de titrage surfacique et par la micro-électrophorèse. Nous avons trouvé que    l'él</description><description>Fundamental aspects of the surface chemistry of calcite, dolomite, magnesite,    and gaspeite in aqueous solutions were examined using different lines of investigation including    experimental, theoretical, and/or computer-assisted modeling approaches (i.e., ab initio    molecular and surface complexation modeling). A Genetic Algorithm (GA) was implemented and tested    for the calibration of surface complexation models (SCMs). The GA can successfully optimize    numerous adjustable SCM parameters without incurring convergence problems while minimizing    numerical instability problems, a notable advantage over conventional deterministic,    root-finding, and optimization techniques implemented in codes such as FITEQL. It was routinely    used throughout this thesis for the simultaneous calibration of surface complexation parameters    (e.g., intrinsic constants, capacitances) at carbonate surfaces. The definition of reactive    surface sites at hydrated rhombohedral carbonate mineral surfaces was critically revisited. Using    calcite as the model mineral, a single generic charge-neutral surface site scheme was proposed    for the formulation of surface equilibria. The resulting molecular representation of surface    equilibria is consistent with experimental and theoretical findings and is compatible with    assumptions implicit in SCMs. Based upon the one-site scheme, new and simplified SCMs for    magnesite and dolomite were formulated. These successfully reproduced published surface charge    and electrokinetic data while yielding surface speciation predictions consistent with available    spectroscopic data. The acid-base behavior of the gaspeite (NiCO3(s)) surface in NaCl solutions    was investigated for the first time by means of conventional titration techniques and    micro-electrophoresis. Surface protonation and the electrophoretic mobility of gaspeite are    strongly affected by the background electrolyte. Acid-base surface complexation reactions,</description><creator>Villegas-Jiménez, Adrián</creator><contributor>Alfonso Mucci (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Jeanne Paquette (Internal/Cosupervisor2)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Earth Sciences - Geochemistry</subject><title>On the surface chemistry of some rhombohedral carbonate minerals in aqueous solutions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k3505.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2227mq790</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:08612p56n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Canada's oil sand industry produces substantial quantities of oil sands    process-affected material (OSPM) including composite tailings (CT) and tailings sands (TS) that    need to be reclaimed on site. This work evaluated the establishment of a pioneer plant species,    alder, inoculated with a nitrogen-fixing actinomycete, Frankia. The main objectives were to    evaluate alder performance in OSPM and its impact on soil characteristics and microbial community    structure and function. This project was divided into two phases: a field study and a greenhouse    trial. The greenhouse trial tested 2 alder species, Alnus glutinosa and A. crispa, in CT and TS.    In addition to Frankia inoculation, a tripartite association with a mycorrhizal fungus, Glomus    intraradices was evaluated. The field study consisted of a 2 year monitoring of    Frankia-inoculated alders (A. crispa (Ait.) Pursh.) planted in TS capped with overburden material    and peat moss. The parameters tested were the following: plant biomass and nitrogen content; soil    chemical characteristics; microbial biomass; microbial petroleum hydrocarbon mineralization    capability; and microbial community diversity and composition using the molecular techniques, PCR    and DGGE. Alders performed well in OSPM and Frankia inoculation improved biomass acquisition.    Frankia-alders improved a number of soil quality parameters such as pH, sodium content, and CEC.    Frankia-alders presence modified soil microbial activity and diversity. Alder rhizosphere    sustained more microbial biomass than unplanted soil, whereas the tripartite association did not    provide additional benefits. Overall, Frankia-inoculated alders are an interesting    biotechnological approach for the reclamation and revegetation of oil sand process-affected    materials. Abbreviation: PCR (polymerase chain reaction), DGGE (Denaturating Gradient Gel    Electrophoresis), CEC (Cation Exchange Capacity), TS (Tailings Sands), CT (Composite</description><description>L'exploitation des sables bitumineux d'Alberta par les compagnies    pétrolières entraîne une importante production de matières résiduelles de sable bitumineux    (MRSB). Ces MRSB, incluant les résidus de sable (RS) et les résidus composites ou consolidés    (RC), doivent être réhabilités à même les sites d'exploitation. Ce projet a évalué l'utilisation    d'une espèce pionnière, l'aulne, inoculée avec un actinomycète fixant l'azote, Frankia, pour la    végétalisation de ces résidus. Les objectifs principaux étaient d'évaluer la performance des    aulnes dans les MRSB et leurs impacts sur les caractéristiques du sol et ses communautés    microbiennes. Le projet a été divisé en 2 volets : un essai sur le site minier et un essai en    serre. L'essai en serre a évalué 2 espèces d'aulne, Alnus glutinosa et A. crispa, dans les RS et    les RC. En plus de l'inoculation avec Frankia, une association tripartite avec un champignon    mycorrhizien, Glomus intraradices, a été évaluée. L'essai sur le site minier a consisté en un    suivi sur 2 ans d'aulnes (A. crispa (Ait.) Pursh.), inoculés avec Frankia, plantés dans des RS    recouverts de morts-terrain et de mousse de tourbe. Les paramètres suivants ont été évalués : la    biomasse et le contenu en azote des aulnes, les caractéristiques chimiques du sol, la biomasse    microbienne, la capacité microbienne de minéralisation d'hydrocarbures pétroliers et, à l'aide de    technique de biologie moléculaire (PCR et DGGE), la diversité et la composition des communautés    microbiennes. Les aulnes ont bien performés dans les MRSB et l'inoculation avec Frankia a    entraîné un important gain en biomasse. Les aulnes inoculés avec Frankia ont entraîné    l'amélioration de plusieurs caractéristiques du sol, dont le pH, la CEC, et le contenu en sodium.    Ils ont aussi modifié l'activité et la diversité des communautés microbiennes du sol. La    rhizosphère des aulnes a$</description><creator>Lefrançois, Elisabeth</creator><contributor>Lyle Whyte (Supervisor2)</contributor><contributor>Charles William Greer (Supervisor1)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Microbiology</subject><title>Revegetation and reclamation of oil sands process-affected material using «Frankia»-inocculated alders: field and greenhouse trials</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021g177.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612p56n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s111k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Translation of an mRNA begins with the recruitment of the eIF4F complex to the    5' cap of the mRNA and is completed upon start codon recognition by the preinitiation complex.    Regulation of translation initiation is a major mechanism for the control of gene expression. The    focus of this thesis is human 4EHP (h4EHP), a homolog of the cap-binding translation initiation    factor eIF4E. 4EHP can bind to the cap structure but cannot initiate cap-dependent translation.    Drosophila 4EHP functions as a translational repressor of specific mRNAs by forming a "closed    loop", in which the binding partners of 4EHP determine the mRNA specificity. This study sought to    investigate the function of h4EHP by identifying its interacting proteins. In total, three novel    binding proteins of h4EHP have been identified: PERQ1, PERQ2, and eIF4E-Transporter (4E-T). All    these proteins utilize a similar motif for h4EHP-binding. Experiments demonstrate that    h4EHP:PERQ1/2 complexes are involved in translational repression. In addition, this study shows    that the protein levels of PERQ1, PERQ2 and h4EHP are co-regulated. Among them, PERQ2 undergoes    CUL7-mediated degradation upon h4EHP depletion. 4E-T has been shown to be involved in    translational repression, eIF4E nuclear import, P-body formation and mRNA turnover. This study    demonstrates that h4EHP can be localized to the nucleus. However, its nuclear localization is not    affected by 4E-T depletion. The depletion of h4EHP results in a six-fold increase in the number    of P-bodies but has no effect on the rate of turnover of a reporter mRNA. In conclusion, this    study identifies PERQ1 and PERQ2 as two translational repressors; their function and stability    are dependent on h4EHP. The function of h4EHP:4E-T interaction, however, remains elusive.</description><description>La traduction d'un ARNm commence par le recrutement du complexe    eIF4F au niveau de la coiffe (ou cap) en 5' de l'ARNm et se complète lors de la reconnaissance du    codon d'initiation par le complexe de pré-initiation. La régulation de l'initiation de la    traduction est une étape majeure dans le contrôle de l'expression génique. Cette thèse    s'intéresse à la protéine humaine 4EHP (h4EHP), un homologue du facteur d'initiation de la    traduction se liant à la coiffe, eIF4E. 4EHP peut d'ailleurs s'associer à la coiffe de l'ARNm    mais ne peut initier la traduction dépendante de la coiffe. L'homologue chez la drosophile,    d4EHP, est un inhibiteur de la traduction de certain ARNm et agit en formant une boucle 5'-3'    avec l'ARNm. Les partenaires protéiques de 4EHP définissent alors la spécificité pour l'ARNm.    Cette thèse s'intéresse à la fonction de h4EHP en recherchant ses partenaires protéiques. Les    trois nouveaux partenaires identifiés (PERQ1, PERQ2 et 4E-T) utilisent un même motif de liaison à    h4EHP. Mes expériences démontrent non seulement, que les complexes h4EHP:PERQ1/2 sont impliqués    dans la répression de la traduction, mais aussi qu'il existe une co-régulation des niveaux    relatifs des protéines h4EHP, PERQ1 et PERQ2. Ce dernier est d'ailleurs dégradé par CUL7 après la    déplétion de h4EHP. La protéine 4E-T est connu pour son rôle dans l'inhibition de la traduction,    l'import nucléaire d'eIF4E, la formation des « P-Bodies » et le renouvellement des ARNm. Cette    étude démontre que h4EHP a une localisation nucléaire et indépendante de 4E-T. La suppression de    4E-T augmente cependant de six fois le nombre de « P-Bodies », sans pour autant affecter le taux    de renouvellement d'un ARNm reporteur. En conclusion, cette étude identifie PERQ1 et PERQ2 comme    deux inhibiteurs de la traduction dont la fonction et la stabilité sont dépendantes de h4EHP.    Cependant, le rôle de l'inter</description><creator>Ler, Lian Wee</creator><contributor>Nahum Sonenberg (Internal/Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Biology - Molecular</subject><title>Identification and characterization of novel mammalian eIF4E-Homologous Protein (4EHP) interacting proteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1c18dg662.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s111k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zs25x9505</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T02:58:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Two sites, situated approximately 60 kilometers apart in southern Quebec, were    studied to determine what nutrients were most limiting and to compare growth variation on    microsite (3-9m) and landscape scales (100-1000m). One site was found to be 20% more productive    than the other growing at 6.9 m3 ha-1 in its fifth year of growth. Principal component analysis    found no nutrients to be limiting at the more productive site while the other site appeared to be    N and K limited. Microsite scale variation was found to be at least as important as landscape    scale variation in explaining measures of productivity in most cases. Potential problems posed by    microsite scale variation could be addressed using an indicator species analysis. Empirical    distribution function analysis revealed that some species present in hybrid poplar plantations    (e.g. Fragaria spp. and Polytrichum spp.) may be good indicators of low and high productivity    sites respectively.</description><description>Deux sites de plantations situés approximativement 60 kilomètres    l'un de l'autre ont été étudiés afin de déterminer quels nutriments était les plus limitants et    de comparer la variance à l'échelle de 3-9m (microsite) à la variance à l'échelle de 100-1000m.    Un site était 20% plus productif que l'autre avec un taux de croissane de 6.9 m3 ha-1 dans ça    cinquième année. L'analyse de la composante principale a dévoilé que aucun des nutriments n'était    limitant tandis qu'à l'autre site le N et la K parassait être limitants. La variance à l'échelle    3-9m semble être au moins aussi importante que la variance à l'échelle 100-1000m dans son    explication des mesures de productivité, dans la majorité des cas. Le potentiel de problèmes    rencontrés dans l'échelle de variation des microsites peut être expliqué en se servant d'une    analyse d'espèces indicatrices. L'analyse de la fonction de distribution empirique a révèlé que    certaines espèces présentes dans les plantations de peupliers hybrides (e.g. Fragaria spp. et    Polytrichum spp.) pourraient être de bons indicateurs de sites à productivité élevé ou    basse.</description><creator>Labrecque, Jeremy</creator><contributor>James W Fyles (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2009</date><subject>Health And Environmental Sciences - Environmental Sciences</subject><title>Indicator species of soil nutrients and poplar plantation productivity in southeastern Quebec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62f9265.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25x9505</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):22750</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>