<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:28:10Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):9900" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:736667770</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Waite-Amulet property consists of 3,967 acres in Dufresnoy and Duprat townships, northwestern Quebec. It lies approximately six miles northwest of the Horne mine of Noranda Mines Limited at Noranda, Quebec. [...] The copper-zinc-gold-silver ores are obtained at present from the Waite section, the former Waite-Ackerman- Montgomery mine. [...] A large body of similar ore is being developed in the Amulet section. This is the Amulet lower A ore-body which was disclosed by diamond drilling during the spring of 1938. During the summer of 1939 that part of the property lying between F shaft (Amulet section) and the property boundary about one mile to the west was mapped by the writer on a scale of lOO feet equals 1 inch. [...] This half-mile wide strip includes two of the four dalmatianite areas which are found on the Waite-Amulet property. Thin sections made from a representative suite of specimens of rock gathered from this area were studied and compared with a similar suite of specimens from the Amulet lower A ore-body and from the Waite ore-body. Similarities and differences in the rocks of the three localities were noted. Few definite conclusions could be reached because of the limited amount of study possible. It is hoped, however, that the material presented will be of some service in arriving at a more complete understanding of the processes of ore-deposition in this area. [...]</description><creator>Bray, Richard Charles Elliott.</creator><contributor>Osborne, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>A comparison of the non-opaque minerals of certain parts of the Waite-Amulet area, Quebec. --.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784p642.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/736667770</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rb68xf838</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Our knowledge of the fundamental mechanisms of gastric secretion is still incomplete. The cells which secrete acid or pepsin have been identified, but the secretory process is as yet unknown. Fortunately, certain of the factors which influence gastric secretion are known, and this knowledge enables us to control our experimental procedures so that standards of gastric secretion may be obtained. Pavlov described his gastric pouch as a mirror of the main stomach. It is no less true that many bodily states are mirrored and reflected by the gastro-intestinal tract, especially the stomach. This would justify a study of the relationship between the stomach and some other organ or gland which controls some aspect of the internal environment of the body. Such a study might not only determine the inter-glandular relationship but might give us an insight into the normal functions of the glands by making more conspicuous those subtle differences which are usually obscured.[...] The purpose of this study was to make an investigation of the relationship between the parathyroid and gastric glands and the factors concerned in the production of ulceration of the gastro-intestinal tract. The data to be presented in this thesis represent the results of about 350 experiments and over 6,000 separate analyses. [...]</description><creator>Schiffrin, Milton J.</creator><contributor>Babkin, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1941</date><subject>Peptic ulcer.</subject><title>Relationship between the parathyroid and the gastric glands in the dog : the experimental production of peptic ulcer.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4x51hn383.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rb68xf838</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pn89d9638</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>[...] An institution providing facilities for adults, equivalent to those provided for young men and women in the regular day sessions of a college or university, finds that the way is uncharted. It must obtain and build upon its own experience. Even from the United States, where there are now many such institutions, little help is available in an easily communicable form. Over a period of years the officers of Sir George Williams College had acquired many insights into the peculiar problems of adult students in the evening division of its Faculty of Arts, Science and Commerce, and had evolved administrative practices and instructional methods to meet the situation. They felt, in the fall of 1938, however, that the time had come to make a thorough analysis of the nature of that particular part of its student body and to seek objective answers to such questions as, What are the significant characteristics of evening college students? What factors common to employed adult students have an important influence on their achievement? How can conditions for adult college study be improved? This study was undertaken in an attempt to answer these questions, particularly for Sir George Williams College, but also for the benefit of other institutions of higher learning which offer, or may offer, similar facilities for adults.</description><creator>Sheffield, Edward F., 1912-</creator><contributor>Hughes, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1941</date><subject>Sir George Williams University.</subject><subject>Universities and colleges -- Canada.</subject><subject>Adult education -- Canada.</subject><title>College for employed adults : a survey of the facilities in Canada for the formal college education of employed adults and a study of the characteristics and achievement of undergraduates in the evening division of the Faculty of arts, science and commerce of Sir George Williams College.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vf524.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89d9638</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:02871009k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>"Broadly speaking, the sum-total of the concepts involved in any material phenomenon is a constant (P); and if we simplify or diminish the complexity of the substance or matter units (M) reckoned with, we must correspondingly complicate or increase the behaviour factor (B). That is, since the phenomenon is a function of both M and B, we may write P = f(M,B) and any increase in the complexity of M involves a corresponding simplification in B, and vice versa." {Bridges (Alexander, 1928)} This formula no doubt applies to the concepts concerning any field of investigation at a given time. But, since M and B are both variables, it would seem from a survey of the literature over an extended period that P must necessarily be increasing. So it appears to most biologists interested in relating the problems of genetics with chromosome structure and behaviour. Not only to these people, at close range, does P appear to be increasing, but the rapid advances in the field of investigation are even attracting the attention of those not fundamentally interested in this branch of biology. It is becoming increasingly apparent that the not so long ago "upstart science" of genetics has begun to have important implications in other fields of endeavour, however secure the specialists in those fields may have considered themselves in their self-complacent isolationism. [...]</description><creator>Sparrow, Arnold Hicks, 1914-</creator><contributor>Huskins, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1941</date><subject>Chromosomes.</subject><title>Studies on the chromosome spiralization cycle in trillium.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hx11xh86z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/02871009k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fm193</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A peace-time economy of the capitalist democratic type must undergo an extreme metamorphosis before it may be designated as an efficient war-time economy. This is to be expected, since the ends served by the two economies differ so much. In peace, the economy is judged by the efficiency with which it satisfies consumers' demands over a relatively long period of time; in war, the consumer assumes importance only as a producer or as an active belligerent and the economy is judged by the effectiveness with which the fighting forces are prepared and supplied in as short a time as possible. [...]</description><creator>Stovel, John Archibald.</creator><contributor>Hemmeon, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1941</date><subject>FINANCE</subject><title>A study in war finance.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g803t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fm193</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806309j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Die "Aufzeichnungen des Malta Laurids Brigge" nehmen eine Zentralstellung im Werke Rainer Maria Rilkes ein. Sie zeugen, als persoenliches Bekenntnis, von einer durchgehenden Zusammenfassung dessen, was Rilke als junger Dichter und Gottsucher in Paris erlebte und erlitt. Sie deuten aber in ihren tiefsten Moeglichkeiten schon auf die strahlenden Errungenschaften der Reifejahre hin, die Elegien und die Sonette an Orpheus (1). So kommt es, dass Rilke selbst den Malta als eine "Wasserscheide" in seinem Werk und Leben betrachtete (2), und zwar von solcher Ausgepraegtheit, dass, als er ihn geschrieben hatte, er von der groessten Befuerchtung ueberfallen wurde, er muesse als ein ratios nueberlebender" wieder hinter diesem Buche von neuem sein Leben aufbauen. In ihm hat der fragende, fast verzweifelnde junge Dichter die existentiellen Probleme seiner kuenstlerischen Erlebniswelt b1s in ihre dunkelsten Tiefen verfolgt. Die Gestalt des Malte Laurids Brigge wurde Rilke zum Symbol einer Seelenkrise, einer leidensvollen Metamorphose zum tiefaren Menschen- bezw. Kuenstlertum. Und dieser Verwandlung lag vor allem eine erweiterte Selbsterkenntnis zu Grunde, die Angelloz mit den Worten bezeiohnet hat: "cette découverte de lui-même, cette croisière autour de ses souvenirs, oette plongée dans l'enfer humain" (3). [...]</description><creator>Von Cardinal, Clive Helmut.</creator><contributor>Graff, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1941</date><subject>Rilke, Rainer Maria, 1875-1926.</subject><title>Maltesches in Rilkes vor-Malteschem Werk.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s7926.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806309j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of German</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tp97g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis presents the results of a field examination of a part of the north limb of the Marquette syncline. The oldest rocks of the region are Keewatin volcanics, and Van Rise and Leith consider that they are followed by the Mesnard quartzite, which is Lower Huronian age. The writer has recognized and here proposes the name "Mud Lake" series for the conglomerate, slates and greywackes that are separated from the underlying Keewatin and the overlying Mesnard by unconformities. The Mud Lake series has a stratigraphic position that makes its correlation with the Knife Lake slates, the Sudburian and the Temiskaming series permissible. Otherwise the writer has used the stratigraphic map units shown by Van Hise and Leith in U.S.G.S. Monograph 52, except that the Kona dolomite has been divided into two formations termed the upper and lower. The structural relationships of the north limb are described as well as the lithology and degree of metamorphism of the principle units mapped.</description><creator>Wahl, William George.</creator><contributor>Gill, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1941</date><subject>Geology -- Michigan.</subject><subject>Geology -- Michigan -- Marquette.</subject><title>Geology of a part of the north limb of the Marquette syncline.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r854d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tp97g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j8472</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present thesis is divided into a number of unrelated topics, due mainly to interruptions brought about by the war. The original purpose was to carry out an investigation on the ozonization of unsaturated organic acids with the object of establishing more evidence for possible constitutional relationships between ozonides and peroxides, the latter having been the subject of considerable research in the MeGill University laboratories. This investigation, which was cut short by the advent of war, was launched from two seemingly different points of attack. The first, based on the ozonolysis mechanism advanced by Harries and his coworkers, concerns itself with methods for the quantitative estimation of hydrogen peroxide liberated by the hydrolysis of ozonides in solution. The second, founded on physicochemical principles, deals with the variation of the refractive index during ozonization. Section II is an innovation when compared with dissertations presented under more normal conditions. It is the material compiled for a fourth year Honours course in Chemistry. This section has one part on the analytical testing of explosives to which particular attention is drawn in that it has been dealt with much more fully in accordance with its significance and importance to Honours Chemistry students at this time. The third section is the presentation of the results of a study of the characteristics of mink oil. The final main division may be classed as "War Work,- Secret".</description><creator>Weaver, William Strathern.</creator><contributor>Hatcher, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1941</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The ozonization of unsaturated acids. : A course in industrial organic analysis. The characterization of mink oil. Special research project C.E.40.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nm23m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j8472</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9z903292t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is to be a study of poetic drama from 1900 to 1940 with attention directed to plays that were written for production during the last ten years in particular. The dramas to be considered here are limited to those in the English language; but as they all fall naturally into three groups according to the nation which saw their birth, separate accounts will be given of the genre in England, Ireland and America. For purposes of comparison an historical survey of the beginnings and development of English poetic drama will precede the more detailed evidence presented on this century's output. [...]</description><creator>Whitehead, J. V. Elizabeth.</creator><contributor>Files, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1941</date><subject>ENGLISH DRAMA -- HISTORY AND CRITICISM</subject><title>Twentieth century poetic drama in English.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236526c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9z903292t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kd78n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>During the last few years a considerable quantity of western wheat, which would have been graded as No. 1 Northern, has been graded down to No. 3 or No. 4 Northern because it had a greenish cast. Samples of this wheat have been subjected to milling and baking tests by the Cereal Division of the Central Experimental Farm, Ottawa. There was no relation of greenish cast to quality of flour as indicated by the colour of the flour and the quality of the bread made from the flour. The Division of Chemistry, Department of Agriculture, Ottawa, from 1921-30 carried on several experiments to study the relation of stage of maturity and grade of wheat to its protein and ash content. No marked relationships were revealed. In this thesis are presented the results of a study of the relationship of stage of ripening of wheat to its chlorophyll, carotene and xanthophyll content. A modified method for the determination of chlorophyll and an investigation of the chemical properties of an unidentified brown pigment are also presented.</description><creator>Wood, Charles Rowell.</creator><contributor>McFarlane, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1941</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>A study of pigment metabolism in the wheat kernel during ripening.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816q49r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kd78n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p3363</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Various forms of the hairless condition have been described in a number of mammals, including man. The condition may vary from a slight deficiency to complete lack of hair. In some instances other structures derived from the ectoderm are also defective. Teeth, nails, mammary or sebaceous glands are most commonly affected. The condition has been studied chiefly in rodents, but also in man, certain domestic pets and farm animals. [...]</description><creator>Wright, Annie Mary.</creator><contributor>Huskins, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1941</date><subject>Mice -- Genetics.</subject><title>The expression of rhino, hairless and naked genes in the house mouse.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fx719q28r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p3363</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x439z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In 1885 Gottfried Daimler perfected the four cycle internal combustion engine and a year later he used this type of engine to propel a one cylinder motorcycle. This invention of a practical motor vehicle paved the way for a new phase in transportation history until today the automobile has become an indispensable link in the chain of modern transportation. Although the automobile was used in most countries of the world by 1900, the era of the motor cehivle as a dependable and efficient means of transportation did not begin until the second decade of the 20th century. The period from 1900 to 1919 was one of experimentation, both in the building of roads suitable for motor vehicle traffic and in the manufacture of the automobile itself. Since 1920 improvements in highway surfaces and the perfection of motor vehicle equipment have made the automobile an important cog in both passenger and freight transportation of most countries. [...]</description><creator>Wykes, Neville George.</creator><contributor>Culliton, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1941</date><subject>Roads -- Canada.</subject><subject>Transportation -- Canada.</subject><title>The highway transportation problem in Quebec.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zk51vk998.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x439z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j098zf20k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One of the most valuable constituents of personality is ability to modify behaviour readily and effectively in accordance with changed conditions. That individuals differ greatly in this respect (even though apparently equated from the standpoint of education, occupation, intelligence and socio-economic status) is indicated by the ease with which some individuals shift behaviour to correspond with the requirements of the immediate environment, whereas others fail to adapt or do so only with considerable difficulty. Frequently, failure to modify behaviour is attributed to force of habit or mechanization. On the other hand, in many cases, an examination of an individual's approach and response will show that the behaviour manifested is the result of intelligent assumptions and planning. [...]</description><creator>Ross, Verity Mitchell.</creator><contributor>Luchins, A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1952</date><subject>PSYCHOLOGY -- MENTAL TESTS</subject><subject>PERSONALITY</subject><title>A comparison of the effect of Einstellung in different age groups.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b8515r49d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j098zf20k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr172121n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The scope of economic science in dealing with existing measures of economic policy is confined to judgements, on economic grounds, of how completely and efficiently the measures attain their postulated ends. From this viewpoint, the Canadian Unemployment Insurance Act, 1940, is studied by analogy to similar Acts which exist (or have existed) in Great Britain, Germany, and the United states of America. The ends it desires to attain are carefully deduced from the provisions of the Act, and analysis and analogy, from both the short- and long-run points of view, show how far the Act will be likely to fulfill its aims completely and efficently. On the basis of conclusions reached here certain recommendations are made. The study ends with a final evaluation of the Act as it now exists, and of its place in the Canadian Economy both during and immediately after the war.</description><creator>Graham, Charles R.</creator><contributor>Hemmeon, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Unemployment insurance -- Canada.</subject><title>Unemployment insurance in Canada.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5712m989d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr172121n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8049g8043</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Rickets is a condition made manifest by defects in the calcification of growing bones. The changes in the bones result in outward symptoms which may be recognized clinically, such as, enlargement of the wrists, knees and ankles, bowed legs, and the rachitic rosary. In normal growth of bone, there appears, on the diaphysial side of the narrow cartilage, a continuous layer of empty cartilage cells forming an almost straight line. Growth of the bone is obtained by the degeneration of a new row of cartilage cells and ossification of the former row. In rickets, the degeneration of the cartilage cells ceases and consequently there is no ingrowth of capillaries and ossification cannot occur. Since this cessation of degeneration does not affect all cells at the same time, the epiphysial cartilage, on the diaphysial side, becomes irregular. The prevention and cure of rickets may be brought about by the inclusion of vitamin D in the diet provided calcium and phosphorus are also present in adequate amounts. When vitamin D is fed to rachitic animals, ossification begins again in the empty cartilage cells. A new row of empty cartilage cells will generally appear within twenty-four hours of ingestion of the vitamin. [...]</description><creator>Graham, Walter Donald.</creator><contributor>McFarlane, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>Studies on the determination of vitamin D.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mz59c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g8043</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9019s5603</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The tessellated darters of the genus Boleosoma were first described by Rafinesque who,in 1820,named the Johnny darter Etheostoma nigrum. The type specimen was from the Green River of Kentucky. The species was transferred to the new genus Boleosoma by De Kay in 1842,and thus became Boleosoma nigrum. This and related genera have been grouped together by some taxonomists into the family Etheostomidae,though they are now usually included with other perch-like fishes in the family Percidae. The Johnny darter belongs to a group of fish which is apparently prone to speciation. A glance at the taxonomic history of the darters will clearly show that,with the passage of time,a greater number of species and subspecies are being recognized. Since the purpose or the writer's work is to demonstrate that in Quebec the Johnny darter 1s represented by three races or populations that are separable on the basis of squamation and the number of rays in the soft dorsal fin, it would perhaps be advisable to describe the species nigrum and a few of its subspecies. [...]</description><creator>Hall, Charles Eric.</creator><contributor>Wynne-Edwards, V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Fishes -- Québec (Province) -- Geographical distribution.</subject><subject>Osteichthyes.</subject><title>Geographical variation and distribution of the Johnny darter (Boleosoma nigrum olmstedi) in Quebec.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gm80hz62x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9019s5603</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Zoology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5x21tj44w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The genus Triticum and the genus Avena give rise to many aberrent species. These have been extensively studied genetically, cytologically, and cyto-genetically by many different workers.  They have also had their overt diagnostic aberrancies statistically analysed.  Triticum vulgare gives rise to a mutant which greatly resembles Triticum spelta.  The mutant arises in the heterozygous form and is called a speltoid.  In a similar manner fatuoid oats arise in Avena sativa. [...]</description><creator>Hecht, Maurice.</creator><contributor>Huskins, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Physics.</subject><title>A statistical analysis of speltoid wheat (heights and number of culms).</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s7526g310.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5x21tj44w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v692t940f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>For many years after the death of Henry Fielding, the magnificent achievements of the man as a novelist eclipsed his dramatic works to such an extent that his plays were either totally ignored by critics or summarily dismissed as the worthless scribblings of an indigent hack. Arthur Murphy, Fielding's first official biographer, insisted that: "When he had contracted to bring on a play, or a farce, it is well known by many of his friends now living, that he would go home rather late from a tavern, and would, the next morning, deliver a scene to the players written upon the papers which had wrapped the tobacco, in which he so generally delighted." In spite of the fact that many later critics, notably Thackeray, took this remark to mean that Fielding in his youth was a literary Bohemian, it is now generally agreed that it proves no more than that the man's financial troubles often forced him to write hastily and without much revision. [...]</description><creator>Heller, Mildred.</creator><contributor>Files, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Fielding, Henry, 1707-1754 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>The significance of Henry Fielding’s dramatic works.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52jb948.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v692t940f</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n583xz16k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recently there has developed an increasing realization of the value of intavenous protein as a replacement therapy in the acute plasma loss (M. R. C. 1940) of haemorrhage, (Strumia, Wagner and Monoghan 1940), burns, (Wakeley 1941, Black 1940, Elkington, Wolff and Lee 1940) and crushing injuries, (Trueta 1940), and in the more chronic deficiencies accompanying sepsis and nutritive disturbances. As a result, the demand for human plasma has become greater than the supply. The great value of protein feeding in the overcoming of infection, the protection it affords against liver damage, (Radvin 1940) and the relation of plasma protein level to the healing of wounds have all recently been emphasized by Whipple and his associates, (1940 and 1941). They point out that homologous protein introduced intravenously can supply such deficiencies where it is available in sufficient amounts, (Daft Robscheit, Robbins and Whipple 1938). The problem is how to tap the unlimited reservoir of heterologous plasma obtainable from the larger domestic animals. [...]</description><creator>Henry, James P.</creator><contributor>Meakins, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1942</date><subject>Experiemental Medicine.</subject><title>The effects of irradiation of protein antigenicity.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059cb44q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n583xz16k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mm958</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nous assistons depuis quelques annees en France a un renouvellement d'inter~t a la vie religieuse qui se manifeste par la conversion de nombre d'ecrivains et par des oeuvres dont 1 1 atmosphere est essentiellement religieuse. Un Jammes, un Claudel, un Gheon, et un Le Cardonnel, pour n'en mentionner que quelques-uns, ne sent pas les premiers venus, et temoignent de la diversite de talents qui travaillent a construire la cite mystique des lettres.[...]</description><creator>Branchaud, Mary St. Irene, Sister.</creator><contributor>Du Roure, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>BREMOND, HENRI, 1865-1933</subject><title>Henri Bremond : critique original des mystiques.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43p126q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mm958</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:08612r651</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the course of the cytological studies of cereals conducted in this department it was noticed, in a number of cells, that two or more bivalents were interlocked with each other at meiotic metaphase. The percentage of cells containing such interlocked bivalents is unusually high in the speltoid mutants of wheat (Triticum vulgare Host), unbalanced types having 40 or 42 chromosomes with a homozygous deficiency instead of the usual 42, and resembling Triticum Spelta more than T. vulgare. [...]</description><creator>Boothroyd, Eric Roger.</creator><contributor>Huskins, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Trillium erectum -- Cytology.</subject><title>The interlocking of non-homologous bivalents in Trillium erectum L.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cx15k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612r651</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gp04x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:40Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Research workers on human nutrition have shown the value and importance of fresh vegetables in the diet, especially for their mineral and vitamin content. Of recent years the consumption of such fresh vegetables has greatly increased, which in turn has brought about the necessity of storing vegetables in order to have a continuous supply. Celery is one of the most important stored vegetable crops and at the same time one of the most hazardous to store. In spite or its importance, very little experimental work has been done as yet on vegetable storage problems. Because low temperature is probably the most outstanding means of prolonging life of stored products, commerce has used it extensively and through common experience has come to use methods which yield fair results. However, it is well known to those concerned therein that storage conditions could be improved greatly. Moreover, it is a fact that storage facilities to-day are usually inadequate even in the light of the limited actual knowledge on the matter (Cook, 1935), and it goes without saying that great advances could be made if the storage problems were thoroughly investigated. One way, and probably the most efficient way, of tackling the problem is to find the katabolic activity of the product while in storage.It is with this object in mind that this work was undertaken. In the choice of our techniques effort was mas to avoid overlapping or repeating previous work, but to complete it.</description><creator>Bertrand, Paul.</creator><contributor>Scarth, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Horticulture-Botany.</subject><title>Physiological changes in stored celery.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sw88b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gp04x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Horticulture</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:np193c91m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:41Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It has been found that increase in bursting strength of paper is accompanied by a decrease in the dielectric constant of that paper. This is true whether the strength is increased by pressure on the wet sheet or by beater treatment. Two explanations have been made for this relationship, an increase of fibre-to-fibre bonds and increased flatness of the fibres with increased strength. It has not been possible to separate these two effects. The anisotropy of cellulose as a dielectric has been established and a method devised whereby the axial and transverse values of the dielectric constant of the cellulose fibril could be measured. [...] These results have been interpreted in terms of the relative freedom of groups on the cellulose chain and it has been suggested that absorption and dispersion in cellulose· is probably due to displacement of hydroxyl groups restrained by secondary and coordinate valence forces rather than to rotation of glucose anhydride rings. A dielectric value versus water content curve has been obtained and found to agree with previous measurements. This curve definitely shows that the first water sorbed on cellulose is strongly held and has a low dielectric constant. Attempts to calculate the dielectric constant of the sorbed water from the dielectric values have shown the impossibility of such calculations on the basis of present knowledge.</description><creator>Brown, Douglas Frederick.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The dielectric constants of cellulose and of water sorbed thereon.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w37639974.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/np193c91m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x920g083x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>L'oeuvre de Marcel Proust englobe une série d'éléments aussi divers que l'imagination peut les concevoir. ''A la Recherche du Temps Perdu" est à la fois une sorte d'autobiographie, un roman historique,une analyse psychologique,et un -traité philosophique. Tous ces aspects se combinent et se lient inextricablement dans le héros qui représente l'auteur lui-même. La diversité des sujets,l'originalité et la complexité de sa méthode et de son style présentent un problème littéraire extrêmement difficile à analyser. [...]</description><creator>Beebe, Mary Elizabeth.</creator><contributor>Du Roure, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Proust, Marcel, 1871-1922.</subject><title>Les sources de l’oeuvre de Marcel Proust.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wg65z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920g083x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g158bm360</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:21:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In its development from the unorganized data of Natural History, the youthful science of Ecology has evolved along two rather divergent lines. The first of these, called by Chapman, "Autecology·, deals with some single species of plant or animal 1n relation to its environment or to some restricted part of its environment. This approach has the obv1ous advantage of limiting the field and eliminating many complexities. Its disadvantages l1e in the fact that it tends to over emphasize some isolated part of what ought to be a broad and complexly interrelated structure. The other aspect of Ecology, called ·Synecology' by way of contrast, takes as its material some complete community of organisms, treating it as a whole composed of integrated units, the species present. Such an undertaking is extremely difficult due to the interplay of so many factors, both physical and biotic. It makes use of all of the available information of Autecology and adds to it a vast amount of other data peculiar to its broader outlook. It is this latter aspect of Ecology which must finally establish the major principles of the science. [...]</description><creator>Adams, James Russell.</creator><contributor>Wynne-Edwards, V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Biotic communities.</subject><subject>Ponds.</subject><title>The biotic cycles in northern pond communities.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b647c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g158bm360</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Zoology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):9925</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>