<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:58:14Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2000" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cd04m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The INCO finishing procedure represents the near final stages of copper production at the Copper Cliff Smelter in Sudbury, Ontario, whereby semi-blister copper, at 4--6 wt % Ni and 2--3 wt % S, is processed into blister copper, at 100 ppm S and 0.4 wt % Ni in a modified Pierce-Smith converter combining top-blown oxygen injection and bottom-blown nitrogen stirring of the melt to accelerate semi-blister desulfurization. The procedure is performed in two stages of equal duration: in the first, melt saturation with oxygen and sulfur elimination from 2--3 wt % S to 300 ppm is achieved by 45 minutes of oxygen top-blowing and nitrogen bottom stirring; in the second stage, oxygen injection is terminated and sulfur removal from 300 ppm to 30--100 ppm. proceeds by the ppm to 30--100 ppm proceeds by the reaction of dissolved S and O under a further 45 minutes of nitrogen stirring. Cu-S and Cu-Ni-S alloys were also exposed to the open atmosphere to examine desulfication of stagnant melts under air. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Roumeliotis, Ioannis John.</creator><contributor>Demopoulos, George (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Harris, Ralph (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Desulfurization of INCO semi-blister copper</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1j92g948s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cd04m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149r76c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:42Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Today, great emphasis has been placed on waste produced by the metals industry. Until recently, hydroxide precipitation was considered the ideal choice for handling metallurgical effluents. Metal hydroxides are stored in landfills, although they are not ultimately stable and may redissolve into groundwater with slight changes in pH. An alternative is to adsorb dissolved metals onto stabilized silica sols ("activated silica"), which are colloidal polymers produced by acidifying silicate solutions. Metal-loaded sol may subsequently be desorbed with concentrated acid. The products are a potentially valuable concentrated metal solution and recyclable sol. Dissolved metal adsorption with silica sols was compared with precipitation, either with lime or sodium hydroxide. Optimum adsorption and desorption conditions were determined for cobalt. Dissolved metals separation by selective adsorption was demonstrated for cobalt/copper and cobalt/iron (ferric) combinations. A cadmium ion selective electrode was used to examine the adsorption/desorption process "in situ".</description><creator>Rodgers, Stacey.</creator><contributor>Distin, P. A. (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Environmental.</subject><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Cobalt removal from aqueous solutions using stabilized silica sols</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/05741t92g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149r76c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:08612q795</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:43Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Biological treatment of pulp and paper wastes by activated sludge is widely practiced in industry to reduce the organic content and toxicity of the wastewater. Most industrial applications require the treatment of a combination of streams from various processes. The composition of the combined stream varies since shock loadings and spills may occur. The objective of this research was to determine the effects of these variations on the microbial community and, ultimately, on the kinetics of the reduction of biological oxygen demand (BOD) and chemical oxygen demand (COD). This will improve the understanding of control requirements for the process. Effluents from two mills in Quebec were examined. Initially, effluents from a chemithermomechanical pulp (CTMP) mill were used in this research. The objective was to study the effect of six different waste streams mixed with total mill effluent (0--100%) on the reduction of COD and on the microbial population. The remainder of this research focused on treating effluents from a Kraft mill and investigated the effect of hydraulic residence time (HRT) and step inputs of 1%, 2.5% and 5% black liquor on the reduction of COD and BOD5 and on the microbial population. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Peters, Jennifer, 1973-</creator><contributor>Beck, D. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Environmental.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>The activated sludge treatment of pulp and paper wastewater /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1r66j3282.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612q795</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p096931h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:44Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis outlines the implementation and testing of a binocular active vision system. Emphasis is placed on the bilateral gaze controller that allows the robotic system to perform specific orienting tasks. The gaze controller, based on existing biological gaze control systems, is capable of tracking a moving target by integrating smooth pursuit and saccadic modes of operation. Furthermore, the controller is able to gracefully fuse eye and head movements without the need for a separate head controller. This work represents the first time a head platform has been implemented with the bilateral gaze controller. Experiments and simulations that yield the dynamic structure and performance of the eye-head system are presented. Although severely limited by spatial quantization and a low sampling rate, the gaze controller is able to adequately follow a moving target. Results also indicate that the addition of a head platform improves the overall performance of the system, as expected.</description><creator>Palatsoukas, Demetrios.</creator><contributor>Galiana, H. L. (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Gaze control fusing eye-head coordination with unified saccadic and smooth pursuit modes of operation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306t131p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p096931h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biomedical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6m311r513</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:45Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the electrolytic production of zinc, cobalt is removed from zinc electrolyte by cementation with zinc dust Prior to electrowinning. Although the thermodynamics for this reaction are favourable, kinetic barriers to cobalt reduction render the method impractical unless activators such as antimony or arsenic in conjunction with copper are used. There is a large body of work studying the effect of these additives, yet the mechanism by which they act is still poorly understood. Moreover, regardless of the beneficial effect of the activators, from time to time the process fails to meet the target level of 0.1 mg/L cobalt in the purified electrolyte, with negative consequences in the electrowinning operation. Even when the target conditions are met, zinc dust consumption is excessively high: satisfactory operation requires up to 300 times the stoichiometric amount of zinc dust. In the present work the role of the antimony/copper activators was investigated in a batch cementation process using synthetic electrolyte. The objectives were to study the fundamentals of cobalt cementation in zinc sulfate electrolyte with conventional additives, to clarify the action of additives and their role in cementation, and to identify and test novel additives. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Nelson, Amy.</creator><contributor>Demopoulos, G. P. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Novel activators in cobalt removal from zinc electrolyte by cementation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gq35t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6m311r513</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vj90k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Slider-crank mechanisms are widely used in reciprocating machinery, where transformation from rotational into translational motion (or vice versa) is required. Moreover, the use of these mechanisms is quite common in robotic and mechatronic systems when complex motions are to be produced with rotational actuators. However, the velocity ratio of the slider-crank mechanism is configuration-dependent and thus, elaborate algorithms are required to precisely control its performance. In this thesis, a planar cam mechanism with an oscillating follower is proposed as a device that renders the velocity ratio of the slider-crank mechanism constant, an operation that is termed here velocity-ratio rectification ; it is expected that the rectification will ease the feedback control of the slider-crank mechanism in mechatronic applications. A methodology for the optimization of this mechanism is developed. First, the performance of the slider-crank mechanism is analyzed and optimum geometric parameters are obtained. Then, an expression for the input-output relation of the cam mechanism at hand is derived, and the corresponding displacement program of the follower is produced. In addition, an approach for the optimization of planar cam mechanisms with an oscillating follower is introduced, to minimize the overall size, while maintaining an acceptable force-transmission performance based on bounds on the pressure angle. A Graphical User Interface (GUI) is developed to allow for the above-mentioned optimization in an interactive mode; the GUI is successfully used in an example of the design of a reducer-rectifier cam mechanism that rectifies the velocity ratio of the actuator of a robotic quadruped.</description><creator>Navarro-Martínez, Oscar R.</creator><contributor>Angeles, Jorge (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><title>The synthesis of speed-rectifying mechanisms for mechatronic applications /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/mc87ps681.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vj90k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cn69m618b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:46Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Microwave radio links, operating in the millimeter wave region, must account for the effects of rain when considering transmission loss. In this work, a theoretical model is used to generate the specific attenuations based on perturbation theory with spheroidal or Pruppacher-Pitter raindrop shapes, and Marshall-Palmer or Weibull drop size distributions. The specific attenuation is fitted to the power law relation with rain rate and the parameters are used in a two-component rain rate model in order to estimate the attenuation along the path. The theoretical model is simulated and compared to the ITU and Crane prediction methods. Both moderate and tropical climates are considered. A simple line-of-sight radio system is then simulated and evaluated by incorporating the rain attenuation in the channel. Finally, three basic network blocks are discussed and analyzed for links affected by rain.</description><creator>Nader, Joe.</creator><contributor>Morgera, Salvatore D. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Modeling and performance of microwave radio links in rain</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892d07q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cn69m618b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kc839</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:47Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An electrochemical permeation cell has been used to test the influence of microstructural characteristics of metal specimens and electrochemical processing parameters on electrochemical hydrogen diffusion. The affect of intercrystalline volume, entry surface roughness, cathodic charging current density and different cold working conditions on hydrogen diffusion through polycrystalline metals was tested. Nanocrystalline specimens of pure nickel and of 80%-Nickel 20%-Iron were tested to determine the affect of intercrystalline volume on hydrogen breakthrough diffusion. Specimens of pure palladium were tested to determine the influence of entry surface roughness, cathodic charging current density, different cold working and texture conditions on hydrogen permeation. A series of permeation tests performed on nanocrystalline nickel were used to optimize the measurement conditions. Experiments performed on 80/20 Ni-Fe thin foils determined that the hydrogen breakthrough diffusion coefficient drops dramatically with increasing grain size in the range of 20--40 nanometers. Above 40 nanometers, the breakthrough diffusion coefficient reaches a steady-state level. This decrease in breakthrough diffusion coefficient is thought to be due to a decrease in intercrystalline volume. Tests performed on palladium showed that the hydrogen effective diffusion coefficient increased logarithmically with increasing cathodic charging current density. These experiments also demonstrated that the optimum charging current density for palladium is 0.1 mA/cm2. Other tests on palladium determined that the surface roughness, on the entry side of the specimens, had no influence on the effective diffusion coefficient, processing efficiency or hydrogen subsurface entry concentration. Experiments on cold rolled palladium sheets determined that cold working dramatically lowers both the hydrogen subsurface entry concentration and effective diffusion coefficient. The lowering of the effective diffusio</description><creator>Morris, Brian, 1974-</creator><contributor>Szpunar, J. A. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Microstructural characteristics and processing parameters affecting hydrogen permeation through polycrystalline materials</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jn65k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kc839</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:76537318v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:48Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Peroxidase enzymes oxidise phenolic compounds to produce free radicals which spontaneously polymerize and precipitate from solution. In order to be able to compare the performance of the various enzymes, a technique for the evaluation of the kinetic constants governing the reactions was developed. In order to do so, the reactions which occur between horseradish peroxidase, phenol, peroxide and aminoantipyrine in an assay were first defined then mathematically modeled. The kinetic model was applied to reactions conducted under a range of initial concentrations of peroxide and phenol. The model was calibrated against experimental data using a genetic algorithm. Based on this approach, an optimal set of kinetic parameters was determined which accurately reflect the trends in experimental data. Due to assumptions used in the development of the model and observations made on the laboratory and modeled data, it was found that the model was applicable to reactions in which the initial phenol concentration was above 1 mM and the peroxide concentration over 0.15 mM. These conditions can now be used to extend the application of the model to evaluate the kinetic parameters associated with other peroxidase enzymes.</description><creator>Massam, Alexandra.</creator><contributor>Nicell, J. A. (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Environmental.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>A kinetic model for the transformation of phenol by peroxidase /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128d08z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537318v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3484zj80t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:49Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nineteen bacteria were tested for growth on paraffin wax as the sole source of carbon. Paraffin wax is a solid mixture of hydrocarbons including n-alkanes ranging from C18H38 to C37H 76. Of the nineteen bacteria tested, four bacteria (Arthrobacter paraffineus ATCC 19558, Mycobacterium OFS, Pseudomonas fluorescens Texaco and Rhodococcus IS01) grew well on paraffin wax. However, only one, Rhodococcus IS01, was found to rapidly and completely degrade a mixture of paraffin wax liquefied with hexadecane using the Self-Cycling Fermentation (SCF) technology. This strain was able to degrade n-alkanes ranging from dodecane to heptatriacontane as well as highly branched hydrocarbons such as pristane and hepta-methyl-nonane. Kinetic studies performed with Rhodococcus IS01 growing on mixtures of n-alkanes showed that the hydrocarbons were degraded in ascending order of chain length: shortest to longest chain. The short lag period between the biodegradation of the different n-alkanes suggested that the growth of Rhodococcus IS01 on mixtures of n-alkanes followed some form of diauxie. Further kinetic studies were conducted growing Rhodococcus IS01 on individual and various mixtures of n-alkanes; these showed that the initial first-order oxidation constant decreased with increasing chain length. This trend is suspected to be due to an enzyme specificity constraint rather than to a mass transfer limitation. In addition, it was also observed that the maximum specific growth rate constant (mumax) increased with increasing n-alkane chain length. Rhodococcus IS01 was also found to produce a cell-associated biosurfactant.</description><creator>Marino, Fabien.</creator><contributor>Cooper, D. G. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Biodegradation of paraffin wax</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3b591b56n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zj80t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gn07j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:50Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In order to keep up with the ever-increasing demand in communications, photonic technology, that has potential benefits in low power consumption, large bandwidth, reduction in payload mass and volume, and electromagnetic interference immunity, offers an alternative approach for the future communication satellites. An optical multi-carrier demultiplexer/demodulator (MCDD) system using acousto-optic technology has been built and characterized for satellite on-board processing (OBP). In this work, the design and implementation of this demonstrator are presented. The challenges for introducing the optical technologies are also discussed for the optics, optical packaging, and opto-electronics. The system was characterized and demonstrated a channel capacity of 438 channels with a power consumption of 63.9mW per channel.</description><creator>Lin, Leo Y., 1972-</creator><contributor>Plant, Dave (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Aerospace.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Design, implementation, and characterization of an optical multi-carrier demultiplexerdemodulator for satellite on-board processing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bv73c2731.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gn07j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bk128d097</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Column flotation as a concept was introduced approximately 90 years ago at Inspiration Copper Co., Arizona, with the first successful installation occurring at Les Mines Gaspe, Quebec, in 1981. Column flotation has since been applied to many other industries including deinking of recycled paper. The research is a comparison of industrial bubble generating devices in a pilot and laboratory column using water/Dowfroth and pulp sampled on-line from a local deinking plant. The pilot column tested combinations of 6, 4 and 2 stainless steel (ss) porous spargers, and filter cloth and jetting sparger; the lab column used a single ss porous sparger. Long term tests on the pilot column were also done to evaluate maintenance issues. Trends from the water/Dowfroth tests were used to predict results using pulp. Six ss spargers outperformed the other spargers in all cases. The performance of the lab column sparger matched 4 spargers, with the filter cloth performing marginally better than the jetting sparger or 2 spargers. Gas holdup (Eg) and bubble surface area flux (Sb) gave good correlation with ink removal with all spargers failing within a narrow range. Surface area flux is suggested over Eg unless bubble diameter or superficial gas velocity are indeterminable. Sb &gt; 100 s-1 gave ink removals equal to the plant Voith cells. An Sb below 40 s-1 gave zero ink removal. The lab and pilot column followed slightly different trends which was attributed to column diameter (i.e., wall effects). The ss and filter cloth spargers present long term maintenance issues due to plugging. The performance of the 6 ss spargers decreased more quickly than any other during the long term tests, attributed to lower air velocities per pore.</description><creator>Leichtle, Gunther F.</creator><contributor>Finch, J. A. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Agriculture, Wood Technology.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Analysis of bubble generating devices in a deinking column</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53k0182.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128d097</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wh246v104</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:51Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The analysis and implementation of a connection intensive, easy to assemble and misalignment tolerant optical interconnect for use within a photonic backplane implementing a Hyperplane architecture is presented. The system employs arrays of diffractive minilenses where many optical beams pass through the same minilens. This clustering scheme achieves both a high window density and a moderate window size as well as having benefits in terms of misalignment tolerance. The system is composed of pre-assembled modules in order to ease the system integration phase. Two interferometric alignment techniques are used to achieve the very demanding module component alignment tolerances. Simulation as well as implementation results are presented and discussed.</description><creator>Lacroix, Frédéric K.</creator><contributor>Kirk, Andrew (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Analysis and implementation of a clustered, scaleable and misalignment tolerant optical interconnect</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6q182n34z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246v104</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kd17cw22s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:52Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effects of high-strength concrete on the seismic performance of reinforced concrete exterior beam-column-slab subassemblages were investigated by comparing the behaviour of three full-scale specimens. Two specimens, one constructed with normal-strength concrete and one constructed with high-strength concrete, were designed with square columns. The specimen tested in this thesis was constructed with high-strength concrete and designed with a circular column. All the specimens were designed as ductile moment-resisting frames and tested under reversed-cyclic loading. The Canadian Standard, CSA A23.3-94, limits the concrete compressive strength used in seismic design to 55 MPa. The applicability of the current design specifications, developed for normal-strength concrete, were investigated when applied to ductile beam-column joints made with higher strength concrete. The reduced amount of confinement reinforcement permitted by the New Zealand Standard is also investigated. All specimens in the study were instrumented to allow for detailed strain, load and deflection measurements to be monitored during testing process. The hysteretic behaviour of each specimen was analysed in order to investigate energy dissipating characteristics as well as attainable ductility levels. Strains in the slab bars were used to determine the amount of effective slab reinforcement which contributes to the negative flexural capacity of the main beam. Deflection and strain measurements were used to determine the full torsional response of the spandrel beams. Non-linear dynamic analyses were also performed to compare the predicted seismic performance of normal-strength concrete and high-strength concrete prototype structures.</description><creator>Koch, Pierre-Alexandre.</creator><contributor>Mitchell, Denis (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Seismic response of high-strength concrete beam-column-slab specimens</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fn1071122.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kd17cw22s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:000002215</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:53Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Numerical experiments were carried out to determine tube geometries for more efficient thermal storage. A finite element simulation code developed earlier, which solves the two dimensional governing conservation equations was employed to examine the thermal performance of horizontal annuli of the following configurations: (a) Square external tube with a circular tube inside---Annulus Type A; (b) Circular external tube with a square tube inside---Annulus Type B. Effects of the Rayleigh number as well as heating of the inside, outside or both walls at a temperature above the melting point of the material were studied. Flow and temperature patterns within the melt, local heat flux distributions at the heating surface and the cumulative energy charged as a function of time are presented and discussed. To enhance the heat transfer rate during melting in horizontal annular containers various innovative passive methods were examined. Eccentric annular configurations are identified as superior to concentric tubular geometries due to the vertically upward orientation of the buoyancy force in the melt phase at higher Rayleigh numbers. In addition to this the effect of flipping the container at pre-selected times after initiation of melting as a measure to increase the heat transfer rate during the last stage of the melting process is also examined and discussed.</description><creator>Khillarkar, Dipendra B.</creator><contributor>Mojomdar, A. S. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Melting of a phase change material in horizontal annuli</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/765373194.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/000002215</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913r96k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:54Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bidding for electricity supply, as adopted by the UK electric power system, is One of the best ways to introduce competition among electricity suppliers. This thesis research concentrates mainly on the study of the rules governing the operation of the England and Wales Power Pool, with the objective to explain and justify these rules through rigorous theoretical analysis, and to provide a deeper understanding of the pool operation. In order to provide a broader picture beyond the pool operation, an extensive review of the electricity industry in England and Wales as a whole is also presented. In the theoretical aspects of the thesis, several tools are used, namely, the Switching Curve Law derived from the solution of the Unit Commitment problem through the Lagrangian Relaxation approach, as well as the game theory and Bayesian analysis.</description><creator>Jia, Songtao, 1970-</creator><contributor>Gallana, F. D. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><subject>Energy.</subject><title>A study of the England and Wales power pool /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4t64gq363.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913r96k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50gz27r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:55Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Conceptual urban runoff (CUR) models are commonly used in the Planning and design of urban drainage systems. These models often require a large number of variables and parameters in order to accurately describe, the complex relationships between rainfall, runoff and watershed characteristics. This requirement has often become a barrier to the use of such models, because of the difficulties involved in the estimation of these parameters. Hence, there is a great need to develop a robust and reliable automatic calibration procedure to assist in the identification of the best set of optimal parameters for a CUR model. The present study is therefore concerned with the automatic calibration of a typical and well-known CUR model, the U.S. Environmental Protection Agency Storm Water Management Model, or SWMM. In this study, two automatic calibration methods were considered based an two different optimization algorithms: the Downhill Simplex (DHS), a popular local optimization technique, and the Shuffled Complex Evolution (SCE), a global optimization procedure. The consistency of SCE in estimating the SWMM model parameters was assessed under two different scenarios: (1) using "error-free" synthetic data, and (2) using observed data available an the Upper Bukit Timah catchment in Singapore. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Javaheri, Hamed.</creator><contributor>Nguyen, V. T. V. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Physical Geography.</subject><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><subject>Hydrology.</subject><title>Automatic calibration of urban run-off models using global optimization techniques</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fb494b44m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gz27r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zg606</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mushroom tyrosinase (polyphenol oxidase, EC 1.14.18.1) was investigated as an alternative to peroxidase, enzymes for the catalytic removal of phenolic compounds from wastewaters. The maximum catalytic activity was observed at pH 7; however, significant activity was observed at pHs ranging from 5 to 8. Tyrosinase was unstable under acidic conditions and at elevated temperatures. The activation energy for thermal inactivation of tyrosinase was determined to be 1.85 kJ mol-1 at pH 7. The transformation of phenols catalysed, by tyrosinase was investigated as a function of pH, initial phenol concentration, and additives. Phenol was transformed successfully with tyrosinase, over a wide range of pH (pH 5--8) and a wide range of initial concentrations (0.5 mM--10 mM). Some chlorinated phenols were also successfully transformed with tyrosinase. Polyethylene glycol and chitosan did not improve the transformation efficiency of phenol. However, chitosan was successfully used to remove coloured, products resulting from treatment Since coagulation with aluminium sulfate failed, the colour removal induced by chitosan addition appeared to be the result of simultaneous coagulation and adsorption mechanisms. Minimum doses of chitosan required to achieve 90% of colour removal were logarithmically related to the quantity of phenol treated. All solutions of phenol and chlorophenols treated with tyrosinase, had substantially lower toxicities, than their corresponding initial toxicities. Chitosan addition enhanced the reduction in toxicity very effectively. The toxicities of the phenol solutions treated with tyrosinase were markedly lower than previously reported toxicities of solutions treated with peroxidase enzymes.</description><creator>Ikehata, Keisuke.</creator><contributor>Nicell, James A. (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Engineering, Environmental.</subject><subject>Engineering, Sanitary and Municipal.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Characterisation of tyrosinase for the treatment of aqueous phenols</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773x77w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zg606</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v405sc419</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:56Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The hydraulic behavior and mixing processes in wastewater basins are studied experimentally in a laboratory scale model. The laboratory basin is modeled after a full scale aerated lagoon system operating in Saint-Julie, Quebec. Three experimental techniques are used to reach the objectives: (i) video flow visualization, (ii) tracer studies and (iii) two-dimensional flow measurements using hot-film anemometry. Experiments are conducted on non-aerated basins, as well as on artificially aerated basins. The flow visualization and flow measurements show that the hydraulic behavior of non-aerated wastewater basins is very complex, due to the formation of flow patterns such as stagnant zones and recirculation. The location and size of these flow patterns are determined using the measured velocity flow field and the flow visualization images. Mixing in these basins is highly non-uniform since flow is clearly segregated into high-velocity and low-velocity areas. The exchange between these areas is very low, affecting the distribution of solids and contaminants. When artificial aeration is introduced, mixing becomes more uniform. Flow measurements and visualization indicate that the size of stagnant zones and the extent of recirculation decreases. The tracer studies show that, in general, aeration tends to decrease the actual residence time of the waste material. Calculation of the dispersion number, d, and the dead volume, Vd, are not sufficient to characterize the effect of aeration on mixing. The understanding of mixing and transport mechanisms in wastewater basins is important, because such basins are often used in applications which require settling or mixing of solids and contaminants.</description><creator>Iasenza, Robert.</creator><contributor>Babarutsi, Sofia (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Environmental.</subject><subject>Engineering, Sanitary and Municipal.</subject><subject>Hydrology.</subject><title>Mixing and transport processes in wastewater basins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75df67c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v405sc419</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tx31qk938</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:57Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Frequency filtering networks have numerous applications in consumer products. For high-speed and low-voltage systems, continuous-time filters are the preferred choice---these filters have become very popular with the wireless industry. Unfortunately, continuous-time filters have a high production cost since they are not geared toward mass production. This thesis proposes an analog filter structure that can be both mass produced and customized for a particular application. Such a structure is possible through the use of a state-space approach, and log-domain filtering. First, a general state-space formulation is presented; a method of obtaining the state-space coefficients from an equivalent LC ladder network is described. Such a set of coefficients results in a realization with low noise and low sensitivity properties. Next, the effects of coefficient quantization on a state-space filter's response is examined. An optimization procedure is outlined to obtain the best approximation to the desired transfer function. In order to implement the proposed filter structure, a universal log-domain cell is presented. Such a cell can be used to produce the stages required by any filter design (input, output, and integrator stages). Using the universal log-domain cell, a systematic approach to realizing any arbitrary-order filter is described. Next, the peripheral components needed to complete the filter are presented. Included are a novel 8-bit DAC, used to implement the programmable current sources that bias the filter, and V-to-I and I-to-V converters, used to interface the current-mode filter with voltage-mode instruments. Finally, experimental results from several prototype boards are used to verify the feasibility of the proposed filter structure. These boards make use of ICs fabricated in a 0.8 mum BiCMOS technology; included are an IC with stand-alone programmable current sources, an IC with a third-order filter, as well as one with a fifth-order filter. The results from the test boards clearly demonstrate the programmability and functionality of digitally programmable state-space filters.</description><creator>Hematy, Arman.</creator><contributor>Roberts, Gordon W. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Digitally programmable analog log-domain filters</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t4221.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qk938</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945t002</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:58Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Wireless digital data system designers have formidable future design challenges in order to provide the mobile user with a quality of service comparable to that of a wireline system in such metrics as responsiveness, quality, and throughput. The goal of this thesis is to address the throughput component of a mobile wireless digital data communication system with a novel design approach. This thesis explores the incorporation of simple software agents into a mobile wireless digital data communication system. The receiving software agent monitors the quality of the wireless channel and the retransmission statistics of the communication system. Based on these observable states from the channel and the recommendations of the software agent's knowledge bases, the agent takes the appropriate actions in the expectation of realizing the greatest possible throughput for the wireless digital data communication system. This thesis utilizes the GSM standard mobile wireless digital data communication platform model. Within the context of this model, the construction and integration of necessary components, such as error-control algorithms and software agent entities, are described in detail. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Heaps, Richard P. A.</creator><contributor>Morgera, Salvatore D. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Throughput analysis of a mobile wireless digital data communication system incorporating simple solftware agents : a simulation approach</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tm70mx60x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945t002</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8049g717z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The degree of waste paper recycling has been increasing steadily in North America over the last decade. Today, it is recognized that the flotation deinking process is one of the most important processes in waste paper recycling. This is demonstrated by the numerous variety of industrial flotation cell technologies currently available. Column flotation, developed in the mineral processing industry, is proposed as an alternative to other flotation technologies due to its low capital costs and improved separation performance. The flotation column requires an air sparging device to produce bubbles. Previous experimentation has shown that columns run with internal porous spargers initially produced excellent ink recoveries and low organic losses but eventually the sparging system plugged and performance deteriorated. In this work, an air sparging technique, based on a static inline pipe mixer was compared to a porous sparger. Both air sparging systems were evaluated in-plant on a lab scale flotation column to determine their relative merits, confirm previous work and compare to a circuit of full scale deinking cells. The effects of gas rate, retention time, wash water rate, froth height were investigated. It was found that the static mixer sparger was an excellent alternative to conventional porous spargers due to its stable operation and ability to control bubble size. As with porous spargers, the bubble surface area rate produced by the sparging system was found to be an important parameter in determining ink recovery. Two flotation circuits based on columns with the two competing sparging systems were scaled up using long term test data and compared. Operational boundaries for the static mixer sparger system were also defined.</description><creator>Hardie, Colin Alexander.</creator><contributor>Finch, James A. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Mechanical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>In-plant comparison of internal and external spargers for flotation column deinking</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010s26c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g717z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gh93h1671</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:15:59Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A laboratory sheet former using the twin-wire concept has been designed and constructed. It is capable of simulating a wide range of industrial papermaking conditions and can generate a pressure profile very close to that of an industrial machine. The machine has three components: the headbox section, the drainage section and the sheet pick-up section. All three sections are activated and brought up to operating speeds independently, with the headbox flow being diverted back into a reservoir. Once all systems are running at their operating conditions, the headbox flow is diverted to form a jet and steady-state sheet forming occurs for a certain period. The sheet and seven white water streams are collected during operation. The system is currently able to simulate the papermaking process up to the beginning of the vacuum drainage section; the sheet which it creates has a consistency in the vicinity of 11%. Mass balances of better than 95% have been achieved for both water and fibre. The magnitude of the pressure profiles generated has been measured or calculated. Continuing work will bring the sheet consistency into the 15% to 20% range; once this is attained, an efficient tool to optimize wet-end chemistry will be available.</description><creator>Hammock, Christopher J.</creator><contributor>Garnier, Gil (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Agriculture, Wood Technology.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Design and development of a laboratory scale twin-wire sheet former</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ww72bd80t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h1671</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988n246</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The growing need for integrable test solutions has prompted the creation of various test bus standards. A mixed-signal test core is an ideal complement to these standards. This work presents the design and implementation of an integrable test system. The design consists of two major components: a stimulus generator, and a waveform extractor. A memory-based generator is used to construct the stimulus generation component. Such a circuit repeats a finite portion of an infinite-length PDM sequence in order to produce any arbitrary analog waveform. The circuitry is simple to design---it is comprised of a scan chain, and a 1-bit DAC; it is also area-efficient and robust (mostly digital design). Furthermore, since the analog signal is generated from a digital bit-stream, it is both stable and repeatable. The extraction component of the test system focuses on the capture of steady-state type responses. A novel A/D algorithm is presented: the Multi-Pass technique. By taking advantage of repetitive waveforms, the Multi-Pass convertor achieves both area-efficiency and high-speed performance. A single on-chip comparator and sample-and-hold circuit is sufficient to extract analog waveforms. In addition, a novel, area-efficient, integrable, and highly-linear voltage reference design is presented. Experimental results from two prototype boards serve to validate the proposed test system design. The first board implements the system using discrete components; the second makes use of a custom IC fabricated in a 0.5 mum CMOS process. The work presented in this thesis provides the groundwork for obtaining a practical and fully integrable mixed signal test system.</description><creator>Hajjar, Ara.</creator><contributor>Roberts, Gordon W. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>An integrable mixed-signal test system /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wp90f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988n246</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xg960</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:16:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new, distributed model of the primate oculomotor system is presented. This model generates saccades (rapid eye movements) of various amplitudes, and it is able to exhibit various saccade-related phenomena, including multiple and interrupted saccades. The model differs from those in the literature in some of its hypotheses about the roles of the classes of neurons investigated here, but it remains largely in line with the current knowledge about saccade generation. The Superior Colliculus (a layered structure in the midbrain) plays a particularly important role in the model, and it is represented by three different layers: visual, burst, and buildup. The burst layer includes neurons that encode initial motor error, while the buildup layer houses cells whose shifting activity during a saccade provides an estimate for dynamic motor error. Collicular fixation neurons are also modeled, and they are characterized by a Winner-Take-All competition with burst neurons. Such a competition dictates whether a saccade is generated or not. Other saccade-related brainstem, structures, including omnipause neurons, medium-lead burst neurons, and the neural integrator, are also modeled.</description><creator>Hafed, Ziad M.</creator><contributor>Clark, James J. (advisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>A neural network model of the primate saccadic system /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jd46r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xg960</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2025</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>