<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:35:12Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):38100" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5712mc08m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The creation and manipulation of infinite images is central to Bruno's thought, but to the best of my knowledge, this has never been properly treated before. This project is a departure from much of the current scholarship on Bruno which has focused on his contribution to scientific thought, and downplayed or ignored the Hermetic and magical elements which pervade his work. Each chapter deals with different works of Bruno, and different aspects of his philosophy, and each is rooted in the larger project of uncovering the role, meaning, and application of images in Bruno's thought. The general arc of the thesis is from the interior and personal to the cosmological and metaphysical. Chapter 1 begins with a study of the faculty of phantasy and the role of images on human cognition. This is Bruno's epistemology and anthropology as expressed in Imaginum. Chapter 2 covers the ethical and social applications of images, and how the control of images manipulates reality. This concept is represented in the reconstruction of the universe in The Expulsion of the Triumphant Beast. Chapter 3 deals with the physics---or mechanics---of his philosophy, with its roots in Hermetic magic as described in Vinculis and Magia, wherein images are used to create bonds. Chapter 4 addresses Bruno's cosmology, which adopts the Copernican model and reinterprets that model as a hieroglyph. It is the heuristic key in Ash Wednesday Supper, the image of which exists in the faculty of phantasy and becomes embedded on to the universe. The two become indistinguishable and work in union. Through the coincidence of opposites, matter becomes form and God becomes man. The image of the infinite cosmos becomes re-embedded in the single instance of an image in the faculty of Phantasy. The conclusion will bring together these epistemological, ethical, mechanical, cosmological, and metaphysical strains of Bruno's philosophy into a statement on the Brunian reformation as he saw it, and on the contemporary relevance of his theory and application of images.</description><creator>Storch, Michael.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Bruno, Giordano, 1548-1600.</subject><subject>Imagination (Philosophy) -- History -- 16th century.</subject><title>Applied imagination : Giordano Bruno and the creation of magical images</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Michael Storch, 2007</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cf95jg465.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5712mc08m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wm117t01t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to determine whether certain non-musical components of a performance affect evaluator's performance quality ratings. Specifically, if there is an age at which point the presence of a music stand (i.e. an implied use of the score), the performers attractiveness, attire, stage behaviour and perceived level of accomplishment impacts performance ratings. Fourteen cellists were videotaped performing by memory, and then a second time with their music on a music stand, synchronizing their motions with the audio feedback from their first performance. The cellists and their performances were evaluated by 1024 individuals with no formal training in music ranging in age from six to fifty-five years old. Each evaluator was assigned to one of six groups: Visual only, Audio only, Memorized, Dubbed, Random 1, or Random 2. Results revealed that the presence or absence of a music stand had no impact on performance ratings. Performer attractiveness affected performance ratings for both sexes, although contrary to previous findings, being attractive was not advantageous. Dress had an inverse effect on ratings of female performers and poor stage behaviour affected ratings of both sexes. Although evaluators were unable to predict a performer's proficiency based solely on gesture, proficiency gestures made by musicians during performances affected ratings. Evaluators in the audiovisual conditions gave performers who appeared less accomplished significantly lower ratings than those in the audio only condition. Evaluators aged 13 were more critical than younger evaluators with their musical ratings and their ratings were also affected by the visual aspects of a performance. These results suggest that older non-musician evaluators use visual aspects to help their evaluations of subjective musical elements because they have a hard time hearing differences.</description><creator>Siddell-Strebel, Jeanne.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Music -- Performance -- Evaluation.</subject><title>The effects of non-musical components on the ratings of performance quality /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Jeanne Siddell-Strebel, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85ng408.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wm117t01t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Schulich School of Music</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:br86b763z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Spectacles of justice preoccupy contemporary American culture. Legal culture---including the Watergate trials, the Lewinsky scandal, and OJ Simpson's trial for alleged murder---assumes a central place in the American imaginary. Configurations of the law are not limited to media reportage and televised docudramas. Nor are arbitrations confined to law faculties and the spaces of formal courts. Working through depictions of due process in different ways and in different zones, contemporary American writers point up the prevalence of legality in everyday life. Whether on college campuses, in TV studios and suburban homes, or at theatres and racetracks, justice mediates interpersonal relations. Personal narratives proliferate as modes of self-justification. Everyone has a right to represent her side of a story. As interpretations of reality, however, none of these stories can claim absolute justness. No one has a monopoly on the law or victimhood. This dissertation inspects how Jonathan Franzen, Don DeLillo, and Jane Smiley present the inconsistencies of the law. These American novelists emplot global escapes into their work as a means to inform notions of liberty and jurisprudence. For these writers, freedom requires the recognition of contradictory---and unanticipated---narratives. "Justice Theory" emerges where media, gambling, performance, and suburban studies intersect with ethics, globalism, and narratology. In Franzen's novel The Corrections and essay collection How to Be Alone, self-validation requires the appreciation of the stories of others. In DeLillo's later works, particularly the plays The Day Room and Valparaiso, justice materializes in terms of isolation and the will to alter personal stories. For Smiley, as construed in her long novels The Greenlanders and Horse Heaven, dynamic responsive actions attend risky, unpredictable encounters in competitive milieus like the racetrack. These authors reveal that executions of justice and the perpetration of injustice involve varied consequences. The law is not only about punishment and recompense. Rather, legality directs the consequences of its applications toward the ideal of justice, which evolves alongside the subjects that it serves and the stories that they relate.</description><creator>Polley, Jason S.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>DeLillo, Don.</subject><subject>American literature -- 20th century -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Franzen, Jonathan.</subject><subject>Justice in literature.</subject><subject>Smiley, Jane.</subject><title>Acts of justice : risk and representation in contemporary American fiction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Jason S. Polley, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73q1226.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/br86b763z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vn12t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Predictors of long-term academic outcomes among Naskapi adolescents from Kawawachikamach, a reserve in Northern Quebec, were examined. Adolescents from this community as from other First Nations communities are statistically at risk for high school drop out and lower levels of educational attainment. However, efforts by communities during the past two decades to narrow the gap in educational attainment between First Nations students and the general population has resulted in significant gains for students who live on reserves. In a series of three initial visits that spanned a year, adolescents from grades 6 through 11 completed a battery of measures used to assess a broad range of components of social competence. Intelligence and school grades were used as markers of the academic success; social perspective coordination and attachment to father, mother, and peers as indices of social adaptation; and identity with Native culture as an index of cultural identity. The follow-up indicators of academic success were based on school records of graduation from high school and of admission and entrance into post-secondary institutions. As expected within the academic domain, both intelligence and school grades contributed to long-term academic achievement. Within the social domain, social perspective coordination skills and attachment to father, but not attachment to mother or peers, promoted academic achievement. Within the cultural domain, lower identification with Native status was associated with school achievement. These findings highlight the need to promote both social and academic competence in the quest to further improve rates of high school graduation and post-secondary enrolment. The link between attachment to father and academic success also suggests that educational interventions should be focused on the family as well as the child. With regard to educational planning, the government-mandated curriculum should be adapted so that the Naskapi and majority education can be integrated in complementary ways rather than being pitted against each other in a way that allows for success on only one. Although each First Nations community is unique with regard to history, culture, language, and educational values, the identification of multiple predictors of academic success among Naskapi adolescents is likely relevant to other communities.</description><creator>Root, Rhoda.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Educational attainment -- Québec (Province) -- Schefferville.</subject><subject>Naskapi Indians -- Education.</subject><title>Predictors of educational attainment among Naskapi adolescents</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Rhoda Root, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29bb109.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vn12t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8049g911q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Quebec City - Windsor corridor is the busiest and most important trade and transportation corridor in Canada. The transportation sector is the second largest greenhouse gas (GHG) emission category in the country. Governments around the world, including Canada, are considering increased mode share by rail as a way to reduce transportation emissions. To understand whether freight mode shift is a realistic means to reduce transportation emissions, an analytical model is needed that can predict the effect of government policy on mode split. This thesis provides background on the freight transportation-GHG nexus in Canada and describes the development, implementation, reasoning behind, and results of, a Stated Preference shipper carrier choice survey for the Quebec City - Windsor corridor conducted during the fall of 2005. It then describes how the resulting carrier choice models are used to estimate the potential to displace truck traffic to rail (premium-intermodal) under current conditions, as well as to test the effectiveness of different possible future policy or service offering scenarios. The results show that premium-intermodal has the potential to capture a substantial share of traffic between the main destinations in the Quebec City - Windsor Corridor. However, its ability to contribute significantly to reducing CO2 emissions is limited. According to the analyses conducted, potential reductions are considered to be in the range of nil to 0.413 Mt---a fraction of what the federal government was hoping to be able to achieve through "further public-private collaboration to promote the use of intermodal freight opportunities and to increase the use of low-emission vehicles and modes" (Government of Canada 2002). At the same time, these potential reductions are based on a small proportion of total truck-related emissions and a few city-pairs. Extension of the current analysis to more city-pairs separated by longer distances might arrive at different conclusions.</description><creator>Patterson, Tai Zachary.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Greenhouse gas mitigation -- Ontario.</subject><subject>Railroads -- Freight -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Freight and freightage -- Environmental aspects -- Ontario.</subject><subject>Railroads -- Freight -- Ontario.</subject><subject>Freight and freightage -- Environmental aspects -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Greenhouse gas mitigation -- Québec (Province)</subject><title>Freight shipper mode choice in the Quebec City-Windsor Corridor and its impact on carbon dioxide emissions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Tai Zachary Patterson, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r741p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g911q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qn59q856x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation investigates the early twentieth century work of Irish-born interior designer and architect, Eileen Gray. While the existing literature has tended to read Gray and her work primarily in relation to major male modernist movements and figures, this dissertation contends that considering her engagement with the alternative modernisms developed by other women artists and writers at the time will enrich our understanding of the wider social, cultural and historical implications of her work. In order to make sense of what scholars have long recognised as Gray's critically different architecture and design I analyse her work in relation to three of her female contemporaries: the artist Romaine Brooks, and writers Radclyffe Hall and Djuna Barnes. Such an analysis reveals that Gray's critically different work was importantly related to the critically different aesthetics, genders and sexualities that Gray and many of her female contemporaries cultivated at the time. The first chapter argues that debates about domestic architecture and design were also importantly debates about modern bodies and subjects and provides the framework for the analyses that follow. Chapter 2 compares Gray's early lacquer works, La Voie Lactee (ca. 1912), Le Magicien de la Nuit (1913) and Le Destin (1914) to Romaine Brooks' two paintings from 1910, White Azaleas and The Screen, focusing on their use of decadent aesthetics. Chapter 3 considers Gray's first intricately designed house, E.1027 (1928), in relation to the content and cultural impact of Radclyffe Hall's 1928 novel, The Well of Loneliness. Chapter 4 examines Gray's extremely private and less known house, Tempe a Pailla (1934), in relation to the obscure and non-communicative narrative strategies of Djuna Barnes' 1936 novel, Nightwood. Overall, the argument that binds my dissertation is that Gray's work both contributed and responded to changing conceptions of gendered and sexual subjects in the first half of the last century.</description><creator>Rault, Jasmine.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Women architects.</subject><subject>Gray, Eileen, 1878-1976 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><title>Eileen Gray : new angles on gender and sexuality</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Jasmine Rault, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mk487.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qn59q856x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pg15bk184</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation examines George MacDonald's preoccupation with his literary predecessor Percy Shelley. While eminently Victorian in many ways, MacDonald was equally a late Romantic, who was inspired by the Romantic poets and positioned himself as the heir to their radical tradition. While he channeled their visionary ardor, he also made it his duty to correct what he saw as their flaws. I read MacDonald through the figure of Shelley, with whom MacDonald seems to have personally identified, but to whose atheism MacDonald, a devout believer, objected. MacDonald's fascination with Shelley works its way into his fiction, which mythologizes literary history, offering fables about the transmission of the literary spirit down through the generations. Throughout his work, MacDonald resurrects Shelley in various guises, idealizing and reshaping Shelley into an image that is startlingly like MacDonald himself. This project contributes to MacDonald scholarship by offering a new approach to his work. It positions MacDonald, who is often portrayed as an ahistorical myth-maker, in an explicitly historical light, revealing him as a Victorian mythographer who was deeply invested in questions of literary criticism and historical succession. Chapter 1 introduces MacDonald's concern with literary genealogy, and discusses how his work as a literary critic and historian idealizes Shefey. Chapter 2 examines how MacDonald's Phantastes portrays literary history as romantic quest, featuring Shelley as a heroic but fallen knight, and opening questions about literary fatherhood. Chapter 3 interprets the gothic tale "The Cruel Painter" as a myth about the transition from the Enlightenment to Romanticism, in which MacDonald rewrites the story of Shelley's involvement with Mary Godwin and her father William Godwin. Chapter 4 considers Sir Gibbie and Donal Grant, works in which MacDonald explicitly critiques Shelley, and implicitly positions himself as the savior of the English literary tradition. Chapter 5 investigates MacDonald's later works, The Flight of the Shadow and Lilith, in which Shelley---and evil itself---become more complex entities. Throughout the dissertation, particular attention is given to the issue of repeating history vs. redeeming history, a tension that is reflected in MacDonald's use of vampire imagery to portray the unredeemed past.</description><creator>Koopman, Jennifer.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>MacDonald, George, 1824-1905 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Shelley, Percy Bysshe, 1792-1822 -- Influence.</subject><title>Redeeming romanticism : George MacDonald, Percy Shelley, and literary history</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Jennifer Koopman, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cv43p234m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pg15bk184</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w3763c05t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>While the groundbreaking insights that contemporary theorists have formulated with regards to space---as a multiplicity without essence, as an active event, and as inseparable from subjectivity, power, Otherness and time---have ostensibly purged it of its traditional understanding as absolute, a specific visuality characteristic of Cartesian perspectivalism remains privileged in its theorization which force it to remain so. While the complexity of space cannot be recovered from an abstract contemplation of its visual geometry in a way that reflects these contemporary concerns, there have unfortunately been relatively few attempts to imagine space away from the visual in a way that challenges its traditional absoluteness. To this end, it is argued that because sound and music contain implicit and explicit spatialities, the sonic represents a rich and unexplored area from which to imagine a radical non-visual space that discursively organizes space according to a different economy through which to challenge its assumed visuality. And yet, even when space has been approached through sound, there is a tendency to exteriorize sound into an object or a set of practices that robs it of its defining quality---its own "soundfulness". By breaking down those factors that are considered salient to how space is conceived today along sonic rather than visual lines, the argument is made that the "soundfulness" of sound's physical properties gives it a complex texture of excess that is corporealized within the body and forwards the philosophical possibility of unfolding the spatiality of sound according to vectors beyond the visible in a way that, while reflecting contemporary concerns, prevents its return to absoluteness. To take seriously this "soundfulness" thus allows us to recuperate the sonic as a philosophical and political way of experiencing and knowing the world, including that of space. The arguments, as well as being drawn from the insights of contemporary spatial theory, the physics of sound, the phenomenology of listening, rhizomatic and feminist theory, quantum mechanics and musicology, will be explained through an understanding of space as sound and exemplified in The Disintegration Loops, a post-minimalist musical piece by sonic artist William Basinski.</description><creator>Guimond, David.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Music -- Philosophy and aesthetics.</subject><subject>Space and time in music.</subject><title>(Re)sounding : disintegrating visual space in music</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© David Guimond, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q8576.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w3763c05t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History and Communication Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322j92s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this study is to understand the logic of popular mobilization in Sao Paulo (Brazil) and New Delhi (India) and to explain why subaltern groups use their political freedoms to mobilize on some issues and not on others. More specifically, the study attempts to address a puzzle: Why do the popular sectors not mobilize to make claims for health when the vast majority of the urban poor experience severe health deficits? My contention is that the nature of public discourse determines both the emergence of popular movements and the issues on which they engage in claims-making. Competing ideas about what democracy is and what it ought to be, the meaning of social justice, and the relationship between democracy and social justice, constitute the 'raw materials' around which mobilization frames are created. The empirical evidence presented in this study supports my claim that the nature of public discourse is crucial for democratic deepening from below. Based on extensive field research in low-income communities in Sao Paulo and New Delhi, my study explains the differences and similarities in the political actions of the urban poor. In India, the near-absence of a public discourse on health accounts for the lack of mobilization by subaltern groups to seek improvements in their health situation. In contrast, I find that there has been a tradition of public discourse on health in Brazil since the 1970s when "external actors" such as doctors and progressive Church officials became engaged in social causes and contributed to the emergence of health movements. However, since Brazil's transition to democracy, this public discourse has fractured, becoming more receptive to "new" health issues such as violence, even though "old" health problems continue to persist. While the popular sectors experience the dual burden of "old" and "new" health problems, they are perceived to be the cause of many "new" health hazards like violence rather than its victims. The disengagement of "external actors" from "old" health issues and the widespread perception that the popular sectors are themselves to blame for the "new" health problems has inhibited popular mobilization for health in democratic Brazil.</description><creator>Gupta, Madhvi.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Brazil -- Politics and government -- 2003-</subject><subject>Social movements -- Brazil.</subject><subject>India -- Politics and government -- 1984-</subject><subject>Democratization -- Brazil.</subject><subject>Democratization -- India.</subject><subject>Social movements -- India.</subject><title>When democracy is not enough : political freedoms and democratic deepening in Brazil and India</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Madhvi Gupta, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cr56n534c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322j92s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gm80j081h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The citizens of utopian Renaissance cities have in common the confidence in the power of reason and moral virtues. The purpose of the thesis is to prove that, in spite of the imaginative and unreal aspects of these utopian societies, they contain the prodroms of the modern societies. The utopias of the Renaissance are projects of a new commonwealth, based on justice and education. The Italian peninsula of the XVI and early XVII century spawned several works belonging to this literary genre, inspired by Plato's Republic and initiated in England with Thomas More's Utopia (1516). Those considered in this thesis, besides Utopia, are: Francesco Doni's Il mondo savio e pazzo (1552), Francesco Patrizi's La Citta felice (1553), Ludovico Agostini's La Repubblica immaginaria (1580), Tommaso Campanella's La Citta del Sole (The City of the Sun) (1602) and Lodovico Zuccolo's Il Belluzzi (1621). The thesis examines these six main literary works according to the concept of uchronie and escapism, the definitions of utopia by Karl Mannheim, J.C. Davis and Mikhail Bakhtin, the religious and Arcadian elements and the relationship between utopia and satire. The thesis analyzes three essential aspects of the utopian tales: city planning, relationship between man and woman, and education. The utopias of the Renaissance also reveal two different visions: one innovative if compared to the society of the time, and another, post-tridentina, oriented towards a return to more traditional values. The thesis examines the influence of More's work on the utopias of the Renaissance by analyzing and comparing a series of topics, like the title of the work, the narrator, fantastical names and ideas, the role of Plato, property and inequity, the choice of woman and the concept of beauty, daily labor, the function of God, and the concept of law. The utopias of the Renaissance have various modern aspects: a utilitarian justice, a better place of woman in the society, the laicity of the government, the "rationality" of war, secularism, education, health, social justice, assistance to elderly. They also contain myopias, like an unrealistic economic model and a static society.</description><creator>Langford, Charles K.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Italian literature -- 16th century -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Utopias in literature.</subject><subject>Italian literature -- 17th century -- History and criticism.</subject><title>Le utopie rinascimentali : esempli moderni di polis perfetta</title><language>ita</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Charles K. Langford, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jq803.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gm80j081h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Italian</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gf76j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Saccharomyces cerevisiae Kre5p is important for the biosynthesis of beta-1,6-glucan, which is required for proper cell wall assembly and architecture. A functional and cell biological analysis of Kre5p was conducted to further elucidate its role in beta-1,6-glucan synthesis. Kre5p was found to be a primarily soluble N-glycoprotein of ~200 kD that localizes to the endoplasmic reticulum. Observation of Kre5p-deficient cells reveals a severe cell wall morphological defect, and kre5Delta cells were shown to have only residual levels of beta-1,6-glucan. KRE6 was identified as a multicopy suppressor of a temperature-sensitive kre5 allele, suggesting these proteins participate in a common pathway. An analysis of truncated versions of Kre5p indicates that it may have two independent, essential activities, or that it functions in a homodimeric state. Finally, Candida albicans KRE5 was shown to partially restore growth to kre5Delta cells, suggesting it has a function similar to that of the S. cerevisiae protein.</description><creator>Levinson, Joshua N.</creator><contributor>Bussey, Howard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Saccharomyces cerevisiae -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Glycoproteins.</subject><subject>Saccharomyces cerevisiae -- Cytology.</subject><subject>Fungal cell walls.</subject><title>Functional and cell biological characterization of Saccharomyces cerevisiae Kre5p</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h357z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gf76j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:76537286s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Lipopolysaccharide (LPS) from Gram-negative bacteria triggers a protective inflammatory response in a normal host. In classical laboratory inbred strains of mice, the Lps locus controls the rate of exponential Salmonella growth in spleen and liver during the early phase of infection through its effect on innate immunity. The gene encoding the Lps mutation was recently identified as the Toll-like receptor 4 (Tlr4 ). Toll-like receptors are a group of evolutionarily conserved pattern recognition receptors involved in the activation of the immune system in response to pathogen. The discovery of mouse Tlr4 as being the gene encoding the Lps mutation provided the possibility of studying the role of this gene in chicken susceptibility to infection with Salmonella typhimurium. To achieve this goal we have cloned the chicken orthologue of mouse Tlr4, determined its sequence, mapped it in the chicken genome and showed its linkage to susceptibility to infection with Salmonella typhimurium in the chicken.</description><creator>Leveque, Gary.</creator><contributor>Malo, Danielle (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Agriculture, Animal Pathology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>Identification of the chicken toll-like receptor 4 (TLR4) gene and its role in the susceptibility to Salmonella infection</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483m01s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/76537286s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gm67s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>NCoR and SMRT are corepressors that interact with the ligand-binding domain (LBD) of retinoic acid receptors (RARs) in the absence of ligand to repress transcription. This interaction is allowed through the presence of small alpha-helical motifs found in corepressors that interact with residues lining the hydrophobic pocket of the RARs. Unlike RARalpha and RARgamma, RARbeta weakly interacts with NCoR and SMRT. Here we show that the determinants in RARalpha present in helix 1 (H1) (I188), H7 (A311), H9 (D346), and H10 (M377) are important for corepressor binding. Substitution of these amino acids with RARbeta corresponding residues decreased interaction with SMRT. Moreover, gain of function experiments showed that introduction of some of these determinants in RARbeta resulted in an improved ability to interact with SMRT. Furthermore, the hinge region of RARalpha is very important for the stability of the LBD and corepressor binding. In a mammalian two-hybrid assay, we show that in the presence of NCoR, RARbeta hinge region could not stabilize as much its LBD as RARalpha. However, RARalpha hinge efficiently stabilized the LBD of RARbeta in the presence of the corepressor. We also show that the RARbeta H12 inhibits interaction with corepressors. Deletion of H12 rescued these interactions both in solution and on DNA, and rendered RARbeta a potent repressor in vivo. These results suggest that RARbeta, although having a high degree of identity with RARalpha, has major conformational differences that affect its ability to interact with corepressors. All together, these modified receptors will be useful tools to identify determinants in RARs important for corepressor interaction and help elucidate the precise molecular mechanism by which RARbeta acts as a tumor suppressor.</description><creator>Latreille, Mathieu.</creator><contributor>Giguere, Vincent (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Retinoic acid receptors (RARs) hinge and helix 1 play important roles in the interaction with NCoR and SMRT corepressors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t8122.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gm67s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g445cg10w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Automated video surveillance is a field in rapid expansion. Our research goal is to build a 3D person tracker for indoor video surveillance. In order to put our work in context we review various vision-based techniques for tracking people and detecting abnormal behaviours. The approaches are presented in bottom-up fashion starting from low-level algorithms to segment foreground objects, to trackers and action recognition systems. We also present a model-based camera localization technique. Our contribution is a 3D tracking system that can be subdivided into three modules: background subtraction, camera pose estimation and the tracker itself. The background subtraction algorithm uses the Discrete Cosine Transform coefficient blocks of JPEG encoded images as observations to compute the most likely state of each block with a Hidden Markov Model. Camera pose estimation is implemented as an edge-based CAD model registration technique using a particle filter. Finally, the tracker uses the registered model to perform 3D tracking from monocular images by assuming that the feet of people touch the floor. It's able to estimate the position and speed of tracked people at 2Hz, the maximum frame rate of the network camera. This tracker is in fact a blob-based tracker combined with a particle filter estimator. Preliminary results demonstrate that this system works well in its application context: hallway monitoring. Existing systems that use the output of trackers to recognize activities are reviewed. Finally we propose a few ideas on how to use a 3D tracker to classify scenes in order of interest with the most unusual first.</description><creator>Lamarre, Mathieu.</creator><contributor>Clark, James J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Sociology, Criminology and Penology.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Tracking and activity classification in video surveillance applications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9z903173d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g445cg10w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4x51hk959</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Leishmania protozoans are the etiologic agents of the disease leishmaniasis. The parasite exists in two morphological forms: promastigote and amastigote. Promastigotes are found in the gut of the sandfly vector while amastigotes reside inside the vertebrate macrophage. Leishmania, an obligate intracellular parasite, resists toxic reactive oxygen species (ROS) from both endogenous and exogenous sources. Like other protozoa, Leishmania lacks some of the antioxidant defence enzymes such as catalase and glutathione peroxidase (Gpx) that are usually found in aerobic cells. Instead they possess the antioxidant thiol compound trypanothione, in association with specific trypanothione linked antioxidant enzymes such as peroxidoxins. The transformation from promastigote to amastigote is a crucial step for parasite infection and survival. The molecular basis for this transformation is not clearly understood. Recently it was shown that the peroxidoxin gene is present in multiple copies in Leishmania. In the present study we examined the potential of antisense RNA and double stranded RNA (dsRNA) to perform functional knockout of the peroxidoxin gene. Towards that end antisense RNA and dsRNA expressing plasmids, targeting the peroxidoxin gene, were constructed. Leishmania promastigotes were subsequently transfected with these plasmids and the levels of peroxidoxin gene expression were studied. The results from this study suggest that there is no apparent reduction in either the levels of peroxidoxin mRNA or the protein in the transfected promastigotes as compared to the non-transfected cells.</description><creator>Khan, Mahmood Ali, 1962-</creator><contributor>Matlashewski, G. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Leishmania -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Leishmaniasis -- Molecular aspects.</subject><subject>Antioxidants.</subject><title>Peroxidoxin gene expression in Leishmania</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nw414.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4x51hk959</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sq87bw30v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study focussed its energy on the evaluation of a dielectric pasteurization for fresh meat. This research investigates ways to reduce the bacterial load on raw beef surfaces with microwave or RF energy in combination with different packaging methods and a natural antimicrobial combination. Sterilized raw beef cores were inoculated with Escherichia coli biotype 1, Pseudomonas D17 and Carnobacterium "845" of a known inoculum. Treatments were imposed to the cores and packaged in either retail or vacuum packaging. The treatments for the full experiment were RF1 (600W-30s, 400W-30s, 200W-60s), RF2 (600W-30s, 400W-30s, 100W-60s), Nisin-lysozyme alone, Nisin-lysozyme/RF1 and Nisin-lysozyme/RF2. Positive and negative control treatments were added to facilitate the comparison. Microbial analysis, pH measurement, L*a*b* colour measurement and sensory evaluation were performed during the storage period to follow the evolution of the meat samples. No significant reductions (P &lt; 0.05) in bacterial numbers were observed in this study and none of the treatments showed positive results. Therefore the treatments used would not be considered as a good pasteurization treatment for keeping the quality of raw beef. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Lacroix, Karine.</creator><contributor>Raghavan, G. S. V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Meat -- Microbiology.</subject><subject>Meat -- Preservation.</subject><subject>Dielectric heating.</subject><title>Dielectric heating for antimicrobial treatment of fresh meats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z890rw25g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sq87bw30v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mp48sf41d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study examines the development, organization, and implementation process of an intersectoral work insertion program (ISWIP) that is implemented through the collaboration of six stakeholders from different sectors of the community, including health and employment. The research objective is approached by case study methodology whereby the main methods of inquiry are documentation collection, participant observation, and semi-structured interviews. An innovative program logic model is developed that illustrates key components of using an intersectoral approach: leadership, sharing resources, and serving interests. The study demonstrates the relevance of local development to the social integration of individuals with mental illness. It also provides insight into the challenging nature of collaboration; obstacles such as negotiating roles, maintaining interests, and dealing with unforeseen consequences can be sources of frustration and tension among participants. Communication, attitude, and stakeholder involvement, are mediating factors in overcoming conflicts, reducing tension, and promoting successful collaboration.</description><creator>Lal, Shalini.</creator><contributor>Mercier, Celine (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Sociology, Public and Social Welfare.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health.</subject><title>Intersectoral collaboration in a work insertion program for individuals with mental illness : a case study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w658f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mp48sf41d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214q91m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Non-synostotic occipital plagiocephaly (NSOP) is a term commonly used to describe asymmetry of the infant skull arising in the perinatal period. There is preliminary evidence in the literature suggesting that infants with NSOP may exhibit a motor delay. However, confirmation of this delay, as well as elucidation of the factors that may contribute to this delay have never been empirically determined using standard measures of motor performance. The objective of this study was to compare motor skill acquisition of infants with NSOP to a matched group of normal healthy children. The results indicated that infants with NSOP are more likely to be delayed in the acquisition of early motor skills when compared to typically developing infants. This delay appears to be associated with a lack of exposure to the prone position while awake. Findings suggest that clinicians should assess the possibility of motor delays when evaluating these children.</description><creator>Kennedy, Eileen Elizabeth</creator><contributor>Majnemer, Annette (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><title>Motor skill acquisition in children with occipital plagiocephaly</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kp90f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214q91m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dv13zw235</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Inuit infants throughout the Arctic experience higher mortality and poorer health than their non-Inuit counterparts, and suffer disproportionately from bacterial and viral infections. This research initially reviews the health status of these infants, with a focus on Canadian Inuit communities and reference to other circumpolar regions, as appropriate. It also discusses the wide range of inter-related factors that affect their health and their susceptibility to infection: their demographic, social, economic and physical environment, as well as personal health practices and the availability of high quality, culturally-appropriate health services within their communities. Data were then analyzed from a cohort study of 46 healthy Inuit infants that had been previously conducted in Iqaluit, Nunavut from December 1995 to November 1997. Hospitalization and morbidity patterns were examined over their first year of life. Infants experienced an average of four respiratory tract infections (RTIs) annually, which accounted for half of the hospitalizations in the cohort. Some interesting trends were evident from assessment of risk factors for hospitalization and infections using multiple linear regression. Infants of mothers with higher educational attainment spent six fewer days in hospital per year (95% CI: -14.6, 2.9), after adjustment for confounding variables. Adoption appeared to have adverse health effects in addition to those that would be expected due to lack of breastfeeding alone; among infants who were not breast-fed, adopted infants had three more RTIs per year than non-adopted infants (95% CI: 0.5, 5.1). These results provide support for undertaking larger epidemiological studies in order to clarify the role of these risk factors, so that future preventive efforts can be informed and effective.</description><creator>Jenkins, Alison L.</creator><contributor>Gyorkos, Theresa W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>Factors influencing the health of Canadian Inuit infants</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mk69f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dv13zw235</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4t64gq08x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The validity of niche-assembly rules in explaining community structure is revisited by testing for ecological separation among ferns. An intensive, fine-scale survey of fern abundance and environmental variation was done in 1-ha of old-growth forest. Three methods of detecting niche segregation (canonical correspondence analysis, detrended correspondence analysis and GIS mapping) suggested that most fern species at the site are distributed according to distinct environmental preferences. The most important gradients separating fern species are first, the amount of soil moisture and second, soil nitrate concentration. Contrary to other findings, pH had little influence on controlling fern distribution. Spatial autocorrelation, detected by partialled ordinations, obscured the presence of niche partitioning. As well, sampling grain changed the apparent location of some species on environmental gradients and their ecological similarity to other species. Finer-scaled environmental heterogeneity or dispersal-mediated processes may account for the unexplained variation in fern species abundance of this site.</description><creator>Karst, Justine.</creator><contributor>Lechowicz, Martin J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Ferns -- Québec (Province) -- Mont-Saint-Hilaire -- Geographical distribution.</subject><subject>Niche (Ecology)</subject><subject>Ferns -- Ecology -- Québec (Province) -- Mont-Saint-Hilaire.</subject><subject>Geographic information systems -- Québec (Province) -- Mont-Saint-Hilaire.</subject><title>Ecological separation among fern species in an old-growth forest</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k898j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4t64gq08x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3b591b119</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Reduced levels of health-related quality of life (HRQL) post-stroke are an important issue to address in rehabilitation. Despite improvement in function over time, HRQL remains poor for many stroke survivors. This longitudinal study is aimed at estimating the extent to which physical performance, social, and psychological functioning influence HRQL. Forty-three community-living persons with stroke were recruited to participate in a six-week intervention preceded and followed by a performance- and interview-based evaluation assessing different levels of disability and functioning. HRQL was measured by the VAS of the EQ-5D. Regression models generated cross-sectionally demonstrated that physical performance, social, and psychological functioning explained up to 90% of the variation in HRQL. A GEE model revealed that, over time, only upper extremity functioning had a significant relationship with HRQL. Much attention has already been focused on increasing physical performance in rehabilitation. However, clinicians should consider other components that affect HRQL directly or indirectly through physical performance. Only by treating the different components of functioning at various levels can HRQL be ultimately increased.</description><creator>Jung, Helen.</creator><contributor>Mayo, Nancy E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><title>Physical performance and health-related quality of life post-stroke</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zc77sr768.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3b591b119</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v979v476x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new clinical measure of postural adaptation, the Advanced Mobility and Balance Scale (AMBS), was developed to assess balance capacities of stroke patients in standing and walking. In the first pilot study, involving 12 stroke patients and 6 healthy subjects, we found excellent interrater reliability and reasonable discriminative capacity of the AMBS. However, high-level functioning stroke subjects could not be differentiated from healthy subjects. In order to refine the scoring of the AMBS for better discrimination, we conducted a kinematic analysis of head turning while walking in 10 stroke patients and 5 age-matched healthy subjects. Results showed that stroke patients manifested disrupted head-trunk-pelvis coordination and increased footpath deviation during head turns towards the paretic side. These abnormal patterns are likely due to compensations and altered sensorimotor integration processes.</description><creator>Kairy, Dahlia.</creator><contributor>Fung, Joyce (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Paquet, Nicole (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><title>New insight into postural adjustments during locomotion post stroke</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n043m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v979v476x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9880vs720</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The process of islet isolation destroys extracellular matrix and eliminates potentially important inter-cellular relationships. We have previously shown that isolated islets embedded in a type I collagen gel, in the presence of a defined medium, undergo a phenotypic switch to duct-like epithelial structures through a process known as transdifferentiation. The aim of this study was to characterize the specific effectors implicated in islet cell transdifferentiation in order to better understand the factors that confer morphogenetic stability on cells in the isolated islets. We demonstrated cytoplasmic immunoreactivity for TGF-beta isoforms over 8 days post isolation using canine islets. Islet-to-duct epithelial transdifferentiation was correlated with the total amount of TGF-beta and was maximal at 48 h of culture. Up regulation of TGF-betaRI and TGF-betaRII expression on day 2 post-isolation was demonstrated by immunohistochemistry and Western blot analysis, and correlated temporally with the induction of cell proliferation. The presence of TGF-beta1 in culture supernatants was detected using the PAI/L assay. The peak TGF-beta1 level was 10.94 +/- 2.27 pM (active form) and 52.23 +/- 1.57 pM (total TGF-beta) at 48h. Addition of exogenous TGF-beta1 at different concentrations caused an accelerated and more pronounced epithelial transformation at 5--10 ng/mL compared to lower concentrations (0.5--1 ng/mL). These studies confirm the biological potential of islets of Langerhans to transdifferentiate to duct epithelial structures. TGF-beta signal transduction appears to play an important role in this process.</description><creator>Hazrati, Ali.</creator><contributor>Rosenberg, Lawrence (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><title>The role of transforming growth factor-beta (TGF-) in the transdifferentiation of islets of Langerhans to duct-like epithelial structures /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569620d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9880vs720</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Surgical Research</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fj86j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>To assess the changes in glycolysis of skeletal muscles within metabolic stress and to test whether metabolic stress-induced oxidative stress and malnutrition were associated with these changes, slow- (soleus) and fast-twitch extensor digitorum longus (EDL) muscles were studied in zymosan-induced critically ill, pair-fed and control rats for 7 days. Thiobarbituric acid reactive species (TBARS) concentrations were increased in both stressed and pair-fed rats. In slow-twitch muscle, the fructose-1,6-bisphosphate (F-1,6-P2)/fructose-6-phosphate (F-6-P) ratio was decreased in stressed rats and was not altered with increased food intake. F-1,6-P2/F-6-P ratio in soleus was correlated with both TBARS and muscle dry weight. In EDL, the F-1,6-P2/F-6-P was unaffected and neither oxidative stress nor muscle weight correlated with the ratio. In conclusion, metabolic stress-induced oxidative stress and malnutrition influenced glycolytic slowdown only in slow-twitch muscle.</description><creator>He, Ying, 1972 Apr. 20-</creator><contributor>Bissonnette, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Glycolysis.</subject><subject>Malnutrition.</subject><subject>Rats -- Physiology.</subject><subject>Stress (Physiology)</subject><subject>Muscles -- Physiology.</subject><title>Impacts of metabolic stress-induced malnutrition and oxidative stress on biochemical changes in the slow- and fast-twitch skeletal muscles of rats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2514nn122.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fj86j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9593tw93h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T20:48:39Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The mechanisms by which Angiopoietin-1 (Ang-1) modulates the survival of human endothelial cells were investigated. Ang-1 inhibited both TNFalpha-induced and serum deprivation-evoked apoptosis, an effect which was associated with attenuation of caspase activation, inhibition of Smac release from the mitochondria, up-regulation of Survivin-1 expression (IAPs member) and a significant activation of the pro-survival PI-3 kinase/AKT pathway. In addition, Ang-1 activated, in a time-dependent fashion, both the anti-apoptotic ERK1/2 and pro-apoptotic p38 MAP kinases. Ang-1-evoked ERK1/2 activation was mediated in part through the PI-3 kinase pathway, whereas both, the PI-3 kinase and ERK1/2 attenuated p38 MAP kinase activation. We conclude that Ang-1 promotes endothelial cell survival through several pathways including the PI-3 kinase/AKT and ERK1/2 pathways, up-regulation of Survivin-1 as well as inhibition of Smac release and caspase activity. The preferential activation of these anti-apoptotic effects, as opposed to the activation of pro-apoptotic p38 MAP kinase, results in a net survival response.</description><creator>Harfouche, Rania.</creator><contributor>Dhindsa, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Hussain, S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Apoptosis.</subject><subject>Glycoproteins.</subject><subject>Endothelium.</subject><title>Modulation of endothelial cell survival by the angiopoietin-1Tie-2 receptor pathway</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/736666340.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9593tw93h</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):38125</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>