<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:27:31Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34575" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x346d589w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The four studies in this thesis deal with peripheral and central factors in phantom limb phenomena. Study 1 documents sensations referred to the phantom limb during transcutaneous electrical nerve stimulation (TENS) applied at the outer ears, face, and torso. The results suggest that some phantom sensations are maintained by activity of sympathetic fibers in the stump. Other sensations appear not to involve a peripheral mechanism. Studies 2 and 3 focus on sympathetic nervous system correlates of phantom sensations reported during TENS applied at the outer ears and contralateral leg. The results indicate that TENS significantly reduces the intensity of phantom limb paresthesias whereas a placebo control has no effect. Significant relationships between (a) phantom limb intensity and (b) stump skin conductance and temperature suggest that a cycle of sympathetic-efferent-somatic-afferent activity explains phantom limb paresthesias. Skin temperature was significantly lower at the stump than the intact limb in amputees with phantom limb pain (PLP), but not in those with a painless phantom, or no phantom limb at all, indicating that PLP is associated with reduced blood flow to the stump. Study 4 examines PLP that resembles pain experienced in the limb before amputation. These somatosensory memories constitute compelling evidence of a purely central component of PLP. Finally, amputees with and without PLP could not be differentiated by scores on personality, depression, or anxiety inventories. The results of the four studies indicate that the experience of phantom limb paresthesias involves a central mechanism that acts on peripheral structures whereas others qualities of experience depend exclusively on activation of central neural structures. Implications for treatment, research, and clinical practice are discussed.</description><creator>Katz, Joel, 1954-</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Amputees -- Psychology</subject><subject>Phantom limb -- Research</subject><title>Painful and non-painful phantom limbs : the influence of peripheral and central factors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859h28b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x346d589w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pr76f519r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ly-6 molecules are glycosylphosphatidyl inositol (GPI)-anchored cell surface proteins found on hematopoetic cells. Their functions are unknown. Some studies suggest functions in lymphocyte activation while others suggest an involvement in migration or tissue localization. There is also evidence for their participation in intercellular adhesion which is consistent with both of the above functions. Our approach to understanding their function is to identify the molecules with which they interact. Studying primarily Ly-6E, our strategy was to create a soluble form of Ly-6E. This was done using the expression vector pEXV-3 containing an Ly-6E DNA fragment modified to encode the Ly-6E protein lacking the hydrophobic C-terminal signal for GPI-anchor attachment. This construct was transiently transfected in Cos 7 cells. Expression of soluble Ly-6E was confirmed by immunoprecipitation. The Ly-6E protein was expressed at a preparative level and I developed the purification procedure using sep-pac and HPLC. The first experiments were performed in the development of the procedures for crosslinking soluble radioactively labelled Ly-6E to its natural ligand(s).</description><creator>Saulnier, Giselle.</creator><contributor>Palfree, Roger (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Production of a recombinant soluble form of mouse differentiation antigen Ly-6E and its use in ligand studies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278v90z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f519r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:db78td80g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigated the hypothesis that delayed first language acquisition impedes syntactic learning in a second language. English syntactic skills of two deaf groups and one control group were investigated. One group of deaf subjects acquired a first language on schedule in early childhood, American Sign Language (ASL), and commenced learning English at school age. The other deaf group had significantly delayed first language acquisition, and began learning both ASL and English at school. Two English tasks were administered, grammatical judgement and syntactic comprehension. The stimuli were grammatical and ungrammatical exemplars of six types of syntactic structure ranging from simple to complex. The results supported the hypothesis and were consistent across all tasks. The delayed, first language learners were significantly less accurate in grammatical judgement and comprehension and significantly slower in response latency. These findings indicate that early first language acquisition is critical for successful second language syntactic learning.</description><creator>Lock, Elizabeth A. (Elizabeth Ann)</creator><contributor>Mayberry, R. I. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1996</date><subject>Psychology, Cognitive.</subject><subject>Language, Linguistics.</subject><title>Critical period effects on the acquisition of English syntax by deaf individuals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b2773x35c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/db78td80g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w0892c491</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The neuromuscular junction is a complex structure resulting from the interaction of an innervating neuron and skeletal muscle fiber. The neuron releases a molecule called agrin which acts via a muscle specific tyrosine kinase, MuSK, to initiate the localized differentiation and specialization of the muscle membrane at the synapse. A defining characteristic of the postsynaptic aspect neuromuscular junction is the concentration of acetylcholine receptors (AChRs) at the crests of junctional folds. Also clustered to these sites is the dystrophin associated protein (DAP) complex, a collection of proteins previously associated with muscular dystrophy and synapse formation. A central component of this complex, dystroglycan, had previously been shown to bind to agrin with high affinity. Inhibition studies that blocked agrin binding to dystroglycan indicated that dystroglycan might be required for synapse formation. In addition, several properties of dystroglycan, including its ability to co-cluster with the AChR and to bind both the neural and muscle forms of agrin, made it an obvious candidate as the putative co-receptor for MuSK. Based on these results we have attempted to define the role of dystroglycan in synaptogenesis. We studied nerve muscle co-cultures derived from Xenopus embryos and found that dystroglycan is present at almost all neural agrin and AChR clusters. This holds true even in developing synapses as well as in extrasynaptic clusters of AChRs. AChR and dystroglycan aggregates can be induced in vitro, by treating myotubes with agrin and/or exogenous laminin. The AChR clusters formed by laminin application were larger and more dense then those formed by agrin treatments and could be inhibited by the addition of anti-laminin antiserum or laminin fragments that do not self-polymerize. In addition, laminin, unlike agrin, was found to induce AChR and dystroglycan clustering independent of MuSK activation. The introduction of an antisense dystroglycan construct into the C2C12 muscle cell line and the resulting reduction in expressed dystroglycan on myotubes also had little effect on phosphorylation but instead reduced the number of agrin induced AChR clusters on myotubes. These finding suggested that dystroglycan is not the co-receptor for MuSK but rather functions at a point in AChR clustering downstream of agrin-MuSK signaling. When similar experiments were conducted on dystroglycan null myotubes we found that these myotubes respond to agrin in a manner similar to wild-type myotubes but that the AChR clusters formed on null myotubes were two to three times larger, half as dense and significantly less stable. Synapses in chimeric mice with dystroglycan deficient muscle were similarly affected. In culture and in vivo the absence of dystroglycan also resulted in the disruption of laminin, perlecan and acetylcholinesterase localization to AChR clusters but did not affect rapsyn or agrin localization. Finally, I present unpublished observations that suggest that the close association of dystroglycan with rapsyn and AChRs may not result from a direct interaction between dystroglycan and rapsyn. From these results we propose that dystroglycan is a key element of a "trap" required for the consolidation and stabilization
ofAChR clusters and that dystroglycan·basal lamina interactions are necessary for the
assembly ofthe synaptic basal lamina.</description><creator>Jacobson, Christian B.</creator><contributor>Carbonetto, Salvator (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Myoneural junction.</subject><subject>Dystrophin.</subject><subject>Glycoproteins.</subject><title>The role of dystroglycan in the formation of the neuromuscular junction /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3484zj43p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w0892c491</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75df21r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation is a comparison of local church conditions in three German Protestant church districts during the National Socialist era: the Nauen district in the Brandenburg Church Province of the Old Prussian Union Church, the Pima district in the Saxon Evangelical Lutheran Land Church and the Ravensburg district in the Wurttemberg Evangelical Land Church. It focuses on the attitudes and roles of the pastors, curates and vicars who served in the primarily rural parishes of these districts, analyzes the effect of the 'national renewal' that accompanied the National Socialist seizure of power upon the church conditions in their parishes, and probes their own attitudes toward the prevalent religious nationalism of the day. Following a comparison of the controversies surrounding pastoral appointments in Nauen, Pima and Ravensburg, the study examines the nature and intensity of church-political conflict in each of the districts during the National Socialist era. Finally, the study closes with a consideration of clerical attitudes toward the National Socialist euthanasia programme and the antisemitism that led to the Holocaust. Drawing on official church correspondence at three levels (parish, district and land church), parish newsletters, accounts of meetings throughout the period, the study concludes that while these Protestant clergymen generally shared a common conservative nationalist outlook, the manifestation of the church struggle in their parishes took diverse forms. Parishioners in Nauen and especially Pima (but not Ravensburg) displayed a high level of interest in their churches in 1933, in part an effect of the strength of the national renewal in their regions. In Nauen, the church struggle was channelled into the quest for control of pastoral appointments. In Pima, the church struggle mirrored the course of events in Saxony as a whole, and included extreme 'German Christians,' radical members of the Confessing Church and a moderate movement for church</description><creator>Jantzen, Kyle.</creator><contributor>Hoffmann, Peter (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Protestant churches -- Clergy.</subject><subject>Church and state -- Germany -- History -- 1933-1945.</subject><subject>Germany -- History -- 1933-1945.</subject><title>Protestant clergymen and church-political conflict in national socialist Germany : studies from rural Brandenburg, Saxony and Wurttemberg</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4j03d155h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75df21r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773x36n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Crickets provide a useful model system to study how animals analyze sound frequency. While much is known about how sound frequency is represented by central neurons and in behavior, little is yet known about auditory receptor neurons. I investigated physiological and anatomical properties of auditory receptor fibers (ARFs) and functional organization of their axon terminals, using single-unit recording and staining techniques. Behavioral experiments suggest that crickets are sensitive to two broad frequency ranges, centered at 4--5 kHz for acoustic communication and at 25--50 kHz for predator detection. However, cricket ARFs fall into three distinct populations, based on characteristic frequency (CF; low frequency, ~3--5.5 kHz; mid frequency, 9--12 kHz; ultrasound, ≥18 kHz). One striking characteristic of single ARFs is the occurrence of multiple sensitivity peaks at different frequencies, which implies that the wide audible range of crickets is mediated by these multiple sensitivity peaks, even though CFs of ARFs are clustered at the three small ranges. To understand how populations of ARFs code sound intensity, level-response functions are examined. Physiological parameters derived from level-response functions are diverse, and are systematically related to threshold within each population. Low-frequency ARFs comprise two distinct anatomical types, based on the distributions of axon terminals, which also differ physiologically. Thus, based on CF and anatomy, cricket ARFs can be classified into four distinct populations. To understand how information flows from peripheral to central neurons, the positions of varicosities, i.e. output sites, of ARF axon terminals are mapped on a two-dimensional coordinate system. In crickets, the ARF axon terminals are functionally organized with respect to frequency and intensity. Anatomical organization with respect to threshold is related to physiological organization, which may reduce non-linear effects in postsynaptic</description><creator>Imaizumi, Kazuo.</creator><contributor>Pollack, Gerald S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Auditory perception.</subject><subject>Audio frequency.</subject><subject>Crickets -- Behavior.</subject><subject>Sensory receptors.</subject><title>Peripheral representation of sound frequency in cricket auditory system : beyond tonotopy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sv417.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773x36n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mk617</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research examined the relationship between client emotional expression and the level of working alliance between therapist and client. The data were collected from 24 psychotherapy sessions conducted by exemplary psychotherapists of different theoretical orientations. The results of the quantitative analysis indicated that there was no significant linear relationship between the level of intensity of client emotional expression and the level of working alliance. Client emotional expression occurred independently of the level of the working alliance. Using a qualitative method, the study restricted its sample to 5 episodes each from the high and low working alliance sessions in order to examine therapeutic processes surrounding client emotional expression more closely. It was found that the nature of emotional expression and the interaction between therapist and client were quite different in episodes taken from the high and the low alliance sessions. In the high alliance sessions, clients expressed their troubling feelings as they examined their problems. Client emotional expressions were signs of productive therapeutic process. On the other hand, in the low alliance sessions, clients expressed anger and frustration toward their therapists for certain breaches of their relationship. Independently of the differing theoretical orientations, the therapeutic process appeared to converge particularly in the low alliance sessions, showing a similar pattern of therapist and client transactions. In addition to the findings, the study proposed a qualitative method suited for examining a wide variety of questions arising from clinical practice.</description><creator>Iwakabe, Shigeru.</creator><contributor>Stalikas, Anastassus (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Psychotherapy.</subject><subject>Therapist and patient.</subject><subject>Emotions.</subject><title>The relationship between client emotional expression and the working alliance : an exploration of emotional expression episodes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fq977w702.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mk617</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6h440v26h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Over the past two decades, Taylor (1983; Taylor &amp; Brown, 1988) has explored the tendency of individuals to develop positive illusions in coping with stressful, or traumatic events. These illusions consist of unrealistic positive self evaluations, exaggerated perceptions of control or mastery, and unrealistic optimism. According to Taylor, illusions are important in accomplishing several tasks associated with successful adaptation, namely, search for meaning, regaining a sense of mastery, and restoring self-esteem through processes of social comparison. The purpose of the study was threefold: (a) to explore the construct of positive illusions (PI), (b) to explore employees' use of PI in coping with a stressful work event, and (c) to discover how PI, temporal distance, level of perceived stress, and a priming manipulation affect the type and frequency of inferences made while responding to items taken from a coping inventory. The study was conducted in two phases. In Phase I, 209 nurses responded to a questionnaire which identified their level of PI, perceptions of occupational climate, and job satisfaction. They were also asked to describe a stressful work situation, and their appraisals and coping strategies used to manage the event. Results demonstrated that the PI construct for this population was best identified by enhanced self-perception, high dispositional optimism, and low internal locus of control. PI were associated with high self-efficacy for resolving the stressful event, appraisals of challenge, positive reappraisal and self-controlling coping, and the nonuse of escape-avoidance coping. In Phase II, 36 nurses "high" and "low" in PI were assigned to two priming conditions. Nurses participated in a think-aloud procedure during which time they rated 16 coping items in relation to their previously identified work event and gave reasons for their ratings. After protocol analysis, results demonstrated that, (a) the type of prime used affected the consistency of recall even after controlling for temporal distance, and (b) positive illusions, prime, and time interact to produce significantly different patterns of self-statements and contextual inferences for the four groups. The results demonstrate that measures which rely on the recall of coping strategies need to be treated with considerable caution.</description><creator>Freedman, Sandra.</creator><contributor>Dumont, Frank (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Adjustment (Psychology)</subject><subject>Nurses -- Job stress.</subject><subject>Organizational change.</subject><title>Positive illusions, coping, and inferential reasoning during the process of organizational change</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8w32r722x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6h440v26h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h347q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The goal of this study was to verify if differences in respirable dust and respirable quartz concentrations exist with respect to the mines, the ore deposit types and the nature of workstations. One hundred and seventy-nine respirable dust samples were collected in the six mines studied, in compliance with the method recommended by the Institut de recherche en sante et securite du travail du Quebec (IRSST). Then, samples were analysed using X ray powder diffraction technique to determine respirable quartz concentrations. Results indicated statistically significant differences in the normalised exposure levels to respirable dust (p = 0.017), to respirable quartz (p &lt; 0.001) as well as the quartz percentage in the respirable dust (p &lt; 0.001) of the six mines studied. When grouped by ore deposit type, normalized exposure levels to respirable dust were not statistically different. However, statistically significant differences were noticed for normalized exposure levels to respirable quartz (p = 0.004) and respirable quartz percentage (p &lt; 0.001) according to ore deposit types. For all mines studied, respirable dust concentrations were all below the admissible exposure value whereas about 9% of the respirable quartz concentrations were equal or above the admissible exposure limit. Gold ore deposits hosted in quartz veins had the highest normalized respirable quartz exposure levels, as well as the highest percentage of quartz in the respirable dust when compared to gold ore deposits with sulfide lodes, the copper-zinc ore deposit and the disseminated gold ore deposit. The study also revealed that workers who worked in the ore crushing and hoisting departments as well as loading and transport had higher normalised exposure levels to respirable quartz than workers who worked in the drilling and blasting or those who worked in the maintenance department. In conclusion, this study stressed that quartz content in the mined rocks seems to be the most important factor influencing on respirable quartz concentrations in the mine worker's respiratory zone, but the relation between the two variables were not strongly correlated (Rs = 0.254, p = 0.005). Furthermore, the study showed that the gold ore deposits with quartz lodes had the highest normalized exposure levels to respirable quartz. Also, the workers assigned to ore crushing and hoisting departments as well as transport and loading had the highest exposure levels to respirable quartz. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Gagné, Lise.</creator><contributor>Dufresne, Andre (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Perrault, Guy (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Occupational Health and Safety.</subject><title>Exposition professionnelle aux poussières respirables et au quartz respirable dans les mines métalliques du Nord-Ouest québecois</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0p096876n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h347q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Occupational Health</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:05741t47n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>To argue that inferences drawn from a test of writing are valid, empirical evidence must demonstrate that the test adequately represents the construct it is designed to measure (Messick, 1998). The writing component of the Canadian Academic English Language (CAEL) Assessment, was developed in the early 1990's to represent the construct of English in use for academic purposes (EAP). Since that time, EAP approaches have been criticised within the fields of both language testing (Alderson, 1993; Clapham, 2001) and genre and composition studies (Freedman, 1999). Writing is currently viewed as a "site of social and ideological action" (Schryer, 1994), embedded within, and interacting with the disciplinary, historical, political and cultural contexts in which it acts (Freedman and Medway, 1994; Norton, 1995). Informed by cultural-historical Activity Theory (Cole and Engestrom, 1994; Vygotsky, 1989), this research examines the "social actions" which characterise performance on the CAEL writing test in relation to two other tests of English as a Second Language (L2) writing, the personal essay and the timed-impromptu essay. In Study 1, the semiotic potential of each test is defined by analysis of the verbal accounts of 4 raters and 20 test takers. In their accounts, what separates the EAP writing test from the other tests of writing is the academic expertise the EAP test elicits. In Study 2, the scores from n = 375 EAP essays and n = 271 cloze tests are compared in order to examine how much of the variance in each test is accounted for by academic expertise. Taken together, Studies 1 and 2 provide empirical evidence of what performance on the EAP writing test means to those engaged in the activity of testing. Evidence that the EAP writing test represents a construct, which has been reconceptualized to reflect current theories of writing, addresses the criticism of EAP-based tests and provides a model of inter-disciplinary test validation in relation to evolving construct</description><creator>Fox, Janna D.</creator><contributor>Turner, Carolyn E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>English language -- Study and teaching -- Foreign speakers.</subject><subject>English language -- Examinations.</subject><title>It's all about meaning : L2 test validation in and through the landscape of an evolving construct</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440v27s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/05741t47n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Second Language Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pn89d829r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation explores the conflicts, contradictions and paradoxes inherent in the lives of those women who, as artists and academics, seek to connect their personal and professional lives in their work. It explores how creativity and the pursuit of self-knowledge relate to the lives of female artists and academics. The dissertation arises from a study of my own experience as woman, writer and academic. Inquiries into creativity and feminist, critical and cultural theory provide the framework for examining how the identity of the female artist is shaped within the patriarchal institution of academia, an institution originally created by, and for, men and still strongly influenced by this history. These inquiries allow a deeper understanding of the impact of this institution on the life and work of the female artist both within and beyond the academy. As a self-study, the distinctive voice of this dissertation is developed through autobiographical narratives, journals, letters and a development of personal metaphors, as well as through a dialogue with others. This is therefore a performative text in which narratives map a process of transformation that traces the artist's path from silence to voice. This work has important implications for women in higher education as self-study is revealed to be an essential methodological instrument for the articulation of alternative, authentic perspectives of marginalized and under-represented women. Moreover, the acknowledgement of the academic/artist paradigm in teacher education opens the path for a re-viewing of the metaphors of self-denial, impersonation and masks that are part of the landscape of teacher knowledge.</description><creator>Gamelin, Anastasia Kamanos.</creator><contributor>Beer, Ann (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Women college teachers.</subject><subject>Women artists.</subject><title>Home and away : the female artist in academia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sv42h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pn89d829r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04dr29r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Retinopathy of prematurity (ROP) is a potentially blinding retinal disorder, which results from the exposure of the premature infant to hyperoxia. The diagnosis and the assessment of severity of ROP are based on the degree of retinal vascular abnormalities (such as avascular peripheral retina and neovascularisation), which are observed upon fundus examination. However, even if the vascular consequences of ROP are resolved, functional sequels such as high myopia, anisometropia and strabismus, may persist through adulthood. In severe cases, even more dramatic consequences, namely retinal detachment and blindness, may also occur. In oxygen-induced retinopathy (OIR), the animal model of ROP, hyperoxia-induced vasoobliteration and neovascularisation have been studied extensively in mice, rats, cats and dogs. However, the functional and ultrastructural changes that might result from the exposure to hyperoxia have not yet been examined in details. In this study, we report functional, as assessed with the electroretinogram (ERG), and structural, determined with histological sections of the retina, consequences of postnatal hyperoxia which took place during a period of intense retinal maturation, that is, the first 14 days of life of Sprague Dawley rats. Our results indicate that there is a sigmoidal dose-response correlation between the increasingly longer duration of oxygen exposure, and the decrease in the postreceptoral retinal activity, as revealed by the gradual reduction in the amplitudes of rod and cone dominated b-waves and oscillatory potentials. Furthermore, the cone function appeared to be slightly more affected than that of the rod. Also, of all the ERG components the oscillatory potentials, especially the short latency ones, appeared to be the most sensitive to the hyperoxia. The gradual thinning of the outer plexiform layer (OPL) is also correlated with the duration of oxygen exposure, while the reduction in the number of horizontal cells is not. Secondly, our experimental approach has allowed us to evidence a period of higher oxygen susceptibility (a window), which takes place during the second week of life of the newborn rats, more specifically around postnatal day 10. Several oxygen exposures of short duration, which included this period, were shown to be more detrimental to the rod and cone function than longer exposures taking place prior to or after this window. This would suggest that during the normal maturation process, the immature retina is not equally sensitive to the hyperoxic insult, presumably because specific retinal structures (synapses in OPL) are targeted by oxygen. Finally, Trolox C, a potent water-soluble antioxidant, partially prevents the functional and structural consequences of OIR. The prophylactic effect appears to benefit more the rod function than that of the cone. To conclude, we believe that this new knowledge will help us understand the pathophysiological processes at the origin of oxygen toxicity in the immature retina, thus, significantly increasing our insights on the human form of this disease, namely ROP, which as a result, will be instrumental in devising new therapeutic avenues to help fight this potentially debilitating retinal disorder.</description><creator>Dembinska-Knypinski, Olga.</creator><contributor>Lachapelle, Pierre (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Structural and functionnal [sic] consequences of oxygen induced retinopathy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fn42h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dr29r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v712f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of these experiments was to investigate learning and memory extensively in two nonverbal domains (olfactory and visual), and to determine similarities and differences in the function of the neural substrates that subserve these modalities. Two complementary methodological approaches were taken: (1) examination of learning and retention in patients with resection from left (LR) or right (RR) temporal lobe, and (2) study of brain function via Positron Emission Tomography (PET) of healthy subjects during memory processing. Two parallel recognition tests were developed (one olfactory, one visual) that examined memory at three stages: following a single exposure to test stimuli, after four exposures, and following a 24hr delay interval. In the olfactory patient study, LR and RR groups performed significantly worse than the healthy control subjects, with no difference between the patient groups; thus suggesting a lack of hemispheric superiority for this task. The PET study of healthy individuals supported the bilateral participation of piriform cortex during olfactory recognition. The results from these two studies, along with findings from animal work, suggest that the piriform cortices may play a role in odor memory processing, not simply in perception. On the face memory task, LR and RR patients showed different results. Only RR patients were impaired, while LR patients did not perform differently from controls. This unique face learning paradigm was sensitive to right temporal lobe damage, and correctly classified patients by side of resection with a sensitivity rate of 82% and specificity rate of 79%, suggesting its possible utility as a clinical tool. PET face memory findings indicated greater participation of fusiform regions during long-term recognition, and greater right prefrontal activity during short-term recognition, when these conditions are directly compared to each other. Finally, PET was used to study the same healthy subjects performing parallel odor and face working-memory tasks, focusing on regions previously shown to be important for working memory. Results revealed similar regions of activation in dorsolateral prefrontal cortex in the two modalities. This indicates an overlap in the brain regions that process olfactory and visual information when the same cognitive manipulations are being carried out online.</description><creator>Dade, Lauren A.</creator><contributor>Gotman, M. Jones (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Learning -- Physiological aspects.</subject><subject>Memory -- Physiological aspects.</subject><title>Brain structures subserving olfactory and visual learning and recognition : similarities and differences in nonverbal memory processing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vq27zq204.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v712f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:765372804</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study sought to investigate the application of artificial neural networks (ANN) and fuzzy inference systems (FIS) to variably saturated soil moisture (VSSM) redistribution modelling. An enhanced approach to such modelling, that lessens computation costs, facilitates input preparation, handles data uncertainty, and realistically simulates soil moisture redistribution, was our main objective. An initial review of existing soil hydrology models provided greater insight into current modelling challenges and a general classification of the models. The application of AI techniques as alternative tools for soil hydrology modelling was explored. A one-dimensional (1D) model based on ANN and FIS was developed. To estimate fluxes more accurately, multiple ANNs were trained and combined by way of an FIS. The main body of the model employed the ANN-FIS module to model soil moisture redistribution throughout the profile. When tested against the SWAP93 model, the ANN-FIS model gave a good match and maximum error of &lt;8%; however, it did not show a notable computation cost shift. The investigation proceeded with development of another ANN-based 1D modelling approach. This time, the soil profile or flow region, regardless of its depth, was divided into ten equal parts (compartments). The ANN was trained to estimate moisture patterns for a whole soil profile, from the previous day's soil moisture pattern and boundary conditions, and the current day's boundary conditions. The model was tested against SWAP93 where an average SCORE of 90.4 indicated a good match. The computation cost of the ANN-based model was about one-third that of SWAP93. At this point the study sought to develop a 3D modelling approach. The ANN was trained to estimate the nodal soil moisture changes through time under the influence of six neighbouring nodes (in a 3D space, two on each axis). The model's accuracy was tested against the SWMS-3D model. An average SCORE of 91 and a 15-fold decrease in computation costs showed a quite acceptable performance. Results suggest that this approach is potentially capable of realistically modelling 3D VSSM redistribution with less computation time. Finally, pros and cons of these ANN-based modelling approaches are compared and contrasted, and some recommendations on future work are given.</description><creator>Davary, Kamran.</creator><contributor>Bonnell, R. B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Soil moisture -- Mathematical models.</subject><subject>Neural networks (Computer science)</subject><title>Soil moisture redistribution modeling with artificial neural networks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1544br114.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/765372804</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:08612q29z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, we develop a first principle technique to study linear AC and the nonlinear DC quantum transport in diffusive conductors. Starting from Buttiker's theory for AC and DC transport, the emittance and nonlinear DC conductance are found in terms of the scattering matrix and it's functional derivative. New theoretical tools are developed to compute the functional derivative of the scattering matrix, which would otherwise be unaccessible. These results allows us to compute the linear AC and the nonlinear DC conductance for a diffusive conductor from first principles, for the first time in literature. The sample-to-sample AC conductance fluctuations are computed for a diffusive conductor. In this regime the dynamic response of the conductor can either be capacitive or inductive, depending on impurity configuration. Our results also suggest a crossover for the AC conductance distribution, from a symmetric to a non symmetric distribution function as the number of impurities increases. A degree of generic behavior is discovered, in that the AC fluctuation amplitudes become independent of the strength of the impurities, although it depends on the impurity density. A sample-to-sample analysis of the nonlinear conductance fluctuations, in the diffusive regime, is also reported. In this situation the distribution function is found to be a symmetric Gaussian like function for small disorder and a symmetric exponentially decaying function for large disorder. An interesting result is that the conductance fluctuations increase in an exponential fashion with N, the number of impurities. We also considered in this thesis the magneto-conductance fluctuations of a quasi-1D quantum wire with artificial impurities (antidots). This problem can only be solved numerically because of the finite size of the artificial impurities. We develop a novel transfer matrix technique to solve the quantum scattering problem by computing the scattering wave function, as a function of the external magnetic field. The Landauer-Buttiker equation is used to compute the magneto-conductance. This work is motivated by the experimental study [1], where several conductance fluctuations anomalies were reported. Our numerical results give good quantitative agreement with the experimental data and confirms the physical picture obtained from the experiment.</description><creator>De Jesus, Tiago.</creator><contributor>Guo, Hong (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Physics, Electricity and Magnetism.</subject><title>Admittance fluctuations in nanostructures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hh18c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/08612q29z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t148fj78v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>High pressure (HP) processing has been emerging rapidly as a novel technique for non-thermal preservation of foods. Application of HP processing for shelf life extension of orange juice was the principal objective of the current research. To accomplish this objective, and to establish a scientific basis for HP processing of orange juice, a systemic approach was used which included the evaluation of: (a) HP inactivation kinetics of pectin methyl esterase (PME, the key enzyme in orange juice implicated with respect to quality changes), (b) destruction of spoilage microorganisms and changes in product quality, (c) HP process verification and finally, (d) storage studies on HP treated orange juice. In preliminary studies, the effect of HP treatment on indigenous microorganisms, texture and color of selected fresh fruits and vegetables were evaluated. Results showed that HP had a significant effect on the destruction of microorganisms. Product texture and color were mildly affected, often resembling the appearance of mildly heat-treated products. Pressure induced inactivation kinetics of pectin methyl esterase (PME) was investigated at pH 3.7 and 3.2 in freshly squeezed single strength (12.6°Brix) and concentrated (10--40° Brix) orange juice. Results showed a biphasic nature of pressure induced inactivation of PME in both juices. The first phase consisted of rapid change in inactivation of enzyme, designated as instantaneous pressure kill (IPK), due to pulse pressurization, followed by gradual inactivation of enzyme, characterized by a first order rate of inactivation during pressure hold-time. Combination treatment involving pressure cycle, pressure level and pressure hold-time was then evaluated for inactivation of PME using a response surface methodology. Overall, pressure pulse had a lower effect on inactivation of PME compared to other factors. Pressure destruction kinetics of Leuconostoc mesenteroides and Saccharomyces cerevisiae the spoilage organisms in orange juice, were then investigated. Pressure destruction kinetics followed the same dual effect behavior, as observed with PME inactivation. IPK effect increased with pressure cycles and was more pronounced with S. cerevisiae that Leu. mesenteroides. Storage studies of HP treated single strength and concentrated orange juice were conducted at selected temperatures (4, 10 and 20°C). Results showed that treated juice was microbiologically stable from a few days to several weeks depending on type of juice, storage temperature and processing conditions. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Basak, Sarmistha.</creator><contributor>Ramaswamy, H. S. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>High pressure (Technology)</subject><subject>Orange juice -- Quality.</subject><subject>Orange juice -- Storage.</subject><subject>Orange juice -- Preservation.</subject><title>Studies on high pressure processing of orange juice : enzyme inactivation, microbial destruction, and quality changes, process verification and storage</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8s45qb557.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t148fj78v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mn96g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Protein translation in mammalian cells can be divided into three stages: initiation, elongation, and termination, which require several factors. The peptide elongation factor 1A (eEF1A-1), which was formerly referred to as eEF-1alpha, is a guanosine triphosphate (GTP) binding protein and it is responsible for bringing aminoacyl-tRNA to the ribosomes in the process of protein synthesis. The S1/eEF1A-2 factor also referred to as S1, is an isoform of eEF1A-1. Both proteins are expressed from two distinct genes and share 92% identity in their amino acid sequences. Besides the tissue specific expression S1/eEF1A-2, little is known about the functions of the S1/cEF1A-2 isoform. The objective of this thesis is Thus to investigate the function of the newly discovered peptide elongation factor A-2. The fact that the eEF1A-1 and Sl/eEF1A-2 isoforms' expressions are inversely controlled during development, led me to hypothesise that S1/eEF1A-2 down-regulates eEF1A-1 expression. The goal of the present work was to establish whether S1/eEF1A-2 is responsible for the down-regulation of eEF1A-1 during development in brain, heart and muscle, and how its expression influences cell biology. To address this hypothesis, several cell lines were transduced with an adenovirus expressing S1/eEF1A-2. Ectopic expression of S1/eEF1A-2 in the cardiomyocyte cell line H9c2 led to a down-regulation of eEF1A-1. Similar findings were observed in neuron-differentiated P19 cells, Hela cells, and WI38 cells. Furthermore, S1/eEF1A-2 expression led to a reduced rate of peptide elongation as demonstrated by ribosomal transit time analyses. My data suggest that S1/eEF1A-2 may compete with eEF1A-1 in peptide elongation, leading to a reduced elongation rate, which could be responsible for the relative down-regulation of eEF1A-1. This would imply that terminally differentiated cells, which express high levels of S1/eEF1A-2 (neurones, myocytes, and cardiomyocytes), have a distinct kinetic of peptide elonga</description><creator>Bourbeau, Denis, 1971-</creator><contributor>Wang, Eugenia (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Characterization of S1eEF1A-2 function, a sister gene of elongation factor 1A-1</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/47429b857.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mn96g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hh19n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation asserts a strong connection between democratic culture and the novel form in the period 1832--1867. As England debated constitutional reform and the extension of the franchise, novelists Charles Dickens, Elizabeth Gaskell, and George Eliot endeavoured to define human communities on democratic terms. Drawing on work of contemporary political philosopher John Rawls to develop a methodology that considers constitutions and novelistic representations as analogous contexts for reasoning about shared political values and citizenship, this study provides readings of Bleak House, North and South, and Felix Holt that emphasize each novel's contribution to the period's ongoing deliberations about pluralism, justice, and the meaning of membership in democratic life. When read alongside Bentham's work on legislative reform, Bleak House offers a parallel model of social interaction that weighs the values of diversity of thought, security from coercion, and the nature of harmful actions. Felix Holt and North and South are novelistic contributions to defining and contesting the attributes of the new liberal citizen. Through their central characters, as well as in their respective novelistic practices, Eliot and Gaskell highlight the difficulty of uniting autonomous individuals with collective social groups, and this was as much a problem for literary practice in the period as it was for constitutional reform.</description><creator>Bentley, Colene.</creator><contributor>Wihl, Gary (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>English fiction -- 19th century -- History and criticism.</subject><subject>Social problems in literature.</subject><subject>Gaskell, Elizabeth Cleghorn, 1810-1865. North and south.</subject><subject>Eliot, George, 1819-1880. Felix Holt.</subject><subject>Dickens, Charles, 1812-1870. Bleak House.</subject><subject>Bentham, Jeremy, 1748-1832.</subject><title>Constituting political interest : community, citizenship, and the British novel, 1832-1867</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zw13x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hh19n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602250r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We introduce and study new lattice gas models of hydrodynamics to simulate thermal fluids in non-equilibrium. The new approach consists in modifying the conventional Lattice Gas Cellular Automata method for fluids by removing the constraints of the Fermi exclusion principle and by introducing internal potential energy levels for the particles. These modifications allow the effective employment of Monte-Carlo dynamics for the evolution of the models, so that the temperature is defined in a natural way, and the introduction of interactions becomes straightforward. Because the transport properties of fluids determine their behavior in non-equilibrium, we study in detail the effect of our modifications on transport coefficients. We derive expressions for these coefficients in two ways: from Chapman-Enskog expansions and from linear response theory. Because of the potential energy, the transport properties are more similar to those of real fluids than are conventional LGCA models with kinetic energy only: the bulk viscosity is non-zero and thermal diffusion is well defined over a range of densities and temperatures. We construct several models to illustrate the advantages and implications of our approach. One model is used to study the local temperature distribution in a simulation of Rayleigh Benard convection. Another is used to introduce interactions between particles and to simulate the 1st order phase separation of a fluid into the regions of low and high density. This latter model is also used to study the dynamics of interfaces between the phases. We observe the effects of inertia at the interface and demonstrate that the mean square width of an initially flat interface scales as t3/2 for late times t.</description><creator>Baran, Oleh.</creator><contributor>Hattis, Dik (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Physics, Fluid and Plasma.</subject><title>Numerical studies of thermal hydrodynamics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t796w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602250r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zs25xb21x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Interferons (IFNs) are polypeptides that protect the body from microbial infection by the activation of genes that inhibit the replication of such pathogens. STAT1 is a transcription factor that is activated by IFNs and virus infection, and propagates signals to the nucleus by binding DNA enhancer elements to induce the expression of IFN-stimulated genes (ISGs). One such gene product is the double-stranded RNA (dsRNA)dependent protein kinase, PKR. PKR is an important determinant of host resistance since it has the ability to bind dsRNA, an intermediate produced during viral replication, and to phosphorylate the eukaryotic translation initiation factor-2alpha (eIF-2alpha), a modification that inhibits of protein synthesis. Additionally, recent findings have shown that PKR can modulate various signaling pathways. The objective of this research was to understand the involvement of PKR in the IFN signaling pathways. We observed that the catalytic domain of PKR interacts with the DNA-binding region of STAT1 in vitro and in vivo. Overexpression of catalytic mutants of PKR blocked STAT1 DNA-binding and ISG expression upon IFN or dsRNA treatment. The capacity of catalytic mutants of PKR to negatively regulate STAT1 DNA-binding is attributed to its ability to interact with STAT1 since in cells lacking PKR or expressing an RNA-binding mutant of PKR, unable to associate with STAT1, STAT1 displays augmented activity. A mutant of STAT1 (TM) unable to interact with PKR displayed elevated biochemical and biological activities; findings consistent with the role of PKR in regulating STAT1 function. Alternatively, the interaction between PKR and STAT1 has the ability to inhibit PKR activity in vitro and in vivo; a phenomenon not observed with STAT1 TM. In parallel, PKR was also found to interact with TYK2, the upstream activator of STAT1. IFN treatment promoted the dissociation of PKR from TYK2 in a manner dependent on TYK2 kinase activity. Furthermore, we observed that TYK2 phosphorylates the amino terminus of PKR in vitro and in vivo on tyrosine. Taken together, PKR appears to function as an important scaffolding protein for the IFN signaling pathways. Alternatively, PKR activity itself is also regulated at multiple steps along this pathway. Thus, it appears that there is an intimate cross-talk between components of the JAK/STAT pathway and translational machinery.</description><creator>Wong, Andrew Hoi-Tao, 1974-</creator><contributor>Koromilas, Antonis E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Interdependence of the double-stranded RNA-activated protein kinase, PKR, and the transcription factor, STAT1, in intgerferon signalin and translatioinal control</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xn35r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zs25xb21x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3n204081h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis includes four studies investigating neural correlates underlying pitch perception, and effects of tonal context on this percept. Each study addressed the issue from a unique methodological perspective. The first study confirmed that tonal context can affect the way a tone's pitch is perceived. In this study, normal listeners made pitch discriminations between tones varying in pitch and/or timbre, a difficult task when presented in isolation. Increasing tonal context increased performance, with melodic context providing the most facilitation. A similar task was presented to patients with unilateral focal excisions in the temporal lobe. Patients with right but not left temporal lobe lesions were impaired at using melodic cues to facilitate performance. Posterior extent of the lesions did not affect results, implying that right anterior temporal regions can process pitch information relative to tones heard previously. A functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) study using a similar task with normal listeners found converging evidence. Melodic context produced the most activity in right anterior superior temporal gyrus (STG), as well as the most facilitation behaviorally. A positron emission tomography study investigating neural processing of song stimuli broadened the investigation to include a comparison between musical and linguistic processing. Left frontal and temporal structures known to be involved in language processing were active when subjects attended to song lyrics, and right temporal-lobe structures were again implicated in melodic processing, suggesting that a song's lyrics and melodies are processed separately. These studies find pitch processing in tonal contexts to involve right temporal-lobe structures. The right anterior STG in particular appears to be involved in processing pitch relative to previously heard tones. This suggests that the right anterior STG processes tones with respect to their tonal context, which entails holding contextual tones in memory while processing subsequent tones. This region has connections to right dorsolateral frontal areas previously implicated in tonal working memory, possibly providing a mechanism for holding contextual tones in memory. Supporting this theory, all contextual conditions in the fMRI study produced activity in right dorsolateral frontal cortex.</description><creator>Warrier, Catherine M.</creator><contributor>Zatorre, Robert (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Musical pitch.</subject><subject>Hearing.</subject><title>Contextual effects in pitch processing : investigating neural correlates using complementary methodologies</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2j62s6432.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3n204081h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773x386</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The ability to suggest a means of solving a novel problem through the remembering and recalling of previous experiences is a tenet of the Case-based reasoning (CBR) paradigm. This approach is well suited for the engineering design domain since an effective and efficient solution can often be synthesized based upon previous designs rather than starting from scratch. Although significant advances have been made, this technique suffers disadvantages when dealing with complex design problems and novel situations. This thesis aims at automating CBR's adaptation mechanism, that up until now had yet to be fully explored, as a way for solving the non-routine design of complex structures such as electromagnetic devices. We propose a system architecture that combines the strength of multiple reasoning paradigms built on top of CBR. It flexibly uses different knowledge sources, fully exploits its experiences, and provides a dynamic environment where different alternatives can be examined under different abstraction views. In addition, such a framework can be used to broaden the spectrum of design problem solving from routine and non-routine to future creative design.</description><creator>Vo, Quang Vinh, 1959-</creator><contributor>Lowther, David (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Case-based reasoning approach for the non-routine design of electromagnetic devices</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225c71r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773x386</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jq085m982</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>One hundred nine HIV seronegative gay (HSG) males from the Montreal gay community, drawn from downtown health clinics, advertisements in gay friendly newspapers, and referrals from colleagues, were examined with respect to how they were coping with the HIV and AIDS epidemic (July 3, 1981 to August, 1998). Participants were asked to complete both a detailed demographic questionnaire and the Ways of Coping Questionnaire. Coping theory and coping research relevant to the research at hand are discussed in detail. Results indicate that HSG males in Montreal are coping most frequently with the HIV and AIDS epidemic through the "escape/avoidance" coping strategy, and least frequently through "confrontive coping." In addition it was found that the only significant results, by age group, relate to the "accepting responsibility" and "escape/avoidance" coping strategies. Research limitations, suggestions for future research, and clinical implications are discussed.</description><creator>Watson, Scott C. A.</creator><contributor>Talley, W. M. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1999</date><subject>Adjustment (Psychology)</subject><subject>Stress (Psychology)</subject><subject>Gay men -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>AIDS phobia.</subject><title>Coping with the HIV and AIDS epidemic in HIV seronegative gay males in Montreal</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75df24k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jq085m982</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h3498</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ubiquitin is a highly conserved 8 kDa protein whose many cellular functions are mediated by its covalent ligation to other proteins. Conjugation of ubiquitin is a multistep process involving a ubiquitin-activating enzyme (E1), ubiquitin-conjugating enzymes (UBCs or E2s), and ubiquitin protein ligases (E3s). The multi-ubiquitination of substrates marks them for degradation by the 26S proteasome. Previously, rat UBC4 isoforms homologous to S. cerevisiae UBC4/UBC5 were cloned and characterized (Wing and Jain, 1995) (Wing et al., 1996). The UBC4-1 isoform is highly expressed in the testis, and the UBC4-testis isoform is induced in round spermatids. This thesis describes the identification and characterization of E3s interacting with these UBC4 isoforms expressed in the rat testis. First, the isolation and characterization of a novel E3 from rat testis extracts, E3Histone, is described. E3Histone mediates conjugation of ubiquitin to histones in a UBC4-dependent manner. Interestingly, E3Histone was immunodepleted by antibodies against Cdc27, a subunit of the a̲naphase-p̲romoting c̲omplex (APC), an E3 which plays a critical role in the regulation of the cell cycle. However, E3Histone and the APC are distinct complexes. Gel filtration resolved the 600 kDa E3Histone from the 1500 kDa APC. E3Histone interacts preferentially with UBC4, whereas the APC interacts preferentially with UbcH10 and shows specificity for the substrate cyclin. E3Histone and the APC may be members of a newly-recognized family of combinatorial E3s that share some common core subunits, such as CDC27, yet possess distinct subunits that confer upon them their respective E2 and substrate specificities. In addition, E3Histone activity was detected in extracts from various purified germ cells. Induction of UBC4 may lead to the increased ubiquitination of histories and together with E3 Histone may play a role in the chromatin condensation that occurs during spermatid maturation. Secondly, the characterization of a HECT domain E3, Rat100, is described. UBC4-1 and UBC4-testis were found to transfer ubiquitin to Rat100 in vitro. Immunoblotting showed that Rat100 has a molecular weight of 300 kDa, and that the developmental and cell-specific expression of Rat100 correlates with that of UBC4. The induction of Rat 100 may playa role in the activation of ubiquitin-dependent proteolysis during spermatogenesis.</description><creator>Oughtred, Rose W.</creator><contributor>Wing, Simon (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Characterization of ubiquitin-protein ligases in the testis interacting with the UBC4UBC5 ubiquitin-conjugating enzymes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021g91h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h3498</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644t25c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:46:37Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fragmentation by blasting is distinct from other method of rock breakage due mainly to the short time scale involved in the application of stresses. In the present work, the dynamic rock properties, applicable to non-static fragmentation process have been measured and compared with measured values of other fracture related properties. Further, these are examined to establish correlation with respect to their physical, mineralogical and micro-structural characteristics. The rock types selected for the present work ranged from nearly homogenous isotropic rock to an-isotropic rocks. The nearly isotropic rock were represented by three different types of granites. The an-isotropic rocks consisted of gneissic granite, gneiss, marbles, limestone, and quartz. The dynamic compressive strength, measured under a strain rate of 10 3/sec, has been found to be about 2.5--4.6 times the compressive strength measured under static conditions (strain rate of 10-6 /sec) for similar dimensions of rock samples in a wide variety of rock types. It has also been found that this ratio is higher for low strength rocks, and lower for high strength rocks. The particle size distribution resulting from high velocity impact breakage is much smaller than in the static case. The degree of fineness (50% passing) generated under dynamic breakage is well correlated with the dynamic compressive strength; however, there appears to be no correlation between static compressive strength and the corresponding fragment size distribution. Except for static compressive strength, the dynamic strength was found to have no significant correlation with the measured values of fracture toughness, tensile strength, or comminution work index. The fracture toughness value is found to be controlled by the largest crack or grain size and to some extent, by porosity. The effect of crack density appeared to be non-linear; the fracture toughness initially decreases with increase in crack density, but further increase in the latter results an increase in toughness. This suggests the behaviour of rocks in dynamic compressive breakage is different than that due to static single crack growth. The work index (WI), which represents a fracture process at an intermediate strain rate correlates better with the Brazilian tensile strength than the static and high strain rate compressive strengths. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Prasad, Umesh.</creator><contributor>Mohanty, B. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Geology.</subject><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Dynamic fracture characteristics of selected rocks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gj03b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644t25c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):34600</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>