<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:46:19Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40750" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988k68v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A systematic survey of the microbial and invertebrate natural enemies of Phyllophaga spp. was conducted from 1979 to 1981 in 45 localities in southern Quebec. Chronic but low (nonepizootic) rates of biotic regulation were found in all host life stages except eggs. The natural enemies included 36 species of predatory and parasitic insects, 15 mite species, six fungal species, five bacterial species, three different nematodes, one virus, one gordian worm, and one sporozoan. Microorganismal pathogenicities to white grubs were demonstrated by infectivity tests and laboratory bioassays using four methods of inoculation. Field-type microplot studies on the fungus Metarhizium anisopliae and the nematode Mikoletzkya aerivora were undertaken in 1982. The fungus and the nematode showed potential as biological suppressants of Phyllophaga grubs by causing 91% and 68% mortality, respectively. Twenty-seven chemicals were tested as attractants against P. anxia adults in 1981 in four localities in southern Quebec. Hexanoic acid was consistently the most attractive chemical to beetles of both sexes.</description><creator>Poprawski, Tadeusz Jerży.</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Insects -- Viruses.</subject><subject>Beetles -- Québec (Province) -- Diseases.</subject><subject>Phyllophaga.</subject><subject>Viral insecticides.</subject><title>Natural enemies of Phyllophaga spp. (Coleoptera: Scarabaeidae) in Southern Quebec, with special reference to entomopathogens</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w032381p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988k68v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rv194</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Biological and immunological aspects of the host-parasite relationship were examined in mice which are susceptible (A/J) and resistant (B10.A) to Giardia muris. B10.A exhibited a shorter latent period, lower cyst output during the acute phase of the infection and shorter period of cyst release compared to A/J. Characteristics of the infection transmitted from mouse-to-mouse and those induced by oral inoculation with cysts or trophozoites were similar. The infection was longer in male A/J and B10.A mice compared to females. Susceptibility and resistance during both the acute and elimination phases of the infection were under non-H-2-linked multigenic control. A/J and B10.A differed in non-specific serum IgG and IgA, but not in the specific IgG and IgA to G. muris. Specific antibodies participated in complement-mediated killing of trophozoites. Spleen, mesenteric lymph node and peritoneal cells from A/J and B10.A mice had a similar ability to kill trophozoites. The capacity of B10.A to mount inflammatory responses was greater than that of A/J. A/J were more immunosuppressed than B10.A during the infection, particularly at mucosal sites. Macrophage-like suppressor cells were shown to be the mediators of this suppression.</description><creator>Belosevic, Miodrag.</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Giardia muris</subject><subject>Giardiasis -- Immunological aspects.</subject><subject>Mice -- Parasites.</subject><title>Biological and immunological aspects of the host-parasite relationship in infections of mice with Giardia muris</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8049g5877.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rv194</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Parasitology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54kn907</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The continuous culture performance of a custom designed cell-retention (CR) bioreactor prototype was investigated for the acetone - butanol - ethanol (A-B-E) fermentation by Clostridium acetobutylicum. A mathematical model for the kinetics of the A-B-E fermentation was developed reflecting the biochemical pathway and culture behaviour. Dynamic and steady-state behaviour of C. acetobutylicum in the CR bioreactor was simulated on the computer and experimentally tested. In an operational mode with a total cell-retention, a steady-state operation of the bioreactor was predicted up to 52 g/L of sugar in the feed stream. The sugar was completely utilized. Experiments confirmed the suitability of the model and its predictions including the independence of the key process parameter concentrations from the dilution rate. For the feed sugar concentration in excess of 52 g/L an unsteady-state fermentation system behaviour was predicted by computer simulation and an oscillatory performance of the bioreactor was observed experimentally. Additional bleeding of the whole cell broth from the fermentor resulted in stabilizing the bioreactor performance.</description><creator>Mulchandani, Ashok K.</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Solvents -- Synthesis.</subject><subject>Fermentation.</subject><title>Biosynthesis of industrial solvents in a cell-retention fermentor</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hd76s095d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kn907</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sb397910b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mucopolysaccharidase-producing oral bacteria may contribute to the pathogenesis of inflammatory periodontal disease in several ways. Bacterial mucopolysaccharidases, in the area of the gingival crevice, can destroy important components of the ground substance of connective tissue leading to periodontal destruction on the one hand and enhancing the spread of bacterial toxins on the other. Partial breakdown of proteoglycan due to penetration of small amounts of these enzymes may also expose cryptic antigenic determinants, resulting in destructive autoimmune reactions. Finally, mucopolysaccharidase-producing oral bacteria may interact symbiotically with other pathogens of the gingival sulcus by enzymatic breakdown of tissue to release fermentable substrates for these pathogens. In the present investigation, it has been shown that anaerobic mucopolycaccharidase-producing bacteria are common inhabitants of gingival sulci of humans and that these microorganisms significantly increase in number in periodontal pockets of patients with inflammatory periodontal disease. Peptostreptococci probably are the most predominant producers of mucopolysaccharidases by virtue of their occurrence in subgingival plaque as well as the abundance of enzyme they produce. Peptostreptococci strains isolated from diseased periodontal pockets have been observed to convert from rough-colony-forming cells to smooth-colony-forming variants upon culturing in vitro. In dental plaque, hyaluronidase-producing peptostreptococci exist predominantly as the rough-colony-forming variants which produce higher amounts of hyaluronidase. Purified extracellular hyaluronidase from Peptostreptococcus strain 84H14S is different from previously reported bacterial hyaluronidases in several respects. It has different substrate specificity and optimum pH for activity. Also, the specific activity of this enzyme is much higher than any previously purified mucopolysaccharidases. Peptostreptococcus strain 84H14S is further shown to release potent cytotoxic factors into the culture medium, in addition to hyaluronidase, during its growth cycle. This may confer additional virulence to this bacterial genus in periodontal disease.</description><creator>Tam, You-Cheuk.</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><title>The role of mucopolysaccharidase-producing anaerobic oral bacteria in the pathogenesis of inflammatory periodontal disease /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/fj236279s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sb397910b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w032382z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A definition of difficult labour was developed after reviewing the literature, consulting with experts, and examining alternatives. Difficult labour, in primiparas, was defined as either prolonged labour with vaginal delivery, longer than 15 hours from admission to full dilatation, or cesarean section after admission for uncomplicated labour. This measure proved, to a satisfactory degree, practical, reliable and valid. A study of predisposing factors, measured prior to labour onset, was conducted in 1,125 primiparas at two hospitals, a community hospital and a high-risk referral hospital. Analysis was restricted to 781 primiparas, admitted to hospital for uncomplicated (spontaneous) labour. Rates of difficult labour were 17% at the community hospital and 24% at the high-risk referral hospital. Rates of cesarean section were in keeping with high rates reported elsewhere, but rates of prolonged labour were higher than expected. Anxiety about childbirth, as self reported prior to labour onset, was not found to predispose to difficult labour, nor was lack of attendance at childbirth education classes. Factors predisposing to difficult labour, at both hospitals, were short maternal height (p = 0.01) and heavy body mass index, kg/m('2) (p = 0.01). Further research is needed, using a reliable measure of difficult labour, to clarify reasons for labour differences between women and hospitals.</description><creator>Thomson, Mary Ellen.</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>Factors predisposing to difficult labour in primiparas</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227mq55d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032382z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zc77sq915</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of the work that comprises this thesis was to examine the position-dependent behavior of the human ankle joint dynamics. A series of experiments based on the use of system identification techniques were carried out; the experimental stimulus consisted of small-amplitude, stochastic perturbations of the ankle. The response to this input was modulated by two, experimentally-controlled parameters: tonically-maintained mean joint angles and tonically-maintained triceps surae or tibialis anterior contractions. This permitted the identification of the dynamic response of the torque (passive and active mechanics) and agonist electromyogram (reflex dynamics) for a functionally significant span of mean ankle angles and levels of tonic muscle contractions. The major conclusions of this work were that (1) the position-dependent changes in the passive joint mechanics were large and functionally significant; (2) the active joint mechanics depended entirely on the magnitude of the actively-generated torque with position-dependent changes in the active mechanics being relatively small and variable; and (3) the triceps surae stretch reflexes depended upon the position of the ankle while tibialis anterior stretch reflexes did not. The functional implications of these results and, in particular, the relative importance of the active and passive processes in the behaviour of the ankle joint have been considered in light of these findings.</description><creator>Weiss, Patrice Lynne.</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Position dependence of ankle joint dynamics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623hz494.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77sq915</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6395w802q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Age-related differences in the in vivo incorporation of 32-P into mouse myelin basic proteins (MBPs) of the central nervous system were observed. The resulting specific radioactivity (S.A.) of the MBPs appeared to be related to the S.A. of the acid-soluble pool of phosphates of myelin. In development, MBPs were phosphorylated in vivo prior to the onset of myelination in the brain, indicating that MBPs are phosphorylated prior to their deposition in the myelin sheath. The incorporation of 32-P into MBPs and the turnover rates of MBP phosphates were studied in vivo in developmentally-related myelin compartments. The results suggest that there are two separate events in MBP phosphorylation and that the turnover rates of the MBP phosphates derived from these two events are different. A model for MBP phosphorylation, that could explain these observations, is postulated and discussed in the light of existing information.</description><creator>Ulmer, Jeffrey Blaine</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>The phosphorylation of myelin basic proteins and its relevance to myelin biogenesis /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dd12k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6395w802q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rv20w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Hydrolysis and adsorption-desorption reaction of pyrophosphate (PP) and orthophosphate (OP) were studied in two Quebec soils (St. Bernard and Dalhousie) and three minerals (goethite, kaolinite, and montmorillonite). Soil and soil mineral samples were fractionated by size into two separates. Soil and goethite samples adsorbed more OP than PP whereas kaolinite and montmorillonite adsorbed similar amounts of OP and PP. Pyrophosphate and orthophosphate adsorption was found to be related significantly to extractable Fe. Furthermore, kaolinite and montmorillonite desorbed similar amounts of OP and PP whereas more OP than PP was desorbed from soil and goethite samples. Moreover, adsorption of OP and PP was found to be mainly chemical adsorption. Smaller particle size induced higher P adsorption and desorption from both P sources compared with the coarse particle size. Goethite samples had slower rates of hydrolysis compared to soil and clay mineral samples. Furthermore, kalolinite and montmorillonite did not increase the rate of PP hydrolysis even with reduced adsorption of PP compared to soil and goethite samples. Chemical hydrolysis was found to be a significant portion of the total hydrolysis. Smaller particle size and high PP adsorption induced smaller PP hydrolysis than with coarse particles. Moreover, added OP reduced the amount of PP remaining nonhydrolyzed. First-order rates of PP hydrolysis were faster in nonautoclaved than autoclaved samples. Rate of PP hydrolysis increased with increased temperature and the effect of temperature was more obvious in the autoclaved than nonautoclaved samples.</description><creator>Al-Kanani, Thamir Sadoon H., 1951-</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Soil absorption and adsorption.</subject><subject>Soils -- Phosphorus content.</subject><subject>Phosphatic fertilizers.</subject><title>Adsorption-desorption of pyrophosphate and orthophosphate, and pyrophosphate hydrolysis in soils, goethite, and silicate clay minerals</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k930bx92j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rv20w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Renewable Resources</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zg64tm77k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study describes the types of statements made by nurses as first impressions (hypotheses) of patient problems treatable by nurses in response to limited information (cues). Subjects were nine groups of nurses (n = 243), who varied in length of experience and in educational level from diploma students through masters students. Completion of a paper and pencil task yielded 4199 hypotheses which were classified into 13 categories. Major differences were found between types offered by a group of master's students who had studied the diagnostic process and the remaining groups. Of the former's hypotheses, 85.6% were nursing diagnoses compared with a range of 35.5 - 61.4% from the latter. Possible reasons for nurses' inability to make nursing diagnoses are failure to hypothesize the presence of appropriate problems and a lack of distinction between a nursing diagnosis, a medical diagnosis, data and plans for care.</description><creator>Craig, Jennifer L. (Jennifer Lynn)</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Nursing -- Research.</subject><subject>Diagnosis.</subject><subject>Nursing.</subject><subject>Nurse and patient.</subject><title>Types of statements made by nurses as first impressions of patient problems</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913q67x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zg64tm77k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational Psychology and Counselling</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97kr215</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The cross sections for muon pair production in antiproton-nucleus and pion-nucleus collisions have been measured using a 125 GeV/c beam incident on a tungsten target. Both cross sections agree well with data scaled from other beam energies. The measured cross section for antiproton produced pairs is a factor of K = 2.45 larger than the predictions of the Drell-Yan model using structure functions measured by deep inelastic lepton scattering experiments. The Drell-Yan formula has been inverted and the antiproton and pion valence structure functions have been extracted from the data. The shape of the antiproton structure function agrees well with the shape of the proton structure function measured by deep inelastic scattering experiments. The shape and magnitude of both the antiproton and the pion structure functions agree well with measurements made by other muon pair experiments.</description><creator>Schappert, W. (Warren)</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Muons.</subject><subject>Antiprotons.</subject><subject>Partons.</subject><title>Antiproton and pion structure functions from dimuon production at 125 GeVc</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x4740.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kr215</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fb494927r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The intranuclear cascade is an approximate microscopic model of heavy-ion collisions in which the space-time evolution of the nucleons is followed as they collide with one another. This model is used: (a) to test the validity of simpler models as the two-fireball model; (b) to estimate the validity of the assumption of chemical equilibrium and to calculate the total pion production cross-sections; (c) to investigate the average primordial charge multiplicity and the number of participants as a function of the beam energy.</description><creator>Maso, A. C. P.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Heavy ion collisions.</subject><title>Equilibria and hadron multiplicities in heavy-ion collisions</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pt49g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fb494927r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:p2676w33c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Biochemical theories postulate that deficient serotonergic functioning may be etiologically related to affective illness and aggressive behavior. In Study I mood and aggressivity were measured in thirty-six normal male subjects before and after ingestion of a Tryptophan Depleted, Tryptophan Loaded or Balanced amino acid mixture. While no differences in aggressivity were found, the Tryptophan Depleted group scored significantly higher at posttest on the MAACL Depression Scale than the control groups and demonstrated selective attention for dysphoric themes. In Study II a Balanced or Tryptophan Depleted amino acid mixture was administered to eighty normal male subjects prior to placing them in either a positive or negative environment, with or without instructions concerning the potential amino acid effects. The tryptophan depleted group became significantly more depressed than the control group regardless of environmental condition or instructional set. These findings suggest that lowered tryptophan may result in a central serotonergic dysfunction which is causally related to depressive affect and possibly to the pathogenesis of clinical forms of depression.</description><creator>Smith, Scott E. (Scott Edward)</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Aggressiveness.</subject><subject>Amino acids -- Physiological effect.</subject><subject>Men -- Psychology.</subject><subject>Depression, Mental.</subject><subject>Serotonin.</subject><title>The psychological effects of diet induced lowered tryptophan in normal human males /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9k41zf27z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/p2676w33c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225b776</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The dynamic distribution of pulmonary ventilation was studied both theoretically and experimentally. The human lungs were simulated as two compartments driven by independent cyclic pleural pressures. The distribution of tidal volume depended primarily on the regional pressures, but dissimilar pressure swings generated sequential flows. A model of the tracer dynamics in the lung during a breath showed that the ventilation per unit volume was proportional to the time derivative of krypton-81m activity normalized by the activity itself. In gamma camera measurements, the average flow distribution was independent of frequency and tidal volume, but the flow per unit volume in left lateral decubitus subjects was greater in the dependent than the non-dependent lung, and sequential flows were evident. However, lung sound amplitudes were in phase over the dependent and non-dependent regions, varying as the square of the airflow at the mouth. The frequency composition of the sounds remained constant. Thus, nonhomogeneous pleural pressure swings appear to control the dynamic distribution of ventilation. This time-varying quantity can be measured using a short-lived isotope but not directly with lung sounds.</description><creator>Shykoff, Barbara Ellen.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Respiration.</subject><subject>Lungs -- Ventilation.</subject><title>Ventilation distribution in the lung during cyclic breathing</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6395w8030.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225b776</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:t435gd74s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study area encompasses 1100 km('2) in northwestern Connecticut and adjacent Massachusetts. It contains three lithologic-topographic belts: a crystalline upland, a marble lowland, and a phyllitic upland; each having two tills, the youngest of Woodfordian age. The youngest or "upper" till has ablation, resedimented (diamicton), meltout and basal facies. The older or "lower" till has oxidized and unoxidized zones. Tills and till facies of each belt can be discriminated by grain size and clast weathering characteristics. Abundance isopleths of upper till heavy minerals and exotic clasts indicate strong topographic control of basal ice movement and possible glaciotectonic thrusting. Field relationships and upper till compositional changes in the crystalline belt suggest this sequence: (1) erosion of the bed, (2) lodgment of till, (3) erosion of the bed and reincorporation of previously deposited till, and (4) ice stagnation. Entrained subglacial material locally was frozen during (3).</description><creator>Smith, Philip Alson.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Drift -- Massachusetts.</subject><subject>Drift -- Connecticut.</subject><title>Discrimination and provenance of tills in northeastern Connecticut</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cr162.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/t435gd74s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b2773w419</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In existing algorithmic programming languages, algorithms are expressed almost exclusively in the present tense. This thesis examines the feasibility of adding tenses other than the present tense to algorithmic languages. The benefits of such extensions are studied with regard to clarity and succinctness of algorithms, readability of programs and efficiency of implementation. The specifications are given for T-Pascal, a derivate of Pascal with a past tense, a future tense and a subjunctive. The utility of the additional tenses is illustrated by comparing code of programs in T-Pascal with other standard programming language solutions. The results indicate that the additional tenses are practical enhancements to an algorithmic language. An implementation of a compiler for the new language shows that programs in T-Pascal are in most cases as efficient as program written with the conventional tools of an algorithmic language.</description><creator>Strothotte, Thomas.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Algorithms.</subject><subject>Programming languages (Electronic computers)</subject><subject>T-PASCAL (Computer program language)</subject><title>Temporal constructs for an algorithmic language</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dd13v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b2773w419</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xk81jm14w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The need for systematic research of patient selection variables and group composition dimensions that are related to favorable group therapy process and outcome has been emphasized repeatedly by clinicians and researchers alike. The present study attempted to address this issue by investigating the efficacy of pretraining work behavior as a selection and a composition variable in group psychotherapy. The work behavior of 66 outpatients in nine cognitive-experiential pretraining groups was measured. Six of the pretraining groups were recomposed into either high or low work therapy groups on the basis of the pretraining scores. The other three groups entered therapy intact. The therapy groups met once weekly for 90-minute sessions and were time-limited for an expected duration of two years. The orientation was psychodynamic. Audiotapes of group sessions from the first five months of therapy were process-analyzed by means of the Therapeutic Work Rating System to assess levels of work in therapy. A comprehensive battery of outcome measures was administered before therapy and six months after therapy began. Hypotheses were formulated concerning: (1) the effects of composition on process and outcome; (2) the relationship of work behavior to outcome; and (3) the rates of premature termination. The results indicated that pretraining work behavior had merit as a composition variable and showed promise as a selection variable. Group composition was shown to have a strong effect on therapy process, but less effect on outcome. Patients in the high work therapy groups produced significantly more work and worked at significantly higher levels than patients in either the low work or intact therapy groups. In terms of outcome, few significant group condition differences were found. When group conditions were collapsed, a general trend of improvement was found for 10 out of 12 outcome variables. Pretraining work scores correlated modestly with improvement on four outcome variables. Dropout rates were higher than predicted and appeared to be affected by recomposition. The methodological limitations and the clinical implications of the study were discussed in detail. Suggestions for future research were provided.</description><creator>Connelly, Jacquelyn Lois.</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Group psychotherapy.</subject><subject>Behavior therapy.</subject><title>An analysis of therapeutic work behavior for selection and composition in group psychotherapy /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5d86p113c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xk81jm14w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x633f198w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effect of the key physiological parameters on the production of solvents in the acetone-butanol fermentation using the anaerobic bacterium Clostridium acetobutylicum was examined in this work. The theoretical solvent yield was calculated based on expressing stoichiometric relationships between the substrate and the products of the process. The maximum theoretical yield under the acceptable process conditions was established ranging from 38.6% to 39.9%. A linear correlation was established between the production of solvents and gases which varied with the mixing rate of the fermentation system. Elevated hydrogen partial pressure affected the metabolism of C. acetobutylicum resulting in increased butanol and ethanol yields (based on glucose) by an average of 18% and 13%, respectively. A mathematical model for the batch acetone-butanol fermentation was formulated using original experimental data for the microbial growth, sugar consumption and metabolite biosynthesis. This model was used for computer process simulations. Parametric sensitivity analysis indicated the importance of the key process parameters. A method of systems analysis was applied in analysing pronounced physiological differences in the performance of one of the C. acetobutylicum culture strains. The cellular transport mechanism for substrate (glucose), solvents and acids through the cell membrane was established to depend on its permeability and the number of sugar transport "sites". Experimental results obtained from the study of the uptake of 3-0-methyl glucose (0.7mM) by the "normal culture" and the "retarded culture" confirmed the theoretical predictions of a slower transpost in the "retarded culture". The theoretical predictions were further confirmed by additional experimental results. A mathematical "Physiological State Model" was developed which includes the culture physiological parameters as well as the internal and the external culture conditions. Using this mathematical model the standard and the substandard acetone-butanol fermentations could be simulated. These results demonstrate the application of the method of systems analysis in elucidation of the role played by the key culture physiological parameters in the fermentation process.</description><creator>Yerushalmi, Laleh.</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Fermentation.</subject><subject>Clostridium acetobutylicum.</subject><title>Physiological aspects of the acetone-butanol fermentation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483k06z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x633f198w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ht24wk016</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Seasonal priorities for the use of current photosynthate were studied in the leaves of Betula glandulosa Michx. and Ledum groenlandicum Oeder from northern Quebec. A sequential extraction scheme was developed to separate ('14)C-labelled leaf tissues into several classes of organic compounds. Data were analysed in terms of carbon use priority (CUP) defined as the ('14)C activity in a compound category as percentage of the total activity in the leaf. Developing leaves represented the strongest sink for current photosynthate among evergreen leaf age classes. In both species the priorities for structural components, leaf protection and metabolic components decreased while the importance of cellular lipids and storage carbohydrates increased with leaf age. The deciduous leaves had higher overall carbon use priorities for metabolic components, cellular lipids and storage carbohydrates. The priorities for structural components and leaf protection were higher in the evergreen leaves. Leaf protection was an important consideration in both species. Both B. glandulosa and L. groenlandicum leaves (1) allocated photosynthate to antiherbivore compounds when leaf succeptibility was highest, (2) used both quantitative and qualitative type defenses, and (3) reduced carbon use for quantitative type defenses during active growth.</description><creator>Prudhomme, Thomas I.</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Betula glandulosa -- Analysis.</subject><subject>Photosynthesis.</subject><subject>Plants -- Development.</subject><subject>Ledum groenlandicum -- Analysis.</subject><title>Priorities determining the patterns of photosynthate use in leaves of a deciduous and an evergreen subarctic shrub from northern Québec</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q811kk36b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ht24wk016</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wd375x127</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A multichannel detection system based on a linear photodiode array (PDA) is described. The design and construction of the detection system and a rapid slew-scan computer-controlled stepping motor grating drive system is detailed. The theoretical performance of an optimized PDA system is contrasted with the performance of photomultiplier tubes. A technique is described which allows the dynamic range of the PDA to be extended by one order of magnitude towards higher light levels. A wavelength calibration procedure is outlined which results in a wavelength prediction accuracy of (+OR-)0.003 nm. A theory for high resolution spatial image positioning is presented and the ability to detect varying degrees of spectral overlap is evaluated. Applications of the PDA to the measurement and characterization of transient signals is described.</description><creator>McGeorge, Scott W. (Scott Wilson)</creator><date>1985</date><subject>Trace elements -- Analysis.</subject><subject>Atomic spectroscopy.</subject><subject>Detectors.</subject><title>The application of a linear photodiode array as a multichannel detector for inductively coupled plasma atomic emission spectroscopy /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/00000076b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wd375x127</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns064677m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ces trois etudes, basees sur un scheme d'apprentissage social, visaient le developpement d'instruments d'evaluation et d'intervention aupres de personnes agees vivant dans la communaute. La premiere etude a demontre qu'une intervention aupres de gens lors de la pre-retraite peut contribue a l'augmentation des attentes d'efficacite de soi, particulierement en ce qui a trait a leur planification d'activites satisfaisantes. Cette recherche a aussi indique l'utilite d'avoir recours a des groupe de pairs comme modele pour promouvoir l'adaptation a la vie de retraite. La seconde avait pour objet de comparer les attentes sociales de deux groupes de femmes (jeunes, agees) face aux consequences de l'affirmation de soi. Les femmes plus agees choisissaient moins souvent de s'affirmer car elles ne croyaient pas que ceci provoquerait chez les autres les comportements desires. Les plus jeunes etaient plus portes a s'attendre a une reaction negative de la part de leurs amis. Les deux groupes anticipaient une augmentation de leur egard-de-soi suite a la mise en action de comportements affirmatifs. La troisieme etude utilisait un scheme a cas unique pour evaluer l'effet d'une intervention d'habiletes sociales sur six femmes agees. Il s'agissait de modifier les comportements-cibles individuels par le truchement de techniques behaviorales (tels que repetition, modelage et retroaction); de selectionner des objectifs specifiques a l'environnement natural de chaque sujet; et de faire de la restructuration cognitive. Les resultats obtenus indiquaient l'efficacite du traitement pour ameliorer et maintenir les comportements cibles chez tous les sujets et ce, pour toutes les mesures utilisees a divers intervalles de temps. Cette etude illustre egalement l'application d'une telle methodologie dans un milieu clinique.</description><creator>Engels, Mary-Louise</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Behavior modification.</subject><subject>Behavioral assessment.</subject><subject>Assertiveness (Psychology)</subject><subject>Social skills.</subject><subject>Older women -- Psychology.</subject><title>The assessment and modification of social skills in older women /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/37720d52t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064677m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3197xm569</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Pyrophosphate retention and half-life values, and pyrophosphatase activity, were determined in 24 organic soil materials containing &lt; 20% ash. Pyrophosphate retention was correlated with ash content (r = 0,876**) but still was weak. Pyrophosphatase activity (11,6 to 148,1 mmol.kg('-1).2h('-1)) was higher in virgin than in cultivated materials and was promoted apparently by nonspecific acid phosphatases. The interaction between water-soluble pyrophosphate and pyrophosphatase activity explained 77% of the variation in log-transformed half-life values ranging from 0,1 to 3,7 days. Copper decreased significantly pyrophosphatase activity. However, pyrophosphate hydrolysis rate was not affected significantly by Cu contents up to 1177 mg.kg('-1) in humic materials. Because of rapid rates of pyrophosphate hydrolysis in humic and mesic materials compared with rate of P uptake by onions, no significant difference in bulb yield and P uptake were obtained at harvest between pyrophosphate and orthophosphate fertilizers.</description><creator>Parent, Léon-Etienne.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Phosphatic fertilizers.</subject><subject>Histosols.</subject><subject>Pyrophosphates.</subject><title>Retention, hydrolysis and plant availability of pyrophosphate applied to organic soil material</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612p390.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xm569</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Renewable Resources</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5425kb566</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Does an organization's competitive strategy influence the design and use of its management control system? Research methods based on selective interviewing, questionnaire data from 91 Canadian manufacturing firms, and multivariate statistical procedures are used to test hypotheses related to this question. Major findings are discussed by considering individual design attributes of both operational and management control systems. The major conclusion of the study is that organizational strategies and controls are linked in systematic ways. The effects of two complex sets of competitive strategies on management accounting and control systems are discussed. Additional findings related to the effects on control systems of technology, external control, and firm size are also reported. Based on the findings of the study and a detailed literature review, implications for managers and researchers are discussed.</description><creator>Simons, Robert Leslie.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Organization.</subject><subject>System analysis.</subject><subject>Management.</subject><subject>Management -- Research.</subject><title>An investigation of the relationship between management control systems and organizational strategies /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/c821gk64r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5425kb566</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945r56h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Graph-monoids are introduced as algebraic objects which correspond to congruences over graphs. Varieties are defined, and a one-to-one correspondence between varieties of graph-monoids and varieties of graph-congruences is demonstrated. This is viewed as a generalization of the known correspondence between monoid varieties and congruence varieties. Some classification and effective characterizations of graph-monoid varieties are obtained. These are used to decide membership in the wreath product of certain monoids varieties and the variety of definite semigroups.</description><creator>Weiss, Alex.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Semigroups.</subject><subject>Monoids.</subject><subject>Graph theory.</subject><title>Varieties of graph congruences</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bk128b66f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945r56h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dn39x2124</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The principal objective of the present thesis has been to develop a methodology for the simulation and optimization of electric power generation by solar ponds. A mathematical model for the analysis of the economic performance of a solar pond electric power system using a heat engine is developed. A salient feature of this model is a simple method for the analysis of a Rankine cycle. Other features include a mathematical model of the solar pond, of the energy exchange properties of the heat exchangers, as well as of the power required by the circulating pumps. The net electric power is expressed in terms of the thermodynamic properties of the organic working fluid, the temperatures of various thermodynamic states, the flow rates, the temperature and geometry of the solar pond, and the local climatic conditions. The system sizing and operating conditions which minimize the cost per kilowatt hour of electric energy is then determined through an optimization routine. The optimal storage depth and heat extraction scheduling are obtained by a semi-analytical method as well as a discrete optimal control technique. The possibility of an ice storage to act as a cooling source for an SPPP has also been investigated, which showed considerable improvement in the system's efficiency and reduction of electric energy cost. The possibility of making the NCZ of a solar pond float over a layer of fresh water has been investigated. The economical feasibility study of the concept for electric power generation was achieved using the model developed earlier. The thesis finally examines the means of enhancing the thermal storage under a solar pond by circulating LCZ brine through a network of buried horizontal pipes in the warmer part of the year. This heat stored can be used for the operation of a heat engine during the winter time if the LCZ brine is then used as a heat sink rather than a heat source. The present thesis has shown that the commonly held belief that SPPP can only function at acceptable efficiencies under semi-tropical conditions of SPPP in northern climates resulted in electric energy costs of 8.5 (CENTS)/KWh which is comparable with that of estimated by Israelis for an SPPP in semi-tropical conditions.</description><creator>Moshref, A. (Ali)</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Solar ponds.</subject><subject>Solar energy.</subject><title>Simulation and optimization of electrical power generation by solar ponds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9306sz976.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dn39x2124</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qf85nb94r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:05:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The propagation of acoustic plate-mode waves in composite membranes is studied. A computer program has been developed and used to calculate the wave velocity and electromechanical coupling factor in these structures which may consist of any combination of piezoelectric layers with arbitrary orientation and surface metallization. In particular, shear modes (SH) in zinc-oxide and selenium membranes, as well as stiffened-Lamb modes in ZnO membranes and ZnO/Si, ZnO/GaAs composite membranes are studied. The surface-acoustic-wave propagation in selenium and in selenium layers on tellurium has been extensively studied using an improved computer program. The study shows that surface-wave coupling factors in the range of 0.5 to 1.5% are possible with these structures. The calculated sensitivity of the velocity and coupling factor to errors in material constants shows that an accurate value of the e(,11) constant for selenium is necessary for an accurate estimate of the coupling factor. A technology for fabricating selenium-tellurium layered structures for SAW propagation has been successfully developed. Measurements on fabricated SAW delay lines were carried out and estimates of the coupling factor and the acoustic attenuation obtained. These measurements, taken together with previously published results, confirm that the published value of e(,11) = 0.32 C/m('2) is too small.</description><creator>Nassar, Abubakr A. (Abubakr Abbas)</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Acoustic surface waves -- Computer programs.</subject><subject>Acoustic surface wave devices.</subject><subject>Piezoelectric devices.</subject><subject>Acoustic surface waves.</subject><title>Excitation of surface waves with piezoelectric layers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5h73pw82n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qf85nb94r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):40775</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>