<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T22:58:57Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2250" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ms35tb593</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Thalamotomy and pallidotomy constitute the two principal neurosurgical treatments for Parkinson's disease. Both the thalamus nuclei and the internal globus pallidus structures are found very close to the internal capsule, a critical structure that must be avoided in performing the lesion. This forces the lesion of parts of the thalamus and the globus pallidus mediale to be achieved with a spatial precision on the order of 2mm. The leukotome is a neurosurgical tool consisting of a 20cm rigid shaft with a thin metallic wire attached to its tip that can be taken in and out of the body of the shaft. It is used as a knife to perform the excision. Some critical basal ganglia structures show no anatomical differences at all on MRI scans, even though they have different functionality. In order to provide the neurosurgeon with this missing information, we have developed a deformable volumetric atlas of the basal ganglions from the cryogenic slices atlas of Shaltenbrand and Wahren. The atlas can be non-linearly deformed to fit a patient's MRI. We have developed a visualization platform for pre-operative and intra-operative utilization of the atlas and of the MRI datasets. Any number of datasets can be superimposed (MRI, atlases, virtual lesions...). Merging of datasets with different extents and different resolutions is supported. The platform includes 3D visualization tools as well. Graphical tools allow the neurosurgeon to see projections of the leukotome from any point of view over the MRI data and the atlas. The software is able to create models of lesions that can be compared with the MRI data and the atlas. It can also suggest an operation protocol (how to use the leukotome) if a target volume is given. This target volume can easily be drawn on the atlas by the neurosurgeon.</description><creator>St-Jean, Philippe.</creator><contributor>Peters, Terence M. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Engineering, Biomedical.</subject><title>Computer guidance for thalamotomy and pallidotomy</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h989r527f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tb593</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Medical Radiation Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj236421s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Microwave power is seen as a promising alternative to conventional methods for drying freshly harvested grains to safe storage moisture levels. In an attempt to elaborate a continuous flow microwave dryer, the optimum operating characteristics of a prototype microwave antenna were investigated during a low power microwave drying simulation with corn at three different moisture content levels (15%, 23% and 30% w.b.). The antenna consisted of a slotted waveguide with the orientation and width of the slots being the main points of investigation. The optimum angle of the slots with respect to the direction of propagation of the travelling wave was found to be in the neighbourhood of 55° at all moisture contents. Slots 13 mm wide gave better results than the 6 mm ones which are often suggested in literature.</description><creator>St-Denis, Eric.</creator><contributor>Raghavan, G. S. V. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Microwave heating.</subject><subject>Corn -- Drying.</subject><title>Performance optimization of a multi-slotted waveguide for microwave processing applications</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8g84mp499.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236421s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:d217qr739</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Internet's growing acceptance as a key medium to educate people is the main focus of this thesis. Although distance education has been a popular learning method since the end of the 19th Century, never before has technology made it so easy to disseminate knowledge by linking different media formats---e.g. text, sound, video. In fact, this huge library accessed by a universal interface, is one of the key contributions that the Internet and the World-Wide Web have brought to the learning process. The main goal of this thesis is to encourage instructors to create and deliver courses using the Internet and, most of all, to show that the process can be simple and effective. In order to support this study, four major Course Management tools are presented and analyzed: Pathway by Solis-Macromedia, LearningSpace by Lotus, WebCT by The University of British Columbia, and Virtual-U by Simon Fraser University. As a result of this thesis, a Grades Application was developed using the Internet protocol. This application is an uncomplicated, yet effective solution for using the Web to manage, calculate, and view students' marks. With the open architecture of the Web and standard programming languages such as JavaScript and Perl, the system will execute in most computers available in universities around the world.</description><creator>Spiller, Simone.</creator><contributor>Ratzer, Gerald (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Education, Technology.</subject><subject>Information Science.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Distance education on the world-wide web</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v0621.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/d217qr739</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d220m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recently, NF-kappaB activation has been shown to be directly influenced by the cytoskeletal environment. In an attempt to better understand and characterize cytoskeletal regulation of NF-kappaB a series of experiments were designed to determine whether the microtubule (MT) stabilizing agent taxol could affect NF-kappaB activation in the presence of different NF-kappaB inducers. Pretreatment of murine NIH 3T3 and human 293 cells with 5 muM taxol resulted in complete abolition of phorbol, 12 myristate, 13-acetate (PMA) mediated NF-kappaB activation including loss of DNA binding potential and reduced CAT reporter activity. Phosphorylation and turnover of IkappaBalpha was effectively abrogated in taxol pretreated COS-7 cells. However, taxol was not capable of preventing TNF-alpha induced NF-kappaB activation nor could taxol suppress IkappaBalpha inducible phosphorylation in TNF-alpha treated cells, suggesting TNF-alpha may function through a microtubule-independent pathway. In vitro kinase assays of PMA stimulated cells established that taxol could reduce activation of protein kinase C by 30%, establishing loss of PKC activity as a possible regulatory step in taxol-mediated suppression of NF-kappaB transactivation. Indirect immunofluorescence analysis revealed that PMA treated COS-7 cells underwent dramatic changes in cell morphology as well as depolymerization of MTs. These observations were similar to that seen for nocodazole treated cells, a known MT depolymerizing agent. In contrast, taxol blocked both nocodazole induced effects as well as PMA induced morphological changes. These findings establish a potential mechanism for taxol-mediated stability of MTs and inhibition of NF-kappaB activity, suggesting a link between the state of microtubule integrity and gene regulation.</description><creator>Spencer, William John.</creator><contributor>Hiscott, John (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Phorbol ester-mediated NF-Kappa-B transactivation is selectively inhibited by taxol</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7w62fb51q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d220m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hx11xg99t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Let V be a set of distinct points in some metric space. We draw the following proximity graph on V: For each point x&amp;isin;V , let sx be the open ball centered at x with radius from x to its nearest neighbour. Then (a, b) is an edge if and only if sa and sb intersect. This graph is known as the sphere of influence graph of the point set V. In this thesis, we demonstrate that in the d-dimensional infinite-order Minkowski metric, no sphere of influence graph of n vertices contains ( 22d-1-2d-1 )n edges or more. We also prove an asymptotic lower bound of ( 2d+2-3d-4 )n/9 on the maximum size of the graph. Lastly, we demonstrate an upper bound of 15n on the size of the sphere of influence graph of n vertices in the Euclidean plane.</description><creator>Soss, Michael A.</creator><contributor>Toussaint, Godfried (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>On the size of the sphere of influence graph</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qf14b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hx11xg99t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nz806202d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Chlorpheniramine, a reversible competitive inhibitor at the H1-receptor that has demonstrated potent, long-lasting antihistaminic activity with only mild side-effects, has been a popular choice for the treatment of allergic conditions and is a common component of cold/cough preparations. A number of groups have studied the pharmacokinetics of chlorpheniramine since its development, but results have been conflicting. Moreover, most of the pharmacokinetic studies had only involved analysis of the parent compound and excluded pharmacologically active metabolites. As part of a new pharmacokinetic study of chlorpheniramine, an enantiomeric method to resolve chlorpheniramine from its N-demethylated metabolites and chlorpheniramine N-oxide was required. The use of high performance liquid chromatography (HPLC) with the amylose tris(3,5-dimethylphenylcarbamate) chiral stationary phase (AD-CSP) failed to resolve the enantiomers of chlorpheniramine and its metabolites. Capillary electrophoresis was used to screen a number of chiral selectors including hydroxypropyl beta-cyclodextrin, sulfated beta-cyclodextrin and carboxymethyl beta-cyclodextrin. The resolution of the enantiomers of chlorpheniramine and its metabolites was achieved using carboxymethyl beta-cyclodextrin obtained from Wacker Chemie, Munich, Germany. Detection limits of chlorpheniramine down to 200 ng/mL were achieved by concentrating samples and using sample stacking methods.</description><creator>Soo, Evelyn Chun-Yin.</creator><contributor>Wainer, I. W. (advisor)</contributor><contributor>Kazlauskas, R. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Chemistry, Pharmaceutical.</subject><subject>Chemistry, Analytical.</subject><title>Chromatographic and electrophoretic separations of chlorpheniramine and its metabolites</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2227ms05m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nz806202d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zg649</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Almost all peroxisomal proteins, which play significant roles in peroxisome biogenesis, are synthesized in the cytosol and imported into peroxisomes post-translationally. Failure to assemble normal peroxisomes causes detrimental disorders of peroxisome biogenesis known as peroxisomopathies. In the present study we examined (1) the peroxisomal import competency of unfolded proteins, and (2) the essential amino acid sequence of peroxisomal targeting signal type I (PTS-1) peptide. In the first part, human serum albumin (HSA) with seventeen disulfide bonds was fully reduced at 37°C and partially reduced at the room temperature. Microinjection of HSA that was unfolded, biotinylated and cross-linked with PTS-1 peptides demonstrated colocalization with peroxisomes, indicating the peroxisomal import competency. Furthermore, they induced heat shock protein (hsp) 72 which is a part of hsp 70 molecules. In the second part of our studies, we examined the essential amino acid sequence of PTS-1 by observing the peroxisomal import competency of mutated PTS-1 peptides and their inducibility of hsp 70 molecules. The hydrophobicity and basicity of the last seven amino acids from the carboxy-terminal were shown to be essential in the peroxisomal import. Furthermore, all the mutated PTS-1 peptides induced hsp 72 response. These results suggest that the ability of hsp 70 molecules to interact with the last seven amino acid sequence of the PTS-1 peptide plays a crucial role in the peroxisomal import.</description><creator>Song, Hong Chang.</creator><contributor>Walton, Paul Albert (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>The role of protein structure and heat shock protein 70 molecules in the import of peroxisomal proteins /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ms35tb60v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zg649</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anatomy and Cell Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qv33rz65k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis describes two studies that were performed to explore how the gustatory code is influenced by ingestive and motivational variables. To examine the possibility of a dissociation between gustatory sensation and perception that may be accounted for by integration of the gustatory code with limbic aspects of feeding, I first compared citric acid detection and recognition thresholds in two groups of patients, and a group of healthy control subjects. Patients had undergone resections from either a right or left anterior temporal lobe for the treatment of intractable epilepsy. A Positron Emission Tomography (PET) activation study was then performed on a separate group of healthy subjects to ascertain brain regions involved in the perception of citric acid. A role for the right anterior temporal lobe in taste quality recognition was elucidated in that experiment. As taste perception generally occurs with olfactory perception, in the context of feeding, I designed a second study to explore cerebral processing of flavor. This study used PET to determine if unimodal taste and smell processing differs from bimodal flavor processing. Evidence for a flavor specific neural network was found.</description><creator>Small, Dana.</creator><contributor>Jones-Gotmani, Marilyn (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Psychology, Physiological.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Central taste and flavor processing in humans</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pg12d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qv33rz65k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mx63r</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Platelet aggregation is mediated primarily by the binding of fibrinogen to its membrane receptor, GPIIb-IIIa, but such an interaction may not be sufficient to support aggregation. This question could potentially be resolved by reconstituting GPIIb-IIIa into a model membrane system. A protocol was developed for the generation of liposomes containing purified GPIIb-IIIa. Flow cytometric techniques confirmed that the receptor was present in the lipid bilayer and were used to evaluate the characteristics of fibrinogen binding to the liposomes, which like fibrinogen-platelet interactions exhibited specificity, saturability, time-dependence, and calcium-dependence. No fibrinogen-specific aggregation of GPIIb-IIIa-liposomes with stir or shear was observed, as determined by flow cytometric cell counting and microscopic examination of particles. In contrast, platelets rapidly formed large aggregates in the presence of fibrinogen. It thus appears that elements other than fibrinogen and GPIIb-IIIa play an important role in platelet aggregation.</description><creator>Sloan, Stephen Michael.</creator><contributor>Frojmovic, Mary M. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Glycoprotein IIb-IIIa-liposomes bind fibrinogen but do not undergo fibrinogen-mediated aggregation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qz20sv95j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mx63r</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1j92g9492</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis describes a method for mapping unknown large scale static environments using a hybrid of topological and metric representations. A global map is formed from a set of local maps for sub-regions of the environments. Each local map contains quantitative environment information used to define a local reference frame. These maps are referred to as islands of reliability because they are associated with the sub-regions whose local structure is best matched to the sensors we are using. The connectivity of these islands is represented topologically. The key mapping problem we consider is where to place the islands of reliability and to what extent they should cover the environment. This is accomplished by defining the placement criteria in terms of the task to be satisfied and the uncertainties of the mapping agent. Islands are distributed about the environment at areas suitable for extracting metric information relevant to a localization task.</description><creator>Simhon, Shlomo Saul.</creator><contributor>Dudek, Greg (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Physical Geography.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Islands of reliability of hybrid topological-metric mapping</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7d278w396.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1j92g9492</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042w097</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We present an approach to vision-based mobile robot localisation. That is, the task of obtaining a precise position estimate for a robot in a previously explored environment, even without an a priori estimate. Our approach combines the strengths of statistical and feature-based methods. This is accomplished by learning a set of visual features called landmarks, each of which is detected as a local extremum of a measure of uniqueness and represented by an appearance-based encoding. Localisation is performed using a method that matches observed landmarks to learned prototypes and generates independent position estimates for each match. The independent estimates are then combined to obtain a final position estimate, with an associated uncertainty. Experimental evidence shows that an estimate accurate to a fraction of the environment sampling density can be obtained for a wide range of parameterisations, even under scaling of the explored region, and changes in sampling density.</description><creator>Sim, Robert.</creator><contributor>Dudek, Gregory (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Artificial Intelligence.</subject><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Mobile robot localisation using learned landmarks</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/r781wj19q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042w097</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52jb107</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this study was to determine the impacts of irrigation tailwater and sewage lagoon discharge on the water quality of Crowfoot Creek, Alberta, Canada. The monitored irrigation tailwater accounted for more than 55% of the water flow in the basin. With the exception of the early part of the 1997 irrigation season the irrigation tailwater only impacted the phosphate and total phosphorus levels in the creek. High values for all parameters were recorded in the early part of the 1997 irrigation season, due to irrigation source water quality or deposition of contaminants into the irrigation canals during the 1997 spring runoff. The impact of the sewage lagoon effluent on the water quality of the creek was minimal to insignificant. The primary sources of contamination in the watershed are thought to be direct cattle access to the creek, soil erosion and surface runoff.</description><creator>Shrivastava, Vikram.</creator><contributor>Bonnell, R. B. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Irrigation water -- Environmental aspects -- Alberta -- Crowfoot Creek Region.</subject><subject>Water quality -- Alberta -- Crowfoot Creek.</subject><subject>Agricultural pollution -- Alberta -- Crowfoot Creek Region.</subject><title>Creek water quality impacts : irrigation tailwaters and sewage discharges</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3j3334475.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52jb107</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z311n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:15Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cells of the oligodendrocyte lineage go through a complex sequence of division, migration and differentiation. In transgenic mice in which the first exon of myelin basic protein (MBP) has been replaced with the Lac Z reporter gene, Lac Z expression emerges adjacent to the putative source of the oligodendrocyte lineage, after PDGFaR-expressing progenitors have left the ventricular zone. This suggests transcriptional activity at the MBP locus begins in oligodendrocytes at the premyelinating stage of development. Low-level Lac Z expression is also observed in the presumptive grey matter from embryonic day 12 (E12). In contrast, transgenic mice bearing Lac Z fused to various lengths of the MBP promoter suggest that, while capable of driving expression in oligodendrocytes, the MBP promoter is unexpectedly sensitive to deregulation from elements adjacent to its chromosomal integration site. Expression of one construct may identify transcription factors involved in establishing the oligodendrocyte lineage as early as E9.</description><creator>Schwartz, Zachary.</creator><contributor>Peterson, Alan C. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Prenatal activation of the myelin basic protein locus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m166h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z311n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5999n544b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Subsurface peat decomposition, through CO2 production, was analyzed in laboratory and field experiments in a bog, poor fen, and beaver pond margin at Mer Bleue, Ottawa. Intact core samples in 10 cm depth intervals from 5--45 cm below the surface of each site were incubated in the laboratory. Treatments involved aerobic and anaerobic conditions at 4 and 14°C. Field measurements of CO2 flux were made by a static chamber technique. Incubation results indicate modelled CO2 surface fluxes differ amongst wetlands. Aerobic CO2 modelled surface fluxes at 4°C were 2.3, 3.1 and 4.2 g CO2 m-2 d-1 for the bog, the beaver pond margin, and the poor fen, respectively. On average, aerobic production rates from peat cores with field moisture conditions were 11.7 times larger than anaerobic production rates. A mean Q10 of 2.3 defined the role of temperature. Differences among the peat samples were related to degree of decomposition, and differences among the sites were related to trophic status and nutrient availability. A model of CO2 production was constructed and validated against field fluxes of CO2. The model provides a good prediction (r 2 = 0.72) of subsurface peat decomposition. The results suggest that warmer peat temperatures and lowered water tables, as predicted by climate change scenarios, will increase surface CO2 fluxes due to peat decomposition.</description><creator>Scanlon, Debra A.</creator><contributor>Moore, Tim (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Peatlands -- Ontario.</subject><subject>Atmospheric carbon dioxide -- Ontario.</subject><subject>Peat -- Biodegradation -- Ontario.</subject><title>Carbon dioxide production due to the subsurface decomposition of peat in a Canadian bog, poor fen, and beaver pond margin</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j96023118.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5999n544b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tx31qk98n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This ethnographic study combines qualitative and quantitative research methods to examine the relationship between culture and language disability. Nine Cree and nine non-Cree couples, all parents of a language-disabled child, were interviewed. The parental responses from the two cultural groups were compared. Comparisons of interest included language socialization patterns, the influence of culture on the concept of language disability and perceptions of speech-language pathology service delivery. Few crosscultural differences in parental responses about caregiver-child interaction and about language disability were identified. It is hypothesized that a process of cultural blending may account for these findings. However, differences relating to the perception of speech-language pathology service delivery were found. While both groups described poor access to services, long waiting periods for intervention and insufficient quantity of service, there were differences in degree reported between the Cree and non-Cree families. The clinical implications of these findings are discussed.</description><creator>Saville, Deborah M.</creator><contributor>Crago, M. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Health Sciences, Speech Pathology.</subject><subject>Anthropology, Cultural.</subject><subject>Sociology, Ethnic and Racial Studies.</subject><title>Language and language disabilities : aboriginal and non-aboriginal perspectives</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88cj74j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qk98n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Communication Sciences and Disorders</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zk51vj91v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Over two thousand environmental, non-governmental organizations (ENGOs) exist in Canada, many of which are concerned with biodiversity. This thesis documents a participatory action research (PAR) project that was designed to identify and explore effective ENGO strategies for protecting biodiversity, key barriers that impede progress, and to develop actions for overcoming the barriers. The qualitative findings and outcomes, which are the product of interviews and workshops conducted over a fifteen month period, primarily with eleven selected ENGOs, are discussed and recommendations made. These results have been used to identify key principles to enable ENGOs to design more effective programs. To adequately protect biodiversity, many new programs, from local, highly specific to global and broad, will be needed. The study emphasizes the importance of both ENGOs and the general public being involved in such programs, and of focusing on the underlying causes, and not the symptoms, of the biodiversity crisis.</description><creator>Sarwer-Foner, Brian.</creator><contributor>Hill, Stuart B. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Biodiversity conservation -- Canada.</subject><subject>Green movement -- Canada.</subject><title>Strategies of Canadian environmental non-governmental organizations for protecting biodiversity : a participatory action research study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v692t845m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zk51vj91v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Natural Resource Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rv042w100</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Gait speed is an ideal measure of locomotor recovery following stroke but its responsiveness and clinical terminants have received little attention. The main objectives of this prospective study were to identify the most responsive clinical measure of gait speed, and to identify predictors of gait speed recovery in the acute phase post-stroke. Fifty clients were evaluated on four tests of gait speed, and other measures of disability and impairment during the first and fifth week following a first-time stroke. Responsiveness was estimated using standardized response mean, and four other indices. Multiple linear regression was used to identify significant predictors of gait speed measured at follow-up. Walking 5 metres at a comfortable pace was identified as the most responsive method of measuring gait speed. Functional mobility and initial gait speed were significant predictors of gait speed recovery. Task-specific training may be warranted to improve this outcome.</description><creator>Salbach, Nancy M.</creator><contributor>Mayo, Nancy E. (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><title>Gait speed as a measure of stroke outcome</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2b88qf15m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rv042w100</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pr76f5710</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A large number of behavioural methods have been developed to investigate nociception and the actions of analgesic drugs in animals. The formalin test is increasingly used as a model of injury-produced pain. The generally accepted method of rating pain used for mice is to count or time paw licks. The aim of this study was to examine scoring properties of other behaviours in the formalin test in mice, and determine the best measure of pain. In the first experiment, the behavioural responses to intraplantar injection of a series of formalin concentrations were assessed. In the second experiment a fixed concentration of formalin was used, and the effects of increasing doses of various analgesic and non-analgesic drugs were examined. A time sampling method with momentary rating of nociceptive behaviours and behavioural state was used. A correlational analysis of the data indicated that combinations of pain behaviours performed better than any single measurement, and the relationship between formalin concentration and behavioural measures were stronger when mice were habituated to the environment prior to testing. All four analgesic agents, morphine, amphetamine, dipyrone and xylazine, produced dose-dependent suppression of pain behaviours. The nociceptive measures were not significantly altered by sedative or neuroleptic drugs. Considering the dose-effect relations for formalin and analgesic and non-analgesic agents, together, indicated that the sum of favouring, lifting and licking was the most consistent measure of both, pain and analgesia.</description><creator>Saddi, Ghada-Maria.</creator><contributor>Abbott, Frances V. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><subject>Psychology, Psychobiology.</subject><subject>Psychology, Physiological.</subject><subject>Psychology, Experimental.</subject><title>Scoring properties of the formalin test in the mouse</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8336h3943.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f5710</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3f462759q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The research tests the potential of the Community Supported Agriculture Financing Method (CSAFM) as a viable alternative to traditional debt financing in Agriculture. The CSAFM provides the Farmer with a source of non-farm equity capital and an element of risk reduction which are supplied by each Member/Investor (M/I). By receiving cash up-front (from selling shares of the harvest) several months prior to seeding, costs of inputs are covered and financing costs on operating capital eliminated. Moreover, the Farmer is guaranteed a market and price for his harvested produce. M/I benefits include receiving organic produce at a discount to retail market prices. A case study of a Canadian CSA "ABC" operation is presented to show the impact of the share price on the farm budget and M/I returns. A detailed budget analysis, demonstrates the benefits of CSA marketing versus marketing through an organic wholesaler, and CSA financing versus line of credit or loan financing. Although it was discovered that the share price was not calculated from a total budget, the Farmer was still better off with the CSAFM, which increased revenues by 34.0%, eliminated financing costs equal to 1.1% to 3% of total revenues, and yielded a net balance between $1,875.25 to $2,057.66 more than traditional techniques. For the M/I, data were collected during the 12 week contract period to value each weekly CSA delivery against both a non-organic market value (NOMV) and an organic market value (OMV). The M/I's (OMV) return on the $180 share price was 38.9%. Given the results of the study, the CSAFM does qualifies as an alternative financing method in agriculture, displaying a win-win relationship for both Producer and Consumer.</description><creator>Sabih, Sacha Francis.</creator><contributor>Baker, Laurie (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Agriculture, Cooperative -- Canada.</subject><subject>Agriculture -- Finance -- Canada.</subject><subject>Alternative agriculture -- Canada.</subject><title>The CSA method of alternative financing in agriculture : a case study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q8465.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3f462759q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x129c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>B+/- mesons are reconstructed via two decay modes: B+/-→ccK+/- and B+/-→J/yK+/- from data collected by the CDF experiment, corresponding to an integrated luminosity of 109 pb-1. An unambiguous B+/-→J/yK+/- signal is observed; however, the B+/-→ccK+/- signal was not of sufficient quality to allow for the determination of the relative branching ratios of the two processes.</description><creator>Saab, Tarek.</creator><contributor>Ragan, Ken (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>Study of charmonium final states in B meson decays</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892d098.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x129c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h663d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The neocortex and the thalamus send dense, glutaminergic projections to the sensorimotor striatum. The cortex targets a distinct class of striatal interneurons immunoreactive parvalbumin (PV). The first objective of this study was to determine whether the parafascicular thalamic nucleus ( Pf) also targets PV-immunoreactive interneurons. An anterograde tracer was injected into the Pf of normal adult rats. It was found that 75.9% of thalamic boutons synapsed onto unlabelled dendrites, 22.5% onto unlabelled spines, and 1.6% targeted PV-immunoreactive dendrites. The second objective of this study was to determine whether competition between corticostriatal and thalamostriatal fibres during development account for the sparse thalamic input onto PV-interneurons. Neonatal rats were bilaterally decorticated and were injected with an anterograde tracer into the Pf as adults. It was demonstrated that 77.2% of Pf synapses were formed on unlabelled dendrites, 21.9% were upon unlabelled spines, and 0.9% targeted PV-immunoreactive dendrites. We conclude that the Pf nucleus sends a minor projection onto PV-immunoreactive interneurons in the normal rat striatum. Our results suggest that competition between thalamic and cortical afferents does not underlie the establishment of stable synaptic connections of excitatory afferent terminals onto PV-striatal interneurons.</description><creator>Rudkin, Teresa.</creator><contributor>Sadikot, Abbas (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Organization of the thalamic projection onto parvalbumin- immunoreactive striatal interneurons : a study of the normal topography in the rat and its alteration following neonatal decortication</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf2687333.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h663d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b8204</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The highly varying course of MS has made it difficult to establish accurate prognoses about its natural history. The reliability of neurologic impairment grades obtained by clinical examinations of patients is becoming recognized as important. Current statistical methods in natural history studies of MS are essentially classical survival and linear models, applied to clinical data and with mortality, impairment, and secondary progression of MS, as outcomes. However, more sophisticated modelling attempts, in particular ones that account for the fluctuating course of MS, are rare. Stochastic and time series models are two such recent methods that have been proposed. As more complex statistical models are being called upon, it is crucial that practitioners consult with statisticians to ensure that the models are being correctly selected, applied, and interpreted.</description><creator>Rouah, Fabrice.</creator><contributor>Wolfson, Christina (advisor)</contributor><date>1997</date><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><subject>Statistics.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>The natural history of multiple sclerosis : a review of current modelling approaches /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sz060.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b8204</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1g05ff00m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bicaudal-C, a Drosophila gene, is required for centripetal follicle cell migration in the egg chamber and anterior patterning of the embryo; its exact functions are unknown. BICAUDAL-C carries five KH domains required for in vitroRNA-binding and for in vivo activity. Here, I show that Bicaudal-C functions, through RNA-binding, to regulate oskar expression during mid-oogenesis. Females carrying mutations in Bicaudal-C in the regions encoding its KH domains display premature, ectopic translation of OSKAR at the anterior of their stages 8--10 oocytes; this likely accounts for the disruption of anterior patterning in embryos of Bicaudal-C/+ females. Also here, I propose that oskar and gurken share common regulators, including Bicaudal-C. This is based on the discovery of dorsalized progeny of Bicaudal-C/+ females, and on the dominant enhancement of the Bicaudal-C/+ phenotype by specific gurken and cornichon alleles. Finally, I describe a yeast two-hybrid screen used to investigate BICAUDAL-C-protein interaction.</description><creator>Rother, Katherine L.</creator><contributor>Lasko, Paul F. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Drosophila -- Molecular genetics.</subject><subject>Oogenesis.</subject><title>The KH domain protein BICAUDAL-C regulates oskar expression during Drosophila mid-oogenesis /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zz68n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1g05ff00m</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b8515q631</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Species with different requirements can coexist if the environment varies in space; we therefore expect a positive relationship between species diversity and environmental heterogeneity. In this thesis I examine the influence of environmental structure on patterns of fern diversity in one hectare of old-growth forest and compare these patterns to other surveys covering a broad range of scales. The nineteen species recorded in the hectare had non-random spatial distributions and differed in their soil preferences. Diversity was positively related to soil moisture and negatively related to soil fertility, but there was no relationship with environmental variance. The counteracting influence of dispersal may predominate over selection processes at the hectare scale. Both species-area curves and the decreasing correlation of species composition with distance had very similar slopes over quadrat sizes ranging from 1 x 1 m to 50 x 50 km, suggesting that some diversity patterns may be independent of scale.</description><creator>Richard, Monique, 1972-</creator><contributor>Bell, Graham (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Ferns -- Ecology -- Québec (Province) -- Mont-Saint-Hilaire.</subject><subject>Species diversity -- Québec (Province) -- Mont-Saint-Hilaire.</subject><title>Fern species diversity in relation to spatial scale and structure</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2r36v0639.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b8515q631</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7m01bn86v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T04:19:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study compared the effect of two contrasting nutrient environments on the growth rates of 12 Carex species from the Mont St. Hilaire Biosphere Reserve, Quebec. All species demonstrated higher growth rates under conditions of high nutrient availability. There was no correlation found between maximum relative growth rate (RGRmax), leaf production, and biomass. High nutrient availability produced a reduction in root/shoot ratio, while leaf production was the trait that showed the greatest response to contrasts in nutrient availability The Carex species were found to be relatively slow growing plants, with growth potential ranging from stress tolerant to competitive. The species from lowlands are more competitive and have higher growth rates; the upland species are more stress tolerant and have lower growth rates. The abundance of a species at Mont St. Hilaire was found to be unrelated to its growth potential.</description><creator>Reygadas, Fabiola.</creator><contributor>Lechowicz, M. J. (advisor)</contributor><date>1998</date><subject>Soil fertility -- Québec (Province) -- Mont-Saint-Hilaire.</subject><subject>Carex -- Québec (Province) -- Mont-Saint-Hilaire -- Growth.</subject><title>The effect of soil fertility on the growth of Carex species from temperate forest environments /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322g493.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7m01bn86v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):2275</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>