<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T01:56:28Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):26775" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6682x4295</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is a study of two major figures among the royal Safavid women in the sixteenth century, with a special focus on their political activities and style of leadership. I examine the socio-political careers of Pari Khan Khanum (955-985/1548-1578) and Mahd-i 'Ulya (d.987/1579) in connection with family and dynastic politics as well as the power struggle and factionalism among the qizilbash tribes. A detailed analysis of these powerful female political figures of the Safavid court leads one to conclude that first, royal women faced particularly complex social and personal restrictions, but nonetheless some managed - through their privileged status as upper-class women with access to education, wealth, and social and family networks - to advance their careers in politics. Second, these women were subject to the political rules and games of their time but faced additional impediments, for they competed with other women such as co-wives, sisters-in-law and others for social recognition and influence, at times leading to the ruthless elimination of female and male rivals. Third, Safavid women came to play an active role in shaping central political decisions and the succession of sovereigns. This reflects not merely gendered semi-nomadic Turcoman roles but also urban Iranian-Islamic transitional traditions which are comparable to Ottoman and 'Abbasid counterparts.</description><creator>Birjandifar, Nazak.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Mahd-i Ulyā, d. 1579.</subject><subject>Parī Khān Khānum, 1548-1578.</subject><subject>Iran -- Kings and rulers.</subject><subject>Safavids.</subject><title>Royal women and politics in Safavid Iran</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Nazak Birjandifar, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/h702q664p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6682x4295</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:hd76s043n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the construction and utilization of gender in religious nationalist projects. Communalist groups sacralize gendered understandings of time, space, and community, rooted in the bifurcation of the public (masculine) realm and the private (feminine) sphere. Nationalist understandings of citizenship maintain the public and private division, but acknowledge the potential to politicize both. In this conception of citizenship, the private (feminine) is deployed to achieve social and religious change. This thesis analyzes two contemporary South Asian transnationalist groups, the Muslim Tablighi Jama`at and the Hindu Vishwa Hindu Parishad, and investigates women's participation in the nation as cultural repositories and as pedagogues. In these roles, women are able to recover and disseminate the "true" values and identity of the degenerate community, thereby revitalizing the nation. However, while women are empowered in these roles, they are simultaneously limited by patriarchal expectations of ideal womanly behaviour.</description><creator>Jalalzai, Sajida.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Nationalism -- South Asia.</subject><subject>Religion and politics -- South Asia.</subject><subject>South Asia -- Politics and government.</subject><subject>Tablighi Jamaʻat.</subject><subject>Women -- Political activity.</subject><subject>Viśva Hindū Parishad.</subject><title>The politics of recovery : women in the Tablighi Jamaʻat and Vishwa Hindu Parishad</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Sajida Jalalzai, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sb397862w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/hd76s043n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ns064634t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is an evaluation of the extent to which theories of focalization are useful for the analysis of point of view in film. In it, I apply the small number of focalization models advanced within film studies to an analysis of the works of an internationally acclaimed Taiwanese director, Edward Yang. I reveal that Yang's films serve well to demonstrate how the conventional typologies of external and internal focalization are convenient labels that mask the considerable degree of ambiguity that is reflected by processes of focalization and narration in many films. Furthermore, I illustrate how an application of the alternative theory of auto-focalization to film analysis can generally free us from the limitations of these typologies, by drawing our attention to the iconic implications of film imagery. Finally, I determine that both models of focalization are largely useful for highlighting the degree to which the functions of character-focalizers and narrators can be indistinguishable, particularly in self-reflexive films.</description><creator>Benoit, James.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Motion picture producers and directors -- Taiwan.</subject><subject>Characters and characteristics in motion pictures.</subject><subject>Yang, Dechang, 1947-2007 -- Criticism and interpretation.</subject><subject>Motion pictures -- Taiwan.</subject><title>Working through the ambiguities of focalization with the films of Edward Yang</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© James Benoit, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/q237hs25b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ns064634t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of East Asian Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:v118rd771</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Despite being dismissed as low brow, nonsensical and a cheap form of entertainment, the present cultural phenomenon of reality television reveals a shared space where people are exposing more personalized, emotional aspects of themselves than typically seen in other genres of television programming or areas of contemporary public life. This recent trend of reality TV is both heightening and challenging many of the long-standing ethical debates over the boundaries between public and private, individual and collective as well as rational and emotional experience and needs to be considered within a pedagogical context. This study will explore reality television's position as a means of popular education, while attending to a broader social context of changing media and corresponding cultural shifts. A McLuhanesque study, this thesis will investigate what socio-cultural changes are occurring in our media environment as a result of our experiences within new media technologies.</description><creator>Barnett, Bonnie Maureen.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Reality television programs.</subject><subject>Popular education.</subject><title>Emotional awareness : using reality television as a tool for popular education</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Bonnie Maureen Barnett, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vt150j53n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/v118rd771</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Culture and Values in Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sj139227s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Current prediction equations for glomerular filtration rate (GFR), the most important measure of renal function, are neither accurate nor precise in children. Clinical data were abstracted from 207 charts of pediatric patients with renal disease attending the Montreal Children's Hospital from 1999-2004, to derive serum creatinine (SCR)-based equations and test their ability to predict iothalamate clearance, a gold standard measure of GFR, using linear regression and the Bayesian Information Criterion. In a separate study, CysC-based equations were derived from data on cystatin C (CysC) previously measured in 103 children between 1999 and 2003. Two SCR equations were derived for patients with or without spina bifida. Mean biases were -0.97 ml/min/1.73m 2 and +1.2 ml/min/1.73m2, respectively. Precision, 95% limits of agreement, and sensitivity for detecting abnormal renal function were superior for the new formulae compared to previously published equations. Two CysC-based equations were derived with or without the inclusion of SCR, which were less biased and more precise than comparison formulae and more sensitive but less specific for detecting GFR &lt; 90 ml/min/1.73m 2. Future studies should evaluate the equations derived here, in different populations of children.</description><creator>Zappitelli, Michele.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Physiology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Epidemiology.</subject><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><title>Derivation and validation of prediction equations for glomerular filtration rate in children</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Michele Zappitelli, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t212c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sj139227s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483j67g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study objectives were to measure the concentrations of albumin, prealbumin and transferrin in amniotic fluid (AF), and to establish if these concentrations were associated with infant birth weight (BW). At St Mary's Hospital (Montreal, Quebec), 294 AF samples were collected from mothers undergoing routine amniocentesis (12-19 weeks gestation). Exclusion criteria included subjects having gestational diabetes, multiple births or fetal genetic abnormalities. AF samples were analyzed by capillary electrophoresis (CE) at 190 nm. Analysis of variance and multiple linear regressions were performed. AF prealbumin could not be detected by CE. However, ANCOVA showed that transferrin was different among BW categories. Multiple regressions showed the parameter estimates for transferrin and albumin were negative, but neither was associated with BW in our study population. In contrast, transferrin was negatively associated with BW in our LBW infants. Our study shows that 2nd trimester AF transferrin may emerge as a biomarker for poor in-utero growth.</description><creator>Zablith, Nadine.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Albumins.</subject><subject>Transferrin.</subject><subject>Fetus -- Growth.</subject><title>The association between amniotic fluid albumin, prealbumin or transferrin and the fetal growth /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Nadine Zablith, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d6834.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483j67g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bb81p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>All aminoglycosides have the potential to cause nephrotoxicity. Previous studies have shown that this toxicity was altered according to the macronutrient composition of dietary regimens offered to female rats. In a first study, adult female Sprague-Dawley rats adapted to a standard chow diet, the standard chow with 20% added casein or with 55% added casein were treated for 10 days with a nephrotoxic dose of gentamicin sulfate (40 mg/kg/day, i.p.) or a saline solution. Food ingestion patterns and gentamicin nephrotoxicity indices were measured. In a second study, rats were fed the same diets, however, the treatment given was a sham injection. Results suggest that chronic gentamicin treatment leads to a decrease in food intake and flattening of the rhythms of food ingestion. Also, chow feeding and chow added with 20% casein were found to be more protective against gentamicin-induced nephrotoxicity than chow added with 55% casein.</description><creator>Zeeni, Nadine.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Nephrotoxicology -- Nutritional aspects.</subject><subject>Gentamicin.</subject><title>Effect of dietary protein level on gentamicin-induced nephrotoxicity in rats and on the circadian rhythms of food ingestion</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Nadine Zeeni, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bg257f34x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bb81p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cz30pt019</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In glomerular epithelial cells (GEC), the actin cytoskeleton is a key determinant of cell morphology and functions, including permselectivity. Complement C5b-9 induces sublytic GEC injury associated with GEC morphological changes and proteinuria. This study addressed the role of Rho GTPases in complement-mediated GEC injury. We demonstrated that the amount of active RhoA increased; while the amount of active Rac1 and Cdc42 were decreased in C5b-9 mediated sublytic GEC injury both in vitro and in glomeruli from rats with PHN in vivo. Complement mediated inactivation of p190RhoGAP may contribute to complement-induced RhoA activation. Overexpression of constitutively active or dominant negative mutants of RhoA, Rac1 and Cdc42 distinctly altered GEC morphology and F-actin pattern. Complement caused changes in GEC actin cytoskeleton, at least in part mediated by a downstream kinase of RhoA--Rho kinase (ROCK). Activation of RhoA exacerbated complement-mediated cytotoxicity in GEC, while inhibition of ROCK attenuated it.</description><creator>Zhang, Hui, 1971-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>The role of Rho GTPases in complement-mediated glomerular epithelial cell injury /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Hui Zhang, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/z316q178t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cz30pt019</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988k14j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study presents techniques that can be applied to optimize the quality of coated fried chicken nuggets. Heat and mass transfer during deep fat frying of breaded chicken nugget was simultaneously modeled using the moving boundary concept. Numerical software FEMLABRTM 3.0 was used to solve the proposed model. To validate the model, experiments were conducted. Chicken nuggets were made with wheat flour based batter and breading. The samples were fried in a fryer using oil temperatures at 160, 170 and 180°C. Total frying times ranged from 90 to 300 s. A good agreement was obtained between predicted and observed results. During the deep-frying process, the chicken nuggets samples shrank because of moisture loss and protein denaturation. Particle density and bulk volume shrinkage were analyzed at 3 different frying temperatures (160, 170 and 180°C). Particle density and shrinkage of the samples was measured using the liquid displacement technique with water. A linear relation was found for particle densities with moisture loss. The relationship between volumetric shrinkage and moisture loss was also found to be linear and the linear equation may be useful in predicting the volumetric shrinkage during frying. In order to reduce the oil absorption of chicken nuggets during the frying process, the influence of pretreatment in microwave on the moisture and oil transfer in the coating and core layers of coated chicken nuggets were studied. Chicken nuggets pretreated in a microwave oven for 1 or 2 min were fried at 160°C for times ranging from 90 to 300 s to evaluate oil transfer. Microwave pretreatment had an important effect on moisture loss and oil uptake of chicken nuggets during deep-fat frying.</description><creator>Wang, Yunfeng, 1970-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Microwave heating.</subject><subject>Convenience foods.</subject><subject>Cooking (Chicken)</subject><subject>Deep frying.</subject><title>Heat and mass transfer in deep fat frying of breaded chicken nuggets</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Yunfeng Wang, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0r967399r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988k14j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9g54xh96x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We consider a firing rate and a spike frequency adaptation (SFA) model of a one-dimensional neuronal network with axo-dendritic synaptic interactions. The neuronal network we focus on has a compactly supported connectivity pattern. The model equations are integro-differential equations with spatio-temporal delays arising from the finite axonal conduction velocity. We show that travelling wave solutions of these models are determined by mixed-type functional differential equations with both advanced and retarded delays. Especially, both delays depend on a unknown travelling wave speed. Based on the discussion of homogeneous steady states of model systems, we investigate the travelling front solutions of the firing rate model and the travelling pulse solutions of the SFA model. For the special case of a Heaviside firing rate function (the limit of infinite gain of a sigmoidal firing rate function), we obtain a special relationship between wave solutions, and then find analytic travelling wave solutions. For the models with a general sigmoidal firing rate function, we investigate the dynamic behavior in tails of travelling wave solutions, and perform the numerical calculation of travelling front solutions. Keywords. Neuronal network; firing rate function; mixed-type functional differential equations; delays; travelling wave solutions</description><creator>Wang, Wei, 1974-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>On solutions of advanced-retarded travelling wave equations arising in a neural field theory</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Wei Wang, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kn419.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xh96x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1831ck26k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Telomerase is the ribonucleoprotein enzyme whose principal function is to catalyze the de novo addition of telomeric repeats to the ends of linear chromosomes. Telomerase activity is predominantly observed in cancerous tissues and rarely in normal somatic cells making telomerase an attractive anticancer target. BIBR1532 is a highly selective pharmacological inhibitor of telomerase catalytic activity and induces telomere shortening and eventual growth arrest. We treated drug-sensitive and drug-resistant human leukemia and breast cancer cells lines with BIBR1532 and observed telomere shortening and a progressive decrease in proliferative capacity or colony forming ability. This effect was increased with the co-treatment of traditional chemotherapeutics, suggesting that pharmacological telomerase inhibition in combination with chemotherapeutics may be a valid strategy for the treatment of both drug-resistant and drug-sensitive cancers. Finally, our results support further investigation and development of pharmacological inhibitors of telomerase catalytic activity.</description><creator>Ward, Ryan J.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Pharmacological telomerase inhibition can sensitize drug-resistant and drug-sensitive cells to chemotherapeutic treatment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Ryan J. Ward, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj4304952.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1831ck26k</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:fj236232w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In Saccharomyces cerevisiae, zinc cluster proteins form a major family of transcriptional regulators for a variety of processes, yet many putative zinc cluster proteins have unknown functions. Previous studies assigned phenotypes to some of these proteins, a few of which showed previously unknown functions in pleiotropic drug resistance (PDR). The first study presented here focuses on a phenotypic analysis of double deletion mutants to further our understanding on functional relationships among zinc cluster proteins that mediate PDR. The second study focuses on a newly characterized zinc cluster protein, Asg1p, and its functional role in regulating stress response genes. In both studies, we found that the relationship among zinc cluster proteins is highly complex and tightly regulated.</description><creator>Wai, Carol.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Functional analysis of zinc cluster proteins in Saccharomyces cerevisiae</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Carol Wai, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j098zb35k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/fj236232w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8049g5435</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Background. Fatigue is a debilitating consequence of lung cancer and its treatments. Reviewing the literature in cancer-related fatigue provides few etiological factors, making evidence-based interventions limited. In this study, previously identified factors as well as muscular and cardiorespiratory function were assessed as potential contributors to fatigue in stages 3A/B and 4 NSCLC patients. Methods. Participants were evaluated by a physical therapist within the McGill Cancer Nutrition and Rehabilitation Program. Performance-based measures of physical function [upper limb strength and endurance (Jamar dynamometry), lower limb strength (30sec chair rise), cardiorespiratory function (2 minute walk - 2MW)] and a symptom questionnaire (Edmonton Symptom Assessment Scale) were conducted at one point in time. The primary endpoint of global fatigue rating was assessed using the Brief Fatigue Inventory (BFI). Results. Fifty-eight patients (30M:28F, mean age 68 +/- 12) participated in the study. Forty-three percent were actively receiving treatment at the time of assessment. On the BFI, 67% had moderate or severe fatigue and 84% indicated fatigue had interfered with their functioning during the past 24 hours. Global fatigue scores were unrelated to hand grip strength or endurance measurements, hematological parameters or sleep quality but were significantly correlated with chair rise performance, overall rating of breathlessness, patient rating of pain and patient rated weakness. Multivariate regression analysis suggested the best model for global fatigue scores incorporates patients' ratings of weakness, breathlessness and chair rise performance. Conclusions. Fatigue is prevalent and impacts on the function of advanced NSCLC patients. Several key factors contribute to this fatigue, with muscular and cardiorespiratory restrictions playing an important role. Such findings may have clinical implications in the recommendations of rest and exercise to best manage fatigue.</description><creator>Swanson, Tara.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><subject>Biology, Physiology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Oncology.</subject><title>Physiological correlates of cancer-related fatigue in advanced non-small cell lung cancer patients</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Tara Swanson, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vb61g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8049g5435</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n870zr09s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study compared the cost-effectiveness of four tuberculosis (TB) control strategies for detecting and treating latent tuberculosis infection (LTBI) among long-term travellers to countries where TB incidence is elevated. The decision analysis considered hypothetical cohorts of travellers from Canada and the United States (U.S.) to Mexico, Haiti, and the Dominican Republic. Strategy I consisted of screening for incident infection via two-step tuberculin skin testing prior to travel and skin testing upon return from abroad, followed by standard LTBI treatment with isoniazid for skin test converters. Strategy II carried the additional recommendation of isoniazid treatment for individuals who screen positive for LTBI before travel. Strategy III consisted of post-travel tuberculin skin testing alone, and isoniazid for all reactors. Strategy IV consisted of post-travel chest radiographic screening alone, and LTBI treatment for travellers with inactive TB. All strategies were compared with the status quo strategy of passive case detection. Costs were assessed from the viewpoint of the health system, in year 2003 Canadian dollars, and effectiveness was measured as cases of active TB prevented. In the base analysis, travel duration was 3 months. Strategy III (the single post-trip tuberculin test) was most effective in reducing future incidence of active TB, with the lowest incremental cost per TB case prevented. The best candidates for TB screening were travellers born in Haiti who visited Haiti, for whom Strategy III cost an estimated $37,613 per TB case prevented. Even for this group, however, no net cost-savings resulted from any screening strategy.</description><creator>Tan, Michael Chung-Yin, 1974-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Epidemiology.</subject><title>Tuberculosis screening of long-term visitors from low incidence to high incidence countries : a cost-effectiveness study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Michael Chung-Yin Tan, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dp991.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n870zr09s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z029p500w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The differentiated cell types of the mature pituitary gland are defined on the basis of the hormone that they synthesize and secrete. The temporal appearance and spatial localization of terminally differentiated cell types in the developing chick anterior pituitary gland were characterized using in situ hybridization and immunohistochemistry to identify the presence of pituitary hormone transcripts and protein, respectively. Corticotropes expressing ACTH were detected at embryonic day 7 (E7), melanotropes expressing MSH and gonadotropes expressing FSHbeta/LHbeta were detected at E8, thryotropes expressing TSH were detected at E10, somatotropes expressing GH were detected at E12 and lactotropes expressing prolactin were detected at E14. Hormones were localized to distinct but overlapping regions of the pituitary gland, with the exception of growth hormone which was only present in the caudal lobe of the anterior pituitary gland. The expression patterns of several transcription factors and signaling molecules that have been shown to participate in pituitary cell type differentiation in mice and zebrafish were also analyzed. The ventral diencephalon expresses Shh, Bmp4 and Fgf-10, suggesting that these signals may be critical for chick pituitary gland development, as demonstrated in other species. Similarly, the transcription factors Lim3, Pitx1, Pitx2 and Pit1 are likely to regulate gene expression patterns in the developing pituitary that are essential for the initial differentiation of Rathke's pouch and terminal differentiation of cell types.</description><creator>Parkinson, Nicole.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>Ontogeny of signaling molecules, transcription factors and differentiated cell types in the developing chick pituitary gland</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Nicole Parkinson, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cj82k759n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z029p500w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Human Genetics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bn999700t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Relationships between cardiovascular and neural activities were explored in 11 patients with intractable epilepsy. Using depth electrodes, we examined the cardiovascular response to direct electrical stimulation, and monitored EEG activity during simple physical and mental challenges known to elicit a cardiovascular response. Stimulation was most commonly performed in four regions: the hippocampus, amygdala, and the supra- and sub-callosal anterior cingulate cortex (ACC). While increases in systolic blood pressure (SBP) in response to electrical stimulation of these brain regions were observed with equal frequency, a striking cardiovascular response was observed in one patient when stimulating the supracallosal ACC (an increase in SBP of almost 50 mmHg). Cross-correlation analysis revealed significant relationships between EEG power and SBP during physical but not mental challenges, and the pattern of these relationships was only observed for power of EEG data recorded from the ACC. The observed relative timing of the correlations was consistent in the three patients whose SBP increased upon ACC stimulation. These results support the role of the ACC in cardiovascular regulation, as revealed in previous studies in experimental animals.</description><creator>Syme, Catriona.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Cardiovascular reactivity and the anterior cingulate cortex</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Catriona Syme, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010q33c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bn999700t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8p58pd24s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Introduction. Ototoxicity refers to medication-caused auditory and/or vestibular system dysfunction resulting in hearing loss or dysequilibrium. The potential damage that antibiotics eardrops can produce when placed directly into the middle ear in some cases is still unknown. Objectives. To determine the safety of use of the new ciprofloxacin/dexamethasone otic drops in patients without an intact tympanic membrane. Materials and methods. Ciprodex/dexamethasone eardrops were tested in an animal and human model. The animal part was performed in 13 adult chinchillas; Auditory Brainstem Response (ABR) was used. For the human part, twenty subjects were enrolled in the study; Distortion Products Otoacoustic Emissions (DPOAE) testing was used. Results. Animal Part: after the tube insertion ABR threshold mean value was 19.6+/-13.3 dB for all the animals. On the last evaluation (day 60), the mean threshold was 19+/-13 dB for the experimental ears, and 13.7+/-12.2 dB for the control ears, this overall analysis showed no significant effect (p-value = 0.661). Human Part: the mean thresholds for the pre-treatment test were 4.87+/-6,34 dB for the DP value and -0.87+/-7.93 dB for the Ns value. In the post-treatment evaluation the mean thresholds were 3.48+/-4.40 dB for the DP value and -8.02+/-7.57 dB for the Ns value. Conclusions. The use of CiprodexTM eardrops seems to be safe when instilled in ears without an intact tympanic membrane.</description><creator>Munguia, Raymundo.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>CiprofloxacinDexamethasone ototoxicity in an animal and human model</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Raymundo Munguia, 2005</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b155b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pd24s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Otolaryngology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z113s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The incorporation of temporally extended actions, or options , into the reinforcement learning framework has proven to be useful in planning and knowledge representation. Options provide a form of temporal abstraction, as they represent courses of action of variable duration. At the same time, agents operating in large domains often require the use of function approximation in order to generalize their experience over many states. Previous research has demonstrated the theoretical properties and usefulness of options in small domains where function approximation is not necessary. However, the theoretical and empirical properties of options with function approximation are still not well understood. In this thesis, we investigate the performance of options with the CMAC function approximator on an implementation of the game Asteroids (Atari, 1979). Our results demonstrate that options can be integrated successfully with function approximation. If good options are available, they can facilitate faster learning.</description><creator>Mouadeb, Mark.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>A study in using temporal abstraction and function approximation in reinforcement learning /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Mark Mouadeb, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3x816m88t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z113s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945r115</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to investigate the dynamic patterns of pressure distribution of curved running with and without banked surfaces at two speeds. Seven male elite runners ran at 3.8 m/s and 7.0 m/s in three different conditions: (1) straight, and along a curve with either (2) no side inclination or (3) an inclination of 19%. Running speed significantly affected peak pressure for plantar foot regions (p&lt;0.05); however, few significant main effects were found for surface running condition or foot side. Center of pressure displacement showed similar patterns in both the medial-lateral and heel to toe excursion regardless the running condition, speed, or foot side. Future study needs to reduce measurement variability as well as to consider other dynamic foot-to-shoe components such as shear stresses.</description><creator>Murias, Juan Manuel.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Running -- Physiological aspects.</subject><title>The effect of banked-curves on running mechanics : plantar foot pressures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Juan Manuel Murias, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d791sg61j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945r115</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Kinesiology and Physical Education</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225b32v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>DNA microarrays provide data for genome wide patterns of expression between varying conditions. Microarray studies often have small samples sizes, however, due to cost constraints or specimen availability. This can lead to poor random error estimates and inaccurate statistical tests of differential expression. We compare the performance of the standard t-test, simple fold change, and three small n statistical test methods designed to circumvent these problems, by applying them to simulated and experimental microarray data. The Empirical Bayes t-statistic was the most robust and effective method across simulated data and experimental data. Overall, the Empirical Bayes methodology provided the most optimal balance between specificity and sensitivity in detecting differential expression.</description><creator>Murie, Carl.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Biostatistics.</subject><title>Comparison of small n statistical tests of differential expression applied to oligonucleotide arrays</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Carl Murie, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m900nt84h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225b32v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cv43nx22t</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>There is abundant evidence to support the role of exercise in the well being of community-dwelling elderly people. However, the role of cessation of exercise specifically in institutionalized populations has not been addressed in depth. The effectiveness of exercise programs has mainly been analysed as a function of physical performance, when many of the benefits of exercising in the elderly appear to belong in the bio-psychosocial domain. Additionally, the effects of non-continuous exercise on physical function are not fully understood. Twenty-nine residents of Ste-Anne's Hospital were participants in a scheduled, physiotherapy-led exercise program. Twenty-five completed testing on physical performance and bio-psychosocial function at four evaluation times around two repetitions of a 12-week exercise class intervention separated by a 12-week period of no exercise. Physical function of the high level group was measured with the 2-Minute Walk Test and gait speed, whereas the performance of the lower level group was monitored with the Physiotherapy Functional Mobility Profile and a measure of activities of daily living. Results. Cessation of exercise was associated with deterioration in physical performance in both the higher and the lower level groups. Furthermore, in the lower functioning group, deterioration in physical function occurred over the time period of the study. Bio-psychosocial characteristics illustrated a small deterioration following cessation of exercise. Conclusions. These findings support the need to replicate this study with a larger sample size. In spite of limiting factors, it does appear that a modification of current practices in exercise programming for older, institutionalized people, would be beneficial to this population, and would increase alignment with recommended best practices based on research with other populations of older adults.</description><creator>Marshall, Sarah C.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Health Sciences, Rehabilitation and Therapy.</subject><subject>Gerontology.</subject><title>The effects of exercise cessation on physical and bio-psychosocial factors in an elderly institutionalized population /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Sarah C. Marshall, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90dv85v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cv43nx22t</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sn009z07c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Childhood overweight and obesity has become a significant health concern worldwide. Obese youth are now being diagnosed with health complications and chronic diseases previously observed only among older adults. In order to improve their health and decrease their risk of premature mortality, secondary prevention is essential. To help guide development of an effective intervention program for obese youth referred to specialized clinical care, a chart review was conducted on adolescents seeking physician treatment for obesity. Data indicate that this patient population suffers from obesity-related health complications, faces social issues and exhibits lifestyle practices predisposing them to weight gain. Given that physical inactivity is one major risk factor for obesity in this population, a logic model and training module have been developed for a physical activity intervention program, with nutrition interventions to soon be incorporated. This program, called Mentors in Motion, provides mentoring to obese youth as a means of enabling positive changes in physical activity behaviors, mental well-being and overall health. A pilot study research protocol was also developed as part of the thesis activity to test the effectiveness of Mentors in Motion and to determine further program needs and enhancements. The pilot study has been funded by the Canadian Institutes for Health Research and is underway.</description><creator>Markin, Carrie.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Obesity in adolescence -- Exercise therapy -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><subject>Overweight persons -- Rehabilitation -- Québec (Province) -- Montréal.</subject><title>Mentors in motion : a physical activity intervention for obese adolescents</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Carrie Markin, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2f75r8234.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sn009z07c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Dietetics and Human Nutrition</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7d278t36z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We compare the results of two regional atmospheric models, Canadian Regional Climate Model (CRCM) and Mesoscale Compressible Community Model (MC2) at a mesoscale resolution of 51 km, using 5 cases with different synoptic characteristics over the Mackenzie River Basin. CRCM has physics appropriate for coarse resolution typical of climate models, while MC2 is a mesoscale model with fine resolution physics. The results of both models are largely similar, indicating CRCM physics is able to reproduce mesoscale features. There are however differences. CRCM has stronger and expanded warm and cold bias at low levels compared to MC2. We identified surface initialization and coastal topographic precipitation as two processes responsible for these differences. The underprediction of precipitation over the western slopes of the Rockies is related to the cold bias found at the lee of the mountain barrier in CRCM. Furthermore, our results suggest that the use of different cloud schemes is another factor causing differences between the models.</description><creator>Mati, Iriola.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Atmospheric Sciences.</subject><title>A comparison study of two regional atmospheric models over the Mackenzie Basin /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Iriola Mati, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jm214p37m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7d278t36z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290967c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mental illness is characterized by alterations in thinking, mood and behavior and is associated with significant distress and impaired functioning. Many mental illnesses and medications used in their treatment, can in some way impair fitness-to-drive. This thesis comprises two independent but complementary articles. In the first article, the authors review the most recent literature on fitness-to-drive amongst individuals with mental illness, including those using psychotropic medications. In the second article, the authors assess current attitudes, practices, and knowledge of Canadian psychiatrists concerning driving safety amongst individuals with mental illness using a nation wide cross-sectional survey based on a random sample of practicing Canadian psychiatrists.</description><creator>Ménard, Ingrid.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Health Sciences, Mental Health.</subject><title>Canadian psychiatrists' current attitudes, practices, and knowledge related to fitness-to-drive in persons with mental illness</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Ingrid Ménard, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/n583xv24n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290967c</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Physical and Occupational Therapy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827b983</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T03:24:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Loss of germ cells that entered meiosis at different developmental stages was compared. Mice were injected with BrdU at 13.3, 14.3 or 15.3 days post coitum (dpc) and sacrificed either 3 days after BrdU injection or 4 days post partum (dpp). BrdU-labeled germ cells were detected in ovarian sections through double immunofluorescent staining for BrdU and either GCNA-1 or MVH as a germ cell marker. The results show that the loss of germ cells that entered meiosis at 13.3 or 15.3 dpc was excessive compared to the loss of total germ cells. Such preferential elimination was not found for germ cells that entered meiosis at 14.3 dpc. We conclude that oocyte loss during meiotic prophase is influenced by the timing of meiotic onset. The mechanism of germ cell loss during ovarian development was tested by the presence of markers for apoptosis. Mouse ovaries were isolated at 12.5 dpc, 18.5 dpc and 2 dpp and cultured with doxorubicin (DXR) to induce cell death. Ovarian histological sections were double immunofluorescent stained for GCNA-1 and cleaved caspase-3 or PARP-1. The results suggest that caspase-3 is not activated in germ cells throughout ovarian development whereas PARP-1 is activated in germ cells at 12.5 dpc and 2 dpp but not at 18.5 dpc. Thus, no evidence has yet been provided to support the hypothesis that oocyte death during the meiotic prophase is mediated by apooptosis.</description><creator>Fazio, Cynthia Marie.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Oogenesis.</subject><subject>Ovum.</subject><subject>Apoptosis.</subject><subject>Meiosis.</subject><title>The influence of meiotic onset on and the role of apoptosis in oocyte death during the meiotic prophase /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Cynthia Marie Fazio, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pg15bf235.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827b983</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):26800</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>