<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:48:15Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):41225" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r1705</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis first attempts to characterize amorphous material with respect to its performance in the marine soils from an engineering viewpoint, by selecting and testing some marine soils sampled in East Canada. The second concern of this study is to develop a better understanding of particle interaction between clay and amorphous material complexes and the mechanism of soil performance. Soil properties and behavior are not only controlled by the quantity, but also by the composition or type of amorphous materials. The mass ratio, defined as Fe$ sb2$O$ sb3$/(Fe$ sb2$O$ sb3$ + SiO$ sb2$) in units of mass, can be used as a parameter to evaluate the effect of amorphous composition. By changing the mass ratio, which in effect changes the composition, soil properties/behavior can be altered. Shear strength, consistency limits and suction all increase with an increase in amorphous content, but vary with mass ratio. Maximum shear strength and minimum consistency limits and suction are observed for soils with amorphous material composed at a critical mass ratio of 0.40. Soil properties are significantly related to the soil's acidity/alkalinity (pH), due directly to the pH dependency of surface charges of amorphous solid particles. The basic mechanism that governs the soil's performance arises primarily from the very active surface characteristics, i.e. the large surface area and high surface charge, of the amorphous material complex. The roles played by this special soil constituent can be generalized in two functions: water holding capacity and bonding action. While the large surface area necessitates a rise in the soil's water holding capability, the high surface charge enhances the bonding action in-between clay particles. Significant cation bridging and hydrogen bonding, and strong electro-static attractive force established in the silica-iron amorphous complex, especially at the mass ratio 0.40, contribute to the high shear strength observed in the soil. The laboratory-prepared soil samples showed a good behavioral simulation to the natural marine soils in East Canada and, hence, a much clearer picture for understanding the sensitivity of such soils as Quebec Champlain Sea clays, as well as the general soil problems related to the roles played by the amorphous materials, is achieved. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Wang, Bing-wu.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Marine and Ocean.</subject><subject>Applied Mechanics.</subject><title>A study of the role and contribution of amorphous materials in marine soils of eastern Canada /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/td96k329x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r1705</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kh04dq36z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Natural killers (NK) are a subpopulation of lymphocytes that are defined by their pattern of cytotoxicity against other normal and neoplastic cells of predominantly hemopoietic origin. Although they have been programmed to recognize a limited spectrum of targets, their activity can be augmented by certain immunoregulatory substances. The molecules that mediate the recognition events have not yet been identified. I describe here the derivation and characteristics of a variant clone (Clone I) of the human leukemic cell line K562. These cells, selected for decreased binding to peripheral blood lymphocytes, were less sensitive than the parent to lysis by NK in the resting, but not in the augmented state. Although their major plasma membrane proteins appeared identical to those of K562, they contained an additional minor group of fucosylated glycolipids. A later subclone of Clone I, selected for resistance to Concanavalin A, reverted to an NK sensitive pattern and exhibited the parental profile of glycolipids. The results illustrate in an in vitro model how a leukemic cell can modulate its membrane to escape surveillance by NK cells, and suggest that the glycolipids might be involved (directly or indirectly) in the mechanism.</description><creator>MacDougall, Stephen L. (Stephen Lindsay)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Effector:target interactions in the human natural killer cell system : characterization of the target structures</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qr46r169d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kh04dq36z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pr76f4170</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the association between ethnic relations, ethnic cohesion and economic activities in Punta Arenas, Chile, a city inhabited by immigrants from Europe, Central Chile and Chiloe and their descendants over the last century. Through the historical study of changing ethnic interaction in economic activities, marriage and social institutions in the city, of the organization of each of twelve ethnic collectivities, and the analysis of occupational and marital data on nearly seven thousand individuals we demonstrate that the concept of ethnicity (a) can be used to promote inter-class solidarity within the ethnic collectivity, leading to ethnic cohesion; (b) can be used to demarcate class differences between collectivities, rationalizing privilege and exploitation; and (c) can be consciously rejected in favor of claims to national hegemony and/or class mobilization, for example. The significance of ethnic origin in organizing social interaction coincides with its utilization in pursuit of class interests.</description><creator>Nock, Laurie</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Economic anthropology -- Chile -- Punta Arenas</subject><subject>Punta Arenas (Chile) -- Ethnic relations</subject><title>Ethnicity and economics in Punta Arenas, Chile</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vx021f99h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pr76f4170</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296wz77f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This research serves to answer the following basic question: Are potential toxic effects of hemoglobin solutions due to hemoglobin itself? Homologous and heterologous stroma-free hemoglobin and polyhemoglobin were investigated for their effects on complement activation, blood coagulation, platelet aggregation, blood cell counts, plasma electrolytes, proteins and enzymes in rats. A modified Mayer's method for testing whole complement hemolytic activity (CH$ sb{50}$) was developed. C$ sb3$ and C$ sb{ rm 3a}$ were also measured. Purified homologous or heterologous stroma-free hemoglobin or polyhemoglobin did not cause complement activation when incubated with rat plasma or when infused into rats. In addition, blood coagulation parameters did not change significantly in rats who received purified homologous or heterologous stroma-free hemoglobin or polyhemoglobin. Polyhemoglobin prepared from homologous or heterologous hemoglobin did not induce any changes in total leucocyte, differential or platelet counts. Effects of PolyHb and stroma-free hemoglobin on platelet aggregation were also studied. Plasma electrolytes, proteins, and enzymes tested were all within the normal ranges in rats who received purified homologous or heterologous polyhemoglobin infusions. Infusion of membrane stroma and endotoxins caused complement activation. This suggests that it is not purified hemoglobin or polyhemoglobin, but contaminants in hemoglobin preparations, which are responsible for some of the potential toxic effects observed. This study also has practical implications. It shows that only highly purified hemoglobin preparations should be used as blood substitutes for clinical applications.</description><creator>Ning, Jing, 1953-</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Effects of heterologous and homologous stroma-free hemoglobin and polyhemoglobin on complement activation, blood coagulation, platelet aggregation, and blood cells in rats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qb98mg18w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296wz77f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tm70mv886</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The perturbative regime of Quantum Chromodynamics (QCD) is considered and certain aspects related with higher order corrections (HOC) are studied. Certain large correction terms in the perturbative expansion are determined, in particular for large transverse momentum $(p sb{T})$ direct photon production. The origin of these terms is specified and simple forms, called K-factors, are provided (soft gluon approach). Furthermore, for processes initiated by 2 $ to$ 2 particle subprocesses the structure of the complete HOC is analyzed. It is shown that when structure functions and/or fragmentation functions are involved, there is a gauge invariant part that dominates HOC over a sizable kinematic range. Simple and general expressions are derived allowing an easy calculation of this part. Also, it is shown that, under certain approximations, this part reduces to the form of the simple K-factors. Other aspects of HOC, in particular the dependence on the choice of scales, are considered. Using complete HOC, detailed analysis of recent and old data on large-$p sb{T}$ direct photon production is carried out. The dependence of the form of the gluon distribution on the choice of the scales (physical versus optimal scales) is discussed and it is concluded that appreciable ambiguity in this distribution still remains.</description><creator>Papadopoulos, Stavros</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Physics, Elementary Particles and High Energy.</subject><title>Aspects of perturbative corrections in quantum chromodynamics</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gh10j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tm70mv886</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gb19f6531</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>For two decades, multiple observations of nonparallel pancreatic secretion, wherein digestive enzyme proportions change rapidly following various digestive stimuli, have conflicted with the concept of exocrine pancreatic homogeneity and the exocytosis model of parallel synthesis, transport and secretion of proteins. Evidence of pancreatic heterogeneity is presented, potentially resolving this longstanding controversy. Correlation and regression analysis simultaneously demonstrated exocytosis and nonparallel secretion, suggesting the existence of multiple heterogeneous exocytotic pathways. Next, heterogeneous prestored pancreatic protein sources were directly demonstrated using double isotopic labelling; temporal and secretagogue-specific regulation of the heterogeneous secretory sources was uncovered. Finally, specific enzyme proportions were linked to the heterogeneous sources by densitometric measurements of electrophoretic gels of secreted proteins. Thus, it appears that differential secretion from heterogeneous sources of prestored secretory proteins containing unique proportions of digestive enzymes is the basis of regulated nonparallel secretion in the exocrine pancreas.</description><creator>Miller, Paul E.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Differential secretion from prestored heterogeneous protein sources is the basis of regulated nonparallel digestive enzyme secretion by the exocrine pancreas</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9c67wn56x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gb19f6531</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vd66w062m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Certain critics claim that Paul Valery has, in his Cahiers (Notebooks), opened the way to a new study of man by approaching the subject with methods derived from the natural sciences. The present work investigates these claims by examining closely all the scientific analogies which Valery uses to clarify his analysis of the mental mechanism, in order to determine the relevance of these analogies, as well as their effectiveness. A comparison is drawn between the attempt of the poet and the general semantics of Alfred Korzybski, which also professes to ground its knowledge of man only on scientific and not philosophical foundations. The search for bases taken from science yields few convincing results; thus, Valery's attempt appears to have failed. However, in a philosophical context this attempt is regained. The failure of a "science of man" is tempered by a "phenomenology of power"!</description><creator>Parkinson, Theresa</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Valéry, Paul, 1871-1945. Cahiers</subject><subject>General semantics</subject><title>Paul Valéry à la recherche du pouvoir : les Cahiers : essai suivi d'une comparaison avec la sémantique générale d'Alfred Korzybski</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k3569522r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vd66w062m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cf95jc041</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Experiments were conducted with littermate gilts maintained in stainless steel metabolism cages within environmentally controlled rooms and consuming a corn-soybean meal based diet. The objectives of these studies were to investigate the impact of different dietary levels of manganese (Mn) and/or stage of the reproductive cycle on mineral metabolism and more specifically Mn metabolism in primigravid gilts and rats. Nutritional status was assessed using conventional balance studies, the analyses of physiological fluids (urine, plasma, colostrum, milk), tissues of the dam and offspring, and by a radioisotope dilution-balance technique. Trace element retention in the first-litter gilt was not significantly altered by dietary Mn restriction (11 $ mu$g/g DM) or by different stages of the reproductive cycle. In contrast, among the macro elements, phosphorus and perhaps calcium retention were improved in late gestation, whereas magnesium and nitrogen retention were unchanged. The weight of the litter at birth from dams consuming the low Mn (LMn) diet was significantly less than high Mn (HMn) gilts (96 $ mu$g/g DM). The Mn concentration in the liver and kidney of HMn gilts were significantly higher than in LMn gilts at the end of lactation. Likewise, the bones from HMn piglets contained higher concentrations of Mn at birth, and the liver and kidney concentrations were greater at weaning. Dietary Mn intake did not influence the rate of $ sp{54}$Mn excretion by the gilt during late gestation. The endogenous fecal Mn component was of similar magnitude, averaging 0.26 and 0.21 mg/d for the HMn and LMn gilts, respectively. However, the endogenous contribution to total fecal Mn was almost 8 fold different, representing 0.12% and 0.82% of total fecal Mn for the HMn and LMn gilts, respectively. The biological half-life of Mn in the body of the gilt was not influenced by dietary Mn within the intake range of 26 to 210 mg/d and averaged 54 days. The turnover rate (TR) of Mn was es</description><creator>Rhéaume, John</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Rats -- Reproduction.</subject><subject>Swine -- Reproduction.</subject><subject>Manganese.</subject><subject>Trace elements in nutrition.</subject><title>Manganese nutrition in rat and swine reproduction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2z10wq903.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cf95jc041</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h265f</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The hypothalamic supraoptic nucleus (SON) in the rat contains neurons that synthesize either vasopressin (VP) or oxytocin (OT) and receives inputs from medullary nuclei. While VP neurons receive inputs from noradrenergic cells in the caudal ventrolateral medulla (cVLM), no pathway from medullary nuclei had yet been described that would account for the excitation of OT neurons produced by gastric stimuli. Retrograde tracer experiments revealed a direct pathway from the nucleus tractus solitarius (NTS) to the SON, made up of axons arising from noradrenergic and non-noradrenergic neurons. Immunocytochemistry experiments identified putative transmitter substances in non-noradrenergic neurons as inhibin-$ beta$ and somatostatin-28 (SS-28). During intracellular recording experiments, SS-28 hyperpolarized and reduced the spontaneous activity of SON neurons, an effect that was reproduced by the fragment SS-28(1-12), but not by SS-14. In the majority of cases, discrete in vivo electrical stimulation of the caudal NTS caused primarily an enhancement of the electrical activity of VP and OT neurons in the SON. Experiments were also undertaken to study the organization of afferents to VP and OT neurons. Transient bilateral blockade of neuronal function in the VLM abolished the caudal NTS-evoked excitation of VP neurons, but not of OT neurons. This data suggests that stimuli such as hypovolemia may be relayed from the NTS to supraoptic VP neurons via a synaptic relay in the cVLM. Oxytocin neurons would receive direct NTS input that may transmit visceral or somatic stimuli.</description><creator>Raby, Wilfrid Noël</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>Medullary afferents to neurosecretory neurons of the rat supraoptic nucleus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nv935372f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h265f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:kw52j875n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Polyinosinic: polycytidylic acid (pI:C), an interferon (IFN) inducer, was used to investigate the role of IFN in the graft-versus-host reaction (GVHR), induced by injecting parental cells into F1 recipients and assessed for immunosuppression and pathological lesions. PI:C-treatment of recipients, but not donors, before GVHR-induction suppressed the GVHR, an effect seen only with C57BL/6 (B6) and not A donor cells. Using fluorescein-labelled donor cells, pI:C-treatment was seen to cause a marked decrease in donor cell survival after 2 days. Elimination of donor cells was specific for the B6 donor, was associated with increased natural killer (NK) cell but not macrophage cytotoxic activity, was radioresistant and anti-asialo GM1 sensitive, evidence supporting NK-mediated rejection. Plotting donor cell recovery against the number of cells injected into variously treated recipients indicated that in unstimulated mice a constant proportion of the injected cells were rejected, pI:C increasing that proportion, suggesting that pI:C changes F1 NK target repertoire. PI:C-treatment after GVHR-induction increased the severity of the GVHR, especially soon after GVHR-induction, the effect waning afterwards. No strain dependence was observed. These results demonstrate that IFN/IFN-activated cells play an important role in the regulation and in the immunosuppression/pathogenesis of a GVHR.</description><creator>Peres, Amos</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>Effects of an interferon inducer, pI:C, on the graft-versus-host reaction</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hg17w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/kw52j875n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5d86p104d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>To elucidate the structure and the function of the prolactin receptor, I have used molecular biological techniques. After unsuccessful screening of expression cDNA libraries with poly- and monoclonal antibodies, synthetic oligonucleotide probes, deduced from tryptic fragment sequences of the purified receptor, were used to isolate the rat liver prolactin receptor cDNA. Using this cDNA, the regulation of prolactin receptor expression by estrogen treatment and during ontogenesis was studied in female rat liver and revealed both pre-translational and translational control of the receptor. Finally, the human prolactin receptor cDNA was isolated. It encodes a long form of receptor (598 aa) compared to the rat liver receptor (291 aa). Both forms present regions of strong identity with the growth hormone receptor, suggesting that prolactin and growth hormone receptor genes form a family.</description><creator>Boutin, Jean-Marie</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Cloning and expression of the rat and human prolactin receptors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7p88ch219.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5d86p104d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97kr194</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>To overproduce biologically active polyomavirus (Py) middle tumor (T) antigen in human 293 cells and to efficiently transfer the middle T gene into a variety of other mammalian cells, two helper-independent recombinant adenoviruses (Ad) were constructed. A hybrid transcription unit encoding Py middle T antigen was substituted in either orientation for most of the E1 region of the Ad5 genome. Permissive 293 cells infected with each recombinant virus produced elevated levels of Py-specific transcripts and middle T protein. The functionality of the recombinant virus-encoded middle T was evidenced by its ability to associate with and serve as a substrate for human pp60$ sp{{ rm c}-src}$ and to transform Rat-1 cells. Ad recombinants of similar structure expressing Py small T antigen alone and all three Py T antigens together were also constructed and characterized. The recombinant viruses expressing middle T antigen were modified by inclusion of the simian virus 40 3$ sp prime$ RNA-processing signals and/or the Py enhancer to improve their ability to act as expression and gene transfer vectors. The resulting Ad recombinants, constituting a matched set, synthesized middle T protein at different levels in human 293 cells ranging up to 75 times the level observed in a Py lytic infection of mouse 3T6 cells. The amount of stable middle T-pp60$ sp{{ rm c}-src}$ complex was proportional to the total amount of middle T expressed up to a certain level and did not further increase in conditions of extreme middle T overexpression. The presence of the Py enhancer in modified recombinant viruses augmented transient and stable middle T expression in selected cell lines which do not express the E1 functions. Two immunologically distinct middle T subpopulations, representing 30% and 70% of the total middle T present in the cell, were purified by immunoaffinity chromatography from recombinant adenovirus-infected 293 cells. While the smaller middle T subpopulation displayed associated tyrosine kinase activity, the larger one did not. Cellular proteins copurified differentially with each middle T subpopulation. The 92K, 85K, 61K, 36K proteins and pp60$ sp{{ rm c}-src}$ were exclusively found with the 30% subpopulation. The 70-72K doublet and 37K proteins associated with the middle T of both subpopulations. Ranges of transformation frequencies were observed after infection of a variety of murine and human cell strains and lines with recombinant viruses expressing Py middle T antigen alone or all three Py T antigens. Despite the resistance of human cells to transformation, a human mammary epithelial cell line (184A1N4) was successfully transformed. Independent transformed cell lines were isolated and properties indicative of oncogenic transformation were extensively analyzed, highlighting the critical role of the middle pp60$ sp{{ rm c}-src}$ association in middle T-mediated transformation. Transformation of 184A1N4 cells could provide an attractive model for the study of human breast cancer.</description><creator>Davidson, Dominique</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Construction of adenovirus vectors for the efficient transfer and overexpression of polyomavirus middle tumor antigen in mammalian cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bh95j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kr194</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k35695231</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Oral sorbent therapy, as an adjunct or a replacement for dialysis therapy, is one area of research with great potential. If successful it can help kidney failure patients avoid a "life on the machine" existence. For the past twenty years the major problem was in finding an effective oral sorbent for urea. The use of oral microcapsules containing a urease-silica adduct and ion exchanger zirconium phosphate, though successful in reducing urea levels, resulted in a number of problems including a negative calcium balance. In this thesis it is demonstrated that the use of microcapsules containing a urease-zeolite preparation may be a potential route to urea removal. The use of zeolite ion exchangers, and zeolite W in particular, can alleviate the above mentioned problems of zirconium phosphate. In addition, the use of enzyme envelopes on zeolite support, which replaces silica, can reduce the amount of ingested material by at least 25%. The present "in vitro" study shows that the microcapsules remove up to 80% of urea in less than one hour. Preliminary "in vivo" experiments on Sprague-Dawley uraemic rats treated with ingested microcapsules indicate reductions in urea level and a lengthening of survival times compared to controls.</description><creator>Cattaneo, Maurizio Vittorio</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Health Sciences, Medicine and Surgery.</subject><title>The potential of microencapsulated urease-zeolite oral sorbent for the removal of urea in uraemia /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9880vr62j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k35695231</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gk57b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Ultrapotassic, potassic alkaline and shoshonitic magmatism with subduction-related affinity co-existed in a Proterozoic (1089 to 1076 Ma) plutonic environment: the SW Grenville Province. The stocks have silica-saturated and undersaturated, felsic-to-ultramafic units emplaced diapirically in separate, progressively more mafic batches of magma. Most magmas crystallized in situ, and were saturated in apatite, biotite and clinopyroxene. Fractionation of these minerals from a single parental mafic magma is ruled out as the fractionation process prior to emplacement during which Ba, Sr, Nb and Zr were incompatible. Felsic magmas in endoskarns have been contaminated by marble. The paragenesis, the primary LILE, Ca and Al enrichment, and depletion of Nb and Ta typical of ultrapotassic rocks of island-arc, the NE-trend and SE-younging of this belt suggest active NE-trending, SE-dipping subduction during this episode of magmatism and are used to delimit allochthonous terranes.</description><creator>Corriveau, Louise</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>Potassic alkaline plutonism in the southwestern Grenville Province</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gt54kn85c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gk57b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geological Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8p58pd64r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An adequate definition of stability for linear, discrete time, invariant, infinite order systems, and factorization properties in the corresponding space of transfer functions, lead to the design of finite order robust controllers. Moreover, this class of controllers is shown to stabilize stochastic systems. The stabilization by a class of robust adaptive controllers, of non-necessarily minimum phase stochastic linear systems (with possibly unknown or heterogeneous delay) is proved. The plants considered may be slowly time varying. Simulations permit to emphasize the interest of our approach. Compared with the standard Recursive Least Squares and Stochastic Gradient Algorithms, the algorithm we introduce, is more satisfying. Compared with fixed control techniques such as H$ sp infty$-optimization, the adaptive control is shown to have at least a wider range of use, but lower performances.</description><creator>Cantalloube, Hubert</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Robust adaptive control : a Bezout approach</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cb58h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8p58pd64r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0k225b687</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The activities of Neurospora endo-exonuclease, an enzyme which had been implicated in DNA recombination and repair, on double stranded DNAs are characterized further in this work. Endo-exonuclease is shown to have a very low bona fide endonuclease activity on covalently closed circular double stranded DNA. Much higher activity is seen with linear double stranded DNA. The enzyme is shown to bind the DNA at a terminus and track in the 5$ sp prime to 3 sp prime$ direction to make site-specific nicks and double strand breaks at or very near the hexanucleotide sequence pAGCACT or related sequences. The nuclease has a higher affinity for binding DNA with protruding 5$ sp prime$-p termini than for DNA with flush or recessed 5$ sp prime$-p termini. All of the above activities with linear DNA are dependent on the presence of the 5$ sp prime$ terminal phosphates. A very specific, cytosolic inhibitor of endo-exonuclease has been purified. The inhibitor is a single polypeptide of 24 kDa which is trypsin-sensitive and very heat-stable. The protein inhibits the double strand DNase activity of endo-exonuclease competitively and fully when present in excess. The inhibition of the single strand DNase activity is noncompetitive but incomplete even when the inhibitor is present in excess. The inhibitor is also shown to inhibit the site-specific nicking and breaking activities of endo-exonuclease. The 24 kDa inhibitor is present in the cell in three forms: two free forms and one in association with inactive but trypsin-activatable endo-exonuclease. One of the free forms is shown to be related to an inhibitor which is induced by heat shock. Several inhibitory polypeptides (with molecular sizes of 94, 83, 52, 35 and 17 kDa) copurify with the 24 kDa inhibitor and are immunochemically related to it. The results of immunochemical studies of these polypeptides indicate that the 24 kDa inhibitor and endo-exonuclease are derived from a common higher molecular weight precursor, probably 94 kDa in size. A role for the inhibitor in the regulation of endo-exonuclease activities is suggested. Finally, a model for the action of endo-exonuclease in recombination and double strand break repair is proposed.</description><creator>Hatahet, Zafer</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Chemistry, Biochemistry.</subject><title>Neurospora endo-exonuclease : actions on double strand DNAs and a specific inhibitor</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/2n49t265d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0k225b687</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:st74cr09n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effects of glucocorticoids and agents affecting membrane phospholipid metabolism on $ beta$-adrenergic receptors ($ beta$AR) have been studied in A549 cultured human lung tumor cells and in IM-9 cultured human lymphocytes. Various glucocorticoids increased the density of $ beta$AR in A549 lung cells but not in IM-9 lymphocytes, although they did increase insulin receptor density in IM-9 lymphocytes. In contrast, bee venom phospholipase A$ sb2$ (0.05-0.2 units/ml), but not phospholipases C or D., downregulated $ beta$AR in IM-9 lymphocytes, but did not affect $ beta$AR in A549 lung cells. Upregulation of $ beta$AR by glucocorticoids was partially reversed by arachidonic acid (10 $ mu$M) but not by lysophospatidylcholine. These results suggest that glucocorticoids upregulate pulmonary $ beta$AR partly through their inhibition of membrane phospholipase A2 and the subsequent generation of arachidonic acid and/or its metabolites, which may act by modulating a direct effect of glucocorticoids on the synthesis of $ beta$AR. Coculturing IM-9 lymphocytes and A549 lung cells results in a 2-3-fold increase in the density of $ beta$AR in A549 lung cells. Lymphocyte conditioned medium (LCM) has the same effect, which is moderately sensitive to heat, is retained by ultrafiltration over a 10,000 m.w. cut-off filter, and is reduced by trypsin treatment or by preincubation of lymphocytes with cycloheximide (1$ mu$m). Treatment of lung cells with cycloheximide also prevents the effect of LCM. Glucocorticoids, which also increase $ beta$AR density in A549 lung cells, markedly potentiate the effects of LCM. Gel permeation HPLC of LCM yields 3 peaks of biological activity with M.W. 70,000, 35,000 and 15,000. Monocytic Interleukin-1 (IL-1) mimics the effect of LCM in that it increases $ beta$AR density in A549 lung cells and its effect is potentiated by cortisol. Recombinant IL-1$ alpha$ is somewhat more potent then IL-1$ beta$, while Interleukin-2 and interferon-$ alpha$ are inef</description><creator>Stern, Ligia R.</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Regulation of beta-adrenergic receptors in cultured lung cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dv13zv04r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/st74cr09n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr171x89h</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Simulations based on a month of radar data from Florida, and a summer of radar data from Nelspruit, South Africa, were used to quantify the errors in the measurement of mean areal rainfall which arise simply as a result of the extreme variability of convective rainfall, even with perfect remote sensing instruments. The raingauge network measurement errors were established for random and regular network configurations using daily and monthly radar-rainfall accumulations over large areas. A relationship to predict the measurement error for mean areal rainfall using sparse networks as a function of raining area, number of gauges, and the variability of the rainfield was developed and tested. The manner in which the rainfield probability distribution is transformed under increasing spatial and temporal averaging was investigated from two perspectives. Firstly, an empirical relationship was developed to transform the probability distribution based on some measurement scale, into a distribution based on a standard measurement length. Secondly, a conceptual model based on multiplicative cascades was used to derive a scale independent probability distribution.</description><creator>Seed, Alan William</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Rain and rainfall -- Statistical methods.</subject><subject>Rain and rainfall -- Florida.</subject><subject>Rain and rainfall -- South Africa -- Nelspruit.</subject><subject>Rain and rainfall -- Measurement.</subject><title>Statistical problems in measuring convective rainfall</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/08612p35w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr171x89h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vh53ww515</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The human health risk associated with exposure to pesticide formulations applied to New Brunswick forests was examined for 31 sites of cancer, using measures of exposure based on the proximity of non-city population centers to spray areas. Two organochlorine and two organophosphate exposure indices were developed by using maps of areas sprayed each year during the period 1952 to 1976. These data were analyzed in relation to cancer incidence rates during the period 1977-l980 for 254 New Brunswick municipalities. Follow-up case-control studies of the cancer sites considered does not seem to be a matter of high priority at present. However, continued surveillance and data analysis involving more recent data is needed, particularly in the case of organophosphate formulations, due to the relatively short interval between exposure and outcome ascertainment for this exposure.</description><creator>Seliske, Patrick</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><title>Forestry pesticide spraying and cancer incidence in New Brunswick : an ecological study</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ns064673h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vh53ww515</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913q57p</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Gas phase axial dispersion for gas-liquid countercurrent contacting in mobile bed contacting (MBC) and in a spray column were measured for 240 combinations of five variables, gas and liquid flow rate, packing size and density and static bed height, for MBC; for 114 combinations of three variables, gas and liquid flow rate and static bed height, for the spray contactor. The experimental technique was dynamic response to a tracer, coupled with moment equations for the system in axially dispersed plug flow (ADPF). The ADPF model was found to represent well the residence time distribution curves for all experiments with both gas-liquid contactors. Comprehensive correlations were obtained as axial dispersion number, D/u$ sb{ rm G}$d$ sb{ rm p}$, for MBC; as dispersion length, D/u$ sb{ rm G}$, for spray contacting. For spray contacting, gas dispersion length increases strongly with liquid flow rate but varies little with gas flow rate and column height. For MBC, axial dispersion number is very sensitive to packing size and to liquid flow rate, but has low dependence on static bed height and gas flow rate. Axial dispersion number is linearly proportional to liquid holdup, with this proportionality a weak function of only static bed height. The trends in axial dispersion number with operating variables for MBC parallel those for countercurrent gas-liquid flow in fixed bed contacting (FBC), but with the much higher throughputs possible with MBC than in FBC, axial dispersion number is typically about one order of magnitude higher. In both contactors the effect of axial dispersion on mass transfer is demonstrated to be very important at high recovery level. A comprehensive analysis of hydrodynamics and mass transfer in MBC is presented. For the model of transient response of mass transfer between two fluid phases, both in axially dispersed countercurrent flow, moment equations were derived for the general case and for one special case. These moment derivations provide the needed theoretical framework for future experimental investigation of the degree of interaction between coefficients of mass transfer and of axial dispersion.</description><creator>Ercan, Cemal</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><title>Gas phase dispersion in mobile bed and spray contacting</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1v53jx76c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913q57p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bk128b62b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis is divided into two parts. In part I, the monomeric and dimeric metal carbonyl complexes, M(CO)$ sb6$ (M = Cr, Mo, W), CpMn(CO)$ sb3$ (Cp = $ eta sp5$-C$ sb5$H$ sb5$), ($ eta sp6$-C$ sb6$H$ sb6$)Cr(CO)$ sb3$, (CpFe(CO)$ sb2$) $ sb2$, (CpMo(CO)$ sb3$) $ sb2$, Mn$ sb2$(CO)$ sb{10}$ and trans-Ir(CO)Cl(PPh$ sb3$)$ sb2$, have been embedded into polystyrene (PS), poly(methylmethacrylate) (PMMA) and poly(styreneacrylonitrile) (PSAN) polymer film matrices. The environments experienced by the metal complexes as a function of the polymer type have been characterized by vibrational spectroscopy and have been compared with those of the structurally-related solvents toluene, ethyl acetate and acetonitrile, respectively. Several of films have been subjected to UV irradiation in order to study the solid-state photochemistry of metal carbonyls in donor and non-donor polymer matrices and the effect of the polymer microstructure on the photodecomposition of the complexes. Iodine oxidation of the dimeric complexes in different polymer films and the chemical reactivity of Vaska's complex in PS upon exposure to the simple molecular gases, H$ sb2$, O$ sb2$, CO, SO$ sb2$ and I$ sb2$ have also been examined. In part II, treatment of an electrically-nonconducting copolymer of 3-methyl- and 3-hexylthiophene with (CpFe(CO)$ sb2$(H$ sb2$C = CMe$ sb2$)) BF$ sb4$ gave an electrically-conducting material ($ sigma$ = 10$ sp{-3}$-10$ sp{-4}$ $ Omega sp{-1}$ cm$ sp{-1}$). The IR, UV and NMR spectra of this material and of model complexes suggest that (CpFe(CO)$ sb2$)) $ sp+$ residues, which are attached to the sulfur atoms of the thiophene rings of the copolymer backbone, induce the improved conductivity.</description><creator>Gao, Jian Ping, 1960-</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Chemistry, Inorganic.</subject><title>Polymer films as media for organometallic chemistry, and the preparation and characterization of an electrically conducting poly(3-alkylthiophene)-iron(II) complex</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5t34sk269.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bk128b62b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pz50gw903</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Fluoride ions smoothly destannylate organotin oxides, sulfides and selenides to liberate highly nucleophilic species ("S$ sp{2-}$", RS$ sp-$, RO$ sp-$, RSe$ sp-$, etc.). Also, the first nucleophilic oxide "O$ sp{2-}$" and selenide "Se$ sp{2-}$" transfer agents are reported. The tin atom thus serves as a general "group 16 (VIB) transfer agent". In the presence of crown ethers or ammonium salts, this process results in a new way to generate "naked" nucleophiles. Novel anhydrous fluorinating systems (CsF and crown ethers) involving solid-liquid phase transfer catalysis have been designed and studied. In addition, C-C bond forming reactions have been investigated by fluorodestannylation. As an extension of these results, fluorodegermanylation and fluorodeplumbylation reactions are reported. As a generalization, fluoride ion demetalates the whole group 14 for releasing nucleophilic species. Some pentacoordinated intermediates have been observed by $ sp{19}$F and $ sp{119}$Sn NMR spectroscopy in fluorodestannylation, thus confirming the model of nucleophilic substitution at tin and silicon. Mechanistic aspects are discussed along with a possible metal proximity effect in the enhancement of the nucleophilicity of an anion. Finally, in the presence of silver salts, bis(tributyltin) oxide acts as a mild oxygen transfer agent in converting primary organic iodides and bromides to alcohols.</description><creator>Gingras, Marc</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Fluorodemetalation reactions of organogermanium, -tin and lead compounds</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/wm117p59d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pz50gw903</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54kn86n</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis addresses the ill-posed problem of estimating two-dimensional motion in time-varying images. The approach proposed here uses the theory of stochastic processes at the formulation and solution stages. Independent Gaussian random variables are used to model the relationship between motion fields and images, and vector and binary Markov random fields are used to model motion and motion discontinuity fields, respectively. These models, combined using Bayes rule, result in Gibbsian a posteriori probability distribution from which the Maximum A Posteriori Probability (MAP) and the Minimum Expected Cost (MEC) estimation criteria are derived. Optimization of these criteria is performed using stochastic relaxation. The MAP estimation is extended to handle large displacements via hierarchical approach. Deterministic approximations to some of the stochastic algorithms proposed are derived and compared with their stochastic counterparts. The colour information is incorporated into the estimation process. Numerous experimental results are included. Two of the methods proposed are applied to motion-compensated interpolation and shown to reduce certain type of errors.</description><creator>Konrad, Janusz</creator><date>1989</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Bayesian estimation of motion fields from image sequences</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kt564.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54kn86n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8g84mm94q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Yaffe, Phyllis Cohen, 1948-</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Picasso, Pablo, 1881-1973 -- Themes, motives</subject><subject>Picasso, Pablo, 1881-1973 -- Criticism and interpretation</subject><subject>Painting -- Themes, motives.</subject><title>The 'artist and model' theme in Picasso's work between 1926 and 1963 /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w0892b53d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8g84mm94q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Art History</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29b682q</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:08:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>De Bie, Linden J.</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Mercersburg theology</subject><subject>Theology, Doctrinal -- United States</subject><title>German idealism in protestant orthodoxy : the Mercersburg Movement, 1840-1860</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gb19f6549.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29b682q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Religious Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):41250</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>