<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T02:23:49Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33725" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jw827d34z</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Responses from pedigree selection for resistance to gibberella ear rot were assessed in four maize (Zea mays L.) populations, two selected after inoculation of Fusarium graminearum (Schwabe) macroconidia into the silk channel and two selected after inoculation into developing kernels. Responses were significant in both populations selected for silk resistance and in one of the populations selected for kernel resistance. Selection was more effective in later generations and genetic gains were associated with among-family selection but not with within-family selection. Results obtained here indicate that responses to selection could be more efficiently obtained by applying high selection intensities in advanced generations, by managing earlier generations as bulks and by reducing the number of plants per family. In another experiment, a wide sample of Argentine maize germplasm was evaluated for silk and kernel resistance to gibberella ear rot and to fusarium ear rot (caused by F. verticillioides (Saccardo) Nirenberg [=F. moniliforme (Sheldon)]. Several entries exhibited disease resistance in comparison with local check hybrids, particularly for fusarium ear rot, the most prevalent ear rot in Argentina. Results obtained in this study suggested the presence of general mechanisms controlling silk and kernel resistance to both diseases. In a supplementary study, viral diseases were surveyed in maize fields from the provinces of Ontario and Quebec in 1999 and 2000. Barley yellow dwarf was found in 1999. Sugarcane mosaic, maize dwarf mosaic and wheat streak mosaic were found in 2000. These diseases were not important for grain-maize planted in May, the most prevalent kind of maize crop in these provinces. Some of these diseases, such as sugarcane maize mosaic and maize dwarf mosaic were found important only in maize fields planted during or after the month of June, and this is of commercial relevance only for sweet corn.</description><creator>Presello, Daniel A.</creator><date>2001</date><subject>Virus diseases of plants -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Fusarium diseases of plants.</subject><subject>Corn -- Diseases and pests -- Ontario.</subject><subject>Virus diseases of plants -- Ontario.</subject><subject>Corn -- Diseases and pests -- Québec (Province).</subject><subject>Fusarium graminearum.</subject><subject>Corn -- Disease and pest resistance -- Genetic aspects.</subject><title>Studies on breeding of maize for resistance to ear rots caused by Fusarium spp. and on the occurrence of viruses in maize in eastern Canada</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gj01s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jw827d34z</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9p290c151</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:00Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation situates literary modernism in the context of a nascent form of globalization. Before it could be fully acknowledged global encroachment was, by virtue of its novelty, repeatedly experienced as a kind of shattering or disintegration. Through an examination of three modernist novels, I argue that a general modernist preoccupation with space both expresses and occludes anxieties over a globe which suddenly seemed to be too small and too undifferentiated. Building upon recent critical work that has begun to historicize modernist understandings of space, I address the as yet under-appreciated ways in which globalism and its discontents informed all of the locales that modernist fictions variously inhabited. For Joseph Conrad, James Joyce, and Virginia Woolf, the responses to global change were as diverse as the spaces through which they were inflected. I begin by identifying a modernist predilection for spatial metaphors. This rhetorical touchstone has, from New Criticism onward, been so sedimented within critical responses to the era that modernism's interest in global space has itself frequently been diminished. In my readings of Conrad's Heart of Darkness, Joyce's Ulysses, and Woolf's To the Lighthouse, I argue that the signs of globalization are ubiquitous across modernism. As Conrad repeats and contests New Imperialist constructions of Africa as a vanishing space, that continent becomes the stage for his anxieties over a newly diminished globe. For Joyce, Dublin's conflicted status as both provincial capital and colonial metropolis makes that city the perfect site in which to worry over those recent world-wide developments. Finally, I argue that for Woolf, it is the domestic space which serves best to register and resist the ominous signs of global incursion. In conclusion, I suggest that modernism's anticipatory attention to globalization makes the putative break between that earlier era and postmodernity---itself often predicated upon spatial compression---all the more difficult to maintain.</description><creator>McIntyre, John, 1966-</creator><contributor>Hickman, Miranda (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Space and time in literature.</subject><subject>Conrad, Joseph, 1857-1924. Heart of darkness.</subject><subject>Modernism (Literature)</subject><subject>Joyce, James, 1882-1941. Ulysses.</subject><subject>Woolf, Virginia, 1882-1941. To the lighthouse.</subject><title>Modernism for a small planet : diminishing global space in the locales of Conrad, Joyce, and Woolf</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g158bj81d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9p290c151</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c247dt68k</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis investigates the question of how the arguments of a given verb are linked to positions in a phrase structure. Through a study of passives, psych verbs, and ditransitive verbs in Japanese, it provides empirical support for the hypothesis that arguments having particular thematic roles are associated with particular syntactic positions systematically. Chapter 2 deals with passives, in particular, two types of passive constructions, direct and indirect passives. Following some previous works, it is argued that the subject of a direct passive is generated in the same position as an object of the corresponding active verb, having the same thematic role, whereas the subject of an indirect passive is projected as an argument of a separate predicate. Several pieces of evidence for this hypothesis which are not given in the literature are provided here. Chapter 3 is concerned with psych verbs, focusing on those that participate in a causative alternation. It is proposed that causative counterparts of these verbs can have two different structures that are parallel to the two types of passives discussed in Chapter 2. The subject of one type is generated in the same position as the object of the noncausative counterpart, having the same thematic role, whereas the subject of the other type is projected as an argument of a separate predicate. Chapter 4 takes up ditransitive verbs, specifically, those that have inchoative counterparts, which do not project the subject of the ditransitive construction. There are two types of such verbs: one promotes the accusative argument of the ditransitive construction, rather than the dative one, to the subject of the inchoative counterpart, while the other chooses the dative argument over the accusative one for the subject of the inchoative counterpart. It is argued that this reflects the difference in the base-generated position of the dative argument between the two types of verbs. Moreover, the dative arguments of the two are distinguished in terms of thematic role. This research is meant to contribute toward having a further understanding of how the participants of an event are expressed in grammatical forms.</description><creator>Matsuoka, Mikinari.</creator><contributor>Travis, Lisa deMena (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Japanese language -- Verb phrase</subject><subject>Japanese language -- Passive voice</subject><title>Linking arguments to phrase structure : a study of passives, psych verbs, and ditransitive verbs in Japanese</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ff3656865.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c247dt68k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Linguistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xd07gv27q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>To elucidate mechanisms involved in the regulation of a number of mammalian cell differentiation events, studies were performed to characterize the transcriptional repression functions of the Groucho/TLEs, Hairy and Enhancer of split (Hes), and Runt-related (RUNX) protein families. These proteins have been shown to have overlapping or antagonistic roles in a number of cell differentiation processes, in both Drosophila and mammals. More specifically, the aim was to elucidate mechanisms by which Hes and RUNX-mediated transcriptional control is modulated, with respect to their interactions with each other and the Groucho/TLE proteins. It is shown here that mammalian Hes1 requires TLEs to repress gene expression, similar to the requirement Drosophila Hes proteins have for Groucho. It is shown further that TLEs also interact with mammalian RUNX proteins and inhibit RUNX's ability to transactivate gene expression. In contrast, Hes1 also physically associates with RUNX and enhances RUNX-mediated transactivation. These results, together with our additional finding that RUNX can inhibit Hes1-mediated transcriptional repression, suggest for the first time that RUNX and Hes1 proteins regulate each other's transcriptional functions. This thesis also shows that Hes1 can be found in a discreet nuclear subcompartment involved in the regulation of gene expression, termed the nuclear matrix. Nuclear matrix binding is mediated by the same Hes1 C-terminal domain that acts as a binding site for Groucho/TLEs, which also localize to the nuclear matrix and are required for Hes1-mediated transcriptional repression. Both the nuclear matrix association and transcription repression activity of Hes1 are inhibited by deletion of its C-terminal region, indicating that Groucho/TLEs act as transcriptional corepressors for Hes1. Together, the material presented in this thesis suggests that Hes1 and RUNX proteins interact with each other to modulate gene expression in the development of a number of tissues.</description><creator>McLarren, Keith W.</creator><contributor>Stifani, Stefano (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Biology, Molecular.</subject><title>Characterizing the physical and functional interactions between RUNX, Hes1 and TLE proteins</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jw827d357.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gv27q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gh93h1183</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:01Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Using the Galerkin method to solve nonlinear integro-differential equations of elliptic or parabolic type one needs to solve the resulting nonlinear systems of algebraic or ordinary differential equations. To solve these equations with Newtons method or a variant thereof can be very difficult and one needs a good initial guess for the methods to converge. Also there might be multiple solutions and it is virtually impossible to track all of them. In addition it is hard to study the parameter dependence of solutions. We developed a remedy for these problems by developing the sequential spectral method which avoids solving a nonlinear system altogether. In the sequential spectral method a scalar nonlinear algebraic or ordinary differential equation is solved at the initial stage and then the solution of the original problem is obtained through iterations, we never have to solve a nonlinear system at any stage of the method. The sequential spectral method converges linearly for steady state problems and superlinearly in the case of evolution. With the sequential spectral method we can obtain solutions to any desired accuracy with much less effort than with the Galerkin method. We can also increase the spectral degree of accuracy while the method is running. In addition one can easily detect the existence of multiple solutions by observing only a single equation and one can track those solutions. The behavior of the solution and the dependence on parameters can be estimated and one can also determine the blow up time for the corresponding parameter values by studying only a single equation. We further show that the sequential spectral method can be applied to a system of nonlinear elliptic partial differential equations.</description><creator>Mansoora, Abida.</creator><contributor>Gander, Martin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>The sequential spectral method for integro-differential equations /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/st74cs079.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h1183</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k643b2726</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this thesis, I argue that identity construction is a postal effect: it results from a transmission of some sort, received or sent. I examine three instances of postal effect. In a chapter on Jacques Derrida's "Envois," a collection of fragments presented as if transcribed from a one-way love letter correspondence, I explore the performative force of relayed address. Working from Derrida's account of the literary performative, I point out that the "Envois" letters are addressed to "you" in the singular, which implies an address reserved for a particular subject, but that the postal relay of the collection enacts a repetition of their address. For the reader of the book, this repetition has evocative force which I compare with the force of transference in the context of the psychoanalytic situation. In a second chapter on the "Envois" letters, I examine their haunting effect. The "Envois" letters have an I/we signature that intimates pluralities in the writing subject. I argue that this signature is the effect of a postal relay of another order: a phantom, which Nicolas Abraham and Maria Torok define as a gap in the psychic topography of the subject caused by a secret unwittingly received along with a legacy. To a certain extent, the "Envois" letters are written by Plato's "in-voices." In a chapter on J. M. Coetzee's epistolary novel Age of Iron, I explore the gift effects of a posthumous letter. Age of Iron is an epistolary novel consisting exclusively of a single letter written by a dying South African woman, Mrs. Curren, to her daughter, a political objector who has emigrated to the United States. Writing her letter in the knowledge that her death is imminent, Mrs. Curren anticipates her daughter's mourning. Working with J. L. Austin's doctrine of illocutionary forces and Derrida's analysis of the gift event, I postulate two effects of Mrs. Curren's letter, one that annuls the gift in a circular return and another that surpasses this circuit with textual diss</description><creator>Hogarth, Claire Milne.</creator><contributor>Hensley, David D. C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Epistolary fiction.</subject><subject>Derrida, Jacques. Envois.</subject><subject>Coetzee, J. M., 1940- Age of iron.</subject><subject>Identity (Psychology) in literature.</subject><title>Epistolary constructions of identity in Derrida's "Envois" and Coetzee's Age of Iron</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kw52j9607.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k643b2726</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of English</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:j9602248q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:02Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of these investigations was to compare changes in child conduct problem behavior and parental ability and to examine the relationship between parent and child outcome. An A/B research design was used across two studies with a total of 34 children (aged 3--10 years) and 43 parents randomly assigned to one of three parent-mediated treatment modalities (i.e., individualized conjoint behavioral consultation using a self-administered treatment manual; CBC, group-administered videotape parent training with shared consultant contact; GVT, and self-administered videotape parent training with minimal consultant contact; VT). In the first study, child outcome was evaluated using direct observations of target behavior, along with pretreatment and posttreatment estimates of problem behavior on standardized instruments. Both single- n and group analyses were used for analysis of data. The results indicated that 77%, 50%, and 75% of children in the CBC, GVT and VT groups respectively, evidenced at a minimum, small improvements in their conduct problem target behaviour. In addition, parents reported global improvements in children's problem behavior. No differential effects of treatment group, however, were detected. A second study was carried out to examine the mediating factors thought to produce children's behavioral improvements. Outcome was evaluated for parents through the use of observed child-management skills during parent-child play interactions and by using pretreatment and posttreatment estimates of parental knowledge of behavioral principles and attitudes toward parenting (i.e., satisfaction, involvement and limit setting). Further, children's level of deviancy (e.g., noncompliance) was examined during parent-child play interactions. Results of single-n analyses varied depending on the parent variable examined, however group analyses revealed improvements in parental use of several child management skills and in parental knowledge. For the children, ind</description><creator>Illsley, Staci D.</creator><contributor>Sladeczek, Ingrid E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Parenting.</subject><subject>Parent and child.</subject><subject>Problem children.</subject><subject>Problem children -- Behavior modification.</subject><title>Remediating conduct problems in children : examining changes in children and parents following consultation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0v8382207.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/j9602248q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Educational and Counselling Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dj52w645c</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The objective of this research was to further understand the behavior of the soil under the action of a tillage tool, with the purpose of finding a relation between the tool geometry and the resultant soil seed bed. Thus the problem consisted of understanding the mechanics of producing soil break up and to find a logical method of analyzing it. The problem was solved using fundamental principles of soil mechanics and force equilibrium analyzis. As a result, a mathematical model was developed which describes three failure zones within the cut soil volume. The model can be programmed into a computer to generate maps of normal and shear stresses to visualize the three failure zones. The failure zones are the shear failure zone, the tensile fracturing zone and the no failure zone. The tensile fracturing zone is delimited by the tensile stress reaching the tensile strength of the soil at the given soil moisture content and soil density. The tensile strength of the soil was measured using an apparatus and method designed in this research. The mathematical model gives an explanation of the mechanics of crumbling and the shape of the failed volume, but it does not give information concerning soil aggregate quality and arrangement within the soil furrow. Then, a method of analyzing the formed aggregates was developed which considers some soil physical properties of aggregates. The study concluded that the smaller tool width and the smaller tool rake angle, among the ones used in this research, produced the most efficient geometry in producing the largest amount of soil break up, the most uniform aggregate formation and the most stable aggregate arrangement. The same tool geometry requires less energy per unit volume of soil disturbed. The best performance is produced at the lowest soil water content among those tested.</description><creator>Ibarra, Sandra.</creator><contributor>McKyes, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Shear strength of soils.</subject><subject>Soil structure.</subject><subject>Tillage -- Equipment and supplies.</subject><title>A model of stress distribution and cracking in cohesive soils produced by simple tillage implements /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wk93x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w645c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural and Biosystems Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:g732db647</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new method for the synthesis of the [4,3,1] carbocyclic core of the squalene synthase and farnesyl transferase inhibitor CP-225,917 is developed. The key step relies on the [6+4] cycloaddition between a tropone and a cyclopentadiene. This reaction proceeds with excellent regio- and stereoselectivity and allows rapid and convergent access to the polycyclic core of the molecule. In the course of this work, it was discovered that the cycloaddition process is significantly accelerated in presence of the catalytic amount of ZnCl2. This is the first example of Lewis acid catalyzed [6+4] tropone cycloaddition. Introduction of other functional groups towards the synthesis of CP-225,917 skeleton is described. The key to the success of this strategy is a position selective Baeyer-Villiger oxidation on the tricyclic cycloadduct. This reveals functionality which can be used to elaborate the C9 side-chain and incorporate the bridgehead olefin.* *Please refer to dissertation for diagrams.</description><creator>Isakovic, Ljubomir.</creator><contributor>Gleason, James L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Chemistry, Organic.</subject><title>Synthesis of the carbocyclic core of CP-225,917</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m613n026z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/g732db647</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qr46r271n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:03Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>CWH41 is required for beta-1,6-glucan biosynthesis and encodes glucosidase I, an enzyme involved in protein N-chain glucose processing. Therefore, the effects of N-chain glucosylation and processing on beta-1,6-glucan biosynthesis were examined, and it was shown that incomplete N-chain glucose processing results in loss of beta-1,6-glucan. To explore the involvement of other N-chain-dependent events with beta-1,6-glucan synthesis, the S. cerevisiae KRE5 and CNE1 genes were investigated, which encode homologs of the 'quality control' components UDP-Glc:glycoprotein glucosyltransferase and calnexin, respectively. The essential activity of Kre5p was found to be separate from its possible role as a UDP-Glc:glycoprotein glucosyltransferase. A ~30% decrease in beta-1,6-glucan was observed upon disruption of CNE1, a phenotype which is additive with other beta-1,6-glucan synthetic mutants. Analysis of the cell wall anchorage of alpha-agglutinin suggests the existence of two beta-1,6-glucan biosynthetic pathways, one N-chain dependent, the other involving protein glycosylphosphatidylinositol modification. Fks1p and Fks2p are related proteins thought to be catalytic subunits of the beta-1,3-glucan synthase. The fks1Delta mutant was partial K1 killer toxin resistant and showed a 30% reduction in alkali-soluble beta-1,3-glucan that was accompanied by a modest reduction in beta-1,6-glucan. The gas1Delta mutant lacking a 1,3-beta-glucanosyltransferase displayed a similar reduction in alkali-soluble beta-1,3-glucan but did not share the beta-1,6-glucan defect, indicating that beta-1,6-glucan reduction is not a general phenotype among beta-1,3-glucan biosynthetic mutants. FKS2 overexpression suppressed the killer toxin phenotype of fks1Delta mutants, implicating Fks2p in the biosynthesis of the residual beta-1,6-glucan present in fks1Delta cells. Eight out of twelve fks1tsfks2Delta mutants had altered beta-glucan levels at the permissive temperature: the FKS1F1258Y N1520D allele was severely affected in both polymers and displayed a 55% reduction in beta-1,6-glucan, while the in vitro hyperactive FKS1T6051 M761T allele increased both beta-glucan levels. These beta-1,6-glucan phenotypes may be due to altered availability of, and structural changes in, the beta-1,3-glucan polymer, which might serve as a beta-1,6-glucan acceptor at the cell surface. Alternatively, Fks1p and Fks2p could actively participate in the biosynthesis of both polymers as beta-glucan transporters. beta-1,6-Glucan deficient mutants had reduced in vitro glucan synthase activity and mislocalized Fks1p and Fks2p, possibly contributing to the observed beta-1,6-glucan defects.</description><creator>Dijkgraaf, Gerrit J. P.</creator><contributor>Bussey, Howard (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Glucans.</subject><subject>Fungal cell walls.</subject><subject>Saccharomyces cerevisiae -- Genetics.</subject><subject>Saccharomyces cerevisiae -- Cytology.</subject><title>N-chain glucose processing and proper -1,3-glucan biosynthesis are required for normal cell wall -1,6-glucan levels in Saccharomyces cerevisiae</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322f93f.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qr46r271n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2v23vv881</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this thesis is to evaluate the downscaling ability of one-way nesting regional climate models (RCM). To do this, a rigorous and well-defined experiment for assessing the reliability of the one-way nesting approach is developed. This experiment, baptised the Big-Brother Experiment (BBE), is used for addressing some important one-way nesting issues. The first part of this work is dedicated to the development of a scale decomposition tool employed for the BBE. This tool involves a new spectral analysing technique suitable for two-dimensional fields on limited-area domains, and is based on the discrete cosine transform (DCT). It is used for degrading the spatial resolution of the lateral boundary conditions (LBC) used to drive the Canadian RCM (CRCM), for extracting mesoscale features from the atmospheric fields, and for regional validation, and producing power spectra. The second part of the thesis describes the BBE framework and its first results. The BBE consists in first establishing a reference virtual-reality climate from an RCM simulation using a large and high-resolution domain. This simulation is called the "Big Brother". This big-brother simulation is then degraded toward the resolution of today's global objective analyses (OA) and/or global climate models (GCM) by removing the short scales. The resulting fields are then used as nesting data to drive an RCM (called the "Little Brother") which is integrated at the same high-resolution as the Big Brother, but over a sub-area of the big-brother domain. The climate statistics of the Little Brother are then compared with those of the big-brother simulation over the little-brother domain. Differences between the two climates can thus be unambiguously attributed to errors associated with the dynamical downscaling technique, and not to model errors nor to observation limitations. The results for a February simulation shows that the Canadian RCM, using a factor of 6 between the model and the LBC spatial resolution, and an update interval of 3 hours, is capable to pass the BBE test; thus showing the reliability of the one-way nesting approach. In the third and last part of the thesis, the BBE is used to investigate the sensitivity of an RCM to the spatial resolution and temporal update frequency of the LBC. It is shown that spatial resolution jumps of 12, and an update frequency between twice a day (every 12 hours) and four times a day (every 6 hours), are the limits for which a 45-km RCM yields acceptable results.</description><creator>Denis, Bertrand.</creator><contributor>Laprise, Rene (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Physics, Atmospheric Science.</subject><subject>Geophysics.</subject><title>A test for evaluating the downscaling ability of one-way nested regional climate models : the big-brother experiment</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/jq085m957.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2v23vv881</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Atmospheric and Oceanic Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ms35tb04h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Previous studies on Leafy reduced-stature (LRS) maize found that it had extremely early maturity and a higher harvest index (HI), leading to high yields for its maturity rating. Whether this apparent high HI is relaxed to its earliness, or can also exist among the medium or late maturity LRS maize has not been previously investigated. It was also of interest to know if the traits that produced the LRS canopy structure have pleiotropic effects on root architecture. Finally, field observations indicated that LRS maize had a lower incidence of common smut. It is not known whether this apparent resistance is specific to smut or includes other diseases. Using a wide range of the most recently developed LRS hybrids and some conventional hybrids, a two-year field experiment was conducted to examine the HI and disease resistance of LRS maize. HI, yield, and yield components were compared between the two genotype groups (LRS and conventional) under different population densities. The resistance to the natural incidence of common smut and artificially inoculated Gibberella ear rot was also tested. Morphology and fractal dimension analyses of roots at an early development stage were conducted in indoor experiments. These analyses were performed with WinRHIZO (version 3.9), an interactive scanner-based image analysis system. This work showed that: (1) There was no relationship between the HI and maturity; higher HIs can also exist among the medium and late maturity LRS hybrids. (2) While LRS maize hybrids have the potential for high yield this was not realized in the LRS hybrids used in this work. Further breeding and development of optimum management practices are needed to fully exploit this potential. (3) During early development LRS hybrids generally had more branching and more complex root systems than conventional hybrids. (4) Fractal dimension, as a comprehensive estimation of root complexity, was highly related to major root morphological variables, such as root total length, surface area, branching frequency and dry mass. (5) Of the hybrids tested the greatest resistance to both common smut and Gibberella ear rot, two major ear diseases, occurred in some of the LRS types.</description><creator>Deng, Yinghai, 1966-</creator><contributor>Smith, Donald L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Corn -- Disease and pest resistance -- Québec (Province) -- Genetic aspects.</subject><subject>Fractals.</subject><subject>Corn -- Morphology.</subject><subject>Corn -- Roots -- Anatomy.</subject><title>Development and disease resistance of leafy reduced stature maize (Zea mays L.)</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1n79h619v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ms35tb04h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w9505214n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study investigates the constitutive elements of a prototantric scripture, the Mahamayuri Vidya-rajni sutra (MMVR) in its Chinese translations. The Scripture of the Great Peahen, Queen Protectress consists of long lists of indian divinities, most of them non-Buddhist, followed by Sanskrit magical spells (dharaṇi) which were used in ritual to bring rain, conquer enemies, cure sickness, and eliminate a host of other obstacles. The language of the text is hermetic and describes a pantheon of gods and goddesses which were completely alien to the Chinese patrons who sponsored the performance of the rites of the MMVR by Buddhist specialists. Despite this, there were no less than six known Chinese translations, dating from the 4th to the 8th centuries, and Japanese historical chronicles testify to its continued use till the 13th century in Japan. This essay offers a complete translation of the Scripture, and explores the rationale of the text. It seeks to analyze the tradition of the Pali protection spells (paritta) and tries to understand the role of non-Buddhist divinities within the Buddhist context of magical protection and the Chinese traditions of invocation and propitiatory spells. By reviewing influential theories about the evolution of Buddhist esotericism, the author tries to ascertain the place and role of the Scripture and its central divinity, the Great Peahen (Mahamayuri), in the formation of Tantrism.</description><creator>DesJardins, J. F. Marc.</creator><contributor>Dean, Kenneth (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Theology</subject><title>Mahamayuri : explorations sur la creation d'une ecriture prototantrique</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b779m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w9505214n</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of East Asian Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9g54xk243</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The phosphodiesterase (PDE) inhibitors Pentoxifylline (PTX), a general inhibitor, and Rolipram (ROL), a type 4 inhibitor, have been shown to have anti-inflammatory effects. They elevate intracellular CAMP levels and suppress the production of inflammatory cytokines such as tumor necrosis factor (TNF)alpha, interferon (IFN)gamma, and interleukin-12 (IL-12). These drugs have also been reported to modulate the immune response in favor of Th2 responses and to be therapeutically effective in various models of autoimmune and/or inflammatory disorders. Their effects on nitric oxide (NO) production are not well studied. Inflammatory cytokines and NO are important mediators implicated in islet beta-cell destruction. In the first part of the study, we examined the effect of PTX and ROL in preventing insulitis and diabetes in non-obese diabetes-prone (NOD) mice as a spontaneous model of insulin-dependent diabetes (IDDM). We found that a 4 week treatment with either PTX or ROL had a strong protective effect, that was still apparent 11 weeks after withdrawing the drugs. Both drugs were equally effective at optimal doses in preventing mstiulitis and diabetes in NOD mice. In the second part of the study, we examined the effects of PDE inhibitors on NO production by peritoneal macrophages and RAW 246.7 cells. We also correlated these effects with elevated cAMP levels. We found that both PTX and ROL suppress NO production by IFNgamma and lipopolysaccharide (LPS)-activated macrophages. The inhibitory effects correlated with elevated CAMP levels and were mimicked by other agents which elevate CAMP levels such as dibutyryl cAMP, 8-bromo cAMP, and Forskolin. This suppression was found to be at the transcriptional level. In vivo, ROL treatment prevented macrophage activation by staphylococcal enterotoxin B (SEB) and suppressed NO production by these macrophages in ex vivo culture. In the third part of the study, we examined the effects of PDE inhibitors on NO production by insulin-producing NIT-1 insulinoma cells and normal islet cells. It has been reported that islet beta-cells express PDE3 and PDE4. We found that inhibitors of PDE4 (ROL), PDE3 (Cilostamide; CIL), or a general inhibitor (PTX), suppressed NO production by islet cells. A combination of ROL and CIL appeared to have more than an additive effect, suggesting synergism. Like in macrophages, the suppression was at the transcriptional level and mimicked by other agents which elevate cAMP levels. In vivo, ROL treatment suppress iNOS expression in the islets of NOD mice with cyclophosphamide-accelerated disease, as determined by immunohistochemistry. These studies establish for the first time that PDE inhibitors have a therapeutic potential in IDDM and other NO-and/or cytokine-mediated inflammatory disorders.</description><creator>Beshay, Evette A.</creator><contributor>Prud'homme, Gerald J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Pathology.</subject><title>Prevention of type 1 diabetes with phosphodiesterase inhibitors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x346d587b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9g54xk243</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h989r478q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Nitrogen and sulfur deposition and water table level fluctuations have the potential to influence the C biogeochemistry in peatlands. Processes in peatland mesocosms were examined under steady state and dynamic conditions at different rates of N and S deposition, and water table levels. Net turnover rates were calculated from diffusive-advective mass-balances of pore water constituents. The limitations of the approach were tested with tracer experiments, which showed that diffusive-advective transport adequately described the flow of dissolved substances in peat columns. Incubation experiments quantified potential CO2, CH4, DOC, H2S and Fe 2+ production rates. The vegetation assimilated most of the deposited nitrogen and sulfate when water table levels were high. Lowered water table levels resulted in seepage of sulfate to the water table, reduced the rates of photosynthesis, and increased the soil respiration rates. The potential for sulfate reduction was fairly large, despite small in situ sulfate concentrations, and the CO2 production could not be fully accounted for by known processes. Potential rates of sulfate reduction were large both in samples taken from the field site and from the controlled experiments. SO42- addition resulted partly in stimulation, partly in reduction of potential CH4 production rates suggesting that the relationship between sulfate reduction and methanogenesis is not exclusively competitive. Changes of the water table level had in situ effects on CO2 and CH4 production rates not explainable by a distinction in aerobic/anaerobic conditions. Anaerobic in situ rates at greater depths were much lower when the water table was at the surface of the mesocosms than when it was at greater depths. This might have been due to in situ accumulation of CO2 and CH 4 in the deeper peat, which lowers the energy gain of anaerobic C mineralization. Flooding and draining of peat soil resulted in a delayed onset of CH 4 production, in increased anaerobic CO2 production and decreased CH4 production rates, and in the decoupling of gas exchange from production rates. These results document that fluctuations of environmental variables on short time scales have an impact on rates of C turnover in peat soils, and also limit the predictability of fluxes by statistical models.</description><creator>Blodau, Christian.</creator><contributor>Moore, Tim R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Peatlands -- Ontario -- Ottawa Region.</subject><subject>Carbon cycle (Biogeochemistry) -- Ontario -- Kenora Region.</subject><subject>Peatlands -- Ontario -- Kenora Region.</subject><subject>Carbon cycle (Biogeochemistry) -- Ontario -- Ottawa Region.</subject><title>Carbon biogeochemistry in northern peatlands : regulation by environmental and biogeochemical factors</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/br86b492s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h989r478q</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geography</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7h149r290</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A road sign recognition system poses a real challenge for machine vision. It must recognize a wide variety of road signs under considerable variations in illumination and imaging geometry---all in real-time. This thesis presents a modular road sign recognition system relying on modelling for both detection and recognition. It divides into three main stages of processing. The first, concerned with detection, exploits the specific colors of road signs. The color constancy problem caused by the daylight illumination variations is addressed directly with a physics-based model supplemented by a calibration stage using real data. The second stage of processing, devoted to recognizing road signs in regions of interest found in the detection phase, involves a database containing more than 400 road signs arranged in a tree structure, and uses a novel correlation-based template matching technique relying on a bitwise encoding that accounts for both color labels and affine variations in the image formation process, and which also allows to build templates that are able to represent classes of objects. The content of the database used by the recognition algorithm is generated in a deterministic and automated manner by way of geometrical modelling of the image formation process starting with only model images of the road signs to be recognized. The recognition algorithm exploits color as a first logical classification step to direct the search for a road sign in the database, with the later finer steps being driven by correlation scores obtained from template matching. At the third stage of processing, a scene understanding module exploits constraints on the position of road signs along with the spatial relationships they must have in certain cases to other road signs in the image to filter out false positives. During processing, the system incorporates top-down mechanisms that use data fed back by partial recognitions, which allow to progressively gain more information about</description><creator>Lauziere, Yves Berude.</creator><contributor>Gingras, Denis (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Ferrie, Frank P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2002</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>A model-based road sign recognition system /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9g54xk25c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7h149r290</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526d96d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Mathematical and stochastic computer models were built to simulate concurrent engineering processes (CE) in order to study how different process mechanisms contribute to new product development (NPD) performance. Micro-models of various phenomena which occur in concurrent engineering processes, such as functional participation, overlapping, decision-making, rework, and learning, were included, and their effects on the overall NPD process were related to process span time and effort. The study focused on determining under what conditions CE processes are more favorable than sequential processes, in terms of expected payoff, span time, and effort, as dependent variables of functional participation and overlapping, and the corresponding trade-offs between more upfront effort versus span time reduction.</description><creator>Bhuiyan, Farina.</creator><contributor>Gerwin, Donald (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Thomson, Vince (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Industrial.</subject><subject>Operations Research.</subject><title>Dynamic models of concurrent engineering processes and performance</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913r52h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526d96d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mechanical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mc87ps036</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We study the phenomena of fracture in polymers at the molecular and continuum level. At a molecular level, we study the failure of polymer/polymer interfaces. Our main focus is on a specific mode of failure known as chain pull-out fracture, which is common to weak adhesive junctions, and polymer blends and mixtures. In the case of the interface between incompatible polymers, reinforcement is achieved by adding a block copolymer to the interface. We introduce a microscopic model based on Brownian dynamics to investigate the effect of the polymerization index N, of the block connector chain, on fracture toughness of such reinforced polymeric junctions. We consider the mushroom regime, where connector chains are grafted with low surface density, for the case of large pulling velocity. We find that for short chains the interface fracture toughness depends linearly on the polymerization index N of the connector chains, while for longer chains the dependence becomes N 3/2. We propose a scaling argument, based on the geometry of the initial configuration, that accounts for both short and long chains and the crossover between them. At the continuum level, we study the pattern selection mechanism of finger-like crack growth phenomena in gradient driven growth problems in general, and the structure of stress-induced morphological instabilities in crazing of polymer glasses in particular. We simulate solidification in a narrow channel through the use of a phase-field model with an adaptive grid. By tuning a dimensionless parameter, the Peclet number, we show a continuous crossover from a free dendrite at high Peclet numbers to anisotropic viscous fingering at low Peclet numbers. At low Peclet numbers we find good agreement between our results, theoretical predictions, and experiment, providing the first quantitative test of solvability theory for anisotropic viscous fingers. For high undercoolings, we find new phenomena, a solid forger which satisfies stability and thermodynamic criterion. We further provide an analytical form for the shape of these fingers, based on local models of solidification, which fits our numerical results from simulation. Later we study the growth of crazes in polymer glasses by deriving the equations of motion of plastic flow at the craze tip, and the steady-state velocity profile of this flow. By developing a phenomenological model, we solve the full time-dependent equations of motion of this highly non-linear phenomena. Our simulation produces the steady-state cellular pattern observed in experiments. We further show that polymer glasses with lower yield stress produce cellular patterns with sharper tips and more cells, indicating instabilities with smaller wavelengths.</description><creator>Sabouri-Ghomi, Mohsen.</creator><contributor>Grant, Martin (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><subject>Physics, Condensed Matter.</subject><title>Study of fracture and stress-induced morphological instabilities in polymeric materials</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ft848s203.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mc87ps036</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9w032465h</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Horseradish peroxidase (HRP) enzyme catalyzes the oxidation of aqueous phenols by hydrogen peroxide resulting in the formation and precipitation of polymeric products. The technical feasibility of this enzymatic process for the treatment of industrial wastewaters that contain phenols was investigated. Bench-scale experiments were conducted in which the influences of selected components in the waste matrix on treatment efficiency were assessed. Experiments with synthetic phenol solutions revealed that the toxicity of HRP-treated phenol solutions declines with time and is dependent on the presence of protective additives, the mode of reagent addition, and the presence of wastewater constituents. Also, many phenolic solutions can be completely detoxified by providing an additional dose of hydrogen peroxide after the completion of the enzymatic reaction. Chitosan was found to be an effective additive for reducing the amount of enzyme required to accomplish phenol transformation in synthetic and actual wastewaters. HRP was able to accomplish the treatment of phenols in the presence of a wide range of concentrations of suspended solids, salts, metals, and other inorganic and organic species that are frequently present in industrial wastewaters. In certain instances, treatment was more effective in a real waste matrix as compared to the treatment of pure solutions of phenol due to the presence of particular waste components. However, sulfide, manganese(II) and low quantities of cyanide negatively impacted upon the enzymatic transformation of phenol. It was demonstrated that actual industrial wastewaters collected from pulp and paper production and petroleum refining operations could be treated with HRP and H2O2 to meet regulatory discharge limits for phenol. The enzymatic process can selectively target phenols, which are a major source of toxicity in the wastes, for treatment. Treatment of real wastewaters may require higher than stoichiometric doses of hydrogen peroxide due to the inherent peroxide demand of reduced wastewater constituents or catalytic decomposition of peroxide. HRP-treatment improved wastewater quality as reflected in a significant toxicity reduction. It can also result in a substantial decrease in the biochemical and chemical oxygen demands.</description><creator>Wagner, Monika.</creator><contributor>Nicell, J. A. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><subject>Engineering, Environmental.</subject><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>Horseradish peroxidase-catalyzed removal of phenols from industrial wastewaters</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/5425kc32t.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9w032465h</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:k0698912g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We describe our investigations into photochemical and micro-structural characteristics of sol-gel derived silica-methacrylate composites (SAC). Upon irradiation with UV light, thin SAC films undergo spatially localised increases of the index of refraction, a macroscopic property that has been used in the photo-lithography of passive integrated optics devices. Our spectroscopic studies indicate that UV initiated free-radical polymerisation of methacrylate substituents trigger further growth and densification of the silica host. This advances our molecular level understanding of photo-reactions in hybrid organo-silica networks. We examine laser-initiated organic chain growth in SAC planar waveguides. Optical modes initiate polymerisation of methacrylate substituents along the propagation path. In turn, the nascent reaction medium presents a non-uniform refractive index profile to the guided laser beam. Spatially localised and intensity-dependent refractive index changes create a lens-like profile in the medium. As a result, the beam self-focuses along its propagation axis without diffraction. We describe oriented organic chain growth in the nonlinear optical and highly anisotropic reaction field provided by a linearly polarised, self-focusing laser beam. A self-focusing laser beam induces an anisotropy in the refractive index profile of SAC waveguides. We characterise laser-induced birefringence in the hybrid network through polarised waveguide Raman spectroscopy and optical birefringence measurements. Long-range periodic self-organisation in sol-gel derived silica acrylate composites formed in the absence of external templates was observed for the first time. Significantly, the periodicity associated with this structure is approximately 200 nm, approaching the optical wavelength regime.</description><creator>Saravanamuttu, Kalaichelvi.</creator><contributor>Andrews, M. P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2000</date><subject>Chemistry, Polymer.</subject><title>Photo-induced structural transformation in sol-gel derived silica-methacrylate composites</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mk596.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/k0698912g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hh148</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In this work, the design, simulation and optimization of a Mach-Zehnder 3-wavelengthoptical demultiplexer (MZ-3WDM) have been performed using a combination of theeffective index method (EIM) and the 2D finite difference vectorial beam propagationmethod (FD-VBPM). Furthermore, the theoretical design and performance predictions ofthe demultiplexer are verified experimentally through device fabrication andmeasurements. The combination of the effective index method based on the Rung-Kutta method and afinite difference vector beam propagation method (FD-VBPM) provide for acomputational design tool that yields useful results. The average extinction ratios of thedemultiplexer, which were achieved theoretically for the 980nm, 1310nm and 1550nmwavelengths are 34db, 32db and 26db respectively. [...]</description><description>Dans ce travail, la conception, la simulation et l'optimisation d'un démultiplexeuroptique de 3-longueurs d'onde de Mach-Zehnder (MZ-3WDM) ont été exécutées enutilisant une combinaison de la méthode pertinente d'incrément (EIM) et de la méthodevectoriel de propagation de faisceau de la 2D différence finie (FD-VBPM). En outre, laconception et les prévisions théoriques d'exécution du démultiplexeur sont vérifiéesexpérimentalement par la fabrication et les mesures de dispositif.La combinaison de la méthode pertinente d'incrément basée sur la méthode de RungKuttaet une méthode finie de propagation de faisceau de vecteur de différence (FDVBPM)prévoient un outil de conception de calcul qui donne des résultats utiles. Les tauxmoyens d'extinction du démultiplexeur, qui ont été réalisés théoriquement pour deslongueurs d'onde de 980nm, 1310nm et de 1550nm sont respectivement de 34db, 32db et26db.[...]</description><creator>Twati, Mohamed Otman</creator><contributor>Ooi, Boon Tek  (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Pavlasek, Tomas J. F.  (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Engineering.</subject><title>Design and fabrication of a 3-wavelength optical demultiplexer in glass</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676x37p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hh148</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97ks068</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Objective. To identify predictors of catch-up growth during the first year of life among small for gestational age (SGA) infants in a developing country setting. Design. Cohort study, with follow-up visits at 1, 3, 6 and 12 months. Setting. Pelotas, a southern Brazilian city. Population. SGA infants who were born in 1993 and whose families lived in the urban area of Pelotas. Main outcomes. Weight and length gain from birth to 6 months and from 6 to 12 months. Results. Two hundred twenty term SGA infants were targeted for follow-up, which was achieved for 205 (93.2%) infants at 12 months. At 6 months, the proportion of infants with weight-for-age and length-for-age z-scores &lt;-1.28 SDS was 18.9% and 37.8%, respectively. At 12 months, the proportion of children with a weight-for-age z-score &lt;-1.28 SDS increased to 35.2%, whereas for length-for-age this proportion remained about the same as it had been at 6 months. Severity of intrauterine growth retardation, body proportionality at birth, maternal remunerated work after delivery, maternal age, parity, maternal prepregnancy body mass index and maternal smoking during pregnancy had no significant effect on postnatal growth in the first year of life. Those infants who were weaned by 1 month had faster weight and length gain by 6 months. Socioeconomic status (SES) modified the effect of breast feeding duration on weight and length gain in the first 6 months of life. Among high-SES families, those children who were weaned by 1 month gained 578 g more than those still breast feeding at 6 months. Among low-SES families, however, those children who were weaned by 1 month gained 349 g less than those still breast feeding at 6 months. Those children who were weaned by 6 months had faster weight gain from 6 to 12 months, and this association was not modified by SES, while low SES was associated with slower weight and length gain in the same period. Children of short (&lt;150 cm) mothers gained 1.31 cm less (95% confidence interval -2.52 to -0.1) by 6 months than those of mothers &gt;160 cm. Children who were hospitalized showed a nonsignificantly slower length gain throughout the first year of life. Conclusion. SGA infants experienced catch-up growth for weight and length but remained shorter and lighter than those in the NCHS reference population at both 6 and 12 months of age. Socioeconomic status and infant feeding were the main determinants of catch-up growth.</description><creator>Horta, Bernardo Lessa.</creator><contributor>Kramer, Michael (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Health Sciences, Public Health.</subject><subject>Health Sciences, Human Development.</subject><title>Determinants of catch-up growth in small-for-gestational age infants</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6682x564z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97ks068</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Epidemiology and Biostatistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:00000176j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Small endotherms typically have elevated and relatively invariant rates of metabolism, but adaptations such as food hoarding and hibernation endow some species with considerable energetic flexibility in responding to resource fluctuations. I examined the interactions between resource availability, food hoarding, and hibernation in a population of eastern chipmunks (Tamias striatus) subjected to seasonal and multi-annual periods of resource shortage. Incompatibility of torpor and digestion could be an important constraint associated with relying on stored food rather than body fat during hibernation, but documentation of torpor patterns and digestive efficiency of captive chipmunks revealed that digestion is actually enhanced by torpor expression. Measures of energy expenditure and food delivery by free-ranging chipmunks in autumn revealed that food hoarding also permitted rapid accumulation of large energy reserves before thermoregulatory constraints necessitated termination of above-ground activity. Thus, a combination of food hoarding and hibernation permits rapid energy accumulation when resources are abundant and effective energy conservation when resources are scarce. Despite this, chipmunks responded to experimental increases of autumn hoard size by substantially reducing winter torpor expression, suggesting that much of the resource accumulation permitted by larder hoarding is allocated to maintaining elevated rates of metabolism in the winter hibernaculum. This pattern of allocation suggests torpor expression is associated with important costs and contradicts a major paradigm of hibernation research by demonstrating that low levels of torpor expression can reflect an absence of energetic necessity rather than a lack of physiological capability. In an ecological context, the capacity of chipmunks to vary expenditure according to resource abundance represents a potent decoupling mechanism in consumer-resource interactions. Energetic flexibility of this form</description><creator>Humphries, Murray M.</creator><contributor>Kramer, D. L. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Eastern chipmunk -- Ecology.</subject><subject>Eastern chipmunk -- Food.</subject><subject>Eastern chipmunk -- Hibernation.</subject><title>Food hoarding and hibernation in chipmunks and the ecological consequences of energetic flexibility</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9s161785r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/00000176j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rn301292p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the lifeworlds of Somali returnees in Ethiopia. Their experience of flight and return is distinctive, shaped by the history and culture of the Somali people and the political and economic conditions of this part of Africa. In emphasizing this distinctiveness, this thesis is an implicit critique of recent efforts by academics and aid agencies to homogenize the experience of refugees in this region and elsewhere. In Ethiopia, "development" and humanitarian aid, in interaction with political contests at many levels, provide the context for interpreting refugee experience and action. Globally, the most powerful of the reductionist accounts is based on the "trauma model" of refugee experience. In this model, "refugee experience" has come to be virtually synonymous with "psychosocial" and, in turn, "mental health" and "post-traumatic stress disorder" (PTSD). Somali refugees and returnees in Ethiopia, however, do not address violence, death, and war-related distress in a framework of psychological medicine, with its goal of reducing psychological, emotional and physiological symptoms of individual distress. Rather, such distress is predominantly assimilated into the framework of politics, with its goals of survival and restitution. Emotion, and talking about emotion, evoke complex individual and collective memories that situate individual and local community experience within, or in juxtaposition to, other realities: competing powers such as the Ethiopian and other states, dispossession, and the precariousness of survival in a harsh natural and political environment. Historical narratives, collective memory, anger, and the rhetorics of development and humanitarian aid play important roles in these communities' efforts to rebuild social networks and what they refer to as a "decent human life."</description><creator>Zarowsky, Christina.</creator><contributor>Young, Allan (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Somalis -- Ethiopia.</subject><subject>Refugees -- Ethiopia.</subject><title>Refugee lives and the politics of suffering in Somali Ethiopia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dj52w646n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rn301292p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10wr934</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-23T04:41:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The thesis aims at contributing to clarify broad conjectures on growth, such as, (i) the extent to which growth constitutes an imperative for the firm, and (ii) what leads some firms to enjoy continuing growth and a continued existence, while others, after experiencing continuing growth, end up contracting and decaying. As a result, the thesis seeks to develop a deeper understanding of the mechanisms fostering and precluding growth, while also identifying challenges and opportunities in managing growth. The thesis comprises four interrelated essays: (i) Chandler on the growth of the firm---this essay scrutinizes The Visible Hand (Chandler, 1977) seeking to answer the question "What is Chandler's theory on how and why did the modern business enterprise (MBE) appear and grow?" Four processes are identified---MBE formation, MBE development, industry formation, industry development. Their analysis within a process-oriented view (Mohr, 1982) discloses chains of necessary conditions in growth-related processes. Moreover, two growth-related dilemmas are advanced and the firm-industry co-evolution is explored. (ii) Identifying the building blocks of growth dynamics---this essay addresses the question "Which are the basic processes of change that form the dynamics of growth?" Drawing on Mario Bunge's philosophy (1973--1989; 1979), a framework of qualitatively different modes of change is derived. The framework allows the identification of elementary units of the growth dynamics. These comprise the following types: quantitative, qualitative (dialectical), goal-directed, interactional, causal, structural, random. In addition, complex units of growth dynamics made up of combinations of elementary units are also advanced: evolutionary motor of firm growth, co-evolutionary motor of growth relating firm and industry, and different instances of continuing growth motors. (iii) Describing growth trajectories of firms---the question "How can growth trajectories be represented?" is addressed in this essay. An indicator of size, which automatically adjusts for inflationary and deflationary changes in currency value is proposed. This indicator enables the drawing of growth trajectories of firms in the economy over long periods of time. (iv) Growth trajectories of General Electric and Westinghouse: a comparative study---this essay addresses the question "Why do some firms experience continuing growth and continued existence while others decay and disappear?" The growth
trajectories of these two companies are drawn and examined over twelve
decades. The longitudinal analysis reveals two sets of growth-related traits in
firms: business-oriented and organization-oriented. 8usiness-oriented traits
relate to ways of managing relevant issues in business. These are: enterprising
approach, growth motives approach and change approach. Organizationoriented traits refer to ways of managing the organization, its resources and
practices. They are: organizing approach, resource allocation approach,
problem-solving approach, managerial hierarchy development approach. The
essay advances the notion that as a firm grows, it faces conflicting forces that
push the firm towards either of two extreme poles: self-perpetuation or selfdestruction. Evidence is provided that General Electric developed selfperpetuating traits throughout its existence, white Westinghouse more often than
not developed self-destructing traits.</description><creator>Fleck, Denise L.</creator><contributor>Jorgensen, Jan (Supervisor)</contributor><contributor>Mintzberg, Henry (Supervisor)</contributor><date>2001</date><subject>Corporations -- Growth.</subject><subject>Business failures.</subject><subject>General Electric Company.</subject><subject>Westinghouse Electric Corporation.</subject><subject>Industrial management -- Management.</subject><title>The dynamics of corporate growth /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hh63sx560.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wr934</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Faculty of Management</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):33750</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>