<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-24T23:27:56Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):9825" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d5700685</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:16Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In recent years the Science of Nutrition has made tremendous strides. It has at last been recognized that our diet affects significantly our physical as well as our psychological well being. Although a great deal of work has been done on diets from the physiological standpoint, very few investigations have been concerned specifically with a psychological approach. The present experiment is designed to study an aspect of the Science of Nutrition from the psyohological approach. While this undertaking was not concerned specifically with either the sciences of Psychology or Nutrition, it was an attempt to experiment in that region where the two disciplines overlap. It was an attempt to associate the two sciences. For it is on the overlapping areas of scientific disciplines that there remains much ignorance, and where research is needed. The object of this experiment is to investigate the effect of a diet deficient in vitamin B on learning ability in rats. Further details will be given in the following chapters. The writer of this thesis does not make claim to much originality. It was rather his attempt to verify the conclusions and to refine and improve the techniques of other workers. The work was begun on December 26,1939. It was concluded about August 24, l940. The writer designed and constructed 25 rat cages, 3 Carr Mazes and 3 galvanized tin tanks.</description><creator>Woo, Wesley Stewart.</creator><contributor>Kellogg, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>PSYCHOLOGY -- MENTAL TESTS</subject><subject>Psychophysiology.</subject><subject>Vitamin B1.</subject><title>Thiamin (vitamin B1) and its effect upon learning ability.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/d504rp385.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d5700685</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:b5644v79w</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:17Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A considerable amount of work has been done on toxicity by various workers but no definite, satisfactory method of expressing a definition has yet been devised. That an insecticide should be efficient in killing the insects against which it is used goes without saying, but it is difficult to frame a satisfactory definition of toxicity, which, in the case of a contact poison, is concerned with the inherent killing value of the poison as it comes in contact with the exterior of the insect's body. The chief object of these experiments is to develop a simple method of comparing contact insecticides, so that a number of insects can be treated in a reasonable amount of time, and to provide results that can be reproduced by further tests, within the range of experimental error. The method consists of measuring the concentration of nicotine in the form of a sulphate that will give 50 per cent kill, and to use that as a standard. Then the ratio of this amount to the amount of another substance giving the same mortality may be regarded as an insecticidal index for that substance. [...] The action of a contact insecticide [...] may be brought about by an interference with insect respiration caused by mechanical plugging of the spiracles, or by an actual process of tissue alteration or destruction caused by the poison [...] The toxic action of nicotine is that of a fumigant, dependant upon the passage of the vapor into the tracheal system of the insect. [...]</description><creator>Cannon, Frederick Merriet.</creator><contributor>Brittain, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Entomology.</subject><title>The standardization of a method for utilizing Drosophila Melanogaster as a test animal for toxicity experiments with nicotine. --.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440w79r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/b5644v79w</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Entomology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3197xp74n</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:18Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Although Salmonella pullorum has for many years been the subject of much investigation resulting in the accumulation or considerable knowledge of its various characteristics, there still exists some confusion regarding its exact recognition. This, and the fact that the genus Salmonella has undergone radical change through the newer methods of antigenic analysis stimulated particularly by White and Kauffmann, seemed to warrant a reinvestigation of the fermentation and agglutination reactions of Salmonella pullorum. As the historical resume will indicate, much of the work done on this organism has aimed at amplifying into species rank minute differences between this organism and the closely similar gallinarum. A discussion on the validity of this species differentiation is included in this thesis as a natural corollary of the main purpose which is to define the criteria by which Salmonella pullorum may be recognized. [...] The existence of cholera-like or typhoid-like epidemics in domestic birds has been known for many years. However, careful bacteriological study has been carried on only since the latter part of the nineteenth century. [...] From this time on, definition of these two micro-organisms was attempted on one or other of three grounds,- fermentative, serological and pathological. [...]</description><creator>Byrne, Joseph Lawrence.</creator><contributor>Smith, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Bacteriology. </subject><title>The differentiation of salmonella pullorum by fermentation and agglutination reactions.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rj430768s.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3197xp74n</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bacteriology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n009w538b</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:19Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The alkali metals, because of their extraordinary properties and comparative ease of theoretical treatment have figured largely in the theories of the solid state and the optical properties of metals. [...] One very significant result of this work is that transmission curves calculated from the values of the refractive index and extinction coefficient show a gradual onset of transparency and "do not allow one to talk of the point where transparency commences". [...] One would thus expect a falling off in the photoelectric emission to be connected with the region of transparency. This is observed in the alkalis. But the alkaline earth metals [...] also show a falling off of the photoelectric effect in the ultra-violet (at about 2200 A for barium). Hence one would expect a region of transparency for barium films around that wave-length. It was to check this prediction of theory that the following investigation was carried out. [...] It may be pointed out that expectations based on the conception of free electrons in a metal are less likely to be applicable for divalent metals than for monovalent. But it is difficult to understand the successful correlation of optical and photoelectric properties of the alkali metals, if the alkaline earth metals show no correlation whatsoever. [...]</description><creator>Bychowsky, Victor.</creator><contributor>Watson, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Physics. </subject><title>Optical absorption by thin barium films in the Schumann region. --.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/j67317010.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n009w538b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0p096b08x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:20Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>"In spite of all that is written, said, and done, this great, big, incontrovertible fact stands out-the Negro is progressing, and that disproves all the arguments in the world that he is incapable of progress." L'amélioration de l'état et de la position sociale des Noirs est un des faits les plus saisissants de notre vie d'aujourd'hui. Depuis le commencement du vingtième siècle, période plus libérale et plus tolérante que nulle autre auparavant envers le Noir, il commence à pénétrer dans tous les domaines de la pensée, de la vie intellectuelle, sociale et politique. Il reste beaucoup à faire, naturellement, car les meilleurs changements sociaux s'effectuent lentement et graduellement et le Noir, en sus d'avoir à s'adapter à la haute culture de la civilisation moderne, rencontre dans ses efforts d'avancement un immense obstacle de préjudice qui, dans quelques endroits, lui oppose des barrières presque infranchissables. [...] Le roman, genre qui est aujourd'hui un des plus importants de la littérature, nous offre un excellent moyen d'étudier le Noir. [...] Nos études et nos recherches faites, donc, sur le Noir dans toute cette période-là, nous ont poussé à la soutenance de la thèse que les romanciers français ont fait de la race un portrait juste, fidèle et d'une grande réalité. [...]</description><creator>Boger, Dellie Lee.</creator><contributor>Du Roure, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Blacks in literature.</subject><subject>French fiction -- 20th century -- History and criticism.</subject><title>Le noir dans le roman français.</title><language>fre</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gk48w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0p096b08x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1n79h750j</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The results of partitioning the feed consumption of growing bacon-type swine into fractions used for body maintenance and for body weight increase are reported. The regression equation found to fit the data was: y = 0.524 + 0.102(W)^0.73 + 1.163(ΔW) in which y= calculated feed intake, (W)= body weight, and (ΔW)= change in body weight. The data indicate that approximately two-thirds of the feed eaten by full-fed growing pigs is used for body maintenance and one-third for body weight increase. Standard partial regressions show that of the variability in feed consumption accounted for by body size and by rate of gain, 40 per cent is associated with the former factor and 60 per cent with rate of gain.</description><creator>Ashton, Gordon Clemence.</creator><contributor>Crampton, E. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1939</date><subject>Animal Nutrition and Breeding. </subject><title>The utilization of feed for body weight maintenance and for body weight increase by growing bacon-type swine. --.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/028710071.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1n79h750j</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Animal Nutrition and Breeding</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:nk322h65p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:21Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Classical organic chemistry was inclined to consider dimerisation - the initial step of polymerisation - as involving two fundamentally different processes. The first treated of those unions wherein the component atoms were bound in the same manner as in the monomolecular substance. By this process rings of four, six, or eight carbon atoms were postulated as being-formed, through a valence redistribution. This was termed the true polymerisation process. The second class concerned those combinations whose formation involved a shift of atoms. Such were called condensing, or linear polymerisations. [...]</description><creator>Reid, Evans B.</creator><contributor>Stevens, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Dimeric ketenes and cyclobutanediones.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644v80n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/nk322h65p</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mw22v864d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:22Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The state of aggregation of the molecules in a liquid is a problem which has not yet been solved. In a gas it universally considered that there is a random distribution of the molecules, the kinetic energy of the molecules being sufficient to over come any forces of attraction between the atoms or molecules of the gas. In the solid state on the contrary, there is a definite structure. Each atomoccupies a definite position in a crystal lattice, these small units of structure being arranged in a definite manner to make up a larger crystal, which may or may not be large enough for the eye to see. [...]</description><creator>Naldrett, Stanley N.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>An investigation of the state of aggregation of a one component system in the critical temperature - critical pressure region.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ws859j634.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mw22v864d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gh93h265p</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:23Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In the past fifty years or so, molybdenum has come into considerable prominence. Up to the beginning of the last World War, its main uses were in connection with the manufacture of magnet steels and of chemical salts such as ammonium molybdate and molybdic acid. However with the World War molybdenum became important owing to its use in a number of special steels. During this period a vast amount of experimental work was undertaken and a more extensive search was made for molybdenum deposits. While the industrial application of molybdenum has been extensive in the last decade or so, the demand for it will doubtless be further increased by the present war. With this thought in mind a study of the available methods of analyses for molybdenum was undertaken.</description><creator>Morehouse, Clarence K.</creator><contributor>Mennie, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>A study of some methods of separation and determination of molybdenum.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/vm40xv98q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h265p</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:mg74qq22v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:24Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Dans la littérature canadienne-française c'est la période de 1860-1900 qui est la plus intéressante et la plus importante au point de vue littéraire et historique. L'histoire fut la source d'inspiration de ces grands poètes canadiens français comme Crémazie, Fréchette, Chapman et LeMay qui appartiennent a la meilleure époque de la littérature de ce jeune peuple. Il n'est pas étonnant que l'histoire, surtout l'histoire du Canada, ait été l'inspiratrice de ces poètes, parce qu'on ne saurait nier l'influence de l'histoire chez les peuples depuis le commencement de la civilisation et surtout dans la littérature nationale d'un pays. [...]</description><creator>McNamara, Mary F.</creator><contributor>Du Roure, R. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>French Language and Literature.</subject><subject>Literature and history.</subject><subject>French-Canadian poetry -- 19th century -- History and criticism.</subject><title>L’histoire dans la poésie canadienne-franc̀aise de 1860-1900.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cz30pw836.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/mg74qq22v</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French Language and Literature</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7s75dg68v</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Reactions of synthesis are of prime importance in organic chemistry. The reaction itself may be of practical interest by reason of its uniqueness, smoothness, and the high yield of product which may result from it. From a theoretical point of view, however, the mechanism of the reaction may be of greater importance. The discovery of a new synthetic method, whether by design or by accident, is followed by a period of expansion wherein the reaction is applied to a great many cases in order to determine the limits of the reaction. [...]</description><creator>McCoubrey, James A.</creator><contributor>Stevens, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The Grignard reagent and ethylene oxides.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xk81jp726.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7s75dg68v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3484zk712</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Out of Canada's present total population of about eleven millions, some four and a quarter million are the brain and manual workers of all kinds who from year to year contribute to the national income a varied stream of goods and services. This is the Canadian working population. It includes the unemployed, for they are potentially part of the national factors of production whether we manage to use them or not. And it includes employers and employees of all kinds. Customary reckoning does not include in the working population the two or two-and-a-quarter million women who as housewives or helpers in the home - "homemakers", as they are aptly described in Census schedules - are quite clearly workers in the wider sense of the word, and in fact contribute a large fund of services to the national income. [...]</description><creator>Marsh, Leonard C.</creator><contributor>Hemmeon, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Occupations -- Canada.</subject><subject>Labor supply -- Canada.</subject><subject>Economics.</subject><subject>Unemployed -- Canada.</subject><title>The Canadian working population: an analysis of occupational status divisions and the incidence of unemployment.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/sf268830g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3484zk712</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s1784p63s</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The study of soil and applied potash reported in this thesis was undertaken as part of the general research program of the Macdonald College Pasture Improvement Committee. The Committee was set up in 1930 for the purpose of studying means for the maintenance and the improvement of the pastures of Quebec. The members (see appendix I), composed of representatives from the departments of Agronomy, Animal Nutrition, Botany and Chemistry, have followed the policy of studying the fundamental and scientific aspects of the pasture problem of Quebec as well as attacking it from a practical viewpoint. [...]</description><creator>Marcello, Louis S.</creator><contributor>Wrenshall, C. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>The availability and fixation of potassium in pasture soils.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8k71nm22b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s1784p63s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kw868</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A great deal of research work has been done in an attempt to find a method by which the lignin fraction of plant material may be determined accurately. Fairly satisfactory methods have been worked out for woods and straws, but very little attention has been paid to the lignin content of vegetables. It has been the purpose of this work to study a few of the methods available for the determination of lignin and to apply what has appeared to be the most suitable method to the determination of the lignin content of vegetables. [...]</description><creator>Manning, Kenneth R.</creator><contributor>DeLong, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>Studies in lignin: the lignin content of some common vegetables with observations on methods for the determination of lignin.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kk91fp81d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kw868</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:zc77st04f</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In recent years the most rapidly developing branch of applied chemical science has been that of plastics and artificial fibres. The advances made in th1s field during the past decade, by the development of new substances with desirable properties, and by the industrial application of these substances to a wide variety of purposes, have provided a truly astonishing chapter in the history of our technological progress. But th1s iS not to say that a great many of the fundamental problems do not still remain. As usual, industrial development has outstripped the progress of the purely scientific understand1ng of many of the phenomena involved. [...]</description><creator>Lovell, Edwin L.</creator><contributor>Hibbert, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Some properties of long chain molecules and their solutions.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/zp38wg64p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/zc77st04f</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1v53k1102</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The cyanide process as actually applied to the extraction of gold and silver from their ores is generally considered to have originated with British Patent nos. 14,174, Oct. 19, 1887, and 10,223, July 14, 1888, issued to J. S. MacAuthur, R. W. Forrest and W. Forrest. The first patent emphasized the efficiency of cyanide as a solvent for gold and silver, and the superiority of dilute solutions. The dissolved gold was to be recovered from the solution by any convenient way, "such as evaporating the solution to dryness and fusing the resulting saline residue, or by treating the solution with a sodium amalgam" (30). [...]</description><creator>Leblanc, Raymond F.</creator><contributor>MacEwan, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Mining and Metallurgical Engineering.</subject><title>The influence of certain factors and impurities on the precipitation of gold from cyanide solution by zinc dust.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8623j201r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1v53k1102</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7w62fc29d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Boron is an element definitely known to be essential for the normal growth of higher plants but its true role in the physiology of the plant is still a matter for conjecture. Doubtless its metabolic functions will ultimately be revealed by physiological and biochemical studies but it was thought that a thorough investigation of the influence of boron on the anatomy of the plant would constitute a desirable ground work for such researches. An indication of the role played by boron in the life of the plant, might suggest other related studies likely to yield constructive results. Accordingly the studies described below were undertaken in order to obtain a full comprehension of the anatomical features which result from an inadequate supply of boron.</description><creator>Lachance, René-O.</creator><contributor>Coulson, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Plant Pathology.</subject><title>Pathological anatomy of boron-deficient plants.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/73666776q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7w62fc29d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Plant Pathology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ww72bf77q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The Reciprocal-Trade-Agreements Program of the United States, is conceivably the cardinal experiment in an endeavor to revive international trade by a policy of removing and reducing excessive commerce barriers. The cooperation between the United States and Canada in this pursuit, affords an excellent opportunity to analyze the results of this stratagem. Divided into 7 chapters, this study devotes the first 2 sections to a brief history of Canadian-American trade policy; and an appraisal of the foremost methods of conducting commerce, with particular emphasis on "most-favored-nation" proposals. Chapters 3, 4, and 5, present a detailed exposition of the actual tariff revisions entailed in the 1938 agreement, as compared with previous rate schedules. The concluding portion is a statistical summary of trade value fluctuations of certain selected commodities, followed by an evaluation of the role of tariff manipulation in evolving these changes.</description><creator>Kirchschlager, Hellmuth L.</creator><contributor>Hemmeon, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>United States -- Commerce -- Canada.</subject><subject>Canada -- Commerce -- United States.</subject><subject>Economics.</subject><title>The New Trade Agreement between the United States and Canada, signed - November 17, 1938.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pn89d9620.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ww72bf77q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:h415pd66m</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Much work on organic peracids had been done in these laboratories: as a continuation of this work, Hatcher and MacLauchlan measured the conductivity of nitric acid and hydrogen peroxide mixtures. Their results showed a variation similar to that found with organic acids and hydrogen peroxide. Since organic acids and hydrogen peroxide were known to form peracids, it was suspected that the same occurrence would take place with nitric acid and hydrogen peroxide. [...]</description><creator>Hughes, Robert E.</creator><contributor>Hatcher, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>Physical properties and chemical reactions of hydrogen peroxide, nitric acid mixtures.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/028710089.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/h415pd66m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gx41mm93q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Since the summer of 1935, field parties of the Geological Survey of Canada, under the direction of Dr. A. W. Jolliffe, have been engaged in mapping the geology of the area immediately north of Great Slave lake, adjacent to Yellowknife bay and the Yellowknife river. The writer was a student-assistant on these field parties during the summers of 1937, 1938, and 1939. One of the most interesting rock units encountered during this mapping is a basic intrusive sheet which outcrops a short distance east of Yellowknife bay. This gabbroic body is the subject of this thesis. [...]</description><creator>Hill, Lawrence S.</creator><contributor>Osborne, F. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>A petrographic study of a basic intrusive sheet in the Yellowknife area, Northwest Territories.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7s75dg694.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gx41mm93q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Geology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:xd07gw78d</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The critical temperature has been defined as that temperature beyond which a gas cannot be liquified regardless of the pressure, and, according to the old classical theory, the change from liquid to gas at the critical temperature could be made to follow a smooth transition in all physical properties such as density, viscosity, surface tension. This conclusion arises from the idea that a gas possesses no structure but a purely chaotic and random distribution and that, in the liquid, the molecules are merely under greater attractive forces due to their closer proximity. Accordingly the transition from the liquid to the gaseous state at the critical temperature should be smooth and the density of the system should be everywhere the same in the system after the critical temperature has been passed. [...]</description><creator>Harvey, Ross B.</creator><contributor>Maass, O. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The heat capacity of ethylene and carbon dioxide in the critical temperature region.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ht24wn39j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/xd07gw78d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:s7526g30q</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Aujourd'hui on fabrique les livres et lea autos en grande quantité. Pour aider au grand public à bien choisir parmi tant d'oeuvres superbes, on en fait des réclames de toute espèce. L'auto qui réunit vitesse et sécurité, économie et puissance, accé1ération et freinage, souplesse et rendement, élégance et confort, solidité et silence derrière un beau visage, se vend bien de même que le "Vient de Paraître", "Le Livre du Mois", "Prix Goncourt", "Prix Femina", "Un grand succès partout", ou même "Avant Propos par un membre de l'Académie" assure au livre quelque succès. [...]</description><creator>Guyton, Pauline.</creator><contributor>Larivière, H. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>French Fiction -- History and Criticism.</subject><subject>French.</subject><title>La revolte sociale dans le roman d’après-guerre.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kw87j.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/s7526g30q</identifier><degree><name>Master of Arts</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of French</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tt44pq873</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The object of science is to systematize the changes which matter has been observed to undergo, to explain their cause, and to predict their occurrence. The investigations of the chemical reactions of the compounds of carbon have shown, in many cases, that rearrangements of the molecular structures concerned might occur either by the simple readjustment of the atoms already present, or as a result of an addition to, or a remova1 from the original molecule of certain atoms or groups of atoms. Since the molecular structure of an organic compound is its fundamental characteristic, the study of these rearrangement processes has become of prime importance. [...]</description><creator>Greenwood, Sydney H.</creator><contributor>Stevens, P. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Chemistry.</subject><title>The mechanism of intra molecular rearrangements.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xp68kk306.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tt44pq873</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:n296x223x</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:36Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The commercial use of aqueous solutions of potassium cyanide in the extraction of gold from its ores began only in the last decades of the nineteenth century. However, long before this time chemists knew that gold was soluble in aqueous cyanide solutions. In 1805 Hagen stated that "gold was dissolved by a solution of prussiate of potash"(l). The Elkingtons obtained a patent in 1840 for gold plating electrolitically, using as an electrolyte a solution of gold dissolved in potassium cyanide (2). The first scientific literature on the subject was published in 1843 by Prince Bagration (1) who stated "it is certain that in the future, cyanides of potassium must be reckoned as a solvent of gold". [...]</description><creator>Grassby, James N.</creator><contributor>Bell, J. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Mining and Metallurgy.</subject><title>The cyanidation of gold ores, with varying oxygen concentrations.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gx41mm940.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/n296x223x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgy</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:bc386n62g</identifier><datestamp>2020-03-21T17:20:38Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Blossom-End Rot of tomatoes begins as a slightly discolored watery spot at the stylar end of the fruit. This lesion may increase in size until it involves the distal half of the fruit. Concomitant with the increase in size is a change in color through dark brown to black. Such fruit is unsuitable for consumption. Some years ago the Division of Horticulture, Central Experimental Farm, Ottawa, began the culture of tomatoes in a crushed sandstone medium in order to obtain an optimum nutrient solution for tomato growth. [...]</description><creator>Grant, Edwin P.</creator><contributor>De Long, W. (Supervisor)</contributor><date>1940</date><subject>Agricultural Chemistry.</subject><title>A study of the carbohydrate and nitrogen metabolism in relation to blossom-end rot in tomatoes grown under different cultural conditions.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225f19x.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/bc386n62g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Engineering</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):9850</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>