<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:52:00Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):42100" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cc08hk86x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:04Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>It is a common practice to retrieve code from an outside source, execute it and return the result to the user. During execution secure data can enter the program by user input or access of a data resource. It is important to track the secure data once it enters the program to identify possible information flows to unwanted regions of the code which would permit undesirable data output to a user. Most approaches to restrict information flow in programs have fallen short of providing a practical solution for mainstream programming languages. To address this issue, this thesis presents two context-sensitive inter-procedural analyses which analyze an intermediate representation of Java Bytecode for secure information flow. The first analysis assumes that there is only one instance of all class fields where as the second analysis uses points-to information to differentiate between instance fields which belong to different instances of the same class. The analyses track secure information in the program by maintaining sets of secure data. The analyses resolve dynamic method resolution in Java statically by analyzing all possible methods which may be invoked at a call site and merging the secure data sets. We were able to define rules to analyze all the statements in the intermediate representation and also accounted for Java libraries. The analyses do not expect any security annotations in the program. Type information is useful in debugging, guiding optimizations, and specifying and providing safety proofs for programs. A type system for a subset of the Java Bytecode intermediate representation is also formulated in this thesis. An operational semantics is specified and a type preservation proof assures the soundness of the type system. Non-trivial benchmarks were analyzed and explicit and implicit information flows were counted for both analyses. The empirical data collected suggests secure data is used in many statements of programs and output of data to a user at several places in a program can lead to information flow if the user does not have the right permission to observe the data.</description><creator>Ahmedani, Ahmer.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Computer Science.</subject><title>Information flow in a Java intermediate language</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Ahmer Ahmedani, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s664d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cc08hk86x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8336h590d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Soy flour was inoculated with Lactobacillus delbrueckii ssp. lattis R0187, and incubated for 8 h, to evaluate the protein hydrolysis and identify peptides generated by this fermentation, and the impact on ACE and trypsin inhibitory activities. Aqueous protein extracts prepared from different fermentation time periods showed a decrease in soluble protein content (from 2.83 to 0.02 mg/mL), while soluble inorganic nitrogen and free amino acid contents increased (from 0.029 to 0.062% w/w, and from 0.75 to 0.90% w/w, respectively). The protein extracts were analyzed by SDS-PAGE; proteolysis was observed after 5 h incubation of inoculated soy flour, suggesting that glycinin, beta-conglycinin, and trypsin inhibitors, were hydrolyzed. Peptides were isolated by tricine-SDS-PAGE, and analyzed by MS/MS; fragments of soy anti-nutritional factors (Kunitz and Bowman-Birk trypsir, inhibitors), as well as of other soybean proteins, were identified, confirming that these proteins were hydrolyzed. The protein extracts at time 0 h and 8 h were analyzed by RP-HPLC; one fraction was analyzed by MS/MS, which identified peptides from Lactobacillus species. Determination of trypsin inhibitory activity showed less inhibition of the enzyme with inoculated soy flour compared to the control (un-inoculated soy flour), confirming the deactivation of trypsin inhibitors by fermentation. Determination of ACE inhibitory activity showed a higher inhibition with the control (86% +/- 3.0) compared to inoculated soy flour (66% +/- 7.6).</description><creator>Ahmarani, Jamile.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Soy flour.</subject><subject>Lactobacillus delbrueckii.</subject><subject>Trypsin inhibitors.</subject><subject>Fermented soyfoods.</subject><title>Effects of Lactobacillus delbrueckii ssp. lactis R0187 on soy flour fermentation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Jamile Ahmarani, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644w903.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8336h590d</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3t945w20z</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:05Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>As XML gains popularity as the standard data representation model, there is a need to store, retrieve and update XML data efficiently. McXml is a native XML database system that has been developed at McGill University and represents XML data as trees. McXML supports both read-only queries and six different kinds of update operations. To support concurrent access to documents in the McXML database, we propose a concurrency control protocol called LockX which applies locking to the nodes in the XML tree. LockX maximizes concurrency by considering the semantics of McXML's read and write operations in its design. We evaluate the performance of LockX as we vary factors such as the structure of the XML document and the proportion of read operations in transactions. We also evaluate LockX's performance on the XMark benchmark [16] after extending it with suitable update operations [13]. Finally, we compare LockX's performance with two snapshot-based concurrency control protocols (SnaX, OptiX) that provide a committed snapshot of the data for client operations.</description><creator>Ahmed, Namiruddin.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Database management.</subject><subject>XML (Document markup language)</subject><subject>Parallel processing (Electronic computers)</subject><title>Lock-based concurrency control for XML</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Namiruddin Ahmed, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/tq57nv936.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3t945w20z</identifier><degree><name>Master of Science</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Computer Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8c97kv54b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Decisions made in Youth Protection cases are influenced by many different factors that have been outlined in previous research. Assessment tools, definitions of risk and the overarching cultural milieu intermingle to inform the decision-making process and, ultimately the final decision. This research seeks to explore the factors that affect the decision-making process and is intended to build on previous research. By qualitatively analyzing the transcripts from actual decision-making meetings, and talking to the participants about their experiences within the research it was shown that the decision-making process is a complicated one. The roles of the participants within the organization along with the pervasive culture of blame within society seem to primarily affect the dynamics of the people responsible for making the decisions. The effect that these factors have on the actual decision was not studied but would be beneficial to examine. Workers within the organization, especially caseworkers, struggled with wanting more autonomy while simultaneously reported not wanting the responsibility that coincides with it. It is felt that more responsibility would ultimately mean more possibility of blame.</description><creator>D'Amico, Rebecca Anne.</creator><date>2007</date><subject>Social work with children.</subject><subject>Decision making.</subject><subject>Child abuse.</subject><title>Factors that affect the decision-making process in youth protection cases</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Rebecca Anne D'Amico, 2007</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9w032717g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8c97kv54b</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pc289p22g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Purpose. To explore the experiences of healthcare managers at a reformed CSSS (Centres de sante et de services sociaux) in Montreal, Quebec and to document the provincial reforms. The objective is to understand the managers' experiences during a period of transition. Method. This study consists of two methods: a document review of relevant policies and reforms of Quebec's health and social services. Secondly, qualitative interview methods were used to explore the experiences of seven managers within a CSSS and their attitudes towards the reform. Results. Managers described the following: a new window of opportunity, importance of leadership in the reform process, distorted communication, environment of trust, and culture of the organisation. Conclusion. Quebec's health and social services is an ongoing discourse. Distorted communication creates an atmosphere of uncertainty which hinders the reform process. Implications include the need for further research in understanding healthcare professionals and other actors in the reform process.</description><creator>Ali, Shaun Kevin.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Health care reform -- Québec (Province)</subject><subject>Human services -- Québec (Province)</subject><title>Quebec's health and social services in transition : managing change</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Shaun Kevin Ali, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/hm50tw739.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pc289p22g</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:c821gq16x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:06Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This study explored whether the Child and Adolescent Functional Assessment Scale (CAFAS) scores of children in the care of Family and Children's Services of Renfrew County might predict foster placement outcomes. A file review was completed for 268 children, all of whom had at least one set of CAFAS scores completed, to obtain data regarding the number and types of placements they experienced. Placement categories were ranked -- in order from best alternate care option to least-desired -- by 11 agency employees. These rankings were used to calculate total weighted placements for each child as a measure of the child's foster placement experience. In regression analyses, including age, gender, and reasons for placement, CAFAS scores were found to be the most significant predictor of the number and nature of placements experienced by a child. This relationship suggests that there might be value in using CAFAS as a placement matching tool in a child welfare setting.</description><creator>Grenier, Jennifer.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Foster home care -- Ontario.</subject><title>Child and adolescent functional assessment scale : predicting foster care placement outcomes</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Jennifer Grenier, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/b5644w91c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/c821gq16x</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cr56n541s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The purpose of this study was to examine the successes and challenges in implementing community art programs for youth in low-income communities. The National Arts and Youth Demonstration Project (NAYDP) was initiated in September 2001 in five program sites across Canada. This article reports on the qualitative findings of NAYDP staff implementation journals that were utilized in the first term of the project. Findings suggest that community partnerships in program recruitment, youth management and engagement and survey administration were all key aspects in the ability of staff to deliver the program. Positive Youth Development (PYD) provides a guiding framework and implications for social work practice, education and future research are explored.</description><creator>Bellas, Noel.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Student activities -- Canada.</subject><subject>Community arts projects -- Canada.</subject><subject>Students -- Services for -- Canada.</subject><title>Successes and challenges in implementing community art programs for youth in low-income communities : implications for social work practice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Noel Bellas, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/bn999b94q.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n541s</identifier><degree><name>Master of Social Work</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>School of Social Work</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gt54ks30m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Recently Al was replaced by Cu as an interconnecting material. The primary objective of the present research was to investigate the mechanism of texture and microstructure evolution and to study its influence on electromigration in damascene Cu interconnects. For this purpose electromigration experiments were performed on the Cu interconnects in vacuum in the SEM. The in-situ electron back-scatter diffraction (EBSD) investigation of Cu interconnect lines before and after the electromigration failure helped to identify the orientations which were associated with electromigration defect nucleation. A mechanism was proposed which shows the correlation between the texture and electromigration damage formation. The second part of the study involved investigation of texture and microstructure in damascene Cu interconnects. The experiments were designed so as to allow an analysis of both pre and post-CMP (chemical mechanical polishing) annealing on texture and microstructure evolution not only as a function of line width but also line spacing. In order to investigate the mechanism of texture evolution in the damascene Cu interconnects in-situ EBSD study of Cu films was carried out during their thermal treatment in SEM. A similar separate experiment carried out on freestanding Cu film helped to ascertain the role of substrate in inducing the texture transformation at high temperature. Some models were proposed which establish the combined effect of dislocation activity and substrate on texture evolution. Both EBSD and X-ray diffraction (XRD) methods were used to measure the texture. Finally the residual stresses in the damascene lines were measured using XRD to evaluate their impact on the mechanical reliability of the chip interconnect system. The EBSD and XRD studies helped to identify the mechanisms which govern the texture and microstructure evolution in Cu interconnect lines during annealing performed before and after CMP. The role of surface/interface and strain energy on formation of energy minimizing textures was established. The mechanism of texture evolution was explained explicitly as function of principal and shear stress, dislocation density, trench aspect ratio and top passivation layer. Thus, from the electromigration studies it was possible to screen out the undesirable grain orientations. The XRD and EBSD investigations revealed the mechanism of texture and microstructure evolution in damascene lines and were used to explain the impact of various factors like stresses, dislocations, line width, line spacing, trench aspect ratio, passivation layer, substrate on texture evolution. The knowledge gained from these two studies opens a new door giving an opportunity to design the texture and microstructure in the damascene interconnect lines so as to eliminate undesirable grain orientations which are vulnerable to electromigration and mechanical failure. Since the mechanism of texture evolution is now known, one could vary the process parameters like say current density, barrier and passivation layer material and thickness, Cu seed and electroplated layer thickness, additive content in electroplating bath, annealing conditions etc. to obtain an optimum texture and microstructure which provides best reliability against electromigration and mechanical failures.</description><creator>Mirpuri, Kabir.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Engineering, Materials Science.</subject><title>Stress, texture and electromigration in damascene copper interconnects</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Kabir Mirpuri, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/dz010v19c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gt54ks30m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining, Metals and Materials Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:3x816r749</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:07Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Genetic control of susceptibility to tuberculosis in resistant C57BL/6 (B6) and susceptible DBA/2 (D2) mice is multigenic. Susceptibility in D2 is associated with a unique phenotype which includes unrestricted pulmonary replication, severe lung pathology, extensive tissue necrosis and early death. Quantitative trait linkage mapping in 2 genome wide scans was used to determine the number and location of genes controlling differential susceptibility to pulmonary tuberculosis in D2 and B6. In a first scan, 95 informative (B6XD2) F2 mice were infected i.v with 105 virulent M. tuberculosis H37Rv, and survival time was used as a phenotypic measure of susceptibility. These studies identified 3 significant linkages on chromosomes 1,3 and 7 designated Trl-1/2/3 respectively. In a second genome scan, 104 (B6XD2) F2 mice were infected with 10 2 M. tuberculosis H37Rv by the aerosol route, and the extent of bacterial replication in the lungs (CFU) at 90 days was used as a phenotypic measure of susceptibility. Results from this analysis identified a major linkage on chromosome 19 (Trl-4) accounting for 25% of the phenotypic variance. In this scan Trl-3 was confirmed as not only playing a role in overall survival to infection but also bacterial growth in the lungs. Our results suggest a strong genetic interaction between Trl-3 and Trl-4 in regulating pulmonary replication of M. tuberculosis. To further characterize the mechanistic basis of action of the Trl-1/2/3/4 effect on M. tuberculosis infection, global expression analysis of approximately 15 250 genes was utilized to identify genes differentially expressed between the lungs of B6 and D2 mice prior to and during infection with M. tuberculosis . Our data suggests that the classical complement pathway and the apoptotic pathway plays a role in the differential susceptibility between B6 and D2 mice, with these pathways being upregulated in B6. Moreover the increase in neutrophil associated gene expression corroborates with our histological finding of increased neutrophil cell counts in D2 mice. Finally these studies have provided candidate genes that map in the Trl-1 and Trl-4 regions (Cfh and Scd2 respectively).</description><creator>Mitsos, Louika-Maria.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Genetics.</subject><title>Identification and characterization of the genetic component of differential susceptibility to mouse tuberculosis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Louika-Maria Mitsos, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8c97kv55m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/3x816r749</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biochemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:jm214t454</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Skin-derived precursors are multipotent stem cells capable of differentiation into neural and mesodermal progeny. Described here is evidence that SKPs are of a neural crest origin; SKPs neural progeny are peripheral in subtype including peripheral catecholaminergic neurons and Schwann cells, SKPs express embryonic neural crest transcription factors, SKPs migrate via neural crest migratory pathways when transplanted into chick embryos and SKPs respond to factors know to influence neural crest stem cell differentiation in a similar manner. The expression of the neural crest transcription factors in situ identified the dermal papillae of hair follicles as a potential niche for SKPs in the skin. Cells isolated from microdissected vibrissae papillae generated spheres with SKPs properties when cultured under SKPs conditions and like SKPs, could be differentiated into neurons and smooth muscle. In agreement with the hypothesis that SKPs are of a neural crest origin, transgenic mice expressing beta-galactosidase in all neural crest progeny are characterized by beta-galactosidase expression in the dermal papillae, a potential SKPs niche and SKPs cultured from the whisker pads of these mice were also beta-galactosidase-positive. In order to demonstrate the functionality of SKP progeny as a proof of principle of their utility for potential therapeutic cell transplantation therapies, SKPs and SKP-derived Schwann cells were transplanted into various injury and disease models to assess their ability to myelinate. Cell culture protocols based on glial differentiation from the neural crest stem cell literature were adapted to selectively promote and expand Schwann cell differentiation from SKPs. SKP-derived Schwann cells transplanted into injured nerve were able to myelinate regenerating axons. SKPs and SKP-derived Schwann cells transplanted into congenitally dysmyelinated neonatal brains were able to form normal compact myelin. These data demonstrate the SKPs are a neural crest precursor that persists in adult skin that represents an accessible, autologous source of precursors capable of generating functional myelinating cells that could be used to treat disease and injury of the nervous system.</description><creator>McKenzie, Ian, 1977-</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>The neural crest origins of skin-derived precursors : an accessible source of myelinating Schwann cells</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Ian McKenzie, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/s1784q68c.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/jm214t454</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d4112</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:08Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Heat transfer in canned particulate system in Newtonian and non-Newtonian liquids was studied during end-over-end agitation thermal processing in a pilot scale rotary retort. Computational methods for conventional overall heat transfer coefficient (U) and fluid to particle heat transfer coefficient (hfp) were found unsuitable in high viscosity fluids. A methodology for evaluating an apparent heat transfer coefficient (hap) between retort medium and particle, and an apparent overall heat transfer coefficient Ua between retort medium and can fluid was proposed. Use of h ap and Ua concepts permitted direct predictions of particle temperature and lethality based on retort temperature. An L-16 orthogonal experimental design of experiments was carried out to select system factors that significantly affected hap and U a values for particles in high viscosity non-Newtonian and Newtonian fluids. Experiments using central composite rotatable design and full factorial design were carried out to study the effects of selected significant factors on hap and Ua. Using all data obtained, dimensionless correlations were developed for the prediction of hap and Ua values. The developed correlations showed a good agreement with the experimental data. More precise predictions were achieved with trained artificial neural network (ANN) models. The results of ANN models could be compiled using algebraic equations and were included so that hap and Ua values could be predicted without actually using the ANN software. A flow visualization study was conducted to better understand the heat transfer behavior in high viscosity fluids. Results showed that in particulate high viscosity fluids, the particle liquid relative movement was very weak, implying that the heat transfer between them could converge to conduction-conduction rather than convection-conduction, which results in erroneous and unusually large hfp values.</description><creator>Meng, Yang, 1968-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Canning and preserving -- Quality control.</subject><subject>Canned foods -- Sterilization.</subject><title>Heat transfer studies on canned particulate viscous fluids during end-over-end rotation : by Yang Meng.</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Yang Meng, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/7h149t861.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d4112</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:9k41zj803</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effectiveness of a cheap, low-tech, environmentally and technically favorable treatment of secondary treated municipal wastewater by contaminant removal through a floodplain-soil filter was evaluated using floodplain-simulating field lysimeters, packed with a sandy soil in 2002 and sand in 2003 and 2004. Secondary treated wastewaters from Vaudreuil (2002 and 2003) and Pincourt (2004) Wastewater Treatment Plants were used as influent. This was applied at rates of 0.06, 0.19, and 0.31 m3 m-2 d -1 to vegetated lysimeters, and at a rate of 0.19 m3 m-2 d-1 to bare-soil lysimeters. Removal of NH4+-N, NO3--N, and COD from the influent was studied in all three years. Irrespective of flow rate or year, the system removed 62~84%, 96~99%, and 6~67% of TKN, NH4+-N, and COD, respectively, from the influent. Under 0.19 m3 m-2 d-1 flow rate, vegetated systems removed slightly more of these constituents from the influent, than did bare-soil lysimeters. Organic degradation mainly occurred in the top 0.1 m soil depth. Degradation of organic and inorganic influent nitrogen increased NO3--N levels in the effluent. Only minimal increases in soil-N levels and N2O emissions occurred with increasing application rates. The nitrogen mass balance accounted for 85~98% (2003) and 67~96% (2004) of input nitrogen (through leaching, soil retention, and N2O emissions), the remaining portion being attributable to vegetative effects and volatilization of non-N2O nitrogenous gases. The under established vegetation on the lysimeters reduced nitrogen leaching through soil, being 6% (2003) and 60% (2004) more effective than bare soil. Effluent water quality improved with decreasing levels of heavy metals. Compared to influent levels, in vegetated lysimeters, under all flow rates, mean effluent As, Cd, Cu, Ni, Pb, and Zn levels had dropped by 58%, 9%, 3%, 37%, 63%, and 52% in 2003, and by 20%, 63%, 5%, 23%, 18%, 57%, and 79% for As, Cd, Cr, Cu, Ni, Pb, and Zn, in 2004. In both years, similar decreases in heavy metal levels occurred in the bare soil lysimeters. Across all flow rates and influent concentrations, soil heavy metal levels increased. In 2004, even low heavy metal content influent further increased (6~179%) their accumulation in soil. As inputs of heavy metals to the soil increased with the increase in application rates, their associated times to reach maximum permissible limits also decreased. LEACHN simulation of NO3--N in leachate arising from wastewater application, showed lowered levels with increasing flow rates, due to enhanced denitrification in the resulting anoxic upper soil zones. The simulation under continuous wastewater application at different range of nitrogen concentrations (low, medium, high) showed an increase of NO 3--N levels in the leachate with increasing N-levels. For all flow rates, and under tropical or humid conditions, the effluent NO 3--N levels remained below permissible limits for the low-N content wastewater applications. Intermittent applications, under all wastewater N-contents and flow rates, reduced NO3--N levels in the leachate by 51~89% compared to continuous wastewater application, and permissible limits were not exceeded. Hence, wastewater with high levels of nitrogenous compounds, as occurs in most developing countries, could be treated by land under an intermittent application pattern, allowing a considerable reduction in nitrate pollution.</description><creator>Kunjikutty, Sobhalatha Panangattu.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Sewage -- Purification -- Biological treatment.</subject><subject>Land treatment of wastewater.</subject><title>Floodplain filtration for treating municipal wastewaters</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Sobhalatha Panangattu Kunjikutty, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/m039k9484.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/9k41zj803</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Bioresource Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rf55zc96s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An advance in information and communication technology (ICT) is one of the most important forces in reshaping the world economy. So far, research on the role of ICT development in the financial globalization process is very limited. This dissertation is composed of three essays, which aim to fill part of this gap. The first essay explores transmission mechanism between Internet development and foreign direct investment (FDI) in developing economies. The second further investigates why developing economies cannot fully benefit from Internet development and provides policy recommendations. The third studies the relationship among financial integration, ICT and macroeconomic volatility in ten Asian economies. The first essay examines three potential channels: inventory costs, market entry costs and payment of bribes, through which the Internet attracts FDI. It develops a model to explain the role of the Internet in determining inward FDI, and then empirically tests the hypotheses. The empirical findings show that the Internet development in developing economies attracts multinationals, since it reduces their costs of holding inventories and market entry costs. The Internet is found to reduce corruption, but evidence for their combined effects on FDI is mixed. In addition, this study performs Granger causality test and finds a causal relationship from the Internet to inward FDI stocks, rather than vice versa. The second essay examines how the Internet---a communication network---which is characterized by the presence of positive and negative externalities affects the locational choice of FDI. A two-stage model is developed: at the first stage, multinational corporations do not cooperate and determine the degree of investment in Internet technologies, whereas, at the second stage, these firms engage in a Cournot quantity competition for a homogenous product. This model predicts that positive Internet externalities stimulate FDI while negative Internet externalities discourage FDI. These hypotheses are tested by the panel data estimation and the system general method of moments (GMM) estimator. The empirical findings provide strong evidence that the presence of negative Internet spillovers in developing countries discourages inward FDI, and the presence of positive Internet externalities in developed economies attracts more FDI. The third essay looks at ten Asian economies committed to ICT development and financial integration, and presents evidence on whether or not they have experienced greater output fluctuations from 1980 to 2003. A two-country dynamic general equilibrium model is used and ICT is assumed to increase the volume and speed of capital flows. This study's model predicts that economies with a high ICT development or/and a high degree of financial integration exhibit greater output fluctuations in the face of monetary policy shocks, but lower output fluctuations in the face of fiscal policy shocks. The empirical findings estimated by using the panel vector autoregression approach support these predictions.</description><creator>Ko, Kwan Wai.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Communication -- Technological innovations.</subject><subject>Information technology.</subject><subject>Globalization.</subject><subject>Investments, Foreign.</subject><title>Three essays on information and communication technology and financial globalization</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Kwan Wai Ko, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kp78gm661.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rf55zc96s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Economics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wh246x22b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:09Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>In order to ensure aircraft safety during winter conditions, glycol-based deicing and anti-icing fluids are employed prior to takeoff. These products can exert a severe impact on the environment if allowed to go untreated. The present study is related to the treatment of glycol-contaminated wastewaters by the activated sludge process. The specific objectives of the research were to: (1) determine the effects of process parameters such as biomass concentration, deicing fluid concentration and temperature on the biodegradation kinetics. (2) determine the mechanism of deicing fluid removal and model the reaction rates. (3) determine the effects of microbial changes on the treatment process. (4) evaluate the advantages of a sequencing batch reactor for the treatment of deicing wastes. (5) corroborate our laboratory results with field data from an operating wastewater facility treating deicing wastes. The results from the field show that despite the increases in influent organic matter during the deicing season, there were very little changes in effluent values of organic matter. Furthermore, influent concentrations of deicing fluid between 10 and 30 mg/L were reduced to trace amounts (i.e. below 5 mg/L) throughout the deicing season. However, as witnessed by the high sludge volume index during the deicing season, the presence of deicing fluid creates settling problems in the clarifier. The laboratory batch experiments indicate optimal substrate removal rates at biomass concentrations of 1000 mg/L and 2000 mg/L. Very low biomass levels lead to inhibition whereas a high biomass level of 3000 mg/L is unnecessary since the food to microorganism ratio is such that only a fraction of the biomass participates in the degradation reaction. With regards to deicing fluid concentration, organic matter removal rates tend to increase as the deicing fluid is increased. However, at the highest level of deicing fluid, certain inhibitory effects are present. As expected, higher temperatures produce much higher removal rates with the ethylene glycol substrate showing less variation with temperature than the other organic compounds present in the wastewater. With regards to the mechanism of removal, the results showed very little adsorption of organic matter onto the biomass within the first hour of contact. In addition, the total organic matter removal (TOC and COD) followed first order kinetics with respect to substrate concentration. Lastly, sequencing batch reactor operation allowed for much higher removal rates as the microbial population is acclimatized to the substrate with increasing cycles. With regards to the microbial population, the Biolog results showed that there was a decrease in the variety of compounds that could be degraded as the biomass was exposed to the deicing fluid. Furthermore, most population changes occurred at the very beginning of the deicing season and in the first half of the SBR experiments.</description><creator>Kramadhati, Narahari Narasiah.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Environmental Sciences.</subject><subject>Engineering, Chemical.</subject><subject>Engineering, Environmental.</subject><title>The impact of aircraft deicing wastes on the biological wastewater treatment process /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Narahari Narasiah Kramadhati, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/db78th404.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wh246x22b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:m326m6163</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This dissertation examines the rising medicalization of depression in Japan and asks how it has become possible that Japanese, who reportedly barely suffered from depression until recently, are now increasingly becoming "depressed." Drawing upon two years of fieldwork in psychiatric institutions in the Tokyo environs, I examine this change from three different angles---historical, clinical, and socio-legal. First, my historical analysis questions the assumption held by Japanese psychiatrists that depression did not exist in premodern Japan; I show that traditional Japanese medicine did indeed have a notion of depression (called utsusho), conceived as an illness of emotions in which psychological suffering was seen as intimately connected to both physiological and social distress. Though the premodern notion of depression was effectively obscured by the 19th-century adoption of German neuropsychiatry that located depression in individual brains, the current medicalization of depression is nevertheless deeply informed by an indigenous psychiatric theory emphasizing that depression is in part socially produced. Second, I examine how Japanese psychiatrists use this local language of depression in clinical practice in attempting to persuade patients that they are victims of both biological and social forces lying beyond their control. The lack of any psychiatric model of agency concerning depression, however, leads some patients---especially suicidal patients---to question psychiatry's jurisdiction over the meaning of their distress. Third, I analyze how the psychiatric language of depression has been adopted in legal discourse surrounding "overwork suicide," where corporations and the government have been found liable for workers' deaths on the grounds that excessive work stress can drive workers to depression and suicide. Furthermore, the psychiatric language is curiously limited in the sense that, in contrast to the West, in Japan it is men rather than women who have been represented as typical victims of depression. By examining patients' narratives, I demonstrate how psychiatry constructs a gendered discourse of depression, closely tied to local politics about whose distress is recognized as legitimate social suffering. The medicalization of depression in Japan thus suggests not a hegemonic, global standardization, but the emergence of psychiatry as a politically potent---though limited---force for social transformation.</description><creator>Kitanaka, Junko, 1970-</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Depressed persons -- Japan.</subject><subject>Depression, Mental -- Japan -- History.</subject><subject>Job stress -- Japan.</subject><title>Society in distress : the psychiatric production of depression in contemporary Japan</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Junko Kitanaka, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/cc08hk89r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/m326m6163</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Anthropology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:z890rz817</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:10Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Through an in-depth case study of the bicycle industry, this dissertation examines the claims of the developmental state thesis insofar as they pertain to the facilitating of industrial transformation in Taiwan and Korea. The bicycle industry has been chosen because it has the capacity to generate forward and backward linkages to the domestic societies, a capacity that development theorists consider to be an indicator of successful industrial development. I examine the developmental state thesis by investigating how firms compete internationally in the context of state-led export development as well as the conditions that permit upgrading, that is, those that make possible the transition to higher value-added economic activities. This dissertation makes two principal claims: First, what is understood as the East Asian model in the current state-centric literature is really only the Korean model. I contend, however, that there are, in fact, two competing paths/models of East Asian development. Moreover, I argue that existing social structures deserve attention. I argue that the differences in social structures create different relational dynamics between the state and society despite the often-emphasized "state-autonomy" factor, and that they have given rise to the different industrial structures in the two countries studied. Second, the existing state-centric literature implicitly or explicitly infers that the Korean model, in which state and large corporations work closely together, is the key for future growth for late comers. Contrary to this view, I illustrate how upgrading is possible among small- and medium-sized enterprises in Taiwan under a relatively egalitarian system and a particular type of state-society relationship. The state, in this context, provides infrastructural support, which, I argue, is important for preserving horizontal cooperation among firms. This cooperation among firms encourages information and technology diffusion that flows through the economy and leads to the improvement of the social and economic well being of the whole society. On the other hand, the Korean case suggests that the power imbalance and over-dominance of an industrial structure by a few firms leads to a more predatory, vertical and dependent relationship between the large assemblers and smaller parts firms. The Korean policy of picking winners encourages the expansion of large business groups and a mass production system, which, in turn, prevent inter-firm cooperation. The system of the state-large corporation nexus has been effective in catching up in targeted sectors, but I contend that the upgrading does not cascade to other sectors. Moreover, the system has thwarted the development of entrepreneurship in the sector of small- and medium-sized enterprises.</description><creator>Hsieh, Michelle Fei-yu.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Bicycle industry -- Taiwan.</subject><subject>Southeast Asia -- Economic conditions.</subject><subject>Bicycle industry -- Korea (South).</subject><title>The East Asian miracle revisited : the Taiwan-South Korea comparison based on a case study of the bicycle industry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Michelle Fei-yu Hsieh, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kd17cz561.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/z890rz817</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4b29bb11k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Both the differentiation of cortical neurons during development and the regeneration of neurons following peripheral nerve injury are characterized by an increasing expression of axonal proteins such as Talpha1 alpha-tubulin. The mechanisms that regulate the expression of Talpha1 alpha-tubulin and other neuronal genes during differentiation and regeneration are poorly understood. The proximal promoter region of the Talpha1 alpha-tubulin gene contains putative binding sites for the C/EBP family of transcription factors, which is implicated in the regulation of genes in many differentiating cell types or in cells responding to stress. This thesis consists in defining the role of C/EBP family members in the induction of the Talpha1 alpha-tubulin gene in the early differentiation and in the regeneration of neurons. Specifically, the results presented here suggest that C/EBP family members bind to and transactivate the Talpha1 alpha-tubulin minimal promoter and that the Talpha1 alpha-tubulin promoter region that is responsive to C/EBP family members also contains neuronal differentiation and regeneration response elements. Cortical progenitor cell fate involves collaborations between cell-intrinsic factors and extracellular cue-activated signalling pathways. Similarly, the activity of C/EBP family members is regulated by cell-intrinsic factors and by the extrinsically activated Erk 1/2-C/EBP signalling pathway in several differentiating non-neuronal cells. Here we present evidence of an analogous function for C/EBP family members in neurogenesis. The results presented in this thesis show that (1) inhibition of MEK (upstream of Erk 1/2) or inhibition of C/EBP family members blocks cortical progenitor neurogenesis; (2) inhibition of C/EBP family members promotes CNTF-induced astrogenesis; and (3) forced expression of a C/EBPbeta mutant (that is, a mimic of its Erk 1/2-RSK phosphorylated form) enhances the expression of neuron-specific genes such as Talpha1 alpha-tubulin. Neuronal regeneration involves the re-activation of some development-associated genes such as Talpha1 alpha-tubulin and GAP-43. To further define the role of C/EBP family members in the transcription of the Talpha1 alpha-tubulin gene in neurons during regeneration, we crossed transgenic mice that express the beta-galactosidase gene under the control of the Talpha1 alpha-tubulin minimal promoter (Talpha1MP:nLacZ) with mice that carry a null mutation for either C/EBPbeta or C/EBPdelta. The results of facial nerve crush experiments conducted on these hybrid mice show that C/EBPbeta plays a role in the transcriptional activation of the Talpha1 alpha-tubulin minimal promoter following neuronal injury. Injury-induced mRNA expression for either Talpha1 alpha-tubulin or GAP-43 was not noticeably affected by the absence of C/EBPbeta. This suggests that C/EBPbeta-independent mechanisms also play a role in neuronal regeneration.</description><creator>Hein, Paul.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>A role for C/EBP[beta] in neuronal differentiation and neuronal regeneration /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Paul Hein, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/1z40kz11m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4b29bb11k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Neuroscience</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5q47rt13t</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>T Cell Protein Tyrosine Phosphatase (TC-PTP) and Protein Tyrosine Phosphatase (PTP)-1B are two closely related enzymes involved in the regulation of cytokine signalling. While tcptp-/- mice display a wide range of hematopoietic defects and die within three to five weeks after birth, ptp1b-/- mice are healthy and show no apparent immune phenotype; nevertheless, in vitro results suggest that both enzymes negatively regulate interferon signalling. The goal of my thesis was to determine their role in macrophages whose activation and maturation is largely dependent on interferon-gamma. In the first instance, we detected a progressive mononuclear cellular infiltrate in several organs of the TC-PTP deficient mice, which, together with active cytokine production, was likely to be the cause of tissue damage and ultimately their death. Moreover, the tcptp-/- mice showed increased sensitivity to exogenous lipopolysaccharide in vivo and developed symptoms of septic shock. tcptp-/- spleen-derived macrophages were also highly sensitive to lipopolysaccharide. These findings indicated that TC-PTP was necessary for the regulation of inflammatory disease. In the second part, although ptp1b-/- bone marrow presented no abnormalities at the myeloid progenitor level, it contained more colony stimulating factor (CSF)-1 -responsive cells and the CSF-1 receptor was hyperphosphorylated in ptp1b-/- bone marrow-derived macrophages. ptp1b-/- splenic macrophages also displayed upregulated activation markers as well as increased sensitivity to LPS. Collectively, these results indicated that PTP-1B regulated myeloid differentiation and macrophage activation in vivo. Lastly, we wished to delete one or both copies of PTP-1B in tcptp-/- and tcptp+/-mice by interbreeding to study the redundancy of the two enzymes. Our results indicated that the double mutant was lethal at a relatively early stage of embryonic development. Mice heterozygous for TC-PTP on the ptp1b-/- background developed symptoms similar to the tcptp-/- mice, and their macrophages were highly sensitive to interferon-gamma as shown by increased Stat1 phosphorylation, indicating a nonredundant role for PTP-1B and TC-PTP in the regulation of interferon signalling.</description><creator>Heinonen, Krista.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Health Sciences, Immunology.</subject><title>Two related protein tyrosine phosphatases, TC-PTP and PTP-1B, in the regulation of macrophage development and activation</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><rights>© Krista Heinonen, 2006</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/ng451n86d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5q47rt13t</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Division of Experimental Medicine</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:w9505478m</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:11Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The worldclass Hemlo deposit is one of Canada's largest gold producers, containing 95 million tons of ore grading ~8 g/t Au; the mineralization is hosted mainly by two sub-parallel shear zones. However, unlike most Archean lode gold deposits, the ore occurs as finely disseminated Hg- and Ag-bearing native gold in potassically altered rocks, and is associated with molybdenite, stibnite and realgar. Mineralization occurred at greenschist conditions (400 to 500°C), and was subsequently overprinted by a single metamorphic event that peaked at ~630°C and 5 to 7 kb, which recrystallized the ore and alteration assemblages. Retrograde cooling lasted for ~80 m.y., with temperature decreasing on average ~5°C per m.y. Ore formation involved three reactions that affected ∫S2,∫O2, and pH: the dissolution of sedimentary barite, the precipitation of pyrite, and the replacement of muscovite by K-feldspar. During sulfidation, caused by the dissolution of barite, iron partitioned preferentially into pyrite, which prevented the formation of Fe-bearing metamorphic index minerals (such as garnet and staurolite), oxides (e.g., magnetite, hematite, ilmenite), and low- ∫S2 sulfides (e.g., pyrrhotite). In addition, K-alteration strongly enriched the ore zones in K-feldspar (microcline) and muscovite, which buffered pH, and prevented formation of aluminosilicates. Hemlo is an example of a mesothermal deposit which formed from metamorphic fluids with a significant magmatic component. Deposition of native gold and molybdenite occurred due to decreases in pH and ∫O2 that accompanied potassic alteration and pyrite precipitation. Other elements, such as Sb and As were adsorbed initially onto pyrite growth surfaces. Near peak metamorphism, the deposit evolved a sulfide melt that formed through release of As and Sb from pyrite during metamorphic recrystallization, partial decomposition of primary minerals (such as native gold), and interaction of the melt with sulfur-bearing aqueous metamorphic fluids. The mineral assemblages that crystallized from this melt are similar to those predicted by experimental data for the As-Sb-S and related systems, and are interpreted to have formed by fractional crystallization.</description><creator>Heiligmann, Martin.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Geology.</subject><title>Genesis and metamorphism of the Hemlo gold deposit, Ontario</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Martin Heiligmann, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/t148fn38h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/w9505478m</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Earth and Planetary Sciences</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:pk02cf940</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cytoplasrnic male sterility (CMS) is a maternally inherited defect in the production of pollen, the male gamete of the flower. This sterility can be suppressed by nuclear Restorer of Fertility (Rf) genes that normally downregulate the expression of the CMS-associated novel mitochondrial gene. In Brassica napus, nap CMS and pol CMS are associated with related chimeric mitochondrial genes orf222 and orf224, respectively. CMS in both nap and pol is associated with a polar loss of locule development, loss of synchronous locule development and clumping of sporogenous tissue away from the tapetal cell layer, as well as secondary effects on petal and bud formation. In nap CMS, early accumulation of orf222 transcripts in the locule regions of developing anthers is associated with sterility, while the absence of orf222 transcripts from the locules is associated with fertility restoration. Accumulation of novel antisense transcripts of atp6 in a cell specific manner which matches that of sense transcripts of orf222 and atp6 in nap CMS anthers may be indicative of a post-transcriptional regulatory mechanism associated with CMS in flower buds. Restoration of fertility in Brassica napus nap and pol CMS is associated with nuclearly encoded genes Rfn and Rfp, respectively. These restorers are very closely linked to one another, and may be allelic. Further efforts to isolate Rfp have narrowed the genomic region to approximately 105 kb of a syntenic region in Arabidopsis thaliana. Cosmid clones isolated from a library of Brassica rapa genomic DNA introgressed with Rfp have been successfully sorted into contigs through the application of the amplified fragment length polymorphism technique. The region to which Rfp is mapped is syntenic to a region of Arabidopsis DNA that is a duplication of a second location at the 23 megabase region of chromosome 1 of that genome. This region contains pentatricopeptide (PPR) motif-encoding genes that are highly related to other restorers of fertility of other species. By inference, Rfp from Brassica napus may encode PPR motifs. The PPR genes related to these previously characterized restorers of fertility are often found alongside the restorer genes existing as mini-clusters of several PPR-encoding genes. This is likely caused by selective pressure acting on PPR-encoding genes that resulted in diversification and multiplication of these genes. In addition, the PPR genes of this duplicated region are not syntenically located, whereas the non-PPR-encoding genes maintain their syntenic locations. The same is true for orthologous comparisons between Arabidopsis and other plant species. PPR genes are therefore malleable and capable of alteration in response to changing environmental pressures, such as the evolution of sterility inducing genes.</description><creator>Geddy, Rachel Gwyneth.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Arabidopsis thaliana -- Molecular genetics.</subject><subject>Rape (Plant) -- Genome mapping.</subject><subject>Cytoplasmic male sterility.</subject><title>Location and expression of genes related to the cytoplasmic male sterility system of Brassica napus</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Rachel Gwyneth Geddy, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/nk322j975.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/pk02cf940</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Biology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rx913v061</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:12Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A new linear high electric field radiofrequency quadrupole (RFQ) ion trap, dubbed HVTrap, was developed and tested to study the phase space properties of confined particles and determine the suitability of such a device as an ion source/delivery system for high-resolution time-of-flight (TOF) mass spectrometry and to test the possibility of high field RFQ beam cooling in an ion guide. A segmented quadrupole rod structure was built and shown to easily withstand over 4kV between adjacent electrodes placed 1mm apart in 1x10 -4 Torr of helium buffer gas. An innovative resonating circuit design using hollow air-cored induction coils was used to simultaneously deliver the necessary RF and DC trapping potentials to the linear RFQ system as well as deliver the extraction voltages used to eject test ions (Cs+, m/z = 133) produced by a surface ionization source. The resulting ion bunches were delivered to a TOF system for time profile analysis using a multichannel plate detector. Optimal trapping parameters were found to vary with applied RF potentials and extraction voltages. The presence of helium buffer gas at pressures of 10-4 Torr and long cooling times, in the range of 500ms, were found to improve the number of detected ions. A thermodynamic model of the confined ions was used to simulate the extraction process and follow the phase space evolution of the ejected particles through the TOF region. Analysis of the experimental data showed that confined Cs + ions reached equilibrium temperatures as low as 0.45 eV after 500ms cooling periods in 1x10-4 Torr of helium buffer gas. These equilibrium temperatures were also found to be dependent on the number of detected ions and applied RF potentials. Harmonic frequencies in the resonant circuit are thought to play an important role in determining the thermal energies of the trapped ions. This thesis has shown that high field RFQ confinement of ions in buffer gas is indeed feasible and that trapped particles can be manipulated using DC fields superimposed on the RF. In its present form, the HVTrap would be capable of mass resolutions of roughly 1000. Beam cooling using a high field RFQ would also be possible and could potentially accommodate beam currents of up to 100nA. If the ion temperature could be reduced to 0.05 eV, TOF mass resolutions of 30 000 would be possible.</description><creator>Gianfrancesco, Omar.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Physics, Nuclear.</subject><title>Ion dynamics in a linear high field RFQ trap</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Omar Gianfrancesco, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6h440x95b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rx913v061</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tx31qp09c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The literature has indicated that frequently examined patient variables at intake have shown mixed results in the prediction of dropout from outpatient substance abuse treatment. In this research sociodemographic characteristics, substance use and psychological problem severity at intake were examined as predictors of early dropout in 411 patients enrolled in a 6-month outpatient substance abuse treatment program. Early dropout was defined as participation of less than 6 weeks, the first phase of treatment. Another focus of the research was to determine how patients who dropped out of treatment early fared in terms of substance use at 6 months compared to those retained longer. It was found that being younger, unmarried or not cohabitating, and having a greater severity of employment problems at intake were associated with early treatment dropout. Substance abuse and psychological problem severity at intake were not associated with dropout from the first phase of treatment. Patients who left treatment early had some reduction in alcohol consumption at 6-month follow-up, but overall, those retained in treatment longer had better alcohol and drug use outcomes at 6 months. Both the outcomes on retention and substance use were examined in order to explore possible solutions to dropout from the perspective of health services. Despite the improvements in substance abuse for patients retained longer than 6 weeks, it was determined that only 40% of patients were retained for 6 months, thereby indicating that the majority of patients had not received the planned 6-month intervention. In response to these facts, a brief intervention consisting of 5 individual therapy sessions based on coping skills and motivational enhancement strategies was designed and manualized with participation of the clinical staff. Following this, a randomized clinical trial was conducted with 72 patients, and substance use at 6-month follow-up was compared between the brief intervention and the conventional treatment groups. At 6 months, both the brief intervention and conventional treatment groups had reductions in alcohol use compared to intake, but no conclusions could be made about drug use. The implications of the findings for substance abuse treatment service delivery are discussed.</description><creator>Gauthier-Faille, Gail.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Psychology, Clinical.</subject><title>Outpatient treatment for substance dependence : using empirical findings about retention and substance use outcomes to shape treatment services</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Gail Gauthier-Faille, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/v979v6859.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tx31qp09c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychiatry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:cr56n5422</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The leading model for understanding the energetics of anomalous X-ray pulsars (AXPs) is that they are "magnetars"---young, isolated neutron stars powered by the decay of their enormous magnetic fields. The identification of AXPs as magnetars is motivated by the similarity of AXPs to another enigmatic class of sources, the Soft Gamma Repeaters (SGRs). We report on long-term monitoring of AXPs using the Rossi X-ray Timing Explorer (RXTE). We monitor AXPs with RXTE to study their rotational stability, to search for variations in their pulsed flux and pulsed morphology. During our regular monitoring observations we discovered multiple bursts from two AXPs: this was the first time such behavior has been observed from these sources. Prior to our monitoring campaign, the detection of bursts solely from SGRs was the principle difference between AXPs and SGRs. The first detection of AXP bursts came in Fall 2001 when we discovered two SCR-like X-ray bursts from the direction of AXP 1E 1048.1--5937. Due to RXTE's large (1° x 1°) field-of-view we could not unambiguously identify the AXP as the burster. Recently, we detected a third burst from the direction of this source as well as a simultaneous increase in the pulsar's pulsed emission---this clearly identified the AXP as the burster. The most outstanding demonstration of AXP bursting behavior came on 2002 June 18 when AXP 1E 2259+586 underwent a major outburst involving 80 bursts and several changes in the persistent and pulsed emission, including a huge pulsed flux enhancement, a pulse morphology change and a rotational glitch. We also find variations in the persistent emission of AXPs in the absence of an obvious outburst. For example, we discovered two pulsed flux flares from AXP 1E 1048.1--5937. Both flares lasted several months and had well resolved few-week-long rises. The long rise tunes of the flares is a phenomenon not previously reported for this class of object, but has a clear explanation within the context of the magnetar model. All these results imply a close relationship between AXPs and SGRs, which we now believe are both magnetars, and have posed significant challenges to competing models.</description><creator>Gavriil, Fotis Panagiotis.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Physics, Astronomy and Astrophysics.</subject><title>Magnetar-like x-ray bursts from anomalous x-ray pulsars</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Fotis Panagiotis Gavriil, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gq67jw336.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/cr56n5422</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Physics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558j35d</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:13Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A major factor complicating the cleanup at many sites is co-contamination by both organic compounds and heavy metals. Whereas much research has focused on the removal of either organic compounds or metals, relatively few studies have investigated simultaneous removal of organic and inorganic pollutants from soil. The studies reported in this thesis have evaluated a novel technique for the simultaneous mobilization of polychlorinated biphenyl (PCB) compounds and heavy metals (HMs) from a field contaminated soil. Soil extraction with washing aids {surfactants/cyclodextrin in combination with chelating reagent(s)} was optimized for mobilization efficiency, recovery/recycle of washing additives, and in parallel detoxification of mobilized contaminants. PCB extraction efficiencies were determined with a method that converted all the PCB congeners to dicyclohexyl by hydrogenation over palladium. Studies demonstrated that 10 minutes of ultrasonic mixing of field contaminated soil with a combination of surfactant (30 mL L-1) or cyclodextrin (100 g L-1) and a sparing quantity (2 mmoles) of EDTA, simultaneously mobilized appreciable quantities of PCBs and most analyte metals (Cd, Cu, Mn, Pb, Zn, Ni, Cr). Relative to individual reagents, combinations of surfactant (Brij 98, Triton X-301, or Triton XQS-20) or cyclodextrin (RAMEB or HPCD) with EDTA did not influence PCB extraction efficiencies perceptibly. The presence of surfactant or cyclodextrin in admixture with EDTA did not appreciably change the efficiency of mobilization of most heavy metals (Al, Cd, Cr, Fe, Mn, Ni, and Zn) but did increase the recovery of Cu and Pb with nonionic surfactant and cyclodextrin. When coupled with PCB removal by hexane back-extraction and precipitation of the HMs (mediated by hydrolysis of zero-valent magnesium (Mg0)}, aqueous washing suspension was regenerated and recycled twice to mobilize more contaminants from the soil. Three sonication-washes with the same charge of reagent mobilized appreciable quantities of PCBs (68 - 83%) and virtually all of the available Cd, Cu, Mn, and Pb and lesser amounts of the Zn (56%), Ni (59%), and Cr (50%) but only small quantities of Al (28%) and Fe (30%). The release of EDTA from heavy metals complexes was efficient for most metals (99%) but was influenced by the nature of surfactant. EDTA recovery (62-65%) post three cycles of soil washing, hexane back-extraction, and Mg 0 treatment was similar for all reagent combinations. Among surfactants and cyclodextrin, only anionic surfactants suffered losses to Mg0 treatment.</description><creator>Ehsan, Sadia.</creator><date>2006</date><subject>Soils -- Heavy metal content.</subject><subject>Polychlorinated biphenyls -- Environmental aspects.</subject><subject>Soil remediation.</subject><subject>Surface active agents.</subject><subject>Ethylenediaminetetraacetic acid.</subject><subject>Cyclodextrins.</subject><title>Simultaneous mobilization of polychlorinated biphenyl compounds and heavy metals from a field contaminated soil</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Sadia Ehsan, 2006</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4m90f0465.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558j35d</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Food Science and Agricultural Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:7p88cm83x</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:14:14Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>"Inclusion" in the broad sense of access to, and participation in, public policy and services has been lacking in the majority of developing countries---whether authoritarian or democratic---due to highly skewed political, social and economic power structures. To understand why this tends to be the case, the dissertation provides a political economy model for understanding civil society, arguing that the evolution of civil society and its potential as a vehicle for inclusion are conditioned by the economic imperatives in place and the state prerogatives. More specifically, I question the extent to which the neoliberal model allows civil society to fulfill this role, by examining the impact of Social Funds (SFs), a key social policy institution created and promoted solely under the neoliberal model, on civil society in Egypt and Bolivia. I argue that neoliberalism severely limits the possibility of: citizenship construction, achieving development synergy between the state and civil society, or strengthening the latter. These limitations are structural, inherent to the neoliberal development model and the changes it has brought about economically and politically. The research shows how these changes have manifestations within the state, the economy and civil society and more specifically social policy. Just as important, there are limitations intrinsically grounded in the structures found in many developing countries, pre-neoliberal changes. Such structures, I argue, do not allow new institutions like SFs to push forward such an ideal three-way relationship among the economy, state and civil society. Rather than strengthening civil society and creating development synergy, SFs are shown to be just an attempt to give neoliberal policies a human face and subdue any potential for structural changes. More generally, by contrasting the dynamics of civil society under neoliberalism in a developing country with a democratic regime (Bolivia) with those of a soft authoritarian regime (Egypt). I argue that a dichotomous framework, which sees democracy as antithetically opposed to authoritarianism is not necessarily appropriate to the analysis of developing countries. The cases illustrate that the state and civil society, under two-different regime types, continue to share a number of similarities.</description><creator>El-Mahdi, Rabab.</creator><date>2005</date><subject>Egypt -- Politics and government -- 1981-</subject><subject>Civil society -- Bolivia.</subject><subject>Civil society -- Egypt.</subject><subject>Bolivia -- Politics and government -- 1982-2006.</subject><subject>Economic development projects -- Bolivia.</subject><subject>Economic development projects -- Egypt.</subject><title>Social democratization or political manipulation? : social funds in Egypt and Bolivia</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>© Rabab El-Mahdi, 2005</rights><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/w3763c10p.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/7p88cm83x</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):42125</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>