<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="/assets/blacklight_oai_provider/oai2-b0e501cadd287c203b27cfd4f4e2d266048ec6ca2151d595f4c1495108e36b88.xsl"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd"><responseDate>2020-07-25T03:47:35Z</responseDate><request resumptionToken="oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):41075" verb="ListRecords">https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/catalog/oai</request><ListRecords><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2514nm223</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:25Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>An extensive review of all the avoidance apparatus which have been used to date in chemical avoidance tests and also an analysis of the trends and needs for new improved designs led to the design of a new avoidance apparatus. The new apparatus is a viable tool for analyzing the behavioral responses of fish to potentially toxic effluents in three dimensions. The method is quick, sensitive and relatively easy to use if sufficient fish stock is available. The variable parameters of the avoidance reaction were three: (a) the type of the pollutant, (b) the injection system, and (c) the concentration of the pollutant. Statistical analysis for the experiments included preliminary calculations, time series analysis, analysis of variance and Duncan's tests. Preliminary tests evaluated the general disposition of fish in the channel, the influence of a water acclimation jet and also the effects of noise, light and temperature. Experiments were performed to define the optimal number of fish per experiment, the influence of video analysis and also of variability, adaptability and continuity. The types of pollutants used were D.S.S. (dodecyl sodium sulfate)--a well-known reference pollutant, polymers, monomers, a plating industrial effluent and its components (Cr, Ni, Fe). For all of these, horizontal and vertical distributions were produced together with avoidance curves and avoidance reaction representations. The role of the avoidance reaction in relation to lethal and sublethal levels has been defined; after the evaluation of synergism and antagonism phenomena, proposed adjustments for safe toxicant levels have been estimated.</description><creator>Hadjinicolaou, John.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Water -- Pollution -- Toxicology.</subject><subject>Fishes -- Effect of water pollution on.</subject><title>Water pollution control with toxicant avoidance tests</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/8p58pd70w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2514nm223</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dj52w5587</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>A generalized approximate hand method of analysis is presented for determining the lateral deflections and internal forces in complex multi-storey structures subject to lateral loading. The buildings may include symmetric or asymmetric combinations of coupled walls, rigid frames, shear walls, wall-frames, rigid frames with central walls, frames with single and multi-storey bracing systems as well as cores that are either open or partially closed by floor beams. The deformations taken into account include bending, axial, shear and torsion. The analysis is based on the continuous medium technique in which the bents in the structure are replaced by idealized assemblies representing their characteristic modes of behaviour. The proposed method is restricted to structures with uniform geometry up the height and linear elastic behaviour of the structural members. Design equations are presented for the conventional lateral loading cases: a concentrated load at the top of the structure, a uniformly distributed load, and a triangularly distributed load with maximum intensity at the top. The simplicity of this method allows the sway of a structure, the maximum storey sway and its location in the height of the structure to be determined graphically. This procedure enables not only a rapid estimate of the deflections in the structure but together with an assessment of the internal forces it provides a design office method of comparing the efficiencies of different structural alternatives in the preliminary design of tall building structures.</description><creator>Hoenderkamp, Hans J. C. D.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Structural analysis (Engineering) -- Approximation methods.</subject><subject>Tall buildings.</subject><subject>Dead loads (Mechanics) -- Approximation methods.</subject><title>A general hand method of analysis for tall building structures subject to lateral loads /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/f4752h48r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dj52w5587</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6969z1584</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Hepatic alpha-adrenoceptors have been characterized pharmacologically and biochemically. In isolated rat liver cells, activation of glycogen phosphorylase by adrenergic agonists and its inhibition by subsite selective antagonists are mediated by alpha(,1)-receptors that do not display the phenomenon of receptor reserve. When tested in dilute cell suspensions to minimize uptake and metabolism of ligands, these receptors have properties indistinguishable from those of alpha(,1)-receptors in other tissues. In purified liver plasma membranes, the reversible radioligand {('3)H}prazosin labels a single population of high affinity binding sites with properties similar to the alpha(,1)-receptors mediating the glycogenolytic response of intact cells. Affinity labeling of these sites was achieved by using {('3)H}phenoxybenzamine ({('3)H}POB), synthesized in our laboratory. In intact liver cells {('3)H}POB binds irreversibly to stereoselective sites with properties expected from alpha-receptors. Half-maximal blockade of the glycogenolytic response to adrenaline and half-maximal saturation of binding sites occur at the same, low nanomolar concentrations of POB, at which no labeling of serotonin, histamine or muscarinic receptors can be detected. Further analysis of {('3)H}POB binding in purified plasma membranes indicates selective labeling of the alpha(,1)-receptor subtype. Molecular characterization of detergent-solubilized, {('3)H}POB-labeled alpha(,1)-receptors indicates that it is a protein with a Stokes radius of 6 nm, and a subunit molecular weight of 80,000.</description><creator>Kan, Wai Ho.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Pharmacological and biochemical characterization of alpha1 adrenoceptor in rat liver</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xw42n8787.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6969z1584</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:0c483k09s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:26Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The perception of isometric forces was examined under normal conditions, during sustained constant force contractions, and during vibration of the muscle tendon. In these experiments a contralateral limb matching procedure was employed, and force and the brachial biceps and triceps electromyogram (EMG) were recorded from each arm. Under normal conditions it was found that smaller forces were consistently overestimated in magnitude. During sustained constant force contractions the matching forces exerted by the unfatigued arm increased linearly as did the EMG of the fatiguing muscle. These results are consistent with force judgements being made with respect to the excitatory input to the reference muscle. It was further determined that during fatigue subjects were unable to dissociate the force of exertion from the motor command generating the contraction. Muscle tendon vibration increased the variability of force judgements and resulted in the overestimation of forces. This appeared to be due to co-contraction of the antagonist triceps muscle during vibration of the contracting biceps. The increase in the perceived magnitude of force during vibration is again consistent with the centrally-mediated theory of force perception.</description><creator>Jones, Lynette Anne.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Arm -- Muscles.</subject><subject>Psychophysics.</subject><subject>Perception.</subject><title>The role of central and peripheral mechanisms in isometric force perception in humans /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0k225b79r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/0c483k09s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:44558f06b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Bacterial invasion of vertebrates triggers a marked reduction in the levels of iron associated with the plasma transferrin (Tf) pool. This hypoferremic response has been regarded as a host attempt to withhold essential iron from the invading pathogen. The exact nature of the mechanisms involved remains obscure. The plasma Tf iron pool was studied with radiolabeled mouse Tf and its kinetics were determined in normal and infected mice. The plasma Tf iron pool of normal mice was dynamic with a half-life of 0.7 h. Iron left the plasma pool, entered the bone marrow, and was incorporated into erythrocytes. Studies with mice infected with Neisseria meningitidis revealed similar kinetics including no redistribution of iron within the various iron pools. Iron turnover in the Tf pool during the hypoferremic phase was also similar to control rates. Therefore, hypoferremia did not result from an accelerated removal of iron from the plasma Tf pool as previously suggested. These results implicate an impaired return of reticulo-endothelial (RE) system processed iron to the Tf pool during the hypoferremia. The kinetics of iron processing by the RE system were studied by labeling the RE compartments with ('59)Fe-labeled denatured red blood cells. Uptake and redistribution of the label indicated the RE-processed iron was not returned to the plasma Tf pool during the hypoferremia. Fractionation of hepatic cellular compartments showed that this impaired release of iron resulted from a preferential incorporation of heme-derived iron into the intracellular ferritin pool and this produces the hypoferremia. The role of ceruloplasmin (ferroxidase I,EC.1.16.3.1) (Cp) in iron metabolism during meningococcal infection was investigated. Plasma Cp ferroxidase activity was found to increase greatly in mice during the convalescence phase. Ferroxidase-deficient mice became hypoferremic as a result of an impaired return of heme-derived iron to plasma Tf. This hypoferremia was associated with an increased resistance to Neisseria meningitidis infection, an effect readily reversed by Cp supplementation or iron addition. This implicates Cp as an important component in the regulation of the plasma Tf iron pool. It also suggests that the increased levels of Cp during the acute phase response may serve to restore normal plasma Tf iron levels.</description><creator>Letendre, Elaine.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Biology, Microbiology.</subject><title>Regulation of iron metabolism during Neisseria meningitidis infection in mice</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/02870w654.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/44558f06b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology and Immunology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tq57nr74c</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The influence of protein-calorie malnutrition (PCM) on the anti-inflammatory activity (suppression of carrageenan-induced paw edema and pleurisy) of salicylate was studied in Sprague-Dawley male rats. For this purpose, animals were fed a 21% (control) or a 5% (PCM) protein diet ad libitum or a control diet in restricted amounts (pair-fed). A significant increase in the anti-inflammatory activity of salicylate was observed in PCM but not in pair-fed rats. PCM caused a decrease in plasma salicylate (assayed by HPLC) concentration (due to increased synthesis of glycine conjugate and elimination), no change in tissue distribution, and a moderate decrease in serum protein binding of salicylate. PCM exerted inconsistent effects on the activities of liver lysosomal enzymes (activities of (beta)-glucuronidase decreased, of acid phosphatase did not change, and of aryl salfatase increased) and there was no relationship between the lysosome stabilizing and anti-inflammatory activities of salicylate and other aspirin-like drugs (indomethacin and oxyphenbutazone). It was therefore concluded that the PCM-induced increase in the anti-inflammatory activity of salicylate was primarily not due to any changes in its pharmacokinetics or in its effects on lysosomal membranes. The biosynthesis of prostaglandins and leukotrienes was studied because of their important role in inflammatory processes. PCM decreased the biosynthesis by pleural neutrophils of both cyclooxygenase-independent (major products: thromboxane B(,2) and 12-hydroxy-5,8,10-heptadecatrienoic acid) and lipoxygenase-dependent (leukotriene B(,4)) metabolites of arachidonic acid. The biosynthesis of prostaglandins E(,2) and F(,2(alpha)) by renal medulla homogenates and of prostaglandin D(,2) and 12-hydroxy-5,8,10,14-eicosatetraenoic acid by spleen homogenates were also reduced by PCM. At all concentrations of aspirin studied, the amounts of these metabolites were less in preparations from PCM than from control animals. Ho</description><creator>Yue, Tian Li.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Influence of protein-calorie malnutrition on the anti-inflammatory activity of salicylate in rats</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qn59q476k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tq57nr74c</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:x920fx52b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:27Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The characteristics and expression of laboratory derived chloramphenicol (CM) resistance in P. aeruginosa were examined. Resistant strains exhibiting single cell resistance of 1.5 to 2 mg/mL were readily isolated following one passage in CM at 150 to 1000 (mu)g/mL. Isogenic strains, selected on CM at 150 and 500 (mu)g/mL were chosen for detailed study. Resistance was not a consequence of drug detoxification or altered sensitivity of the target site. The resistant strains exhibited unusual phenotypic properties including pronounced variations in growth rate, CM susceptibility and cell morphology as a function of the composition of the growth medium. Growth in CM also resulted in significant alterations in amino acid transport and respiratory capacity, the extent of which varied with the strain, the growth medium and the concentration of CM. These drug and medium-dependent alterations were determined to reside in an increased and highly specific requirement for Ca('2+), Mg('2+), Mn('2+) or Sr('2+). Manipulation of the divalent cation concentration of a variety of growth media resulted in dramatic alterations in growth rate, resistance and amino acid transport. Ca('2+) was significantly more effective than the latter three ions. The expression of native and plasmid-mediated CM resistance was also modified by the external concentration of divalent cations. In view of the nature and specificity of the cation requirement, it was concluded that (1) divalent cation-mediated alterations of outer membrane permeability are fundamental to the expression of native and acquired CM resistance in P. aeruginosa; (2) laboratory-derived CM resistance involves envelope changes, such that interaction with divalent cations promotes more effective exclusion of CM. The latter conclusion is supported by other divalent cation-dependent alterations in envelope function in the resistant strains.</description><creator>Irvin, Jean E.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Drug resistance in microorganisms.</subject><subject>Chloramphenicol.</subject><subject>Pseudomonas aeruginosa.</subject><title>Chloramphenicol resistance in Pseudomonas aeruginosa</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rx913q707.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/x920fx52b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Microbiology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:tb09j643j</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis examines the social accommodations made by prisoners' wives as their husbands pass through various stages in the criminalization process. A combination of methods--in-depth interviews with wives, structured interviews with married prisoners, systematic examinations of prison records, summaries of women's "rap sessions," and a variety of other sources of data--were used to construct an ethnographic account of the social worlds of thirty women married to men incarcerated in two prisons in Vermont. Wives' accounts are quite consistent with other data sources. Prisoners' wives display considerable ingenuity in devising explanations and interpretations of their husbands' criminal behavior which allow their marriages to continue. The effect of these definitions is to "normalize" this behavior and to buffer the wives from external definitions of the situations in which they find themselves. While wives vary these interpretations--and the attendant normalization strategies they employ--depending on circumstances, five major techniques emerge: (1) nurturing, (2) "pain-in-the-ass" behavior, (3) passive distance, (4) co-deviance, and (5) reluctant co-deviance.</description><creator>Fishman, Laura.</creator><date>1984</date><subject>Women -- Psychology.</subject><subject>Criminals.</subject><subject>Prisoners' spouses.</subject><subject>Husband and wife.</subject><title>Women at the wall : a study of prisoners' wives doing time on the outside</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/p2676w34n.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/tb09j643j</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Sociology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:vt150j955</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:28Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Three microalloyed steels were tested under continuous and interrupted loading conditions. These materials consisted of a base steel containing 0.06%C and 1.31%Mn and two further alloys containing single additions of 0.29%Mo and 0.04%Nb. Double hit compression tests were performed on cylindrical specimens of the three steels at 820, 780 and 740$ sp circ$C within the $ alpha$ + $ gamma$ field. A softening curve was determined at each temperature using the offset method. It was observed that, in the base steel, $ alpha$ recrystallizes more slowly than $ gamma$. The addition of Mo steel retards the recrystallization of the base material; it has a greater influence on $ gamma$ than on $ alpha$ recrystallization. Nb addition has an even greater effect on the recrystallization of the two phases. In this steel, the recrystallization of ferrite was incomplete at the three intercritical temperatures. Furthermore, the austenite remained completely unrecrystallized up to the maximum time involved in the experiments (1 hr). The progress of ferrite recrystallization was followed on quenched specimens of the three steels by means of quantitative metallography. Most of the data fit an Avrami equation with exponents in the range 2 to 2.5. A departure from this equation was observed for the final stages of the recrystallization process. Growth rate analysis showed that the average growth rate decreased with time for all the experimental materials, this decrease being greatest for the base steel and least for the Nb-containing grade. The nucleation of recrystallization was observed to occur heterogeneously in the microstructure. The interface between ferrite and austenite was the preferred site for nucleation. Measurement of the number and size of recrystallized ferrite grains showed that some grains begin to recrystallize very early, growing to a large size by the end of the process. The total number of grains increased continuously until almost 80% of the volume fraction was recrystallized. After that, due to coalescence, the number of recrystallized grains decreased very rapidly. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Simielli, Eider Alberto</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Metallurgy.</subject><title>Deformation and recrystallization kinetics of microalloyed steels in the intercritical region</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/4b29b677v.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/vt150j955</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:gh93h027v</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis is a contribution to the covering times problems for random walks on graphs. By considering uniform random walks on finite connected graphs, the covering time is defined as the time (number of steps) taken by the random walk to visit every vertex. The motivating problem of this thesis is to find bounds for the expected covering times. We provide explicit bounds that are uniformly valid over all starting points and over large classes of graphs. In some cases the asymptotic distribution of the suitably normalized covering time is given as well.</description><creator>Sbihi, Amine M. (Amine Mohammed)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Statistics.</subject><title>Covering times for random walks on graphs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/0c483j99r.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/gh93h027v</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:ff3655788</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The effect of electrical double layers on the diffusion of spherical colloidal particles was studied using photon correlation spectroscopy (PCS). The diffusion constant was found to equal that of a neutral particle at low and high electrolyte concentration and was reduced by several percent when the electrical double layer is comparable to the particle radius, in agreement with the general theory for charged particles. PCS studies of bimodal colloidal dispersions included the experimental verification of the bimodal homodyne autocorrelation function and the introduction of quasi-heterodyne detection. The effect of electrical double layers on the diffusion of rod shaped colloidal particles was studied with PCS, using tobacco mosaic virus particles as probes. The results are qualitatively similar to those for spherical particles, with the minimum occurring when the double layer is comparable to the radius of an equivalent sphere. The intensity of the light scattered from latex particles in an evanescent wave was measured as a function of the penetration depth of the evanescent wave. The results were found to be consistent with those predicted from DLVO theory.</description><creator>Schumacher, Gerhard A. (Gerhard Arthur)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Chemistry, Analytical.</subject><subject>Physics, Optics.</subject><title>Light scattering studies on electrostatically stabilized colloidal particles</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/pk02cb54d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/ff3655788</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:2z10wq89b</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:29Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>We use a method of analytic continuation introduced by M. Flensted-Jensen to study the asymptotic behaviour of the heat kernel on noncompact symmetric spaces, for values of the time parameter which are arbitrarily small or arbitrarily large. The same method is applied to one case of the inversion problem for the Abel transform. The results are illustrated with explicit computations for SL(3, R).</description><creator>Chayet, Maurice, 1953-</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Mathematics.</subject><title>Some general estimates for the heat kernel on symmetric spaces and related problems of integral Geometry</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/x059c8253.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/2z10wq89b</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mathematics and Statistics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:5t34sk251</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The generalized local-spin-density functional (G-LSD) theory is proposed which avoids (a) the physical restriction used in the generalized exchange local-spin-density functional (GX-LSD) theory; (b) the homogeneous electron-density approximation in the Hartree-Fock-Slater (HFS) theory and in the Gaspar-Kohn-Sham (GKS) theory; and (c) the time-consuming step to search the optimal exchange parameter for each atom or ion in the X$ alpha$ and $ Xi$a theories. Theoretically, the G-LSD theory is more rigorous than the GX-LSD, HFS, GKS, and $ Xi$a theories. Numerically, the statistical total energies for atoms are better in the G-LSD theory than in the GKS theory. Ionization potentials and electron affinities of atoms, the stability of singly and doubly charged negative ions, and the electronegativities, and hardnesses of the fractional charged atoms with Z $&lt;$ 37 are calculated by the SIC-GX-LSD theory with the GWB Fermi-hole parameters and electron-correlation correction. The self-interaction correction (SIC) is introduced into the multiple-Scattering X$ alpha$ (MS-X$ alpha$) method and used to calculate some molecules and molecular anions. The results show that the ionization potentials from the negative of the one-electron eigenvalues are as good as those obtained in the transition state calculation and in very good agreement with experiment.</description><creator>Guo, Yufei</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Chemistry, Physical.</subject><subject>Physics, Molecular.</subject><subject>Physics, Atomic.</subject><title>The local-density-functional theory : application to atoms and molecules</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/kh04dq377.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/5t34sk251</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Chemistry</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:6d56zx276</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Cette etude propose une analyse de "Tel Quel" en tant que mouvement de neo-avant-garde situe a la frontiere de la modernite et de la postmodernite. Nous y considerons tous les textes de creation (roman et poesie) publies dans la collection "Tel Quel" entre 1960 et 1982, sans negliger l'etude de leur rapport avec la reflexion theorique exposee dans les essais et les articles de la revue. Cette these represente en meme temps un effort de synthese des principales typologies ou tentatives de definition proposees par la critique occidentale pour caracteriser les mouvements litteraires issus des societes post-industrielles: modernite, postmodernite, modernisme, postmodernisme, avant-garde, post avant-garde et neo-avant-garde.</description><creator>Gagné, Marie, 1961-</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Postmodernism (Literature)</subject><subject>French literature -- 20th century -- History and criticism.</subject><title>Le mouvement "Tel Quel": neo-avant-garde et postmodernite</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/3197xm47b.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/6d56zx276</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Département de langue et littérature françaises</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:4j03d044s</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:30Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Previous results indicate that the functional properties of myelinated axons are considerably more complex than previously believed. The purpose of this study was to further examine the functional properties of potassium conductances in dorsal and ventral root (DRA; VRA) frog myelinated axons by intracellular microelectrode recording. The voltage responses to hyperpolarizing current injection demonstrated: (1) a nonlinear voltage current (V/I) relationship in the region just below resting membrane potential; (2) a linear peak and steady state V/I relationship below $ approx$ $-$95 mV; (3) a large effective capacitance of the internodal membrane; and (4) an attenuation of the voltage response reflecting the activation of a voltage dependent anomalous rectifying conductance (G$ sb{ rm AR}$). G$ sb{ rm AR}$ is dependent on the presence of sodium and potassium ions in the external medium and is blocked by cesium but not barium ions. (5) An afterhyperpolarizing potential (AHP) after a train of action potentials was accounted for by the presence of a sodium dependent potassium conductance (G$ sb{ rm K(Na)}$). The functional role of the voltage dependent potassium conductances and G$ sb{ rm K(Na)}$ was examined. G$ sb{ rm AR}$ appears to regulate the length of a post tetanic AHP. Early accommodation (EAcc) is regulated by G$ sb{ rm Kf1}$ in DRA and VRA. Late accommodation (LAcc) and adaptation (Adp) is regulated by G$ sb{ rm Ks}$ in both DRA and VRA. G$ sb{ rm Kf2}$ may also contribute to EAcc and Adp. Action potential repolarization in DRA and VRA is governed by G$ sb{ rm Kf2}$ and G$ sb{ rm Kf1}$ respectively. G$ sb{ rm K(Na)}$ may also contribute to LAcc and Adp. An evaluation of our experimental results using a computer model based Hodgkin-Huxley type equations suggests that the gating of the sodium conductance plays only a minor role in accommodation and adaptation. These results indicate that potassium conductances play a pivotal role in regulating the excitabilit</description><creator>Poulter, Michael Owen</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Biology, Cell.</subject><subject>Biology, Animal Physiology.</subject><title>The role of potassium conductances in regulating the excitability of myelinated axons /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/xg94hq35d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/4j03d044s</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:79407x96w</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This thesis addresses the problem of simultaneously transmitting several data signals across a single channel. For this purpose, a transmultiplexer that uses modulated filter banks is studied. Modulated filter banks comprise filters that are bandpass versions of a lowpass prototype. The filters serve to assign portions of the channel bandwidth to the data signals. The impulse responses of the filters are parameterized by a center frequency, delay and phase factor. The objectives in configuring modulated filter banks are to use the full channel bandwidth for transmission, cancel crosstalk between signals (arises when signals share bandwidth) and cancel intersymbol interference in each data signal. Assuming an ideal channel, a synthesis procedure is developed by assigning a bandwidth to the lowpass prototype and deriving relationships among the center frequencies, delays and phases such that the entire channel bandwidth is utilized and crosstalk is cancelled. New design procedures for an FIR lowpass prototype are proposed such that the intersymbol interference is suppressed. One design method is based on a minimax criterion. Another approach involves an unconstrained optimization of an error function. The synthesis procedure leads to five bandwidth efficient transmultiplexers. Three of the systems implement multicarrier Quadrature Amplitude Modulation (QAM) and two accomplish multicarrier Vestigial Sideband Modulation (VSB). The performance of the five systems is compared with filters obtained by the new design approaches. Also, the issue of channel distortion is addressed. Finally, the transmultiplexers can be converted into new subband systems.</description><creator>Ramachandran, Ravi P.</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Bandwidth efficient filter banks for transmultiplexers</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/9019s3210.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/79407x96w</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8910jv33g</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:31Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The concept of soil buffer capacity was used in this study to investigate the capacity of soil to attenuate heavy metals when acid is involved in the soil system. The buffer capacity of soil in this study was found to depend mainly on carbonate content and cation exchange capacity (C.E.C.) of soils. The magnitude of buffer capacity followed the order: illite $&gt;$ montmorillonite $&gt;$ natural clay soil $ gg$ kaolinite. The study of heavy metal retention in soils was performed both by soil suspension test and soil column test. The results showed that as soils received increasing amounts of acid, high amounts of heavy metals (particularly Pb and Cu) could still be retained if the soils had a high enough buffer capacity to resist a change in pH such that it will not drop to $ Cu &gt; Zn &gt; Cd.$ The order changed to $Pb &gt; Cd &gt; Zn &gt; Cu$ when soils were at low soil solution pH. Relative mobility of heavy metals found from the soil column test followed the order $Pb &lt; Cu &lt; Zn leq Cd.$ The relation of soil buffer capacity and heavy metal retention and movement in the clay soils found from this study revealed that the soil buffer capacity was a parameter that can be used in the prediction and prevention of heavy metal migration in soil. The soil buffer capacity is recommended as a parameter that should be included in the determination of soil properties particularly for the purpose of land application and disposal of wastes with leachates that could contain heavy metals. (Abstract shortened by UMI.)</description><creator>Phadungchewit, Yuwaree</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Civil.</subject><title>The role of pH and soil buffer capacity in heavy metal retention in clay soils /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/gh93h026k.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8910jv33g</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Civil Engineering and Applied Mechanics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:1z40kt54k</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The signal from stationary and flowing material in rapid field echo magnetic resonance imaging sequences is examined theoretically and experimentally. Three sequence variants are considered which differ according to their use of transverse magnetization coherences. One sequence variant attempts to eliminate coherences by cycling the phase of the RF pulses. This approach is analyzed numerically and an optimal RF phase increment is presented. The theoretical response from flowing material is derived by considering the temporal derivatives of position and the gradient waveform moments evaluated over each repetition period. Numerical simulations are used to predict the net response from a voxel. These signal models are used to optimize time-of-flight field echo angiographic sequence parameters for studies of the extra and intra-cranial arteries by assuming mean blood velocities and transit times respectively. The contrast-to-noise ratio per unit time is the function maximized in this analysis and both 2-D multi-slice and 3-D volume acquisitions are considered.</description><creator>Pike, G. Bruce (Gilbert Bruce)</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Engineering, Electronics and Electrical.</subject><title>Signal behaviour in magnetic resonance angiography using rapid field echo sequences</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/rr171x87z.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/1z40kt54k</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Electrical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:dz010q790</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The aim of the work presented in this thesis was to study the effects of 4-aminopyridine (4-AP, 5-100 $ mu$M) on rat hippocampal slices maintained in vitro. Two types of synchronous potentials were evoked by 4-AP: epileptiform bursts and GABA-mediated potentials. Bursts were initiated in CA3 by giant excitatory postsynaptic potentials (EPSPs) mediated by quisqualate/kainate receptors and involving recurrent excitatory pathways. This epileptiform activity occurred despite the presence of potentiated inhibitory postsynaptic potentials (IPSPs) and could propagate to CAl. The second type of activity occurred in all regions of the hippocampal slice and consisted of long-lasting depolarizations (LLDs) mediated by a Cl$ sp-$ efflux through dendritic GABA$ sb{ rm A}$ receptor ionophores. As resection experiments and pharmacological studies indicated that the propagation of LLDs did not require synaptic transmission, we propose that a novel coupling mechanism between GABAergic interneurons involving (K$ sp+ rbrack sb0$ accumulation and redistribution is revealed by 4-AP.</description><creator>Perreault, Paul</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Biology, Neuroscience.</subject><title>A contribution to the understanding of the effects of 4-aminopyridine on rat hippocampal slices /</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/th83m008d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/dz010q790</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Neurology and Neurosurgery</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:rr171x887</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:32Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The present study investigates in vitro electrophysiological effects of therapeutic concentrations of quinidine (5-10 $ mu$M) and its combination with the Class Ib agents mexiletine and tocainide in canine Purkinje fibers with the use of standard microelectrode techniques. The frequency- and voltage-dependent depression of V$ sb{ rm max}$, used as an index of peak sodium conductance, by quinidine and the combination of quinidine and tocainide (50 $ mu$M) were assessed with the kinetics of onset of, and recovery form, rate-dependent block, and the curve relating V$ sb{ rm max}$ to membrane potential. The frequency-dependence of quinidine-induced repolarization abnormalities arising from early after-depolarizations (EADs) was characterized in the presence of low (K$ sp+$) $ sb0$ (2.7 mM) and mild acidosis (pH = 7.06 $ pm$ 0.08). Acidosis was found to favor triggered activity by directly prolonging action potential duration. Quinidine induced two types of EAD-induced triggered activity, viz. arising from phase 2 and arising from phase 3, which differed in the frequency-dependence of their characteristics (activation voltage, amplitude, and coupling interval), and their sensitivities to abolition by mexiletine. Adrenaline (1 $ mu$M) decreased the minimum cycle length for triggered activity, shortened the coupling interval of triggered responses, and transformed single triggered responses into multiple. It also induced rapid activity resembling sustained triggered activity, induced triggered responses arising from phase 2, and facilitated their transmission to ventricular muscle. The combination of quinidine with a Class Ib drug proved to be beneficial by improving its antiarrhythmic effect and preventing its bradycardia-related excessive QT prolongation. Triggered activity was found to originate only in Purkinje fibers, but electrotonic influence from ventricular muscle strongly affected its manifestation. These results provide the evidence that EAD-induced triggered</description><creator>Valois, Maria</creator><date>1990</date><subject>Health Sciences, Pharmacology.</subject><title>Antiarrhythmic and arrhythmogenic profiles of quinidine and their modulation by class Ib antiarrhythmic drugs</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/qf85nb88m.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/rr171x887</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Pharmacology and Therapeutics</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qz20st322</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>This work develops a backfill design procedure aimed to facilitate the optimization of an available mine material in order to meet target objectives in a particular mining role. This required the compilation and analysis of data on fill usage, established design procedures, physical and geomechanical properties, testing techniques and procedures, as well as behavioural modelling methods. A backfill classification system is proposed based upon size distribution. A series of design equations are presented which relate to this system. These equations represent the means by which backfill geomechanical behaviour can be related to physical properties. This is considered to be fundamental to an effective backfill design procedure. Derivation of the equations has been based upon analysis of data from a program of laboratory and in situ testing conducted in ten operating Canadian mines by the author, together with other published work. The in situ testing required the development of a pressuremeter testing procedure novel to underground mining. The theoretical basis for the employment of pressuremeter data has been examined and behavioral equations have been developed to describe the deformation and stress history during a backfill material test. In addition two new equations have been developed for the analysis of pressuremeter data. The in situ data collected has been correlated with laboratory derived geomechanical data for the same backfill materials. The geomechanical properties associated with the proposed backfill classifications have also been related to their influence on backfill behaviour in three mine backfill roles: free standing stability during pillar recovery in bulk mining methods; dynamic interaction with stope walls in rockburst prone ground; and ability to reduce stresses in highly stressed rock masses. This work has been based on new and established modelling methods and aims to provide insight into the effectiveness of the backfill classes in these roles of growing practical significance.</description><creator>Piciacchia, Luciano, 1959-</creator><date>1987</date><subject>Engineering, Mining.</subject><title>Field and laboratory studies of mine backfill design criteria</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6d56zx28g.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qz20st322</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Mining and Metallurgical Engineering</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:sf2685909</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:33Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>Previous research has shown that ingestion of sucrose or injection of glucose following a learning experience can improve an animal's memory for that experience. The present work was directed towards elucidating the mechanisms by which sucrose and glucose produce this effect. Memory was tested by determining the effects of post-training injections of various substances on a conditioned emotional response. Glucose itself exerted a dose-dependent bidirectional action on retention. This action was shown not to depend on particular blood glucose levels. Insulin did not improve retention at any of the doses tested. Fructose, a sugar that does not cross the blood-brain barrier produced a dose-response effect on retention similar to that of glucose suggesting that fructose and glucose may act through a common peripheral mechanism. The observation of a memory improvement following injections of either 2-deoxyglucose or 3-O-methylgucose, two non-metabolized glucose analogs, suggested that the effect of glucose on retention may be due to an action on glucose transport and not to any metabolic effects of glucose. Two peripheral organs were examined for their possible involvement in the memory-improving action of glucose. This action was shown not to be dependent on the adrenal medulla which has been implicated in the action of other mnemoactive treatments. Partial denervation of the liver produced a partial attenuation of the effect of glucose on retention. The results are discussed in terms of the action of reinforcers on endogenous physiological mechanisms that modulate memory consolidation.</description><creator>Messier, Claude.</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Memory.</subject><subject>Psychophysiology.</subject><subject>Glucose.</subject><title>Effect of glucose on memory : examination of possible mechanisms</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/k643b199d.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/sf2685909</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Psychology</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:8623hz426</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><description>The main thesis of this study is that Islam played a role in the history of the Tunisian nationalist movement on two levels. It was considered as a fundamental component in defining the specificity of the Tunisian nation, source of legitimacy of the Tunisian nationalist movement both before and after independence. Moreover, as a fundamental component of the Tunisian "personality", it influenced the mode of communication used by nationalist leaders to mobilize the masses. The biographical approach served to focus the issue through the prism of Habib Bourguiba's life. It revealed that even this most secular of Arab leaders could not shed the Arab-Islamic heritage of Tunisia precisely because Islam, as a fundamental component of the Tunisian "personality" and as the language of the masses, held the key to political legitimacy.</description><creator>Salem, Norma.</creator><date>1983</date><subject>Presidents -- Tunisia.</subject><subject>Islam and politics -- Tunisia.</subject><subject>Bourguiba, Habib, 1903-</subject><subject>Tunisia -- History -- French occupation, 1881-1956.</subject><title>Habib Bourguiba : a study of Islam and legitimacy in the Arab World</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/g445cd94h.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/8623hz426</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:wp988k64r</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:34Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Kim, Sae Jung.</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Korea (South) -- Politics and government -- 1960-1988.</subject><subject>Korea (South) -- Economic policy -- 1960-1988.</subject><title>The political economy of authoritarianism : state-propelled industrialization and the persistent authoritarian state in South Korea, 1961-1979</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/np1939763.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/wp988k64r</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Department of Political Science</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><record><header><identifier>oai:escholarship.mcgill.ca:qj72p7915</identifier><datestamp>2020-04-06T21:07:35Z</datestamp></header><metadata><thesis xmlns="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/ http://www.ndltd.org/standards/metadata/etdms/1-0/etdms.xsd"><creator>Karamustafa, Ahmet T., 1956-</creator><date>1986</date><subject>Sufi literature -- Turkey.</subject><subject>Vāḥīdī, fl. 1522. Menāḳıb-i ḥvoca-i Cihān ve Netīce-i cān.</subject><subject>Antinomianism -- Early works to 1800.</subject><subject>Sufism -- Turkey</subject><subject>Mysticism -- Turkey -- Islam -- History.</subject><title>Vāḥīdī's Menāḳıb-i Ḥvoca-i Cihān ve Netīce-i Cān : critical edition and historical analysis</title><language>eng</language><publisher>McGill University</publisher><type>Thesis</type><rights>All items in eScholarship@McGill are protected by copyright with all rights reserved unless otherwise indicated.</rights><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/downloads/6108vc07w.pdf</identifier><identifier>https://escholarship.mcgill.ca/concern/theses/qj72p7915</identifier><degree><name>Doctor of Philosophy</name><grantor>McGill University</grantor><discipline>Institute of Islamic Studies</discipline></degree></thesis></metadata></record><resumptionToken completeListSize="47894">oai_etdms.s(Collection:theses).f(2019-10-16T06:03:34Z).u(2020-07-23T18:55:55Z).t(47894):41100</resumptionToken></ListRecords></OAI-PMH>